let take our culture back take our
culture back get the Mony off be back
and take our culture back when now we
been here for a million years music
filling up the people's ears and we
always sang our own song Until the music
bu business came along now I don't know
I could be wrong but I ain't about to
just tag along behind somebody with a
bank roll hanging out telling me what I
can sing about take off Co your back
take off Co your back get the monkey off
of be back and take off Co your
back you got the radio you got the TV
screen you got the great Muddy Waters of
the mainstream with the dollar bill
hitting out every word you never going
to get your message heard over some
little buddy with an extra [ __ ] to BU
transmitter and try their luck pirate
with democracy that's seems like a good
idea to me so let's take our coach your
back take our coach your back get the
monkey off of your back and take
back Hollywood spectacle and promade
think of all that money just waiting to
be made all you got to do is go and
you'll be sitting up 30y on gangsters
road now it ain't smart to be misled by
some beus and Butthead you can have the
old hip Seattle slacker just give me a
good computer hacker let's take your
back take your back get the M off of
your back and take off coach your
back
you got to get inside to break it out
you got to be outside to know what I'm
talking about two heads in a million
eyes we can cut this thing right down to
size not culture is weaponry and all our
great humanity and survival is a counter
attack so let's take off Co your back
let's take off Co your back take off
cult your back and get the monkey off of
your back and take up C your
back
woo yeah do time