I believe that any
effort to bring compassion to
Ohio is a good
thing um I am a medical marijuana
patient in the state of Ohio like Donnie
said and I support all
efforts being
made to bring
compassion
um I am a patient in an illegal state
and we got to make the difference we've
got to stop that and we've got to make
it to where I don't have to be afraid
for using making a
Tre I
I it makes no sense to me you know folks
need
to get a grip and quit being so afraid
of a
plant uh we've got housef 24
in Ohio uh it was uh introduced by state
representative kennyo and state
representative Bobby
Hagen so Ohio's got a lot of exciting
things going on right now you know we're
trying to do it legislative wise which
I've been begging for the
last seven years to get our legislators
to stand up so now we got two different
very
different um Constitutional Amendments
that we are trying to get introduced as
well uh because one way or another Ohio
is going to get it whether we get our
legislators to do it or whether we bring
it to the people because Ohio ones are
tired of being
ignore
um two weeks ago I was hospitalized
with calcium deposits on my brain they
did a CAT on in all that my brain is
covered what I found come to find out
over the past few years that I've been
in this activism and in this movement is
that
marijuana uh or cannabis or pot or
whatever you call it or choose to call
it um is actually a neuroprotectant and
an
antioxidant and it can protect
what brain I've got that isn't damaged
from the uh calcium deposits that's
surrounding my brain right
now uh so I don't have cancer I I I
can't go get
chemotherapy so this fight has even
become even more personal because now
it's a life or death situation I knew
that with my big old long list of uh
health conditions and stuff that
cannabis
treated a lot of those
symptoms
but now it can actually protect what
brain I've got left so what I'm hoping
to do is is get folks on a national
level to stand up and do what's right
because right now I think it's y'all
that's going to save my life
um your brain controls everything and I
think I should deserve a
chance at fighting for my
life even though our government says
[Applause]
no they wouldn't lie to us though would
they abely you know they own
patents on canab anoid as neuro
protectants and antioxidants and they've
had that since
2003 how dare them to deny
anyone the right to use something that's
safe as aspir safer than aspon
actually
um I have enough problems with my
health
that I shouldn't have to worry about
being prosecuted and terrified
terrorized by our local law enforcement
or even our federal law
enforcement
so the house bill 214 the Ohio medical
uh cannabis Act of
2012 the AL Ohio alternative treatment
Amendment
um I I I'd say that's progress for Ohio
I'd say that we're moving in the right
direction and
um so keep us in your prayers keep us in
your
thoughts and stand up and do what's
right I'm going to turn the mic over
because we've got a lot of wonderful
folks that uh need to give their point
of view but thank you for giving me a
voice uh thank you for coming to this
wonderful Seattle thank you for inviting
me to
[Music]
Seattle God bless you