associate publisher of high times
magazine the longest running magazine
ever
to talk about our freedom give it up to
my brother rick cusick
thank you
thank you my hero
my name is rick cusick i am the
associate publisher of high times
magazine
thank you
the number one marijuana magazine in the
whole world
you
are the people at the 19th annual
seattle hemp fest the number one
marijuana event in the whole world
soup in a sandwich baby right here
the seattle hempfest has been going on
for 19 years and the seattle memphis has
been protecting our freedom my freedom
and your freedom for 19 years it is my
honor to come here every year and talk
to you
when i hear about the seattle hempfest i
say to myself well what's the seattle
hempfest about
some people would say the seattle hemp
fest is about marijuana
some people would say the seattle
hempfest is about medicine
some people would say the seattle hemp
fest is about
camp hit the number one food fuel and
fiber in the world preferred by my good
friend jack herrera
some people say that's what we're here
for today but you know something when i
think of the seattle hemp fest that's
not the first word
i don't think about marijuana i don't
think about him but i don't think about
medicine i think about those things but
not first the very first thing i think
about is the word freedom
freedom
can you say it with me
one two three
that's right that is the sweetest word
in the world and that is what the
seattle hempfest is about
you might say no no no it's about we no
no you might say no no it's about
medicine about him but i'm gonna prove
it to you i'm gonna prove it to you with
numbers the same way it was proven to me
i'll give you a number
100 million americans out of 300 million
americans 100 million americans have
smoked marijuana at some time in their
lives
and every year in the united states
25 million americans smoking at least
once a year
and every month in the united states at
least 15 million americans smoking once
a month
and
four million plus americans
smoke marijuana every single day
am i to take that there's a few of you
guys out there yeah
every single day
now let me tell you another set of
numbers another set of numbers that
gives that first set of numbers meaning
over 800
americans every year are arrested for
marijuana
over 600 000 americans every year
are arrested for simple possession no
weight no selling just a little head
stash that they want to get high on 600
000 plus americans
let me ask you this
anybody out there
25 years or under under 25 years old
god bless you i wish i was under 25
years old
but let me tell you something 400
000 americans almost 450 000 americans
every year who are arrested in this
country are under
25 years old
make no mistake the war against
marijuana is a war against young people
most of the people who are arrested in
this country are under 25 years old and
that's not by accident they target young
people
when you are young
when you are under 25 years old you have
the opportunity to express freedom like
you never will again in your life you
have the freedom to explore you have the
freedom to find out the things you love
feel free to find out the things you
hate when you're under 25 the world is
your oyster it used to be mine i'm 56
years old and i'm looking back at i had
spent 39 years of my life smoking
marijuana every day
but i am no longer
25 years old and under i am looking at
the ones right now who screamed when i
said are you under 25. i am looking at
the ones that the war on marijuana is
raged against
and i am telling you that this moment
right now in your life is the moment of
your greatest freedom it is the moment
when you must express
your demand for your freedom now and i'm
telling you you look at these old eyes
my young friends i am telling you
that if you do it now if you get up your
ass and you make sure that they legalize
marijuana and now in your life when
there's a greater moment now than it has
ever been
you will never forget it this is the
moment of freedom this is the generation
i'm looking at it right out here i'm
looking at it you are the generation
that will legalize marijuana in your
lifetime
my generation dropped that ball
my generation we thought back in the
1970s we're gonna have this [ __ ]
legalized by 1975
that didn't work
1979 that didn't work
1985 that took on and on
good people my age kept that ball in the
air
19 years they've been doing it here in
seattle and now at this moment in time
at 2010
we have 14 states in this country that
have some form of legal marijuana
medicine
14 states that have medical marijuana
law
we have california
this year that is going to vote on the
legalization
of marijuana
so what you've got to do is get out and
vote what you've got to do is tell your
mother tell your father tell your sister
tell your brother tell everybody you
know that this is the moment that you
must legalize marijuana that this is the
moment you get off your ass and you do
what we didn't do
i am honored to be looking at the
generation that is going to legalize
marijuana are you going to
the associate publisher of high times
magazine i thank you very much for
giving me your time
thanks rick rick will be back emceeing
here in a little while