Chris Conrad is an author a court
qualified cannabis expert and publisher
of the West Coast Lea he's been doing
this as long as we have maybe longer
Chris Conrad thank you Vivan and Hello
Seattle hey did I mention how much I
love you guys you know what I love about
it so much is that we're down in
California in
1996 we put proposition 215 on the
ballot and legalize the medical
marijuana in the state and 2 years later
you guys came right up stepped up to the
plate and voted to legalize medical
marijuana here in Washington state so
you're like a little buddy up the hill
there that we just keep an eye out we
say come on and join us when you get the
chance I remember you know the march to
legalization It's a Long March it's not
a straight trip like a lot of people
think a lot of people in California
right now think that the way that you
legalize marijuana is that somewhere
there's a cliff and a cliff is legal and
and once that's illegal and then at some
point you're going to walk and walk and
to the edge of that cliff and you step
off and it's going to be a straight
plunge right down right down right down
and you hit legalization I am here to
tell you that's not the way it works
when you step off a cliff it's bad news
you're going to get hurt the way you get
to legalization is you take the steps
one at a time and you make the progress
forward for five years Jack ha and I
marched up and down the state of
California educating people to put the
California hemp initiative on the ballot
and we were never able to do it and we
were saying you know we got to get a law
we got to get a law but then Along Came
proposition 215 and it wasn't all it was
just medical marijuana and we said well
we'll do it and shoulder toosh shoulder
we took California back and gave it to
the people of California to have that
freedom with Dennis perona we fought we
struggled and then we thought well this
is nice a few people who have medical
need they get in trouble or they get
busted they can go to court and they get
an offense and we said that's not enough
and so we went to the legislature and we
struggled and we went back year after
year for seven years in a row to the
legislature and then we got
sb420 that allows dispensaries to sell
marijuana for patients around the state
of
California and now here we are in the
great year of
2010 and we have proposition 19 on the
ballad in California Proposition 19 that
was the same number that the
legalization initiative had in
1972 we come back 38 years later and we
get the same number like it's a sign
from the universe like it said the first
time maybe you didn't do enough work but
now you've done the work now it's time
for history to change we are the fulcrum
the Pito in California ready to move
forward and it's not a leap into the
void it is a step of modest change but
it's a step that will make the stigma go
away the big stigma that what's so bad
about marijuana well it's illegal
November the 3D in California that may
turn out no longer to be true and then
I'm going to come back here and I'm
going to hear in 2011 that this very
state Washington and the people here
from the Hempfest coales and stood
together to step forward and legalize
marijuana here in Washington State
[Applause]
and so we've marched around the state we
do the million March for marijuana
around the world we take step by step
forward into the future it takes a lot
of stuff and here's something you might
might not want to hear but it's true is
it takes money like Hempfest needs your
money you need to put some money into
hempest to have hempest if you want
California to legalize marijuana so that
you can legalize marijuana up here we
need some money to come down to
California to help Prop 19 money is the
oil of politics I'm not into
oil okay but when it comes time to
lubricate the gears of Justice we C we
can't keep giving it our blood we have
to give it our money we have to give it
our sweat we have to lubricate history
in order for us to move forward and so I
ask you now will you join
me will you join Jack ha will you join
Amsterdam and step into the
future well we're ready for you so come
with us I'm Chris Conrad read about
history as it changes read the West
Coast Leaf thank you for your time and
thank you
Hest Chris
Conrad