uh the White House put out a statement
that there's no medical value for
marijuana but yet uh we know from
studies and from the work of patients at
a time things that you've Unearthed and
do and that's not true we know from El M
who's getting her medication from the
government that they realize that there
is some truth to what we say so how do
we take a bright mind like Obama and the
White House Administration and make them
realize publicly publicly that there is
a medical value to this plan
um what they always Resort back to is
the lack of peer-reviewed studies where
there are literally I've got about
10,000 peer-reviewed studies on my
computer dealing with cannabis but what
they for the most part they're not
dealing with smoke marijuana other than
early studies from the 70s but there are
a few and more coming out now dealing
with smoke or with extracts and one just
came out last week from Germany
basically challenging the whole idea of
what the federal government is doing
because there is documented medical
value I think the only thing that really
makes politicians listen is when their
constituency contacts them directly
phone email more importantly sometimes
postcards and then they start to see or
visiting them that's what they start to
listen to when they realize that their
positions are in Jeopardy if they don't
follow the correct you know Direction
really and I think that that's starting
to happen more and more because I having
spent too much time this summer in
Washington DC I Now understand much more
of how this how the game is played and
if we can all learn how to play the game
better then we're going to have a
magnified impact on changing things
quicker and easier so I think it's up to
the voice of the people to make it
happen