yeah that that was done even 20 years
ago I have water pitchers and things we
did
um uh made with 20 40 55 hemp fiber into
the uh plastic beads that are used as in
these injection molding machines
but um most of it turned out pretty
brittle the hemp CD cases all of mine
are broken apart my hip scale is uh yeah
I think that was electronics and not the
hemp that failed there but you know all
these little
tchotchkes got made from this uh because
actually it makes your beads cheaper the
hemp is cheaper than polyester so they
can mix the two together when they're
making the beads and it acts it actually
is a pretty good film material and Avail
that technology is available right now
my problem with that is that they're
selling that as hip plastic and hemp
plastic is a whole nother thing where
you actually take the hemp and and turn
it in you know plasticize in it itself
and you can do this with him between the
hip fiber the hemp seed oil are these
incredible plastic parts very much like
Bakelite in the end just from hemp alone
and and you add some preference and
things like that you get amazing
fiber things this is going to be our
future because these things are
biodegradable without killing us you
know and uh and and all those things
we'll learn one of these days to use him