there are Mexican fathers poets laurates
that are prying over the fact that
55,000 people have died in Mexico in the
past 6 years 55,000 people have died as
a result of the drug war there that is
as a result of the War on Drugs here
55,000 people is more than the entire
population of the city of Redmond across
Lake Washington from
us there are proud black mothers in this
country who are enraged it is their sons
and their brothers and their fathers
that are getting hauled off to jail and
saddled with criminal convictions while
they watch their white pot smoking
friends go
free there are presidents in Latin
American countries there are prime
ministers in European nations all of
them watching us and all of them will be
looking at their newspapers on November
7th to see what the headlines
read now a headline is a very simple
statement a headline doesn't get into
the details about why somebody voted the
way that they
did the headlines around the world on
November 7th are going to read either
Washington legalizes
marijuana or marijuana legalization
defeated
again how are you going to vote how are
those headlines going to
read I ask you for yourself for the
state of Washington for the entire world
please vote Yes on initiative 502 and
next year this is going to be an even
bigger party thank you so much