so we can fix it say no to the politics
of fear say no to that politics that
tells you we don't dare stand up for
what we deserve and what we can afford
jobs health care public higher education
instead of bailing out the crooks at the
banks who got us into this mess we need
to bail out the students who are living
like indentured servants and we can bail
out and we can bail out the home owners
who are losing our homes by the millions
while the banks continue rolling in
their trillions of dollars that we paid
them to stop the Foreclosure crisis they
haven't stopped it one bit all of this
is why we need change we have the power
we are the ones we've been waiting for
go to my website Jill stein.org join the
team and let's start back on track we
can change this Breaking Point into a
Tipping Point and take back cannabis and
medical marijuana and hemp and the
economy and the peace and the Justice we
deserve it's all in our hands thank you
so much let's make it happen go have
that