hey guys what's going on yeah love him
to wake you guys up this morning welcome
to him fast this is the Super Bowl of
the canvas community this event right
here is it and you guys were here friday
was a great day wasn't it that's right
dude we got to turn into a positive i
saw many people and it was awesome it
was seattle we had a little bit of
weather and no one cared because we are
freedom fighters and we don't care what
we care about is what we smoke and we
care about our freedom at these rallies
and that's what we do as I mentioned my
name is Earth thrasher i'm also scott
gordon and there's so much going on the
community i just love being a part of
this community i'm from oregon and we
just recently legalized in november and
it was freaking awesome and part of it
was because of you watch the tone ians
we're teammates you know we watched you
guys in 2012 legalized and we choked and
then all of a sudden we came back watch
you guys our legislators learn we can't
buy your weed and all of a sudden we
came back we didn't quit and now we're
legalized the only problem I'm seeing
right now is that we're proud of mash 91
and you guys are proud of i-502 we need
to turn that around so hopefully you
guys will come into organ by so far we'd
continue to by washingtonian weed and
keep educating your legislators we had a
great medical program through the years
and we kept teaching these guys and they
saw they knew they understood weed they
understood what it meant so now we're in
our next phase which is equality you
know when we legalized and now it's time
to equalize and part of that you know is
getting a job without pissing you guys
like pissing in a cup just to get a job
just to get a paycheck just to support
your family do whatever you want to do
you know there's a lot of job
out there doing that even in Washington
Colorado and Oregon where we're freaking
legalized that's [ __ ] right there
can't tolerate that y'all speaking any
you guys watch the presidential debate
here recently the Republican debate yo
we got a bunch of legalized states and
it wasn't even mentioned once not one
time that's crap right there there's
going to be busted out some states in
2016 phone for it was invention once the
other was one cool thing though you know
dr. ben Carson everyone's all fired up
about him right now he said one cool
thing he was talking at the end and he
was all but you know what I'm in the
operating room you know I'm operating on
the person you know I'm not operating on
her skin really doesn't mean anything
and it doesn't tell who they are and
he's right about that but you know what
else doesn't tell their piss when they
piss in a cup it doesn't tell who that
person is that's crazy how's it still
bleep we might smoke two weeks ago three
weeks ago last night doesn't tell who he
is that's crap right there back so we
need to change that no you're intense
especially in legalized states and the
insurance companies are pushing that
crap do you have a business please don't
urine test anyone start changing that
start talking to your buddies when
you're at your business meetings find
out who is to tell him to stop that crap
we want jobs too we want to be equal
speaking of jobs i love you know one of
my things to I wear a lot of hats I'm
420 radio I'm Portland normal because
activism is so important you guys need
to be involved in groups keep activism
going but also have a business surveys
designs right down here at 425 please
support the vendors so many vendors so
many bands lost their slots on Friday
there's a lot of money man when you
support them support this event has been
in free
find the donation boxes make up for
Friday take care of us support I'd love
to see some creativity in this industry
I still see a lot of dabs and bombs
which is great dispensaries which is
great let's be creative man we can do
all kinds of stuff I have seen a lot of
creative stuff but let's keep being
created to keep growing this community
you guys can find me at earth pressure
on twitter 420 radio dot org herbage
designs com and as I said keep
supporting these pants you know one of
the sponsors right here carry gold
records has a great Pam today plant at
4pm this whole area right here will be
rocking today for and that's lotus crush
that's just one of many bands that you
guys can be supporting their support
this community best support music and
we've been living we've been spoken in
our basements all these years listen to
this music so keep supporting these guys
thank you so much Vivian McPeak all
y'all have this crew Sharon winching who
runs the vendors we love you guys Rachel
speakers you guys rock all right