20 years old happy birthday viven the
entire multi hundred person crew has
done one of the most amazing jobs in the
world at focusing attention on a
problem
Vivan hey how you doing Vivian is Keen
to say that this is a critical mess and
we've reached a critical mass well we
reach a critical mass here every year in
the hundreds of thousands of people
Beyond coming to the park join a
marijuana law reform organization it
does not matter which one you join just
get involved register to vote donate to
this great organization the Seattle
Hempfest for the next year
2012 will be the busiest year for Marana
law reform and cannabis consumers in
every single one of Our Lives whether
you're 75 or 18 years old
2012 will be the busiest political year
California Oregon Washington State
Colorado will all have legalization
ballots the state of Massachusetts will
have a medical marijuana
initiative if any one of these states
passes a legalization initiative
that will be the [ __ ] in the armor that
will be the rocket ride to the Supreme
Court where a state not activists not
patients not organizations but a state
will be in such conflict with federal
law that the Supreme Court must rule on
whether or not a state can legalize
marijuana and we are on the precipice
55% 55%
of Americans want marijuana
legalized
demographers believe that by
2020 60% of Americans whether you're a
conservative or you're a liberal you
will want marijuana legalized so this is
a fate to complete it's not a matter of
if or how it is a matter of when
marijuana will be legalized that is is
not in
doubt California's proposition 19 last
year only lost by three percentage
points three percentage points a state
like California which is a nation unto
itself with one eight out of eight
Americans living there came within three
percentage points of legalizing
marijuana
we all have a great opportunity on
October October 2nd put this on your
little iPhones and your Android pH
phones right now October 2nd is the 74th
anniversary of this terrible prohibition
on marijuana beginning we have a blessed
opportunity on that Sunday night normal
is calling for all of us to have normal
hot parlor parties on that night not
only to celebrate the destruction of
this stupid prohibition but public
broadcast will start a five-part series
that night on the alcohol prohibition a
Ken burn series on the absurdity of
alcohol prohibition so at your normal
pot parlor party the whole idea is to
watch this great series on how alcohol
prohibition that only lasted a dozen
years what a stupid policy what a fa
failed social experiment it was and here
we are all these years later 74 years
into marijuana prohibition so it's
self-evident freedom is not Mana from
Heaven if you want to be free work for
it thank you