[Music]
[Applause]
w
[Music]
guys
street I'm standing here at Hempfest in
Seattle with Keith stro the founder of
of normal and thank again thank you for
that and
uh what do you think of this event um
it's a it's my favorite event of the
year uh I travel around and do a number
of these kinds of things but there's
nothing on the scale of the Seattle
Hempfest other than the Seattle Hempfest
so uh for those who haven't seen it it
is incredibly empowering and I I think
12 13 years now I've been coming and I
just uh I find it fascinating and I
think people in other parts of the
country are beginning to pick up on that
same phenomena and the Boston Freedom
Fest is coming up in the month and
that's a wonderful thing on the Boston
common with all the history associated
with that um and in the the port
Portland Hima and uh that's about the
middle of next month as well I was there
last year so 12th and 13th of September
12th and 13th of September uh if you're
in the region at all and you identify
with marijuana smokers or at marijuana
smoking for Christ sake come to this
thing uh you will find lots of people
that are like-minded individuals like
you and uh as I say you'll feel
empowered by
[Music]
it this is peace love and understanding
that we're doing here peace love and
understanding save your seed that
doesn't take a miracle to cultivate the
weed can't sell brownies you can't sell
pot can't sell Rice Krispies at Hempfest
why because we know how to to keep this
thing going and that will bring us
down we have an unprecedented amount of
Freedom here no other city in the world
no other rally in America especially I
don't think any in the world is doing
quite what we're doing so so please
understand we do not want to be the NS
[Music]
man we arrested our 20 millionth
American on marijuana
charges are you ready for 420
in the midsummer the state of California
determined that it would be missing 1.4
billion dollar in taxes if we didn't
Legalize It in California probably 10
times that many
nationally we've helped almost 100,000
people in eight states thanks uh get a
medical marijuana permit so that means
they can legally possess use and grow
medical marijuana
medical marijuana is a great step
forward but it's not the end what we
need to do is in adult marijuana
provision restore industrial hip and
help medical marijuana
patience The Man start it all Jack
[Music]
Hiller that will be the future of all
mankind or there won't be a
future
[Applause]
yeah doesn't matter if you're a Democrat
or Republican we're going to legalize
marijuana no matter what happens in 10
years because when 60% of the American
public wants something they're going to
get
it contact your legislators tell them in
marijuana prohibition to tax and
regulate it the more letters they get
like that the sooner the day will
arrive we're going to legalize
[Applause]
marijuana peaceful look at this it
doesn't have what if this was a drink
fest alcohol Fest meth Fest heroin Fest
cocaine Fest there'll be dead people
here there'll be fights there'll be
stabbings but it's pot Fest it's
Hempfest we are are proud We are loud
give it an h h e e f f p p what do we
want I freaking love Hemp Fest Hempfest
is the
[ __ ] hempest is
badass go him Fest
[Music]
September 12th and 13th Portland Kelly
Point Park yay please come everybody's
welcome
[Music]