I'm a science nut and I look at the
endoc canabo system the marijuana like
compounds that we make and I look at how
they've participated in evolution to the
point that we have humanity and we have
us standing here and sitting here
talking about it and what that direction
means is and shows is that we have to
increase our canabo activity that's the
way Nature has occurred up to now and
now we have the ability to self-reflect
see how we got here and know where we
can go and that's why it's totally
Unstoppable it's just a matter of time
because all we're doing is the Natural
Evolution of Life on this planet and the
critical role that this plant has in
being able to tweak our endocan avonoid
system and to create a world of people
who are more High rather than having it
run by people who are less High yeah