and guys I want to reach out to all of
you here today on this gorgeous day in
this gorgeous Park and ask you to
remember all of the eyes of the nation
are on us right now we have in front of
us guys a chance to continue the work
that you did 15 years ago when you
brought one of the nation's first
medical marijuana bills to this country
here in here in the state of Washington
and because of work that you have done
every every member of the Seattle
delegation to Olympia like senator
kwells who just spoke to you is in favor
of legalization over a year ago they
went on the record and now every single
elected official because of your work
because of you picking up the phone
because of you getting active every
elected official in City Seattle City
Hall is in favor of
legalization and now because of the work
of people like you volunteers activists
who went out and hit the streets and got
hundreds of thousands of signatures last
year year in less than 3 months people
we get to vote for the first time any
state in this nation to legalize
marijuana for adult recreational use
it's i502 and it must pass hey guys as
Vivian said my office handles lots of
legal matters for this great City and
for the for its citizens one of those is
that I'm the chief uh criminal
prosecutor and that means that I'm
responsible for Public Safety that means
I'm supposed to hold accountable people
who would endanger the well-being of
others but when adults use marijuana in
a responsible fashion it's just wrong to
label them criminals it's just wrong
that's why that's why 3 years ago in my
campaign I promised to never file
another marijuana possession charge
again and I have kept that promise and
as long as I'm your City attorney I will
I will keep that
promise but guys don't take this for
granted this beautiful Park this great
Festival that we're having remember you
can still be arrested in Seattle for
possession just because I won't charge
you you can still be arrested and once
you go beyond Seattle it's a completely
different
story and so don't take this for granted
we need to come together we need to
recognize there is one opportunity on
the November ballot and that is to vote
Yes on 502 and send a clear message a
clear message message along with
Colorado along with Oregon and tell the
federal government that prohibition is
wrong it's time for it to come to an end
that's what we need to come together
on you know hempest has been home here
for 21 years and medical marijuana is
something that the city of Seattle has
tried to make available for all of for
all of its its
patients but other cities are are
cracking down on dispensaries they're
cracking down on patients
and remember I'm just one prosecutor and
just one city and we need to make sure
that we change the law it's not enough
to elect a good prosecutor you need to
change the law and that's what we're
here to talk about with
502 we need a complete solution to
Prohibition it's written supported and
passed by the people and it's not just
for people here in Seattle it's for
wachi and Spokan and chahalis Auburn and
Kent and it's a challenge to the root
problem of federal
prohibition patients and recreational
users alike when 502 is pass will have
real arrest protection real arrest
protection that's what 502 will do right
now and it will send that message to
Washington DC that prohibition is
over all right I'm going to wrap it up
now guys but remember this November we
have a chance to redirect law
enforcement priorities to make sure that
we reclaim Industrial Hemp for the state
of Washington
let's make sure that we have a yes on
502 and send a message along with
Colorado and Oregon thank you everyone
thank Seattle you