I think that marijuana is the greatest
gift from our mother earth God the
Creator Gaia the greatest gift that our
planet has given us that hip can restore
all of our energy needs or at least a
large percentage of them you can provide
a huge resourcing in terms of food and
in fiber the only reason we have
marijuana prohibition is because it
produces more fuel fiber food and
medicine than any other plan lit created
a misinformation campaign to call it
marijuana 75 years ago so you know I'm
glad I 502 past but it's really just
partial decriminalization it's not legal
for you to have a single marijuana plant
but this is the most productive plant
known to man not only is it the most
productive plant it produces more fuel
over 300 gallons of oil per acre more
food over 6 tons of protein after breast
oil out of it and more fiber 35 to 40
tons of fiber per acre while at the same
time restoring the soil with the Leafs
and other processes it draws up some
soil nutrients and makes it available in
the next crop rotation you know until
you can grow your own cannabis the law
isn't good enough so I urge you to
register to vote get involved in the
political process at takeover you know
back to the 60s amp is saying Timothy
Leary popularized it with tune in turn
on tune in to drop out we need to turn
on tune in and take over this political
system needs to change you know it's
really the people who brought us
marijuana prohibition where the
petrochemical pharmaceutical military it
does feel transnational corporate elite
faster
[ __ ] at their one who gave us this
and when we can restore him to its
rightful place in our economy and we
grow him without regard to its THC
content because low THC hemp is really
[ __ ] it's all about not growing the
seed because we need the seed to replace
petrochemicals so get involved in the
political process lobby for him talk to
your political you know representatives
and run for office yourself take over
the process that's what we have to do so
I heard you to do that if you don't want
to run yourself supporting somebody who
does but it's really about restoring
power and control to the people right
now all the money's flowing to these
petrochemical Giants and when we take
over it could grow hemp for fuel again
without regard to its THC content but
according to the types of him that are
most productive that means instead of
the money go into these Saudi of kings
and Swiss bank accounts it'll go to our
farmers and into our pockets that will
change the whole economic paradigm
they're keeping us down as long as they
keep yep down so I urge you to work hard
change the system don't accept this I
502 is in marijuana needs to be cheap
and plentiful marijuana isn't bad for
you it's really good for us you know
guys the tanks right gasps couldn't stop
us from smokey grass and we're going to
keep at it and we need to grow to kick
the hip dryers you just get active
thanks for being involved out here and
help restore him goodbye come on give it
up to be spoken