i've been to many events
with thousands of people
and i have never seen such a community
in my life
and i thank you for that
i thank you for that i'm gonna pass it
down so you just
you don't get the whole bag i see you're
thinking something about what's in this
bag and i know what's on your mind
washington state and colorado have done
amazing things and it's not washington
state for instance it is the people of
washington state it is the people of
colorado who have moved forward with
legalization of marijuana in these two
states so i applaud the people for
coming out coming forward making their
voices heard and being organized
in making it happen you see because
that's key
you have to be organized if you want to
get something done
you have to reach out to your
legislators and your politicians and you
have to make them do what needs to be
done and in order to do that you have to
be organized
i don't have much more to say
but two things
number one we all come here from many
different perspectives and for many
different reasons
for ending the prohibition of marijuana
we all have one goal in mind that is to
remove marijuana from the scheduling
system in its entirety not down one or
two levels but completely out of the
scheduling system
we all come here for that we all need to
come together work together make that
happen and i know we can do it we've
done it in washington we've done it in
colorado
and what i ask of you as i close
is to help me take this steamroller
because that's what it is
completely across the country
all the way to my hometown of baltimore
maryland are you with me on that
and i will be here until it's done
if it takes me to the age of 95
but i don't think that will happen
thank you folks
thanks for being here i appreciate you
each and every one of you thank you
thank you so much thank you major neil
franklin from law enforcement against
prohibition