more people that get to use the medicine
the more people will not only be healing
the physical ailments but the mental
ailments that come from not having
enough in that annoyed activity you just
cause yours just genetically a little
weak on it or you're not eating the
right foods or you're not using cannabis
so what I think is that the more and
more people use it the less they're
going to be able to cling the federal
government is not going to go down easy
and they're going to do everything they
can and every step of the way to
maintain some element of control however
we all know that the truth and reality
is on our side so that it will be a
progressive weakening of the stupidity
that they continuously enforce as we
build the strength of knowledge and
truth and I can tell you one of the
robots we're going down now with
cannabis science has to do with HIV and
without going into details we haven't
released things I'm not allowed to say
things that are not properly press
release but in general the reality is
that is somewhere between 35 and 50
million people in the world today with
HIV and that that number is so dramatic
that is going to cause not only the
collapse of communities but of countries
and potentially the African continent on
in terms of economy the United States
does not want that to happen you cannot
produce enough antiretroviral drugs for
50 million people it's not possible
because of the complexity but we can
make cannabis products to satisfy that
size of a population need and you have
50 million people learning the truth in
that sense it's it's irrevocable the
government's position will collapse over
time and we're doing
we can to make that happen sooner than
later