I think we're on the verge of some very
exciting
changes
and people's awareness is growing
steadily in
order uh to have hemp agriculture in the
United States we've been in working on a
number of projects so that we can hit
the ground running when we have hemp
agriculture in the United States we're
working on developing processes and
products so that we are ready to have
hemp agriculture in the United States
we're working with materials that were
grown in Canada and we're using these to
develop these processes because we do
not want to hold our breath waiting for
somebody to change a
law you can't bet on an uncertainty but
there are certain parts of it that are
quite certain I can get hemp fiber
organically grown in Canada I can get
hemp herds by the
bail we can TR we can transport them
without
restriction to our research centers here
in the United
States these are all materials that are
certified noncontroversial
I've been talking with a number of
agricultural research stations who are
very interested
in working with the hemp pressing oil
doing the same processes and analyses to
analyze hemp seed oil to compare them
with the canola oil and the sunflower
oil and the soybean oil that are being
used to make biodiesel turns out that
hemp seed oil with all those double
Bonds in it stays liquid at lower
temperatures one of the problems of
biodiesel is that it tends to gel in
cooler weather
so hemp seed oil biodiesel is more
resistant to jelling in cold
weather with all those all those uh efas
all those polyunsaturated fats they stay
liquid even at freezer temperatures take
a bottle of hemp seed oil when you get
it at the store don't put it in the
refrigerator put it in the freezer and
watch it still stays pourable what other
oil would do that this is
fantastic we're looking at how how do we
prepare for hemp agriculture on a scale
that it can truly make a
difference a real
farmer may not take a crop seriously if
he cannot grow 500 Acres of it so what
do we need in order to be ready for a
500 acre crop of hemp seed making the
assumption that you get a hundredfold
increase with each crop the year before
we need to have a 5 acre seed crop
dedicated to producing the seed for our
500 acre crop the year before that you
need 5 hunds of an acre which is roughly
20 foot by 20
foot and the year before that you need
100th of that which is 2T by
2T that's one plant so it means that we
are four years away from selecting one
plant that meets our needs to having
enough seed to where you can have a 500
acre
crop we need to move forward in ways
where we
build on our foundations and we are
prepared for the the successes my
grandmother always said success is what
happens when preparation meets an
opportunity and so I've spent much of my
life
preparing for various successes that
have shown their face and this is yet
another one