en zo Another Question we have Here is
for Ellie muziek
conventional treatments so I Lost One I
Was A Guess the Law For 12 Years Where
in about when my children Would Be
taking away from Me When I Would Be
arrested working became in Possible in
the 80
because even Floor that backwards It
seem Sometimes with very very support
have Medical Mary wanna en understood My
dilemma and so I got an a Turning from
There Who representime pro bono all the
whis I Would definity Have Been In jail
And I Had A Doctor Who under Stood that
his hippocratical was More important And
The Father takes of Miracle Mary wanna
so he this
have a Judge was Running for election at
the time when so understood that I have
Need A created My hillness not a [ __ ]
that gots work was musevision For Me So
Mary wanna be came Medicine Legally As I
Was A quit it orchest of position and
called Division but Sent stand Because
We have That a
quattroverman into parting with Their
Precious hand Which
one of the doctor presglas
12 Years one hour and I Lot of You There
The Help me That's What I Talk to become
the first Woman to get Legal Mary wanna
from the program that is Today provining
it to 8 People In The enter country And
The One Thing That in realized
ways afterplay speaking awaken People up
to watch Going On