you know five years ago when I was
running for mayor somebody asked me by
position on marijuana legalization and
my answer then was if every politician
that ever smoked marijuana voted to
legalize it to be legal in an instant
funny line right so I didn't think it
was a big deal when I ran for office
five years to come to come out for
legalization the people of Seattle and
voted to make it the lowest enforcement
priority the state had medical marijuana
but I've later discovered it was kind of
a big deal lots of elected official lots
of politicians weren't willing to do it
yet there were a couple before when
Roger good manners in the Statehouse
there's a real leader and there were
others but there weren't that many look
at where it is five years later right
all kids today you were to explain why
you were pouring today I think if you're
a politician not just in the state of
Washington but anywhere in the country
you're going to have to explain why are
you against it that's where this is
going and it's amazing how quickly these
things to move and they move because
people organized because people make a
difference it doesn't happen because the
political leaders trust me most
politicians will only do with the
public's willing to say they want them
to do so you all made that happen but
while I got you here you know we're
winning this issue there's another green
issue we need to win and that's the
fight against global warming that's up
my board content so I'm gonna keep
helping you all with pot legalization
around the country but accessible was I
love you all to help me and making sure
that we make this planet right for our
children and [ __ ] over oil by cold folds
roads and build a better future together
thank you