alright so I take a few you people who
spoke to me before alright well I'm glad
to hear that because I would have talked
about the past the present and the
future and get an idea what I'm thinking
from Sonny's going around for a long
time I first want to start off by
mentioning my dear friends Kevin black
and and Peter McWilliams both of whom
are friends of personal friends of mine
and the stage is honoring them so i say
honor them with high honor peter
mcwilliams and kevin black two wonderful
activist so as far as the past is
concerned I spent a lot of time in court
working to keep people out of prison
almost every day I'm in court working on
that and so I am a very good sense I've
been doing this for 20 years plus a fee
and expert witness and we're seeing a
change in the way the cases are working
and we're seeing a change in the
attitude around the country but we're
also seeing the fact that we're getting
rolled back at different parts of the
world some of what's going on here in
Washington for example it's not exactly
what people envisioned when we pass
i-502 here are a few years ago to
legalize cannabis it's like God but it
wasn't supposed to affect medical
marijuana yet look at the problems is
causing in California we have the
legislature it's got a bill that claims
to be a marijuana reform bill but what
they're going to do is take away legal
defenses from pot growers who are not
licensed by the state though we've had
ever since 2003 and so that's as their
idea of reform is to make it so that
some people will get licenses but other
people lose their legal defense and so
the other thing that we're seeing is
that this whole idea of testing people's
urine as a part of a condition for
getting a job or to have a license these
issues are not going away we call it the
can of bigotry it's like the Jim Crow of
cannabis is what we're setting upon us
right now and so some of these things
that we're seeing as we see Barry former
thinking we also are concerned about
where things are going so when we look
at the past one of the things it's a big
fear
me as we see this big change that's
happening now is that the history of the
struggle to get us to this moment can
very well be lost and we can't afford to
let that happen we've got people who've
been sitting in prison for 20 years
we've got people who've been working as
activist for decades we've got a history
of people who worked underground people
who kept the gene pool alive and so
forth through all these decades and we
need to protect an honor that I'm
working with a group that's called the
420 archive and we're trying to approach
this from three different directions the
first is to get the archives of people
who've been contributors to the field of
Canada's reform and preserves out the
second is to create collections and to
coordinate collections of museum
exhibits of material that goes before
cannabis was ever prohibited and up
through the history are the prohibition
and to create that is something that we
can leave for future generations and the
third thing is it can oral our oral
histories of people who can using
cannabis underground and going
underground and working in the cannabis
industry underground that have never
been free to tell their stories before
so those stories of the people who
risked many years in prison to make sure
that people had some nice herb to smoke
it's not lost in history so I hope
you'll join us in looking at the 420
archive and make sure that histories
preserve the next thing is about to now
and the now is is that as cannabis moves
out of us outlaws status we have a big
fear that what's going to happen is big
corporations when they come in and
they're going to try to take over
control of the work they are friends and
our neighbors in and the people who've
been the growers and so forth for so
long have been working for enough patent
the seat lines and stuff like that so
I'm working with a group called the open
cannabis project and our plan is to try
to get a final way of explaining what
the different seed lines are in turn to
the genetics and their effects and so
forth but also to preserve them and
create the public domain directors that
these already exist so that Monsanto and
corporations like that can't come
and patent those seeds and make you
always have to pay for it we want to
make sure that you'll always be able to
grow your og cush and your blueberry not
have to pay some corporation who comes
in and buys that trademark away so the
name of that group is called you're
hoping cannabis project it's got three
parts to protect access to the seed line
to exist now to protect the integrity so
when people tell you that this is a blue
dream that you know it's really a blue
dream and not oh gee cush both of which
is good i'm not knocking either one but
you want to know what you're getting
right and the third thing is to get the
genome map so look we will know for sure
from here on out okay and so then the
next thing i want to say is is that
where we're heading toward in the future
has things have shifted really
dramatically and now we have dr. Sanjay
Gupta changing his position on marijuana
which is like the whole massive shift
which was much last week when the New
York Times came out in favor of taking
marijuana out of the federal controlled
substance act and this is really hugely
important this is something we've been
saying for a long time and now finally
we've got the New York Times doing it to
say it so I predicting the future of
canvases that we are going to see more
in greater hempfest in the future
morning Draenor free of the future of
protection of all you've got an
expansion of our rights and wait wait
you want to join to the more important
things is that we need more people
smoking herb and more people to
understand it that's why written a book
which has caused the newbies guide to
canvas in the industry going to be out
this year and so if you know people who
should be smoking weed where who should
be in the weed business that you want to
make sure they get it right and don't
screw themselves through each other and
they understand what's going on Tommy's
get a copy that book for Christmas
alright and so then the last thing I
wanted to say is that
save ifs get in your pockets and raise
some money for this thing it doesn't pay
for itself legalization doesn't pay for
itself we need you guys to contribute
okay it's great that you're here today
but Steve everybody else is going to
tell you make sure that there is a
hamfest next year by contributing when
the buckets come around and go wait for
the buckets by the stuff the memo that
shows and stuff like that get the saints
are going to hempfest boy because
without hempfest i 502 and not a past in
Washington we wouldn't have legalization
today and we are in the end we'll all be
much worse off so please join us now one
last cheer give me eight hep hep hep hep
hep hep all right I'll see you guys on
believe online.com