I just want to thank everyone who stuck
around for our presentation here it
means a lot to come out all the way from
Washington DC and speak to all the
hipsters here everybody here as a
hamster who came to seattle hempfest
this year you don't have to be working
twenty-four/seven in the hemp industry
to be a hemisphere you can just you can
become a member of vote hemp and the hip
industry association as a supporter you
don't have to be in the industry so we
and that's one of the ways the distri
has grown is through grassroots support
and just I want to remind every once
again it's been sent a couple times but
we I really think we are the most
powerful movement in America right now
we don't act like it we have to start
acting like it and demanding change at
any politician who blows you off when it
comes to cannabis reform you just have
to tell them I'm not going away buddy
you're going to go away if you don't act
on this issue so anyway let's keep
fighting together and the stay united
and and thanks again for having me here
where to wisdom from Adam never ever
ever go for someone who considers you
criminal for a non-violent offense