ladies and gentlemen Mr Rick
Steves thank you very
much and it feels good to come out of
the closet doesn't it isn't it a strange
sort of concept that we have to come out
of the concept about something that just
feels like a very basic civil liberty uh
you know you've heard all of the um
talking points and so on from the the
main stage and so on and I thought this
is for the the eager students here at
hemp posium so I'm just going to give
you a little background on uh my
experience in speaking out on this issue
in public not at Hempfest it's easy to
talk about it here but it's tougher to
talk about it you know at your parent
teacher Association meetings or with
your friends down the street or or or at
the supermarket or something like this
so I want to talk about that I've also
had some interesting um challenge to try
to understand the other side better
respect the other side understand what
motivates them because you know I think
it's good citizenship all around and
it's just awareness raising and and life
in people sharing other people's
challenges and how they've succeeded in
what they've learned where we can move
forward on this so that's what I want to
talk about uh a little while ago I had
dinner with uh Gil kow's sort of lead
narcotics guy in Seattle wonderful man
beautiful guy I just him and I kind of
clicked and I didn't realize but Carol
lowski had sent him out to listen to me
give my talks around the Pua Sound area
just to see what hempest kind of people
were doing you know and and uh I sat
down with him and we had a great dinner
he disagreed with everything I said
except my contention that you can make a
very good case that the mature adult
Usef marijuana is a civil liberty but he
said you've got to cover the other bases
Driving Access to kids addiction abuse
education all this kind of stuff so it's
a very interesting um it's a very
interesting sort of challenge that we
have here he asked me after that dinner
he said why he said you're some you know
well-off white guy in the severage you
could smoke pot no problem at all you
can invite your friends over and have a
great party no problem why are you in
this fight and I thought about it and
he's right uh you know most of us can
smoke with discretion and be fine uh but
there really is a matter of principle
about this and uh I thought about it and
I thought I am really into travel you
know I'm a travel writer I've spent a
third of my adult life just traveling I
just love going places and to me
high is a place and I really treasure
that and when I want to go there I want
to go there I I don't need my government
to give me a passport for that place now
there are cases when our government can
tell us we can't go there for various
reasons and we got to live with it you
know you can argue about Cuba but you
can't go there all right there's reasons
um when it comes to high I just don't
think there's a good reason I I mean
they've got wrong reasons they've got
reasons based on fear and lies and
what's going to get them elected but
there's no real honest reason why we
cannot go
there I have thought about this a lot
and you know basically a lot of us just
like to smoke pot uh most of my friends
most of my business associates uh you
know if you locked up everybody in our
community that likes to smoke pot
recreationally it would be a major blow
to our communities to our businesses and
so on and it's just sort of my theme
that the mature adult recreational
consumption of marijuana is a Liberty I
don't like to mince around I don't like
to dance around it I just like to say
that really clearly I mean of course
medical marijuana is a very serious
thing my passion is this civil liberties
thing that's why I'm working closely
with the ACLU that's been my theme as a
board member with normal for the last uh
10 years now again our challenge is how
do we protect this civil liberty and at
the same time deal with the downside of
pot marijuana is a drug you can have all
sorts of ideals you know initiative
505's got great great ideals respect
their idealism but I live in a reality
out there I live in a reality where
800,000 Americans were arrested last
year they weren't rich white guys they
were poor people and people of color
they're people for the rest of their
lives they're going to have a a cross to
bear they're going to be at a further
disadvantage and that's just flat out
wrong and the irony is people who make
that law are afraid of them and because
of that law they've got more to be
afraid of we've reached a point in our
society where if we lock up any more
people it's going to get more dangerous
you know what I mean you take
non-violent people who got in trouble
for some experimental drug use putting
them into prison then they come out
they've been to finishing school and
they can't get a job they're going to
become part of that criminal system we
need to take ideas like this and mess up
otherwise you know uh polite dinners and
uh challenge people to say where are you
getting your information how do you
really know that there's so many
exciting things and I've been at this
for 10 years and I've learned these
exciting points that you can just inject
into conversations if you distill it
down to a bumper sticker it's going to
be hard on drugs or soft on drugs and
we're going to lose we've got to get
beyond that we've got to get enough of
an attention span so we can educate
people about this you know you can't do
it on public on Commercial television
very well we do it on on public
television I won't do a pledge drive
right now but I just spent an hour at
kcts with the weekly with a wonderful
panel of people that are co-sponsoring
these inititive
and we really got some great information
out there but it is a trick to get that
information out we produced a half hour
video with the ACLU you might have seen
it you can see it on online marijuana
time for a discussion I just love that
thing because it raises awareness I was
so proud to be a part of
that we wrote that very carefully with
all the legalistic sensitivity so that
we could buy time to put it on Cairo or
KO or King you know we paid them money
to produce it in their Studios and I
mean it's just like you know a th Master
if you pay the money you can can put it
on TV but they wouldn't let us air that
show except once after Girls Gone Wild
at about 2: a.m. you know you could put
it on and uh but it's just like evil
information because it challenges this
status quo with a thoughtful reasonable
harm reduction app Point uh approach to
marijuana drug policy now so getting
back to this how are we going to make it
clear that this is a civil liberty which
my friend on the other side said is a
very strong argument but you got to deal
with the political reality marijuana is
is a drug we're not promoting a use of a
drug we're promoting the right to use it
if you want to I've never promoted
marijuana I'm really careful about that
I promote the use of it as a civil
liberty I think people understandably
need to hear us say that drugs can be
abused it to acknowledge it is a problem
in our society there is an educational
component of this the drinking and
smoking and then driving while
intoxicated is not an issue that we can
wish away the idealists in 505 camp you
know again I wish it was I wish we could
sell the 505 initiative but I want to I
want to put out an initiative that can
be embraced and everywhere you talk
outside of Hempfest parents in the
suburbs don't want their kid hit by
somebody who's high on something that's
not going to go away and we need to deal
with that and we don't have enough
scientific evidence now to deal with it
properly we need to get something where
we can have some funds and a drug that
can be tested by human beings I just
spent a day up at a pharmaceutical
convention up in past effort there with
a bunch of doctors and Pharmacists and
scientists and professors all day long
the topic was the pharmaceutical nature
of marijuana and it was fascinating to
me these are like 300 very highly
trained uh Medical Specialists they
could not the only evidence they were
using was evidence of the effect of
marijuana on rats and hamsters because
it was illegal and they couldn't use
evidence of uh marijuana on people they
couldn't acknowledge even that people
would use it you see I mean there's that
kind of a disconnect right now between
science and acceptable science and the
reality and I just said you know you
don't need to get this hamster High you
know just go across the street and talk
to somebody and ask them what it's like
I mean it's that simple but they
couldn't do it so we have that
challenge um so you got this drinking
and driving concern you got the uh the
whole fear of children and getting their
uh hands on drugs and uh this has got to
be addressed and it's got to be
addressed smartly and that's an issue
that is near and dear to any parents
Hearts I often wonder why our generation
didn't just grow into power and
marijuana would become regulated and
taxed and and like alcohol and so on but
it didn't happen why because we became
we became parents we worry about our
kids and then we are victimized by a lot
of government proper uh sponsored weer
Madness kind of propaganda that twists
the truth and they tell us it's 20 times
as strong as it was when we were kids or
whatever and this kind of stuff and we
buy it so I want to kind of talk a
little bit about this sort of uh
information this angle on the issue and
I want to give you um just sort of my
take on it as a traveler travel
writer I bring a European sort of
sensibility I think to the the whole
discussion and as I mentioned I spend a
lot of time in Europe that's my beat I
write guide books about Europe and make
this TV show on public television and so
on and uh it's so interesting to me how
America brags about how we are the land
of the pursuit of happiness and you know
grab live life with gusto and everything
like that and when you travel a lot you
come home and there's a sort of a
culture shock in reverse and you realize
we are really quite an uptight Society
in a lot of ways compared to Europeans
uh uh you know uh I've I've taken groups
to spas in Germany where everybody just
kind of gets naked and relaxes and my
people won't even go in I mean I just
can't believe it they're just so afraid
of that when I produce my TV show if it
has any any nudity on it it won't be
aired in the more conservative parts of
our country my show which you've
probably seen on Channel 9 actually has
to be aired after 10:00 in parts of our
country because we show 500y old marble
penises and you know 800 year old canvas
nudes uh breasts you know and uh we have
a law that that terrorizes stations into
shielding people's eyes from this kind
of end of uh of of our world and uh when
you travel you realize there are
different ways to address these sort of
edgy issues but here in the United
States I think we are sort of fearful
and driven into sort of a compliance
with what we think is the norm and I
don't think it really is so we have
these these sort of uptight areas and
and for me the whole thing about
marijuana was just one lie too many one
bit of uptightness too many and of
course when I go to your for my friends
over there a joint is about as exciting
as a can of beer uh it's just uh you
know it's very very clear that we've got
this prohibition on marijuana that is uh
something that is very costly to our
society and when you go to other
societies they care about drug abuse and
Drug rated problems just as much as we
do but they approach it in a much more
Progressive and pragmatic way um so I
speak out it uh you know from that
perspective um when I uh part of my work
as a travelers to get people out of
their comfort zones I think this is a
fundamental thing about travel is you
you you hang out with people who find
different tooths to be self-evident in
god-given you look at something that
used to be scary and then you get to
know the person and it's not scary a
whirling dervish I mean looks kind of
freaky to a lot of Americans but if you
talk to the guy and you find out what
he's thinking when he's whirling around
it becomes a beautiful thing it becomes
a very beautiful thing you know F A lot
of people are all uptight about F gr
because you have to force speed the
geese well you can go to a goose Farm in
France and learn a little bit about the
situation and it becomes quite a bit
different uh I have so much fun in my TV
show of trying to expose people to
things we went to Iran very frightening
place I was afraid before I went to Iran
got there and I realized uh they're just
as afraid of us as we are of them and if
we can just meet each other all of a
sudden it becomes much uh sort of more
potential to get together I love I've
just got something in my nature to try
to get people out of their comfort zones
in a constructive way I remember when my
boy was about 3 years old when we were
having you know saying thank you for
table Grace and invite Grandma and
Grandpa over I teach my son at the end
of the prayer to go Allah Allah Allah
and it just to freak out my dad you know
uh and
uh we can get people out of their
comfort zones when we travel and I think
it's a good thing to get people out of
their comfort zones here too I mean to
me Hempfest for a lot of people is uh
out of their comfort zone wouldn't it be
great if a lot of people who don't know
anything about this issue could come
here and just feel this mellow Vibe and
see the police and the mayor of Seattle
yesterday on stage and and see this kind
of commment to uh you know just fun and
civil liberties and uh and compassionate
compassionate medical use and pragmatic
harm reduction so it's a fun challenge
for all of us here um and uh when it
comes to the whole marijuana thing when
you go to Europe it's hard to paint a
broad stroke here because it's easy to
say Europe's this way but the fact is
there's uh 20 different countries and
they all have different rules on this
sort of thing some of them are more
regressive than we are most of them are
much more Progressive than we are
generally in Europe they have drug
policies motivated by pragmatic harm
reduction for eight years of the
administration before Obama any
proposition about drug policy that was
submitted to our government if it had
the word harm reduction in it it was
rejected out of hand that was code for
legalization they would not consider
anything that was not incarceration
based rather than pragmatic harm
reduction based well in Europe they
really are concerned about drug abuse uh
you know they lose a lot of people to
heroin over to us so do we how are you
going to solve that we do it by lock
people up we do it with misinformation
and fear they do it with pragmatic harm
reduction in Europe they believe if you
take crime out of the equation if you
take the money and the violence out of
the equation you can treat drug abuse as
a health problem and an education
challenge that is a beautiful
thing it's really fun to see the
European approach to this um and Europe
has a concern about hard drugs and they
put marijuana in with alcohol and uh and
uh tobacco as a a drug that can be um
not healthy for you and so on but it's
not going to be treated like hard drugs
and uh I think with that approach um you
can look back and see why did marijuana
end up where it ended up it's a
fascinating story uh I was hanging out
with Bud Eagle Crow remember him he was
the guy who deputized Elvis Presley to
be the drug marshal in the United States
back back in Nixon's Rule and when when
Nixon decided to uh well Nixon was just
pissed off about all the hippies who are
standing against his Vietnam policies I
guess and he thought well the main drug
of all those hippies those pnck is
marijuana I'm going to put their drug in
with LSD and uh heroin or whatever and
from that day on I think marijuana has
been tossed in out of where it should be
in with hard more addictive more
destructive drugs and not with alcohol
where I believe it should
be when we look at European European
treatment of marijuana you find you look
at their website in the EU website
there's there's no um there there's no
like um uh well where you find it is
problematic cannabis use if you search
and search and search for marijuana
there is problematic cannabis use I
think in Germany they no in France they
had a a belief that young men would
smoke marijuana so they would be more
comfortable uh courting women and uh
they actually had flirting con
consultations to help guys be more
comfortable with girls without having to
smoke pot there's you know it seems kind
of wacky but what the point is they're
thinking out of the box in order to help
people not uh get into drugs when they
don't need to get into drugs rather than
criminalizing it um when you think about
how Europe handles its soft drug or just
any drug abuse problems it is always it
just seems to me it's always more
pragmatic than we do for instance
alcohol when I'm in uh Scandinavia in
May and June I'm always impressed by how
many wild drunk teenagers are roaming
around town in the back of decorated
trucks pickup trucks and and flatbed
trucks and then I ask my friends what's
going on it's graduation time and all
these kids kids are just getting really
drunk and their parents are hosting the
kers and the deal is the parents will
rent a car a truck with a driver the
parents will get together and have a
keger in each house or apartment or
whatever and the kids will go from house
to house uh being hosted by their
parents and just get really blitzed and
uh the parents know that nobody's going
to be drinking and driving now parents
don't want their kids to drink and and
drive uh you know in America we parents
tell our kids promise me you won't drink
on graduation and never get in a car
with somebody else is driving well
people kids promise that but in very B
in the United States because we have
this just say no approach without the
pragmatism and in the reality kids lie
kids get in cars where people have been
drinking and on graduation every year
kids die in Scandinavia the parents are
more pragmatic kids don't have to lie
nobody drives and drinks kids have a
great time everybody's just wasted the
next day but uh it's a it's a it's a
Scandinavian pragmatic approach to a
drug abuse problem that'd be a very
tough sell here in the United States but
from a Scandinavian point of view that
is smart drug policy you know don't do
the just say no thing hire a driver in a
truck and host the keger now when you
think about that just for a little
something like alcohol similar uh
pragmatism is in other soft drugs and in
hard drugs when you go around Europe uh
you'll find they have a very very
pragmatic approach to hard drug abuse
last year in the un States 18,000
Americans died of heroin overdoses in
Europe 10,000 died it's a major problem
on both sides of the Atlantic here in
the United States we lock up a lot of
hard drug users in Europe uh they don't
lock them up they they treat them as
people who have medical problems they
need to get their lives back on track if
you I was just in Switzerland and when
you want to go to a public restroom I
went to a Starbucks went downstairs to
to go to the bathroom blue lights blue
lights in the Starbucks toilet and then
I realized ah yes blue lights I cannot
see my veins things see I couldn't shoot
up if I wanted to really frustrating and
uh um and then I realized that's a very
very European style pragmatic approach
to a persistent problem you got all
these junkies around here they're always
looking for a private place to shoot up
and you don't want them doing it in your
in your bathroom I was just in Estonia
in a poor part of town in talin where
the Russian Community is that's the
underclass in Estonia and I went to the
gas station into the toilet blue light
same thing they don't want the Russian
drug population shooting up in their
bathrooms okay back to Switzerland all
right they can't shoot up there you go
across the street and you see a machine
bolted to a metal railing used to sell
cigarettes now the machine sells
government subsidized syringes all right
it cost like a dollar for two syringes
they're just generic syringes
distributed by the government that's a
tough sale in the United States but in
Switzerland you're crazy to pass needles
around nobody shares needles you get
them for almost free on the street
corner I didn't realize it but now I've
seen that and everywhere you look you
see former uh cigarette dispensers
selling syringes that's the society
motivated not by incarcerating people
and and sort of moralistic just say no
stuff but pragmatic European style harm
reduction down the street there's a ugly
little gathering of wasted people it's a
cafe fix it's a heroin maintenance
center it looks ugly but it's a
beautiful thing these are people in
tough Straits because of heroin
addiction and they've got a safe place
to get counseling to get uh their their
their uh Habit uh topped up and a place
to uh get their lives back on track and
get back in the job Force it's amazing
I've taken tourists around Europe for
years and a lot of naive Americans say
there's so many drug addicts over here
these Europeans are so liberal and look
what happens well the fact is their drug
addicts are alive and not in jail
they're out on the streets they're in
Cafe fixes heroin maintenance clinics
getting their needles so they don't have
to swap them on the down the alley and
so on it's quite inspiring when I look
at how Europe handles these drug issues
it's not an easy thing drug drug abuse
is a serious problem but we can do
better here in the United States and to
me that's very exciting and a very good
starting point is what we're doing right
here at Hempfest raising awareness of
the fact that marijuana should not be
illegal so when we think
about when we think about marijuana
policy in Europe Holland comes to mind
the Netherlands you know they haven't
arrested a pot smoker there for 25 years
and um you know I've got a guide book to
Amsterdam so I have to do a lot of
research there in the coffee shops and
it is the coolest scene you know I mean
you got Travelers in there checking
their email and they're just one big
cloud of smoke and uh you got older
people that don't really like the the
youthful kind of vibe so they just come
in and get their pot to go they'll Park
their bike come in get what they like
head out head on out uh you got
different sort of personalities of
different coffee shops I've got an older
readership so I get a little more mellow
and laidback kind of places that my
readership would be more comfortable in
and when you go to these coffee shops
you understand the complicated reality
of
marijuana comce post legalization now in
the Netherlands it's not really legal
because you cannot legalize marijuana
without finding yourself in a trade war
with the United States of America I've
Got Friends in Denmark youve probably
heard in Copenhagen of Christiania where
they've got the marijuana and stuff and
uh they tell me I'm up there you know
and there's lots of marijuana flowing
around everything and they say uh be
careful when you leave with this
marijuana because in the in in Denmark
we have to arrest a couple of pot
smokers every year in order to maintain
favorable trade status with the United
States W see they don't they don't want
to arrest him but it's just a pragmatic
thing you just don't want to incur the
economic Devastation of going into a
econom trade war with the United States
so my friends who run coffee shops in
Amsterdam explained to me there's those
kind of Dynamics and there's a lot of
pressure from the United States a lot of
pressure from right-wing religious
groups and so on for them to to roll
back the uh uh liberalness of their
coffee shop culture and their coffee
shop industry also there's this concern
you don't want to have drug tourism
people from more regressive countries
take on the train for 2 hours to get to
the Netherlands they buy up all their
pot then they go home well that's not
Germany doesn't like that Germany says
marijuana is illegal and people go over
to across the border there pick it up
and go home consequently the the coffee
shops with the biggest uh turnover are
the ones right along the border and
those are the ones that are having to
have cards where you have to be a local
citizen to go there and and be a
customer uh you'll hear that they're
rolling them back in the Netherlands
it's it's um you know you always hear
the the news when they roll it back and
then the in practice it sort of lives on
and I don't know exactly what the the
latest is but it's a you know it's a
constant struggle over there because a
lot of forces that are are sort of uh
you know threatened by their Progressive
attitude about this I was talking about
the complexity of what happens after you
do legalize marijuana Roger Goodman you
know him probably he's a local
Congressman he's running for congress
for jamy spots cool guy by the way very
courageous and he's been speaking out in
a very U viable thoughtful easy to
embrace from a general public point of
view drug policy points and uh Roger's
just a beautiful guy years ago he put on
a three-day seminar with the Seattle Bar
Association T the whole theme of the
convention was let's assume marijuana is
legal now what do we do you know how do
you how do you wholesale it how do you
advertise it how do you regulate it this
is nobody's figured this out the
Netherlands have doing this for 25 years
they decided to quasi legalize it but
the wholesale end of it is still wink
wink nudg nudge all right it's called
the gray
area the gray area it's just I was
talking to these guys and uh you know
they've got their laws for instance if
you're an American here you're worried
about oh if they legalize marijuana
they're going to be having big
Billboards advertising it to my children
right across the street from school
these are the issues we should be
dealing with here you know when we think
of practicality where are we going to go
with this well in the Netherlands they
have dealt with this and you cannot
advertise marijuana you cannot you step
into a coffee shop and this is what I do
in my work work I go in as a clueless
tourist and I figure out I'm confused
what do I do and I have to learn and
then I write it down so people with my
guide books can learn from my experience
there you go into a coffee shop if
you've never been in one before you kind
of you're first struck by I want to
spend some money but I don't know what
to buy I where's the menu because they
can't advertise it it can't come at you
it can't be like on a restaurant where
they post it on the door so the guy says
if you want to know what's for sale you
got to push this
button so you push this button and and a
thing lights up and you are physically
Illuminating the menu the point is it
seems like legal hair splitting but the
point is the information doesn't come to
you the consumer goes to the information
now that seems a little wacky maybe but
that's dealing with a very real and
legitimate concern of the general
populace that wouldn't think this is a
fun party all right they don't want
people promoting pot to their kids and
that's I can live with that you know uh
they've got an issue of they don't want
um uh people buying a lot and then going
and and and uh and selling it they
wanted pretty much just small time so
they limit you to a couple of just a
small amount per day very strict limit
of people uh only over 18 that can go
into these coffee shops definitely no
hard drugs the police see it as a
firewall the police like this because
they know where the drug experimenting
population goes and the police are
concerned about hard drug abuse not soft
drug use and the police even have
bulletin boards in these coffee shops so
they can communicate what's dangerous on
the streets in the way of chemical drugs
see know that's and that's a surprise to
think police would find a coffee shop as
a very handy tool for pragmatic harm
reduction drug issues you see that's
real drug policy rather than this just
say no marijuana is going to kill
yourself um in in a coffee shop in
Amsterdam there is a limit of 500 gram
that they can have in their inventory at
any time that's about a pound
they can keep a pound of marijuana in
their shop the mayor of Amsterdam last
time I was there was advocating to
double that limit to 1 kilo because it
would cut in cut down on traffic
congestion because there was so many
little petty deliveries going around all
over town you could you could gross a
ton of marijuana but you can never have
more than 500 grams in stock at any one
time you see so I I just find all of
these little backside issues just so fun
when you think about how Progressive
Europeans are and how creative they are
and how unfear ful they are how
pragmatic they are you know when I was
first going to the Netherlands you were
getting a opportunity to buy pot from
Morocco or Pakistan or wherever now it's
all grown right there in the Netherlands
they've got the technology to grow the
equivalent of Pakistan or whatever you
liked about you know Morocco or
something like that right there and it's
too dangerous and complicated for them
to import it they don't need to import
it anymore it's locally grown there's
just all of these things just Blossom
when you get down to real pragmatic
issues rather than throwing around
bumper stair sckers The Children at Risk
thing is a major concern for Europeans
as well as Americans Dutch cops know
that in the United States it's easier
for kids to get their hands on marijuana
than it is to get their hands on alcohol
because as anybody in this game knows
the best way to lose control of
something is to make it illegal if you
want to make it tough for kids to get
you regulate it you just regulate it
it's such a clear logical sort of thing
that the average fearful voter in the
suburbs needs to learn and that's who we
need to talk with
um when you think about the fear in our
society we can look at Europe and see
how they've handled it 10 years ago in
Portugal they decided to legalize the
consumption of all drugs all drugs and I
just interviewed the uh their drug Zar
who wrote that law for my radio show and
you can see it on my website if you want
to hear it but uh they said after 10
years now they have done a review of the
effectiveness because it was a little
scary you know to legalize the
consumption of all drugs and they've
decided after 10 years even people who
were opposed to it that use has not gone
up they took the crime out of the
equation and now they can deal with it
in a smart pragmatic harm reduction kind
of way pretty good what they've done is
they've made marijuana boring it's no
longer quite so sexy you know and it's
just there for people who want it it's
really quite amazing now a lot of
Americans think there's a whole
reservoir of people out there that would
just love to ruin their lives by smoking
pot if only it was legal these people
are clueless anybody who wants to smoke
pot I think does right and they just
have to be criminals to to do it and I'm
convinced if you legalize marijuana
tomorrow in in Washington state you
might spike a little bit it would settle
back down to about where it is today and
uh it would just be a nonissue that's
what it is in Europe a
nonissue there's no clear rule book
nobody knows exactly how to do it by my
little anecdotal case studies in Europe
every country has a different approach
to it in Spain you will see marijuana uh
leavs all over that are just advertising
little shops they just look like little
Little Nick next shops so and there are
little garden shops and these are grow
your own shops and in in Spain you can't
sell marijuana but you can grow it for
your own use so there's no retail sale
of marijuana but there is sale of all
the gear you need to grow it well and
seeds so next time you go to Spain
you'll see that and you'll have to hang
around long enough to grow it in order
to take advantage of that okay uh now is
that better than the Netherlands or the
Portuguese that P well they're all
better than what we got aren't they
there's no there's no perfect solution
so you're going to hear people
complaining about 502 we need to take a
step forward we need to take it out of
the the the lock up 800,000 people
arrest 800,000 people a year Zone and
then we can figure out where to go from
there but I really believe even with all
of its flaws if 502 passes it becomes
less scary for the people that need to
have the fear take it out of this and
from there we can get to a very
reasonable uh Arrangement like they have
in Europe at least that's my
hope I'll tell you just a few of the
ideas that came from my talk with the U
the main uh drug guy in the Seattle
police force before he went to be the
police chief of another city um his
mission is to protect kids and stop
violence and to enforce existing laws
they don't have strong feelings about
marijuana it's sort of I would imagine
sort of sort of a drag to have to even
worry about this but they have to
enforce laws they're worried about
protecting kids and stopping violence uh
they don't evaluate the laws for them
they don't differentiate between
different kinds of drugs it's just when
they see problems there's drugs there's
hard drugs there's marijuana there's
alcohol it's just problems alcohol or
drugs equals problems uh they're sort of
insulted by medical marijuana because of
the Sham aspect of medical marijuana and
it is if I was a police officer I Would
S sort of be insulted by it too not to
De uh legitimize the whole uh you know
validity of medical marijuana but the
fact is people go in to get their Clinic
card not claiming glaucoma because that
can be checked but they say they got a
sore neck and that really can't be
verified um whenever use that word harm
reduction that's a catch phas for
legalization I hope that's going to
change in the near future
um and
uh one problem they have with our whole
discussion is that they don't believe in
any of our numbers and and it's hard to
get straight numbers anywhere if you
look on the internet who made these
numbers up you know the right or the
left it's just a frustrating thing I
wish we could get more numbers if if you
want to be credible I think it's
important that we acknowledge explicitly
that children need to be protected from
marijuana uh we need to acknowledge that
it's not healthy it can be abused and it
can be addictive I don't even know if it
can be addictive I guess it can be
psychologically addictive I know people
that have smoked every day for 20 years
and they just decide to stop and it's no
problem other people they got weaker
character I guess and they just become
psychologically addicted or maybe it's
physically addicted whatever the case
throw them that bone admit it can be
addictive it's not healthy it's a drug
it can be abuse used I'm not saying it's
healthy I'm saying it should not be a
crime now I've been speaking out on this
for a long time and uh I'll tell you
we've made a lot of progress if you feel
frustrated we've made a lot of progress
when I came out I mean I spoke on Jim
French's show I don't know if your
oldtime satellites know Jim French he
was a great radio guy back in the 80s
and uh' 70s and ' 80s and uh I had to go
as an anonymous responsible you user
back then uh but it's so nice to not
have to be so Anonymous but uh 10 years
or so ago when I joined normal and first
spoke out I just felt like man I was
like some sort of a child molester or
something people push me down in the
chair and there's all these cameras on
me and it was scary now it's not scary
at all I was standing on Main stage
yesterday with the mayor of Seattle I
mean that is really cool every one of
our Representatives is hit to this yeah
yeah I mean the people we've got on
board for 502 it's just inconceivable 5
years ago like Roger Goodman has learned
you cannot assassinate somebody's
character politically now because
they're smart on drugs Roger Goodman's
opponents try to they spend good money
trying to make him seem soft on drugs to
his electrc and every time his opponents
try to assassinate his character because
of his stand on marijuana Roger's
numbers Spike upward all right that's a
new age I'll tell you that is a new age
and we got to be smart to capitalize on
that I think it's it's a little
frustrating for me to come to Hempfest
because I get a sense that 90% of the
people here you know they they just they
just U are not doing anything to push it
forward in a smart way it's a beautiful
Festival Vivian taught me that in a very
nice way that this is a a celebration
for a legitimate part of our society to
come out and be who they are in public
and that in itself is really something
to celebrate you know I mean it's not my
crowd but I just love that we can do
this but what I'm concerned about is how
these laws are messing up people and we
owe it to if we're good citizens we owe
it to each other to get out there now
and uh you know clean up our act and and
use this word in polite company people
freak out when they hear the word
marijuana talk about it in a smart
compassionate knowledgeable way share it
with Community leaders I took my pastor
for a walk and told him I'm going to be
speaking out from now on out about
marijuana and I want you to know why and
he bought it the church Council of
Seattle is with us yeah you know they
are with us teachers are are with us
teachers can't talk because they're
afraid of losing their job or their
option for a raise or something like
that but they're with us politicians are
with us the media is with us when the
mic is off I've been on with the mic you
know all over the country and and people
are asking me all these straight nervous
questions as soon as the mic's off they
say thank you for speaking out you know
we need to speak out we need to speak
out in a way that does not scare people
some people say well what about your
business you know I I employ 80 people
up in Edmonds what's this going to M to
your
business well frankly I'm not worried
about my business I'm worried about the
truth I if it hurt my business I'd do
the same
thing but the fun news is I think it's
actually pretty good for my
business I'm the only business in
Seattle that's not selling Doritos or
Rolling Papers that's got a banner up on
the main stage I think you know and uh
I'm it's a breakthrough this is a real
Market here if you're just looking for
an advertising in but uh you know I get
a lot of people that read about what I
think about marijuana they say I know
what you think about poton we're not
going to use your guide books anymore
and we're not going to take any of your
Europe tours and all I can think is
Europe's going to be more fun without
you
right I really think I really think the
public is aead of the politicians on
this and the politicians are learning
and I actually think the politicians are
head of the corporations I think the
corporations are really the scared ones
and I think the corporations are really
in so many ways they're pissing me off
these days you know uh and uh this is
one area where they just they act like
they're moralistic but they're just
reading the tea leaves and what's good
for their business Google um Michael
Phelps is that his name and uh who was
his under Kelloggs or something like
that uh you know he he was caught
smoking marijuana he was a poster boy
for was it kellogs yes yeah and then so
Kellog was going to say you know get rid
of them and their uh and their uh all
their stock values died when they got
rid of Michael phelp so what was it then
Subway sandwich was also supporting
Michael Phelps they were going to get
rid of him too they had a board meeting
and they looked at what happened to
Kelloggs when they got rid of Michael
Phelps and then Subway thought uh we
better keep them on board in fact they
came out with an advertising campaign
immediately after that called have a
Subway sandwich and feel the
buzz check it out check it out I mean
it's just amazing but it just clarifies
my hunch that they're only moralistic
not because they're moral but because
they're looking to profit maximize and
we can change that so corporations won't
be so threatened by profit maximization
I walk a fine line in my work with my
underwriting and all this kind of thing
and I'm very careful not to be Pro drugs
I mean I'm a harm reduction civil
liberties kind of approach to this and I
think that's our best approach when
we're going out in the public but we've
got to remember our politicians as soon
as they feel like it's safe they raise
their voices but right now it's one of
those third rail issues so um so my
advice to you if you're going to be
speaking out on this uh please
understand we got to get out of the
choir I mean I love to talk on Main
stage but I'd much rather talk at a
rotary club I'd rather talk to 200
rotarians I I mean I'd rather talk to a
couple thousand people here that's more
fun but I'm going to get more
accomplished if I go to a rotary club
you know you can do that you know half
the people here they put on a suit the
next day and go to work you know you can
take it there we don't need to be in the
closet you can't believe uh the fun I've
had speaking out on this all over the
country I got the Lutheran of the Year
award the vitberg award in Washington DC
and they introduced me as a board member
of normal that wouldn't happen a long
time ago but now people know in their
hearts of hearts that you can be smart
on marijuana policy and that means
taking the crime out of this
thing
right so I'm going to wrap up here in a
sec don't be scary I'm this is one of my
themes all my friends un normal we try
not to be scary you know we're out there
in the public you don't want to be scary
look at some of your friends they're
just flat out scary not to you and me
but to the person that needs to vote for
this they're scary I'm not saying it's
right the reality is they're scary so
take the scary out of it uh get involved
in other things so that when you're
involved in something you're involved in
something like really nice and
compassionate drug policy it confuses
people you know they want to like like
you they want to support you they
respect you and then they see what
you're into here also and they give you
more time they give you more credibility
and I find that works really well
preempt attacks I'm telling you they're
worried about kids they're worrying
about driving and they're worry about
hard drugs you can preempt that the only
thing Gateway about marijuana is its
illegality that's what the Europeans
have learned I mean as soon as it's
illegal the only way you can get it I
mean the way most people get it is from
some Criminal on the street who is
interested in getting you hooked on
something more addictive and more
profitable we can talk about that and
then just be straight and honest about
you believe the responsible adult use of
marijuana in a recreational way is a
civil liberty I always like to say I'm a
hardworking tax paying kid- raising
Church going citizen of this country and
if I work hard all day long want to go
home and relax with the joint that is my
civil
liberty so
one of my favorite things I've heard all
in the last couple of years is when our
uh friend John McKay you know our the
prosecuting attorney former prosecuting
attorney when he stood on a stage with
us in the ACLU thing here and he said
it's he's a republican I mean he's just
a hard Law and Order kind of guy he said
this marijuana law that we're living
with is flat out bad law we got that
going on our favor it's bad law mayor
LaGuardia said back in the 30s when
they're dealing with stupid alcohol laws
he said if a society has a law in the
book that it does not to intend does it
not to intend tend to enforce
consistently across the board the very
existence of that law erodes respect for
law enforcement in general that's a big
problem in a society and we got that
going on right now with this war on
marijuana I want to remind you once more
we have a window you'll hear other
people talking about it it's an election
year next year and I understand only
during a presidential election do kids
get out and vote in numbers enough to
make our initiatives viable I I I know
there's FR I'm a I'm a co-sponsor of I
too and I really have a I'm really sad
that we can't have this grow at home
provision you know that's just something
I'm going to live with I know other
people in the medical community have
their concerns and the whole driving
thing but these laws evolve and my main
concern is to get over the summit so
that people out there will see they made
a law that legalized and regulated and
taxed marijuana and you know it's no big
deal consumption didn't go up crime went
out and now we can get along with
normalizing this thing it's a tough
challenge to get 240,000 signatures if
you want to do something and you can
just write a huge check and you're rich
do that and they'll hire other people to
get those signatures but I think it is
really good citizenship and it's good
hempmy go over to that Booth
502 check out one of those little
clipboards go home go to your workplace
let people you know this is smart law
this is good citizenship this is how
we're going to end the war on on
marijuana and then decades from now we
can tell our
grandchildren that Washington state was
the first state that started the end of
the prohibition on marijuana that is an
exciting
opportunity okay so that's just what I
wanted to share with you thank you very
much I hope that we can enjoy the rest
of him happy travels even if you're just
staying home okay thank you very much