we got a very much of a Latin crowd
[Music]
here okay all right all right we got
some here well here's the deal here's
the deal you know here we are in Seattle
in Washington you know we know we have
17 States 17 medical states in America
the United States anyway this part of
America that are medical States but what
I'm here to talk about is the rest of
the world there's so much going on
everywhere else not just America and the
one thing we all got in common with all
those guys everywhere else in the world
is we love one thing cannabis cannabis
yeah cannabis and we got one goal
between us all and that is to make
cannabis legal let cannabis be free and
that's it that's what brings us all
together because for example in Spain
where I live most of the time you can
have uh uh four plants six plants
whatever it's not really uh secure
exactly the number of plants you can but
it's written into the
Constitution that you can grow cannabis
I think that's a good thing you know
that's why I live there okay and then in
Austria you know Austria where Vienna is
you know you think that one uh Little
Country in the middle of nowhere out up
next to Hungary well you can grow clones
there I mean one of my good friends
grows 10,000 clones a week and he's got
one of the any uh clone stores there
yeah 100% legal 100% legal and in
Switzerland things were going 100% legal
to grow cannabis uh God for years for
years we used to grow Fields Fields
literally Fields 10 10 acres uh they
call them hias there but uh you know
lots of for about a period of about 10
years but now it's completely legal to
grow four plants in Switzerland so they
kind of went backwards but you know I
I'm just talking about serious legal
growing and then the Czech Republic
remember it used to be uh Czechoslovakia
and the part of it was a Czech Republic
it's legal to grow there too and by the
way cannabis is
decriminalized um Israel Israel any any
Jewish people here Israelis yeah yeah
okay this is good this is good Israel is
one of the best places for growing
medical cannabis in the world Israel you
wouldn't think of it of course we all
know that Dr rapael mulam a Jewish
fellow Israeli he was the one that
discovered THC and he also discovered
the cannaboid uh receptors in Russia my
first book is now coming out in Russia
it's on the boat right now coming from
China to America so we can ship it to
Russia um anyway it's still illegal in
Russia but they're growing all over the
place Argentina this this winter I go I
go to Argentina I go to to uh
Chile Peru or not no no Peru uh paray
urugai and Brazil and all three of those
well everywhere but Brazil cannabis is
legal it's decriminalized now you can
have up to uh 20 gram that's 2/3 of an
ounce so and then even in in Mexico
where I went to school it's uh you can
have five GRS legal so the one thing we
got all in common is is this cannabis
and these guys in the other countries
have done a better job of legalization
than we have and we're leaders here in
America we've already shown I don't know
if any of you guys ever see my uh 10
pound plant video it's on YouTube just
type in hantes in YouTube you see that
uh you see this big video of 10 pound
plants we already teach everybody how to
grow 10 pound plants and so they're
looking for some leadership from us
we've got to make cannabis legal in
America in the United States
and that's what I have to say thank you
very much