what does it do for you how does it
affect you how much taxes will they get
if they include you because sometimes
it's just the money an organ if they
decide that they don't want to
participate they don't get any of the
money I'm kind of looking forward to see
how well that plays out for them all of
a sudden Portland is going to become
uber uber rich and cities likes candy
sandy right next door who boldly spoke
up to my friend and told him no you may
not open a dispensary here well why not
how come I can't open a dispensary here
because we don't like you how is that
acceptable if your city or your chianti
tells you we don't want you here and we
don't like you sure you need to stand up
and tell them I'm here and you're going
to like me you're going to accept that I
use cannabis and I'm going to vote you
out if you don't because your boat
counts and your money counts I love you
guys please share love please be
respectful please put money into bins as
festivals expensive we love you speak up