if you free the plant you'll free the
planet
erv rosenfeld is the longest surviving
federal medical marijuana patient in the
united states
he's the published author of my medicine
give a warm seattle welcome to irv
rosenfeld thanks sir
good afternoon i want to thank everybody
with this home festival it's a great job
they've put on they worked very hard and
like they said a few dollars in the pot
would help to bring this back next year
hey my name is irvin rosenfeld i am the
longest surviving federal medical
cannabis patient in the united states
the federal government's been giving me
marijuana for the last 28 years i
receive over 120 000 medical cannabis
cigarettes so far from the federal
government
now i've always tried to be very
responsible if you see me on any of my
documentaries or in the news shows you
usually see me with a coat and tie on
whenever
you talking about medical cannabis you
want to look better than the crowd that
you're with therefore i could dress like
this today
the point is you've got to be
responsible if you're going to use
cannabis in whatever way you use it and
if you don't use it responsibly then
you're giving me a bad name
i don't like that so make sure you know
what cannabis does to you
and if you it puts you in a position
where you're lethargic and don't feel
like doing something
then don't do it don't put yourself in
that position when you have to do
something
if it makes you
creative makes you a better person and
your thoughts well then when you've got
work to do nothing wrong with it you've
got to know what it does to you you've
got to be responsible
now
i came all the way from fort lauderdale
florida
this is the first time
that i've been here in this crowd and i
must say i'm very impressed so i do hope
that they're able to carry this on and
carry it next year and the year after
that in many years to come but it's
going to be with all your help out here
now
being the longest surviving federal
patient i realized that the history of
the medical marijuana movement i helped
start i planted the seeds in the early
70s for what you see here today in all
of the country
and i realized
that if i died all that information
would die with me
that wasn't fair
so i've been very fortunate to be able
to get a federal patient to be able to
win the struggles the trials and
tribulations it just didn't happen
overnight it was a 10-year struggle so i
sat down and i wrote a book
the book is called my medicine because
that's what it is my medicine
now i'm hoping that this book will teach
the american public that they don't have
the face of when they think about
marijuana they think of some
no good
whatever person sitting back just
wanting to get high
now here i am in a coat and tie now i'm
a financial advisor i'm senior vice
president
of investments for new bridge securities
okay i say that because again i'm a
responsible person
and i use 10 to 12 marijuana cigarettes
per day to do it for my bone disorder it
works as a muscle relaxant
anti-inflammatory for pain i have bone
tumors on my body
now i teach disabled people how to sail
boats in miami
i've been married for 37 years
i do all this
i do all this because i have the right
medicine the people out here you all
have the right medicine but that's only
40 percent of the country right now
that's under state laws we need the rest
to come and join us to be able to enjoy
the freedom the medical freedom that we
have here
so what i'm going to go back to florida
with
is a picture of freedom
of being able to see people
that can do what they want to do
medically speaking as long as they're
not hormones
so when i finish speaking i'm going to
be out down here in the front of the
stage i'll be doing book signings
plus i'm the booth i'm in is the 420
booth which is the hempfire empire booth
number 420. i hope you all come here get
an autographed copy i'll be there all
day and keep in mind they're going to be
bringing a festival here in march all
right to seattle and i think it's
something that y'all want to check out
so to everybody here again
thank you so much
for coming thank you sponsors
okay band
the organizers the people that clean up
the people that set up realize y'all are
just walking in okay it didn't cost you
anything to walk in
everything's provided for you now you
gotta pay for your food you gotta pay
for water but think of everything that's
been done for you by other people
okay so when you see that bucket go
around
you gotta reach in and you gotta give
them something
okay that's to me that's that's also
very important
so
again please be response please be
responsible and use cannabis correctly
thank you
thank you so much herb rosenfeld