song about when the wto came here to
town
and all those streets downtown were
declared no go zones but we went anyway
november 30th 99 history walking on a
tight road flying and making money
pulling on invisible strings
getting into everything [ __ ]
it's hard to believe it's in the food
and the water and the air you breathe
and the chemistry
the biotech
the banker with the bottomless check the
corporations and the ceos and the bottom
line as the profit grows the money talks
you don't talk back they don't like it
when you act like that but didn't we
talk back
coming to town and we swore we gonna
shut it down and they stood there with
their big police they had the national
guard up to keep the peace with the guns
and the gloves and the chemical gas but
still we would not let them pass
they raised and brought in their tempers
shut it down
november 30th 99 millennium passing as
the numbers climb and the people came
from middleweight
must have been 50 000 out there there
were farmers unions rank and file they
dig your ass or it says its own style
they were great big puppets two stories
tall there were drummers drumming in the
shopping mall there was so many people
that you couldn't see how [ __ ] many
people got into the city and the wt no
delegates too but we were locked down so
they couldn't get through
shut it down
november 30th 99 locked down at the
police line and they're hitting you with
everything they got
but you ain't moving like it or not and
they're tying your wrists with plastic
cups and they're loading these up on a
great big box and they're taking you
down to the navy base
pepper
shut it down
now the media loves all the glittering
flash the newspaper's talking out a
whole lot of trash about the violence of
the people in black and how the cops are
so tired it has had to attack and the
secrets hidden in a man deep dark hole
look what they call city hall may never
be told the mayor is out doing the spin
the police chief quit so you can't ask
him where they
shut it down
didn't we
now it's the greatest story ever told
david and goliath though you'd be so
bold standing up to the giant when the
going gets hot and all you got is a
slingshot
well they come in that the world turned
upside down and they gotta pick it up
and shake it gotta turn it around you
gotta take it apart to rearrange it i
don't wanna save the world i wanna
change it and don't let him tell you
that it can't be done cause they're
gonna be the first ones around just take
a little lesson from seattle town
wto and how he shut it down didn't it
shut it down
didn't we
within the 30th 99
bye