gives me great pleasure to introduce to
you right now a champion of Truth and
Liberty I think one of the most honest
politicians we've had in my lifetime us
Congressman Dennis cassin is here to
speak to you let's hear a warm welcome
give your love to Dennis
[Applause]
[Music]
cassin
Seattle on this day in this uh place of
great
Beauty we celebr at the beauty of
Nature and I'm also here to celebrate
the wondrous nature of
[Music]
you the presence that we have here today
binds us as a community it empowers us
it strengthens
us we must become visible in Mass if
we're going to bring about the change
that we want in the society and when we
do that we extend our reach
we bring about new
possibilities and the creative spark
that births action can Usher in a new
world we have to say to America open up
America show yourself time for mass
action this is why and how recent
movements for freedom in Tunisia and
Egypt gain momentum this is how Gandy
cast off the British Empire this is how
America's suffer Jets ended up getting
for women the right to vote this is how
Dr Martin Luther King's March on
Washington became a pivotal moment in
the Civil Rights history of this country
people become visible they go to the
streets they linked arms they marched
they sang We Shall Overcome they walked
the uplet path of Social and economic
Justice people have been on this path
and it's time for us to begin to walk
that path too people then marched to
Glory but not for themselves but for the
benefit of generations to come We Gather
here today in a common determination for
change a sense of commonality of purpose
awakens a purpose a sense of awareness
grows the moment arrives to exercise a
new commitment to cast off an old order
of things this same awareness brought
America's Founders to write the
Declaration of Independence and to
proclaim a new order follow
today it is not a financial deficit that
will bring America down it is a deficit
of public action when people discover
what happens when one person determines
to make a difference and then merges
with the many
likeminded and becomes visible new
possibilities unfold and a new order
follows now Seattle you understand this
because in
1999 Seattle hosted the World Trade
Organization rally and Seattle was the
host to the teamsters and the turtles
marching arm in-arm not too far from
this area demanding once and for all
that we have enforcable workers rights
human rights Environmental Quality
principles in all of our trade
agreements they marched and they chanted
and they said not only we shall overcome
but solidarity forever solidarity for
workers the Seattle WTO cast light upon
the workings of the WTO seattleites
union members trade and activist help
spark a worldwide awareness help spark a
worldwide awareness that workers had to
have rights and that there had to be
Environmental Quality principles and it
was the people of Seattle who identified
that child labor slave labor and prison
labor had to be in trade that
prohibitions on that had to be in trade
agreements Seattle brought that forward
you kept that alive you've nurtured it
large intentional Gatherings like this
one can be a catalyst for powerful
change but we have to be prepared as
George Bernard Shaw once wrote To Dream
things that never weren't asked why not
and let us dream about the America that
we want let us give our dreams some
firmament let our dreams and our
thoughts become words let the words
become Deeds let our action our Deeds
become action let our action build a new
America and a new world Seattle you
shook the world once can you shake it
again I ask
you are you ready here Seattle to
declare once and for all that it's time
for America to end the wars in Iraq in
Afghanistan and Libya are you ready to
do
that are you prepared to demand that our
troops be brought
home are you prepared to demand that
America end its worldwide military
presence are you prepared to demand that
America must lead the way to nuclear
abolition are you prepared Seattle to
demand that we have to repeal the
Patriot
Act are you prepared Seattle to demand
that government spying EAS dropping and
wiretapping of law-abiding citizens must
[Music]
end that our sisters right to privacy be
protected and decisions about women's
reproductive Health be made between a
woman and her da
are you prepared Seattle to say that our
brothers and sisters who are gay lesbian
bisexual transgendered have all full
rights including the right to
marry are you prepared Seattle to demand
the
decriminalization and legalization of
marijuana and demand hospitalization not
incarceration for those with drug
[Music]
problems are you prepare to demand not
for-profit health care for
all education for all retirement
security for
all jobs for
all are you prepared to rescue our
federal government from corporate
interest by calling for a Constitutional
Amendment which establishes only public
financing of of federal elections are
you prepared for that
are you prepared to summon the energy to
rescue our planet to protect our air our
water and our land from further
exploitation by demanding an end to
drilling the Earth fracking the Earth
cracking the Earth and and and an end to
the poisoning of our seas and our skies
and to make sure that we end this carbon
based solution and bring forward a rapid
transition to an environmentally
friendly socially responsible
green economy Seattle Seattle this day
here and now you through your responses
have voiced what I would call the
Seattle declaration let the sound of
your voice today be heard wide and far
let your affirmations give birth to new
actions a new nation and a new world let
your voice once again cause America to
March let your voice once again cause
America to sing let your your voice
cause America to seek new freedoms let
your voice call America to seek a newer
World ours is a Restless Quest For
Freedom we know Wars make us less free
we know fear makes us less free social
and economic insecurity makes us less
free if it is for Freedom's sake that we
gather so then let us be for Freedom's
sake that we act courageously because it
is our and desire it is our desire for
change that carries extraordinary power
to become more than we are better than
we are forged in the human heart ignited
by love and a passion for transformation
our common Unity our common purpose and
our common action can carry the power to
change everything this is the power of
human Unity this is the power of our
Oneness feel it own it
acot at Seattle thank
you us Congressman Dennis cassin give a
hand