right now I'm gonna bring up jodie emery
the incredible life of marc emery we
certain time in a US federal
penitentiary for selling seeds over the
internet it's a disgrace no seeds ever
hurt anybody in the history of the world
she's an incredible tireless campaigner
for her husband she's an incredible
activist and a tremendous person give it
up to Jodie Emery thank you so much and
thank you so much to hempfest this is my
fourth year year and every year I am
filled with hope because i know our
movement is winning and you're here in
the world largest cannabis celebration
there are people worldwide right now who
are so envious of you they would give
anything to come to seattle hempfest and
you are lucky enough to be here because
there are tireless activists working day
in and day out all year long to make
this happen for you for free to attend
so you owe it to everybody here just
give a dollar you've all got at least a
dollar I'm sure please donate to
hempfest because this event is free to
attend to speak about freedom but it's
not free to put on so show them a little
gratitude for that when you leave my
husband's name is Marc Emery used called
the Prince of pot by CNN and the rolling
stone walls eternal media home the world
covered my husband because he did
something no one else would do in
nineteen ninety four hour mark and we
decided to start selling marijuana seeds
to people worldwide no matter where you
lived and in the united states
california passed medical marijuana laws
but there was a need for medicine in the
form of seeds and my husband decided to
be brave to sell those seats to
Americans and people worldwide so not
only did marquetry the prince of pop
provide millions and millions of
marijuana seized two people worldwide to
grow their own medicine and save their
Ally
but he promised that every dollar spent
on those seeds but go to legalization
efforts he find us bowel initiatives for
medical marijuana in colorado washington
DC Nevada Arizona Alaska many places
where a pastor failed mark help make
that happen mark founded the u.s.
marijuana party he's a Canadian citizen
he never even left Canada but he knew
the u.s. is where the drug war begins
and where must end till he financed the
marijuana movement with millions of
dollars all of the money from those
seeds Wednesday activism in this country
in this state in this city and places
worldwide to help the activists on the
ground become leaders in their own right
and take forward the torch of victory
and mark every was the most famous
activist for that reason he said plant
the seeds of freedom to overgrow the
government and here we are today where
the US has made so much progress it's a
beacon of hope for the rest of the world
because the drug war started here and it
spreads around the world like a cancer
it kills people with the drug war in
Mexico it kills people worldwide it
imprisons people ruins families takes
away father's from their little babies
it hurts people who hurt no I'm you
aren't hurting anyone but the law is
designed to hurt you so you like my
husband and every other activists taking
a stand doesn't owe it to the people in
prison and the people who died to change
this law here in Washington this
November legalization is on the ballot
vote YES on I 502 illegal stores selling
legal marijuana to protect you from
going to prison and descend a message
worldwide that we need freedom and
legalization starts here so it comes in
spread throughout the world and my
husband who was imprisoned for his
activism the DEA admitted it was all
about the money they tracked all the
money and he said yeah he gave it all
lated political activists and campaigns
Marc Emery was a threat to the US drug
war and that's why he took him down they
brought him into this country when he
never even came here Marc Emery the
principle of the Canadian who planted
the seeds of freedom to overgrow the
government to save people's lives and
he's a hero like all the heroes in
prison because of this drug war and we
owe it to them because you're here today
you're free today you get to be here you
get to vote you owe it to all of those
people suffering worldwide to change
this to legalize marijuana and
prohibition and supports everybody who's
taking action to make that happen today
so thank you seattle hempfest this smoke
signal goes worldwide and it should be
followed by yes on 50 to legalization
this November vote yes make a difference
save lives and legalize marijuana thank
you very much I'm so do right now look
at his work and read the Prince of cops