put your hands together and please give
a Seattle welcome to Seattle's very own
[Applause]
heror
[Music]
[Applause]
oh
got the
baggage all
right that feeling God know they just
get one up
tight like a game I guess it's
time Dr the garage J right now and it's
a good time
SL
you got to doing
life all
right you feeling all right brother you
got
right all kind
[Music]
of know what you got to that
baggage drop the baggage
feel all
right that feel is know they just get
you up
tight R like a game yes it's time to
go all the garbage up right now and let
the good
[Music]
time
oh
[Music]
how you got to do in life you
know feel all
right you feeling all right brothers
sisters you they got it
right rules like a game I guess it's
time to
[Music]
go the garage right now and let the good
times
[Applause]
[Music]
roll drop the
bagage drop the
B
got the
bage r
now from the
baggage