so what you need to know about
Industrial Hemp is that we've been able
to produce it in Canada now for 14 years
without embarrassment without any
stories of kids going in and selling in
the high schools or any of these
problems whatsoever at all and the
Canadian police have been able to tell
the difference between industrial hemp
and pot really easily and our police are
no dumber than the Canadian place
they're equally dumb I
agree it's so so um we could do this
here and it's just
political um um um inertia lack of any
inertia in politics that that uh right
now that have got us stuck in the mud
and our Farmers totally handcuffed and
so the support we're hearing and seeing
in Congress is from these Farm Belt
states why because these Farmers hear
Canadian radio and they understand that
farmers up north are doing really well
on this crop and they want a piece of
the
action and we can do it here