hey everybody let's get
legal let's get fully legal let's get so
legal that you and I and everybody else
can grow our own and when we grow our
own let's not have to pay a big
fee and let's just keep some of it in
the hands of the people I mean I know a
lot of good people that grow a lot of
good medicine a lot of go herb and they
should be able to continue to do that uh
Vivian just said about the Cannabis
economy and I got to tell you that is
exactly what we need we need the wealth
of hampen cannabis through mom and pop
small businesses all across Washington
we need it in the Farms we need it in
Boutique Winery style grows where uh
cannabis tourists can come and take a
little bus trip and all of that we need
to grow hemp in the Okanagan area
because that ground there some of that
is so bad it would just benefit from him
so much and the people there the
unemployment is so high that they would
have living wage jobs and I want to
remind you all this can happen but we've
got to vote on it all right we've got
initiative 514 so if you want to grow
your own and you have to sign the
petition you have to register to vote
get it done we have until December 31st
to get these all these signatures
on this November the initiative that's
currently on the ballot will pass or
fail with the PE of people of Washington
on its own merits I advise each and
every one of you to number one go out
and register to vote and number two read
what you are voting on don't listen to
what anybody tells you because you're
smart enough to read this for yourself
it's a long read 68 pages but know what
you're voting on anybody vote on alcohol
and then we had a sudden surprise of hey
where' that extra 30% tax come from
there you go right there you know what
make sure you read it okay after
November it is either going to pass or
fail and I want to let you know that a
lot of people that aren't happy with 502
are are not quitting we are not you know
502 is not the Beall and endall of
cannabis reform certainly not in
Washington state and the fact that we're
running this right now proves that
there's another group that's well known
in Washington State for running
initiatives and I hear that they may or
may not Run Initiative in
2013 but it doesn't matter if it's us or
them or whoever else comes next until
cannabis is legal for each and every one
of you and your families and loved ones
and friends and neighbors to
benefit absolutely benefit from having
cannabis available to you I don't know
what to else to tell you we will not
quit
legalization is the safest access for
our
patients you know when you put it into
the economy where anybody can give it
away or trade it or hand it over your
fence like a zucchini to your
neighbor the quality there's no reason
why it can't stay up because we all
believe in it but there's every reason
why the price should go down and I want
you to consider that when that price
goes down you can either shove it into
the hands of the government to use what
they want or you can keep keep that
money in your own pockets and go spend
it out in your own neighborhoods your
own communities and grow your business
imagine all the money currently spent on
cannabis now going into the legitimate
economy you know full-time jobs benefits
for people and I want to also tell you
when you can grow your own in the
backyard how much energy are we going to
save all those thousand watt lights not
burning oh my God P sound energy is not
going to know what to do because our
energy bills are going to go down
because we'll have a
surplus there is so much I want you to
all
consider everything that I've told you I
want you to consider what's in the
current legislation I want you to come
by cely stage up here we are in the
booth right behind cely stage and we
will be there all weekend collecting
your signatures registering you to vote
so that you can make an honest and
informed choice about what vision of
marijuana want a
legalization you want for
yourself your friends your family and
your state and
countrymen so sign I
514 get this on the ballot if you don't
sign it now the closer we come to
December 31st the chance will be that we
won't be ready to go in January of
2013 if we can qualify this we will be
in front of the legislature in January
of
2013 just two months after whatever
happens in the election happens so
please read it I love it it was written
by uh a father who's worried about
cannabis being in in the schools when
his kids are going there when he wants
them to concentrate on their schoolwork
and this guy is a consumer and a patient
and he knows he doesn't want the highest
paid job for a high school student drop
out or otherwise to be drug dealer he
doesn't want our patients that have had
their access in Eastern Washington cut
off and if you haven't heard about it
you know spoke H was first wachi is now
facing problems you know Seattle could
be coming next you know thiron County we
don't know what they'll do but when we
speak out with a voice and tell them no
we're going to have it for ourselves and
we're going to set the rules that's
where they're going to have to
listen we don't create any law when you
create law you conflict with the federal
government and you lose we do what
sensible Washington has done for the
past few years and that's remove the
penalties for adults and when you do
that the federal government is forced to
use its own resources to come after us
just like they did with alcohol
prohibition back in the 20s and the 30s
so don't let them have it we take away
the penalties we don't want the big
cartels coming in
we limit a grow size to 400 square ft
which is about 20 by 20 if you live in a
rural area that's a nice outdoor Garden
because we need a legitimate source of
good cannabis in Washington state we
don't want to encourage the cartels to
come in with huge grows out in the
forest and everything else we should be
able to come together as individuals and
collect our 400 square feet together and
work together not as a corporation but
as collectives and
individuals keep cannabis Safe Keep
cannabis for the
people we love you Hempfest you
roll