our next speaker is not only the
presenting sponsor of Seattle Hempfest
this year that's that huge Banner THCF
Medical Clinic up there not only the
presenting sponsor of Seattle Hempfest
just presented us with a check for
$25,000 yeah but he's a sponsor of me
driving back from Oregon Country Fair
last
year about 4 in the morning I fell
asleep at the wheel and I total my
Explorer
I survive
obviously and our next sponsor gave me
that 2004 Pathfinder that's sitting over
there right there otherwise Vivian's so
broke I'm an activist man I'm so broke I
couldn't I didn't even have the money to
buy a
car Paul Stanford of the THC Foundation
my good brother man thank you for
keeping me rolling cuz I know you and I
have rolled many together give it up to
Paul
Stanford and we'll roll some more
hey you know I want to give a big thank
you to all of you folks for being
here a big thank you because you know we
got to come out of the closet and demand
our freedom we have been put down too
long you know marijuana prohibition
isn't about marijuana it's not about
drugs that's a smoke screen that's the
the story what marijuana prohibition is
really about is power and petrochemicals
and the continued centralization of
Economic and political control so our
job is to speak truth to power and
that's what we are here to do I also
want to thank all of those patients out
there because it's only because of you
patients coming to our clinics and
supporting us that we have the
wherewithal to support this and to
support the
Cause right you know May marijuana to me
is the Creator's greatest gift to
humanity I believe that marijuana is the
plant that produces more fuel more fiber
more food and more medicine than any
other plant on this
planet if you go back all archaeologists
agree that marijuana hemp was the first
crop purposely sown by humans it was
definitely among the first crop and
there's some evidence in Central Asia
that cannabis cultivation went back
40,000 years into the past could well
have been the main reason that our
ancestors came out of uh the hunter
gather way of life and started to uh
grow crops so they could have their
stash and we still need our stash today
you know about 75 years ago the the IND
industries that were affected the
petrochemical wood-based paper the
cotton baronss of the South they
realized that HP was going to displace
their
economic sustenance so they came up with
the lies that they presented to us as
Reaper Badness saying that marijuana
causes us to go crazy and kill our
family and friends that was the LIE they
sold to us we all know that's not true
20 years a Hempfest and there hasn't
been any
violence
so there's an initiative down here in
Washington state there's a couple of
them support all of them support it get
out there and get some signatures and if
you can't get signatures give them money
because every dollar you give them is a
signature that you didn't go out and get
every hour you volunteer to help them is
$10 they don't have to spend it comes
right down to you and me so I want to
once again thank all you folks for
coming out here I'm proud that we can
help and uh help us restore help