thank you baby and I'm thank you all of
you who are manifesting the spirit of
love in a most unique manner
a Salvation I am here to thank you from
the bottom of my heart on behalf of
hundreds of thousands of patients here
in your state of Washington and hundreds
of millions around the world all of whom
want their voices heard all of them are
giving thanks to the Creator for a
wonderful gift that alleviates their
symptoms to many illnesses and it is
called cannabis
we called it marijuana and tried to
demonize it by changing its name but the
miracle kept proclaiming itself and
today everything I wear from my toes to
my head is made from that beautiful
plant that God gave us and said here
take care of your planet
we are so fortunate to have so many of
you who have taken a stand for either
the environment the destruction to the
ocean that's being provided by this
prohibition
whether you're a constitutionalist and
know that the supreme law of the land
cannot be trashed in this fashion while
we stand by and do nothing
we are human beings with a heart and a
soul and a spirit that unites with those
Behind Bars who have committed no crime
they simply found a wiser bud
no
and so it is really really a privilege
to say to you thank you for having
changed this loss here in the state of
Washington
that is not only because you have
patience here but because you are aiding
that lighter day to come shining through
the rest of the world The Dark Knight of
ignorance is over and people like you
have brought in the new day as we Face
the new millennium
your legislators can no longer hide from
you
hey
we can have this this will be political
suicide another election is coming and
you're gonna get answers from them and
you're gonna kick the one side of office
who denied the voters power and the
voters rights
but there is someone with me who is a
hero in our area he's been an advocate
for many many issues and especially for
medical marijuana and lo and behead he
became a patient eventually as well he
just went through about with horrible
cancer and I he can tell you his story I
won't be singing to you today because I
want Norman to speak to you and I want
you to stop by the Green Cross and pick
up a copy of this tape called the war on
us they're behind the stage thank you
they're behind the stakes the Green
Cross
thank you I'm Norm can't tell me his
attorney I had the opportunity to speak
earlier and they'll be asked me to
address you again
at the end of my talk I simply asked
that
what matters most is that all of us
individually collectively as a group as
a community and we truly are a community
here today stand up and be counted that
we create the world we live in by each
and every choice we make every day and
to have the courage to come out of the
closet and speak up and say cannabis
prohibition is wrong is the beginning to
the end of that prohibition
whatever you musika did 12 years ago
this week in a Fort Lauderdale courtroom
would say no to Injustice to to stand up
to prosecutors that wanted to put her in
jail to stand up to the judge in the
criminal justice system that
criminalized marijuana she said no I
will not take a plea I demand the right
to go to a jury trial I want the right
to Advocate before a court of law and a
community of my citizens that using
marijuana medicinally is in fact not a
criminal act but a just that a righteous
act a moral act and she took that stand
she was willing to go to prison to fight
for it and the jury and the judge
acquitted her and found her not guilty
and what really
what really are that day is that the
criminal justice system was saying that
the laws are guilty and that we are
innocent that the laws are unjust and
criminal and yet we are the not guilty
ones and it is Criminal to lock people
up and put them in jail for the simple
possession of marijuana and his unjust
to seize your car and take your property
and deny your student loans and prevent
you from teaching in Community Schools
it's wrong it's unjust and you you must
individually stand up and be counted
today so that you don't become the
criminal the accused criminal tomorrow
so that you won't have to stand up in a
court of law and choose between whether
or not you want your freedom or to cop a
plate and accept drug testing
so join with me
join with me and say these words out
loud
embolden yourself I am not a criminal I
am not a criminal I am not a criminal
well maybe you all right now
listen
each and every time
you stand up for an injustice like this
vast and beautiful ocean you send out a
ripple in a wave of Hope and you educate
the ignorant
so don't be afraid to go home
today tomorrow and next week and when
they ask you where you were on Sunday
say I took part in the road to Justice I
went to the Seattle Hemp Fest I was part
of a new tomorrow
and I understand I just found out coming
from Fort Lauderdale and Vivian I'm
finished I heard that they there's some
sort of restriction about putting up
posters I I didn't see anything about
this in the Big Shot Seattle Times maybe
the stranger in the other papers the way
the mainstream Community will be turned
around is when you show that you are
very much a part of the mainstream your
participation here is it
and help me lb wants to say one last
thing I'm very very sorry but in our
state we have some very special Heroes
such as Norman and a man named Joe Hart
he recently defended and we just passed
away so say a minute praying for him
thank you Seattle we love you
yeah thank you so much it will be a norm