thanks Don
uh so I come from a very different
Washington uh I call it Mordor on the
pomac um you don't smell ganja in the
air you smell sulfur right um and so
it's a different political reality uh
I'm not going to talk about the the
politics of of drug policy in the west
coast much less in Seattle where you
have a a very different world than than
exists in in much of the rest of the
country but I want to talk about how
politics gets done in the other
Washington and why it is that it's so
difficult to get any kind of meaningful
reforms going uh
initialized and uh there is a dirty
little secret in Washington uh there's
one discourse that goes on in public and
when it comes to voting time and all
that stuff and when the doors are closed
I've been doing this for 13 years now
talking to members of Congress and their
staff when they're behind closed doors
the whispering starts so what do you
think about Taxation and legalization
and Regulation and decriminalization
uh and I've heard this from Democrats
and Republicans conservatives and
liberals um and they always talk about
it like they're the first ones who Ever
Raised that question um they're so
deeply closeted in so many ways it's
kind of like going to a Convention of
closeted gay Mormons um they're all
terrified that everyone else in the room
will find out they're the same as
everyone
else um and so one of the things I'm I'm
trying to do is figure out how do you
depolarize what has been traditionally a
third rail or the mother of all third
rail political issues is in in politics
uh that is the drug war third rail are
people familiar with the term third rail
it comes from the subway system right
two rails carry the Train the third rail
carries the high voltage if you touch it
you're dead politically so historically
third rail issues been abortion gay
marriage Aid to Israel the gun control
pedagog budget and drugs and crime um
and so what I'm trying to do is figure
out a way to depolarize that third rail
how do you get politicians to say in
public what they say in private and in
so doing I think there's a there's one
technique uh it's very counterintuitive
that may work um and you could try this
not just at the national level but at
the state and Municipal level with
associations conventions um you know
whether it's a Convention of the chiefs
of police or whatever it's a way to help
people come out of the closet slowly uh
and dip their toes in the water and that
has to do with accountability um it's
it's going to sound heretical but I
think there's too much accountability in
Washington right now
um and I think you might get more
responsive policies if you had
temporarily less accountability what do
I mean by that um Oscar wild once said
if you want a man to tell the truth give
him a mask is there a way we can give
our politicians a temporary mask a
non-binding mask where they can express
their views uh as in a confessional uh
without without risk attack risk of of
of being attacked
outright um the prime minister of of
Luxenberg was talking about a different
third ra issue at home um but he said
look we all know what needs to be done
but we just don't know how to get
reelected after we've done it this is
the problem right and the problem can be
framed I think um I think Bart Simpson
put it very well when Bart Simpson ran
for class president he ran by attacking
his opponent and he said my opponent
says there are no easy answers well I
say he's not looking hard enough that's
the problem in Washington people are
looking for easy answers politicians
think voters will only understand simple
short Solutions and if drugs are bad of
course you have to have a War on Drugs
um if you're a broke you can't have
deficit spending you can't have a
stimulus package uh it's
counterintuitive to argue that that that
you do the opposite might have a better
effect and so the way to do this then uh
is to have a nonbinding straw pole that
is to say a procedural exercise for for
10 minutes no one will know how you
voted your party leadership won't know
your constituents won't know your
funders won't know the lobbyists won't
know the nonprofits won't know no one
will know and for those 10 minutes for
the first time in Washington you will
have the ability as an elected official
to think what is really in the best
interest of the United States of this
generation of the next generation of
Seven Generations down the line whose
job is to look out for the for the
bigger picture and to temporarily put
partisan concerns aside and that and
that would allow them then to to to come
out of the closet and express their
views anonymously and as long as one
person as long as one person votes in
the opposite uh way then no one can know
that it wasn't you uh that did that and
so it's hard to gain this in any kind of
cynical way but it's a way to get
temporary honesty and what that does is
that if you had a straw poll in Congress
that was non-binding because it has to
be non-binding because the
Constitution guarantees that if 1/5 of
the Quorum presentent demands a recorded
vote you have that reported vote with
names and and who voted yes yes or no
but if you have this non-binding straw
poll and it turns out that 2/3 of
Congress or 34s of Congress thinks we
got to decriminalize or tax and regulate
um then just having that aggregate
number at the end 2/3 or 3 quarters
gives members of Congress some political
Capital they can then come out during
the recorded vote and say look um I'm
just being courageous uh I'm I'm
actually saying in public what all of my
most of my colleagues believe in private
and it's time we had an open and honest
discussion about this it's it's it's
it's a if they want to present that as
being courageous I'll let them have it
it's a coward's way out but it's a way
for them to come out of that closet
slowly without risking attack uh and
that jump starts it Leap Frogs the
conversation it's a way of manufacturing
a Tipping Point right so if you imagine
if you had the National Conference of
the chiefs of police and you did this
Anonymous straw poll at the beginning of
their conference and it was announced
that you know 23 third or 3/4 of the
police Chiefs here really believe that
we've gone too far with the drug war we
need to reverse gears uh we need to do
some some counterintuitive things and
imp Implement harming reduction Etc U
that would really change the tenor of
the conversation but right now they're
all sitting up on here on this on the
stage um
closeted and so it's a way for police
Chiefs for other people in sensitive
positions to come out of the closet uh
and that can really spark a different
kind of conversation it could save us
years in terms of of opening up the
discussion so that's what I'm going to
do