if you don't know who Peter McWilliams
was Peter McWilliams was a publisher and
a writer who wrote a book called ain't
nobody's business if you do he was a
very well known in the Libertarian Party
and he unfortunately before he died he
was a defendant in a court case he was
trying to sponsor some grows in in Los
Angeles back in the late 90s and when he
did that they got busted by the feds and
he unfortunately cater him was it aids
patient and they would not allow him to
use cannabis as a condition of his
release because they're drug-testing him
and as a result unfortunately Peter
ended up dying choking on his vomit but
he was a hero to us before he died in
wearing and we were so happy for many
years to honor Peter and his memory but
now we're honoring Kevin black and he's
somebody we're going to miss he just
passed away this this last june and
kevin was the head of security here for
hempfest for a while and what he did is
he turned the hemp fest security in to
hempfest safety making this a very
peaceful event as you know hempfest has
always been very peaceful because
partially because cannabis consumers are
very peaceful people are we and we
deserve that kind of respect and Kevin
also was a bridge between law
enforcement and the hemp fest family so
he performed a very important service
here for hempfest he also and that's
important to get along with lon forth
and we want them to respect us because
cannabis consumers are some of the
nicest most honest decent intelligent
creative people that you know more than
I know that's all I can say we're the
good people and we really deserve out
equal rights and it it's time that we're
treated that way in this discrimination
Kevin also was a regional leader for the
November coalition which brought light
to many people in prison on drug fo and
drug offenses their stories as did our
book shattered lies portraits from
America's drug war that is going to be
coming out later this year as an e-book
it came out in 2099 82,000 is coming out
later this year we're going to update
and then put some news stories because
unfortunately there's still way too many
people in prison still wait too many
people getting arrested for marijuana
offenses all over this country but
meanwhile i want to thank you thank you
to Washington for passing I 502 I know
it's not perfect and a lot of people
aren't so happy with the way it's
unrolling rolling out but it's good it's
sure sent a wonderful message around the
world that we need to legalize it that
we need to stop this discrimination
against cannabis consumers in the
workplace the discrimination that
unfortunately is still going on people
take these P tests and then they can't
get a job and that's not right it's not
fair and it has nothing to do with
whether they can do a job or if they're
impaired on a job or anything it's just
outright discrimination and we have to
say no to drug testing
now Kevin also started he was also
involved with the million marijuana
marches that are still going on these
days around the world and this year I
got to go to to Australia and then been
there which is kind of like the cannabis
capital of Australia and I have you note
that the world is watching Washington
I'm from California we're watching
Washington and next year we're going to
legalize it in California and we're
going to do it hopefully we're going to
do it right we're going to learn from
some of your mistakes but still we still
honor you for your experiment here and
for what you're doing and hopefully
you'll all get involved in demand that
our rights are still respected that we
can do it the right way you know this is
all about equal rights for me it's
always been about equal rights cannabis
consumers deserve equal rights don't we
what do we want equal rights when do we
want it now what do we want when do we
want it what do we want equal rights
when do we want it now thank you so much
keep up the fight it's not over there's
still too many people in prison too many
people getting arrested we need to stop
at and bring freedom to the world but
we're watching and we really appreciate
it thank you everybody have a good
hempfest