it is time we stop arresting marijuana
smokers and there's three basic reasons
one is we're spending an estimated 10
billion dollars a year
chasing and arresting and prosecuting
otherwise law-abiding citizens simply
because when they relax in the evening
they prefer to smoke a joint that's
idiotic and it's a waste of law
enforcement resources
number two prohibition invites the
government into private areas of our
life that are simply inappropriate most
americans agree we don't want the
government coming into our house to know
what books we read uh the subject of our
of our music we listen to and certainly
we don't want them knowing and watching
our behavior in the bedroom well neither
do they have any places to get involved
in the decision as to whether we smoke
marijuana or drink alcohol when we relax
in the evening
now the good news
the good news is that when you ask the
public how they feel about marijuana
penalties you find that roughly 80
percent now say they support the right
of a serious ill patient to use medical
marijuana when a doctor recommends it 80
8 out of 10 americans
well then how come we've only won that
in 13 states for christ's sake it's
because we need to take that support and
convert it into public policy
we know now that 76 of the public three
out of four americans agree with us on
the basic premise
that you should not arrest and jail a
marijuana smoker 76 3 out of 4. so we
have largely won the hearts and minds
of the american public
our challenge is to convert that into
public policy by the way more recently
there was a poll taken nationwide by
zogby the normal commission that showed
52 percent of the public nationwide now
favor not just decriminalizing marijuana
but legalizing it legalizing it taxing
it regulating it like we do alcohol and
one survey by the field poll company in
california found 56
of the people in california now support
legalization so what does this all mean
well it means honestly we're about to
win this issue we're getting very close
to it
i think definitely in your lifetime i
hope in mine but within five years i
think we're going to stop arresting
marijuana smokers in this country and
the first few states are going to begin
to experiment with legally regulated
markets
justice anthony kennedy in writing for
the majority in the u.s supreme court
recently in a case
said the following at the heart of
liberty
is the right to define one's own concept
of existence of meaning of the universe
and of the mystery of the human life it
is the promise of the constitution that
there is a realm of personal liberty
where the government may not enter
well as i said when i started there's
absolutely nothing wrong with the
responsible use of marijuana by adults
and it is of no interest to the
government and they should stop
arresting and start respecting marijuana
smokers
in the end we are only accidentally
talking about marijuana we are really
talking about personal freedom
join normal stand-up legalize marijuana
thank you
right on keith