in in the uh '90s we were making hemp
oil in Ohio with Chinese seeds and it
got pretty
popular and then we started taking the
seed cake the waste product and making
hempen ale out of it and that got so
popular that we were producing oil 24/7
around the clock and I ended up with
6,000 extra barrels 6,000 extra gallons
of oil cuz we were making it for the
seat cake at that point so that became
the oil that powered the hemp car coming
out here 10 years ago if you recall at
Hempfest we had a one of the first
biodel powered cars was here running on
hemp fuel we powered Woody helson's bus
from uh down the West Coast in the
further movie starting here in Seattle
and going down the coast most of them
riding the bicycles but with the bus
following them up and so we proved a
long time ago that we can do this we ran
the the generators here on biodiesel one
year hemp biodiesel it can be done uh
it's extremely convertible but yeah
that's right the there's a lot more
energy in the hemp plant than just the
oil and there's actually a man here
named aguadas he's here at hempest I saw
him last night and he's got a patent for
pyrolization in a in a new way that is
uh very promising for turning much more
of the hemp plant into energy source I I
I kind of discourage
H for energy cuz it's so expensive why
would you take $40 a gallon oil and burn
it up in your car but pyrolization gives
us the opportunity to actually create
fuel economically and it's coming