you know I think that marijuana is our
mother earth
greatest gift to mankind produces more
fuel more fiber and more food than any
other plant on the planet
and marijuana prohibition has never
really been about drugs marijuana
prohibition was always about money power
and the continued centralization of
Economic and political control
the whole marijuana myth was made up to
displace petroleum at five and uh tree
fiber and [ __ ] fiber they couldn't have
made hip illegal if they said it was him
they couldn't have made uh any of that
illegal unless if they said it was
Cannabis they could have made it illegal
it was only by taking this new word
marijuana and using that with raises
propaganda that they were able to
prohibit it so here we have prohibited
the most productive play it on the
planet the one that is also the oldest
cultivated crop all archaeologists
Scream It's been cultivated for at least
ten thousand and maybe over 30 000 years
it's the very basis of Agriculture
itself
so
we've got the most productive crop and
the oldest crop and now we have a
limited legalization with the initiative
here where you can have house but that's
not enough you folks have to realize we
all are going to have to remain active
remain Vigilant and contact our
political Representatives side petitions
we need to change the law even though
it's a better law it's not good enough
until our Farmers could cultivate Health
without regard to its THC content but
with a focus on the most productive
varieties of seed for fiber and all the
various uses of animal until that
happens it's going to be prohibitively
expensive
so when we allow Farmers to cultivate
hip without regard to its THC content
we'll begin to displace petroleum our
Farmers could get that money instead of
the electrochemical pharmaceutical
military industrial transdational
corporate Elite fascist sons of a
[ __ ] that run the world today and
give us the words for oil
we don't need the petroleum you know
everything petroleum touches it makes
toxic
if it's a natural alternative and we
could give the money to our Farmers it's
not going to give to the Swiss bank
accounts and the uh despots around the
world
we need to restore him so I just urge
you guys to get involved don't settle
for the status quo and help us restore
hip thank you