we favor the elimination of all
penalties for the responsible use of
marijuana including the right to grow
your own marijuana and we further favor
the eventual legalization of marijuana
consumers want the same thing consumers
want in any other area we want a high
quality product that's affordable and
convenient and so we support eventually
full legalization I want to be able to
drive down to the local store and buy
some marijuana I want it to be tested I
want to know the strength of CBD THC and
I want to make make sure it doesn't have
any additives to it or pollutants in it
so we are the marijuana smokers Lobby in
America now the bad news is that we're
still arresting 850,000 Americans a year
on marijuana charges there's another
marijuana smoker arrested every 38
seconds uh there have been more than 20
million Marijuana arrest just since
1965 and the real problem with that
policy is unlike alcohol where the
government differentiates between use
and abuse they don't arrest you if
you're an adult for using alcohol it's
only if you abuse it yet for marijuana
they act as if all use is abuse well
[ __ ] of course it's not so we need
to make that
distinction marijuana prohibition for
two or three basic reasons is incredibly
self-destructive first off we're wasting
something like9 to 10 billion a year in
law enforcement resources chasing
marijuana smokers when they should be
focused on serious and violent crime
secondly prohibition invites the
government into the privacy of your own
home where they know what books you read
they know what music you listen to uh
they know whether you how you conduct
yourself in the privacy of the bedroom
and they they know whether you drink
alcohol or smoke marijuana when you
relax in the evening that's offensive to
the concept of right to privacy the
government has no business knowing
whether we smoke or why we
smoke so where does that leave us well
the good news is that we've got three
National polls that show we now enjoy a
the support of a majority of the
American public the gallop pole the year
we founded normal we only had 12%
Nationwide now we have 50% Galla poll
only 46% oppos a new r M poll I think
had 56% support a third poll had 52%
those are nationwide folks we have
largely won the hearts and minds of the
American people there was a Supreme
Court decision and I want to read this
simply because I don't want to get the
language raw uh a couple of years ago in
which
oops Justice Anthony Kennedy in the case
called
um Lawrence Fe Texas said the following
at the heart of Liberty is the right to
Define one's own concept of existence of
meaning of the universe and of the
mystery of human life it is a promise of
the Constitution that there is a realm
of personal Liberty where the government
may not enter well folks we're about to
legalize marijuana you people in
Washington have an especially big role
to play there you vote for 502 and we're
going to send a message to Washington
that you don't have any choice but to
rethink your marijuana policy because
there going to be a number of states are
saying the hell with you we're not going
to enforce it but in the end we're only
incidentally talking about marijuana
we're really talking about personal
freedom that area where government may
not go support 502 let's finally
legalize marijuana in America