I want to talk about something that I
think not many people here aware of is
that the there is another industrial
hemp farming act in Congress and it was
introduced in May by representative ron
paul and it already has more co-sponsors
that we've ever had on an industrial
hemp farming act a bill this is the
leave the third bill that has been
introduced by representative ron paul
and that's because the hard work of a
group called vote hemp all right so vote
HAP is a pretty much single issue
focusing just on the industrial hemp
side of things that Eric stienstra who
is the president of boat him this year
finally got on board with some of us
who've been urging for longer than more
than a year that it's time to hitch our
star to moving medical and recreational
legislation and so we've worked with the
proposition folks in California and
Colorado here in this state we're
including industrial hemp now as a as a
as comes under the will come under the
same initiatives and legislation that's
moving around the country work this is a
new strategy honestly the last 10 years
surprisingly we've worked totally
separate people working on medical
corporate people working on industrial
I've worked separately and I think the
big change in the last 12 months since
we were sitting on the stage a year ago
is that there's a new openness towards
including industrial hemp with what
really is a more popular issue and there
is medical cannabis recreational
cannabis marijuana you know in the East
Coast if you say cannabis people's eyes
glaze over they actually don't know what
you're talking about there's there's
something trying to be quite a bit of
ignorance still as to what do you even
is in what is cannabis you say marijuana
you'd ninety-five percent of people know
you're talking about so I'm just going
to say that you know there is a the East
Coast deficit of knowledge on this issue
and what our biggest challenge is is to
continue to educate politicians that
goes that go to Washington to write laws
that this is a safe issue the industrial
hemp issue and it's probably now the
whole issue is safe it's not just
industrial hemp it's it's mad
Michael it's even the idea of just tax
and regulate so i'll leave it there and
but we there is this bill in congress
and industrial hemp farming act and I
really hope if you're you haven't
already called your Congressman in the
last month you haven't been calling
enough so give them a call or her a call
and ask them to support that though
thank you so much