I'm working on a project uh the hemp
North American Industrial Hemp commodity
Board of
Trade so that parties can uh to set up a
foundation for investment in hemp to
establish uh uh information on the
prices of August hemp fiber August uh
seeds October seeds um to set up the
mechanisms for that we're looking
to do projects that will bring
everything together there's one thing
that was changed in the law since
1937 there was one item that was
deleted from the marijuana portion which
was the provisions for the federal
government to license Industrial Hemp
farming that's right and under the US
constitution rights that are not taken
by the federal government revert back to
the individual or to the local
governments