hey it's morgan fox i'm the
communications manager at the marijuana
policy project um
i really just kind of want to talk about
the television for a little bit um
national
tv is probably one of the most important
uh media
outlets that we can go after just
because it gets the most number of views
uh clips from national tv are the ones
that get posted on blogs and get spread
around a lot more that's what really
grabs people's attention and we've
definitely come a long way in getting
access to national media i mean um
in 2002 uh one of my predecessors uh
tried to call cnn to pitch a story and
uh the receptionist had to put him on
hold because she couldn't stop laughing
and when she brought him back uh her
response was all right mr marijuana what
should i
say uh you want to talk about
and uh
in 2008 they were calling us i mean
we've really come a long way but now
that we have access to it uh it's
becoming a
very much a double-edged sword
it's become harder to control the uh the
messaging and uh
harder to get stories pitched the way
that we really want them to uh because i
mean quite frankly the media cares about
drama they don't care about facts they
don't care about truth all they care
about is what's going to get the most
views and for that they want drama and
conflict so
the trick is to try to get these guys to
focus on the conflicts that we want them
to as opposed to the conflicts that
they find the easiest and the way that
we do that is i mean first developing
relationships with producers to make
sure that we can pitch them the type of
stories that we need to but also by
creating our own conflicts so that we
can control the messaging that means uh
calling out legislators in public forums
so that uh people will start to uh you
know ask questions and uh you know maybe
put them on the spot a little bit they
love it when politicians are embarrassed
and start scammering
we all do yeah
um
instead of them
just waiting for them to find their own
stories and going after things like
conflicts within uh ballot initiative
campaigns or conflicts within the
movement or
you know that
that one dispensary owner who's got a
bunch of ak-47s in the back you know
we need to get them to focus on the
conflicts that we want them to because
those are the juicy stories they don't
really care about uh you know how this
bill is going along unless there's some
sort of hook
and uh as we like move forward and try
to get uh more and more media coverage
for this uh really i mean we can't find
anybody that's going to debate us on
this issue anymore and i've tried uh
so many times i'll be talking to uh
producers and they say well we want to
do a segment on this but we can't find
anybody to uh beat the other side of the
debate i'll do it
masquerade as a drug warrior nice job
well what about the children
absolutely um but uh those are the
things that we need to really
concentrate on uh creating conflicts
that the media wants uh to look at and
that means we have to really try to go
out there and embarrass the people that
are working against us but of course in
like a polite way um right no cream pies
yeah
but uh i mean that's really all i've got
uh if anybody has any questions