who are some of your greatest
Inspirations in our movement I mean it
doesn't have to be someone that's hemp
related but who who gets you going well
frankly one of the best examples of a of
a really valuable committed activist
that I know in the entire country is
Vivian Peak who puts his place on I I
don't know of anyone who works any
harder it's all volunteer labor he's
done for 20 years he's had some health
problems nothing holds them back um and
it's the biggest of marijuana protest in
the world and uh I I it's my favorite
day of the year it used to be two days
now it's three days but my favorite trip
of the year I love forward to so Vivian
would be somebody who stands out to show
what one person could do um I'll I I
would I don't want to be unfair to
people there's lots of people that
contributed um but I think the people
that deserve the most credit right now
are the people that are pushing us
Beyond medical use into full
legalization um and so I I really admire
the efforts undergoing right now in
Colorado Washington Oregon California
and Massachusetts to get initiatives on
the ballot to legalize marijuana in all
five states