i know what i'm
doing he held that truth like a fist
full of lightning
put it out in the world and he let it go
and it went viral out in the cyber space
until nobody could say that they didn't
the truth will get you arrested
but what you don't know will kill you
the truth will get you the rest
should have seen him popping off socks
in the helicopter
has it hovered over here
should have seen the figures on the
ground looking run for cover tangled in
the wounded and dead
it wasn't like they said it was gonna be
there were no heroes in the white house
and those people on the ground they
weren't even soldiers they were
civilians what do you think about
that what you don't know
it came for bradley manning
put him in a little white room where the
light was always on
and then locked the door behind him he
said we're going to give you justice
until the justice is all gone
trooper get you arrested
secrets on the field around the big
machine
the secrets of the poison over history
secrets are a power that a lot could be
seen
behind mystery
that what you don't know can kill you
the truth will get you
and what you don't know can kill you
the truth will get you arrested
they say that history is written by the
victims who define it and then they nail
it down
the other history of the wheel
and wheels spin around
you can't hide away forever you know
sooner or later somebody's gonna see
and chelsea manning with a whistle
and that makes her a hero to me
now what you don't know can kill you
get you arrested