thank you very much
Hest we are born of nature and in nature
we will die oh and if we don't make it
it's not because we didn't try no it's
not because we didn't
try they say they will incorporate the
world oh my dead body Over My Dead Body
Over My Dead Body of
M they have all the money but we have
the will and I would rather be a match
than a paper dollar bill yes I would any
day yes I would
they have the guns all we are is flesh
and blood but we will multiply our
numbers and drown them in our flood yes
we will yes we
will they say they will incorporate the
world Over My Dead Body over dead body
over dead body
over
they have all the power that's what they
say but we will turn those Tangles take
their power away yes we will yes we will
we will not be dissuaded and we will not
turn around we will face those
barricades and we will tear them now yes
we will yes we will everybody sing come
on they say they will incorporate the
world Over My Dead Body Over My Dead
Body Over My Dead Body over
my
you can't call me a fool that's all
right with me I will live this see this
good round world breaking free yes I
will yes I
will they say they will incorporate the
world Over My Dead Body Over My Dead
Body Over My Dead Body over mind one
more time they say they will incorporate
the world oh my de body Over My Dead
Body Over My Dead Body over
my