I'd much rather be here listening to
Bobby plator and talk than to be talking
here on his behalf but unfortunately our
prohibition policies are such that you
cannot even educate as to an alternative
you cannot even teach people there's
another way to think about this issue so
unfortunately I'm here and Bobby's not
but what Bobby's message is is critical
to winning this issue if you care about
this if you care about being a to come
outside go by the Waterfront use
marijuana publicly with your friends
with your family without fear of
provocation without fear of harassment
then you need to be involved in the
issue of ending prohibition and if you
are a senior you need to be involved in
this issue I will say it once we cannot
win this issue without seniors on
board we cannot win this issue without
seniors on board so you right here if
you have grandparents if you have
parents if you have family friends you
cannot be afraid to approach them and
talk to them about this issue you have
to be a voice you have to educate
yourself you have to educate your
parents you have to educate your
grandparents because they vote they
donate they give money they have
influence and if they get on board this
thing will happen it will happen in
Oregon it will happen in Colorado and it
will happen in Washington and after this
November we'll go after the rest of the
states in this Union we'll legalize
marijuana in the United States of
America
yeah so get involved go to the
silver.org the silver.org that's what
Bobby plator is doing that's why he
can't be here right now he's an educator
he's reaching out to seniors he put
together a road show it's the hippest
road show on the senior circuit I'm
pretty damn
sure he goes to senior citizen homes he
goes to retirement centers he goes to
community centers he goes to churches
and he says you have been misled your
entire lives that's right you have been
lied to your entire lives and you have
believed it because it was not your
fault you didn't know better listen to
Fox new that's right and here's what you
got to do you got to get educated go to
the silver tour encourage it give it
money go to the Oregon measure 80
website OCTA 2012.org get educated give
money help us out this is an issue
battle this is a war we are fighting and
if we cannot win right now we are going
to be set back this is an absolutely
critical time you are living in historic
times you are living in a moment of
history in the United States of America
we ended prohibition of alcohol last
century because it was a bad policy that
created organized crime we have to end
prohibition of marijuana in the 21st
century because it's a bad policy and
it's bad for Americans so get involved
go to the silver.org go to OCTA 2012.org
get educated reach out to your parents
reach out to your grandparents don't be
afraid if you show courage they'll show
courage and together we can legalize
marijuana in the United States thank you