hey hey guys this LK I'm here at Seattle
Hempfest with the man himself he drop
again thank you for that the founder of
normal guys so the world's oldest
marijuana
smok it's so what do you think of the
event it's bigger every year I love the
H Fest uh I I made a special effort to
come out again this year I wasn't sure I
was going to come and I started thinking
about it I think I've been 14 of the
last 15 and it is the world's largest
Pot Festival and it is fabulous I mean I
I love the people I love the event uh I
I hope never to miss it very ni very
well I know that uh you've been to a few
of them so the crowd last yesterday
what' you think it was just crazy oh
massive massive crowds and uh the think
that it's pulled together by volunteers
if people think you can't still do
effective political organizing on the
local level I mean this is I think their
budget is something like a half a
million dollar for this event and it is
totally run by volunteers no one gets
paid a time and it is beautifully
organized so uh Vivian mque and all the
good F Folks at hest uh you do great
work it's uh you make us proud as
Stoners uh we really are finally winning
this it's not that we're tricking people
we have a majority of support in the
entire country now that supports
legalizing marijuana when normal was
founded Gall of hold just under first
question on legalization and we only
enjoyed 12% support in the entire
country so uh all that hard work people
have done out there has paid off folks
when their hearts mind