volunteers thank you for this incredible
part that you can throw it for 24 years
and all we love you have to be a part of
it ever since and many guys have been to
the national anthem sometimes with chris
conroy air and Mickey lorises so video
goes the years but that's what it has
taken for this loss to be changing in
the country as they are kinky I am
celebrating my 40th anniversary of being
a medical marijuana patient and all I
can do is send the universe the Creator
on all of you because I would not have
any side today if you hadn't shown me
the way I was not a recreational small
purple folks I've made up for that since
yeah
make no mistake i am one of us we are
the largest segment in this world we
belong to every segment of society here
and abroad I have done every single
state in the United States was carried
out fiddle at Norway's that's about the
Netherlands and I've never been anywhere
but I haven't met beautiful people that
I consider my family all of you all of
the beautiful people of this planet
smoked cannabis or use cannabis oh
praise the Creator forgiving us cannabis
now we gotta am federal laws because
they're interfering with the planets
grow with the people developing they are
not accessing their endocannabinoid
system so they're no longer help us they
ought to be one of every three of us is
Harry so ganser there's an ability of
disease going on that can't be helped
now in the states for marijuana has
illegal we have dropped the dance by
overdoses from chemical drugs and that
is a blessing that we need to talk
forever we go because we need to change
the laws in more than half the country
already we have something going to not a
penny on 420 it's your mistake that
needs to change laws on 420 guys to
learn nobody Spencer betting on anything
except and cannabis marijuana that's it
Nora
Donnie on 420 don't forget it now about
the tour of overdoses it is my pleasure
to see how many people have gotten off
of those drugs and that you're all doing
well but do remember if you're getting
off of heart drops they are
pharmaceutically prescribed or otherwise
do not go cold turkey you got
responsibilities and work to do because
you may harm yourself or do touratech my
arm others around you please
irresponsible but keep up the good work
and guess selfless so that's a beautiful
but you need to get to your president ow
all of you and have your never served by
your relatives and your friends give him
so many words that he can't hide anymore
and he has to come out and son got
executive order that will restore
constitutional rights for the best part
of this society thank you keep up the
good work god bless your little too
scared of love always be your guiding
light love you I don't know if you know
what the Televi for many years is one of
the only people the United States it
gets a big can of joints from the
federal government mailed to her I meses
a prescription not our condemnation on
it is right fast for me to do it and I
am supposed to do it at least there we
do also big
they always part of a pilot / what year
did it start helping the seventh
anniversary of establishing and medical
advance for the sake of Mora who needs
help goes perfectly now they tell you
look Florida it's legal for marijuana
that's a lie there is a fancy both of my
kids but you still have to go to jail on
an attorney you need to change that to
all over the country I know you will
they've done it so far