hi everybody I'm meline Martinez I'm the
executive director of the Oregon
affiliate to National normal I'm on the
board of normal and I'm also the owner
and founder of the World Famous Cannabis
Cafe I don't know if you've heard about
it but it got a lot of news coverage
which was really exciting but in our
state we have a new Progressive um
measure on the ballot and it's measure
74 and John sjo back there I just want
to congratulate you for getting it on
the ballot John you worked hard
yeah yeah it's a regulated Supply system
for medical marijuana patients and
medical marijuana what a beautiful thing
that's how I became an activist because
I somebody told me know it Kaiser they
said no you can't have medical marijuana
because you don't have glaucoma cancer
or Aids well I don't take no for an
answer very well I'm a product of the'
60s the turbulent 60s a child of Dr King
and I don't take no for an answer I'm
one of those fiery Latinas that says oh
what do you mean no so anyway Kaiser
ended up giving me one of their first
letters saying that it was okay for me
to use medical marijuana and I have been
there since the implementation of the
Oregon medical marijuana act fighting in
one way or another to make sure that
patients rights were not stepped on
trampled on and we've actually be been
able to uh get 24 o of storage marijuana
we started out with three which was
laughable because how do you control a
plant with three you know make sure that
you only have 3 o well we fought every
step of the way we finally got um in
2007 24 o of usable marijuana which was
a huge success for all of us believe me
it was amazing to be able to have that
much at the legislature we sat down and
we spoke with law enforcement they had
been after the affirmative defense for
years and they were going to come and
take it and give us nothing in return
and regulate it to the point where there
was only one growth for per residence so
that wasn't going to happen but you know
I found that uh legislator legislators
are actually really nice people if you
sit down and talk to them they have
stories as well so please I I always
tell people you got to get involved like
Douglas and Brian and everyone else you
got to get down there and you got to let
them know who you are and we teach you
know patients and other members of
normal
how to use those tools effectively how
to make sure that they go and they make
contact with these people of course like
everyone else my dream is legalization
and um boy I really am excited Douglas
about your language and I'd like to see
if we can do it in Oregon with you
because I think it's going to take the
whole country yeah we're going to have
to unite and get this taken care of
because although medical marijuana is a
beautiful thing in my state people are
losing their jobs every day because of a
dirty UA I mean it's just not acceptable
they're losing their children their
children are being taken away from them
in dirty custody battles where someone
says you use medical marijuana I mean I
can't even tell you if someone tried to
take my child for me I would not be able
to breathe and so to think that someone
can take your child from you even though
you've applied for the protections
afforded to you is just not acceptable
anymore that's why I say it's time for
us to all stand up put the joint down
away from your bong just for a little
while I mean I've been smoking since I
was 16 and I'm not going to put it down
I'm going to smoke until the day that I
die I'm looking for somebody to hook me
up with one of those oxygen uh things so
I can just vaporize through the little
nostril part you know when I get too old
but no I'm going to and I think it's
important for all of us you know uh
Douglas was just talking about hemp and
I watch Jack har as emperor of hemp may
he rest in peace and actually tattooed
it on my arm I always I always wanted a
big tattoo and I've got Tai ma the first
character for H Ma on my arm and and
that man was a hero to me and he made me
the hemp activist I am today because
America's roots are hemp Roots our
financial our foundation our economy
actually used hemp in it and why aren't
we using why aren't we going back to
those roots I hear people constantly
touting oh our Founders our found our
founders were hemp Farmers because they
were smart enough just like birds to eat
the hemp seed you know when you think
about it birds are more intelligent than
our Congress people than our own
government they'll eat those hemp seeds
first and we need to make that clear to
our to our Congress we need to make that
clear to President Obama we have hemp
fuel no other Americans should go die
for a foreign fuel we can we can grow it
in our country the residue from that
fuel once it's pressed is H flower rich
in the omegas I mean we all fight for
this and we we must continue to move
forward in our state we're lucky enough
that our Senator Floyd pansy actually
passed legislation where hemp is now
something that's acceptable it's the law
in the state of Oregon but of course
those pesky feds we're waiting for their
approval as always with everything and
that's why I think Douglas's approach to
marijuana may I ask you I'm just going
to ask this public because I've asked
other people as an attorney if we
legalize marijuana isn't hemp then legal
in some states yes and in some states
know um our initiative removes ambiguity
but a lot of states have measures in
place that if the federal government
changes its stance on hemp um or on hemp
permits that they can go immediately I
know kck's one I know North Dakota's one
um so there are some states that are
ready to go in the way they've defined
the marijuana plant um um so yeah there
are some states that would be it would
be legal the minut at the feds say so
excellent so I'm going to stop using the
word regulate now I got a good lesson
just like the rest of you no more
regulation we're just going to legalize
that's the new term and I don't know
what what what we can say because when
you say the word legalization it really
does scare a lot of people and when you
say the TA the word tax that frightens
them even more they just want to turn
around and run away because that's it's
scary to think of being taxed again
especially in this economic time but I
think that when we look at our economy
and if we look at the fact that in the
state of Oregon for us 350,000
oregonians consume cannabis on a regular
basis according to government statistics
so if we look at that as in an economic
from an economic perspective it seems
like with medical marijuana patients
we're targeting the wrong population
segment of the population we should be
targeting that
350 you know thousand people or more and
get this get these jobs going we need
green jobs hey they don't get much
greener than growing pot I actually went
to one of my legislators and said you
know I used to work in a women's prison
and we have all this property in there
and I said why don't we use that land
and we have all these wonderful students
that know how to grow why don't we grow
marijuana for the patients in the in the
prison Security's there you know some
people have said I was crazy I'm well
maybe I am a little crazy maybe I am a
dreamer you know but I think that we can
make it all work with all the money we
spend on the prison system let's get
something in return don't you think I
mean why not uh Jeff Merkley now is one
of our Congress people and but he did he
had the conversation with me at least he
was open enough to have that
conversation people aren't always trying
to get into prison so when and it's not
easy to get out I can tell you for one
thing so uh hey why not but uh anyway uh
I am uh pushing it every way I can to
make sure that we let people know that
we are just like myself I'm just a
normal mom blazing the Oregon Trail
every day trying to make it work for
everybody everybody needs to be
recognized as cannabis consumers not
just patients we have veterans with PTSD
and they're they don't qualify in our
state and it's a shame when you look at
those people going and risking their
lives for us and we cannot even afford a
medic IAL marijuana you know that's what
we all fight for the people that can't
have it those of us who are lucky enough
should I say degenerative discon joint
disease I don't know if you want to
count that as lucky but I get to have a
medical marijuana card but what about
the veterans that don't what about the
lady who lost her children so we must
legalize as soon as possible please join
normal thank you
[Applause]