yeah what up
Seattle y'all ready to do some
hip-hop y'all want to hear some
[ __ ]
hip-hop just throw your hands in the a
get them up like you don't care let me
hear you say
yeah say hell
yeah just wave your hand in the sky get
them up like way your
P
yeah say hell
yeah many charge go wires in my
garage suppos be crazy so for the 80s
looking at that your lady why she look
like gr Shady business want to stop and
look at my profile nigg like me cing go
Kango hatch and AR style skills I get up
time my rhy qule St my je to C that food
in time
with bad Aim F I'm going to live forever
Never Say Die that black ey with a black
f with a trip Dad y' look at my watch I
got to shake this spot so P look at this
[ __ ] with Styles look his name is Kum
it's theom me to watch out holy cow I'm
got couple of signs from these trees day
that I became an MC it was the day that
I became the super was the day that I
became the Superman what the Superman
the day that I became the super was the
day that I became the Superman Superman
the day that I became the super what's
the day that I became the Superman what
a Superman the day that I became the
super I'm your idol like Michael so
won't you beat it I'm better like
Shredder I join the foot now I can't be
defeated been treated MC like I was the
80s my style is tigh than what suit on
255 lb L maybe maybe not maybe you
should check that pop this in your day
deck play me in your cassette on Channel
7 News 11 watches who get hurt confused
in the Christian reading the Bible in
the Muslim Church come down to earth now
ask yourself is it worth losing your
title and the right recital I've been
vital since my birth and get faded cuz
they overrated if you lasted two rounds
would have get blasted you Lu you made
I'm the most hated them see like The
Omen you'll be out like last year
looking like jary colan no man no
children no woman man H with the super I
got the West Coast so up I blow up your
spot troop ain't no too tell I can you
you get loose hope that you get used to
Lo so shut up and start think before I
leave you for my M you send me swing the
day that I became a super the day that I
became a Superman what a Superman the
day that I became a super
yeah clap your hands everybody everybody
just clap your hands come on clap your
here is everybody everybody just clap
your head come on come
on we at here we at
here come on come on here
F we at here F we at here say
he say
he St
him St
him wave your hands in get you don't
care [ __ ] say
yeah say hell
yeah super run away I got x-ray I watch
you like anyway we can do this all the
day I more people television back
today's top see you set up for sit down
to tell me about your down you come to
battle you get Dr you on the get you
back where you I don't care if you don't
like me go home and tell your friends
I'm the mighty
AKA also known as you call
[Music]
Superman I love you
Seattle hey this radio WS