all our supply chains are certified
organic and fair trade we super fat our
soaps with hemp seed oil hemp seed
imparts a real smoothness the louder
makes it less drying we've been fighting
since 2001 to Rica Mercia lies
industrial hemp farming in the United
States it's just incredible that we
can't grow you know non non drug
industrial hemp in this country this
country is the largest consumer market
for hemp seed and fiber products and you
know we continue to hand the largest
market for industrial hemp to the
Canadians to the Chinese the Europeans
it's a joke you know I mean we have a
president who alleges that he bases his
policy on science and reason unlike his
predecessor but we have the same they
all drug warriors driving policy under
this administration as as the previous
is every other administration and it's
an incredible incredibly disappointing
our family sponsored and successfully
fought off the DA's attempt to shut off
the imports of hemp seed oil ten years
ago after Jack's Jack Harris stroke in
2010 me and some comrades dug up the
DA's lon in Washington DC and planet
hemp seeds and you can you know look at
that online just recently you know here
we are the fourth year of Obama's term
still no ham I locked myself in a steel
cage in front of the White House and
harvested 12 hemp plants spent three
hours hanging the president about 30
cops and you know a huge crowd of people
about how ridiculous it is that our
government is making my family sent over
a hundred thousand dollars every year to
Canadians in the middle of a recession
you know what you know how [ __ ] is
it that we are still not Rica Mercia
lysing industrial hemp our family also
we don't just concentrate on hand we
give a lot of money to Americans for
safe access the primary group advocating
for medical marijuana we just gave them
dollars you've been supporting them from
the beginning to just drop fifty
thousand dollars on the Colorado
legalization efforts and on the
Washington effort you know we believe
it's an earthquake if we can get the
states to go if we get Colorado and
Washington to end cannabis prohibition
it will be huge and you know I realize
there's controversy here about it but
you know the larger picture is you know
don't let the perfect be the enemy of
the good and you know it'll be just such
an earthquake occurred around the world
we are we also just gave $100,000 to
maps multidisciplinary association of
psychedelic studies an amazing group you
know working to recover to integrate
psychedelics MDMA LSD back into society
in a responsible way you know myself
personally and you know a lot of people
here have found found cannabis and
psychedelics to be huge allies in our
pads you know to help us be more
compassionate and conscious taking this
goal of dr. bronner's 22 yeah I wrote on
so you know you know where you know the
our end game is you know we wanted for
years time to put another zero on those
on those contributions you know we're
growing rapidly we're five million
dollar company ten years ago we're 50
now we kept all executive compensation
521 you don't make any more money just
goes back into movement and so thank you
very much and yeah that's right what
yeah all one God pink here we go