our next speaker Donnie wsha is just one
of the pioneers of industrial hemp in
America he's an attorney he's a
businessman a philanthropist and he's a
long-standing Seattle Hempfest core
member give it up to my brother Donnie
wsha thank you
Seattle hey welcome to the house of Jack
Bill we would not be here hempest would
not be here were not for Jack rare is
that right yeah we owe it to Jack to do
something about this prohibition so I
want to tell you a story about a case
that's going on here in Washington
people haven't read about this in your
newspapers yet but listen to how
ridiculous the drug war gets while you
sit here comfortable in Seattle knowing
that our energy passed an initiative
that keeps the cops off our backs and
out of our pockets the rest of
Washington the rest of America suffers
so it isn't just winning an initiative
in Seattle it's going to get this
gorilla off our backs it's stopping this
whole damn drug war freeing our friends
in jail and starting over again with tax
and regulator whatever you want to come
up with just let's stop this present
chaos okay so listen to this and how bad
the DEA gets in this crazy state of ours
in Washington and if you work for the
DEA and you're sitting here in your tide
eyes today I want you to listen up extra
hard cuz this is about you
okay so we got a normal couple in
Washington the woman is really sick she
had Polio as a child has you know blown
up from that 400 lb gets surgery surgery
goes bad and she spends a month on the
operating table just to save her life
they had her in a coma for a month just
to save her she has no stomach anymore
from this right she's on a crazy diet
where she has to eat papaya all day long
to stay alive they're up there by the
Canadian border in the middle of nowhere
how do you get papaya they build a
greenhouse and filled the greenhouse
with Papaya plants and 2 years later
they got their sust and papayas coming
out of their
greenhouse and the DEA gets gets wind of
them of their sun growing pot in an
adjoining place and the DEA comes up in
the middle of the night with boats up
the
river sneaks on their farm with ninjas
guys in black black hoods I mean this is
how people get killed around here and
they sneak on the farm trying to find
the marijuana and can't find it but oh
there's a
greenhouse okay so they come back the
next day and they do that was what they
call a sneaking Peak okay and now their
technique was to do a knock and talk you
know where they come up and knock on
your front door oh hi we're just looking
for somebody and they look around and
whatever so they do the knock and talk
and they say we could smell marijuana
now these are licensed Washington
patients and that's not easy to be right
these are licensed Washington patience
but this is our federal government at
work so they go to the judge they don't
say anything to the judge about hey we
smelled marijuana at a licensed
Washington patients house they say we
smelled marijuana and that was their
probable cause to come in with
helicopters and 14 agencies 10 and some
officers to arrest this couple and their
31 plants that they were illegally
growing under Washington
law but that's that the tragic part the
tra the de comes in the greenhouse all
expecting to see a room full of
marijuana and find a room full of
papayas and what does the DEA do with
that room full of
papayas what they're taught to do
machete them down and carry them away so
all this work to keep this woman alive
is wasted by these guys tearing down
these papayas that take two years to
produce you know and and so this has
gotten really crazy this case the
husband went to court federal court had
a jury
trial where this is all going on but
because of the way the federal
government is schizophrenic about
medical
marijuana the judge orders that he can't
say anything about medical marijuana in
the trial and he says but wait a minute
it wasn't mine it was my wife's and and
and she's not being charged of course
she's so sick they can't charge her if
they if the jury saw how sick she was
they would let her go she got ordered to
come to court without her wheelchair CU
she wasn't allowed to look sick in front
of the jury we couldn't mention medical
they couldn't mention the fact that on
the wall of the Grove is all her medical
paperwork and her saying this is mine
I'm
responsible the husband being charged
with this crime couldn't even say it's
my
wife's that's how crazy this trial is so
now there are farmers up for forfeiture
they're going to have to go through all
these steps of appeal he lost his job on
and on and on it's just been a you know
from a family that was surviv and
they're going to kill these people and
this is this is our government okay so
you know I I want you to all think about
the hemp and and what it can do for us
but I want you to think about all these
people that we need to go to the aid and
help there's a lot of people out there
and just cuz we're comfortable here and
after years a work we can be comfortable
to it on this grass without having the
cops come in and grab us thank you cops
thank you everybody for being so kind
that we won this Victory here we have to
spread this Victory across the country
so help all these groups you see at
these booths go buy your hemp
clothes join something do something
about it cuz we are in a heap of trouble
these guys are not letting go very
easily thank you