hey thank you very much really pleased
to be here at Hempfest this is my first
Hempfest and I live in Detroit Michigan
and I am here to tell you first of all
Michigan has 200,000 medical marijuana
patients registered in less than 4 years
and so things are really happening in
Michigan Michigan has reciprocity if you
have a medical marijuana card from any
other state you're protected under
Michigan law up to 2 1/2 o of personal
possession and um well if you were
growing 12 plants so I was just telling
a story to somebody and when they called
me I said well I should tell this story
on stage it's kind of interesting so I'm
in Detroit I've been practicing
marijuana law for 25 years basically but
for the last 10 years I've really been
concentrating in it to the point where 5
years ago I had a straight marijuana
practice now at that time all the
marijuana law in Michigan was criminal
defense that's all we had unfortunately
felonies misdemeanors and by the way do
not consent to any searches right don't
ever do that so yeah Fourth Amendment so
uh I've been practicing criminal defense
law and then all of a sudden we get the
medical marijuana law and I had no idea
that was going to happen in Michigan but
I happen to be in the right place at the
right time timing is everything and so
um I jumped on that I formed the law
firm of cannabis Council and tomorrow
you'll probably see me wearing the
T-shirt with my logo so now there are
four lawyers in our law for a Canabis
Council and so uh we represent
dispensaries and uh businesses and also
people who've been busted unfortunately
but the story I was going to tell was
that we needed a home and so real estate
is cheap in Detroit I mean cheap so
they're giving stuff away so uh I was
lucky enough to find this building I
used to drive by it every day on my way
to work at this office I used to rent
and um they wanted a million dollars for
this building and um well I got it for
about you know a tenth of that but the
point of the story was this building
used to be a radio station and the radio
station in Detroit was
wwww and at that time it was a rock in
the 70s it was a rock and roll radio
station and in fact Howard Stern was a
DJ who got a start there in Detroit in
at W4 and the the the stern story is
that W4 changed their format one weekend
from Rock and Roll to Country and Howard
Stern came to work on Monday and said I
am not playing country music I quit Okay
well the short version is I ended up
buying that building and the studio
that's that they used as the broadcast
studio has turned into the medication
Lounge for our clients who are patients
so if you come to Detroit uh you can
come into the lounge there's a Steinway
grand piano in there in 1920 there's a
tuba a trombone a ukulele a harmonica a
guitar um that's actually a a six string
that I bought from for my 50th birthday
that I never learned to play and um
there are a couple other musical
instruments so I invite you all to come
to Detroit and to Michigan um but I'm
here as the representative of Michigan
normal I'm the executive director of
Michigan normal this year yeah right on
we need to legalize it you know some
people say oh we shouldn't have a lawyer
as a director of normal because H he'll
be out of a job if we legalize it so
he's working against his own interests
right yeah uhhuh so I can't get a job
doing anything else you know that's the
problem so anyway um here we are and
uh I'm I think we need to legalize it so
we started a petition drive this year um
we needed
323,000 signatures in Michigan uh we
ended up with 54,000 signatures I
mistakenly thought that volunteers would
get up and do this work to just repeal
prohibition but it doesn't happen that
way um I guess I'm not as good a
marketer as I need to be so we need to
raise a bunch of money we're planning to
do that in the next year or two and and
do it right um and we're looking for
Washington and Oregon and Colorado to
lead the way in legalizing marijuana so
that the rest of us so that we we can
see a wave across the country you know
I'm in Michigan which is just an island
in the middle between Rhode Island and
Oregon or Colorado there's there's not a
whole there aren't a whole lot of
medical marijuana friendly States yet
but you know Arkansas is on the ballot
this year and there are some other
states that are on the ballot this year
and we need to support that so everybody
needs to make sure that you're
registered get registered to vote and
vote to legalize it all right so I'm
looking forward to some really good
music here this afternoon thank you very
much I'm Matthew AEL from Michigan
normal and uh come on to Detroit it's
beautiful peace out you