so just said I'm Roger Goodman I'm the
state representative that chair of the
house Public Safety Committee in the
House of Representatives and Kennedy's
used to be in my jurisdiction they used
to be illegal but now it's in the
Commerce Committee Chair six which is
pretty cool and we now have not just the
Liquor Control Board the liquor and
cannabis for officially as of a few
weeks ago so a lot of changes happening
here in Washington helping to lead the
world again it's really sort of parallel
universes we cannot forget what's going
on in the rest of the country and some
are making more progress so that others
but I've washington needs to be careful
as we continue to lead the way but so
far I think it's it's doing well doing
well enough the market or commercial
market has a time to settle down we have
to worry about people who are truly
medically needy people who don't want to
take the toxic let your chemical
pharmaceuticals
and they depend on it and they need a
lot of it I don't smoke and vaporize it
in soil and digested and it's they don't
they can't afford it so I'm worried
about that in the legislature I'm going
to continue to be a voice to take care
of the truly medically needy on the
other hand we have not really on the
other hand another issue major issue is
the market itself this new legal market
or so far I think this is a showcase we
have a lot of flaws and yet with more
retail availability of a sort of a
supply a taxation that makes sense of a
quaint years to adjust we will again
show the world how it should be done so
the dam has burst cannabis prohibition
is over the war on marijuana is over and
we'll look back on history you know but
we were still fighting it and still cost
a lot and so forth but in the minds of
Americans it really analyzed the world
the war on marijuana is over so to
preside over that after having been a
drug policy reform her and when I got
elected oh they hit me hard he wants to
legalize marijuana blood vote went way
up after that after the people found out
the people are way ahead of the
politicians the opinion leaders and so
it's fun to be ahead of the curve and to
kind of say I told you so but we're
doing it right and so it's part I'm
proud to be a part of that so thank you
very much thanks to hook faster keep it
up keep up your voice