here are today at the 20th anniversary
Hempfest it gives me great pleasure to
introduce to you somebody who is a
champion of Freedom a champion of
Liberty and a champion of Justice
somebody who gets it somebody who says
you know what otherwise law abiding
Americans shouldn't go to jail for
marijuana he is our own Seattle City
attorney his name is Pete Holmes give
him an incredible amount of respect he
to talk to
you happy 20th birthday
Hest what a great
institution hey John hey three
generations if you're from if you're
from Seattle say hi to everybody who's
from out of state welcome to
Seattle I'm Pete Holmes Vivian thanks
for the kind words I'm your City
attorney I want to tell you a couple of
things that I learned when I came to
office Seattle gets it Seattle
understands Seattle is very smart and
yet we couldn't explain why when I took
office of the marijuana possession
charges that were in the hopper ready to
go why were 59% nearly 60% of them
against
African-Americans this city has a
population 8% African-American and 59%
of our marijuana possession arrest when
I took office January 1
2010 were against
African-Americans we know that the War
on Drugs is a
failure and we know that Seattle voters
recognize this and want to make a
difference and hefest is where we're
getting the message out so thank you all
for being
here we have we have this year
signatures are being gathered for new
initiatives there's at least two going
now one that I'm
sponsoring
502 is to legalize regulate and tax for
adult recreational
use it it deals with all of the issues
that we're all confronting
here but in my office we're working
every day we're not going to prosecute
simple possession and we're going to
work to make sure that until it's
legalized for everyone
that we found a way for sick people to
get the medicine they
need there's good in the neighborhood
we've worked we've worked really hard
and the good news is guys A legislature
this year with Republicans and Democrats
passed a comprehensive medical marijuana
bill we almost got there the governor
made a mistake vetoed a lot of it
but don't let that don't let that we're
going to be back in the legislature
again don't let that over overshadow the
fact that a bipartisan legislature
passed a great Bill to get medical
marijuana
out good in the neighborhood we're going
to work on all fronts to make sure that
ultimately adult recreational use is
legal and we're going to do that by
making sure we we work together
that we marijuana reformers are going to
all work together remember we're trying
to get to the same place if you see two
petitions sign two petitions sign 505
sign 502 let's move forward together
let's work together we're looking for
the same
goal in the meantime my office is going
to continue to work to make sure that we
have sane and rational prosecutions
we're not Prosecuting these cases and
we're going to work to make sure that we
change the law in the meantime thank you
so be safe be safe be good to each other
and remember we're all working together
for the same purpose thanks
everybody the greatest City attorney in
the world as far as I'm concerned
Seattle City attorney Pete Holmes did
you hear that he's not Prosecuting for
possession of marijuana in the city of
Seattle did you hear that