hey you know marijuana is the most
important plant on this
planet it is produces more fuel from its
seed more fiber from its stem more
medicine from its flowers and leaves uh
than any other plant and that's the
reason it was made illegal it was really
the petrochemical pharmaceutical
military industrial transnational
corporate Elite fascist sons of a
[ __ ] who made up the mar
Miss they said there's this thing out
there marijuana that causes us to go
crazy and kill our family and friends
what could be more [ __ ] than that
you know no you can drive your car on
pure hip seed oil and that's the reason
it is
illegal so you know finally we've got
some limited legalization here in
Washington you can possess an ounce but
you can't grow your own that's not good
enough we need to be able to grow our
own plants we need to grow the plant
that is the most productive plant on the
planet maybe the plant from which
agriculture was founded it might be the
oldest crop all archaeologists agree
it's been cultivated at least 12,000
years you should be able to grow
it register to vote there's an i
739 petition Booth right over there we
need you to sign those petitions even
better get some petitions and get other
Washington registered voters to sign
them because that's how we make change
if it wasn't for that they'd be throwing
us all in jail
still we don't want that to happen
obviously you know the legislature
passed a bad law 5052 to curtail medical
marijuana but I have a series of clinics
where we have helped over aund ,000
Washington residents get their medical
marijuana permit over a qu million
Americans so far and those people are
able to legally possess use and grow
marijuana but the state has curtailed
that they're saying you can grow 15
plants till next July but next July you
can only grow four here's a petition
right here so we urge you guys to get
these petitions sign them and pass them
around because that's the only way we're
going to be able to change these laws
and contact your legislature because
that's another way to have
input anyway Washington voters you know
420 is coming up this is probably the
most fun place to be at that special
time so hey it's only about 15 minutes
away so stay tuned for that but uh I
just want to thank you all for coming
out here support the Seattle hip Fest
fight for the changes that need to
happen and uh restore him