[Music]
Ro me
spliff yes I'd love to have a
whip twist me up a
but so I can rub this in
D me up a
do with be rocking in deep deep Grove if
you just
[Music]
rolling time to get yourself up on this
in one way PL and let your heart to the
B I mean we're speaking Fus feeling so
what the what the anyway hey me a
SP yes I'd love to check me whip
TST me up
above so I can rub this
up break us up a
do with be rocking in the deep deep gr
when you just
[Music]
rolling
[Applause]
[Music]
n
a
[Music]
oh
w
[Music]
GRE
time to get yourself up on this hill One
Way blank and let your heart do the pain
I mean we're speaking for our freedom so
hey what the what the anyway say throw
me a
SPL yes I'd love to have a
wh whis me up
a so I can love
this bring me up a
goop with be rocking in a deep deep gr
y'all just
[Music]
[Laughter]
rolling
[Music]
a
you