this is such an amazing event as I was
up here on the stage watching that
Divine cloud with smoke come over this
beautiful crowd you were all so
beautiful so beautiful in all of your
diversity and all of your difference I
look out on this crowd I see people of
every age and every
ethnicity I see people that come from
all over from every place from far and
wide and we're all United by our love
for this plant and by our understanding
of one truth that the cannabis plant is
a good plan not an evil plan
[Music]
right you know I remember the last the
first first few hemp fests when there
were just hundreds of people here didn't
stay that way though did it grew to
hundreds thousands tens of thousands of
people
and now we have a movement that's
progressed and mirrored the growth of
this event in 17 States across the
country we have medical cannabis laws
and from the east coast to the West
Coast from north to south from Michigan
to Colorado from New Jersey all the way
here to
Washington patients are now able to
access their medicine in safe
compassionate well-regulated
dispensaries and access
points but that's not all that we've
done right we've also created tens of
thousands of well-paying jobs and
hundreds of millions of dollars of tax
revenue for our communities we've
reduced the burden on law enforcement
and we've made our neighborhoods
safer but the folks in the justice
department for some reason don't think
that those are good things oh yeah so
last year they launched an attack on our
community that attack started out in
Michigan and Montana and when we didn't
notice when we didn't respond when there
was no outcry they expanded it to
California and now they've closed over
400 over 400 dispensaries access points
have been closed in California in the
past
year just last week Harborside Health
Center received notices that the
government intends to seiz the property
that we're located in because we're
serving our
patients but we have no intention of
closing our
doors no way we're never ever going to
abandon our
patience we have nothing to hide and we
have Justice on our side we look forward
we look forward to our day in court when
we intend to teach the justice
department the federal government a
lesson that they are never going to
forget
you know unfortunately I have to tell
you that this cancer is now spread to
Washington and to Oregon just uh last
week four letters went out from us
attorneys in the eastern part of the
state threatening to seize properties
and a bunch more in
Oregon so they're trying to do the same
thing here that they did in California
but we're not going to let them do that
are
we no way no way instead of crushing us
they're going to rise us to righteous
Fury
[Music]
[Applause]
right so I'm happy to tell you that
we've had tremendous support pull in
from all quarters around the country
after harbor side was served including a
really great takeover of the Obama
headquarters here by activists in
Seattle so thank you Seattle for turning
out and supporting us there at the Obama
office right we're all pulling together
with a common message to send to the
president that it's time it's time for
him to keep the promise that he made to
us it's time for him to call off these
Rogue prosecutors it's time for them to
end their horrible campaign because why
because we're not going anywhere
right no way we've come too far and
we've worked too hard and we've made too
much progress to turn back now
right we are going to continue this
battle until we win it we came out of
the shadows and into the light 16 years
ago and we're never going back to that
place of Shadows again are we I know
we've come out of the shadows and into
the light and that's where we're staying
thank you