well welcome
the gasification 101.
oh in 1990 Don and I became the first
people pressing hemp seed oil
in the United States since 1937.
from all of what Jack was saying I
thought
lots of people are already doing it
turned out we were pioneers
the hemp is grown primarily for the
nutritious seed as is the
flaxseed and I in the past considered
flax a competitor to him but the both of
them have an incredibly similar history
the energy in the hemp herds
is about 8 000 BTUs per pound on a
moisture and Ash free basis
the gasification equipment
does pyrolysis followed by gasification
pyrolysis is where the plant material is
heated to turn it into charcoal and
about half of the energy is in the solid
charcoal at the end of pyrolysis and the
other half is in the gases and the tars
that burn off in the making of the
charcoal
so my gasification technology takes
those tars which would gum up an engine
and it turns them into a tar free gas
which can be readily cleaned up and run
an engine
we can take what we can take the
charcoal as a solid before it's gasified
you put it in the soil
and it makes biochar and wood will rock
and if we don't do anything with wood or
hemp herds or plant materials the soil
organisms will burn them into CO2 and
water vapor just as if we had used them
and burned them ourselves
but if we can do work
with our gasifier that prevents the use
of petroleum fossil fuels
we can have a major benefit on the
climate because the energy that's spewed
out by a hundred gallons of gasoline is
one full ton of CO2 greenhouse gas is
spewed out for each 100 gallons of
gasoline
if you want to know what your you know
your carbon footprint is look at it in
terms of how many gallons you burn
that's a big part of it