I've been working with the safer shirts
ever since I read the book marijuana is
safer so why are we driving people to
drink by Steve Fox Paul armano Mason
tvert with forward by retired Seattle
police chief Norm
Stamper I'm an occupational safety and
health
professional and I believe an employee
who comes into work after a night of
drinking is more dangerous than an
employee who comes in to work after a
night of
smoking
it's part of the reason why I'm working
with real legalization we have the short
sheets you've probably seen a petition
that can hold 20 signatures somebody
standing out in front of
Walmart asking you to
uh give the chickens the larger
cages but uh with our petition we also
have an another option called the short
sheet it only holds four
signatures but it also folds in into its
own envelope so you get a couple of
signatures from your friends put a stamp
on it and mail it
in instant
activist check out real legalization
dorg and look for safer shirts on the
internet uh there's a lot of information
to be found there read the book
marijuana safer so why are D why are we
driving people to drink thank you for
coming to Seattle Hempfest