I wrote this song to see 30
four years ago
yeah that's right
and it's called The Sovereign I hate to
have to keep singing it but as long as I
do I will
victim of a tangled yeah
in South Dakota where the fear was
thrown the president so I spent my mind
in the stone they said all people we're
free at our own there was a struggle for
freedom in the Indian home
how many had gone before
tell me how many more
must be lost to the Indian War
the companies look to the high command
and we need to tease to the Indian land
to dig for oil and uranium ore and maybe
have to start a little Indian War
the orders came from away on high that
there was a job for the FBI it won't be
hard I will have to do they just cause a
little tether than part of it through
thank you
know bladder where the spirit that dwell
if there was a time that they remembered
women and children were gathered there
but when the wind blew alone
of those who came to the call in the
time arose in dangerous strangers are
prowling around bring a double through
the reservation round
and that was when the agents are made
their play and I got a soft battle on a
deadly day and three men died in Lakota
land to FBI
en
how many have gone before
tell me how many more must be lost to
the Indian War
oh
Joseph was a man that died that day but
the eyes of the law didn't seem to see
all they cared about was their own kind
gonna get somebody
the charge was set for homicide but
Landon got away
where we lived for a while in the
northern town till they came up and got
it man they brought him back down
they said two times late in a federal
cell
Temptations came from a Washington
congratulations on a job well done two
agents gone is a mighty place but if you
want something bad you gotta suck her a
face
I took a lemon Pelt here up away in
Chains all of those years after suffer
in pain all that all of those years
makes a worry you're strong and the
struggle of the people goes on
how many have gone before to tell me how
many more you must be lost to the Indian
Wars
thank you
stunts was a lower down the winds did
blow with the mighty sound the answer
came in the driving ring this man will
not have died in thee
for the hollow power of the lock and key
ain't nothing to the power of the rage
inside the lightning strikes in the
angry Skies
puts the power into people's eyes
although the weather is building to a
mighty storm and the words and the wind
will come to warm are once more spoken
to your ear only this time the name is
tell me how many more must be lost to
the Indian world
foreign