[Music]
speaking in my official capacity as
mayor I have a message to all of you out
there welcome to
Seattle you know it's it's interesting
uh during my campaign somebody asked me
what my position was on marijuana
legalization and what I said was that if
every politician an elected official who
had ever tried marijuana voted to
legalize it it would be legal in an
[Music]
[Applause]
instant it's the truth it is the truth
folks that we have we have been as a
society very hypocritical and Rick
Steves has spoken about this and your
prior speakers have spoken about this so
we live in a very complicated world
right now where attitudes are changing
and that makes it harder on on lots of
folks it makes it harder on people that
want safe access to drugs it makes it
harder um you know on parents who trying
to figure out what their kids to do tell
tell their kids what to do it makes it
harder on our police force too by the
way and I'll talk about that in a second
it makes it harder but there's a pathway
here that'll make it easier and that
pathway is to recognize that prohibition
as a strategy has not worked the War on
Drugs has not work we can do better
we're in a time where attitudes are
changing attitudes are changing so we
just have to keep diligently talking and
explaining and and being authentic to
our friends and neighbor and our family
members about this issue and attitudes
do change and we can see attitudes
change for the better you know and on a
number of topics 20 or 30 years ago you
wouldn't even have spoken about the
issue of gay marriage to anyone and
that's changed 20 or 30 years ago
legalization seemed a distant something
way in the distance and that's changed
here in the city of Seattle by popular
vote we went as far as we could go which
is that
enforcement of marijuana laws for small
amounts the possession of small amounts
is the lowest enforcement priority for
our police lowest enforcements
priority did you know on that the people
led the people people led and the
politicians followed now by the way just
do us a favor do us a favor lowest
enforcement priority does not mean legal
make life easier for everybody including
our police officers don't light up in
front of them just make life easier for
everybody please
okay but they take the law seriously in
the state of Washington the people led
again and medical marijuana is legal
under state
law now those laws have changed they
become more confusing but the people led
and here in the city of Seattle we're
listening and we're going to make sure
that we do our best to observe that
state law uh protect the rights of
medical marijuana legitimate medical
marijuana users to Safe access to
Medicine
[Applause]
it's not happening everywhere it's not
happening in every city but it's
happening in our city now the problem is
of course that our law at the city level
the laws at the state level all exists
in a world where it is still illegal at
the federal level and we can't we can't
change that from here with our votes but
we can change more state laws both
people have spoken to you about
initiatives you know I mentioned to you
two things the politicians followed
because the people led the initiative
here in Seattle to make it the lows
enforcement priority medical marijuana
you have to keep leading you have to
keep leading and I'll do my best as an
elected official to lead too I'll do my
best as an elected official to lead too
but we need you to keep leading because
if we do that we will make these laws
make sense we will make this community
better thank you all of you for your
work thank
[Applause]
you
the mayor of the greatest city in the
world Mayor Mike mcin show some love
man