so when I was running for office I was
asked what my position was on the
legalization of marijuana and what I
said was that if every elected official
whoever smoked marijuana voted to
legalize it it would be legal in an
instant
so
it's the truth it's the truth here's
what we know
prohibition has not worked it's fueled
criminal
violence right now in this city right
now in this city I know this I know this
right now in this city we have seen
murders because people are murdering
each other over pot we have seen home
invasion robberies because it's it's a
black market substance I have a member
of my staff I have a member of my staff
and like a lot of people he he Brews his
own beer in his house he doesn't have to
worry about somebody breaking into his
house to steal his beer he doesn't have
to worry that when he gives it to a
friend he's subjecting himself to arrest
and the rules we have right now on
marijuana they put too many young people
at risk not just of arrest not just of
incarceration and by the way which Falls
much more heavily much more heavily on
our communities of color than it does on
everyone else but it also fuels criminal
violence and it makes us all less safe
it's time to stop it's time to tax it
regulate it Legalize It vote Yes on
i502 and let's have a same h policy
marijuana policy for this state of
Washington thanks you to Hempfest for 20
years of organizing to change attitudes
and this fall you're going to do it
thank you thank you Mar