than you
to for is
Place Great Place
Place can speakers
Place
governments Can't
some
drug a
drug not Heal Can
can Kid
Andri
marana
marana peret Never
expal to Our
Force to Our teachers Parents
warana
warli
People
maranao drug
drug
Our
drug take cri
out a
healed mys
Tell
People lock Times People
per
Andes People who
care
There There res People love to
rug
Amana
is
Out Of
marana marana is aate drug aate drug
because
There marana can
More marana is
United States with World and we
need
There
People
to supp advocacy
Group With Our mone ble for normal
There's a lot of Good Group for Years
aard member of Nor Those advocacy groups
That are Fighting Against The Drug War
drug Our country are not serves and f
Battle and aage and struggle in our
State House and Our
naal
new in to enforce cons across theard ex
of that Law Law enfor and respect of the
Law
hard kis
Church uned
States
home drug
He is and We Can beond drugs andt drugs
We canart On Drugs Right thanks a l
Thanks for Being have f and Happy
Travels even If Just
home