thank you todd
paul stanford came up here from oregon
and he is
with the hemp and cannabis foundation
the thc foundation they are the event
sponsor of hempfest this year so thc
foundation presents seattle hempfest
he's also the author and chief chief
petitioner of the tax and regulate bill
in oregon give a warm seattle welcome to
paul stanford
thank you vivian
most inspirational speaker in hip hop
hey seattle head fast
wake up it's almost 4 20.
are you ready
all right we're coming pretty quick you
know we have helped in our clinics
almost 100 000 people get a legal
medical marijuana permit how many of you
out there have got one raise your hands
if you've got a legal medical marijuana
permit here
all right
i know you are if you have one of those
conditions hey give us a call we have
doctors who can help you all across this
state
and
we want to see more and more patients
become legal
especially if they have a condition but
you know that's not the end-all and all
there's nothing i would like better than
to see our medical clinics become kind
of
a
side issue and i want to see complete
legal marijuana for every adult i want
to see us all able to grow our own crop
where we don't have to go down and get a
license it's just a
god-given right to be able to grow on
the plant that produces more fiber more
protein more oil than any other plant on
this planet amen brother so we're
working to do that through our uh
political committee if you want to find
out more about it go to hemp.org that's
hemp.org
we have a initiative petition we're
pushing in oregon for 2010 to end adult
marijuana prohibition and restore
industrial hemp if we get it on the
ballot and win the election which is a
hard one
then marijuana be legal january 1st 2000
just a year and a half from now
you know the berlin wall fell very very
quickly and i think weak in marijuana
prohibition we've been waiting a couple
generations to see some progress on this
and finally it's moving forward so go to
hemp.org get involved with the movement
to end adult marijuana prohibition and
stop putting honest americans in prison
for supporting a plant that can save the
planet
i want to thank you all for coming
thanks for having us
and restore him
d paul stanford from the hemp and
cannabis foundation seattle hempfest
event sponsor this year