thank you
folks ready for
420 you guys are ready for 420 now hey T
minus uh 45 minutes here we're almost
time you know what we have to stop the
lies about Canabis it cost so much
suffering in this world so many of our
brothers and sisters are in jail
you know Mark gimy you got his picture
right up here it was Roger Christie a
reverend who was
doing religious work in Hawaii he's
being held without bail they're saying
he's never been arrested for cannabis
before or anything he's 61 years old
they're saying he's a danger to the
community and they won't let him out on
bail and they're holding him until next
April for a trial it'll probably be
after that but uh Eddie lap spoken on
this St many times he's being help for
10 years so we got to let our people go
you know in marijuana
prohibition about 32 years ago I went to
a rally that was much like this one
right in front of the White House
there's a White House smok in organized
by The yippies Dana Bei that got me
motivated and involved in the movement
about 30 years ago I was a Washington
state normal coordinator and I helped
organize the state about
1984 I moved from Washington Oregon to
help the Oregon marijuana initiative and
we put an initiative on the ballot we
lost pretty
overwhelmingly but uh in 84 as well Jack
herrer moved to Oregon
from Los Angeles thank you and he uh put
together book while working on the
marijuana initiative in Portland the
emperor wears no clothes he gave one of
his last speeches here last year in the
heat of the
day but uh you know Jack's book
basically catalyzed us all changed us
all and Jack's book motivated Untold
scores of people get out there work for
Global cannabis freedom and restore
Industrial Hemp this book brought the
whole picture into Focus about hemp and
cannabis you know now know and to see
marijuana catalyzed me marijuana
motivates
me and I studied Chinese for a couple
years and went to school in China and
started importing hip Fabric and hip
paper back in the early '90s and had a
company tree-free Eco paper sold H paper
I started and continue to produce a live
weekly television store show Cannabis
Common Sense plays on cable here in the
Northwest and I also started and today
run THCF the hyp and cannabis
foundation and in addition to being the
sponsors here perhaps most importantly
thf has helped almost
150,000 people all across the United
States from Detroit Michigan and
Marquette Michigan out to Kapaa Hawaii
and Hulu become legal medical marijuana
patients where they can legally possess
use and grow
their
medicine but you know what it goes much
deeper than this cannabis hip is deeper
than its incredibly long tap rout
marijuana's deep you know cannabis H
catalyzed human civilization
itself marijuana jump started human
civilization all archaeologists agree
that cannabis was among the first crops
purposely grown by people over 12,000
years ago people began growing hip and
its cultivation spread from the high
Himalayas of Tibet and uh Nepal and
Pakistan and Kashmir and it spread down
to The Valleys in the Yellow River
Valley in China the Wanga Valley and to
the tigerish rres valley in Iraq to the
cradles of
Agriculture you know marijuana could
very well be the whole reason that our
ancestors gave up hunting and gathered
and started agricultural settlement so
they could have their
stashed and I believe the Cannabis is
the most sacred gift from the Creator to
us Humanity cannabis is the holiest of
the Holy gifts from our mother earth
every part of cannabis hip is highly
useful for the diverse multitude of our
needs and the needs of human
civilization there's only one one plant
capable of taking care of most human
civilization's needs and that's
marijuana when we restore marijuana to
its rightful place and Industrial hip to
its rightful place in our
economy we're going to see marijuana
Fuel and a great deal of our fuel and
energy needs are going to be made from
the seeds of
marijuana marijuana seed oil run any
diesel engine the mar stems produce most
of our fiber can produce most of our
fiber for clothing paper building
materials and it wipe out
deforestation and stop a great deal of
our pollution hydration hip seeds
produce more and healthier oil and
protein hip protein and oils are rich in
the essential fatty acids or the efas
that our brain and cardiovascular system
need marijuana seeds make omega 3 six
and n be the perfect ratio for human
health and hip protein for marijuana
seeds makes all eight of the amino acids
that our body needs again in just the
right ratio for human
health when marijuana seed oil ages and
goes ran it it's no longer useful for a
food but it's a productive biodiesel
fuel you can take that oil for right
into any diesel engine and it's going to
run it with no conversions the engine
are the fuel and you can synthesize it
into gasoline and plastic and anything
petroleum can make it's not only healthy
for us it can solve our world energy
problems wipe out a lot of
pollution the hemp stocks the stems are
the most productive source of fiber on
Earth making 10 tons of bass fiber for
canvas rope lace and linen and 25 tons
of herd fiber for paper and building
materials per acre way back in 1916 the
United States Department of Agriculture
put out a bulletin bulletin 404 said a
waste product for making canvas rope
lace and linen from him that waste
product makes four times more paper than
the most productive tree
species the US Department of Agriculture
back here in World War I put out a video
called hemp for victory they showed
Farmers how to reintroduce him it's
available on YouTube and that's just the
steeve seeds in the
stems you know we need these seeds in
the stems don't throw them away but then
we have the flowers hi flowers make
human brain chemicals or
neurotransmitters and medicines that
help help fight cancer multiple sceris
neurodegenerative diseases
gastrointestinal disorders relieves pain
helps glaucoma stops seizures and spasms
and restores balance in the body
restores homeo basis the flowers of himp
will also make you laugh make you feel
good and relieve depression
post-traumatic stress and
anxiety I truly believe that himp is our
mother earth's greatest gift to humanity
you know the forces of ignorance evil
and darkness are a foot the laws against
marijuana are just claimed wrong
marijuana prohibition is a conspiracy
from the wealthy of this world to feed
us with poisonous petrochemical products
when we legalize marijuana it will
create Untold multitude of jobs and
return economic control to the people
what he say no more Wars for petroleum
when we start to use imp again instead
imp can lead the way to economic and
ecological sustainability and help save
the remnants of our
biospheres precious Heritage for future
Generations in the generation with beond
you know right now cannabis freedom is
Dawning with Vates across the West
California's propop 19 is a
groundbreaking step to legalize
possession cultivation and allow a small
amount of herb allow it
sale Oregon's medical marijuana
dispensary ballot will create
jobs and uh uh help uh patients then in
Arizona and South Dakota they're going
to allow medical marijuana in a
vote so in closing I just want to say
that we have to stop the drug war before
they kick in your door we got to work
together to legalize
marijuana those execution for
anti-cannabis laws in Malaysia and
elsewhere you got to work for Global
cannabis freedom for those languishing
in jails and prisons for the
anti-cannabis laws out there everywhere
we got to work for Global cannabis
freedom for our forest and the web of
life and our mother earth which suffers
from the
extraction and uh poisoning of our
environment we got to work for Global
cannabis freedom and for economic and
political Justice we got to work for
Global cannabis freedom for our brothers
and sisters and all that have fallen
before us like Jack har Todd MCA so many
of us we got to work for Global cannabis
Freedom cannabis hip
marijuana I believe is truly the healing
of the nation so let our people
grow restore himp hip for victory thanks
r