hi I was just over at the imposium stage
uh doing a panel with some other
cannabis activists and we're just
talking about things you can do to
become an activist and uh Ben from the
CDC mentioned that uh nor Callahan uh
says that activism is where you are and
I I think that's really important uh you
got to think local and think simple keep
it simple this is a big
sign with
uh six words five words you know it's
simple
uh you have to find out something inside
yourself how do I help uh and the only
way you can do that is by taking first
steps you you can't be afraid you have
to be willing to experiment and I tried
making
t-shirts and you know I wasn't very good
at first but practice makes
perfect so try different things
experiment find out what you're good at
find something inside yourself that lets
you help someone other than
yourself right now I'm working with the
Cannabis child protection act uh 514 it
would allow uh adults 21 years of age
and older to grow a 20x20 Garden
recreational marijuana it would also
require video proof of impairment before
blood could be used against you in a DUI
we're collecting signatures all over the
place uh we're just behind MC Williams
stage just down the road a little ways
we need help we need volunteers to help
us gather
uh so look for 514 CCPA w.org thank you