mfest happy at best a PFS guys this is
you just your personal freedoms at work
you think this stage gets built out of
midair look at all these canna warriors
around you volunteering their time
putting their energy into this effort
which is called cannabis freedom so
celebrate today is our day tomorrow's
our day every day should be our day yeah
i was thinking trying to think why what
i want to talk to you guys about why I'm
up here you know I'm thinking to myself
last year I was just out there a bender
handing out cards giving out information
telling people keep Washington green
right people are like what do you mean
keep Washington green we just legalized
it does this look like legalization to
you why because you're fleeing to the
rocks and under the trees to smoke some
freakin cannabis well you know what I'm
really proud of our head pass through
and our half the staff because they're
keeping our freedoms alive and our
dreams alive and they're doing their
thing and you know what this reminds me
of years pass and hemp fest so we still
celebrate our freedoms and we still
smoke cannabis where we want to and how
we want to and we're going to continue
to do that so celebrate today I have a
main message to you this this battle is
not done we have a lot of work to do
there's a there's a recreational scheme
which we have in our state where you can
purchase cannabis that's great I voted
for that I'm fighting for that I know
business owners that are putting in
their due diligence I also know some
really lame business owners that are
doing some horse stuff for industry but
we won't talk about that right now
we will talk about is the fact that just
because we can buy it in the store
doesn't mean it's free I want to grow it
in my backyard I want to smoke it where
I want to I bet you do too 1.7 million
people in this state voted for i-502 and
about three-quarters more of that still
think that you can grow plants in this
state just because you don't have a
medicine card you know what I think we
all need to get educated about what our
public policy is what our state policy
isn't get involved I know one thing's
for sure i clambered up to the state
politics this last year and observe the
most dysfunctional state legislative
session entire history of Washington
State we went through three sessions
that's one session plus two more and we
couldn't even figure out our state taxes
and in fact if you're watching the state
Supreme Court just suit our state
legislature a hundred thousand dollars a
day until they figure out how to educate
our freaking kids I'm upset I am a
citizen I voted for cannabis freedom
they're taxing it and they can't even
educate my kids I want you guys to get
involved because this is not going to
end we need to go up there and tell them
I want my cannabis I don't want it to be
shoved through a tax regulated system
and come out dirty I want to have my
rights and we're not going to get our
rights until we get up there we clamber
up there and tell all of them this is
how I want it and I want it right now
because if we don't do that what they're
going to do is they're going to do what
they did a 502 they're going to stifle
it they're going to throw fifty-four
percent in this state into default of a
state law that's actually in conflict
with our state constitution if you read
article 11 section 11 it's only two
lines long so please look it up it says
no jurisdiction can pass laws that are
outside of general law that means they
cannot ban cannabis they cannot ban all
rights to save access they cannot do
what they're doing and we need to go
into the city council and those county
commissioners will you tell them you are
wrong it says so right here in our
Constitution and I don't care what
organization and what Attorney General
comes out with any opinion or citizen
right Stan didn't both with me guys it's
not that hard I only put in a couple of
days a week I still do a lot of fun
things I work with awesome people every
day and people share cannabis with me
every day and when they do that they
break the law I don't want to do that
anymore I want to be free I wouldn't be
a person I want to be a professional I
want to be whoever I want to be and have
the right to cannabis and I want you to
have that right to right I want you to
take pay attention to one other thing in
denver colorado maybe they're doing it
right maybe we're doing it wrong the one
thing they are doing is they got a
general ballot to a local level to
consume cannabis in public at at any
location that has any other smoking so
if you earn a cafe or restaurant and
they have a smoking area you can consume
cannabis out there if it's okay with
that owner of that it's an entity right
at that establishment so think about
that guys we're all around here
frustrated we just want to smoke some
cannabis we have to go over here to the
rocks we have to go over there you know
they can serve alcohol they can tax
alcohol but they can serve cannabis know
what is going on here we need to check
this out it only takes what was it 3,700
citizens the city of Denver I bet you it
takes a little bit around that here in
Seattle so I'm going to ask you one last
thing if you care about cannabis and you
care about freedom of cannabis get
involved