main thing you take anything away from
my talk it's that marijuana him is the
oldest crop purposely grown by people
over 12,000 years ago the first
agricultural settlements in Mesopotamia
along the Tigris and Euphrates River
present-day Iraq and on the opposite
flank of the Himalayas in a china long
the Wang Han River in the Yellow River
both of those civilizations started
growing marijuana you know him they grew
it because it's the plant that produces
the most fuel the most food the most
fiber and the most medicine than any
other plant on this planet so obviously
to prohibit the plant that makes the
most fuel the most food most fiber the
most medicine than any other plant is
wrong so we're working hard to try to
change that you know there are a number
about initiatives out there this year I
particularly have been working in Oregon
because that's where I live and we put a
measure on the ballot there we call
measure 80 it would legalize any
individual to grow their own without any
artificial limits on the amount that
they can grow it also doesn't have any
limits on the amount that you can
possess vlogs it's for non-commercial
use it frees horticultural him sow the
seeds and starts of all varieties of
cannabis will be legal and it legalized
sniff for fuel fiber and food without
regulation the only regulation is that
the strains that grow the best quality
and the best quantity of fiber will be
the ones that Oregon farmers can use you
know there's also an initiative on the
bound here I 502 and one in Washington
Colorado amendment 64 three-stage will
vote on various proposals to legalize
marijuana
this year if any of those paths will
change the whole dynamic it is if all
three of those initiatives pass that
would be like the the end of the Cold
War and the following of the Berlin Wall
it'll be like the toppling of statue of
linen in Red Square back in nineteen
ninety if all three of these initiatives
passed it will send a message that the
people aren't going to put up with
marijuana prohibition any longer and you
know there was a good breakthrough just
this past week in Kansas City Missouri a
jury was impaneled to prosecute some guy
for possession of marijuana and he had
bought some tax stamp they needed there
in Missouri the jury revolted they got
angry at the prosecutor they told them
they aren't going to prosecute this guy
so the judge threw the charges out made
it where he can't be tried again if you
get an opportunity to serve on jury duty
go there and just say no to marijuana
laws tell em you're not gonna Brock
you're not going to convict anyone for a
marijuana crime because marijuana isn't
a crime marijuana is a blessing so you
know we have a booth over here if the
cannabis foundation we've helped over
20,000 people in the state of Washington
altogether about 150,000 people all
across the country get their medical
marijuana permits that is a blessing for
us and a blessing for the patients you
want to find out more about it come
right over to that booth we also have
information about Oregon's measure 80
will be voting on that and in closing I
just want to say you need to register
and you need to vote you need to get out
there
and get your friends to register and
vote we have a real historic opportunity
to end marijuana prohibition this year
in just about two months two and a half
months if we do it will send a ray of
hope for those people that are in prison
all around the world you know here in
America there are over a thousand people
in prison or life without the
possibility of parole who never grew
marijuana I've never heard a better
person never stole anything they're
there just for growing marijuana so get
out there register to vote and make
history thanks you go hip bath