I'm not one for trying to find new ways
to do something that has already been
done and what what I mean by that we
were here once before with alcohol
prohibition
and for instance the last call a book by
Daniel Kent you know and in reading that
and looking at how alcohol prohibition
came to an end
and the groups that were involved and
how they went about doing it you know
the the mothers that came forward you
know protecting their children we have a
similar thing
today there are many many as not many
many different groups many different
perspective many different reasons for
being here at the table to end
prohibition of
marijuana and we have to
ensure that we are working well together
and well oiled machine because a lot has
to be done a lot has to be done
politically at the end of the day what
we want to do is to remove marijuana
from a schedule one category and in my
opinion remove it from the scheduling
system all
together and you
know so how does that happen you know
I'm not going to
you know reiterate what dominic already
talked about but but how does that
happen how do we do that all right we
have two states right now right here in
Washington in Colorado have
begun to
[Music]
move there are 48 other
states that are going to move in a
similar Direction the question is how
would he do it and how quickly will they
do
it one of the things that I think is
important as many of us here are from
other parts of the country is that we
have to connect the dots we have to go
back to our states we have to talk about
this yes at the kitchen tables and in
our own individual circles but we have
to make those connections to the people
who would be responsible in our home
States for make for doing what's
Happening Here the city attorneys for
instance in I'm from earland in
Baltimore I want to give some examples
here in Baltimore where the City
attorney is uh Mr Bernstein you know I
know Mr bernin and I know Pete Holmes
here is my responsibility to connect
those two people so that they can begin
a dialogue so that Mr Bernstein can
learn from Pete Holmes as to what's
happening in Seattle what differences
are being made how's that occurring who
needs to be involved City Council
Members connecting those folks as well
doctors from Maryland need to be
speaking with doctors here in Washington
the liquor control board folks need to
be communicating from Maryland to
Washington State in Colorado you know
however it's being
done and I think that's an important
piece of it because I know people are in
other states just people who have the
power to make things happen in it you're
wonder you're wondering so what's going
on out there in Washington state and
they're developing their own
perspectives about what is happen
happening in Washington state in
Colorado we can't allow them to do that
we can't allow them
to
create myths and rumors and inuendo and
monsters we need to show them what's
happening here and that the sky is not
falling in Washington
state you know so those are just some
examples currently we have momentum in
what's occurring with marijuana policy
reform in this country and we cannot
afford to lose
it the only way that we can lose it in
my opinion is if we don't work together
as a team in making this happen and I'm
going to continue to say this every time
I have an opportunity because in the
past I've seen
infighting among all of us that want to
legalize marijuana day want to remove it
from the scheduling system and we have
to get beyond our own individual
differences we have to leave that
baggage outside you can pick it up when
you leave when we're all done when we
end prohibition of marijuana you can
pick it up and carry it around again if
you want but for this moment for this
effort here you've got to leave it
outside you've got to do that
[Music]
[Applause]
so I'll end with this you know the moms
need to support the cops that want to
get this done and there are a lot of
cops that want to get it done believe it
or not and they're all not members of
leap you know the cops need to support
uh those who just want the right to
enjoy
cannabis those who just want to enjoy
cannabis need to support those who come
to here to this place a medical
perspective those who come to this place
from a religious perspective and the
many different places we come from we
have to support each
other keep the momentum going and share
what's happening here in Washington and
Colorado not just with other states in
the union but we we're already beginning
to see what's happening outside of this
country in other countries like in
Central America
with
Uruguay the move that you're seeing in
Uruguay is because of what happened
here
[Music]
here that's my two cents thanks