all we talk about race and you know that
African-Americans and Hispanics get
arrested more than than Caucasians and
all classes of drug rated arrests they
get sent to jail more they get
prosecuted more and it's totally totally
unfair and does not represent race
characterizations in America but what's
even more subtle underlying this is
privilege some people are allowed to use
cannabis and some people are not that's
all plain and simple it is it's freaking
a privilege game and I'm telling you all
right now that if the people don't
figure this stuff out get cannabis back
in their hands there is something coming
down the pathway and that's called
pharmaceuticalization
okay this is what's going on there is a
company in England that is making a
cannabis
spray okay they are taking cannabis
plants growing them up and dissolving
them in liquid carbon dioxide okay you
take dry ice you put a COR on it and
after a while you get a little mixture
and you can dissolve cannabis in that
mixture it's been done since the 1800s
okay but these guys have figured out a
way to nicely cleanly do it with chopped
up cannabis that they got from Dutch
from the Dutch seed banks okay heard and
then and then what happened eventually
these guys were able to make a mixture
of one strain with a high TC content and
one strain with a high CBD content these
strains are you can find these in in us
and and a bunch of States then they went
to the international naming board and
said this is not Ash oil this is not
marijuana this is
nimals this is a total extraction in
liquid carbon dioxide straight up from
straight ganja that they've mixed up
together in one:1 ratio and they're
calling it naxals they are allowed to
import this into the country it's
straight up from Cannabis and they're
using it in clinical trials which is
great it's medicine for patients in
hospitals but you know what they're
telling the government they're saying
look when you approve our spray leave
cannabis in schedule one but take our
cannabis extraction out of schedule one
so we can make Buu dollars so we do not
have to uh wait for um you know compete
with other Growers so I'm I mean I'm
just telling you this is coming down the
pike it's really crazy it's a crazy
world of privilege that's pharmaceutical
privilege over the people's right to cul
their own medicine if it's not if you
guys don't know about this if if you
want to if you want to know part of
what's the politics please pay attention
to this because before you know it um
you know a pharmaceutical company will
have that in your Bartell so you can get
it prescribed it'll be coming down this
is this is happening under the Obama
Administration and uh Obama himself he
has appointed the major person who was
responsible for raiding all the cannabis
dispensaries in California as to be the
head head of the drug enforcement agency
so you know that's the kind of stuff if
you guys want to keep seeing those kind
of like repressive politics which keeps
lots of people down keeps the keeps the
privilege politics going and don't do
anything about it just kind of keep keep
your little Zone but if you want to see
a change if you want people to have
access to this thing and you I'm sure
you all do because like everybody wants
people to share the the benefits of
Mother Earth I mean this is what this is
it's 37 million year old plan so anyway
I wanted to share that with you I want
you guys to be very excited that you're
in a place like Seattle which allows
100,000 people to come together like
this I mean this is pretty amazing
nowhere else in the world has this
happen but you know it cannot be just
once a day once a year it has to be all
the time okay you can't just go to one
place and feel like you can be
comfortable on cannabis anywhere in the
world it should be a cannabis free zone
a Zone that's cannabis can freely be
talked about consumed if appropriate and
just you know part of our lands like
it's been forever so that's what I
that's what I hope to see and any I'll
be back with you all next year