we've been putting up with people going
to jails and prisons for 1 2 10 5 20
years for marijuana it's got to end it's
an outrage it's an injustice we are not
a threat we're Americans we're we're
peaceful we're
nonviolent and you know what's happening
today at Seattle Hempfest the police are
handing out bags of Doritos we're
winning we are winning this war on
us and we might be living in this Oasis
called seatt ble but somebody while
hempest is going on somebody's life
changed today somebody had that cop car
behind their behind their car today
somewhere in America they had their
doors kicked in today somewhere in
America they had the handcuffs go on
today somewhere in America their life
will never be different their family
might be broken up they might lose their
marriage they might lose their home they
might have their kids taken away they
might be put in jails and prisons like a
common criminal when all they've done is
kick back and enjoy some music and watch
some tunes watch the TV and hang out and
feel good and relaxed while other people
smoke cigarettes into the cancer ws and
drink alcohol into the detox center no
one's ever died in 5,000 years of
smoking marijuana no one's ever
overdosed no one's ever had a toxic
reaction no one's ever had DTS no one's
ever had their brain fried or their
liver destroyed no one's ever gotten
lung cancer for marijuana despite the
lies despite the lies and we're winning
it's so beautiful to see this beautiful
community culture here for the first
time able to celebrate a serious win
major 64 in Colorado i502 in Washington
state
groundbreaking potentially gamechanging
events all of our Lives we lived under
this this meme this prevailing myth that
marijuana prohibition is an iron curtain
it's here to stay there's nothing you
can do about it it's never going away we
just blown that right out of the water
we know that's not true we know that
prohibition is more like a brick wall
and we took a few bricks out you take
another couple bricks out and the right
couple bricks out the whole thing is
going to come tumbling down it's not
about if it's going to happen now it's
about when it's going to happen because
we're going to win this thing and if we
have to come back and do another 100
saddle Hemp Fest if our great
grandchildren have to do this and bear
this weight and this load and this
responsibility the Stress and Anxiety to
throw a Seattle hempest and urban center
in one of the most beautiful series of
parks right on the Puget Sound in one of
the gems right in view of the Space
Needle if we've got to continue to do
this whatever it takes whatever it takes
necessary to win our freedom and our
equality and our Justice we're going to
do it and it just feels so good to be
able to stand up here with all these
great speakers and activists and and
performers bands and DJs vendors and
sponsors and volunteers and this
incredible beautiful audience that's kep
pfest violence free for 21 years
so beautiful such a beautiful statement
of unity and community of power you know
Hest is an act of love for all of us
volunteers because we love this crowd
and this community so much it's a leap
of faith every year praying nothing goes
wrong nobody jaywalks and gets hit by a
car or nobody falls on the rocks and or
drowns in the water or walks across the
railroad tracks and gets hurt the last
thing we want is for any body to get
hurt at Seattle Hempfest so thanks for
keeping an iy being responsible keeping
yourselves safe stay high
drad high and rated