if the voters vote yes for your
initiative can we see a peaceful
transaction in the federal government
stay out of our out of the business of
orient or do you anticipate um more
court proceedings or how's that going to
proceed
i anticipate more court proceedings uh
we designed our
proposal to
deal with the what i've always
considered an inevitable challenge
by the federal government
we've done that by
raising a number of findings by the
people
we all live under the belief here in the
united states the people are the
sovereign and the ruler
so based on that belief we've
had findings by the people written into
our proposal
much as
oregon's death with dignity law was
enjoined in federal court and went to
the supreme court after two years on a
fast track supreme court ruled that
doctors can recommend our prescribed
phenobarbital for
terminally ill patients we think our
bill will
go into federal court and inevitably
change the controlled substances act
an even bigger hurdle is the single
convention treaty which mandates the
cannabis be a schedule one substance
in oregon our board of pharmacy has
already rescheduled marijuana to
schedule two as the board of pharmacy in
iowa so two states have already broken
with that restriction in contradiction
to the single convention treaty
our initiative also imposes a system of
controls that we lifted from the single
convention treaty
so
time will tell i have no confidence in
the
composition of the supreme court under
chief justice roberts but
you
it's the best shot we have i believe
thanks