this one's for you
[Music]
Seattle
I smoke two joints in the morning I
smoke two joints at
night I smoke two joints in the
afternoon it makes me feel all
right I smoke two to in time of PE and
two in time of
War I spoke to before I
spoke and then I smoke
tomor my dad want to me on you be hard
working
man mama was on you do the best you
can but then one day I met that man who
came to me and
said hard work hard work fine but first
take care of told now I smoke when I get
up in the car I smoke to
Joint I smoke to Joint when I played
and at every 10,000 I smoke I smoke two
time oface and two enti
War I smoke to before I
smoke and then I
[Music]
[Applause]
smoke
[Music]
a
but
D me you be hardw working
man mama she want told me son you do the
best you
can and then one day I met that man who
came to me and said what did he say hard
work good and hard work F but first take
care of so now I smoke two TS in the
morning I smoke two TS at
night I smoke two in the afternoon that
makes me feel all
right I smoke two TS in time of peace
and two in time
for I smoke two joints before I smoke to
and I smoke
smoke that's what
[Music]
I legal up
here I need a real estate
[Music]
agent
hope to Jo with me in the
[Music]
morning to with me in the after
yeah
[Music]
that's
w