the song I wrote about my hero
my musical hero everybody got a musical
hero Michael Bob Marley my name Bob
Dylan everybody's got a musical hero
I've had a whole bunch of them my time
but we got to matter the most to me when
I was coming up and learning how to play
a guitar with Sam Hopkins
they call it a lightning that was a
professional land
from Texas to a little town called
Centerville Texas
a little small town not a minute here in
Seattle up with the old fresh air Tavern
and this is what happened
no one could sing the blues like
lightning Hopkins
up again
that's when I heard him for the first
time
cutting into the noise of the car
and my whole world went upside down I
just had to learn to sing and play
guitar so I got on my bicycle with a
high-rise handle ballrooms and I would
ride for 20 miles on a run I got every
one of his records I could find back in
yes I did I had 11 of them
I never learned to play the blues
I hope that's all right
I never learned to play the moon but I
could sing and play a guitar on
oh
now I use later up in Seattle town
lightning came to playing three nights
in a row
I caught it with him early in the
dressing room
somehow I just had to live alone
so once you got my guitar and I started
playing and I'm beating him up a song to
celebrate
by the radio at the car and all of his
records and I'm glad I was to meet him
at night when I think about what he
taught me without even knowing it and
all the lessons that I still had to
learn and lightning use his dream when I
was done he told me a story every time
I hope that's all right
I never learned
that this is what he told me he said he
was walking around in Texas one time he
was only 12 years old he was carrying
his guitars almost as big as he was he
tired of marine cold we saw some people
were having a picnic
man he has the biggest thing for his
meal okay turn him away he said because
he was too raggedy you can still
remember how it made him feel he looked
after the distance to his dark
sunglasses and he grinned a little more
just a chance he said now I got money in
the bank back home
I hope that's all right
I never learned
oh man I guess again
foreign
relaxing guitar on