if you think and you look historically
marijuana was not prohibited until 37
and so up until that time you actually
had a legal viable market and just
because of market shares and
say competing market interest
as it pertains to safe with industrial
hemp you had
randolph hearst who wanted to ensure
that wood fiber became the fiber for
paper you had
dupont and other chemical companies who
wanted to
see cotton move forward and so they
wanted to demonize
marijuana and so and if you look at what
happened with the prohibition of alcohol
and you had basically the same setup
it's just taken many more years because
let's say
interference and obstacles that came in
place but clearly i think you will in
fact see a change and
a rebirth of an industry and one of the
things that's very important to me is
ensuring that local farmers will have
the opportunity to benefit
what i
think not only for the hemp
industrial hemp but also in the
marijuana for cannabis that's where we
should allow for the
growing to occur you can see small
businesses
and it's going to be a birth of an
industry that's going to bring
a lot of new jobs a lot of new jobs to
our communities
and you can see what has happened just
in colorado and what what we'll be
watching in the next couple of months in
washington state to see how that plays
out and clearly we're in a position
knowing that we're the grassy capital of
the world that we can vote
that we will in fact be able to be in
the market on a on a national basis and
actually
be branded for the product that we have
will anything happen to people currently
in prison for marijuana related
convictions and what about people being
charged at the time of legalization if
it should happen
well the way it works is that at the
time of the conviction it was against
the law and so those convictions will
stand that does not mean
that the legislature cannot uh revisit
and look at this issue on a let's call
it somewhat of a case-by-case basis uh i
expect that once uh
ip53 whatever the ballot measure number
is passes the legislature will start
looking at what is the impact on our
prison system uh currently and how does
it uh pertain uh to the changes that we
made uh i believe it was just in 2013 we
did a remodification of
the penalties that a person would face
if they had
previously as anything over an ounce was
a felony we changed that through the
legislative process to up to four ounces
is now a misdemeanor and so i expect
that you will see at some point looking
at what is the cost drivers for the
prison system as to what we think we
should be modifying if anything at that
point uh there's no guarantee i mean the
reality is they were when they were
convicted it was in fact a felony and so
just the passage of it will not change
that
uh regarding the other part rick
sorry
well if they're
i guess it's going to be based on when
the charging instrument
comes through the reality we're going to
have this uh period of time over a year
from uh basically 2015 up to 2016 that
you're gonna have the transition i will
expect that you'll what you'll see in
many of the district attorney's offices
and in uh that are the only district
attorney's offices do felony work they
will start looking at what the reality
is as to what the people have actually
passed and i do believe that you'll see
charging practices change based on the
passage of ip53
yeah
and i'd like to mention you know under
the letter of the law you know nothing
changes
the legislature could very well take
that issue up and additionally we've
some we've seen especially in denver and
seattle once the law passed we saw
prosecutors like drop a bunch of charges
against people so i think you will see
practically speaking an improvement in
how people are treated um but uh we may
need a legislative fix especially as we
look forward towards how much money
we're spending on these cases locking
these people in prison if somebody
happened to be in prison for four or
five ounces you know at their home which
would now be allowed under new approach
i think that'd be something that the
legislature even potentially certain
judges
definitely could look at what have we
learned from colorado and washington and
what are these two states done
especially well or poorly from what
you've seen
sure i think that
in washington
the bill is fairly poor it doesn't allow
people to grow their own
it does it limits the possession to an
ounce
if you have over 28 grams in washington
you're
have a misdemeanor if you have over 40
grams you'll go to jail so this is
dramatically better than that
and in colorado they have a particularly
onerous system of regulation that
requires video cameras on the grow site
from seed to sale with video feed to the
state store it's definitely over
regulated
we've seen prices of seven and eight
hundred dollars an ounce in washington
and uh several hundred dollars an ounce
in colorado we're not going to wipe out
the black market at those prices folks i
think
initiative 53 will do that and
a 35 an ounce tax is certainly
reasonable and i think it's a lot better