now one of the reasons that so many
Americans are angry is they see a
criminal justice system which comes down
very heavily on the poor and on people
of
color in Vermont Oregon or any place
some kid gets picked up with marijuana
that kid is likely to have a police
record for the rest of his or her
[Music]
life but apparently if you are an
executive on Wall Street whose greed and
illegal Behavior destroyed this economy
nothing happens to
[Music]
you so what Wall Street has got to learn
and Corporate America has got to learn
is that we are going to bring Justice
back to a broken Criminal Justice
System we have got to rethink the
so-called War on
Drugs it turns out turns out that over
the last 30 years Millions of Americans
have police records for possession of
[Music]
marijuana it turns out that the federal
controlled substance act list marijuana
is a schedule one drug right next to
[Applause]
heroin that is why I've introduced
legislation to take marijuana out of the
federal control substance
Act
but when we talk about
drugs all of us have got to recognize
that in my state of Vermont neighboring
the Hampshire and all over this country
we have a major crisis in terms of
opiate
addiction heroin addiction and people
dying every day from overdoses
what we have got to do as a nation is to
understand that the most effective way
to deal with drug and alcohol abuse is
not making them crimes but making them
health
issues