Industrial Hemp is a strategic food and
resource for fiber which you can make
clothing canvas paper and also that
cellulose can be used to make the new
substance in 1936 that Dupont wanted it
to just be made out of coal or out of
oil you can use the same byproduct you
can use the same uh product of cellulose
in the stock of the sensia in other
words we could be growing medical
marijuana and take the stock of it and
make plastic to build homes for
Hawaiians at very inexpensive rates or
we could build an automobile I could
show you a picture real quickly here on
page 50 of a car that Henry Ford made
out of cannabis I know it's hard for
people to believe it but here's a car
made out of cannabis that not only did
Henry Ford want the car to be made out
of plastic made from hemp but he wanted
it to be run in other words the fuel
there was a process where you could
renewably take plants especially hemp
and after you take the seeds off for the
food to feed starving people or to feed
animals or to press that oil into the
lubricating uh lubricants for the grease
and the oil in the car so literally we
can use
plants natural resources given to us by
God our creator to solve problems here
in
Maui now the National Review which is
the uh publication of the conservative
right and William F Buckley who is a
scholar has come out recently this is
the second front page in a year where he
said yeah it's p people uh the drug the
War on Drugs is the War on Drugs really
lost and he gives 17 scholarly points in
this magazine where he feels that the
way to go is harm reduction and
immediate relaxation of laws against
cannabis for even recreational use