[Music]
So ganja
plant me the ganja farmer deep down in
the earth where we plant the ganja babon
we light it up on fire and shine I'm
just another ganja
plant call me the ganja farmer Deep down
in deeper where we put the gun
belong see the big sticking helicopters
flying through the arrow. What do we
want to call them? Call them weed
eaters. Never going to sprinkle the
water upon the land. And they never
bring a fertilizer to a
farmer. Don't get out of control. Don't
smash the officers up under your
license. You cannot today. Go away.
Under the radar we play and out of jail
we'll
stay. Just another ganja
plant. Call me the ganja farmer. Deep
down in the earth where we put the ganja
[Music]
belong. My daddy was a ganja
plant called the ganja farmer deep down
in the earth used to put the ganja.
[Music]
Marijuana, you got my heart pumping. The
marijuana, it got my fist pumping. The
marijuana, it got my chest pumping. Son
of the rhythm. Come to tell this world
something. The marijuana, it got my feet
stomping. The marijuana, it got my fist
pumping.
[Music]
Marijuana
say if you don't want to call it then
call it sensia. Know what to call it.
They call it the indigo. Know what to
call it. They call it marijuana. But I
say ganja. Oh ganja. Ganja. Ganja.
Ganja. Oh ganja. Ganja. Ganja. But she
plays
every I say when I
[Music]
pray just another ganja plant.
Say I'm the ganja
[Music]
plant. Just say I'm the ganja plant.
I say I'm the ganja planter.
[Music]
[Applause]