I love
them yeah
[Music]
a
[Applause]
[Music]
he
m
[Applause]
[Music]
look up every day and say you want to
have a meal you get the little cut and
you want to have it heal can't accept it
that J is real Mr Man what your deal I
think you have everything sign and
sealed because the color of my skin far
I will appeal say babyon I've come to
chop at your Shield
R ain't going nowhere no time soon
destruction of the Earth rising of the
Moon you plant in your garden and wish
it would blue you're CH in Satan's truth
is
there so far away go
oh what I say so I said
so so far away oh
[Music]
Lord Mother Earth was meant for man and
woman to stay but I see so many of you
drifting away children can't even find
the place to play birs can't find no
seeds in the horses no hey see the
weepers Weeping and it's every single
day I see the Searchers searching for a
bright away oh B long can you hear what
I
say I say going nowhere no time soon
destruction of the Earth the rising of
the Moon let your garden and wish it
would BL chanting sat is
never so far away
[Music]
go and don't you know we going to get it
on day so go nice it's so good good
good so far away
[Music]
oh
[Applause]
[Music]
hey
I just give me a microphone and I will
talk to them I say the people they and
as know they are my friends and they
will be until the
end I said what then the writing on the
wall is the message you send I know
that's will not be in my bread tread and
B long will never see the rising of your
son I
so I said so
[Music]