I don't know where our numbers stand and
all of this initiative drive but it's
kind of up to each one of us to get out
on the street here and and at least you
know get the people around us
energized you know get some petition
signed CU it's that time and we' got to
get it
done so uh here's a song for all the
people who love marijuana
[Music]
roll me a
split yes I'd love to take a whiff
wh me up the
fo so I can rub this
up take us up
a with be rocking in the deep deep grp
if you just roll
[Music]
it time to get yourself abundance in one
W length let your heart do the best
I mean we're speaking for this feeling
so what the what the anyway hey us
F yes we love to take the
wh wh me
up so I can Dr
[Music]
this prank us
up with be rocking in the deep deep
gr just a rolling
[Music]
a
time to get yourself up on this in one
way blanks and let your feet do the pay
I mean we're speaking for this feeling
so what the what the
anyway roll us a
SPL yes I'd love to check it
wh twist me up the
butd so I rup
this bring me up a
do with me rocking in the
mood just rolling
[Music]
n
he
[Music]