[Music]
marijuana
GC sweet
SAA tick
Queen s meia
Delta
N Smoke the
gja all the
time we got to free the
weed take back the
plant we got to take the
[Music]
lead Freedom
Fighter we must
unite fight the power the time is right
cuz we are the
children of the earth
Supreme our right
to the hippie
dream we got to free the
weed take back the
plant we got to plant our
seeds take it to
[Music]
I Swift s
sister
W talking Freedom
[Music]
now the
polican in the
sky arrest my brothers and sisters for
getting
high in the
prison they rocked away
just wait now we'll have our Judgment
Day we got to breathe the
weed take back the
plant we got to take the
lead take back the plant oh yeah wo wo
wo take back the plant take it
to oh
[Music]
take back the plant