one of the important things that I feel
uh for people to know and one of the
main reasons that I'm doing the things
that I
do are because of Jack Jack and for
those of you who are unaware Jack herrer
is a man that you if you've had anything
to do with cannabis in about the last
what 30 years or so you basically owe
this man a big thank you and
unfortunately he is no longer with us to
thank so one of the things that I wanted
to do at this first Hempfest in Tacoma
that we're uh we're going to this
afternoon is we're going to have a
moment of silence for Jacker at 420
instead of the usual Hempfest 420 moment
which uh has been surprising quite a few
people today when they've heard about
that they're they're waiting to hear you
know how many blunts you going to be
thrown out and it's was like absolutely
none we're going to be dead quiet for
for one moment and we're all going to
pay attention to the people that have
been lost for this movement um Mark
Emory is a man that's uh sitting in a
prison up 30 miles from where I stand
right now and he's in jail actually he's
not in jail he's in a federal prison for
selling seeds this is a holdover from
the bush era drug war it's ridiculous
it's ridiculous that Canada allowed a
Canadian citizen to be extradited for a
crime that only holds a $200 fine in his
country at worst at the absolute worst
he was looking at a $200 fine in his
country they extradited him and gave him
to a country a foreign country that is
almost that were trying to get him life
in prison for selling seeds to a plant
that we all know is not harmful is not
going to hurt anybody and is not worth
life in prison for and U that's that's
one of the main main drives that I've
got um if if more people kind of
understand just how important Jack carer
was and the research that he did and
just that the awareness that he brought
to people uh one of the things that I
found I'm a 38-year old male I've been
using cannabis since I was 7 years old
um when I first read the emperor wears
no clothes I was 17 years old and it
completely changed my outlook and
attitude on Canabis I had no idea how
much information was actually out there
and reading that book and understanding
how much research and just devotion you
have to have to find these things that
have been deceptively hidden by the
government for decades that takes some
effort and that that deserves some
recognition and I think that a lot of
the newer generation of people that are
being exposed to cannabis don't
necessarily understand how important the
people are that have gone before you
because what they're not seeing is how
those people influence people like me
people like you people like anybody that
does this kind of thing anybody that
does the you know work for the Canabis
community at the level that I that I
feel I do they know of these guys you
know they treat up with some respect and
you think about the history involved you
know guys like Ed rosenal so there's so
many people I couldn't name them all but
the all the Breeders that have ever come
up with anything that you've ever tried
that you've enjoyed or you've heard
about or heard those are the people that
you know you don't necessarily need to
be go go patting them on the back or
anything but at least give them a little
bit of thought instead of just you know
where's your next bag coming from and
what what's it going to be and you know
strive for some Perfection these people
gave a lot over the course of their
lives and it deserves some recognition
but this this this this testimony right
here is proof Jack that that you might
be going front us but you'll never leave
us bro love you Jack