up here we got two of the gentlemen
very very behind the i-1068 campaign for
legalization of marijuana in washington
state this year
if you've seen any of these petitions
around or heard about this it's probably
because of one of these two guys or one
of the many hundreds of volunteers
across the state that are busting their
asses to get the signatures to do all
this all of you people that are out here
signing all these petitions for every
other petition outside of 1068 every one
of these guys is a paid signature gather
all of the 1068 signature gatherers are
unpaid volunteers and we have got
hundreds of thousands of signatures so
far without the financial incentive
behind it and that's because this is
what people want in this state in this
country for this life
so let's get together and get 1068
signed if you've signed anything else
here today and you have not signed 1068
please do so before you leave get your
friends to do so tell your parents tell
everybody
sign this thing whether you want it
legal or you don't stay you can't stand
it it doesn't matter get on the ballot
and vote for it that's how this country
works
so now a couple words from these guys
so i've been a little too busy gathering
you know signatures to actually prepare
speech so i guess i'll have to ad hockey
my name is chris van putten and i i
coordinate the volunteer efforts
throughout pierce county on behalf of
i-1068 to legalize marijuana
so some people ask me how did you come
to do that
how did you come to become a coordinator
on behalf of 1068
well i volunteered
i started gathering signatures and i
kept gathering signatures and after i
kept gathering signatures and no one
started stepping up as a coordinator i
was selected and i said hey i want to
help other people gather signatures too
originally i guess it all started you
know last fall
started learning about marijuana before
i just been brainwashed stigma publicity
government right i learned about it i
read i read studies after study and the
more i read the less prohibition made
sense
so
after i saw the 1068 was out
signed the initiative
write it
realize i have to make the change i have
to help other people make the change
when we want to see a change in the
world we have to make that change and we
have to let the people
vote on the change and let the
government reflect the popular opinion
of society and my opinion of how the
world should be
doesn't coincide with how it is
so it's then my prerogative
to coordinate and to help
reform society and help all of you
to help 1068 and legalize marijuana
hello tacoma
hey i'm don skacky with initiative 1068
i'm the northwest washington field
director and we are getting it done
and like you've been told
none of us are paid everybody's been out
on the streets they've been out in bad
weather cold weather cloudy weather
sunny weather hot weather they're
getting it done but actually they're not
getting it done you are all getting it
done because without you we can't put on
the ballot our polling says that when
you talk to voters
say yes 35
say no
that is way beyond a margin of error all
we need to do is get it on the ballot
and people will vote yes but if we don't
get it on the ballot you're not gonna
have your chance they're gonna send it
back to the legislature where they can
screw it all up like they tried to sell
it in liquor stores early this year that
doesn't fly with my medicine next to
dangerous alcohol that's right
put this on the ballot if you have not
signed the 1068
register to vote if you're not already
registered sign it if you have not
already signed it and more importantly
we are in the process of counting right
now and we've got a margin of error of
seven and a half percent
and that is because of people like you
that know that once you've signed it
that you've done
and because of all volunteers that i'm
checking to make sure that you don't
sign it more than one time
but lately we've had some problems with
other signature gatherers from paid
petitions claiming to be us
so at this point
it can't hurt
if if you're sure you've signed 1068
please don't sign it again
but if you're not sure if you don't
remember if it was that one or not
or if you thought it was 1068 but when
you look at our sheet take the time to
look at what you're signing
make sure it's 1068 and get it signed
we've got
this event we've got taste of tacoma
we've got hoopfest and spokane we've got
gay pride up in seattle this weekend we
have every other thing that's happening
in the state and i can tell you from as
someone that sat there in that offices
the last couple of days and counted
signatures we're looking at the numbers
and they are damn close people they are
so close that we are either going to or
going to not make it on the ballot by
the slimmest of margins so
talk to everyone you know
ask them to sign
ask them to volunteer
pick up a petition out of the stranger
this week if you put one signature on it
and mail it in awesome if you put five
on it god bless you and if you put your
phil 20 it up you'll be one of the ones
that has changed history and ended
prohibition in washington
state i can't tell you how often i've
stood out for hours and had
person after person come up to me and
say
you know
i can't sign this i my boss will uh
won't let me my government won't let me
all you're signing is to put it on the
ballot so the people can decide
your vote will be secret november
don't let anyone tell you that you can't
sign this because you'll lose your job
this is your first amendment right to re
address i'm sorry to petition your
government for addressing grievances and
when you look at the 14 000 people that
will be released from prison
and all the hundred millions of dollars
and
and mark emery god bless you
mark emery isn't plucked out of canada a
sovereign country a sovereign citizen
and a taken to america and put in a
solitary confinement for trying to get
medicine done
legalize marijuana for adults in
washington state
we're responsible
we can handle it we can it's only a plan
it won't hurt you okay just in case any
of you are unaware
of what you are holding in your hands
the picture of mark emery that you see
before you this is a picture of a man
that is held in a federal penitentiary
not 30 miles from where we are standing
today facing life imprisonment for
selling seeds
this is a crime in his country there's a
200 fine for it and that's it in this
country he's looking at life in prison
so based on the fact that this guy has
been doing everything he can for about
the last 20 plus years to make your life
better if you've smoked pot in the last
20 years you've smoked something that
mark emery was responsible for i
guarantee it you owe this man a lot more
than any of you know
so what we're going to do for him
currently incarcerated 30 miles that
direction is we're all going to say
three words very loud together a few
times and we're going to send them a
message we are going to say free mark
emery
free mark emery
free mark
thank you
and it is 420 people but we are again
asking you to not smoke anything in the
park
the last thing from 1068
do your duty and sign that petition do
your duty and vote your conscience in
november
but let's eliminate the basis
for a lot of people in washington's
convictions where they can't get housing
they can't get educational loans they
can't get jobs all because they made a
choice safer than alcohol and i said it
in fremont and i'll say it here i'm a
working man i want to go to work i want
to support my family i want to pay my
taxes
and i want to make a choice that's safer
than alcohol and i don't want to go to
jail for having made that choice
thank you
thank you everybody for showing up for
this coma hemp fest staying calm helping
everybody out following the non-smoking
rule in the park for tobacco
and uh just kind of help it out in
general if any of you see anybody that
needs a hand please try and lend a hand
if you see garbage that's overflowing
you see anybody with one of these help
shirts on out here let them know we're
trying to get it cleaned up we want to
be able to come back we need your help
to get the city to let us do that next
year if you don't want to travel to
seattle to go to one of these help us
keep it here help us grow it bigger
and if you register to vote here you can
sign the petition at the same time
all right everybody we're about ready to
get the pa going back up get some music
going again so thank you very much for
attending the first annual tacoma
headfest brought to you by eatonfly and
tacoma help company