[Music]
I want to tell y'all a little bit about
a plant I know that can save the world
it grows long and tall and has flowers
that can make your mind swirl it's a
funky plant with a five that is
resistant to rain and mold it's the
strongest plant five and known to man
the best rope you'll ever hold well the
Pioneers covered up the wagon trains
with a canvus made of hemp and
Washington and Jefferson grew it on
their Farms said to make the most of it
the first Stars and Stripes were swn on
him the first constitution too this is
around the world for food fiber oil
medicine and Fuel and if we press seeds
we won't have no need for any other oil
we can make paints and we run our car
we'll go back next season it'll fix the
soil the mostut see we can put in the
mouth with Omega 6 and3 we can feed the
world with the tree of life and live
sustainably but if we gun down all the
trees we won't have nowhere to fre grow
Fields the pimp instead we can make our
paper build the house from it it's the
grow Wild and Free Living the way that
we ought to be going to leave my
children a better world to my ancestors
left
wo
[Music]
wo marijuana plant they have to call it
dope can also be made into oil or rope
some people say you smoke it and you
feel fantastic but from hemp you can
make an alternative to plastic made from
plants not petroleum so it won't still
be around in 403 it can bio to grade
which means a vess pollution just
another reason for a head
[Music]
Revolution
with the flowers the female H plant make
the best medicines on Earth helps Cancer
and a patients eat their food helps
those with depression overcome the blue
gloma epilepsy nausey insomnia stress
steros psychos P PMS all the studies
have been done and all the doctors agree
but they can't make money out this PL
see because it's free it grows from a
seed while them free like we are to be
you know the future it's grown in our
own
backyards we cut down all the trees we
won't have nowhere to be we go fields of
P we can make our Pap for the house for
God his going Wild and Free Living the
way that we are be going to leave my
children a better world than my
ancestors left
me wo
wo
La wo wo
[Music]
oh
in the mid 1930s it was the billion
dollar crop with the invention of the
the quarter that they can produce a
nonstop but then a smear campaign with
Mexicans the blame thought of making
people thinking to make your brain go
pop yeah since then it's never stopped
it ain't like getting high for paint and
crack rock time to bring it back to
Nature time to bring back some life let
the farmers do their job stop giving
them strip renewable resources
life-giving forces panels for your cars
and saddles for your horses do mon
making the wrong choices suicide jeans
extinguishing our voices cutting down
the trees polluting the Seven Seas
leaving the F of the planet to the
corporate entities corrupt politics
Warfare disease now it's time to make a
change it's time to plant seeds NRI you
the oil seeds it gives you all the
protein you will ever need you can make
it in a sandwich with jelly or Jam won't
make it in a soap or a lotion for your
hands you can make it in the fuel put it
right in our cars and we won't need the
oil and won't have to start water you
can make it into paper right as much as
you please cuz it grows like a weed and
we won't have to cut trees so put your F
that H such a versatile plan and don't
let the government tell us we can cuz H
can help us all in so many ways and it
doesn't mean that we will all be living
in a days versatility sustainability
look at history it ain't no mystery H
for
victory we down all trees W have nowhere
to can make our the house got going Wild
and Free Living the way that we are
people my children a better world than
my ancestors left
me wo
[Music]
wo