President Obama famously said in 2012
after the Colorado and state of
Washington votes when asked you know
were they going to interfere he said he
I figure fish to fry and has been quite
clear that there are other things with a
perfectly legal that are more
problematically interest the
clarification with Deputy Attorney
General Cole sending out parameters by
which the federal government is is going
to not fry those smaller fish
unfortunately there are 93 US Attorney's
some of whom have been frightened small
fish and we saw an outrageous case here
in Oregon this summer where the US
Attorney's Office was going to prosecute
and Native American teenager by all
accounts an exemplary young man for the
possession of the equivalent of
marijuana cigarette which as you pointed
out introduction has been decriminalized
in Oregon since 1973 I mean it was just
stunning and several of the delegation
were inquiring as to what their
prosecutorial priorities are are there
not any drug kingpins organized crime
white-collar crime what the hell are you
doing and they ultimately dropped it but
there is absolute schizophrenia with the
DEA which is out of step with the
president and his pronouncements in fact
it took them until last year to actually
acknowledge publicly that marijuana is
not more dangerous than methamphetamines
a stunning admission
on their part but you've you've seen
maybe the weekend news and The
Washington Post to talked about the
failures of DEA to deal with the opioid
epidemic that is literally killing tens
of thousands of people in recent years I
think we're in a situation where
Secretary Clinton if she's elected will
build on that I think she is quite open
to dealing with fixing that the two big
problems that the industry has in terms
of taxation and in terms of banking and
allowing the states to go their separate
ways I am optimistic that Congress will
make the job easier but i think a
clinton administration will build on the
foundation perhaps move it a little
further and in trouble i don't know i
mean this is a man who doesn't agree
with himself alibi out
and as God is my witness I i if he said
that he was either going to prosecute to
legalize we don't know that he would say
the next day and he doesn't know what
he'd said interesting but mercifully I
think we will be spared the specter of
him trying to figure out what his
beliefs are that he would inflict on the
American public at least through
government will still have any quick
turn off the television shut down the
computer or hold the newspaper don't
hold the newspaper getting to the
newspaper turn off those other sources
will stop covering
[Music]
[Applause]