we're watching where people understand
that the insane policy of forcing a
state legal marijuana business to be
conducted on an all cash basis actually
I I have thank you for reminding
everybody how old I am I've been working
on this issue for a long time I have
never met a human being regardless of
how they feel about whether marijuana
should be legal or not I've never met
one person who feels that there's any
rationale to force it to be conducted in
all cash basis and we're gaining support
we have bipartisan support for
legislation to deal with fixing that
item and 280e I met with several hundred
tax practitioners this morning several
of whom were really concerned that again
state legal marijuana businesses cannot
fully deduct their business expenses so
they have an effective tax rate that's
two three four times what a typical
business with that and when I introduced
that legislation at my press conference
was Grover Norquist the Republican you
no no no tax pledge guy who convenes all
the conservative activists in Washington
DC on a weekly basis and Grover was
there sort of indicated this is not
partisan what I think is going to happen
since we have eight states OD it's going
to pass in California i was there again
last friday going to arizona this week
where it's a head medical marijuana will
pass in florida I
with at least seventy percent yes vote
and even though it's just mega Florida
will become the second largest legal
marijuana market in America so what you
are seeing is the momentum that is
building we've got people who have been
supportive of these and there's going to
be a tipping point where over 270
million people will be in states for
some form of marijuana business is legal
at the state level so I think the game's
going to break we're going to get an
opportunity for the banking to be taken
care of Chewie and ultimately I think
we're going to also have the damn brake
as it relates to research there's been a
little loosen with DEA we have
bipartisan support for a piece of
legislation that would really unable
marijuana research be conducted with the
same sort of provisions and safeguards
as other controlled substances which now
it's more stringent for marijuana so I
think we're watching this year with
those election results in less than
three weeks changing the dynamics on the
bath on the ground with the momentum
that we've built I think it's all about
a turn in the next conference