[Music]
well come climb the mountain with me
come see what we can see come climb the
mountain with me and then we will all be
free
some man are born to lead some men have
Destiny but some men plant the seed and
some men set it free
[Music]
so come climb the mountain with me come
see what we can see come climb the
mountain with me and then we will all be
[Music]
free one man said we must hear one man's
voice was clear one man heard the call
his vision speaks for all
[Music]
so come open your eyes with me and come
see what you can see it's time for the
world to know the emperor wears no
clothes come open your eyes with me it's
time for you to see it's time for the
world to know the emperor wears no
clothes it's time for the world to know
the emperor wears no clothes the emperor
wears no clothes the emperor wears no
clothes the
emperor wears no clothes