Thank you for taking time for him.
Tonight on our show, we have a very
unusual and a unique guest. Unusual in
the sense that he has spent a lifetime
defending the sanctuary of the
individual and trying to bring it bring
bring about the importance that
government stays out of the individual's
life and the individual's allowed to
make their own choices. Brent, he's a
futurist. He's able to foresee farther
down the road than many of his
contemporaries and tries his best to
bring forth his knowledge and his
insights. Please welcome on our show Dr.
Timothy Larry. Well, Casper, it's a
pleasure to be here. I uh approve very
highly of your program. I understand
it's growing nationwide now. Yes, sir.
Yes, sir. How many uh cities are you in
now? At present, we're in 80 cities and
in 44 states. Oh, boy. That's good. And
uh getting the word out like this is
very exciting. Uh now you've always been
known as the highest rider of every
generational wave. The what? The highest
rider of every generational wave. You've
been the forefront. You've been there
from from the World War II to the early
60s, the '7s, able to, you know, speak
the voice and be heard and foresee it.
Realizing this, how do you think the
wave of the hemp movement is going to
settle into the population and break
upon the the uh shores of our ecology
problems?
Frank, the shores are ecology problem.
Yes, sir. I can see that. Oceans of
green hemp doing
that.
Um,
the present laws against hemp, I think,
are the most
irrational and uh I would say almost
insane pieces of puritanic legislation.
Maybe you have to go back to the Salem
witchcraft trials to get something where
so much hysteria has picked out
something so benign and so harmless and
so profitable and so productive and had
this all out moral fierce religious
campaign against uh
hemp. Why do you think that uh there is
this uh religious fundamentalist and
police government uh prejudice against
him? Well, how do you explain it? My
personal views that I feel that it stems
from a lot of the uh well companies and
the people who can make money off it
being illegal, keeping it illegal and
together put together a propaganda
campaign to mislead the public
and I feel that it will set into u the
people's mind eventually when the truth
is more exposed. Now you I understand
that we're not going to talk about the
religious or the emotional psychological
aspects of hemp. Correct. The
recreational. Yeah, we won't talk about
that at all. We're going to talk about
the uh
practical uh and the profitable and
productive. Yes, sir. And the ecological
aspects of it. Absolutely. Uh I don't
know a lot about that. I've read books
by Jack Herrer. I've listened. Gosh,
there's so many programs and so many
articles these days. Everywhere you turn
around, you hear intelligent discussions
about hemp as a substitute for oil. Hemp
as a substitute for wood pulp. Hemp as a
source of energy. It's exciting. The the
thing that I know most about however is
the uh puritanical crusade against hemp
because you know I I I was in prison for
four and a half years for under an ounce
right for the possession of two roaches
which had been planted in my car by a
generous overly generous policeman. Um
and uh at one point I found myself in
prison facing like 50 years
imprisonment. I was 50 years at the
time, 50 years old going, "Well, this is
a strange series of events for such a
harmless u and even beneficial situation
to be charged with so much time." Um,
now you escaped from there, too, didn't
you? The first Well, I did what any
sensible 50-year-old would do if you're
facing 50 years in prison for two
roaches of marijuana they planted in
your car. Uh, the only common sense
thing to do is to escape. and I did that
and uh made a few little be movie
adventures there.
U there are there are many things in our
society that have to be controlled and
governed. Uh for example, oil look at
the way oil is polluting and um um our
atmosphere and acid rain and so forth.
Uh guns should be controlled. I think
drugs like steroids should be
controlled. I think there should be
probably more control over alcohol and
nicotine and the but of all
the of all of the uh botanical
vegetable species that the government is
attacking, marijuana is the one they're
going after. That's interesting. You
know, I sometimes say that um hemp is is
a is a is a democratic plant because it
was during the Democratic uh regime of
Jimmy Carter that uh hemp was legalized
in 14 states and uh Carter himself and
his cabinet wanted to decriminalize
marijuana. And in 1980, you had uh the
Republicans coming in with a hard line,
typical crush them, down him, just say
no. Yeah. And suddenly the new drugs
which are everywhere are drugs that I
never heard of back in the 60s and the
late 70s. Things like crack and cocaine
and steroids. Uh they they didn't exist.
So I call them the Republican drugs. Now
they're Republican drugs. Why? Because
Republicans are hardliners like to feel
tough and aggressive. And I'm number
one. And we're going to go over there
and we're going to know kick butt. Mhm.
And if you're going to go out there and
you loot a lot of savings and loans
companies and if you're going to go out
there, you know, you got to have a lot
of energy and you got a lot of
self-confidence. You got to take to up
with cocaine or a little steroids there.
Arnold Schwarzenegger, of course, is the
typical example of the of the steroid.
we call him Conan the Republican, you
know, whereas uh the one thing about the
the use of of hemp as a uh as a as a
drug, I've had to warn Republicans about
this. If you're a Republican and you're
a hardliner and you want to go out there
and kick and scratch and get yourself to
the top and if you're in the army or the
police or anything, you ought to have to
be tough and mean and stay away from him
cuz he will turn you into a wimp. I
mean, really, look at Carter. He was
believing in peace and love and we stop
all the wrong things, right? All the
terrible things. All the terrible
things. You understand why? Right now,
the government is spending much more
money crushing the the production of
hemp. And another thing that puzzles me
about the insanity or the even the
diabolical nature of the right-wing
religious Republican situation.
U why do they go after the American
farmers? They spend more money fighting
hemp in this country. You know, in in in
California, which is my home state, uh,
hemp was the number one agricultural
cash product. In Iowa, in Tennessee,
like back in Indiana, where I'm from,
how many states? Uh, at least that we're
aware of 28 or more. Yeah. Honest
farmers out there trying to make a
living of growing hemp. And the
government is out there arresting these
goodhearted free enterprise farming
agricultural Americans. Meanwhile, down
in Colombia and Peru,
these gangsters, these cocaine cartel
people are making billions of dollars
and we're spending less money on them.
It's a how come I think you're probably
right that
uh they uh they don't want people to be
using hemp because it would interfere
with the oil monopoly. It would
interfere with the wood pulp monopoly.
Uh, and also I
think there's something really
religiously diabolic and evil about the
right-wing Christians in this country
who go after him because they hate
people to have pro-choice and to make
your own decisions about your life and
uh they seem to be some of the people
too who overlook the medical aspects of
Absolutely. Yeah. Yeah. Now, from your
perspective and being in being a
psychiatrist as you are, you've had the
opportunity to become acquainted with
many different aspects of healing and
some of the some of the more positive
benefits of the uses of hemp. Could you
share that please?
Well, there have been enormous number of
studies that show that hemp and cannabis
is of course extremely necessary for
certain forms of glaucoma. You simply
have to have it. Mhm. There in many
states these these fanatic anti-pleasure
people are so afraid that the patient
who's going blind might enjoy the
experience that you got to go blind you
to die but don't have a good time
because the Republicans are in power. I
mean that's apparently the logic here.
Aren't they using it too for anorexia
and for cancer aids? Exly. me. There's
one terrible thing about hemp and I
don't want to get into the u you know
the use of marijuana but I got to be
honest with you there are some terrible
side effects of smoking or using
marijuana. One is
um it's called refrigerator blackout. I
mean you get the munchies. Oh okay. You
know you suddenly you smoke a joint and
suddenly you there you are the next
thing you know you've eaten nine pounds
of fig noon and say that that now that's
that's dangerous. You got you got to be
careful there. Uh on the other hand, if
you're dying of cancer or malnourished
because of stomach problems and you
don't have any appetite, hemp of course
is the logical and obvious and natural
medicine to give you an appetite to see
you through that period. But again, a
good true Puritan would rather have you
die.
Now, we have a good meal while you're
giggling.
We also know that it's good for stress
to calm you down. And from a viewpoint
of a psychiatrist, is there any benefits
for someone who might be having
emotional or mental problems as opposed
to giving them like
um volumes or some of these other
stronger drugs that seem to be causing
problem like Prozac and so on? Yeah.
Well, number one, I don't want to come
out like a smart smartass here and every
psychological situation is individual
and needs its own u you know its own
pharma pharmacology. So I don't want to
generalize um but certainly uh the
things about hemp is it's not addictive.
It's extremely uh harm doesn't have any
of the side effects of uh many of the
euphorics and the
anti-depressants that are approved and
that doctor's prescriptions will give
you. So uh yeah there's a
uh you see the thing about religious
fanaticism is that the crazier the
nuttier the wilder and almost the more
nonsensical the belief the more you hang
on to it. So that um I've debated for
many years a man who was the head of the
DEA for about five years name is Peter
Beniger. Yeah, you have. And I can't
believe him. He's going after hemp. And
he's trying to say that oh hemp
one they gave a lot of some some mice
some hemp and it made male mice, teenage
male mice and it made their breasts grow
a little. So he say college boys you see
going why is he going? the real problems
of cracked babies in the in the inner
city and alcohol which was our number
one drug here and uh nicotine half a
million people die a year from that.
Here's this guy blathering on about the
the dangers of of uh
of I don't know he never did mention
whether uh whether marijuana would make
girls breasts bigger but I don't even
want to get into that. The whole thing
is now you've also had a few debates
with Gordon Litty too. Yeah, that's
right. Yeah. and uh he seems to think
that uh marijuana i.e. camp is one of
the um the plants that's going to lead
to a complete social breakdown and our
structure of government and you see well
I know Gordon Lady uh I've been debating
him I've known him for years over 25
years I know exactly how his mind works
and like a good army man like a good
military man like a good policeman like
a good follower of his leader uh Richard
Nixon okay Gordon Litty has never had
one unauthorized thought in his life. So
he he reads the the line so he knows.
But what LSD makes you jump out of
windows. Uh marijuana makes you uh what
is that? Not I forget what it is. I say
it's the gateway drug. Yeah. What's the
gateway drug? Yeah. It's the gateway
drug. Yeah. So uh
um I see I must say here and I don't
want to offend anyone and if you're a if
you're a deeply uh devout Christian I
want you to turn your TV off now. But uh
I feel that there's a great problem in
this country in a violation of our civil
liberties and personal rights on the
basis of the federal government
interfering with women's bodies about
abortion and uh the uh these insane war
on drugs. It's a war on drugs. It's a
war on Americans. It's not a war on
Russians or evil communists and all
that. You made us a war against 40 or 50
million of us marijuana smokers in this
country, which in a way seems like a
weird thing that uh majority in Congress
should suddenly declare war on 30
million otherwise taxpaying uh
reasonably productive American citizens.
Um the
uh I think that uh the basis is
religion. Okay. And basis is that you're
not
allowed to choose what you want to do.
It's like any fanatic religious they'll
tell you you can't use contraceptives
because you can't enjoy sex. And if you
do
have conceive a baby, you have no choice
about whether you want to uh bring this
baby when you can handle this baby. And
the same thing is true about u about u
the choice of uh of your own
self-medication. And uh I I personally
believe that u the war on drugs is the
worst attack on American freedom that
we've experienced in in 200 years. You
know this is the 200th anniversary of
the Bill of Rights. It was in 1791 that
they passed those 10 wonderful bills and
the basically what most people don't
realize is that the Bill of Rights in
the Constitution is designed to protect
the individual against the government.
Mhm. So, the government can't come into
your house without a search warrant. The
government can't put u soldiers in your
house. The government can't force you to
uh to testify against yourself. The
government can't tell you what to read
or write. The government can't tell you
how to worship your own god. The
government can't tell you how to really
mind your own business. So, um uh it's
both ironic and I think it's also very
hopeful that in the year uh 1991 in the
200th anniversary of the Bill of Rights,
uh this hemp movement is is growing. And
I want to tell you it is growing. I give
a lot of talks to uh to students and
colleges and the awareness of the
insanity of the marijuana laws is
becoming uh I think more and more
obvious. That tells us that perhaps we
are finally making an impact across the
United States and perhaps around the
world. We are really enjoying this
interview and we'll be right back after
this. Thank you. Welcome back to Time
for Him. Today on our show we have the
distinguished Dr. Timothy Liry. Timothy,
I think you've been aware of some of the
changes in the laws here within the
American uh structure of Congress and
all the way down to dog catcher opinions
from Nancy Reagan swaying our opinions
to just say no. Uh I have a
mot and a bumper sticker and a t-shirt.
It says just say K. No, think for
yourself and don't believe what Nancy
Reagan says. Don't believe what I say.
think for yourself and question
authority and uh you'll uh well because
of this conservatism though some of the
laws that were established during the
Carter administration such as um
decriminalization of of marijuana etc
are beginning to go back to another era
back when minds were narrow and Alaska
they've changed the laws back to stiffen
the laws we are going through a period
now it's a uh what happened in the 60s
and 70s we had in this country a Classic
Renaissance. Now read the history books.
A renaissance is a period when there's a
sudden surge in self-exression in the
rights of the individual, a loosening of
the control of authority, a questioning
of religious dogma, and then a lurch
forward. This is always followed by a
hardlined retreat. So that it's at the
same time that u there has uh in the
last 10 years in America under Reagan
and Bush and this very repressive hard
line, look what's happened to the rest
of the world. Um, you
know, in in Russia just uh 3 weeks ago
when they had that uh coup and then uh a
bunch of young people in in Moscow
protected Yelen and and stop the tanks.
You know who it was that was stopping
the tanks? It was young Russians
students who were throwing flowers at
the tanks. That sounds familiar, doesn't
it? Does that sound familiar? They
learned that absolutely from the
American um uh in the 60s and 70s when
we were questioning the authority of of
Johnson and and Nixon and stopping the
Vietnam War. Uh uh another thing that
was amusing about the the Russian
Revolution and it's very connected with
this the three men who young men who got
shot by the tanks and were immediately
promoted to the highest office or honor
of the Soviet Union. the highest order
of of the of the of the land. They were
three hippies. They had one was a
grateful dead
head and one like heavy metal rock and
uh they let their hair grow and they all
had learned to smoke a hashish in
Afghanistan. And indeed they were trying
to stop the tanks because it was their
brothers and their friends and their
colleagues who were in the tanks because
the uh there turned out that the the
Soviet soldiers that have been sent to
Afghanistan hated the idea of going down
there and uh killing Afghani people for
no apparent reason. So that I'm very
proud of the fact that although in
America we've had this uh this very
predictable but very violent and mean
and nasty Puritanism and you can't smoke
cigarettes and there's they're censoring
uh rock and roll records and they're
censoring books. Now one by one they're
going down the list of personal
freedoms. At the same time, the basic
American freedoms which we uh set going
in the 60s are appearing in the Soviet
Union. I go with you and ours are
reversing it seems like. Yeah. It seems
like the hemp issue could be one of the
last strong divides that we face as a a
body of people in America. One everybody
seems to have an opinion. Everybody
seems so upset.
The hemp issue is the place where you
can draw the line. And uh anyone who's
watching this program in in your city,
there's obviously a uh a channel which
is carrying this message, get in touch
with the people that are producing this
show in your locality. And uh start
embarrassing your local politicians by
asking them, for example, of of your
congressmen and assembly men and women,
how many of you smoked marijuana when
you were young? Huh? We know that about
80% of the members of Congress under the
age of 50 were smoking marijuana. How
come they could do it? and we can't do
it. There's even been reported rumors
that people all the way up to the White
House may have been involved too. White
Oh my god. We do know that Ronald Reagan
u u smoked marijuana because that came
out in the book by Kitty Kelly when
Ronald Reagan was governor of California
used to smoke marijuana and and you know
when you think about it when you think
about it that explains everything about
poor Ronnie Reagan. It shows you why
Republicans should not smoke marijuana.
Why is that? Well, the amnesia, you
know, the forgetfulness, the short-term
memory loss, the cheerful, hey, what's
wrong, baby? Everything's fine, even
though the the country's going down.
Yeah. Okay. The the long naps after
lunch, you know. I mean, Ronnie, come
on. Leave marijuana alone. No, by the
way, both Ronnie's children, um, Ron Jr.
and Betty Davis, uh, of course, kind of
silly. The point I'm making here about
the place I think to take a stand,
abortion rights is one place, but
marijuana and you can do it. The way to
do it is through humor. Write letters to
the editor. Uh challenge uh politicians
as to whether they really think that
alcohol is more dangerous than
marijuana. And if so, why? and uh on a
very common sense, logical, friendly, uh
humorous. Uh you've always been one for
the wit and to tickle people with a
laugh and make them think. I've noticed
you do what you can to stimulate the
mind in a fun way. That's the aim of the
game. I think that's oftenimes why
you've been so misconstrued by your
contemporaries. They they can't take a
joke.
Well, uh good. I'm glad I misunderstood.
Um the uh the number one way to bring
down any repressive authoritarian regime
is irreverence and I pride myself I
think I have a very high IQ that is
irreverence quotient and I have been a
leading denter in this country uh during
the uh the uh Johnson administration
during the Nixon administration I'm
proud to have been I'm proud that
Richard Nixon called me the most
dangerous man in America I mean after
all what an honor and yeah
really And I want to uh urge those of
you who just think for yourself. And u
the hemp issue is a wonderful issue to
bring people together because it it
brings together ecology. It brings
together a substitute for petroleum
which of course is the real Republican
addictive drug. It's such an
ecologically uh helpful situation. Uh
above all, it prevents us from cutting
down the Amazon rainforest for wood pulp
because or for um or cutting down for
fiber because we all know that hemp is
by far the best uh material. So that
there's something that's very wonderful
about a plant and and that human beings
kind of rally behind a plant. those five
wonderful leaves that kind of represent
uh wonderful and the great thing about
it is the rightwing Republicans and the
right-wing religious fanatics hate it
and you know why they hate it because it
makes people feel free and makes feel
people free feel uh funny and and
independent and u now I would if they if
they hate it it's got to be something
good about it that's my logic I would
shoot myself if I didn't ask this one
last question and that is oh my god
don't I know cuz so many people say you
had Timothy Liry there why didn't you
ask him in tried to shy away from the
recreational uses so we don't want to
make it a long respond but do you feel
that when consumed as a recreational uh
plant that it can bring you more in tune
with your own being with your own self
maybe put things into better perspective
or is it like liquor when you drink it
you're just so out of touch that you
don't know what's going on well I spent
40 years scientifically studying the
various botanical
vegetable gifts that the plant queendom
has given the mamlian animal kingdom and
there's no question in my mind that uh
the mushrooms and marijuana are the
greatest gifts given to us by the
vegetable the plant the
kingdom you can misuse marijuana
uh it does make you
uh there are like three dangerous Side
effects of marijuana. One is you kind of
see too much and that makes you kind of
a little uh a little spacey because you
know you you're you just do see so much.
And the second is short-term memory
loss. Like you forget what you were
talking about. And the third dangerous
side effect. I
forget. No. Um don't ever smoke
marijuana. Use marijuana. If you have if
you're going to go to school, uh if
you're going to do anything that
requires attention, concentration, just
absolutely stupid, do not use marijuana.
Marijuana should be used for moments of
u of uh of real celebration and of
glorification. And the one thing about
marijuana is it's not a loner. It's it's
something that you do with somebody
else. Okay. The idea that someone go off
and smoke marijuana by themselves, I
mean, it's ridiculous. Kind of like kind
of like doing this talk show that we've
had the chance to do today. Yeah, I want
to thank you very much for being a guest
on our show. I've been told by the side
people here on the sides that we need to
wrap it up and I tell you, you've really
had you've given us a lot of food for
our minds. Well, I'm all behind your
cause and it's an honor and pleasure to
be with you and thanks to the crew who
did a great job. Like to have you back
on again sometime. Okay. Thank
you. And the next time you see me,
remember that you'll know it's time for
him. So, please join in, look around,
tell your friends, get copies of the
show, send it off to governors, send it
off to senators, send it off to people
whose minds are closed, tell your
friends about it. If you are a victim of
this uh war on drugs and feel that
bringing your story to us might
enlighten it to the nation where we can
help make a change, please let us know.
If there's people in your community who
need to be focused on, please let us
know. And if you have a challenge
regarding any of our statements,
remember Jack Herer once said, $10,000
to anybody who comes on to this show and
disproves our findings. Jack Harer
stands behind that statement. It's an
honor to have him on our show. And
again, I'll look for you the next time.
Thank you.