right now
the government is spending much more
money crushing the production of hemp
and another thing that puzzles me
about the
insanity or the even the diabolical
nature
of the right wing religious republican
situation
why do they go after the american
farmers
they spend more money fighting hemp in
this country you know in california
which is my home state uh
hemp was the number one agricultural
cash product in iowa in tennessee and
like back in indiana where i'm from how
many states uh at least that we're aware
of 28 or more yeah honest farmers out
there trying to make a living growing up
and the government is out there
arresting these good-hearted
free enterprise farming agricultural
americans meanwhile
down in colombia and peru these
gangsters the cocaine uh cartel people
are making billions of dollars and if
we're spending less money on them i said
how come i think you're probably right
that um
they uh they don't want people to be
using hemp do because it would interfere
with the oil monopoly it would interfere
with the wood pulp monopoly
and also i think
there's something really religiously
diabolic and evil
about the right-wing christians in this
country who go after him
because they hate people to have
pro-choice and to make your own
decisions about your life and they seem
to be some of the people too who
overlook the medical aspects absolutely
yeah now from your perspective and being
being a psychiatrist as you are you've
had the opportunity to become acquainted
with
many different aspects of healing and
some of the some of the more positive
benefits of the uses of ham could you
share that please
well there have been an enormous number
of studies that show that
that hemp and cannabis
is uh was extremely necessary for
certain forms of glaucoma you simply
have to have it
there
in many states
these fanatic anti-pleasure people are
so afraid that the patient who's going
blind might enjoy the experience that
you got to go blind you can die but
don't have a good time because the
republicans are in power that's
apparently the logic here are they using
it too for anorexia and for cancer
exactly aids i mean there's one terrible
thing about hemp and i don't want to get
into the uh you know the use of
marijuana but i got to be honest with
you
there are some terrible side effects of
smoking or using marijuana one is
it's called refrigerator blackout when
you get the munchies oh okay you know
you suddenly you smoke a joint and
suddenly you're there you are the next
thing you know you've eaten uh
nine pounds of fig newton and say that
now that's that's dangerous you got it
you gotta be careful there uh
on the other hand if you're dying of
cancer or uh malnu nourish because of
stomach problems and you don't have any
appetite hemp of course is the illogical
and obvious
and natural medicine to give you an
appetite to see you through that period
but again
a good true puritan we'd rather have you
die
now we all have a good meal while you're
giggling
we also know
that it's good for stress to calm you
down and from a viewpoint of a
psychiatrist is there any benefits
for someone who might be having
emotional or mental problems as opposed
to giving them like
valiums or some of these other stronger
drugs that seem to be causing problems
like prozac and so on
yeah
well number one i don't want to come out
like a smart
smart ass here and
every
psychological situation is individual
and needs its own uh you know it's on
pharma pharmacology so i want to
generalize
but certainly uh the things about hemp
is it's not addictive
it's extremely uh harm doesn't have any
of the side effects of uh many of the
euphorics
and the antidepressants
that are approved
and the doctor's prescriptions will give
you so uh
yeah there's a
you see the thing about religious
fanaticism is
that the crazier the nuttier the wilder
and almost the
more nonsensical the belief to already
hang on to it so that uh
i've debated for many years a man who
was the head of the dea for about five
years name is peter benson yeah she has
and i can't believe him he's going after
him but he's trying to say that
oh
him
they gave a lot of some some mice some
hemp and it made male mice
teenage male mice and it made their
breasts grow a little so he's like few
college boys he's even going to i think
why is he going the real problems of
crack babies and the inner city and uh
alcohol which was our number one drug
here
and uh nicotine
half a million people die here from that
here's this guy's blathering on about
the
dangers of uh
of uh
i don't know he never did mention
whether uh whether
marijuana would make girls breast
breaker but i don't want to get into
that the whole thing is now you've also
had a few debates with g gordon liddy
too yeah that's right
and uh he seems to think that uh
marijuana i.e hemp is one of the uh
the plants that's going to lead to a
complete social breakdown and our
structure of government
and you see well i know gordon liddy uh
i've been debating him i've known him
for years over 25 years
i know exactly how his mind works
like a good army man
like a good military man
like a good policeman like a good
follower of his leader uh richard nixon
okay gordon linney has never had one
unauthorized thought in his life
so he reads the line so he knows that's
what
lsd makes you jump out of windows uh
marijuana uh makes you uh what does that
not forget what it is it's the gateway
drug yeah it's a gateway drug it's the
gateway drug yeah