what we've got here the first thing I
should show you is this shirt this is
made of uh hemp with a blend with cotton
this is a 55% hemp 45% cotton it's
that's made of hemp 55% hemp correct it
lasts longer it's 26% more water
absorbent it's more insulative uh and
it's much stronger than regular cotton
would be wow um in the foreground here
I've got three pieces of paper one of
them this is like a parchment style
paper here this is what your Declaration
of Independence and Constitution were
originally written on a paper similar to
quality of this this is a filtration
paper here tea bags things that you need
to have stay strong when it's wet
because hemp fiber is strong it doesn't
lose that when it's in water this in the
middle is a looks like a newsprint type
of paper it's a pul type of paper and
made of huh correct uh did they use this
back in the early days you know like
around Constitution time or something
yeah well they didn't use this this is a
p paper they use more like this the
fiber um paper that's and they wrote on
it manuscript paper daily right now uh
over here we have some seed this is used
as bird seed right now yeah get the
birds high right yeah it's called Happy
Bird actually birds sing better um
because when they use it we don't know
if it's there's very little THC in there
it seems to be because it moistens their
throat because it has a lot of oil in
fact it's 30% oil and right next to it
here we have some hair gel this is made
from hemp oil and it's also got some
herbs in it some of the herbal hemp in
it now moving forward a little further
we see some other products that are made
from the seed when the seed is crushed
it produces uh oils
and a uh high protein powder here which
is called CA cake this is more
nutritional than any other thing that we
know of accepting for soya and in terms
of digestibility it's more digestible
than soya so it actually uh when you
look at parts of the world like um
northern Africa and bagladesh in these
areas where there's a lot Mass
starvation a lot of that is a result of
international laws that are preventing
them from growing hemp for use as a food
supply which it has been for thousands
of years for these count yes exactly the
law is the single convention Treaty of
1961 by the United Nations and you
notice that the big periods of
starvation began in the mid-60s late 60s
and continue on to today within 10 years
of banning hemp starvation became part
of the norm for these parts of the world
wow now these two pieces of oil uh I
mean samples of oil this is a raw oil
you see it's got a little brownish color
similar to the seed itself this on the
other hand has been distilled and so
it's cleaner looking um you can make
anything from machine oil to cooking oil
out of these wow these are all fibers
from the plant this is a rather Raw
fiber this is called a toe line both of
these are from Russian hemp Russian hemp
right now this string here and this rope
they're both from Hungarian hemp this
has been made into a bag here through a
macet process they've wrapped it up
here's a PO holder made out of it your
balls of twine this tea bag back in here
and it swings us right back down to the
plant from which all these products can
be made w