you know the other day I was on a TV
program when a moderator come on came on
he looked into the camera and said while
other candidates for Governor are
running on better schools and more roads
Gatewood Galer is running on legalizing
marijuana and I said hold it right there
Bob let's get something straight just
like these other candidates I Envision
better schools and I Envision more roads
and I did Envision delivery of healthc
care to the rural areas and feeding our
hungry and housing our homeless the only
difference between me and these other
candidates is that I figured out a way
to pay for it without putting it on the
shoulders of the already
over first day in office I'm going to
ground every helicopter the state of
Kentucky owns they're not
going there're not going to be
helicopters having over the fields and
Gardens of the people the state Kentucky
this is America not Afghanistan and
we're not an occupied territory I'm not
going to treat us like we
[Applause]
are it is obsene that we have 66 out of
kuy's 120 counties that can't even
afford to educate their own children and
yet the Kentucky public sending out
hundreds of millions of dollars and the
American public is sending out billions
of dollars in taxfree income to the
international criminal syndicates in
South America Mexico for a plant my
granddaddy used to grow by a thousands
of acres and I'm going to redirect that
money out of the hands of these
international criminal syndicates and
I'm going to put them into the Capital
Tax cers of frankfur so I can lift the
people of Kentucky out of poverty and
out of the misery and out of these last
place standard
that
and not only am I going to redirect this
money but I'm going to redefine the role
of government in policing private
behavior in the state of Kentucky we
live a poli State we live in a police
state you can be leave here go out and
get in your car and they can set up a
random road block in front of you make
you get out of your car bring a dog up
to sniff you your car and all his
belongings take blood out of the Yar
make you pee in the bottle and stick
their hands where the sun don't shine
that's a police state that's a please
take come
[Applause]
out you think John Wayne would put up
with
that that John's driving his horse down
the trail and they dro the log in front
of him said John get off that horse we
going to take blood out of the arm got
to pee in this bucket we're going to
stick our fingers up your
[Applause]
but think John Wayne would say I'm
afraid not
Pilgrim this is where I draw My Line in
the Sand and this is where we're Drawing
the Line in the Sand in the state of
Kentucky we're going to return privacy
and individual dignity and freedom each
and every individual in the state of
Kentucky and get the police out of the
business of promot promoting morality
and put them back in the business of
promoting Law and Order in the state of
Kentucky