joining us on the program is Debbie
goldsberry who's the co-founder the cab
cannabis Action Network acronym can
welcome to our show what is Ken all
about well cannabis action network is
what's called an unincorporated
association where a charity were a group
of people who have got together for a
common cause our cause or our goal is to
legalize cannabis okay now I've noticed
from being involved with the hemp
movement that it's not always that the
ladies seem to want to speak up or
they're not half there in the front
lines you are a good example someone
who's not intimidated by being out there
I think they're afraid for their
children I think they're afraid of the
repercussions that can happen in their
professional lives how do you do with
that let's see well I don't have
children that's easy professional life
no that's animal activist and what do
you tell you speak yeah um well
basically I think what it is it's a
difference between the way that male and
female are socialized in our country of
females are literally socialized to be
more in the background we find in the
marijuana movement what's going on that
when females do join the movement
they're working behind a table or
they're in some sort of a supportive
role usually they choose that position
because that's where would feel more
comfortable when a woman actually does
step forward there is a lot of
discrimination it have its not
discrimination solely within the
marijuana movement the whole entire
country if not the entire world however
that works but there is a lot within the
marijuana movement and that's like
everyone says there's a lot of
middle-aged men involved a lot of it is
the Washington DC political scene it's
been like this year for hundreds of
years okay um as far as getting more
people involved i think it's important
for women who are involved to stand up
and take a forward roll in a movement
that's what we're all about occasionally
i fear the reference the girls who can
the ladies that can sew and your
co-founder who else found put this
together with you let's see well the
cannabis Action Network wasn't actually
founded by all women or
girls what it started out with it was a
group of college students around the
state of Illinois along with national
normal in Wisconsin normal in the long
run when it came down to it after we
gone through a couple years let's see
what we didn't actually start can right
away i should say we started the him
tour project on cannabis action network
came after about a year a year of him
tours after we decided that we did need
to start some sort of a movement at that
time a group of us i guess you could say
friends got together a girl who were
friends and we started a national
organization so that's how now uteri
know from reading in High Times Magazine
I've been an association of course with
the hemp organization Anza you do go
coast to coast and you've had the
opportunity to see firsthand the
enthusiasm or lack of enthusiasm towards
the hip movement how strong of a body do
you think we have I think we have a very
strong body about enthusiastic
supporters out there what we found when
we go across the country it pretty much
goes with the marijuana laws in a place
like New York City or a state where
there's the decriminalization you know
just criminalisation law we don't get as
much support in a place where there's a
lot of harsh laws a lot of police
intimidation on we get a lot of support
basically what's happened is that the
more the government fights against us
the more that we the users the cannabis
supporters realize that we have to get
together and work three guys okay now
when you raise your voice in society you
raise it with strength and pride but a
lot of people still aren't being able to
have the opportunity to hear now do you
continue you kind of continue with hemp
tears and so how do you plan to continue
to promote them well the the way they
haven't or works is it has a couple
different levels it starts off at the
beginning level the beginning level is
to get our activists to find the people
who are interested in legalizing the
activist supporters who can carry on
bigger and better projects usually takes
a couple years in any given area to get
a good solid core of activists after
that we take we change the platform
instead of finding our activists what we
do is we want to educate the public we
would call that an eight or remain
focused or we bring along a national
speaker like jack herer lv music in the
medical marijuana patient that's the
point that we're at right now doing our
aid tours educational forums to reach
out into the public that false things
like debates and lectures public forums
after that Nets point threat right now
after this we plan on developing a new
strategy how do we get bigger how do we
get better our goal right now is to have
statewide conferences in every state get
the organizers together to meet at
roundtable discussions and to form or a
more direct political agenda lobbying
direct demonstration type of things ok
now you stamina Lexington Kentucky are
there chapters or other can
organizations across America that people
can contact to there are can
organizations cannabis Action Network is
not a membership organization it's a
network of organizations across the
country and activists involved in the
network we have about 200 organizations
it has grown exponentially two years ago
we only had five so instead of actually
encouraging people to become can
organizations we encourage people to
develop their own organization study
local drug policy come up with something
that will be effective right in their
hometown from touring coast to coast I
know you've had a chance to meet a lot
of people what have you seen firsthand
what injustice have you seen firsthand
that are stemming from the prohibition
laws that you really think need to be
immediately changed oh boy I've seen a
lot of injustice as the main thing that
I think is that we need to educate our
enforcement police departments basically
I could tell you a story about Oakland
California we were out in Oakland at a
Grateful Dead we had her what we do is
we set up pimp information tables
display books t-shirts and stuff like
that we had a permit to set up the table
or in at the Grateful Dead lot like I
said please come by they say where's
your permit we show them the permit they
say marijuana table permit this can't be
possible marijuana is illegal you can't
be here you can't do this they say we
have to call the sergeant hold on to the
permit so police officer has a permit
with their motorcycle cops the guy gets
on his motorcycle with the permit and he
leaves just leaves the other cops say
well it doesn't matter anyway because if
we would if you know even if you have
your permit we're going to park our
motorcycles right in front of your table
nobody's going to come up to your table
the sergeant comes he says where's your
permit we say permit the cop just drove
away with our permit he said you don't
have a permit you can't be here will
arrest you if you don't leave right now
so right there we have it it's the
discrimination against the marijuana
it's discrimination against the culture
and it's just a blatant violations in
that they don't really understand the
Constitution that's what we're trying to
do now you say you set up booths at the
Grateful Dead concert so any information
do you give to get out of these boots
well our main focus is what we call our
hemp museum we have different displays
of hemp products that come from around
the world right now you can import
products we display the seeds in the
seed cake the granola bars the cloth
different things like that we pass that
information we solve products that
display our message basically we feel if
somebody wears a t-shirt around with the
marijuana slogan tens of thousands of
people will see that message over there
of course the next couple years
excellent you know if you had the
opportunity to encourage somebody to to
join you would you encourage them to go
on the road working to their in their
own local areas or and how was you I
would you go about recruiting that
individual i would encourage each person
to choose their focus individually can
decide what your best designed to do
within this movement there are a million
facets that we need to inter cover
basically what do you tell ladies when
they come up and say i want to get
involved but i'm afraid if I do that
I'll lose my children well that's a
tough question um I tell people first of
all what they need to do is they need to
educate themselves when it comes to a
situation something like losing a child
number one you're going to be faced with
the authorities when you're faced with
the authorities that's basically what we
say is it's a it's an on-the-spot type
thing educate yourself so if you're
faced with a problem you can argue your
point there's no reason why you should
have to worry about your children being
taken away there is nothing wrong with
supporting First Amendment are you
primarily an informational organization
or can someone call they need help in a
particular area and find that type of
help well like I said we're in network
and we can act as a referral to
different organizations whereas we might
not have that many resources or
information much information at our
Kentucky base we can refer you to all
kinds of people all over the country so
you can help people take care of
problems hopefully in their own areas if
you had the opportunity to say one thing
to the people sitting at home listening
that might encourage them to get off
their fanny and do something productive
what would that be oh I would have to
say that it's working and that's what
people have to understand the problem
that we have right now is that the
situation has reached a critical point
our laws are bad the laws are so bad
that people don't even realize anymore
that there is a problem as far as the
Constitution they don't realize they
have the right to speak up for their
rights they don't realize there's the
right to protest they don't realize that
they can pass out information about
marijuana it's illegal so what I would
tell people is you know basically the
only way that we're going to change this
the only way that we're going to change
this debate is to get out there to
exercise our First Amendment rights and
to talk to people about it once you
start talking to people you become
empowered people understand the that
it's the truth and literally your
thanked a million times I it's been nice
having you on our show it's refreshing
to hear someone speak as honestly as you
do I wish you all the luck and
everything that you're doing I can be
back on our show again sometime as we've
learned today there's a lot going on in
the world that we still need yet to
change we can't do it without a group of
people joining each other to make that
difference please take the time take the
courage to make a difference in your
community until next time keep strong
keep happy
keep wise