thank you for joining us today on our
program we are blessed to have the
distinguished individual dr. Todd
makarria come on to our show and share
some interesting viewpoints and some
successes that they've had in the Bay
Area in California for those of you who
are not acquainted with this gentleman
he's very impressive very impressive
background he is a psychiatrist and
private practice in Oakland and Berkeley
he is a gentleman who introduced the
first methadone maintenance program in
alameda county that's right and he's
also a member of the California Medical
Association he's certified by the
American Society of addiction and
addiction medicine and the California
Society of addiction medicine is a
qualified medical review officer right
that's right kind of blue that he's a
he's also the co-author of a very
impressive landmark bill that has
happened in San Francisco called
proposition P this man's background goes
beyond that but for now that basically
covers the things that we're going to be
approaching now proposition P a lot of
people have become aware of that through
the press and the media coverage and I
know people becoming aware your
background recognizes that you have a
lot going for you intellectually and so
that when you make a comment that we
should pay attention to him as a medical
resource for the curing of pain and
relieving of pain and other diseases it
comes with a lot of impact well thank
you very much it's a pleasure to be here
one of the problems that we had what
we've been having problems for many
years of getting access to medicinal
cannabis and once upon a time I was in
charge of the marijuana research for the
National Institute of Mental Health in
Chevy Chase this is back in 1967 but
since that time there's been a minimal
amount of progress in getting cannabis
available for medicinal use
only recently has there been some
compassionate access and only recently
have there been some grudging admissions
by the scientific and medical
establishment that cannabis in fact had
therapeutic efficacy okay and I feel
very bitter about this because I know it
to be a cover-up since before marijuana
was taken away from availability by the
1937 Tax Act medicinal cannabis also
became unavailable deleted from the 1941
formulary and pharmacopoeia now why did
that go hand in hand like that because
it was part of this so-called send them
a signal school of propaganda and
disinformation that the police had to
maintain in order to continue the
fictionalized killer weed or part of
reefer madness and so saying that that
cannabis had medical or medicinal
utility would have run contrary to their
fiction that they needed to maintain in
order to continue credibility and not
having people question why marijuana was
in fact prohibited now that's the only
plant substance drug which is not really
a dredged sinner that's been treated
like that I mean we have opium is still
available cetera for medicinal purposes
etc don't we and other forms of that's
what even cocaine but because of the
several factors the growing popularity
popularity and the promotion of
synthetic drugs by the pharmaceutical
manufacturers that started in the 1890s
and went on through the 1900s and has
escalated ever since with a new and
better allegedly of synthetic substances
no money could be made many patents and
they weren't interested in promoting the
use of cannabis although Eli Lilly &amp;
Parke Davis
contained a farm for developing
pharmaceutical strains and
pharmaceutical strength plants up until
1937 hmm and then they're just not
disregarding all that path past evidence
until now you're bringing it to life
well yes and that's well it's very much
like living at least in the medical
world with a depiction of the Planet of
the Apes and what happened to medicine
after they wanted to get rid of all
these human kinds of advances in
technology and they reverted to some
form of medicine that resembled
something that happened in the Middle
Ages or worse okay well now see people
are able to recognize that him can be
made into paper fiber and fuel but when
it comes with the idea of being medicine
outside of smoking it as far as relaxing
taking care of stress etc it's hard for
them to imagine in what areas hemp can
actually be utilized for now you say
that it helps in aids as an example well
okay back to this issue of censorship
and it's being swept under the rug okay
and the importance of bringing this back
to consciousness and bringing it back to
the awareness of the medical community
as far as a therapeutic agent and that's
why the text of the initiative or the
proposition in San Francisco that I
co-authored contained the term restore
could you take the moment and read it to
our audience yes I appreciate that
recommendation to amend the health and
safety code of California one the people
of the City and County of San Francisco
recommend that the state of California
and the California Medical Association
restore hemp medical preparations to the
list of available medicines in
California licensed physicians shall not
be penalized for or restricted from
prescribing hemp preparations for
medical purposes to any patient
definition the term hep medical
preparations means all products made
from hemp cannabis or marijuana in all
forms that are designed intended or used
for human consumption
Shin for the treatment of any disease
the relief of pain or for any healing
purpose including the relief of asthma
glaucoma arthritis anorexia migraine
multiple sclerosis epilepsy nausea
stress for uses an antibiotic and anti
emetic or as any healing agent or as an
adjunct to any medical procedure for the
treatment of cancer HIV infection or any
other medical procedure or herbal
treatment now that is a very broad
definition of medicine or medical or
medicinal applications it is but the
definition of hampa medical preparations
is well documented in previous of things
like the u.s. pharmacopoeia and that in
fact all the definitions are in place
ready to go for medicinal use of crude
cannabis products to be restored
excellent to the formulary excellent and
so we're in this wonderful posts of a
passage euphoria Dennis Peron the the
sparkplug behind this has appointed me
the medical coordinator for the
committee for compassionate use his
organization to get this on the ballot
and then now we're trying to figure out
what do we do now all of a sudden we
become successes after all these many
years having been failures and looked
upon as outcasts deviants nuts
irresponsible love dope smoking hippies
and other kinds of negative stereotypes
that we've been stuck with which is all
part of the suppression campaign to keep
a cannabis marijuana or hemp illegal I
see a lotta has to do with people of
your stature being willing to come forth
into the public light and make these
statements because you know you leave
yourself wide open I'm certain you
realize that for a variety of tax
be from government agencies or private
industry yes because it's really part of
a campaign to maintain these collective
fictions in order to prop up these
flawed policies that they need to
attempt to discredit or tarnish or kill
the messenger somehow so as to not be
made to confront the actual facts and
deal on a level playing field with what
is in fact happening when we come back I
like to be able to go a little bit
farther as to how the next step
appropriate prep proposition P
preparation preparation a helps take
care of a pain yes it does it's going to
be implemented in the direction that is
going to have to go before it becomes
completely successful we'll be right
back after this we're talking today with
dr. Todd materia and we are learning
some of the benefits of course for the
medical uses of the hemp plant but now
we also have some challenges against us
still that we've got to ever come you
have n cumbered the first leg of the
journey chief just the first battle
basically you've got it legal in a city
but now I understand from talking to
Dennis Peron another's you still have to
encumber the state laws and the federal
laws now how do you plan on taking
getting this into the next phase I've
already worked on attempting to surf on
this event wave and have taken a running
start by contacting the California
Medical Association with regard to the
possible passage of this before it
actually passed and so I'm asking them
to become involved with helping to
implement implement the intent of the
proposition which specifies that the
people of the City and County of San
Francisco recommend that the state of
California and the California Medical
Association restore had preparation
etc how do you think that will be met
with trepidation by the California
Medical Association but it's been put on
a fast track to be reviewed by their
scientific council and I spoke with the
president of the CMA dr. Howard Lang who
impresses me as a forthright courageous
person but I don't know how he feels on
the issue he was vaguely aware of having
seen it across his desk but then passed
it on to the appropriate staffers down
at their headquarters office in San
Francisco and they were aware that it
had passed but we're not aware of how
the California Medical Association was
obliged to be involved there isn't any
kind of way we can force the CMA to be
involved in taking a stand yay or nay
but if they do support this they're the
options of activity are to publicize it
amongst their physicians and also start
working in Sacramento for legislation to
make this possible and of course
statewide okay now is there a chance
that a federal agent or estate agent
would still take action in the city of
San Francisco and began arresting people
when they are growing marijuana hemp
well this is always possible but we have
this unique situation in San Francisco
where the district attorney has assured
us that he will not prosecute any cases
for six plants or less that are growing
for medicinal purposes if the person
demonstrates that they are that they
have medicinal intent or documentation
Gatewood Galbraith once made the comment
on a show of ours that if he were able
to real Eagle eyes Hampton Kentucky all
the tourists become any fill up all the
hotels when I spoke with Dennis Peron he
made comment that now that this has
happened in the medical field variety of
organizations from muscular cirrhosis
etc are awaiting to open up foundations
and officers etc in the San Francisco ie
bay area do you foresee that happening
and if so is that going to make the
movement stronger
I hadn't thought of that eventualities
essa Sara Lee but I would welcome that
because it would with what we have in
mind help everybody including the
sufferers that were in need because now
that we have the de facto
decriminalization even though the state
attorney general is the right-wing
individual that will probably oppose
this and ironically he was the opponent
to the DA who lost the race for the
state attorney general to him so there
won't be any love lost between them
theoretically the state attorney general
could send state police and state
narcotics agents to go and do this kind
of enforcement but it would be a
difficult and outside of the area of the
usual responsibilities saying you know
you don't see a tak like they had in
humble county well I think that in San
Francisco where you have an
uncooperative local da with the state
laws you have the mayor and the public
health establishment on your side as
soon as we get back to San Francisco
Dennis and I have a meeting with the
head of the San Francisco Health
Department that we will start moving
forward in making something happen de
facto that would be politically suicidal
to to be punitive and to attempt to stop
by either federal or state intervention
that theoretically they could but to
target people who are compassionately
using cannabis this especially in an
election year would not look too good
with regard to washington the state of
unreality inside the beltway that
doesn't really have any substantive
health policy and to do something
negative like this would be I would say
not good politics but back to trying to
implement the intent of this we are
going to be presenting to the state to
party of the county health person then
a draft of a questionnaire in a form
that we will have distributed by the
health department and publicized by them
to the physicians in San Francisco that
we are starting a research project to
determine the impact of this in terms of
the first way of accurately assessing
actual hazards and benefits of cannabis
products okay that will involve the
visits by the the users to their family
physician or if they don't have one find
one because to get a prescription for us
using cannabis they'd have to have a
signature of a prescribing physician
because it mandates that we're not going
to be punished for prescribing and then
should the police come and investigate a
growing situation in a window box or
something of that nature patio that the
person with the furnish proof that this
was for medicinal purposes and they
would be functionally sheltered and
decriminalized for their compassionate
access to cannabis now as a quid pro quo
we ask that they give us certain facts
with regard to their the use for what
meant for what ailment and we have all
these conditions listed here and this
will be part of the form that will ask
the patient to a complete and the
physician also now I know one thing that
the taxpayers from the bay area would be
concerned about is when the berlin wall
came down all the people came rushing
out and there was an overflow into a new
city and not enough to take care of when
this wall comes bursting down in san
francisco you can have people from Miami
New York everywhere coming into San
Francisco needing this medicine to
relieve themselves from AIDS glaucoma
etc etc and there's going to be an
enormous amount it appears people
seeking your help how are you going to
prepare to take care of that I think the
San Francisco physicians can respond to
that challenge
and that they can provide them with good
medicine and also with frankness with
regard to their substance use patterns
and not have to be hypocritical or
fearful that anything will be happening
to them so that they're not going to
turn down the business and we're talking
about people publicizing to the medical
community that this is what happened and
this is what the public health
department is doing to try to help
implement it one of the things we're
going to ask for some office space in
the public health department but we'll
pay for it okay and we're then going to
start soliciting contributions or money
to implement this research project
another thing that we're going to ask
the Public Health Department do is to
monitor the purity quality and strength
and do chemical analyses on the hampa
specimens that will be submitted by
users because they would like to know
about different issues of purity for
example fungi and molds this is really a
critical issue for the AIDS patients
because those that have compromised
immune logic systems and problems with
recurrent pneumonia to have sources of
mold or fungi come in courtesy of the
the leaf would be not good for their
health probably okay and so we have to
study the level of occurrences of these
kinds of contaminants molds fungi
possibly somebody might have something
in their soil they didn't know about
that would get into there like a heavy
metal and that the essential health the
department's laboratory would be a pro
would be protecting the health of the
citizens of San Francisco for drug
surety with regard to cannabis plus
providing us a source of information for
other phases of research which will be
structure-activity relationships and
variety strain other kinds of botanical
or a species the kinds of different
differences or growth techniques will
also start coming online with regard
two issues of what are good medicines
what are undesirable effects and all
that generating new research and new new
approaches to problem that's right in a
population which will give us this
information in exchange for being
protected sounds excellent and this is
the kind of thing that I'm quite excited
about I think that we are sending the
right signal to the Beltway back here
and we need to do so still and i think
that this kind of initiative will help
demystify because it will involve the
medical community and learning what is
real and what is hysteria so that more
legitimate information will come from
this and i'm asking to be appointed
principal investigator for this research
effort I'm sure solista coordinated and
we've also enjoyed having you on our
show we really have to go at this point
but we'd like to have you come back soon
next time you get a chance to be on the
show would you please certainly will
thank you very much thank you very much
for tuning in to our program we're doing
what we can to bring in the information
to you as quickly as we as we come
across it until we're in touch again
keep happy keep strong keep why