thank you for joining us today on the
program we were lucky enough to have a
very interesting guest and one who has
been a leader in the hemp movement for a
very long time he's the news director
news editor of high times magazine steve
bloom steve thank you for coming on the
show today
your voice in the movement has been
heard for a long time and high times
magazine has had a direction
on bringing information about the hand
plant and the hemp movement to the
public
in any aspect that they can
at the same time you've also had to deal
with some problems over the past few
years we want to talk about all of that
first of all
the uh voice that you put together high
times magazine how did that all come
about
we're based in new york city
we're a fairly small operation magazine
publishing company
that publishes high times as well as a
couple of other magazines
and
we
we turn out a magazine every month like
everybody else does you know in our
business you know we're no different
than most people when it comes to that
it's our job to write headlines to
assign to bring in photos to do all the
leg work that it takes to get the whole
magazine produced from beginning to end
that's what we do we're all
professionals at that
and then by the way we're also advocates
you know that's what makes it unusual
okay now the fact that you are advocates
and you're out there with your neck on
the line being willing to put your face
and your time and talent out
there for people to see and to enjoy and
learn from it's also caused you some
problems um in new orleans you were
subpoenaed
into court
and a problem came up that
many people know about but not not in
full detail well we've documented it you
know in high times and
and it's been documented uh by the
mainstream press as we like to sort of
call it
washington post wall street journal
usa today they've looked into our
situation what was going on there and
the situation
pretty much was through a campaign to
to gut the indoor
growing industry
they targeted high times as well as the
the main
information vehicle that has been
spreading this this news
about growing
indoors and they wanted to snuff out the
industry and you know get rid of high
times at the same time if they could and
they also targeted a magazine called
synomia tips
and targeting meant that they um they
started a grand jury
they
indicted um well they indicted the
president of a company called the seed
bank
out of that grand jury they
won information from high times
regarding a possible criminal conspiracy
you know connecting us with him and we
of course are connected in a business
relationship he advertises through high
times but they seem to think it's
something bigger and vaster than that
you know that we're you know in the
midst of you know some sort of you know
major clandestine activities to
distribute marijuana all over the world
or something it's just absurd you know
we're or a magazine that talks about it
well now with high times being
established is what many people say the
bible of the movement
i mean you were there before anybody
else was it seems like i mean you were
reporting
and covering stories that people
wouldn't pick up and cover
all right so with you being out there
and and bringing that information home
that makes you an easy target how do you
protect yourself now how do you go about
getting advertisers how do you go about
raising funds to keep the magazine going
well it's not fundraising you know we're
a magazine we uh we put a magazine
people buy it you know uh that's one
major source of revenue high times has
uh as as good sales
and we thank all our you know dedicated
loyal readers they
you know i times is hard to get
sometimes people always tell us that um
all over the country you know we get
questions you know where do i where can
i get it where do i get it people drive
miles out of the way to get it it's
amazing we're spirited by those stories
but but you know it's just yeah i'm told
that in some parts of america it's
illegal for them to have the magazines
that's the absurdity of it you know they
can be told that by somebody in some
locality and they'll believe it and then
we'll get these calls you know it's high
times out of business or hard times and
we constantly get you know not lately
but but we have in the past you know i
mean i can't remember one real recently
but but we just generally get that kind
of thing and it's just all this
disinformation that got spread around
about high times that the d a you know
our arch enemy you know uh you know
likes to constantly spread you know they
can just
send it out into the media it gets
picked up it gets spread around you know
in stories and water service stories
before you know it it's just sprinkled
into the
consciousness of people you know that so
and so you know has occurred you know
and and that's not true okay now when
i've traveled across seas i've been to
amsterdam and germany and i've been i've
been to lucky enough to be a few places
courtesy of the united states army but
i've had the chance to do that
and
when i was across these i noticed
that your magazine is there your
magazines in amsterdam your magazines in
england your magazines in canada your
magazines all across the coast false not
in canada illegal encounters it's
illegal in canada but it can maybe
through mail order people are getting
right right so you are reaching an
international audience so therefore you
focus on the world scene
now there's been some changes in the
laws regarding hemp and there's been
some people and i think australia who
are trying to bring him
into a cash crop situation and to help
feed the people down there when you
focus in the world seeing what
directions do you go
i sterling i don't know very much better
than a proposal to the uh the government
there for uh uh and project uh
we focus on um a lot of the aspects of
where hemp comes from around the world
at this point we're unearthing it at the
same time all the activists are you know
we're all working at a feverish pace you
know the activists and the entrepreneurs
i must add uh you know there's money out
there and people are trying to make it
as well as spread the gospel about you
know hemp you know so uh so you know
we're doing that you know as well
yeah and you're doing an excellent job
we'll be talking more with steve bloom
right after this
you're actively seeking new advertisers
and you're also repositioning the
magazine and putting it into a different
direction isn't that right well the base
of advertisers the government's scared
off uh through the harassment of
operation green merchant uh
we have
we've had to look elsewhere uh and
fortunately as i said before the readers
have been able to sort of carry the load
and very devoted and keep us keep us
afloat but we need more advertising to
really you know run a
you know a better operation you know
overall and we've been just looking out
to you know
more obvious markets uh the
entertainment world uh record companies
film companies book companies they
are very reticent but you know that's
our little test each time we uh we make
a breakthrough
i don't know if i should show
advertising but this is
an advertisement uh from columbia
records who said that they would not
advertise in high times at one point we
were told because of our support of
normal okay somehow or other this group
persuaded them
to have the advertisement because they
want it it's something some wall broke
down very quickly for some strange
reason and it's a good wall for us
and we're hoping it'll be more of that
just you know getting out in the
community people have been afraid to
touch us now over the years your your
content of your magazine has gotten
stronger
and it's become more focused and i
believe you've even been responsible for
uh breaking news bringing new
information to light that kind of
rattles the trees
well we are you know our main claim to
fame in recent history is the whole hemp
information that we've uncovered you
know uh we did a big story on jfk
recently that uh that is sort of
will be becoming a major motion picture
now it's yeah it's coming in the movies
coming out about jfk i mean that kind of
uh information uh you know we we jump on
the stuff that's not told you know and
uh that's where we see us as ourselves
as the alternative press at this point
because there's so many angles
sometimes maybe a little too heavy on
the conspiracy side we have to sort of
rules a few out you know in editorial
meetings but but you know the hemp uh uh
information is a grand conspiracy theory
you know when you really dig into it all
and uh and that's what's i think
ultimately really fascinated us that
it's so deep
and you've also been attributed or your
magazine has been attributed to help and
to bring the focus to the hampton
movement like an umbrella where people
can all get to know each other and
interact
as you continue to grow how do you plan
to incorporate that that particular we
want them to start advertising that's
the other side uh i guess uh but they
know that i don't have to tell them
through this medium uh but uh we were
hoping to create a hemp industry in a
sense you know that will benefit us as
well uh i don't think that's mercenary
you know we you know we have to survive
and and just like the previous companies
who are no longer advertising well there
are a few you know the lighting systems
and stuff like that the growth the grow
companies so to speak garden you know
stores and so on they um you know they
have come back in drips and drabs but we
need to look elsewhere and there's a
whole hemp industry that's waiting to
sort of really blossom you see it here
in this building downstairs you know the
whole row of people with hemp them
merchants and
it's pretty amazing to watch you know
how it's how it is expanding and there
really is money in it i think and people
are going to make money from it too and
it'll be good it'll help fund the
movement and and get you know you know
we need more money here in this whole
movement and hopefully it'll get spread
around the right ways you know so it's
just not a few entrepreneurs you know
and when people think of high times
magazine they think of it sometimes as
strictly a marijuana magazine and
there's a lot more to it than that now
isn't there well you know we really are
the only marijuana magazine so we'll
still you know i don't mind that banner
kind of changing the terminology
somewhat to hemp or whatever but uh you
know within that i mean we voice of the
counter culture we have a little slogan
i mean many people ask well what's the
counter culture or is there a counter
culture you know and we think there is
you know we've uncovered that as well
you know people don't want to know about
hemptour they don't want to know there
are people all over the country that's a
counter culture
counter cultural movement of people
doing that and it just does it gets
local coverage but it doesn't get any
you know national you know it's not
reported like they'd rather report in
the new york times a few weeks ago that
there's a whole decline in marijuana use
and so on and so forth and they don't
want to acknowledge that there's a whole
rise in a movement of people who think
that you know it should be legalized and
you know that doesn't indicate decline
they don't want to recognize that you
know there is a counter culture of
people out there it's just not as usual
it was in the 60s it doesn't make as
good pictures crowds aren't big enough
for them or something but you're still
making a change in people's lives you've
occasionally
picked up the banner in somebody's world
who's been arrested or been treated
unjustly and with the power of the press
shall we say you've corrected an
injustice
we'd like to discuss a couple of those
stories when we come back after this
we're here today with high times editor
steve bloom steve as we said earlier uh
the power of the press can make a
difference in personal lives now you on
a personal example have shown by
personal example how that can be
achieved and some of the things that
you've done and then you've written
about it
yeah there was one situation where i was
arrested uh last year in new jersey and
it really put the drug war right in my
face you know we get so much information
to high times from people who are
arrested all the time but it's detached
you know from the reality of it
happening well what happened to me you
know
and what happened kind of uh in in brief
is i was driving uh at night uh new
jersey
uh
speeding and i was pulled over for a
speeding violation and that just wasn't
enough you know they i was driving a car
that uh that they
presumed guilty uh an old firebird 70s
kind of car if it's some sort of profile
i'm told
and i was just coming back from a dead
show so i kind of looked apart but you
know so once he sized me up you know
it's like we're getting this guy out of
the car and to be honest i had been
stopped one other time in new jersey
within that year you know and so i was
like oh no here we go again same damn
car you know whatever uh and i hadn't
had the car very long either just
somebody you know just the way that
happened it's a great car but for some
reason they you know they hate it in new
jersey and uh and so they brought me out
of the car and proceeded to search and
since it happened in the previous time
as well i knew they were going to the
patch search
and they you know they pat you down
which really is a major violation right
there you know but they're allowed to do
this for some reason you know and first
of all why are they taking me out of the
car
that's the whole point i mean in my mind
it's like why did he why did that even
stop start you know as as a necessity
that's the change in life from you know
my time when i was younger first
learning how to drive and maybe having a
speeding violation and you get your
ticket and that's it and you go to now
you know this whole hysterical response
to a simple traffic violation and even
if you get out of the car without being
told to they'll put a gun well then of
course it gets worse you know my story
is not as bad as you know a lot of
others i'm sure you can hear but they
did uh they did take me out they found a
pipe in my pouch uh and uh and i was
arrested for the pipe simply for the
pipe no no quantity of anything other
than you know what was called less than
50 grams which they tested the pipe to
find little flakes of you know trace
and but meanwhile i'm arrested
handcuffed fingerprinted the whole
[ __ ] thing
the whole thing the whole thing
i'm sorry uh i'm i'll do that again i'm
uh
i'm cuffed uh fingerprinted you know
rested they're taken to the station
house the whole thing you know and uh
this is all for a pipe so uh i was let
out in about an hour you know it wasn't
the worst experience of my life i
suppose they didn't hit me they didn't
do anything you know they didn't beat me
nothing happened terrible like that it
was sort of a state of unreality when i
went back to my car and i just drove
home okay i just got arrested okay and
i'm out of my own you know recognizance
and now i have to do the whole court
thing so i went to a lawyer and a friend
of mine who's a new jersey lawyer and
she decided to take the case she's a
corporate lawyer who really didn't have
the time to do it and so she's a real
great hero to me having
having taken this case pro bono
and did some research we found some
interesting precedents and used it to uh
to overturn the search okay and we lost
in the first round and we won in the
second round on this on the the state
level going to trenton
he had to get through one round because
it was a small town that just no way
they were gonna slap the cops wrists and
then we had to get out of that town and
go to the state house where they didn't
care about that little town's concerns
apparently or got a cool judge you know
you know they got the judge suite of uh
of uh trenton or something you know who
really you know heard our story and was
actually disappointed the state didn't
really try and defend themselves very
well they thought oh they'll just you
know and they they came with a real
uh lame approach to you know not even
trying to like sell the you know that i
was really guilty of anything just yeah
you know he did this to you um i didn't
do anything i moved my hand like this to
get my wallet to my pouch and he thought
i was going for a gun you know it's just
all this uh so you know from firsthand
experience yeah they they'll make up
anything you know and and the hemptour
people have told me you know well and
i've learned you know you can't drive
around anymore with you know anything
wrong with your car that anything
they'll pick you off you know that's the
police state stuff that we're dealing
with that's scary and and i think people
realize that on a day-to-day level an
average citizen now i think it's really
seeping and they realize i mean except
for the you know the hysterical people
who are in favor of the drug war who are
of the few but they bark loudest you
know you know we you know most people
still i think are opposed to that kind
of encroachment on their freedoms i mean
the average american citizen you know so
when it comes out of drug-related uh
behavior which people think is no big
deal in the first place you know i have
a lot of average americans and then they
they're getting stopped on top of it
they're getting really incensed
you know it's and it's costing money
obviously as well you know they're you
know it's cripping their whole you know
financial you know life it could be any
number of things my case is such a small
little situation but it did teach me how
you have to fight back and what it costs
to fight back my lawyer said it would
have cost so much money and i realized i
probably wouldn't be able to afford it
right you know so the whole system is
not set up very well to fight back
um we've only got about a minute or two
left
and there's a
great number of journalists in america
who like to be able to have a forum i'm
sure as yours and be able to
voice their opinion as you do but
the way the laws are written and the way
the harassment and various communities
are are presented to people they have a
tendency to withdraw from having the
courage to do that
what would you say to these journalists
now dealing with the rights that we have
in america how would you how would you
individually i mean uh and in their life
because we need journalists
well i i guess they must have problems
from from publication publication
depending on the editorial slant you
know where do they want to go you know
with their editorial focus do they i'm
amazed you know the amount of say hemp
editorials you see all over the country
drug legalization editorials again you
see from you know real average you know
the you know the main the daily papers
all across america it's not a word that
seems to be having a hard time getting
spread you know it's it is fanning out
all over the place but but i'm sure it's
a tough sell some places you probably
have to just
you know pitch it real hard you know
like like anybody else would you know
come at him and almost sort of a
business like approach you know the
quality manuscript on something that
says your point of view you know you can
probably get in his guest editorials i
don't know i don't think it's that hard
i mean we are somewhat of an island
right now in in in the world of
publishing you know we're doing
something that nobody quite is doing and
you know sometimes that's that excites
us and other times we'd rather we'd
rather have a few more friends you know
like you understand what we're doing you
know we're really not bad guys i don't
know why the publishing industry a lot
of times doesn't lend more support
towards what we do you know they just
we're like the the stepchild or
something and they want to just like
they want to watch from afar you know
you see how we are we're like the guinea
pigs you know in this first amendment
experiment or something and it's like
let them deal with it and well we are
dealing with it we have a good lawyer
and we have the resources apparently to
to get as far as we've gone they haven't
sunk us
you know they would like to have can
they haven't and uh and everybody thinks
why don't they just come up and
bust us all or something you know it's
not that easy they've got nothing on
them it's nice
are you doing this
you know they were taking pictures of us
the other day at the washington uh
i'd like to say on behalf of the members
of the hemp movement and i have spoken
to many of them
they're very appreciated for what you
are doing and the fight that you are
you're making possible and the way
you're raising their voices it's been an
honor to have you on our program i'd
like to have you back again sometime
okay that sounds great i want to thank
everybody who is the those devoted
followers of high times i mean they're
amazing
more after this