I don't know Jackie reminds me another
fella I was telling about running for
for governor he said well I'll be for
you or against you whichever helped you
the most
tells you that the solution to a
present-day problem is doubling the
prison population over the next 20 years
has its head stuck where it's never
going to discover the thousand points in
light of George
this man is an alien he's not a
conservative he's an alien he and Ronald
Reagan both uh they are willing to
imprison a whole generation of people to
keep intact the federal chemical and
pharmaceutical monopolies in this
country which he's well vested in each
and I think he's a vampire I don't think
he's an American I think he's a vampire
willing to suck the life out all us
victims in order to remain powerful men
in a powerful position but let me take
this opportunity right here wherever
this gets shown in limitation I am
pleased and honored to be in the
presence of one most brilliant man in
the United States this gentleman next
year author of Emperor wears no clothes
and so much more than just an author a
researcher and a dedicated and diligent
activist and a man who I know for a fact
is responsible for tens of thousands of
people in this country being able to
come out of the closet and stand up out
of the darkness and stand up out of
Oppression and despair and lives of
quiet desperation and be able to point
source of knowledge and the truth and
the point of light that this man right
here is personally responsible for
putting together I would not be where I
am today were it not for Jack hair and I
know that a lot of people would not be
Walking Tall with dignity and a sense of
Pride and a sense that they do no wrong
by communicating with Mother Earth
through the herb and in other Fashions
and this man right here is responsible
for as much of it as I know of I'm sure
other people deserve credit to have
helped him out but this man right here
is one of the most brilliant people in
the United States today and I hope
someday that this country and the people
winning will reward him appropriately if
what he's done for freedom and
individuality and civil liberties and
Mother Earth in this country I want to
take an opportunity right now amen does
that mean does that mean they got free
grass for the rest of my life
let me show you something you can take
back and give you better photos this is
Mr Henry Ford
in 1941 with Popular Mechanics magazine
showing off his car made from hemp
oh is that when the whole car itself was
made from him and it says so right there
in Popular Mechanics 1941. is that nice
one more deal in the car that's in here
which I mean they should have never let
us find out
every once in a while
dedication dedication and intelligence
you know I think Edison said the genius
is one percent inspiration and 99
perspiration this man right here is oh
yes yeah he certainly has thank you I'll
tell you I have a lot of good teachers
okay this man wrote a book that I read
that was one of the really him Michael
Aldridge had written some of the
greatest work on him long before I even
really understood him he wrote it in 77.
oh yeah the Kentucky uh what was it
marijuana peace
and that and the prospectus so he is not
somebody who's needs to come to me and
learn about him I learned a lot about
him from him wow I was born in Jack