Joining us today on the program was one
of San Francisco's hardest working
activists, Dennis Peron. Dennis has been
working in the uh gay gay community
trying to change and make a difference
for the people there as well as working
in the hemp community and his political
ideas and his political efforts have
made a change and an impact on that city
that will last for its history. Dennis,
thank you for being on our show. Thank
you, Casper, for having me. One of the
things that uh I was talking about in
regards to the changing of history in
San Francisco is Proposition W. Some
people nationally are aware of it. Many
aren't. But what you did with
Proposition W is really a landmark.
Well, I'll tell you what happened. It
was um Proposition W and Proposition P
ar uh arised out of a marijuana bus that
I had. I was busted in 1977. And I used
to run the Big Top Pot Supermarket.
Okay. And it was a one-stop pot
supermarket, one-stop shop for all your
pot needs. Okay. And it was a very
elaborate setup. And uh when I came when
it came to San Francisco, I had trouble
buying pot and I had to like kiss a lot
of ass and I had a lot of uh hassles
getting pot. So I just decided to start
a pot supermarket myself. Well, sell pot
myself. had evolved into a supermarket
because there were so many different
kinds of pot and at that time and
different prices and everything. So I
um I tried to get as many different
kinds of pot together in one spot as I
could. Okay. And the um the idea grew
and grew and grew and before you knew it
I had three scales, 15 people working. I
had four people that all they did was
roll
joints and um every night we would sell
pot to about five 600 people. It was a
very elaborate setup, beautiful house
and customers were treated with dignity
and respect and no one was ever
jipped. In 1977, I got busted like I
said and
uh we had a 4mon trial after I got
busted. I didn't mention that I I got
shot during that raid.
Um in the leg, right? Yeah, I got shot
in the leg. Um what it was is the but
the supermarket was going down and uh I
heard a ruckus at the door and I went to
the the stairway to see what was going
on and I see this uh guy coming up with
a gun, big old floppy hat and fatigue
jacket and I think the first thing I
think of course is a rip that these guys
are going to rob us. Mhm. So, the first
thing I do is grab something close by,
which was a MTL Hamburg water bottle,
and I hold it up the stairs like go down
the stairs and we'll forget all about
this. But before I'd even got the bottle
up, the guy had shot me. And he got me
with the first shot and threw me back.
And then another shot went past my ear.
And this was the point where I was
convinced that these guys were murderous
ripoffs, that they were going to kill
everybody in the house. So, I was
willing to give them everything I had.
Of course. Uh, the guy comes up the
stairs and puts a gun to my head and I'm
thinking that goodbye Dennis.
Fortunately, another guy comes in the
room. And it turns out he's a cop. Turns
out they're all cops, much to my
surprise.
Uh, so I was shot and I remember the day
that that day they were taking me out of
the u the house on a stretcher and out
in front of the house there was five or
6 hundred people that had gathered
around the house mainly my friends and
customers and when they took me out I
shot a peace sign to those people and
the whole street
screamed Dennis Dennis Dennis
That kind of support must have helped
you healed. And it did help me feel a
lot better even though I knew it was
kind of curtains for the big top. Yeah.
That was an end of an era. And that's
when you brought forth Proposition W.
Now, what's Proposition W exactly?
Proposition W, like I said, aroused over
the bust. And I knew that people of San
Francisco wanted marijuana legal. I knew
that because we had a 1972 referendum on
Proposition 19. It was a statewide thing
where San Francisco voted 52% to
legalize
marijuana. So I and my friends went out
collected 16,000 signatures to put a
referendum on the ballot. It was a local
initiative, but it out and out legalized
marijuana for cultivation, sale,
possession, anything you wanted to do.
You wanted to take a bath in it, you
could do that. Okay. Now, wasn't that
contrary to federal? It's contrary to
state and federal. But um the way I see
it, San Francisco is very unique. It's a
city and a county. We elect our district
attorney. We elect our mayor. We elect
our board of supervisors. In many ways,
these people are responsible to us.
Okay. Also to state law, but to the
people that elected them. And so I
directed at the chief of police and the
district attorney. Seemed that those two
people were mainly involved in marijuana
prosecution and arrest. And um it won by
58%. Excellent. I collected those
signatures just before I went into jail
on the big top pot supermarket bust. I
got 6 months and um while I was in jail,
there was an office opened for charter
commissioner. My friends got the papers
for me and before you knew it, I was a
candidate for office while I'm in jail
and also proposition W was given a
letter of designation and that was going
on. What a turnaround. I like to say
most politicians um wind up in jail, but
I started my political career in jail.
So, I figured I'd skip a step.
Uh well, in November came around, I got
20,000 votes and came 300 votes shy of
winning the election. Wow. Proposition W
got over 58% of the vote uh to become
technically the law of San Francisco.
Okay. The will and the spirit of the
people. Well, I had allies in the um
political arena. My main ally was my
good friend Harvey Mil, the first gay
case supervisor ever elected in the
nation. And my other ally was George
Moscone, the liberal mayor of San
Francisco, who was a friend of the gay
community, who was a friend of the
ptheads. And he was just a friend of the
the uh weak people and the the people
that had no voice.
Now, you said that the assassination of
Harvey Milka really changed uh the
course. Well, before I was to leave
jail,
Harvey and George would be dead.
killed by an ex-marine, an ex- cop, an
ex- fireman, an ex-s
supervisor who went on a Twinkie eating
Coca-Cola laced
rampage and politically assassinated
Harvey Milk and George Muscone.
The bullet that ripped through Harvey
and George's
brain set the gay movement back at least
10 years. And everyone knew that, but
not everyone knew that it also set the
marijuana movement back 10 years.
That we had this victory and the pe the
two people that were going to see it
enforced were now
dead. And the guy that did it is
claiming he ate so many Twinkies. That's
why he did it. So needless to say,
Proposition P W got put on the back
burner and u kind of forgotten including
by myself because like Harvey was my
friend and I I couldn't even think about
Prop W. All I could think about is
revenge, revenge, revenge. Harvey is
dead. George is dead. We've got to get
we've got to try to get back our power.
I know we can never get those two men
back. So I ran for Harvey
seat. I fortunately lost in retrospect
as
fortunate but uh Proposition W was quite
forgotten not by me but by the
politicians and by the police and by the
district attorney. But then over the
years you've made it a point to bring a
lot of uh awareness to people about the
hemp movement. Well, you know,
marijuana, we've always had the all the
issues on our side. We've always had the
truth on our side, but I've really found
out 22 years truth is not enough and
that um in many ways people are
brainwashed.
And so I know that we can't rely on
people's brain anymore in America. And
that in a way we have to rely on the
only thing that seems to be left and
that's their
heart and their conscience.
And right now, San Francisco is going
through a very serious AIDS crisis as
America
is. And uh we have a lot of sick
people. We have a lot of dying and we
have a lot of
pain. And out of that pain arose
Proposition P, the medical marijuana
initiative that I just put on the ballot
this year. And I understand that the
success of that has really rocked the
nation. And we'll be talking about that
just as soon as we come back.
Welcome back. We're talking with
activist and political leader Dennis
Peron. Now, Dennis, you commented that
this particular proposition rose up out
of the AIDS community and the pain and
the suffering that you saw uh for uh the
relegalization for medical uses is what
this is all about, isn't it? It's true.
It's what it's about. Well, let me tell
you something about how it became into
being. It was January 27th,
1990 that we were sitting home. It was
about midnight and we were just ready to
go to bed when I hear a knock at the
door and I'm going down to Anzor. Before
I get down there, a sledgehammer breaks
the door down. And in come these five
people who claim they have a search
warrant. My immediate reaction that
these guys are rips because number one,
I'm not even
dealing. But they're not rips. They're
cops. They claim that they heard
somebody. Somebody said that I had
marijuana for sale. On that
basis, they got a
warrant. They found marijuana in my
house. They found 4 ounces of marijuana
in my house. But what they also found
was my very sick best friend dying of
AIDS.
And their behavior that
night reminded me of what the Jews had
to go through during the uh Nazi
era. My very sick friend was thrown on
the ground with a gun to his
head. The son I
raised was intimidated and brutalized,
thrown on the ground. That night we
heard gay AIDS jokes, gay
jokes. We were physically and brutally
intimidated by these
thugs who found 4 ounces of marijuana in
my house. Okay. They arrested me for the
ounces and nine months later I was
exonerated because the 4 ounces of
marijuana were claimed by my very sick
and dying friend Jonathan West.
Before he died, he testified that the 4
ounces of marijuana in the house were
his and the charges were dropped against
me. Two weeks later, he
died. Was he using these for this
marijuana, the hemp for medical
purposes? Yeah. Cuz now we've heard on
this show and from other sources that it
can be helpful in relieving pain. It can
be helpful in taking care of nausea,
helping with the easy pain, the nausea,
increasing appetite, etc. Primarily why
I did it because marijuana was keeping
Jonathan alive for the last 3 years of
his life. He had no
appetite. He had everything. He had
cancer. He had
pneumonia. He was 90 lb.
Marijuana was literally keeping him
alive. It was offsetting all the side
effects of the ACT and the chemotherapy
and all the myriad of drugs he was
taking, legal drugs that had severe side
effects from depression to vomiting to
diarrhea. So then you took this and you
went out and put together proposition in
memory of Jonathan West his eulogy. I
collected
16,500 signatures to put marijuana as
medicine on the ballot in San Francisco.
I never dreamed in my wildest dreams
that we would get 80% of the vote, but
in fact, that's exactly what happened.
Now, what does the wording pretty much
specify on? Is it strictly for medical
purposes? Is that how it's worded? Is
there Yes, it's strictly for medical
purposes. It's only for people that have
certain
ailments that are covered under the
initiative. Now, does this mean that
their doctors can prescribe it or that
if they're just caught with it and they
have uh proof of a certain ailment, then
there's no prosecution? Well, legally,
uh, Proposition P has no stature. It is
merely an advisory to the city and
county of San Francisco.
However, I think the district attorney
can read numbers and I think that he
knows that the people of San Francisco
are serious. As a matter of fact, we got
more votes than the district attorney.
Okay. We're the highest vote getter in
San Francisco history. Now, how many
districts are there in San Francisco?
There are 628 precincts in San
Francisco. There are 11 different
districts. Okay. Now, you brought in and
what 30 of those 30 of those precincts.
In the gay districts, we had 30
precincts. There was 100% for
Proposition P, not one dissenting vote.
And Proposition P seem to have crossed
all the boundaries. I know that everyone
thinks San Francisco is cook city. And
in many ways, it is Cook City. 40% of
the people are totally
kooky, but 80% aren't. And I think that
is a telling thing here that we have
crossed the Coo boundaries. We've gone
beyond cooked and we even got the
elderly people to vote for this. And a
matter of fact, I had elderly people
calling me up to me and saying, "Dennis,
you know, I used to use this stuff when
I was a kid. My mother used to give me
this for, etc., etc., etc. She used it
for rheumatism. She used it for a
bronchitis. And they actually had a
tincture they put on
people's knees and joints for arthritis
and rheumatism. And so we even got the
old people. And I know that people
think, well, older people are very much
against us. Wrong. Older people are
against drug use per se and drug abuse.
But quite frankly, I'm against drug
abuse myself. And so we are talking in
medicine. We know we haven't changed the
law. However, we have given the people
of San
Francisco a defense in court. Okay. You
know, is this defense good for strictly
residents of San Francisco or if
somebody's from New York visiting cuz
they know that they're not feeling very
healthy and they are looking for an
avenue which they can relieve pain that
to show up in San Francisco as a tourist
to take care of this problem or well uh
it does seem to become that San
Francisco is going to become the lords
of America because after the election I
had gotten phone calls from all over the
nation from the people from multiple
scerosis to cancer and this and that and
they're anxious to come to San
Francisco, but now because now they
think they can get treated. Now, are
they also going to be able to grow it
and raise it? Well, s like I said,
Proposition P has no legal stature.
However, there is a political aspect of
San uh P that makes it very
interesting. It was during a mayor's
race that Proposition P was on the
ballot. The top two vote getters are now
in a runoff.
One of them is Frank Jordan, an ex-
police chief who is trying to be a
liberal, and one of them is the
incumbent mayor who is a liberal. They
have both been in contact with me asking
me how they can help enforce Proposition
P. Excellent.
I am playing that card. I am playing
each against each
other for the for the betterment of this
country. And do you think you're going
to be able to get this to spread out now
through not just the state, but do you
think this will start big popping up now
and like new Well, my new demands are um
six plants. Six plants per par per AIDS
patient, per cancer patient, multiple
scessive, whatever you got, six plants.
You're allowed to grow your own six
plants. And what I'm really asking for
is de facto legalization of marijuana
for cult cultivation of marijuana for
medical purposes.
I can't ask I I am asking the city of
county of San Francisco to look the
other way. Okay. When they see six
plants growing in a window to just look
the other way. I I know I cannot change
state law out of San Francisco. Although
I do believe the state of California is
ready and we are taking this initiative
on the road. Our next uh targeted
location is Santa Cruz, California.
Okay. And after that I want to take it
to Humboldt and Menescino and to Los
Angeles right into the belly of the
beast. Okay. Now if someone how do they
protect themselves? I mean if they're
growing six months they have to have a
statement from a doctor saying that they
are AIDS patient or that's exactly what
we're advising patients to do to get an
advisory note from their doctor. Okay.
That says if marijuana were legal I
would prescribe it. And that's all they
because doctors cannot legally prescribe
it. Now,
uh I do believe that there will never be
another prosecution for marijuana in San
Francisco
again. I believe that because I am going
to stand in the way of anybody that
tries to prosecute anybody for um
marijuana in San Francisco. Proposition
W. It was at the right time, the right
place, but Harvey dying and George dying
screwed it all up. But I intend to bring
up Proposition W, the one I put on
before along with Proposition
P, to try to make San Francisco the
place we wanted it to be. Excellent. And
uh I want to you know let you know I
I've been aware of your work in the
movement for a long time and you know
you've made quite an impact on many of
the activists coast to coast and are
looked upon as one of the most
intellectual and hardworking leaders in
what we're doing. It's been an honor to
have you on our show. I like to have you
back again. You've come with so much
knowledge and information. We have a lot
of stories. Anytime you want me back,
Casper, it's been pleasure. Thank you so
much. And I also like to have you
realize that anybody can get out there
and join this fight. Anybody can make a
difference. The important thing is to
get up and do it. Until we have the
opportunity to get together the next
time, keep strong, keep happy, keep
wise. Thank you.