well I must say it's been an honor to
know Gatewood the number of years that
I've known him I met him back it was
Earth day and it was
1991 and we were filming segments for
time for hemp in San
Francisco we'd gone up to San Francisco
Ed Rosenthal I wanted to be a guest on
the show and we had anticipated spending
the day filming a big interview with Ed
and going over his library of books that
he'd written and uh about an hour before
I and the camber crew and the sound crew
got there Ed apparently thought it'd be
a good time to drop two hits
acid so uh did there wasn't much to
interview at that point yeah you know so
we went down to uh Earth Day a little
early and Jack har said that a friend of
his by the name of Gateway galberth was
going to be around we should try to make
it a point to get Gatewood on the
program as a guest and he said that
Gatewood was running for governor of
Kentucky and I said he's
what he said he's running for governor
of Kentucky and I said and he smokes
pot and gate was I mean and Jack Harris
said yeah and he'll make a great guess
so you should make it a point to talk
with him well those of you who've known
me a long time may know that my family
has a political background in the state
of
Indiana my mom was uh the first female
to be president of the County Council in
our area and in the history of of
Delaware County and she broke a lot of
ground she was a woman's Liber as we
called them back then and she taught me
at an early age the importance of one
standing up for yourself and being who
you are and true to
yourself which gate would represented as
a candidate and she taught me
the ins and outs of
politics and I knew after hanging out
with Jack hair that even though he had
the truth about making paper and fiber
and fuel out of this fantastic plant
that unless you make a change in
Congress or you make a change in the
Senate you're not going to get a whole
lot done you're just going to be
educating people about the truth
and when I heard that we had somebody
from the marijuana movement running for
governor of a
state that impressed me until that point
I had known Jack hair and the
intellectual aspects of this plant of
this of the history of this entire
travesty and we had worked on the
California hemp initiative and I saw
with Jack hair how through politics you
can make a
change but the idea at that time when
Gatewood was running for
governor coming out of the closet about
smoking marijuana and talking about
using the revenue that comes from
generating taxes from creating
industries that are built on making
fabulous products from this plant and
how we were saving the environment and
how we were saving dollars it all made
sense and suddenly not only did we have
Jack hair's
knowledge we had the sensibility of
Gatewood galberth as a
candidate now another aspect about
Gatewood unlike a lot of us in the
marijuana movement when I came into the
marijuana movement I came in because
Jack har needed somebody to run his
office while he went on the road to talk
about paper fiber and
fuel Jack came into the movement because
some lady introduced it to him and he
wanted to smoke it and it was like
that's how you made the book about
getting high high and this and you've
all heard that story Gatewood came into
it because his grandfather and his great
grandfather and his great great
grandfather and his great great great
grandfather and I think the people who
knew Jesus in your family all grew
marijuana but they didn't grow it to get
high they grew it to make oil they grew
it to make rope they grew to make papers
they grew as an industry and as they
were doing so they were making a
environment that was considered one of
the
wealthiest
commonwealths in the history of the
United States so here I had somebody
from the belly of the Beast getting
ready to sit down and talk to me for the
first time and a very rational
intellectual
way that I've never been dealt with
before On My Level in politics My Level
meaning the voter the person who's going
to be voting in New York Kentucky
Maine somebody who works on
candidates campaigns and knows how to
put together the importance of all the
fine points of how we get a candidate
elected and all the key reasons he
didn't come in here and going we want to
get high
which we do and on by the way those of
you who are very comfortable knowing
that we've outlawed this plant because
it keeps those of us from getting
high no it just keeps you from getting
taxes from us getting high um Gatewood
talks
sensibility the interview that I did
with
Gatewood when I showed it to my parents
very conservative
Midwestern running for office my my mom
very very well known in politics on a
Statewide level very active
campaigner they were blown away their
comment was this man should be governor
of
Kentucky when I got done talking with
Gatewood for the very first time it made
sense to me that he should be governor
of any
state he was the first person who was
actually talking dollars and cents get
rid of the smoke and noise and
Industries and bring in the green
industry what do you hear now I almost
wanted to throw up in my own mouth when
I heard Al Gore stand before Congress
and talk about getting rid of the smoke
and noise industry and bringing in the
green industry and he said everything
that gate was said except for one
word
hemp when President Obama addressed the
United States after this
horrific spill in the Gulf
he stood before America and
promised to set us free from foreign oil
that we were going to take care of the
problems that developed this mess off of
our Shores and he said everything that
Gatewood galberth has been saying for 20
years except for one
word
hemp I get a little agitated when I talk
about our politicians because it's too
late now for any politici to stand up in
front of me and you and anybody else in
this country and say oh I didn't know
that you can make paper and fiber and
fuel out of this plant no I had no idea
we were spending this much money putting
all these people away Behind
Bars when we should take that money and
put it into the school systems my gosh I
had no clue to this
travesty because people like gatew
galberth has been standing on the
corners of every street corner in this
nation saying the truth along with Jack
hair along with Dr Todd mcara and Keith
strop and every other hardworking
activist that has known the truth for 20
years so when someone like gate MC
galbert says to me he's running for
office for governor of the state of
Kentucky and it this his intention to
take this plant the revenue from this
plant and generate from IT jobs that
will benefit those people living in
Kentucky the revenue will help benefit
schools for the children going there to
get their brains fed in
Kentucky it's going to take care of the
health care problems for the senior
citizens that are facing a federal
bankruptcy of our social security in 13
years in
Kentucky that he has a solution to the
problems in
Kentucky that will ultimately bring
forward a solution to the problems in
America I believe
him he handed out 20 years ago a book to
everybody who would pay mind to it the
marijuana feasibility study how you
would take this plant put an end to our
economy began to take it put it into
fuels by just changing the car a little
bit here by putting it into the papers
and the fibers and the fuels and making
the jobs and the revenue and the taxes
and how we would stop putting the money
into the prison system and into the
court systems and we could save the
taxpayer and we would have a beautiful
society that was designed to
educate our citizens and stimulate
creativity and to bring forward an
environment low on
crime that would not cost the
taxpayers a large amount of money I
believed him he spoke to me as a voter
looking for solutions to horrific
problems that laid at my feet and the
feet of my
children that was the impact that I had
from Gateway G Al when he sat down and
took time for hemp now when Gatewood
took time for Casper over the years as a
friend
amazing I've had it with the planet
sometimes and I would call Gatewood up
and say I can't take it that the world's
beat me and I get off the phone and I
got it I'm regenerated I'm
okay gatewood's been there when I said
Gatewood the world loves me today it's
been a good
day and as a friend we've
laughed and I know the Merit of this man
the character of this man and there
hasn't been a time that this man has let
me down as a
friend or as a citizen of my
nation the one thing I am most baffled
by
as how it is he has not been elected yet
to the seat of the governor of
Kentucky he speaks
rational he speaks
truth he speaks plain English and
anybody who's going to go and put their
vote on any candidate is looking for
someone who speaks the truth and plain
English that's why I've never understood
how it is a man and who had the answers
to the problems this state faces has yet
been able to do so now our country is
facing a horrific
time we know that by the end of May over
half of the United States is in
bankruptcy over 20 states have already
filed bankruptcy state stimuluses are
going buildy up the Federal stimulus are
being uh taken from the states and uh
they don't know what to do and by July
August and other 10 or 15 will be filing
bankruptcy by the end of the year maybe
all but three will go under we are
cutting funds for our children's
educations I hear every day how when I
wake up we're closing schools here in
Oregon we're shutting down libraries in
in in California we're cutting members
off the police department and Iowa all
my gosh we're laying off state workers
in
Ohio I hear how our nation was held
hostage by our Congress because they
couldn't figure out this handful of
money on this budget that equaled to
what they spend on the War on
Drugs what I don't hear from anybody but
people like Gatewood and Ron Paul and
Dennis
cenage what I don't hear from my
Congress what I don't hear from my
Senate are answers answers that has been
given to them in plain English and a
book and books by Jack hair books called
the feasibility study by gate MC
galberth books by Ed Rosenthal books by
Ethan nlman don't tell me you're stupid
don't play me as
stupid that's why every time gate was
says he's running for governor I always
say I expect to be in the governor's
office with with
you on Election Day