Kentucky was the world's largest
producer f for over 100 years it was our
largest cash crop for for more than a
century and and uh imagine that a state
whose largest cash crop was hemp and uh
I'm sure that the the smoking aspect of
it was uh you know was also well
represented um people
um of course in the early 1900s it uh
went down and they legalized it in 37
and
um Kentucky should be the place where
cannabis is returned as a cash crop in
the state of Kentucky and I started out
a long time ago to try to make that a
reality uh I'm a fourth generation
Kentuckian uh I was 24 years old in a
milk man in
1971 when I decided I was Grist for the
mill I was end up in prison or in in
jail or dead at an early age so I
decided that uh I better learn the
system
so uh or I was just going to be a victim
of it so I decided I was going to go to
college become an
attorney and while I was at it if I was
going to put that much into it I might
as well become governor and change the
marijuana laws in the state of Kentucky
and quit treating our people like we're
an occupied
territory and take the government out of
the the helicopters uh out of the air
that are hovering over the fields and
Gardens of the people of state of
Kentucky and put marijuana into the
hands as many sick and dying people in
State as I possibly could and that's
what I started out to do 40 years ago
and I've gotten up every day since that
time to do that I've run for office in
the state of Kentucky on several
occasions this is my fifth time for
governor I've also run for uh a uh
agricultural commissioner attorney
general in Congress twice I've ped some
mighty impressive numbers I won't bore
you with them all but let me tell you
that this time we is the very best
chance that I've ever had to actually
win the governor of the state of
Kentucky let me tell you what that would
do to the political landscape in the
United States of America that would be
phenomenal there was an independent uh
elected for the first time in 150 years
in Rhode Island last last political
season but he had been a state a US
state senator out of that uh out of that
state so he already had a Statewide
basis to go independent with my running
mate and I are totally independent no
party affiliation whatsoever I've got a
lady running mate that named D Riley
who's phenomenal uh the mother of six
two adopted one of her natural children
in Special Needs she knows where the the
politics hit the road about policies for
women and children in the state and
she's smart as attack and we need more
women in leadership rols in the state of
Kentucky U I am running this time this
is what I say they say galbert you're
perennial candidate that's well ky's got
perennial problems if the people in
Kentucky had who had beaten me had
actually fixed the problems I wouldn't
had to run again but they didn't and
they have it and they can't because
neither party can produce a candidate
can disengage from the partisanship long
enough to work the other side to get the
job
done and the leadership of the parties
in both the major parties state of
Kentucky had the horns locked up like
two bull elk fighting over territory
while the business of the people lays
dead in the
dust so my running rate and I say that
only an independent who doesn't care who
gets credit for doing what's right for
the people of the state of Kentucky
stand the best chance of untying that
gordian not and letting both parties
operate in the fashion that a lot of the
well-intentioned membership really want
to want to work the beauty of it is
we're not looking to replace either
party we're not looking to throw the
Rascals out we're not looking for you to
vote against your uh you know your
representative or Senator and we don't
want you to renounce your family's party
we're not asking you to do that we're
not asking you to vote for the dreaded
other party we're asking you to vote for
an independent who wants to work with
you to try to get the job
done and so U I've offered myself again
this time and the difference is there
are several things uh first of all is
that everybody's sick and tired of the
gridlock in Kentucky as they say I
accuse Kentucky of being the victim of
electile dysfunction that they they just
can't seem to get it right and uh so U
what we think is that uh we know for a
fact that we're already climbing in the
PO I I said the last time uh they they
ped us about 6 months ago at 5% they
said what' you think I said that's great
with me I I believe we'll be 10% by May
and 15 to 20% by September we were at
133% in April so you know we're moving
on up we're really not spending any
money we don't have it to spend uh but
I've never spent more than $20,000 on
any campaign in the past we spent
140,000 on this so
far uh you
know 990,000 of it is my
money I I practice law for a living I
live I live fee to fee uh but I smell it
this time I smell it this time that
people are sick and tired of it I got
endorsed by Union the other day and I
said why uh you know why did you folks
endorse me he said because you've never
lied to us Gatewood I said well hell if
I was going to lied to you I'd already
been elected you know and and people are
understanding that and people were
gluing into that so uh what does an
election for Gatewood galberth in
Kentucky mean for the people of the city
of Portland and the C people of Oregon
I'll tell you what it means For the
First Time In My Memory that I've ever
heard the people of America are going to
have a champion who believes it when the
founding fathers conferred sovereignty
on us as human
beings when they said that every every
human being is endowed by their creator
with life liberty and pursuit of
happiness certain inalienable
rights and uh for the first time to
think about
that before the American Revolution came
back we were all
property we belong to the local king or
queen to the local Warlord whoever
possessed the most gun powder in the
valley you didn't have any inalienable
rights people didn't have any
inalienable
rights if the ruler said hey come in
here off with their head there you went
there was nobody to intercede on your
behalf but the founding
fathers took humankind out of the
category of property and conferred on
them the concept of sovereign human
beings self-d
determinative indiv
individualized wor something
individually and something that the
government couldn't take away or mess
with and they wrote a
constitution the Declaration of
Independence didn't become law but the
Constitution they fashioned to try to
immortalize that was was their attempt
to write the set of laws that was going
to keep that project in mind so it was a
human Revolution that conference of
sovereignty on the individual and then
they turned just loose and with that
kind of Freedom we've come in America
and that's the way supposed to have
started out and what we've been trying
to keep up but that concept of
individual sovereignty is under great
pressure
today and the current generation is
facing the greatest threat of all of
having the Bill of Rights just flat
drawn out from underneath
us in the uh in the nanny State thought
line of protecting us from ourselves
but what it is is a is a is a absolute
assault on the uh on the Privileges of
sovereign human beings and Sovereign
citizens of the
Constitution so the uh the right to life
Liber and pursuit of happiness is not a
law because it is not in the
Constitution but in the state of
Kentucky the very first section of the
Constitution of the state of Kentucky
says that we are
all uh possessed of inalienable right to
life liberty of
Happiness so I'm going to reconstruct
ky's policy and kuy's government around
that
thesis and we're going to ReDiscover
whether America still has a pulse we're
going to try to become the template of
what freedom of the individual means in
the state of
Kentucky I believe we'll become a
tourist
Mecca I believe that people will come in
from all around uh the the country and
the globe to see what it likes to live
free
and I'm not talking about riots in
streets I'm not talking about uh you
know people causing tumult out in public
I don't see that happening I just think
that the idea that we're attempting it
is going to bring in the right-minded
people but uh we're going to try to
spread it out we're going to try to
ReDiscover the American Revolution and
we're going to do that by uh putting the
processes and the surpluses of a form of
government out to the people instead of
special interests I know who those
special interests are and I'm going to
put a stop to it and the savings we're
going to put back into the hands of the
people