you know back in the early 90s after you
met Willie Nelson uh I was honored to
get a call from you and say Willie
Nelson's going to contact you and I I
could hardly believe it actually when
you called and told me that but you know
less than a couple weeks later that
really happened I really appreciate that
but then about 3 weeks after that I flew
there to Lexington and starting at the
Hyatt Regency right next to is it rup
Auditorium rup Arena rup Arena you took
off in your red Mercedes-Benz station
wagon and drove uh in a hemp biodiesel
car could you tell our audience a little
bit how how that came about and how you
actually first taught Willie Nelson
who's now a big proponent of biodiesel
about H biodiesel we' always heard that
Rudolph diesel had manufactured his
diesel engine runoff seedo we really
didn't understand quite grasp that this
was in the early '90s late 80s and then
a fellow from Nevada Las Vegas Nevada
came through town driving a little
Volkswagen diesel and he was running it
off Burger King oil and so we had just
uh derived some hemp oil out of hemp
seeds hemp seeds are 30 to 40% oil by
weight you got 100 lounds of hemp seeds
you can drive 30 to 40 PBS of pure oil
out of it and so we had some of that and
he tested it out in his engine and he
said this is the best seedor that I've
ever driven this car on and so we had
seedor when Willie came in to do a
benefit concert for me we poured that
hemp oil into my Mercedes diesel and
drove it about 110 mil across Kentucky
and it was the first time in I guess 50
to 60 years that any vehicle had ever
been driven on depoil on the United
States roads but Willie told me later on
12 years later actually no I mean now
about 10 years later he says gate wood
he says that afternoon we did that
taught me what it was all about and
that's the reason I started my bio fuel
company was from what we learned that
afternoon driving your Mercedes across
there and we also smoking about the
biggest Hooter at probably Road in
Kentucky at the time and there was a
caravan of us we went from uh the Hyatt
there and and R Auditorium through
Frankfurt the state capital which is
about 80 Mi and then alog together 120
Mi all the way into Louisville which is
the largest uh city in Kentucky and then
he did a big benefit concert for you
there there that night that's right and
so uh it was a real honor to participate
that in that and I know CNN uh had their
environmental show earthwatch and they
covered that pretty intensely so you're
running for governor again if you were
elected what are the top three action
items that you would enact as
Governor you know Kentucky is a
dysfunctional State uh We've not been
able to pass a a balanced budget in uh
in four out of the last seven sessions
we've had to go to special sessions and
advanced sessions to get the actual
budget passed because neither party can
produce a candidate can disengage the
partisanship long enough to work with
the other side it's just all very
vicious and vituperative and people are
getting turned off with all the negative
ads and what we've got to do first and
formost is to restore a sense of
integrity and honesty and even
handedness in the process itself we
could come up with all kinds of
hypothetical programs and uh that we
could apply and let people have access
to but it would get shredded by the uh
by the uh the policies of fear and
retribution on the state level so we've
got to return uh integrity and Trust in
the process itself uh in state of
Kentucky it's very poor we we're among
the third or fourth poorest state in the
Union we've got 23 states of app 23
counties of Appalachia which are the
poorest uh regions of the Union of the
states so uh we need to
uh uh we need to uh uh get people
interested in the process again because
nobody wants anything to do with it it's
just so dirty and mean and Despicable
and everybody's calling everybody I've
run before where I said I believe all my
opponents are Honorable Men and what
they're saying about each other is true
which makes them all unfit for office
you know but uh so so the first thing is
to try to restore that integrity and the
way we we do that is by giving everybody
a chance to do right uh you know we
cannot oppose these people we can't
overpower them we've got to control them
into doing what they believe is right
for the people in ky's Dynamics for 40
years the Democrats ruled everything
that the Republicans didn't have any
didn't have the house didn't have the
Senate and didn't have the governor's
office for 40 years the Democrats ruled
over the Republicans and treated them
like and so uh 10 years ago the
Republicans took over the Senate and
they've been practicing the politics of
Retribution for the last 10 years and
you know they've been treating the
Democrats like they got treated for
those 40 years and the Democrats don't
know what to do they're screaming like
scalded dogs you know but they did it to
the Republicans and so uh the fell
there's been one fellow who's doing it
he's called The Bully uh the leader of
the Senate and you know he is a bully
and he can be other than Charming on
many occasions but he's just giving the
Democrats what it is they gave the
Republicans all that time so what I'm
telling the people state of Kentucky
look it's time to stop practicing the
politics of Retribution and get into
practicing the politics of achievement
you know we can no longer you know be
retributive and because it's killing the
state of Kentucky we're bankrupt we're
absolutely desperate for cash and that's
why I believe that my plan to
immediately start planting hemp as a gas
crop next spring you know within 2
months after I take over the office
state of Kentucky my My First Act I'm
going to do is I'm going to take the
military helicopters out from going over
the fields and Gardens of the people of
state of Kentucky you know this is
America not Afghanistan and we're not an
occupied territory and I'm not going to
treat our citizens like we are one I'm
going to take the Army and the National
Guard out of police activities they're
no longer going to be assisting State
Police
those helicopters are going to be used
for emergency medical and disaster
relief
only and so we're going to revolutionize
the relationship between the police and
the people there's no longer going to be
an US versus them kind of attitude
that's going to be we and there's going
to be respect given and don't come in
here and mess up don't come in here and
confuse our Civility and statesmanship
with being weak on anything we're
not but we're going to start treating
people as Sovereign human beings we're
going to get marijuana into the hands of
medic the sick and dying folks
immediately as soon as we can are we're
going to try to set up a a evenhanded
tax regulatory system on it so we can
get some new tax money in instead of
taxing uh you know instead of putting
more taxes on the wage earner here in
the state I mean let's face it uh the if
we just took the profits of the drug
lords and put them into our educational
system it'd be soled
overnight saw a bust of a drug lower
down Mexico the other day he had 12
billion do
stacked stacked in a
room1
billion now that's that's the budget of
Kentucky for two years he had stack
there what we could do with education
what we could do the other thing I want
to do is I'd really like to sue the
farmaceutical companies and make them
come up with hundreds of millions of
dollars in drug treatment programs for
the uh for the problems that they're
solving with their pharmaceutical
medicine