I say how can I say this? You can't
believe how advanced we are as an
independent ticket. Independent scares
the be Jesus out of the powers that be.
Independent means that they don't have
any power over you. They can't instill
party
partisanship. We are absolutely
unaffiliated with anybody. All we want
to do is what's right for the people.
And if we can set that template, if we
can show it can be done, there's going
to be a popular
uprising. There's going to be we will be
defeating money that's 10 times 20 times
what we
have. But if your votes not for sale, it
doesn't make any difference how much
money the other side spends. That's
true. And the word is out. The buzz is
us. the state employees, 38,000 people,
they hate they hate the present governor
and they're all for us. The the head of
the union has already come to us and
say, "Hey, we're out there working for
you right now." You know, the u the we
came out against mountaintop removal
that made
extremely ecologically uh uh destructive
way of extracting coal. We came out
against it. We're the only candidates
against it. I've got the only one
running mate who's a woman. She's the
only woman in the race. There's 350,000
more women vote in that race than men
do. I only need 450,000 votes to win
this
thing, you know. So, we got the we got
the the the environmentalist. We have
the
military. I' I've got honorable
discharge from Marine Corps. And I tell
you, this present governor, the uh who's
going to have the Democratic nomination
because he's an incumbent, the other
day, he uh he did not go to a gathering
at Fort Campbell where President Obama
came down to honor the Navy Seals who
took out
Osama. Our governor refused to go down
with him because he didn't want to have
his picture taken with Obama.
He said he had some he had to be talking
with some other business leaders in the
state at that time. So he couldn't
afford to change his
schedule. And so I thought that was an
affront to every military person in the
whole damn state that he was too
cowardly. He didn't want his picture
taken with Obama because Obama was
roundly defeated in Kentucky. But there
comes times when you've got to set aside
that kind of partisanship and exercise
some common sense and pay homage to
brave people like those Navy Seals who
went in there and did something that I'm
sure a lot of us like to have seen
done. And so uh he's roundly and roundly
uh roundly dis disgusted a lot of
people. So he is ready for a big
downfall and the Republican is uh just
he's not he's not going to make it. The
Republican is toast already. So we have
an extremely weak field that we're
running against and so we ought to win
this thing is we can just put up a
modicum of credibility and
responsibility. So uh you know kind of
you know it's kind of like the NBA
finals. Your team might not be in the
finals when they may be as a half a
continent away, but you know, take pay
attention to them box scores there in
Kentucky. They're going to be fun to
keep up with. We're going to get a lot
of national and international attention.
So, Gatewood, we got time for one more
little uh stump speech here. Let's show
them your book and your website and tell
them how they can get in touch with you.
Folks, this book right here is called
The Last Free Man in America Meets the
Synthetic Subversion. It was a number
one seller at a major market for 11
straight weeks. And an exgovernor says
it's the best statement of freedom in
America he's ever read. This is a fun
book, folks. I left out 100% of the sex
and 80% of the drugs, but it's still a
kick-ass read. So, the uh you can go to
gatewood.com to get our political get
our political site. at that same spot,
you can find out how to get in touch
with us and request a book, and I'd be
glad to send you one. I'd appreciate a
donation in return, but after I send you
one, there'll be an envelope with it.
Send me some money if you like the book.
But, uh, it's
gatewood.com that people all over the
world can contribute to us, folks. We
have gotten contributions from out of
the country thus far. If you're a big
dog, I mean, if you're a big dog, come
on. Jesus Christ. What was it going to
take to get you guys out here to get
this thing done? You know, I know people
who uh who are helping out uh the
marijuana policy project, I think, has
as a couple of big donors uh of an
insurance, of course. Yeah. A big
insurance company. He says he's going to
put an initiative for medical marijuana
on the Ohio ballot. He just came out the
past few weeks and said that. Look, you
couldn't put your money in any more
honorable place than to try to get
marijuana as a medicine in the hands of
the sick and dying people of the United
States of America. You just with that
money, you could buy relief from people
who right now are suffering from chronic
pain. from people who suffer all day
from chronic pain. You could bring
immediate relief to those people with
the proper application and direction of
really a very small amount of money. So
gatewood.com, get in touch with me. I'm
going to show you how to bring relief to
to hundreds of thousands of people and
relief to your own soul because you you
you'll feel a lot better about yourself
after you get this done. All right.
Thank you, sir. Thank you, sir. I want
to thank you for coming to Portland.
Thank you. I must uh have the honor of
being