[Applause]
Well, this is a very special day and a
very special event at a very special
time if I might say so myself.
You know, every generation that comes
along, it becomes necessary for somebody
to step forward who can articulate a
message of freedom and hope and show us
a pathway from tyranny into liberty. And
for this generation, that person was
Jack Harer.
He wrote the book The Emperor Wears No
Clothes in the late
1980s. And it's a collection of news
stories and clippings and factoids and
editorial. And it pretty much blew the
lid off of uh the whole international
awareness about the hemp plant, the
cannabis plant, what it used to do for
us, how it's been used for 5,000
years in thousands of different ways.
and also why it became illegal in this
country and how it was done and how it's
been persecuted and
victimized for decades for almost 80
years. Jack Hair came to the first
Seattle Hemp Fest in
1991 and it was a lot like this right
here. It looked really a lot like this
in Volunteer Park in Seattle.
And I just want to say that these guys,
Justin and everybody have done an
amazing job. Give a hand for all the
volunteers and all the folks that made
this possible to bring. We're
celebrating a different aroma in Tacoma
today.
We're celebrating the cannabis plant,
one of the most versatile plants in the
world. So,
keep going. So, in in honor of Jack
Herror, who you know you know Jack had a
stroke and a heart attack speaking at at
uh the World Hemp Expo in Oregon and uh
most people would have been done from
that point. They never would have gone
back on the road again. But Jack, even
though he was half paralyzed from a
stroke and he had to learn to speak
again, he wasn't that great of a speaker
all of a sudden. That didn't stop him.
And Jack went back on the road and never
missed another Hemp Fest after that
Seattle Hemp Fest. And when he had his
next stroke, he was speaking at Hemptock
down in Portland last year, right after
he spoke. No one's that dedicated. Jack
literally gave his life for the cannabis
movement. He refused to stop and every
year he got better and better. He got
his speaking skills back and pretty soon
you could really understand him. But it
never stopped Jack. And uh he always
would have to be in his booth meeting
people and signing copies. The emperor
wears no clothes. And uh so in honor of
Jack Hera, I want to if we can do this
with this many people, but I think we
can call enough respect and enough honor
for Jack to say thank you by a brief
moment of silence. So we're going to do
that. If we can hear this generator
behind us, we know we're doing a good
job. Let's just take a few moments out
for a brief moment to send out a prayer
to Jack because I think he's here with
us.
[Applause]
Thank you so much. And uh I'm going to
give back give a hand to this man who's
making it all possible.
[Applause]