[Music]
welcome to San Francisco a city of
creativity community and cannabis
culture Today We Gather to celebrate the
10th anniversary of the San Francisco
daadu which first took place in
2014 although daadu began its journey in
2013 it was here in San Francisco that
the event truly found its West Coast
Spirit what started as a small
celebration has since grown into one of
the most respected gatherings in the
Cannabis community and this year we
honor a decade of passion craftsmanship
and connection at the heart of this
event is Mila Johansson the hash Queen
this is her story and the journey of
daadu Mila Johnson has dedicated her
life to revolutionizing the way we make
and appreciate hashish from her days
running Amsterdam's first Coffee House
in the 1960s to her Innovations in
cannabis extraction MAA has always been
a Pioneer her Creations the pollinator
and isolator made hash extraction
accessible to enthusiasts worldwide and
cemented her Legacy as the hash Queen
one night I'm standing in front of my
clothes dryer and I noticed what the
clothes are doing tumbling inside the
dryer and we just put a screen around
the drum of the clothes dryer but by one
inside and turned it on and lo and
behold 5 minutes later there's all the
crystals lying at the bottom pollinators
we call them yes daadu was born from
Mila's Vision to bring the Cannabis
Community together to celebrate the art
of resin
[Music]
extraction I started the first abue in
uh 2
13 for my birthday it was my 69th
birthday and I just wanted to do
something fun it began as a birthday
celebration but soon transformed into a
global phenomenon showcasing the best
traditional and modern extraction
techniques it was just going to be a
one-time Affair for my birthday and
never again but people liked it so much
that uh for months later we were in
Barcelona and a few months after that
actually we at our first Dadu right here
in San
Francisco and this is that 10y year
anniversary of that
Dadu I think since then we've had about
50 davidus we travel all over the place
and have them through Europe and right
after this tomorrow actually I'll be
flying to Mexico where we'll have a Dadu
in
guadalahara and then on to Costa Rica
Peru
Argentina Brazil and finally Colombia
and everywhere we'll be having a Dao the
one in Colombia will also have my 80th
birthday party uh that's my near
future today daadu honors 10 years of
innovation friendship and
community in
2014 daadu came to San Francisco for the
first time the first dabad do in San
Francisco in 2014 I attended it and it
was a wonderful thing uh Ed Rose th I
believe DJ Shaw was there you had Todd
mccormic there was uh corge santes um it
was a wonderful event we came together
in this passionate way in such a long
time ago I had heard about this concept
they were doing the dabad I had went to
one davidu in Colorado and I had the
opportunity to be a part of this amazing
thing and I participated in setting up
the Davido in 2014
with Nick douge for Hitman Glass that
event was extremely special it was a
small intimate Gathering where people
were just starting to explore new
possibilities in cannabis resin
extraction the entries then were solvent
and solvent list it was the first press
the and I forget that guy's name but he
had the first Ros and press going on it
was just incredible like people lined up
and all they had was buds they weren't
even doing like little Rosen bags or
anything like that it was like all just
buzz and the the line was for days
Davido is about Community it's about
hash and it's a celebration of Mila and
it's somebody we all love very much you
know to be a part of something so
special that that's why I feel like I'm
here I I live for those moments and
those experiences where I can be part of
something so much bigger than myself MAA
brought together a community of
enthusiasts who were eager to share
their passion for hashish the atmosphere
was electric filled with a sense of
curiosity and camaraderie you had uh uh
Hitman
Glass Marin Asher was like the
entertainment when VA came into America
at that point DJ had gotten her together
with spoiled Rob which is spoiled
patience Collective who's one of the
goats for separating lipids fats waxes
getting down to distillate you know uh
Delta 9 Delta 8 along with holy water
you know it it it goes back real far
Davido is uh has a place in my heart
right now because I was in a room full
of people who love cannabis I don't
think there was one person in that room
who didn't love
cannabis and that's a kind of rare thing
for our community these days and I think
it's a really precious thing that that
we had for many years and so seeing this
community and have a place really
important function that first event was
a symbol of the cultural shift happening
within cannabis a move toward quality
craftsmanship and
Community even then it was clear that
this Gathering was something special but
that first one in America was something
that was just extremely unique and here
it is back now and it's a great thing to
see how far she's come and over 50 to
this point it's incredible but to be a
part of the 10-year anniversary and to
be here and to be doing this right now
are just incredible to see where it has
come because it was so organic and like
gray Market at the time and you know
almost secret like you had to call in
find out where it was you know you
really couldn't put it on the thing she
was by herself at that time too so her
little crew wasn't with her and to again
to see where she's at with her books and
the class and the level of boug that's
here now and the professionalism and to
see all the Young Folks cuz I'm I'm an
older dude at this point to see where
it's went and how professional and how
clean everyone is is just incredible
rible fast forward to today and the
essence of dabad do Remains the Same
everyone here is a judge this
inclusivity is what makes the event
truly unique participants from all
backgrounds come together United by
their love for resin and the desire to
celebrate the craft as I don't usually
like all these cups and competitions
where you only have a few judges I
determined to have a hash competition
where everybody is a judge I can respect
everybody's knowing what they like best
we get people from all over the world we
got people flying in from Canada we've
got people from as far as Florida in the
US Humble County La we got a bunch of La
entries uh there is some amazing hash
from Morocco that that somebody entered
I mean we have tons of really really
cool stuff and Dadu is just so much more
than that it's like carrying on the
legacy of MAA being able to also
celebrate her and give something back to
the community I think I've been to uh
like four or five dadus I've been to uh
Barcelona a couple times Colombia uh
Mexico super excited to um have
everybody here and to be helping mil
with this and uh to be kicking off her
2024 Dabo tour we got a lot of great
entries a lot of great hash there's over
a pound of hash being smoked here today
I mean that's pretty incredible I think
we have 100 people to smoke a pound of
hash we got the whole crew here Focus V
rousing Tech James make a te let going
to be a good time we's smoke some good
hash there's more than enough hash to go
around more than enough hash for
everybody to try all the different
amazing entries we have bubble hash we
have rosin and then we have traditional
and Temple balls so those three
categories are what we're judging today
and you know I'm just blessed to be a
part of this thing at daadu the
competition celebrates the Artistry of
resin extraction with three categories
that showcase the diversity and
craftsmanship in the world of
concentrates let's take a closer look at
each one first we have ice waterer hash
this concentrate is made using a
solventless extraction method that
preserves the purity of the plant by
agitating cannabis plant material in ice
cold water the tricomes tiny resinous
glands rich in cannaboids and tpin are
separated from the rest of the plant
once collected and carefully dried
what's left is a highquality hash known
for its potency and smoothness next up
is rosin another solventless concentrate
rosin is created by applying heat and
pressure to cannabis flour ke or hash
this process results in a sticky
resinous substance that's rich in both
cannaboids and Turpin rosin has quickly
become a favorite in the concentrate
world for its Pure Clean flavor and high
potency finally there's the temple ball
a traditional type of handrolled hash
known for its distinctive shape and
silky texture made by pressing high
quality tricomes into a dense rounded
form Temple balls have a rich tpine
profile and are known for their potent
effects each entry is presented
anonymously labeled only by a
number this ensures a focus on the
quality of the product rather than its
origin we are getting ready to get all
these uh out to the people we're doing
intake right now last minute intake but
we're uh numbering everything so that
it's Anonymous so that people don't know
what's what necessarily uh we have a lot
of amazing entries three categories
we've got rosin we've got water has and
we have traditional SL Temple balls
really amazing stuff I I've seen them
come in over the last month and it's
nothing but spectacular I'm seeing the
best of the best and I judged K ofest
2024 there was amazing stuff there too
but this is just really special ipants
rate each entry across four categories
smell look taste and effect actually I
always feel that a Dadu is uh like a
wine tastery you get 20 bottles of good
wine and you get a a bunch of people and
you know they're going to have a good
time and it's kind of the same way the D
do because everybody who comes there
loves hash and there's competitors and
some of those entries are fantastic the
same day everybody has to try all the
entries and vote for them and at the end
of the day we'll know who the winners
were we are judging each entry on a
scale of 1 to five based on these
different categories look taste effect
and smell we're going through each one
of the entries one by one each judge
will write down their favorite first
second and third place then we're going
to tally it up at the end and announce
the winner at 9:00 p.m. tonight
first comes the smell each judge inhales
deeply exploring the Rich Turpin those
aromatic compounds that make each sample
unique the look is next with judges
examining the color texture and
consistency of the resin the golden
shine of a well-made rosin or the rich
dark tones of a classic hash tell their
own stories of care and craft then
there's the taste arguably the most
enjoyable part each judge takes their
time savoring the flavors whether it's
floral spicy or earthy the effect
completes the experience the way each
entry feels whether it's relaxing
uplifting or somewhere in between adds
the final touch to the
score the judging isn't just about
finding a winner it's a collective
experience where people share notes
debate their favorites and enjoy the
moment the true magic of daadu is the
community it creates where cannabis
enthusiasts from different backgrounds
come together to celebrate their shared
love of
resin Mila Johanson is at the center of
it all smiling and interacting with
attendees sharing stories from her
journey the atmosphere is electric with
people exchanging ideas enjoying the
company and remembering why they fell in
love with hashish in the first
place for MAA daadu has always been
about more than just competition it's
about
connection what I like about daadu most
is that nobody's looking at their phone
MAA says everyone's communicating
whether they're from the same part of
the world or
not as the night comes to a close the
scores are tallied and the winners are
announced cheers erupt as the top three
entries in each category are celebrated
[Music]
for these extractors it's a recognition
of their dedication craftsmanship and
the countless hours spent perfecting
their
[Music]
products but the prizes are just part of
the story the real reward is being part
of this community one that values
craftsmanship creativity and connection
here at Dabo everyone is a winner Bound
by the shared journey of exploring and
celebrating cannabis
resin I am just like estc static right
now like everything I feel like we've
worked hard for is on a table right now
and we've really been pushing ourselves
to like become the like one of the best
and it just feels good to come in here
and have that experience with you guys
and I respect a lot of the other work on
the table and just like this right here
wasn't easy it was not this is a great
competition thank you so much for having
it it's a really awesome to be here so
as we celebrate 10 years of daadu we
also celebrate the incredible impact of
MAA Janson from Amsterdam's underground
cannabis culture to the global
phenomenon that is daadu her journey has
been one of passion perseverance and an
unwavering love for hashish M was doing
it before anybody else was doing it uh
she wasn't just the best at what she did
she was the only person who did what she
did she was and is a Pioneer and she's
always had deep roots in the Cannabis
Community she's always been present
whether we were in fashion or we were
out of fashion and a lot of transitions
like that have happened over the years
whether you know we are at the height of
the drug war or whether we were soaring
on the success of
legalization M's Legacy lives on not
just in her Innovations but in the
community she has built this event is
really a celebration of one person and
that's her Legacy is this event is her
Legacy that's Mila so thank you
[Applause]
guys as we look to the Future dabad do
continues to embody her vision and event
where cannabis lovers from all over the
world can come together learn and
celebrate the art of resin extraction
and I just want to present you with the
queen herself
Mila thank you so
much it's the wonderful to be here I
really enjoyed myself and still SM at
that there thank you so man thank you
for everything that you've done it's
been my
pleasure and I love you all
just stay
Hi here's the 10 years of dabad do and
to many more
ahead this is more than just an event
it's a family a movement and a
celebration of the beauty of cannabis
and the connections it Fosters
[Music]