[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James loud
podcast and today our special guest is
Angela Baka she is the editor of my book
cannabis breeding the editor of high
price the Cannabis cancer connection the
original cannabis Prohibition in
California cannabis and clinical
practice and so many other books she's
touched the work of so many other
individuals in the Cannabis industry and
she works for Oaker Dam as well thank
you for coming on the show thank you for
having me absolutely so we work together
uh every day for about N9 months
literally and you got me focused in a
way that most people could never get me
focused and I think part of that was
that you were waking up at 4:00 a.m. and
I was waking up at 5:00 a.m. and it's
hard to find people that kind of match
your speed when it comes to work
especially early morning like that not
everybody likes waking up and working
first thing right out of bed but that
was my way of finishing this book and uh
yeah you're a big reason the book is
actually here that that we have a
printed version of it so thank you so
much for that of course and you
contributed the book you know beyond
editing and going you know I think
perspective in so many different things
um you know and the whole getting me
Focus part was great because I've been
working on this book for five years and
and tried writing this book over and
over and I didn't have it exactly how I
wanted it and finally we figured it out
there was this recipe for success I
wrote this draft I think the draft was
pretty good by the time you got it and
then we still had a lot of refining to
do and a lot of work uh more than I
would have ever expected would go into
something we put into that book it was a
really fun project for me to work on
because I've worked on a lot of
horiculture content and a lot of
genomics content but I still had this
blind spot when it came to breeding and
getting to do this book filled in all of
the blind spots so that was really fun
for me yeah it's funny from the outside
breeding seems like A+ b equals c and
it's so much more complicated than that
and they're so much more involved one
it's one thing making seeds but actually
breeding and breeding towards goals and
breeding intention depending on what
you're looking for an outcome uh you
know there's just so many different
directions see that's funny to me
because the way I've distilled it to
people when I explain to them oh I
understand breeding now is it's growing
except you take notes and pay attention
yeah record it's a lot of it's a lot of
data collection and I think like with
our facility that's what we do it's data
collection uh collecting data on
everything and I'm I'm one of those
people I like collecting data I like
looking at things over time it's you
know growing flow it's like you're
looking at that Harvest and maybe you're
looking at the next Harvest how how can
I improve it but with genetics you're
looking like how can I improve it over
time uh and what is that thing that I
created and how can I make it better you
know you're trying to improve the gene
pool as opposed to taking away from the
gene pool which I think is what a lot of
people do uh not intentionally but I
think a lot of people are just breeding
to breed and to make seeds and you're
looking at the whole plant right you're
not just looking at the end product like
you're looking at every little detail
about how it grows and its environment
and I think that gets lost a lot when we
talk about cannabis varieties because
everyone just wants to know what kind of
high they're going to get yeah or you
know I think we we have an overemphasis
on look and bag of feel and we need to
go back to like how does it make me feel
like I've been talking about that a lot
on the show it's like uh ever since my
friend Dave passed uh Dave mesford he
was in the book yeah and he passed on
420 and so we've put a re-emphasis at
our facility and how does it make you
feel at the end of the day what are we
doing this for we're doing this for the
effect the medical benefit whether you
want it for recreational or whatever
it's medical at the end of the day so I
think Dennis PR said it best a long time
ago it's funny because even uh with my
lower tolerance now some of some of my
favorite varieties I've ever smoked were
some old hippies 1970s strains like
they're just so much more pleasant than
a lot of the stuff today yeah there's
such a wide variety of stuff I mean
we've kind of pigeonholed ourselves into
this galato Market especially in the Bay
Area but then if you drive up to Humble
or you go to Menino or you go over to
any of the other countries there's a lot
more variety and uh we need to get back
into the variety and looking at what's
going to improve the Vigor of the plant
what's going to have you know long-term
improved effects on the plant I think
that's so important well and I know as a
patient that's what I get excited about
when I walk in a dispensary and I see
what's there it's the variety that gets
me excited it's not one thing or the
other thing it's the options and I think
that that's what we get lost on too
there's never going to be the one thing
I want lots of things yeah me too I I
think it's so subjective to the
individual as you've written in other
books as well um that what one person
likes isn't necessarily what the next
person likes or needs and it's so
subjective to the individual you know
across the board and some people like
that narcotic effect and some people
like that uh you know the the stimulant
effect and some people like somewhere in
the middle and then some people just
like hanging out and feeling a little
bit you know I want the stimulant every
time I want the thing that's going to
narrow me in and focus and actually I've
just started playing with thcv strains
yeah a friend of mine from phos actually
sent down an extract called get [ __ ]
done nice and when I smoked that it
didn't taste very good it didn't look
very good the first thing I did was made
this like big list of like the cleaning
projects and the work projects I was
going to take on and I did it yeah thcv
has you know it's funny CU you sent me a
picture of the ratios of thcv in one of
the products that you got and I was like
wow these you know it's like we're
talking about huge percentages and yeah
it's an extract but we're talking about
two to one and then I start reading more
on some of the stuff that was in our
book the um what was Pink boost goddess
pink boost goddess and the pink boost
goddess they're they're breeding it into
a on to one now which is Leaps and
Bounds from the stuff we were looking at
like eight years ago where it was like
showing up as a small
percentage uh you know and I think I've
been turned off by the
thcv as straight thcv it doesn't do
anything for me that I enjoy I don't I
don't like the effect really um but
maybe as a full spectrum product I would
you know I think I only try the full
spectrum products anymore I've already
learned that lesson I'm not ever
interested in anything that's isolated
or artificially high in one canono yeah
I mean I got a vial of pure thcv and I
like was dabbing it and trying it and
then like waking up in the morning and
trying it and then trying it in the
afternoon after I'd smoked a bunch and
the effect it got me high but it didn't
get me like an enjoyable High it wasn't
like I wanted to go smoke more of it it
was more like try I was trying it trying
it because I'd heard like okay well it
helps with uh you know if if you're on a
diet it helps with uh appetite
suppression and it helps with all these
things and focus I've heard a lot of
things oh yeah and for me that wasn't
the case and I think I get a lot of that
from just playing THC you know if I'm
looking for appetite suppression I need
a sativa or something that's more of
that equitorial that basically is that
stimulant side and then I'm not hungry
and I get that just from stuff that's
like a super silver haze I don't feel
like eating necessarily but if I smoke
the narcotic stuff that's very like uh
strong the first thing I want to do is
eat some food or some Granddaddy Purple
but see we asked too much of cannabis
right like we're trying to alter all
these cannaboids to get these different
effects but there's already an herb out
there that suppresses your appetite and
your your sugar Cravings which is gestra
sylvestra yeah and I might be saying
that wrong um but that will do exactly
what we're trying to get thcv to do so
it's so funny to me we're going so hard
on breeding thcv up for this thing when
it already exists pink boost goddess is
really cool I think that was cool that's
there's a great section in the book on
pink uh Pink boo goddess and I feel like
uh you know Dale Hunt is an amazing you
know he wrote a whole chapter for the
book uh you know there's a couple people
Matt Schneider from apical biotech wrote
the tissue culture chapter and as we
were working together this book became
so much bigger than just the James loud
book of reading it's like okay well
James loud my name is on the cover but
it's the contribution of over 20 people
uh and their hard work and you know a
complete chapter from Dale Hunt a
complete chapter on tissue culture from
Matt and then Mojave did contribution
Reggie Gino he was like one of the most
valuable people contributing to the book
because he was questioning me on like do
you mean this or do you mean this
because the way you're writing it it
says this but I think you're meaning
this um or maybe you're meaning this and
I want to know and so then he made me do
a lot of thinking which is good I was so
surprised by Reggie because we thought
Reggie was just going to come in and
kind of do an accuracy check but he did
a line edit uh like he really read the
book and picked out pieces and I think
it's better for Reggie's line edit and I
also just I always admired Reggie before
this experience but I admire him tenfold
now after working with him on this book
yeah so Reggie he's just amazing I mean
yeah I thought that he was just going to
in and read it and give me his opinion
on whether it was like even worth
publishing and then he went in and just
really read it in detail gave us honest
feedback and you know you yeah it's just
amazing having people like that
contributing so and someone of his
caliber I mean he basically wrote the
forward in the book and the forward is
just it's the best forward I've ever
read in a book and it happens to be in
my book so I'm really proud to have him
as part of the contributing team that
made this book so special I had fun
working on that forward with him because
I I gave him a prompt and he wrote it
and I came back in and what I was really
trying to do is getting him to kind of
pull some of his unique experience that
people have not heard about or don't
understand in cannabis and using that to
contextualize what he was doing and I
think he ended up liking the end product
a little bit more because of it because
I kind of pushed him to talk about some
things he wasn't going to talk about and
you can't hear about it unless you read
the book well it's funny cuz I made made
a list of all the people that I would
want to write the forward for the book
and he didn't even seem like someone
that would be attainable to have on and
he wasn't on the list because he was
like that there's a couple people that I
really look up to and and he's one of
them I met him a long time ago uh in the
early days of uh Halen labs and back
back when uh they were Halen had just
merged over in Berkeley and so Reggie
was there and he was younger no gray
hair but really just an amazing guy and
I really looked up to him and I'm like
that guy is super smart and super
amazing and just super friendly he was
always really nice um I feel like I was
just starting to understand what
breeding was back 10 years ago you know
and so just I'm I'm extremely blessed to
have so many great people in the book
and then Hara who did the
layout she's amazing love har she uh
there was a lot of changes that we threw
at her at the end and she just went
through and just did such a good job I
mean um everything is so special about
the book and then the cover there's
actually hidden designs in the cover
that we we put in there and Ben who's
the photographer did that shot and did
did a little photo editing and I feel
like it's a super unique cover has
anyone ever actually found the hidden
symbols in the cover and pointed it out
to you without you saying something no
but if anybody can uh guess what they
are they get a free pack of seeds oh
fine so yeah randomly so yeah we'll do
that on the podcast if you guys have the
book because a lot of people that watch
our show have purchased the book and
there's other there's other symbols in
the book there's all kinds of stuff so
it was a fun project um if you would
have told me how crazy it was going to
be before I wrote it I probably would
never have done it um you know five
years ago when I first had thought about
doing it I didn't realize what writing a
book meant and now I have so much more
respect for these other authors that
have written these great books uh you
know it's there's just so much to go in
even smaller books it's just so much
energy and so much time if you want to
write something good and then all you
can do is write the best book that you
can do and then you put it out there for
the world and the world interprets it
however the world interprets it so and
they've been interpreting it pretty
positively right I think so I think it's
been really good we're still getting
sales so I mean I think that's a good
sign and uh yeah I I just I think the
book is really
well-rounded uh and this is just the
beginning we're going to do more
versions down the road I don't know when
but you know I'm sure we both need
breaks for a little bit before we do
another version I will say I have read
almost every grow book that has ever
been published everything that even kind
of touches on cannabis breeding there is
nothing like this book right now um the
way it's organized the story it tells
but also the information it gives like I
walked away understanding breeding and I
always thought that that was the most
complicated thing in cannabis yeah and I
don't anymore because it's not that
complicated but nobody has sat down and
actually put it to work words in the
same way so I think it's just so cool
that this book
exists yeah me too and it's something
you know it's like I I've always wanted
I think part of growing up for me has
been like how do I contribute to this
bigger thing that we're all part of and
I feel like I found where my
contribution lies within the genetics
and within the breeding and to be able
to write a book um yeah it's just as as
you get older it's like what's your
legacy what are you leaving behind and
you have your legacy with all these
books that you edited and you know with
the stuff with Oaker Dam and I feel like
you've contributed heavily to so many
people um and I feel like I want to be
the gortex for all these big brands with
my genetics and you're kind of like the
gortex for all these authors and it's
just amazing you know and I think that
uh it's we're an extremely special time
in the Cannabis space because it's not
stable yet we're not quite sure where
it's going there's still a lot of
information to be discovered that's why
there's going to be more breeding books
we haven't got it all down there's no
but yours was the first that's going to
unleash the rest I think yeah and I'm
looking forward to other people writing
cannabis breeding books I think there's
a need for it everyone has their own
opinion on it there's different
directions we can go my book kind of has
everything and I feel like if people
want to dive into some of those
specifics there could be a whole book on
tissue culture for cannabis you could
write 400 pages on that so this is what
excites me about this book and what
excites me about cannabis in general
right I don't think in any other field
of plants science people have gotten
this excited about breeding as they do
about cannabis right but there's a whole
world of plants out there to breed and I
think this might open the door for
people to start talking about that like
I was saying with appetite suppression
we're all obsessed with breeding thcv
and creating it from yeast and creating
patent medicines from it there's a whole
world of plants that already do these
same things
OIC there's a there's a plant that does
the same thing that suppresses the glp1
receptor right I think it's called
berbery but
don't quote me on that right but there
are plants out there my big hope with
cannabis after all of these years
especially as a patient has always been
that cannabis busts the door open on on
plants in general but also on healthcare
because we've had this inordinate focus
on single cell molecules as being able
to cure and treat things they do not
cure and treat things neither do plants
but when you start understanding the
components of plants and we've never
studied anything more than we've studied
cannabis at this point right then you
start kind of like rethinking how you
look at Healthcare and it's kind of an
incredible thing that cannabis is able
to do for us totally I mean we used
plant medicine for thousands of years
and we've only gone away from it with
modern medicine in the last 200 years
well and even with modern medicine we
have this thing where we say oh we know
this plant is medicinal we're going to
isolate one compound from it because
that's the thing that does this it's
never the thing that does this and
that's also what cannabis is teaching us
that there's a whole host of molecules
flavonoids tpin they exist in other
plants oh yeah the endocannabinoid
system does not exist to interact with
cannabis it exists to interact with all
of the foods that we eat that come from
the earth as well as herbs right yeah I
mean it's this stuff is all over the
place I mean cannaboids are in breast
milk so we have these receptors in our
body thank God it puts the babies to
sleep right totally and I mean we have
these receptors in our body there's a
reason for it and I think we really need
to explore it and now you know laws are
changing the landscape is changing to
where we can do a lot more research and
there's so many people interested and it
also is normalizing cannabis you know we
have guys like Luke scarmazzo that did
14 years in prison and for a plant you
know and I think it's pretty wild I'll
correct that I don't think Luke did 14
years in prison for a plan I think Luke
did 14 years in prison for telling the
feds to [ __ ] themselves yeah I think
that's 100% why he did that prison time
his free speech
yeah and unfortunately that's the world
we live in you know so like how free are
we you know I guess it's all just a
difference of opinion but well when even
half the Cannabis industry says to you
when you talk about Luke's case and they
go well you know he made that music
video where he said [ __ ] the feds as if
he deserved it right when like freedom
of speech is Central to who we are as
Americans you even have people in the
Cannabis industry defending that as a
reason to put him behind bars that's
really sad you know and yeah it's just
there's there and there's so many
instances of this that have happened
time and time and time again uh but then
cannabis is still we Circle back to
cannabis is like the bad guy right and
slowly but surely we are normalizing it
uh people like yourself putting this in
books uh podcasts where we're talking
about it where you get the normal person
that ends up finding this podcast they
watch it and they can relate something
that you're saying or I'm saying and
then all of a sudden wow or they know
somebody that had cancer and then all of
a sudden they're like oh well maybe it's
not so bad because they had cancer and
it helped them eat when they had cancer
and they
survived uh these Miracles we had Maya
from Oman and she gave us a different
perspective on it she's really amazing
what was her different perspective well
it was just basically these Miracles
that people experience you know and she
pointed that out and I think my mom and
dad saw Sanjay gupa in 60 minutes saw
that these kids were like not having
epilepsy or not epilepsy but they
weren't having seizures right so it
changed the seizure they're having all
these seizures they started taking CBD
and then the seizures went away and so I
think that was the big changing point
for my parents but like a lot of people
they see these Miracles and so these
Miracles once once you have a miracle
happen to one of your friends or your
family then you realize maybe this isn't
so bad and maybe we we were looking at
it the wrong way okay so can I talk to
you about Utah just a little bit sure
okay so so when I first I I was living
in the Bay Area for 10 years um and then
I had my my husband my boyfriend at the
time who's now my husband was living in
Salt Lake City we both have family there
and the rents were flying in Oakland and
he's like you know if you live with me
your rent will be 300 a month so I moved
to Salt Lake City and decided to travel
back to the Bay Area once a month so I
can still work cuz I was the editor of
cannabis now at the time right um so I
was coming back doing my cannabis thing
every six weeks or so and then going
back to Utah our apartment was at the
base of um Capitol Hill in Salt Lake
City right where the capital is and I
moved there months before Utah became
the first state to pass a CBD only law I
immediately made a friend with someone
who was lobbying up there for CBD and so
I I immediately fell head first into the
situation where I was trying to explain
cannabis to Mormons right wow and for
them it was very much like they love
hearing Miracle stories M and that was
also what pushed cannabis into the leg
instead in the Utah legislature was
these stories of these children with
epilepsy MH um what was interesting is I
started kind of being I got sidelined
right away um I I was introduced to one
of the Mormon moms who was running the
bill and she had looked me up on the
internet and she said right away I saw
you you're from the Bay Area you're
friends with gays and
legalizers right wow she's like nobody
wants to hear what you have to say so I
immediately got behind the scenes and
started kind of whispering in the ear of
people about what to say to these
legislators legislators so by 2014 the
CBD bill is happening on 2015 I'm hiding
in the office of Senator Mark Madson who
is the grandson of the Mormon prophet um
and also the first person to run a full
medical cannabis bill in Utah and he was
sitting there saying I need someone to
talk about this I'll call up a friend
who's a researcher on this one second
right so I'm connecting him to everybody
and so it was this whole like Miracle
situation in Utah that had they like
their belief in magical thinking um that
really turned them on to cannabis you go
to Utah now you will not hear a
conservative Senator say a bad thing
about cannabis right because we turned
the tide on these medical stories and I
still like can't get over like how the
culture changed because of these stories
and it really is because of the patience
again like we really passed legalization
in so many states because of money
people wanted tax money people wanted to
make money but what really got the
conversation going were these stories of
patience and I definitely taught Mormons
how to dab oh wow I taught Mormons about
cannabis and I feel like that was really
like my time to do God's work if you
will because I I helped spread it in a
place where it was never going to spread
yeah I sent a whole bunch of I sold a
bunch of seeds over in Utah and uh you
know for medical and it was pretty
amazing I mean I think they have a
really good climate for growing oh
really um yeah it's hot dry high
altitude so they did really good with my
seeds okay they did really good in fact
I was really impressed um they they did
some indoor and you know it was also
really amazing but also the cultivator
really good guy uh but yeah Utah I think
you I was super surprised with that when
I heard that someone from Utah wanted my
seeds I was like really and then I had
to look if are they even legal this guy
going to go you know he wanted a lot of
seeds and I'm like okay well really
interesting the patients who had tried
to pass that that bill in the
legislature the year I was working there
so that was 2015 y it lost my husband
graduated grad school and we're like
let's get the [ __ ] out so we moved to
Portland Oregon almost immediately but
the patients who left behind they didn't
stop the ones who were working on that
bill became the chief petitioners of
prop 2 wow which passed in 2018 and now
Utah is a medical cannabis State totally
right totally weird producing in the
state there's a lot of people producing
in the yeah you know it's funny though
they're producing a lot of bad weed in
Utah I wouldn't be surprised although I
have seen I mean that I have pictures of
some amazing stuff that was produced in
Utah so there's only eight Growers oh
wow only eight legal Growers right and
so there's 880,000 registered patients
in the state of Utah less than 20,000 or
so
actually but most of it's bad yeah well
and here's the thing about Utah Right
Colorado is a day drive away Nevada is a
day drive array some parts of Oregon are
a day drive away right so
they're not really buying Utah weed oh
wow that makes sense it makes sense and
I just can't wait for the day for
interstate commerce it's so silly that
we're still having this conversation
that we can't legally cross state lines
with cannabis like you can do whatever
you want but as far as federally illegal
it's still federally illegal there's no
interstate commerce so we can't produce
a [ __ ] ton in California and then go
sell to Utah or North Dakota or South
Dakota or Utah wants our weed yeah I'm
sure and that's something I was feeling
especially talking to some old friends
at the emerald cup and getting to talk
to other people in the California
industry because California is my home
um California Cannabis is hurting
they're really hurting and until they
can legally ship things out that they
were already sending anyway before
legalization happened they're going to
continue to hurt well and they're going
to continue to do stuff uh the
traditional way
and I think that the the best solution
is for them to at the very least even if
they don't want to go federally legal
allow interstate commerce from legal
state to Legal State wreck to wreck
medical to let the world experien
California Cannabis there's already a
demand for it when I was in Spain in
2022 apparently in the in the clubs in
Barcelona they brag about it being C
weed right of course nobody from
California says C sure but that's still
the thing they all want Ki weed just the
way people want Nappa wine well it's
mostly California genetics and I think
we're the epicenter right here in
California the Bay Area Los
Angeles uh I would say West Coast but
like really California is I was you know
o oaksterdam Oakland has been there's a
reason it's called Oaker Dam because we
were the epicenter for the longest time
especially uh 215 215 days it was like
booming genetics wise too so they want
the best in and I've seen a lot of stuff
in Europe that says Cali it's definitely
not Cali it could be Canadian but it's
you know not necessarily californ right
they're putting California on people
like oo California in in the Netherlands
in Spain all over but slowly it's
becoming normalized uh we got Germany
going online big countries that are
going recreational as a country and I
love that you know we got Jamaica is you
know we got some islands and we have you
know I think Colombia still has a long
way go but they have potential Mexico
they're going to go fully wrecked I
can't wait till Mexico goes yeah I mean
once these things start to unfold and
then we got it Canada and Mexico and
they're fully wrecked we have to do it I
just think it's silly I mean I I think
it's silly now it's totally silly now
but also like for the sake of all the
people we know and love like we need to
be able to send cannabis out of
California yeah absolutely and really
most of the market demands California
and weed yeah I mean and the thing is I
think other States produce prod amazing
Oregon produces amazing flow they
produce or just far north California
let's get real they'll hate me for
saying that but it's the truth I would
say the best growing climate in the
whole United States is actually like
Southern Oregon oh of course yeah so but
it's that region right the far north of
California the far south of Oregon like
that is where some of the best weed
comes from yeah especially I mean the
outdoor weed you know indoor can be
grown good anywhere right anybody who
knows environment and can control your
environment fully you can and cure
correctly you can grow good flour
anywhere pretty much anywhere um but
outdoor I feel like there's only a
limited amount of places that that you
can really you know that really perform
well as a whole you know you can grow
autof flowers in certain places that you
wouldn't normally be able to do Alaska's
kind of special they have a really short
growing season really long light I think
otof flowers go really well there that's
where all the flowers came from is up at
the top of the poles right right mhm for
sure so
it's it's really interesting moving
forward you know genetic wise also
Regional and being able to you know we
talk about in the book a little bit
about breeding for specific regions and
I think people are starting to get back
to that I mean obviously the big
companies are looking at that but I
think a lot of breeders it's on their
mind is like especially if they're
breeding for outdoor where they want to
produce seeds that go on an acre it's
like well are those the optimal seeds
for that location as far as climate as
far as elevation and all these other
things is like is that the optimal
variety for that and so I think that's
the problem with a lot of these other
states like Utah too is they're trying
to grow pop popular varieties that were
bred in California well that's happening
all over the world it's like I got guys
in the Caribbean they want to grow OG
Kush and it's like that's not
necessarily you know and the thing is is
maybe you want to grow an OG hybrid but
you don't want to just grow OG Kush and
it s or you just you know it's like I
want to grow gelato and I want to grow
in the Caribbean but I can't wait for
the day that they try to breed strains
that are for where they are and they
have that uniqueness to them because any
foodie will tell you too like that's
part of why I like going different
places to try different things not to
get the same thing grown in a different
climate right and all this will happen
over time we're going to like uh
repopulate the world with land race
genetics over the next hundred years and
so you know I mean through taking
genetics everywhere finding out what
works the best it's going to 100 years
from now it's going to be pretty wild if
we're all you know obviously we won't be
around 100 years from now but the plant
will still be alive okay this is a
question I have coming from working on
your book yeah what is a land Race So a
land race is not a lot of people get
confused they think land race is feral
but land race is not that's feral if
we're talking about feral the stuff that
that's indigenous or feral to that
region that's grown on its own and it's
populated and through natural selection
that is not what land race is land race
is something that's grown for several
generations and selected by the people
for a spefic specific use or purpose and
that's what most people don't know that
right but yeah but land race genetics is
Mojave said it best once it leaves the
land the race is over right right and so
I have this huge collection of land race
genetics where we're using it for
breeding potential um and so where we
can test it out in different regions and
then hybridize it and see how those
hybrids work uh I have my friend fritzy
he's going around uh next month he'll be
over in Asia looking for more seeds for
us
and we're constantly looking for new
things for the gene pool so that we can
test it and see how it performs and how
it can benefit us but I think as a whole
you know even in 10 or 15 years the
landscape is going to change completely
breeding I mean there's a lot of science
going into it but uh you know geoc
climatized we use the word geoc
climatized in the book and Reggie told
me that was a good good idea by the way
to use geoc climatized I've been
criticized by people for using the word
geoc climatized because it's almost like
you're putting new land race genetics in
places and optimizing those for the
specific conditions that but you are
yeah that's the idea right that's the
point is trying to optimize genetics for
specific locations and you know that's
the future that's the future of genetics
and I think to say that everybody's just
going to grow indoors that's silly I
think we have this amazing light called
the Sun and if we can we can utilize
that uh either wholly or partially I do
love love mixed light because I feel
like it gives you a mix of an amazing
product that gets the benefit of the sun
and the light and the control of the
environment well and we know that THC
production is a response to UV light
right and so that's what's exciting
about people actually starting to breed
in different parts of the world Beyond
California is that there's a different
spectrum of light in different places
that's what's going to bring out
different canabo right different Tarpin
different flavonoids different
everything yeah and you can take well
the the beauty of this plant is you can
take OG kush or any other cultivar that
you know and you can grow it here
Outdoors you can grow it in Washington
you can grow it in Texas in some parts
of Texas some parts of Arizona Mexico or
Costa Rica or the Caribbean and if you
were to take that flower and put it side
by side it would all look like a
different expression because phenotype
is basically uh affected by nutrition
and environment so the second you change
the environment you can have a
completely different looking plant with
different tpine expressions or
flavorants as we call them in the book
thanks to the white papers from abstract
Tech um that was an interesting thing
that happened while we were working on
the book right like everyone was very
focused on tpin as far as flavor and
smell and that's that study came out
while we were working on the book and we
had to reorient how we thought about
these things while we were writing it
well and I think we talked a little bit
about THS and then once they came out
with those white papers it was like okay
it's on we need to change the book and
that was actually really cool I love uh
watching science unfold in real time
it's like you know them discover and
these are sulfur based compounds and
talking about sulfur-based compounds and
fils on another because we just talked
about fils being like you know the gas
the skunk the ammonia that you smelling
stuff and they started really you know I
think they changed history on a level
that people haven't done in a long time
especially when we're having this
convers about just tping because
everyone's so focused on
saying this tpine and it's like you know
it's just limey and it's so much more
than that a lot of times it's hard for
us to get out of this mindset of a
single molecule yeah right like we're
all so focused on this one thing doing
this one thing and that's just not
nature right that's not how nature works
well and if it gets me really high it
must be
THC right and I can't wait for the
moment when we don't care about THC in
the same way people don't buy wine by
looking at the alcohol content and going
well this is the highest alcohol it must
be the best wine some bums do but most
people do not right so what was your
favorite part about editing the book
okay my favorite part about editing your
book right was I had known you but I
didn't know you that well yet and you
have a background in in the chef's world
right like a colonary experience and so
when we got to a part where you were
talking about breeding based on FL
flavors and flavor pairings that kind of
spoke to me as an amateur Chef a lot and
so I kind of got really into that
especially because I know when people
pick out varieties they're always
looking at how different flavors and
scents make you feel and how you seem to
be naturally attracted to things that
will make an effect that you like um
talking to you made me buy the flavor
Bible yeah that's one of the best books
out there oh I took it home and it's
like I cook all my own food from scratch
raw ingredients because of my Crohn's
disease right and so that chapter like
spoke to me in a way that I like went
home and started like studying flavor
pairings in a way and so that was really
a cool experience to me of like don't
just enjoy cannabis don't just sniff
stuff and smoke that you like but like
really make this thing exactly what you
want it to be and like that's kind of
what I pulled from your book which was
cool and you could only get that from a
chef's
perspective yeah and you know the thing
is is with breeding there's so many
different directions you can go and
there's no one right way to do it and
everybody has their own way and
especially with the selection process
because it's so subjective to the
individual and I think uh you know as a
chef there's some breeders that breed
they just breed what they want and what
they would smoke and I think that's a
great way to do it too cool bro yeah
right yeah yeah yeah but like oh this is
what I love and I'm G to breed this
because I love this and that's a
beautiful approach too but my Approach
is as a chef is I know what people like
right as a chef you have to learn what
people like even though I like weird
stuff I like weird food I love love it
yeah and so I like exotic stuff and I
like octopus with olive oil and crunchy
salt cool want to try it now that you
said it yeah it's it's so good you know
especially mediterranian octopus is just
amazing and then it has especially if
you do it right with the potatoes you
have soft potatoes and then a little
paprika on there and it's like this this
flavor combination it's amazing but I I
dissect cannabis just as wood food and I
reverse engineer everything that I do
I'm constantly like okay how can we pull
this apart and look at it from each
component and try to optimize it
whatever it is uh and then it goes that
you know with cannabis it's like there's
so many different things too like it
also this day and age we want stuff that
is that will function in a large scale
facility uh it's not just something that
like even though I love breeding for
flavor you know and we might save
something that's really amazing we won't
necessarily release a cut of it or
anything like that but we have that we
we have that on the back burner we can
use it for breeding because it's so
special most of it has to be
commercially viable of course right and
so
unfortunately I guess unfortunately
unfortunately these are all just
breeding goals that you have like if
you're going to sell seeds people want
to get a certain yield off them and so
that's just a reality sure and so that
needs to be one of the check boxes like
does it yield or what does it yield so
you can inform people so but what is
lost when we focus on yield or THC right
and I think that that is like the
education that the the consumer Market
is missing right it's same with food if
we focused on the apples that produced
the most we want to get the apples with
flavor yeah and we we don't understand
that and I can't wait till cannabis kind
of comes around to these understandings
we already have from eating right well
and there is a balance right so like
there's there's a balance and a
threshold and there there's a point
where it's like if it yields so much
it's probably not going to taste amazing
never there's commercial agriculture is
high yield translate to Great Flav
totally you look at wine you look at
produce you you look at pretty much
everything and a lot of times they're
having to pump synthetics into it to get
it to produce like that what are the
best tomatoes heirloom tomatoes the ones
some grew at home yeah grown grown by
grandma or grown by me or whoever it is
it's like those absolutely and I'm an
Italian I make a lot of delicious tomato
sauce and I will not make a tomato sauce
with store-bought
Tomatoes yeah you well you got to go to
brookley bowl and even a good store and
get the fancy Tomatoes but even the
fanciest Tomatoes at the best stores
aren't as good as the stuff that comes
off of my bindes at my house MH um the
ones that make your fingers smell like
tomatoes cuz of the tpin exactly MH I do
the stem rub and I get that I love that
green yeah totally M so yeah and it's
like uh I just I love tomatoes too and I
I have Crohns as well and so I really
don't eat a lot of tomatoes because
they're night shades everybody has
Crohn's now yeah everybody body's got a
digestive disorder now to totally
autoimmune diseases are just at an
all-time high for sure I have some
theories about it yeah right A lot of it
is immune stuff in general right is like
there's a study that was done on the
border of Poland and Russia yeah Poland
is part of the EU Russia is not and in
Poland it's like super sterile like in
their train stations they keep that [ __ ]
sterile yeah don't do the same thing in
Russia right you can also map out
incidences of autoimmune disease on that
border and find that they are like 10
higher on the Poland side than they are
on the Russia side despite people having
similar genetics yeah sterility is on
the side where everybody has it totally
but I also think it's um western
civilization and the diets that we live
on here too and I think there's all
there's so many contributing factors
it's not just one thing I think uh
glyat yeah is a huge one you know and
then just our our diets we're not eating
as nutritious of produce and as you know
I think I think the protein has changed
we used to have more diversity in our
diets uh and then you look at the
lettuce and and things like that and
it's it's completely different than it
was in the 50s and before and so I think
uh pesticides changed after World War II
and that has an effect on it possibly I
mean I'm not an expert on all this and
I'm always trying to think about like
why I am the way I am because I have a
lot of food allergies a lot and also
cannabis helps uh even though I have a
slight cannabis allergy with it gives me
a little rash which it does to a lot of
people we get rashes but uh the the
actually ingesting it helps me if I
smoke it more than if I eat it I don't
really feel great when I eat it as as
great as I do when I smoke it I yeah I
don't like eating weed I never do I
always prefer to inhale or tinctures at
best but I prefer inhaling yeah
tinctures are okay I'm I'm okay with
some tinctures um Amber Alchemy ures are
really good the best tinure I have ever
had I made myself and here was what was
in it it was I was using a volcano Vape
yeah and I was dumping my leftover Vape
into a jar and then I put some fresh
butt in there and then I put some fresh
decarbox butt in there so this was like
a sausage of like cannabis leftovers and
I made a tincture out of that and I've
never felt better and I handed it out to
other patients than I knew they loved
the sausage leftovers I as well too and
I think it's because of the diversity
right like the diversity of what ended
up in that jar at the end was something
you can't recreate on a commercial level
but people loved it well from one batch
to next it's going to be completely
different I couldn't recreate that
tinure never I could never recreate that
tinure well and that's you know
homegrown flowers is a lot like that too
from one batch to the next it comes out
slightly different and sometimes it's
absolutely amazing and anybody who says
they grow A+ plus plus wheed every time
they're kidding themselves because I
feel like the best Growers it's always
good like certain Growers
um myself included I feel like it's
always good when I grow but there's
times where it's just above and beyond
that was a special round or the genetics
just performed really well that time or
you get to know a certain cultivar and
then you're like okay well I know that
we could we need to veg it a little bit
longer and then we need to top it a few
times and it really loves when I clean
out the the undercarriage completely and
thin quite a bit more than other things
and some things they don't like to be
thin the same so knowing your cul of
ours is like half the battle I wrote
this article about cannabis and Crohn's
in 2013 and it went viral and I've had
people to this day still reaching out to
me about it and I regret it and I regret
it because I made it sound like cannabis
is what put my Crohns in remission and I
didn't understand at the time that that
was not the case yeah um and I think
it's a really important thing to talk
about because I've had so many people
reach out to me and the main question
they ask is what's the strain I should
use for my Crohn's disease
and they hate me because every single
time I give them this long complicated
answer that the tldr is I can't give you
that answer yeah right there is no good
answer for that like cannabis can't cure
your Crohn's disease there's no one
thing that you can buy that's going to
cure your Crohn's disease you need to
get sleep you need to get hydration you
need to eat a whole food diet you need
to cut out sugar and processed foods all
of these things feed toally fried food
yeah I I think for me fried foods was
the the worst but also I got Crohn's
worse it came out of remission fully
when I quit smoking oh yeah cigarettes
are terrible for it uhhuh y well
cannabis when I when I quit smoking
cannabis uhhuh and you forced to quit
but I I quit smoking and I was fine for
like the first six months and then I got
like the worst I'd ever had and I lost
about 25 pounds in a month why were you
forced to quit smoking the federal
government oh so yeah they they I had to
pee and it was all it was really bad so
they'll do that I read this study called
care and feeding of the endoc canabo
system um that is really what changed my
perspective on a lot of this because it
was a survey study so it's not just a
study where they look at 15 people and
Report their results it is researchers
looking at the body of research that
exists and summarizing it yeah they
looked at pharmaceutical drugs Alcohol
Tobacco cannabis anything that can
affect your endocannabinoid system what
balances it what upgrades uh upregulates
it what down regulates it and what they
found was what keeps the balance in your
endoc canabo system was sleep hydration
exercise whole food diet right so these
aren't things I can sell to anybody and
nobody ever wants me to say this to them
that there's not one thing that'll fix
this but that is what will fix it is a
radical lifestyle change MH and it's not
the easiest thing to do it's not and I
think a lot of it from for me starts
with exercise like I've lost a lot of
weight this
year and it started with just going to
the gym and waking up and doing it even
if I had to sit in the car 30 minutes
and thought about going to the gym if I
got in there and so you know Lifestyle
Changes aren't
easy and your mind will tell you the
opposite like oh you don't need to do
this or oh you're getting up a little
later so you don't need to go to the gym
today or you don't need to do this and a
lot of times you just got to prioritize
yourself that's what I found we also
live these lives that are too busy and
that's kind of what makes our health
degrade right is it's really hard to
schedule in gym time it's really hard to
schedule in time to make your food from
scratch right this is why people eat
processed food is because you can just
throw it in your mouth while you're
driving somewhere right but you'll pay
the price for that cheapness
later yeah you know it's like I love
cooking as a chef I love taking the
whole day to prepare a meal you know you
go shopping and then you spend a few
hours cooking minimum a few hours
sometimes five hours cooking and I love
doing that there's like this whole
meditation side to that that I love like
getting going back to like a culinary
school where I learn knife skills you
know and I love cutting my vegetables
all exactly the same size and perfect
dices tiny little vegetables is what
makes food so good yeah and all these
things but I don't have time for that
and so I eat pretty basic now but like I
I'm able to cook my meals really fast
and I I do a lot of whole food like
steak I do steak and chicken I do steak
with chicken love steak by itself myself
I love chicken by myself and I love them
together and I do these burritos now
they like steak and chicken burritos so
see and I was a vegetarian for 15 years
and I had to like break that seal to be
able to get healthy because basically I
eat meat and vegetables now and that has
been my life-saving situation I was a
severe case of Crohn's I've had a third
of my colon surgically removed and
moving to a diet with no processed foods
where I eat meat fruits vegetables has
been kind of what has really put me in
remission more than cannabis the goal
has been to not need cannabis unless I
need cannabis and I use cannabis instead
of a Tylenol or something else yeah did
you do an Elimination Diet to figure out
what worked and what didn't work oh
absolutely and so like the diet that I'm
on is called the specific carbohydrate
diet and if it doesn't work for you
there's four things that you remove that
are okay on the diet to see what what
doesn't what's causing the problem it's
eggs nuts um legal sugars as they call
it which is from fruit and honey and the
other Dairy and I found out depressingly
that it's eggs for me like I I just
cannot eat eggs I can't do it I love
eggs I do 10 egg whites before I go to
bed every night love them they don't
love me right so as soon as I cut eggs
out of my diet my life changed
wow so then were you tried before you
had any part of your intestines removed
did you uh or your your
colon yeah which is yeah I mean that's
that's a pretty serious operation people
don't realize how important and your
colon is until there's a problem with it
right and did you quit you you were
smoking cannabis and tried that and it
didn't fully work okay see that's funny
right because I started smoking cannabis
in high school it turned my life around
I was intentionally failing myself out
of honors classes in high school I was
in a Catholic High School and I was so
mad about it right so I was
intentionally failing myself out of
these classes I get high for the first
time and I'm just like well [ __ ] if I go
to college I get a leave this bum [ __ ]
town right so all of a sudden I start
turning in straight A and I start
smoking cannabis I was getting symptoms
at about the exact same time wow by the
time I was diagnosed I had just turned
18 I was days away from moving to San
Francisco for college um and I had this
weird mindset which was like well you've
got a serious illness now you can't do
drugs so I stopped smoking weed and my
first 6 months in college at San
Francisco State I was completely
miserable cycling through prazone and a
bunch of other drugs and basically
starving myself to get through the day
so I wouldn't feel symptoms I had
emergency surgery during my spring break
to remove the first section of my colon
and right after that I started going to
doctor's appointments in San Francisco
all the time and I'd pick up the free
newspapers while I was on the bus and on
the back of the free newspapers was all
kinds of cannabis ads right so I go to a
cannabis doctor for the first time and I
go got Crohn's disease is that enough to
get a card and they were like oh yeah
definitely tot right and so that was the
first time I got a card and I didn't
take it seriously I was buying weed for
my roommates because I was the one who
could get into a club um but I
definitely started moving towards being
a more natural organic type of person
who didn't take pharmaceutical drugs
because of that because I'd walk into a
dispensary and at the time like these
are these old dispensaries in San
Francisco where they're giving you a
Ziploc bag with a computer printer label
on the variety and people are smoking in
the sales floor um but I met people in
there who were patients and they were
talking about peing patience and I
started like thinking about my own use
in a different way and that's kind of
what pushed me on the path that I ended
up on there were some really cool clubs
in San Francisco 14th was the big one
for me 14th in Mission I used to go
there quite a bit um and there was one
on Ocean I used to I used to vent to all
these places too and spark smoke your
weed you never know right yeah mine are
my friends or you know spark was a big
deal for me back uh a long time ago they
used you they were amazing great company
um you know they they bought CO2 when it
was crude and were using it for Edibles
and doing all kinds of stuff my friends
got the first like Eden Labs extractor
when it was for for CO2 when it would
just pump out peanut butter looking
crude it's disgusting you couldn't
really smoke it they were trying to
convince everybody that yeah you just
smoke it and it's way healthier but it
was like it was the crude of crude it
was like crude oil and so but SM spark
ended up interested in purchasing it so
it kind of helped pay for their machine
which was great at 20 bucks a gram back
then which I think it's probably for
that kind of stuff would be a dollar a
gram now or a couple dollars a gram but
yeah and then you know there was Steve
d'angel and Andrew over at Harborside
they were doing it for a long time and
uh the third floor I knew Sean and Mary
well yeah they were work with them a
little bit that's where my wife and I
both got our cards I Frank lcio was my
first doctor that gave me my card Frank
yeah he was amazing
Frank he should have written a book so
he he still could he can still write he
just retired know writing a book is not
like a casual thing right like it's a
big [ __ ] project it's an undertaking
and then I mean people don't know most
people don't know how much goes into a
book as far as like I didn't understand
I thought I could maybe do the layout
right do the graphics or all that stuff
we had to get a graph we had multiple
graphic designers multiple
photographers an editor we had Reggie
who helped and there you know there
there was just so many people that
contributed this or that or a handful of
photos like okay we need photos of land
race stuff well I don't grow a ton of
land race genetics I mean I plan on but
as far as like we went to several people
and you know and then people said oh
yeah I got this and then they don't
respond and and if you get them they may
not be high quality we went through that
for sure but yeah and I was able to
feature a lot of case studies in the
book and I thought that was a lot of fun
I I love doing textbox case studies and
books especially like your book because
your book is a textbook right so there's
there's an information load but then
there's also giving life to the
information and the text box give life
to the information and being able to
talk about specific strains that people
know I think gives life to the content
that was fully your idea by the way and
so that just you know and then I then
you gave me the idea and then it's like
okay let's run with this and we're going
to talk about Sour Diesel we'll do case
studies on this and case studies on that
I think I wrote more case studies than
we included in the book A A lot of that
came from the first grow book I ever
worked on between 2008 and 2010 I was a
student at Mills College at the time and
I had brought my own textbooks knowing
that we were making this one as an Oaker
Dam textbook and I was looking through
it and I remember that was the thing
that stood out to me as case studies
about different businesses to explain
the business Concepts we're talking
about so I pulled that into that first
grow book that I did in a big way and
it's just something that's carried over
in a lot of the Cannabis textbooks that
I've done because there's giving
information and there's giving life to
information and those text box that just
does it in a different way yeah
totally yeah so let's talk about high
price because I think that is an amazing
book you're the one who introduced me to
Luke scarmazzo I've had him on the show
a couple times we filmed some really
cool stuff together he's just an amazing
person and you met him when he was in
prison right you know it's interesting
cuz I heard about Luke a lot before I
actually met him because he was the guy
who made the music video where he goes
[ __ ] the feds and the FEDS said [ __ ] you
and they put him into a federal prison
with a 21-year sentence right and so
right around the time that Obama was
about to transition out and Trump was
about to transition in both Luke gazo's
daughter and his partner Ricardo
montes's daughter were doing a
change.org petition trying to get Obama
to Pardon their dad's right um and so I
I talk to Ricardo in prison I talked to
Luke in prison it ended with Ricardo
getting that clemency but Luke didn't
get the clemency but I really enjoyed
talking to Luke so it turned into the
situation where Luke and I kind of
became pen pals for many years um and
right before the pandemic Luke ended up
in solitary confinement for a long time
a long time he traded a lot of his meals
for paper and pen and he wrote a book
and he knew what I did for work so he
was like Angela can I send you my book
to check out and I'm like sure okay a
lot of people have sent me books that
they wanted to publish over the years
and I skim through them and I'm like oh
this is too much this is a mess this
will never happen Luke's book I sat down
I start reading the next three or four
days after I woke myself up early and
you know I wake up early I woke up even
earlier turned the coffee pot on so that
I could plow through more of Luke's book
because it was so well written and so
engaging um and so when he did come out
of prison he was like let's publish this
book I want you to do it um and what was
interesting is the original version of
the book ended with him in solitary
confinement and when you read the book
at the the way it was at the time it was
it was a tear jerker like I broke down
crying at like 5:00 in the morning
reading the ending of this book wow then
he gets out of prison some time goes by
we're working on the book and it's like
Luke let's talk about prison a little
bit right CU like the book doesn't talk
about being in prison right now it just
talks about what happened leading into
prison so him and I went into this back
and forth where we were talking about
his prison experience where we could
really actually the book is called high
price to actually talk about the cost
like what life was like for 14 years in
prison for Luke gorzo and I think what
we pulled out of it just brought the
book so full circle but also made a
stronger Point than we could have made
while he was still there because now he
can speak more freely about his
experience yeah it's a really good book
I think it's really well written and
I've really enjoyed him coming out to
the facility and we're talking about
doing some seed drops together and some
other stuff I I love seeing him travel
and you know his Instagram he's he's a
you know he's a traveler he's been going
all over everywhere to event whether
it's the California State Fair going
over to the east coast doing stuff he
was in Miami and you know in Florida and
he's he's been travel traving all over
you know his his brand profit is doing
really well and I think they're just
growing exponentially and it's great
seeing someone like him who really
deserves the success of recreational
Cannabis you know uh growing along with
this with the system so first profit
actually has good weed yeah there's not
a lot of good weed in the California
Market that's legal these days right
that's the first thing two Luke has an
enthusiasm for this this industry and
this world in a way that other people in
the industry definitely do not have
right now right and I was born of
spending 14 years mostly in solitary
confinement um he's so happy to be here
he's just he's just happy to be here
he's just gen and he's always in a good
mood I I love that about him uh yeah him
and Mandy are always in a good mood and
it's great seeing them I mean it's that
kind of stuff is contagious he already
became my friend when we were prison P
pin Pals but like now that I know him in
in the real life like I just love that
guy so much Luke is so cool yeah yeah
he's a bless so tell us about your other
books that you've been working on I
think the Cannabis the cancer connection
is really important okay the Cannabis
cancer connection is a really cool book
it's written by a guy named Joe
goldstrich he's an MD and fac and what's
interesting about Dr Joe is he started
his career as a fellow um in a hospital
in Dallas and he was one of the seven
people who was in the room when JFK came
in with the head wound that took his
life right wow and that really shaped Dr
Joe's experience he became a pretty
well-renowned cardiologist over his
experience he always smoked cannabis he
was always kind of healthc conscious I
mean this was the 60s when he was coming
up um and when after he retired he found
that he was like kind of depressed
because he had nothing to do so he had
already been um a California certified
physician he came out and started write
writing recommendations in California um
and he just started learning from his
patients and as a patient I appreciate
about a doctors that he learned from his
patients but one thing that really hit
Dr Joe was patients with cancer because
he was finding that some people were
saying they were experiencing these
Miracle recoveries and then he'd also
have patients who did the same thing
they read about online and they didn't
have the miracle recovery right and
because his background was in research
and researching Materia Meda which he
used to get big paper stacks of research
and go through them to understand he
made cannabis and cancer something that
he just dove first so this book is a
summary of basically every piece of
cannabis cannabinoid research that's
ever been done in the world summarized
but contextualized with the patient
experience right W and so there's some P
like there's some pieces in there that
explain and he'll go into what I was
saying earlier about the endoc canabo
system and diet and lifestyle and how
all of that actually affects cancer
cancer care more than just the Cannabis
himself he points out when you shouldn't
use cannabis when there are actually any
HPV related cancer he points out in the
book does not respond well to THC more
importantly there's a chapter in there
about immunotherapy and immunotherapy
has become a really popular cancer
treatment because for the people who
have cancer that it affects it really
helps it will just knock out your cancer
right A lot of people are using cannabis
for the symptoms of things like
immunotherapy and chemotherapy if you
use cannabis while you're getting
immunotherapy it makes the IM Therapy
Network um this was something he had
pulled from the research but now he's
experiencing in real life because he was
recently diagnosed with a cancer that
responds well to immunotherapy so he
followed his own advice and the cancer
is going into remission wow um so
there's an update of this book coming
soon but I just really appreciate what
he did with this book it's really like
his life's work it's really cool that's
awesome mhm so the origins of cannabis
prohibition okay Dale aringer PhD he is
like the longtime head of California
normal right he's written this this book
which is um originally published in I
think 1998 I might need to check that
later on right he pulled out some pieces
about how California became one of the
first states in the United States to
prohibit cannabis um which is so
hilarious considering we were the ones
who bust this open for the world right
um and a lot of it was based on racism
which are the stories that that we knew
um and so this is just like a really
interesting story that looks at the
politics between like 1910 and 1913 that
led to can California like leading the
way in cannabis prohibition right nice
and then cannabis in clinical practice
okay cannabis in clinical practice was
originally written by my really good
friend Dr David bman anybody who knows
do Dr David bman loves him he's based in
Santa Barbara which is near my hometown
um he worked for uh Governor Ronald
Reagan's drug task force um he he has
some pretty interesting credentials
right um I first met him at Hempfest in
2010 or 12 and I've worked on a handful
of books with him up in Seattle oh in
Seattle yeah definitely it blew my mind
that this like doctor that I had just
met was like hey you want to smoke a
joint on the Rocks nice which is what
everybody does at H Fest right but so I
ended up sitting there and talking to
him for a while finding out that he was
from Santa Barbara which is near my
hometown which is in Santa Barbara
County so we became friends through that
um cannabis in clinical practice was him
trying to put into words all of the
information the doctors typically get
about a drug that they're going to
prescribe their patients but they will
never get for an herb and especially not
cannabis so he put that all into that
into this book then there's four authors
on this book right wow the second author
Maria panado is teaching a cannabis
class that wasand brand new at the
College of Nursing at Seattle so she
adapted the content for her class the
next MD who jumps in is do Carina netti
who is from Brazil and so she has like
actually LED medical cannabis in Brazil
she's testified in front of the
Brazilian Congress for medical cannabis
but her and her team did deep studies
into autoimmune diseases and a few other
conditions and how cannabis affects that
at the cellular level so she amended the
book finally I took a final pass of this
book from a patients perspective and
from a very educated patients
perspective and that is what became this
book which is cannabis and clinical
practice and it's basically everything a
doctor needs to know before they start
recommending cannabis to a patient
that's
awesome yeah we need more books like
that oh my God more more books yeah I
hope people read books well I think
digital books are a thing and so people
like a lot of people like digital books
but I still like books and that's why I
wanted to write a book and you know it's
Luke's book is great and I don't really
read books normally but I I like Luke's
book was an exception um you got it to
me early on right when it was coming out
and I it was a really really good book
um books yeah where do you think books
are going you know it's interesting
though cuz like I read a lot of books um
and there's a lot of books I read that I
don't necessarily want on my shelf and I
don't want other people around me to see
that I'm reading right just like trashy
novels um books like your book are the
kind of book that I want on my bookshelf
yeah I want it as a reference that I can
pull down and so like I think that
that's kind of where books are going
there's the books that you want on your
sh the books you don't want on your
shelf your book is a book that I want on
my shelf because it's the kind of thing
where I need a quick fact I know where
to look for it and I know your book like
the back in my hands so I know where to
find what I'm looking for in there right
well you have the file you can type
search that's true but so could anybody
who gets the ebook right yeah it's it's
really interesting and then you also
work with Oaker Dam doing a lot of stuff
with Dale over there and Oaker Dam isn't
just in Oakland anymore Oak you guys
have spread out all over you guys are
working you know in several countries um
and you want to talk about that a little
bit yeah I started working with Dale at
Oaker Dam to produce a book the bud
tenders guide um which was based on a
lot of their curricula and the curricula
is excellent people don't realize this
Dale brought me in as the Director of
academics so now I produce all of the
curricula at Oaker Dam University um and
that has been such a crazy experience
for me because it's definitely pulled on
all of my skills strengths and knowledge
in a way that no other job possibly
could um so I really appreciate working
with oaksterdam because we're working
with people who actually are going to
have a Major Impact where they are right
I'm from California you're from
California we're all very saturated in
the Cannabis World we're working with
students who are opening businesses and
places like Connecticut and New Jersey
and they have no background in the
history of what is here or all of the
weird deep context that you and I might
have on some of these topics um so it's
really exciting for us to be able to
provide it but it's really excited for
them to be able to get that information
from somewhere like Oaker Dam where we
have the most unique perspective the
other thing I think is really cool for
me about working with oaksterdam is I've
known Jeff and Dale Jones for over 15
years but I've always been adjacent like
I never worked exactly with them but I
was around during Prop 19 I was around
while they were doing their thing and so
I've always
understood the the historical context of
oaksterdam and and where they fall and
this legalization movement and I don't
know that many people in the world
really understand what Oaker Dam in
particular did to make cannabis legal
everywhere and for everyone they may
never know unless we keep talking
talking about it but oakam had the most
Central role in what is today MH I would
agree and I think you know they were at
the epicenter you know we we called
Oakland oaksterdam and then they started
a school and pretty amazing how many
students have gone through Oaker Dam so
many of my friends and colleagues have
either 10,000 yeah and some people went
for weekend and some you know weekend
courses and other people have gone for
longer classes and I they've done so
much um coming from culinary school I'm
not the hugest fan
of uh culinary school for for education
but I feel like with oaksterdam it's a
little bit different I feel like it's a
lot less expensive than culinary school
for one thing and you can do it on
demand now but also you can pair it with
grow like just like you can cook at your
house you can grow plants at your house
but uh it can Empower you to get a job
in the industry so 110,000 people from
116 countries have gone through Oaker
Dam so a lot of people were seeing oakam
on the news coming to Oakland learning
about the Cannabis industry and taking
it home and that's why they have a big
impact to your point about culinary
school that's interesting though is
being a chef is a it's a creative job
right there's technical skills you can
learn like a photographer or a writer or
an artist but there's also like that
innate piece of you that understands
this thing that can't be taught well
there's like the whole mentorship side
of the culinary industry where it's I
talk about this on my show a lot but
it's like uh you know it's passed down
from generations of chefs right so like
you you work under somebody as an
apprentice and you learn all the skills
from them and then you make it your own
and then you pass those down to somebody
else and I believe that the Canabis
world is a lot like that
too and you know I think there was a
lack of information out there and there
was a lot of people if you didn't know
the right person it was hard to get in
now slowly but surely you can go be a
water boy for somebody and water plants
or go trim a lot of people got started
trimming at a very young age yeah and so
many people and there's nothing wrong
with that and it's working your way up
in any industry is a great way to do it
if you want to be in the restaurant
industry and you can't get a job in the
kitchen you can be a buser you can go
it's the only way to do it is understand
the whole business go wash dishes yeah Y
and same thing go uh go clean pots go
clean pots for whatever grow if you can
get in you can get in and hopefully
someone likes you and they see that you
have good work ethic and then you can
you can grow with the company or you can
grow out of the company and then you
know evolve into something else you
can't teach that innate part of you that
understands how to pair flavors or come
up with creative things to cook and it's
the same thing with breeding right like
you can't you can't teach a photographer
to an eye yeah you can teach them all
the skills to use a camera but you can't
teach them how to see and I think it's
the same thing with chefs and breeders
yeah but I think a lot of stuff through
repetition you know you got to start
with the repetition part because a lot
of people yeah they have a natural gift
for some stuff but unless you put it at
the hours you'll never get good well
that's exactly it right you can have
that innate sense in you but if you
don't understand the technical skills
you can't perform yeah say with writing
and it takes Lots yeah I I know
firsthand I am such a better writer
after working with you it's incredible I
feel like if you look at how the first
draft came out and then as you got me to
rewrite stuff and think about what I'm
writing and how I'm constructing
sentences and paragraphs and trying to
tie it all in together because you had a
specific way of doing that which was
very different than my way was like
let's just throw it out there and it's
like no you need to have a introduction
that kind of says it all and then you
you write abouted pyramid yes huh you
put everything at the top and then you
expand on it well that's the thing right
I've always considered myself a writer
I've always loved writing I did not
become a good writer until I became a
good editor yeah I believe it well
sometimes it takes stepping outside the
box a little bit so you can see what's
going on and I fell into this niche of
cannabis because I did one cannabis book
I did another cannabis book and [ __ ] now
I know more about cannabis than anyone
who's never grown cannabis bred cannabis
been a cannabis doctor yeah well and you
know it from so many different
perspectives right and i' I've known
from the authors that I've worked with
that that's something that they've liked
working with me is that I can kind of
extract things out of what they wrote
and beat it up and question it in a way
that someone who's not a medical
professional or a grower or a breeder
could never
do yeah and you were able to get me on
task every day which is something that's
a a challenge for uh you know the best
of the people that I've worked with and
I guess sometimes you just have a good
relationship with people and and there's
um something where you can sync up like
and and I work better with some people
than other people and I have a specific
style and but I'm also a Workhorse I
don't mind being the Workhorse I just
need to have a path and then I need to
dedicate each morning to doing that
that's what I was going to say I'm a
great organizer I'm a great editor a
great manager but I'm only as good as
the person I'm working with and like
that was all you for staying on task and
actually taking it and running with it
yeah and think uh just just waking up
knowing that this is what I'm going to
do for the day and and I need to knock
this list out and sometimes it wouldn't
be that day it would be the next day or
the day after that but I would wake up
and put energy into it every day and
prioritize it I think a lot of times in
life we just got to prioritize stuff I
think maybe you had an innate
understanding of the fact that a book
like this did not exist yet um and that
you were creating the base that a lot of
people were going to work from and there
was like a responsibility that comes
with being able to build something like
that and I wonder a little bit if that's
kind of what motivated you to finish the
book was the fact that you knew that
that's what you were doing I was told by
somebody that I couldn't do it and I
wouldn't have a book by Christmas or the
year after that it would take a lot
longer and also I was 46 years old at
the time and IID told people that I was
going to have a book out and that was
like four years
before and I realized that this was my
last shot at doing it and if I didn't do
it it wasn't going to happen happen and
I was going to give up and I didn't want
to give up I didn't want to tell people
that I was going to do something that I
didn't do so there was all these
different pressures pushing me forward
wanting me to be successful and I was
also I would remind myself of those
things when I was feeling
lazy so you know and I'm kind of like
I'm just wired like that too like I can
create my own type of
stress so I you know and I like I'm a
high functioning per I I function really
well in stress but I you know not a high
functioning alcoholic but I'm a high
functioning person under stressful
situations and that comes from the
kitchen too and where you have this long
line of tickets and orders that have to
go out and you know it's like no one's
going to come save you you got to pull
your pants up look at those tickets and
just do it as fast as you can and I
think a lot of times people are just so
they're waiting for someone to come save
them that person's never coming I was a
bartender and waitress in downtown San
Francisco before I got into cannabis and
I still have anxiety dreams about the
tickets stacking up and getting the
plates out on I have I have nightmares
yeah it's been a while since I had a
nightmare about the ticket counter uh
but like the the ticket machine just
running or the ticket machine breaking
those are the two where it's you got
tickets on the floor or the ticket
machine is broken and the the
restaurant's packed and that's happened
several times and you know I guess
that's why I still have that reoccurring
nightmare but oh mine is the restaurant
is packed I'm the only bartender and
waitress
yeah I still have that dream to this day
and I haven't worked there in like 20
years yeah wow mhm really amazing so if
there was one piece of advice that you
could give your younger self uh coming
into the Cannabis space since we have a
lot of people in cannabis watching this
show what would that one piece of advice
be oh see that's interesting because I
was never trying to get into the
Cannabis space right like that was never
a goal of mine was to work into cannabis
so don't do it
right right there's you know and it's
okay that's a hard question also because
the Cannabis Space is really hard right
now um there aren't a lot of
opportunities the way there used to be I
think that's a temporary situation until
Federal Law changes
um but I would say so here's what I
would say right as someone who's a
professional writer and editor I wrote
for five years for free anybody who
would publish me I wrote for them I did
not care if I was getting paid or not
because I believed in myself enough to
know that if I got my writing out there
that someone would eventually pay for me
yeah um took 5 years but then I had a
very solid career built on people paying
for what I could write and what I could
do so if this is something you actually
really believe in and you want to do
especially creative work Chef's work
writing work artistic work right just do
it just keep creating just keep building
eventually if you stay the course and
you work that side HW hustle yeah you
will get it well so that was going to be
my next question is if somebody wants to
get into writing about cannabis that
they they're passionate about it what
would the best route be and just do it I
would tell them not to focus on cannabis
100% right like don't pigeon hole
yourself to cannabis that's been like
one regret I felt in many ways is that I
felt I got pigeon hold into cannabis
because it's a niche that I felt a niche
that I fell into right um again I have
still today I'm going out of my way to
work on product projects that aren't
cannabis based yeah there's more to this
world than cannabis I know so much about
cannabis it's so easy for me to continue
to produce content about cannabis yeah
but there's so many other things that
matter and to me there's mushrooms
there's all kinds of other things oh the
mushroom industry is like a whole other
thing but the more I've learned like
about Healthcare and cannabis like
cannabis has opened my mind to so many
other things the more I felt compelled
to write about other Healthcare topics
and I hope that we can start looking at
cannabis outside of the box of cannabis
and into how cannabis is going to change
how we do other things yeah I like it
breeding medicine lifestyle drug
Discovery and all these things yeah and
I think a lot of it comes down to
Healthy Living we were talking about
earlier drug Discovery like that topic
itself like still kind of irks me a
little bit right because it's still
based on this premise that we're going
to find this one thing that's going to
cure or treat your problem and you'll
never find this one thing that's going
to cure or treat your problem only you
can treat drug Discovery is like that
one thing that we can patent right so
that's that's kind of what it is it's
like that one thing that we can patent
that does this for this or that it took
us these steps and we had to do this
type of extraction and you know I mean
there drug Discovery and but the thing
is is like from a I see drug Discovery
as an amazing thing because it's like
Okay so we've done all these tests like
they do in Israel where we have these
double blinded
tests and we're looking at large
populations of groups and we're giving
you know trying to solve problems I'm a
Problem Solver as it is I look
everything I do is to solve a problem
and so I like the whole drug Discovery
from that perspective it's like can we
solve a problem with this and the more
we know about it the more problems we
can solve and maybe we can get rid of
ulcerative colitis and autoimmune
disease someday and maybe it won't just
be cannabis but maybe it will be this
combination of stuff but that is the
drug Discovery Canabis but I think
that's the beauty of drug discovery it's
like the more we know the more informed
we are the more we can make better
decisions and maybe we will find
something that makes a difference maybe
it won't be the only thing but maybe
it's something special and unique well
what's important about this drug
Discovery threat is that through trying
to understand these single molecules we
understand the mechanisms of action and
how they work in the body right it's
like how we found OIC is understanding
the glp1 and how that affects your
appetite right so these things are
important like I I have this like
conflict when it came to learning about
medical can abis and going to these
medical cannabis conferences and hearing
them talk about these new canono they
discovered and the pathways they work on
is like wow this knowledge we have about
how these canaps interact with our body
is so important the conclusion is always
so we're going to make a product that
you can buy based on it right and like
that is the wrong conclusion of course
that conclusion is what drives the study
um so there's like this weird balance
with it but patients in particular need
to take some more control of Their Own
healthare more autonomy of what's going
on and that's how they're really going
to find their answers for
sure yeah I mean cuz it's all subject to
the individual so much of it and we all
need different things and we all have
such different body chemistry well with
autoimmune diseases especially something
like Crohn's disease in particular a lot
of this comes down to the balance of
bacteria in your gut right that
interacts with your immune system and
like what's going on in my gut is not
identical to what's going on in the gut
of somebody else with crohn's disease
right what's going on in my gut
in the morning is not the same thing as
what's happening to it in the evening or
after eating this food or that food like
when we actually start studying nature
we start understanding diversity and the
problem with diversity is there's never
one like single solution to anything
it's it's always more complex and
complicated well and for thousands of
years we ate so seasonally you know and
it's thousands and thousands and
thousands of years you know as long as
we've been on this Earth and now we have
tomatoes year round well but people like
me I eat seasonally right I base most of
my food off of a vegetable box that
comes from local organic Growers who are
growing seasonal produce once a week and
that's how I plan my meals is based on
what the fruits and vegetables that are
going to come to me and that's difficult
like not everyone can do that I
understand that not everyone has the
time to cook their own meals but I feel
better for it right really cool MH so if
people are trying to find you on the
internet or out there how do they go
about it luckily I've got a pretty
unique name and I secured all handles on
all social media with my own name right
away so if you look for Angela vodka on
Instagram Twitter Gmail it's me I got
your Tik Tok I don't have a Tik Tok I
know I got yours okay I don't do Tik Tok
I'm too old for that [ __ ] me too me too
but you are on Instagram uh Twitter
Gmail Facebook all the yeah you can
check out my books at flower valley.
press um and what's funny about this is
my public F in company um Flower Valley
Press is not a cannabis name even if
people seem to think it is it's based on
my hometown Loke um which is the flower
seed capital of the world and we call it
the flower Valley so that's where that
name comes from it also happened to
become like a huge cannabis capital in
California very recently which is part
of why I moved home it's pretty wild how
it just overnight became this huge thing
in Santa Barbara County right yes and so
because the county accept it so you know
and large scale it was the one place in
California you could really scale Santa
Barbara County was always going to
become epicenter of cannabis cultivation
in California whether people up north
liked it or not and part of the reason
is because it's 75 and Sunny year round
and we have green houses every Cut
Flower green houses everywhere there
were cut flower green houses everywhere
there was a a Federal Trade pact with
Ecuador and Colombia in the early 2000s
that we agreed to buy cut flowers from
Ecuador and Colombia in exchange for
trying to cut off the flow of cocaine to
the United States and what that did was
put out all of the local flower growers
in my hometown and Southern Santa
Barbara County Northern Santa Barber
County um so when prop 64 was on the
ballot a lot of those greenh houses went
up for sale and they got snapped up real
fast so now we're producing a third of
the legal cannabis in California my
hometown Loke which has been described
by our Congressman Salud caral as the
armpit of his district right it's a
beautiful place on the coast
has the most poverty in Santa Barbara
County wow we passed a law after prop 64
passed in California where we're like no
rules over the state no taxes over the
state no license caps everything goes
right so we have lounges we have a
rotating scene of dispensaries with a
population of 40,000 um we have the only
Cannabis Testing Lab in the county we
have two of the largest extractors in
the state there and we're surrounded by
either um wineries and grape Farms or
cannabis Farms all around um so I got
some fomo and moved home nice excellent
well thank you so much for coming on the
show today uh I look forward to doing
this again soon with our next
book got to take a break before the next
book right absolutely but yeah it was a
blast thanks for coming on the show
thank you for having me absolutely
[Music]
he