[Music]
Heat up here.
[Applause]
[Music]
How's it going everybody? Welcome to
another episode of the James Lab
podcast. And today our special guests
are Aryan Anoa from Greenhouse Seed
Company, Strain
Hunters, so many other things. How are
you guys doing today? We're doing great,
bro. Yeah, we're doing really good.
Thank you so much for having us. It's an
honor to be on your podcast. It's an
honor to be in this great country of
America and Yeah, we had a great time
this week. Yeah. So, I'm so glad I
finally get you on the podcast. We did
during co we filmed together on the
James Loud show. Yeah. I think it was
you and Dust came on and a really,
really good times, you know. Where was
that? That was Well, we did that
remotely. So, I did it from my house,
you guys did it from your house, and you
guys you guys woke up super early in the
morning. Yes, I remember. Yeah, that was
in 2020 or something. That was 2020.
Yeah. The lot's changed since 201, bro.
Yeah. So, you've been a mentor for me
since uh I won my first cannabis cup in
2012. You had 150 cups by then, and
you've kind of helped guide me in the
right direction. Sometimes I'm going
left or right, and you've given me some
good pointers over the years with
genetics, with branding, with a lot of
things. So, thank you for that. You're
most welcome. Happy to share the share
the knowledge and uh help the community.
Yeah. And then Yo's hospitality is bar
none the greatest hospitality in the
world. Whenever I go to Amsterdam, I'm
taken care of. You know, you guys have
an amazing apartment there and, you
know, amazing food. It's always epic
adventure. Yeah. Nice, man. Yeah. Well,
always nice to have you there. So, for
sure. Yeah. I mean, I love the city. I
love the city. Uh except for when it's
freezing cold out. Yeah. Almost always.
Yeah. Don't forget you guys here in San
Francisco have great food, too. We do.
We have amazing food. I would say San
Francisco has better food than
Amsterdam. I agree 100%. So, we have so
much diversity. So, with Amsterdam, they
have good food if you know where to go.
San Francisco just has amazing food all
over. Yeah. But like here, you know, we
went to a few nice restaurants. Any
restaurant could be nice. In Amsterdam,
you really have to hit a Michelin star
restaurant to make sure you're really
good. You know, the difference. Yeah.
So, I wanted to talk a little bit about
today how you guys met. Let's let's go
way back in history to the beginning. I
I want to hear this because I've never
actually heard it before. So, I thought
it would be a great starting point.
Well, let him tell the story because
it's quite funny. Yeah. Well Well, yeah.
He started already way before before I I
joined Greenhouse. So, 1985. No, started
with the seeds and stuff. 1992, the
first dispensary in Amsterdam. Uh I I
was still studying at that point, but
but smoking weed. I was not really an
alcohol guy. I would smoke weed, go to
the coffee shops a lot. And then in um I
went to university in San Diego at UCSD
for a year uh and coming from a weed
background and then going to the states
in those days 90 95 94 95 wasn't weed
everywhere right were no dispensaries
back in the day so I smoked Mexican
weed brick weed you know until I could
find some better ones through people
that I met from normal and uh funny
enough I learned more about greenhouse
because greenhouse was already a little
bit on the radar in America you know So
uh I heard about greenhouse in
California and then when I went back to
America uh to Amsterdam where I lived
all my life and I studied I had to do uh
at some point I had to get a job to pay
the rent right uh after university. So I
I I I got a job at the greenhouse I
applied for a job with ion
coincidentally now looking back it's
funny and then uh just went for a cup of
tea. They had a job interview. I I I I
joined the the the the people that were
there and then I started that greenhouse
and and uh yeah, but the short story is
I never left, you know, but I I enjoyed
it from the get- go and to be honest, I
was really I I I really like liked
cannabis much more than other stuff. And
I really see the benefits, you know,
like I always went with my friends, play
chess, play pool, never won fights,
never won. And I see other friends going
to bars and drinking and, you know,
getting into fights and stuff, trouble,
getting arrested, all that stuff, you
know. I was like, yeah, I was always the
more more chill guy. I do like parties
and everything, but but not really so
much of the alcohol. So when I started
at the greenhouse, I was just, you know,
went after a couple of months, first
High Times Cannabis Cup, I think 95 or
96, and that that was such a big event,
man. And I thought at that point Holland
was so far ahead actually looking back
at that point in time we were ahead of
the rest of the world. Right. Right now
it's a different story. We'll talk more
about it later. But uh I thought we were
going to legalize in two three years at
that moment in time. So you know I
thought okay we're going to do this and
blah blah blah. And then every year was
a different thing you know different
projects. We talk probably more about
some stuff but uh it's always been it's
been really interesting ride you know.
Yeah, it's always an adventure. And you
guys travel so much. Yeah. Yeah. The
travel is a getting an issue now. Yeah.
This year was I think the worst one cuz
we've been traveling up and down. Now we
have Argentina opening up in Brazil.
Yeah. Which before was not on the radar,
but we've been operating in Argentina
the last 10 years to our distributor,
Fran, who I used to work with in ITA in
Spain. And he moved back to to
Argentina. And he said, "Aran, it's
going to open in the future. Can I do
the distribution for your nutrients?"
Yeah, sure. Why not? No, nothing to lose
now. And we started that 10 years ago
and we got everything legalized as one
of the first ones and still one of the
few ones. Yeah. So, we control like 50
60% of the market with nutrients there
cuz you know our our product for for
private growers and also for commercial
growers is probably one of the best and
for sure the most easiest and best
priced one. So in a country like Brazil
and Argentina, Spain, this is a very
interesting, easy product, you know. So
we started with that. So we moved into
Argentina, now Brazil. So now, and we're
in Asia. So instead of being only in
Europe and a little in America, we went
and to the east and to the west from
Europe, you know. Yeah. which creates
like this crazy jet lag because now I
did in four weeks, Bonazeres, Rio, Sao
Paulo, then back to Bangkok and then
back to Vegas. Yeah. But you can imagine
the time difference is 15 hours. Yeah.
So it's ridiculous. We were him and me
were struggling here now this time, you
know, in Vegas with I think I slept 2
hours a day and then you're tired at
7:00 in the evening and you're awake at
11:00. For you it's a lot harder to come
here and then than it is to go back.
Yeah. Because if you arise in if you
arrive in LA or San Francisco, you go 9
hours back, right? But that's from
Amsterdam. That's not from Bangkok,
right? That's another 6 hours. Wow. And
even Yeah. And even then before you
worked in Africa a lot. So Africa is
down. So then the jet lag is is is
minimal. Well, most people know I'm from
Africa original, but if you have if you
take South Africa, Congo, from
Amsterdam, it's a line straight down.
It's the same time zone. Yeah. Yeah. So
there's maybe 1 or 2 hour difference in
some parts of Africa, but not a lot. So
that doesn't affect you. Bangkok is
quite easy. It's 4 or 5 hours. San
Francisco and LA is the worst, you know,
especially coming down here and then
getting into meetings, you know. Oh,
yeah. So you arrive here, it's
technically 9:00 in the evening and then
it's 12:00 again. Yeah. Mhm. And then
you have to work the whole day. At least
there's good food. It's good. The food
you have to be watched because you get
lazy when you eat too much. No. So, and
as everybody know, I'm quite a big
foodie as you. Yeah. So, I really
appreciate the food. I had some great
meals in San Francisco and in Las Vegas
again and like also in Sao Paulo and in
Brazil and in thing, you know, I don't
have time to train. So, that's the other
problem, you know, you gain like 3,
four, 5 kilos every four weeks, you
know, because no time to hit the gym or
too tired to hit the gym. Sure. Or, you
know, you do only half an hour instead
of a proper 50 minutes. So yeah, this
this this this jet lag with our seed
company and our fertilizer company, we
have to fine-tune this system how we're
going to do this because this year was
out of control. Yeah. And then I only
limit myself to a few fairs, you know.
We do Spanabis, we do Berlin, so
Barcelona, Berlin, Bangkok, Buenos Iris,
Sao Paulo, Las Vegas. Yeah. And then
here because you invited us, we did
Turmania this weekend which was a great
show. And then last night the ego clash.
But again we are home at 4:00 in the
morning, you know, right? That's the
industry for you in a nutshell. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. It's every
everybody think it's it's easy but it's
really really hard work, you know. I
think the rock rockstar lifestyle is a
hard lifestyle. I don't think people
give rock stars enough credit too. Like
the musician lifestyle, you know, they
go they go on tour and they hit it. I
mean, it's you guys are living that
similar life right now. Well, you know,
we're good friends with a lot of rock
stars. You probably saw the picture with
Dual Lipa last week. If you see her
travel thing, you know, it's like hard,
you know. Yeah. And then every night she
she's nearly two hours on stage. She
really works her ass off. One of the
nicest people in the industry, by the
way. And that's a rock star, you know.
You see with the DJs, but even a pilot
for an airline, you know. Oh, yeah. It's
horrible. I used to have I used to have
a hashtag, I don't use it anymore. More
miles than the pilot. And then Franco
took it over, you know. Sure. But we
have more miles than a pilot. We're just
looking at my mouse cuz you just
upgrade. I had 650,000 miles. Wow. And
this is just from a few months, you
know, because I use them sometimes. It's
ridiculous. Yeah. It's wild. Yeah. And
then every time you you're almost about
to go back, like now we we fly back
tomorrow and now we're used to this
schedule. So every time you're used to
it and then you go back and you start
from 3 4 days and mostly we are five,
six, seven days there. Yeah. So the
moment you land you, you know, you're
screwed again. Starting starting all
over again. Yeah. But now the holidays
nearly there. We have three more days in
Amsterdam. We have to do a lot of things
and then
take the plug out. So if you were to go
back from the beginning and look at how
it is right now, could have you imagined
it how it is? Yes, totally. But much
earlier when I I started growing
in 82, 83 when I was 16, 17, 18. It was
very illegal in Holland. Still totally
very legal by the way. Nothing changed.
I thought, you know what? And that was
at my time there. I'm I'm a great
mushroom fan. Yeah. In my private life,
I really like mushrooms. I do that a
lot. Also with my family, with my
children, with everybody, my friends
around me. I think it's one of the
nicest things to do. I think it opens
your mind. I think it makes you very
smart. It gives you a lot of um a lot of
new vision on things, you know,
perspective. Perspectives, that's the
good word. My English is not so good as
you guys know, but so good perspective.
So, at that time, I was like, okay, what
I'm going to do? I'm going to go in
marijuana or I'm going to go in
mushrooms. And I realized that mushrooms
also have for some people negative
effects because they take too much and
then they can jump down of a bridge or
do something stupid. Yeah. So I decided
to go with marijuana. This is 8283.
Then I opened my first shop in ' 87 with
two partners very small shop called
Tutti Frutti on the in Amsterdam and
they had no clue about business. Make a
long story short, after 6 months I
stepped out and then they continue with
it and they went broke and then in '92 I
started a real shop. So basically
uh 92 I opened to well you know the
place it's still there and I started
growing in 82 10 years before and the
only reason I opened the shop is that I
could not get rid of my weed anymore and
I was kind of the first sativa grower in
Holland. You know first of all I was the
first marijuana coffee shop in
Amsterdam. So you have to see if you're
talking about
92 90% of the menu was hashis mainly
Moro a little Afghanistan little India
you know charas and then 10% schwag like
some Jamaican some Nigerian stuff like
that you know like brick wheat kind of
stuff bad not good occasionally there
was some something nice there tie stick
maybe some tick or some lumps bread if
you were really lucky you could get your
hands on a kilo yeah wow
But before that, I I supplied Bulldog,
you know, Hank, good friend of my family
and a few other coffee shops. And then I
started growing this new stuff because I
was I'm I'm I come from a growers
family. And my mom used to grow, we were
living in Asia, she had 700 different
orchid things. And my mom comes from a
resistant family in the war, butter
smugglers, you know, against the against
the Nazi Nazi regime. And my grandmother
was butter smuggler. and they were all
doing that and she was a little on the
illegal side. I don't know if you know
the normal orchid growth but there's
some black orchids that cost $25,000 and
she was doing that kind of stuff which
intrigued me. She got very green
fingers. My mom is still alive. She's
nearly 90. Sometimes I post her garden
when it's in full flower. You don't know
what you see. So I got the green fingers
from her. But then I started growing
these sativas in these hes where I got
my hands on and I went back to the
coffee shops and the orange
said we don't know what to do with this.
I so I gave 2 kilos for
free. I was really young you know I was
in my 20s and I thought the owners were
in charge of their shops and not the
dealers. But then 2 months later I came
and I basically got my 2 kilos back and
they said it's cat piss. The Dutch
people don't like it. The tourists don't
like it. Nobody's buying it. We only
want skunk. Wow. And I Yeah. You know,
that was it. You know, I couldn't do
nothing with it. But at the same time, I
was a chef like you when you were young.
This is how I grew up, right? And I
thought, man, this is so good, you know.
And it's not only good for the taste,
but also how it how it is, you know,
like the workout, how you say that, you
know, like the the mental high, you
know, not like this couch look stoned,
you know, right? I thought, why don't
they like this, you know? So I started
going on with it until my wife said,
"Listen, if you're sure that this is
really good, open your own shop." So we
did that in
'92 and the first two years was a total
The first year was a total drama. Make a
long story short, uh Brendan Kennedy,
the owner of the High Times at that
time, Kennedy family, they had like a
consortium with 20 magazines and he
passed by in April and I never forget
this and I had no clue, bro. I didn't
know America. I didn't never heard of
High Times. And he said, "Listen, we're
going to do Thanksgiving, which is your
November, I think." No, we're going to
do a big competition. I'm going to get
500 or,000 people over and we going to
smoke this weed and blah blah blah. And
uh we're going to do an election and
blah blah blah, you know. But nobody
ever heard of High Times magazine. We
didn't even discuss it with the other
coffee shop owners. Everybody kind of
forgot about it until two days before
Thanksgiving. This guy calls me up.
We're coming tomorrow. Yeah. [ __ ] There
was 500 people in front of my door. I
had no clue. This was even before yo was
with me. Yeah. Yeah. So I called all my
friends, you know, come and help.
Luckily, I had my weed. Yeah. I had a
few kilos of that sativa weed, you know,
and um I had master kush at that time
and some with not even a
name. And um they came and they start
smoking it. And the first two Americans
and I I wish I see those guys back. They
said, "Arin, we've never smoked
something like this. This is so [ __ ]
good." And I knew I was on the right
track, you know. And another guy came
and another guy came and it was so And
then suddenly the next three, four days,
they were all sitting in my shop, you
know, like not in the other shops. You
feel the vibe, you know, going with the
cannabis cup. And I thought, "Okay, this
is really good." Now, make a long story
short, at that time, Hank had his hotel,
which he still has. And under there was
the Buddha Club. I don't know if you
remember that. Buddha disco Buddha
lounge and he gave the club to the guys
you know he was also competing of course
and then just don't forget you see five
cameras here but there were 40 like
every television station of the world
was there because was the first illegal
drugs cup yeah so CNN BBC Japanese
television everybody was there and all
my competitors we were all friends and
we're still friends you know I said oh
we have to be careful this going to fire
back in our face this is not good for
the industry we're going to go to jail,
you know, the staff [ __ ] their
pants, you know. Yeah. And I thought,
well, you know, we have nothing to lose.
We're illegal already anyway. You know,
what can happen, you know? Sure. And
then I don't know who was the first
year. We had some characters there with
Steve Hager. I think one of the first
few was with Gatwood Gail Brick. He was
running for governor of Kentucky. So
there is American comes with this big
cowboy hood, you know, which we were not
used to in Amsterdam because Amsterdam
is very very multicultural, you know.
like we're mixed from every like
everything. And I'll make a long story
short, there were six prizes and I won
five times the first prize, you know. I
went to the front and I picked up my
price and I did a camera from there. It
went like this, you know. Well, then you
were on the cover of High Times shortly
after that. Then 95 and 99. Yeah. I'm
the only guy who hit the front cover of
High Times two times, you know, and
three times more with Bud and Flour and
stuff like that. Yeah, that was a great
honor and helped us helped my company a
lot, our company. And uh yeah from there
on we were already of course working
with seeds. Then 95 we started the seed
company. Yeah. And the rest is history
you know you can see where we are
standing now. We grew
organically. So we never borrowed money.
We never wanted to be listed. We had so
many offers. We had so many private
planes flying in. We had a few few years
ago. You remember the Canadians like two
private planes. We have the most crazy
stories that we cannot even tell here.
Yeah. Yeah. But we said no to anyone.
Even like in Thailand now we're very
private with a private family, very good
friends of us and we do it our way and
that's the only way. We don't want to be
listed. We don't want to have investors.
We just grow organically and I think
that's why our company is quite
successful, very healthy, no depth.
Yeah. You know, and yeah, that's how we
do it. Well, yeah. And you've
transitioned all over. You were in
you're you still are in Spain in
Barcelona. You were in the Bass country
as well for a while and you were in the
Congo, you know, you've been all over.
Yeah. What I what I like to do is I like
to go to new emerging markets where I
see options and you know um uh like
so we made a lot of Strain Hunter movies
as you probably know. So one on my radar
for very very long time was Congo. As
you know I grew up in Africa. My parents
lived there nearly 40 years. Um and
Congo was also on my radar. Look, you
have Africa and then you have Congo. We
call it the deep sea. And it's a huge
country. It's the size of Europe. And
you heard a lot of problems about Congo.
It's one of those countries that the
West has totally raped. Yeah. The
Americans, the Chinese, the Russians,
everybody's fighting for the resources
there, which gives it a really bad name,
you know. And you can see the diamond
mine. Well, in my movie, you can see one
of the diamond mines. I went in there.
So our partner is the back nephew of the
former president Joseph Kabila which
father far again was the president
before and got shot then he took over as
a 27 year old and 8 years ago he had to
now it's
tidi so I had a contact through my South
African contact he said Arian we can get
a letter and we can travel free through
the country and we can shoot a movie so
and I know and as a matter of fact we
can still see that we still have to grow
there was still growing there. But if
you're on the equator in that part, your
side, your seeds become twice as big if
you grow them in full sunlight. So they
look really nice, you know, they have a
much much much let's say much better bag
appeal. Mhm. And I could do much more
there. So after make a long story short
after the movie we shot last day we were
sitting in the in the hotel in the VL
and uh that this whole group approached
us you know it was quite funny and come
can we have a talk yeah sure this and
that um we would like to grow in in our
country can you help us I said well I
think it's very illegal here no he said
yeah but we can get an R&amp;D license we're
connected to the president and we want
to get this industry going like Canada
and United States and can you help us
Yeah. I said, "Well, if you guys give me
a letter, I can grow here from
agriculture department or the justice
minister or the department of health or
whoever. We do it." And that's how we
started. And it was great for seeds, you
know, because we built 50 very well, you
probably saw it on Instagram. No. Oh,
yeah. We built very 50 very primitive
glass houses
for 18 hours cuz you're on the equator.
No. So, we work with LED lights. every 3
m we had a little LED light you know to
keep the photo period on 18 hours and
then we had seven big valleys where we
made we made hundreds of kilos of seeds
there so we learned a lot and that's
basically also where now the new base is
coming from so we did millions of plants
in those valleys so if you see now the
new the new full gas uh king's juice
lemon and orange many many of the
strains they they originate from there
that's where we did pre breeding work
until we finalized everything mostly
some in Spain with dust and mostly in in
in Thailand now. Wow. So yeah, and you
guys helped change policy in the Congo.
I mean it was more than just producing
seed. Yeah. So what what people don't
know you know cuz you know there's a lot
of talk about greenhouse and about us
and what are we all doing and you know
we're a McDonald's and all this [ __ ]
you know. So we have a quite a strong
core group.
So from 95 to
2010 which is 15 years we set up in
Holland the cannabis retailers
association. I was a spokesman by the
way. Now Yoa is the spokesman the last
15 years. Yeah. So we had huge issues in
Holland and you have to understand how
this all goes. It's quite a long story
but I'll try to explain it a little bit
in a nutshell. Um, Holland has had the
dispensary model, the coffee shop model,
right? But we were on the scrutiny of
the United Nations, especially France,
Sweden, and America. It's really bad.
It's you're violating international law.
You have signed the convention of 1961
and 60. You cannot do this, blah, blah,
blah. So, we were under high pressure.
So in '95 we decided to start the base a
day which I became a spokesman of and
some strong other guys hang from the
bulldog and many of the big guys were in
there and we start fighting the system.
It's the same time that I created the
king of cannabis and nobody knows why I
created that but it was to create a king
so celebrities can come from America and
start helping advocate our case. And
that really worked out because guys like
Woody Harrison and Bill Maher and all
the big rappers be real. So many so many
people came to our shop because it was a
king suddenly, you know. So it was a
marketing strategic strategic idea for
me. Still the best bobbleheads in the
business. And the best bobbleheads in
the business. I still have my
bobbleheads. Yeah. Yeah. We have to make
them again. We went through. Remind me
later. I told you how funny your story
about the bobbleheads was cuz everybody
was laughing about the bobbleheads.
Yeah. They're classic. I still have mine
at the house. But I can confirm this
story because he was witness of it. He
arranged his story. Yeah. Anyway, so we
start fighting the whole system and make
a long story short, people like Debbie
Goldsbury, Berkeley Patient Group, Steve
D'Angelo, which I met last week with
Harborside. Yeah. They were all coming
to the cannabis cup, you know, and we
were promoting the cannabis cup. At that
time, I wrote the book How to Run a
Dispensary. And then we were in
politics. I spoke in the parliament a
few times to like make sure we we have
more leverage, you know, I said go back
to America and start working your
government. And at one point the
government the Dutch government also saw
okay Americans getting legal now we're
going to go illegal. It's a little bit
funny you know Americans telling us to
be illegal and themselves of course not
on a federal level but on the state
level we're legalizing. Yeah. So that
was the beginning of our politic being
politic involved. Just very recently Yo
beat the mayor of Amsterdam after they
want to kick out the tourists again out
of the center of Amsterdam because he's
getting too busy. Yeah. And basically on
his own
he was much bigger. So in 2004 I went
back to the office and I said to the
guys listen if we want to survive in the
future and want to have a great brand we
should make sure that our message goes
all over the world you know and not only
in Holland in America. So I came up with
we were called in because I was making
king of cannabis with my greenhouse logo
and the lawyers and the mayor of
Amsterdam called me and said listen you
are violating the the laws of having a
dispensary in Holland. So there's five
laws. It's called A H O GJ J. A. No
advertisement, no hard rigs, no younger
people, no deals under five grams, uh
above five grams, and no disturbance in
the street. That's kind of what they you
have to oblige to the a of
advertisement. I was kind of violating.
They said cannot do anything on YouTube
anymore. Greenhouse, too much
greenhouse, cannabis cup, hager, we
going wild. Yeah, this is really And
they liked us because we were the
spokesman. said, "Listen, we're not
going to find you now. Let's stop." Wow.
So, I break my head, you know, and then
at one point I say, "Okay, I said to my
lawyer at that time, I came with this
one night. I just saw the light, you
know." I thought, "Okay, strain hunters,
me and Franco." So, I went to the
office, let's go back to Africa. Let's
start filming there, rough content, and
let's see how get everybody upset. We're
going to get killed. We're going to get
closed. We're going to go in prison.
This is a really bad idea. But when
everybody said that to me, I go the
other way. I think this is going to be a
really great idea because they're
already talking about it. You know, for
sure. The lawyers didn't know what to do
by the lawyers know what to do. And then
later the mayor said, "You really got us
there because you changed the name. What
can they do?" Yeah, it's the same face,
but it's not greenhouse, you know. It's
me, Strain Hunter. So, the first one
with Malawi was a direct success. We had
10 million hits and then National
Geographic came and then later Vice came
with Shane and everybody and well you
know the whole success about this
straight out of the movie but the
message was to show how 200 people
around the equator are depending on
marijuana. So if you go to Africa what
many people don't understand where I'm
from is kids cannot go to school because
they have to guard the kettle.
So a poor African family would have
three fields one corn field or they call
it millie. So that's the food for the
cow and they have maybe one cow and two
goats. They have a vegetable field to
eat themselves and they have a marijuana
field to make a little money. Wow. To
survive and that's where the danger
comes. You know if they're going to take
that away with legalization also those
families have a problem. So I wanted to
show that and you know sometimes things
start going as a roller coaster. You
know like I made Malawi then I don't
know how many more we made but look at
where we went you know. Well, Sin
Vincent, you are there now? Yeah, I'm
there now. Yeah. So, I went there in
2012 because I already knew that the
volcano mountain of Sin Vincent supplies
the whole Caribbean. Weed is not coming
from Jamaica. Weed is not coming from
Florida. Weed is not coming from
Colombia. It's coming from St. Vincent
with the scarabs. Those guys are all in
my in my movie. Yeah. And in my private
life, I travel a lot. So, I met all
those guys. I said, "Okay, I'm going to
film that." Within 3 months after we put
that that uh film out. Yeah. the
president of the prime minister of
finins or the president I don't remember
went on national television you can
google it on BBC say okay the strain
hunters were here we're going to take
their advice we're not going to lock up
people anymore for less than an ounce or
for more you know they can if you're a
tourist you can come smoke on our
beaches so this is the kind of awareness
we wanted to create with those movies
you know so bring something extra to the
table where we can help the community
worldwide not only in our local humbled
area or San Francisco area or Amsterdam
area of Bangkok. No, like a broader
vision where politicians are standing up
say, "Okay, this is reasonable on a
global scale." On a global scale, we did
Morocco legalizing now. We did Colombia
legalizing now. We did Thailand. We did
Swaziland. We did South Africa. We did
Congo. We changed because that was your
question. We changed the constitution of
Congo. Took us 5 years, but it went
through all the parliament. We spent
more than $300,000 from our own money to
change the constitution. And now other
people have the license there and we
don't mind. Yeah. And what and what said
is like what people don't see because
sometimes they see us in a certain way
they don't see the path that that is
before legalization. Right. So what says
in Congo to change the con constitution
what it took was when we when we started
there uh uh cannabis was in the
constitution as the the the devil's
herb. The devil's herb. So it's not like
you start legalization in America where
there is a cannabis culture already. You
start from zero. No, we started at minus
400, you know, so and then to legalize.
And then in 2017, for example, our team
went to Thailand. We're in in Thailand
since 2017 already. Uh our science guy
gave seminars, you know, to educate and
and inform the people. And then when
they said, "Hey guys, there's a chance,
you know, in Thailand, it's going to go
it's going to go the right direction."
and we were busy with other things. I
don't remember what, but we said, "Okay,
we we you went to prison for the for
your life if you were caught with
cannabis." So, we we said, "Okay, you
guys go ahead. It's never going to
happen in Thailand." And then at some
point it just they made the switch. But
what a lot of people don't see is they
they only see, of course, what they see
on Instagram and on online and and
everything, but they don't see the
process before. They don't see all the
hard days and nights. Exactly.
journey even now as we as we speak the
people see what what is happening they
see Thailand they see Africa but now
we're also talking with other countries
around because because Thailand is the
first one in Asia but but you can
understand that the the countries around
are are watching they're looking
observing what's going on so they send
delegations to Thailand we speak with
the government also in Thailand is it's
they started the legalization completely
basically opposite as Canada and Germany
Over there they started with, you know,
in Canada with a big book of regulation,
right? So many rules and made the
product very expensive. In Thailand,
they did the opposite. They said it's
legal from now on. So you say, okay,
what's the legal framework? What?
There's no legal framework. It's legal
now, you know. So they started with
zero. It was like black or white and now
we're writing the book. So the most
asked question to us is how's it going
in Thailand? I hear it's going to go
backward. No, it's not backward. It's
the dance, you know. It's the dance how
we're going to regulate. So, we started
with zero and now we're writing the
book, you know, now we're doing making
the regulations progress. It goes up, it
goes down. Yeah. And it doesn't make it
easy because, you know, uh again on
Instagram, everything's always nice,
parties and and and you know, well,
Instagram is part of the problem with
cannabis right now. I feel like people
are so excited about the way stuff looks
that it's gone away from how does it
make you feel? How does it taste also?
Yeah. Yeah, definitely. Yeah. Well, if
you look at Thailand, it's a good
example he gives. Yeah, like Thailand
League 2 years ago in June 2022.
In 2018, we got the phone call, can you
come and advise at university? There
will be some politicians and everything.
Yeah. And Haiko, who's the guy who is
behind all these papers and everything,
our partner. I said to him, don't go.
And Haiko is from Thailand. He had a
house in Kosamui, so he know Thailand
really well. He said, Arian, let me go.
I said, listen, we're going to spend
$50,000 on a pitch. We have to take two
professors, a doctor, follow up before
airplane tickets, hotels. I'm not going.
Never ever. It will be legal in Asia.
That was my idea. Yeah. Yeah. I was so
wrong. So, in the end, he convinced me
to go. I said, "Okay, you go. You spend
half the money, you take one guy and one
doctor and you go do your thing." Yeah.
He went, he said, "It was great." I
said, "What's the only advice you give
them there?" I said, "Don't make the
mistakes we made in Holland, in Canada,
and in the United States. with all your
bloody regulations, you know,
over taxation. We can talk about that a
little bit later. Yeah. So, I told them
one thing. Don't make that mistake. In
2022, they called me. You can see, by
the way, in my uh in my Thai movie that
we launched in February, the deputy time
prime minister is in the movie. Can you
imagine a deputy prime minister or prime
minister of any western country in a pot
movie? Never. There they came because I
promised them 80 million tourists by
2013 and they're going to get it. Yeah.
Yeah. So, we went already this year to
35 million and next year we go 40
million, then we got 50 million. Yeah.
As long as we're all on board in
Thailand. We're going to try to get the
F1 now in Thailand in Bangkok. We're
trying to legalize gambling maybe and
there's more things going going to
happen. Yeah. So, in 2022 they called us
and they said, "We're going to do it." I
said, "What are you going to do?" We're
going to legalize totally. I said, 'What
do you mean recreational and medicinal?
Just we're going to just let it go. It's
kind of medicinal and we'll see what
happens. And this is where we're
standing now, you know. Yeah. So, and
and this is one of the one of the things
that we as a team bring to the table,
you know. So, if there's two other Asian
countries who are speaking right now, we
just had the two sons of one president
of an Asian country flying into Holland
and Secret Service comes, they put
[ __ ] tape on the cameras and then we
speak. You know, this is how it really
goes. Wow.
And LA was just legalized medicinal
cannabis to the neighboring country of
Thailand. Amazing. And yeah, and this is
and we we are really proud of that, you
know, because Japan next year 25. Wow.
Medical. So, we're talking to the main
guys there. We're advising
Yeah. We we are very good friend of us.
Some few Japanese billionaires are
behind that push Tokyo University and
it's going to happen. It's going to go
slow in Japan cuz it's quite a
conservative country but it's a
beginning and every step helps you know
also like now in Germany also it's it's
it's limited it's with a lot of
restrictions but but it's a big step
because it's the biggest country in
Europe and what about Middle East you
know if if technically you know I'm
quite in shock when I land in San
Francisco in LA in New York and I see
the airports you know same a little bit
in in Europe. Yeah. You go to Abu Dhabi
or Dubai or or Singapore or Hong Kong
you come in a new world. Yeah, they're
way ahead. Yeah. And in 9 January this
year, UAE, so Dubai and Abu Dhabi, the
punishment for smoking went from 30
years to 3 months. That's a first big
step. That's a huge step. That's a huge
step. And nobody realizes this, but you
know, we're Haiko's been working very
extensive with the government there for
the last 3 years maybe. Yeah. You know,
it's difficult because you know, they
have all kinds of issues, you know,
there in the Middle East. Like in the
Middle East, like the Emirates is like
every religious group, every I'm not
allowed to say the names, every other
group, let's put it that way. Yeah. They
all say, "Okay, this stays out of the
conflict zone. This is where our wives
and our kids go to school. This is where
we have the holidays and this is where
we kind of try to figure out solutions."
Yeah. So this the place where we then
also can talk, you know, and see, okay,
how far can we go? So just to give you
an
example, there's a few big party areas
from Ibita that are now going to open in
Dubai, like for example, Ushay. Yeah.
But there's other groups that I know
really well that are not going that are
also invited by the bosses. And then the
conversation goes like, why are you
turning down so much money doing the
party here in Dubai or in Abu Dhabi? Cuz
my people can't use drugs, so we're not
coming. Interesting. So, okay. Well, and
then the sons of the bosses say, "Okay,
well, we'll be working on that." So,
this is where we are standing now in the
real world, you know, like, okay, who's
making the next move? Brazil. Yeah. Very
recently, you can have six plants now.
Yeah. I I came from a fair was 30,000
people. I think I did 10,000 autographs.
So, Brazil, Argentina, Germany,
Thailand. You see the movement going,
you know, where we are involved. the
momentum. The momentum, you know. Yeah.
And then you see our countries like I
see your bloody president Joe Biden
pardoning two bloody turkeys. He's only
president for another month. Okay. But
he pardoned his son. He did and two
turkeys. Yeah. And what about those
20,000 innocent people sitting for
cannabis in jail? Thailand 2022
released on the same day 7,000 prisoners
that were convicted for cannabis. Yeah.
On the same day. 7,000 people out of
prison, which is the way it should be.
And not a single problem with one of
them. And gave out how many clones? Was
1 million. No. Oh yeah. And 1 million
clones. Million. They gave out 1 million
clones. It's more a symbolic thing,
right? But still, it's pretty cool. The
act of giving. Yeah. It's very symbolic.
I think that's amazing. I don't think
there's many presidents in the world
that would do that, you know, million
clones. It's not happening here. No,
it's not happening in the US. Maybe
Trump will do it, you know. Just you
never know. You never know what's going
to happen in the next four years. I
mean, yeah. Yeah. Well, if Trump gives
them out, at least their their biggest,
the best, the most awesome that you'll
ever ever see. The best clothes in the
world, right? Yeah. But and you just
never know what's going to happen. I
think a lot of people are
scared and a lot of people are excited
about what could happen. And I think
we've been going in the wrong trajectory
for the last four years and for more
than the last four years. It's been, you
know, long time. It's a long time. But
let's see now your American government.
If I look around Trump now, Trump is the
only one doesn't drink and doesn't
smoke, but the rest does. If it's Joe
Rogan or it's Alan Musk or whoever it
is, they're all smokers. Yeah. So, let's
see how this will influence him, you
know, and and what kind of decisions
would be made. Look, it can't go any
worse. No, it can't go any worse. And I
think the potential is really good for
change, right? It's going to change one
way or the other. Like, that's the only
thing constant is change anyway, but uh
yeah, we need change. We need change. I
mean, the economy is in a bad place, you
know? And then federal legalization.
It's just it's silly that we don't have
federal legalization for cannabis. It's
on a federal level, yet we have more
than half of the United States in
support of cannabis. You know, we have
more than half of the United States
that's medical. It seems to me that we
need to look at ourselves in the mirror
a little bit differently and I think the
younger generation is getting older now
and they are starting to get into
politics and that's going to be the big
change. So in the next 10 years it's
definitely going to change. I don't
know. Look our our problem is a mult is
a big problem. Yeah. Yeah. We have five
enemies. We have pharma as an enemy. We
have tobacco as enemy. We have alcohol
as an enemy. And we have the religious
people as an enemy. Yeah. four I
probably forgot one maybe big egg yeah
then our governments now if you look at
Japan or Asia you look at Europe and you
look at America
5% 4% obesus in
Asia 25% in Europe 60% in America
our politicians are killing us because
they are responsible for this huge
problem in America with fentinol and
with wrong food. Most of the food you
guys are eating is illegal in Europe or
in Asia in most countries. In most
countries, yeah, a lot of these
addictives and all that kind of stuff
you sue. So if you just take it from
there, if the politicians are already
willing to kill their own people, they
don't give a [ __ ] about cannabis, right?
Yeah. So here is huge problem for us.
Yeah. If our politicians are not taking
responsible responsibility to ban
certain foods and certain chemicals that
are used, why should they worry about
marijuana? Mhm. This is the the the
biggest problem, right? I think, you
know, so we are killing our own
population and we don't give a [ __ ]
Yeah. That's what's happening. Well, and
I mean you you guys can both agree with
me that cannabis makes the world a
better place. And so looking at it any
other way, it's like there's not people
like like alcohol and tobacco are way
worse, right? No matter how you look at
it, you look at the statistics.
Statistically, it's a lot worse. There's
more deaths from alcohol and tobacco
across the board, yet cannabis is still
illegal. Mhm. But cannabis will always
have that stigma and and but it can
change really quickly. You see that for
example, I don't think it had the stigma
200 years ago and I don't think a 100
years from now it's going to have the
same. No, but here is here is different
from madness. No, but and and here is
much more accepted and it's changed also
with the kind of legalization, you know,
even if it's on the state level. But in
Thailand, for example, you see it as
well. Like 2 years ago or four years
ago, of course, it's not. I mean, you
can't even roll up a a joint in in
public. Now, if you go to a Michelin
star rooftop restaurant, for example,
you say, "Oh, can we smoke here?" Yeah,
of course you can smoke. You go to the
smoke area, you roll a joint, and and
other people will ask you, "What are you
smoking?" And they're interested in it
and and everything. in in Holland you
cannot even imagine that you know if you
on the streets right now you can't even
smoke on the streets you can't smoke in
the streets no but cannabis there is
pushed like last week I was giving an
interview on television because there
was a eightpage letter from the from the
mayor about the uh the center of the
city and there's one sentence on coffee
shops and the media pick it out and they
and they they talk about coffee shops I
said we have such big problems in this
neighborhood you know robberies gang
wars uh drug drug uh abuse and and you
pick out this one sentence, there's much
bigger problems, but they keep always
going back to the blame on the sometimes
even I'm in Thailand and and we speak
with the with the minister, I go on
television in Thailand, speak about the
policy, I fly back to Amsterdam, I go to
the council to speak about not smoking a
joint in public in in the the the
contrast is sometimes so big, it's
unbelievable, you know, and then I mean,
I'm born and raised in Amsterdam and I'm
proud of the city, But sometimes
nowadays I'm even a little bit
embarrassed of this situation, you know,
when people say, "Oh, you can't smoke in
Amsterdam anymore." No, it's just on the
street in certain areas. But they're
pushing it in a certain direction. Well,
they've cut down on the coffee shops,
too, cuz there was a lot of coffee shop
400 to 165. Yeah. And I don't want to
cut even more back. And like the whole
thing with tourists now, okay, all the
tourists are coming for the coffee shop,
which of totally [ __ ] of course,
right? Yeah. And in the center or in the
center they say, "Oh, it's so big." But
in the in the red light area, there's 12
coffee shops left. Yeah. Yeah. And the
even the local people there are against
us. They say, "Yeah, the Vistrad, which
is a famous street, they used to have
20. There's zero." And they still think
there are 20 there and they live around
the corner. Yeah. You know, and then the
mayor and and the mayor sitting there in
council. Yeah. So, we're going to ban
the tourists from the coffee shops, but
then the most political parties that are
smart enough to live there, too. Yeah.
So, we're going to get a lot of street
dealers now. Yeah. And guess what?
Heroin and crack is back at the central
station for the first time in bloody 20
years. Yeah. Because there's no cops.
So, not only we don't have housing, we
don't have nurses, we don't have
doctors, schools in Amsterdam are going
to four days because we don't have
enough teachers. Yeah. Yeah. But you
know what what says this information the
the council gets, they don't get it from
anywhere but from us, you know, us as a
community. I'm not talking about us in
general. So even the people watching,
you know, if you want to help
legalization, if you want to help
normalizing cannabis, you have to speak
with your local politicians, you know,
cuz there's a dance always there's new
people coming in and out. If there's new
people coming in the council, I go there
because literally they don't know the
difference between hash and weed. So if
you don't know the difference, how can
you make a policy about cannabis? You
cannot because you don't know what you
what you what you are you know what what
you base your opinion on and then you're
influenced by the people around you that
they likely don't underestimate that and
if people are in in in councils or like
municipalities where it's still a little
bit you know gray area or whatever and
you want to change go out and and talk
with the people if I'm not in Amsterdam
and there's something in the media I
call around nobody wants to go on
television I was like guys come on man
go with your you know tell your story
because people need to know and I also
tell people outside of the business. So
people who produce glass houses and and
put them in Canada and in America, Dutch
Dutch companies that are super
successful in cannabis, please help me
say this message. And then sometimes
they do and that's helpful, you know,
but people need to get the message
across. That's why we do always podcast,
we do seminars. If they invite us in
Canada for a seminar, we go, you know, a
TED talk. We do everything to always
keep talking and informing, educating.
and he's much more diplomatic than me.
So most of the time I let him do it
because I hate them. I can't handle
them. Cuz I tell him straight in the
face, your government is responsible for
losing a 100red billion Yeah. of
economic prosperity in the last 5 years
in the coming 5 years. You killed the
glass house industry. You killed the
light industry. Gavvita was a Dutch
company. It was they sold it for $240
million to HTON. Friends of mine all
Yeah. But they were scared. Yeah. Why
are you selling such a viable good
companies from Holland? You know, nutr
companies all sold. They killed it in
Holland. Yeah. This is the future. You
know, one of the best things biggest
things is going to be it's going to be
bigger than porno and alcohol. Yeah.
Smoking marijuana. You know, it's
bigger. You kill it. Why are you killing
the baby? And I'm just telling that, you
know, and it's it's it's amazing. They
have no clue. Only because of their own
political agenda. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. And
every politician is sitting there
because his own private agenda. There's
not a politician sitting there like a
Gandhi or a Nelson Mandela. We had
that's there for really for everybody in
the community. You know, it's always
like it's a Donald Trump or it's a Joe
Biden with an agenda, right? Yeah. But
is Joe Biden there for us? No. Is Donald
Trump there for us? No. you know, is the
Dutch prime minister there for us? No,
it's very tough to be a politician. It's
something that not a lot of people want
to do. I'm sure it's like me. I'm not
not I have no interest in politics. But,
uh, so as far as you guys are now in
Thailand and you are very vertically
integrated, you're one of the most
vertically integrated companies in the
world. You guys go from not only seed to
sale, but you grow your own that you
sell at your own dispensaries. Plus
you're also moving into GMP
international export. Yeah. So how is
that going? Well look look we're in
Holland and we also have been in Holland
and there we are very very limited. You
know since 2002 I'm not able to go to
one grow room. If I'm being caught in a
grow room and take away all our license
so we can never control our menu. So
some sometime people [ __ ] about our
menu. Some stuff is not the best because
Yeah. But we are depending on a very
illegal market. You get caught with a
little grow room, you go straight four
years to prison. Yeah. No discussion. So
it's very very difficult. So our dream
was to be vertically integrated
somewhere where we can really show all
our skills. Like we make great seeds.
Yeah. But yeah, if you cannot show the
flower, it's really bad, you know. Mhm.
So in Thailand, we have the option now.
We grow polyweed or glass wheat. We call
it premium glass. We grow indoor wheat.
We grow even GMP wheat. We grow outdoor
and from all those products we can make
dry sift, we can make rosen, we can make
bubble hash. So basically from one
variety you have five different things
which is really really nice. And now in
in our six dispensaries that we have
five in Bangkok and one in Kosamu people
can come there and they can have the
whole experience. You want to have
Rosen, you want to have this, you want
to have that, it's all there. So that
was part of our dream, you know, to to
have that vertically integrated to the
max and we are in northeast Thailand.
You can probably compare the climate a
little bit to North Kell, you know, end
of the season, we get our humidity in
the glass houses down to 35% which is
great. Sure. You know, the night and the
day temperature is great, especially
between August and March. So we can make
there a great product. So the next step
to us which was always our step is to
make sure that your mom and my mom can
have it in a pharmacy in a country where
you cannot have it recreational where
you have to go on the street like
England, Germany a little bit,
Australia. Yeah. So probably somewhere
next year we will have our product on
the shelves there for a very reasonable
price. So there you can obtain our great
lemon orange or full gas or super
lemonades or nuri cake or king's kush.
So yeah, that's the vertically
integrated grid dream. But then 3.0 cuz
now it's also GMP and we can make sure
it's on the shelves and we are ourselves
GMP. It's not like that somebody else
has to do the back door or the front
door where it's GMP packed and whatever,
you know, we do that in our own house.
So that's great. So this is the the next
and actually final step of my dream to
be like in different countries, you
know, like like a normal business. Yeah.
like just it's pharma technically but
it's still weed you know it's a great
product and we can make sure that your
grandmother and my grandmother and
whoever can obtain that that product in
a safe way for a very reasonable price
well it's beautiful because it's
somewhere between pharma and a you know
I feel like it's not an absolute pharma
product but it's not an absolute egg
product either it's somewhere in the
middle is yeah look technically it's
totally egg because we grow egg you know
it's a glass also it's indoor you know
it's only the GMP part so basically post
harvest you know the packaging right you
know it's just just to re just to
understand you know haiko and I do the
recreational part he has to do that part
just the SOPs is one me 40 paper oh yeah
paperwork yeah paper all the cgmp
paperwork so it's horrible EUGMP is wild
yeah and we are German EUGMP you know so
that's the highest standard in the world
because you have American GMP you have
Dutch GMP You have Israelian GMP, you
have Thai GMP, but the German one is the
one most recognized. So also the audit
happens from Germany. So the group flies
in and audits our factory and and then
from there we can So we are now 80
months in the process. So we just
started there in 2022. We did a huge
pheno hunt, probably the biggest ever
with 147,000 plants. Yeah. And we can
speak a little bit about that later. And
from there on uh I think mid of next
year we will be in the shelves in
Australia and in the UK or Germany.
Let's see how it goes. Pretty amazing.
Yeah, it's it's a dream. It's really a
dream. I still cannot believe it. So we
don't speak too much about it, you know,
because we want to see it happening, you
know. I don't like to think talk about
things that didn't happen yet. Sure. But
yeah, everybody sees on us on the radar
and yeah, we can't hide it anymore.
We've actually 20 to 23. We opened the
first club June 23. Sean, the first year
me and Dus were like with our captain,
you know, in the airport, you know,
people seeing us, what are you guys
doing here? You know, right? Because we
want to have this little advantage
because we are refitting the factory
that we took over in the north and
adding the GMP part. So now, yeah, you
know, now we're out in the opening and
people are seeing it, you know. So we
came out with it and it's happening.
Nice. Yeah. Yeah. Really impressive. So,
I wanted to go through some of the pheno
hunt stuff. So, we went through 560
different plants or we went through a
part of 560 different plants. 420. 420.
Exactly. What the [ __ ] It's 420. Yeah.
Talk about Jesus. Is that on purpose or
is that That one's just magic, right?
That's just magic. I I have a sense for
it. So, this is the first time smoking
this this uh cross. Which one is this?
This is our drips. Oh, I like that one.
It's the one I picked. Yeah.
What cross is that?
Extremely special.
I feel like there's several
different uh expressions within the
Progyny. Out of all the seeds we popped,
there there's I wouldn't say there's
super consistency, but there is with
with uh there's maybe four or five
different phenotypes that really stand
out in this one. in that. Yeah, in that
one. And I think that's one of them for
sure. So, we have to do a little bit
more selection on them. Yeah, I think
there could be more selection. I mean,
this one's really good. The one that we
picked, I feel like that was the one
that had the best nose and the best
structure. How many seeds you had out of
this one? We we popped uh 40 of those.
So, we have 40 different five fenos in
there. Yeah. And this is the one pheno.
I think that's But see within that that
there's a couple different ones that
like that's the nose, there's there's
the nose and then there's the structure
and then finding them. Cross those two
again. Exactly.
Exactly. The bud structure is nice.
Yeah.
It's not completely closed as far as the
bracks or completely open. It's It's got
good structure. Mhm.
I think the flavor is nice. That's
garlic in it. I'm really liking the
flush that we use on this, too. How many
What do you flush? 10 days. We flush
eight days in cocoa. So, seven or eight
days. And it eight was perfect this
time. Well, yeah. It's typical. And it's
tough with a pheno hunt because you have
stuff that finishes at different times,
right? So we have stuff that pull at day
53 and then we have stuff by hand. No,
all the plants. All is Yeah, we hand
water our entire flush. Yeah, we we hand
water our entire growth. That's crazy. I
know. That's a little crazy. I like
irrigation except for the flush. I feel
like we basically want to run it through
each plant and we do we just do once a
day cuz we do pulse feeding normally
with cocoa. Uh so we multiple times a
day. We we feed like 16 times a day. Um
and you feed 16 times a day. 16 times a
day. Holy [ __ ] That's like every 50 40
minutes or what? 50 minutes. I think
every 50 minutes we're feeding on this
on this one. Anyway, we we've
experimented. So what we do is we do
trials here. I mean we're a re research
and development facility. So we'll try
different things to get optimal results.
And I feel like we got pretty good
results with this. And then with the
flush we hand water and we make sure to
get it flushed through. And and it's too
thick to run through the lines anyway.
There's so much molasses in it that you
could never get that through your drip
system. No, not through the irrigation
at all. It's going to clog up then.
Yeah. But flavor-wise, I think
what it's smooth. I expected a little
bit more of the flavor from the smell. I
had have to say. Yeah. I feel like
you're right. It could be even coming
down here. It's not quite as turppy as
the flower. No. Yeah.
But that's why we're phen hunting. So
looking for those winners. Yeah. So in
Thailand you guys are doing huge pheno
heads. How do you go through that many
plants? Obviously you can't smoke every
single one of them. No.
So um we have
32 flowering uh flowering glass
houses. Everyone fits 1550 plants.
So, um, we try to limit it to one or two
varieties. Yeah. So, we put out 1,500
kind of 1500 plants. So, once 1500 seeds
Yeah.
So, that makes it already a little bit
easier, you know. Mhm. So, from there
on, we pull out the 10 best, grow them
another time, and then also grow them
indoor. Yeah. And then we keep five.
Nice. Yeah. So because we saw in the
past that sometimes in the let's say
third or fourth crop some hermy pops up
suddenly. Yeah that can happen that your
first two crops nothing happened. Yeah
it's fine. And then sexual stability and
whatever that
her different time of the year maybe
it's more hot in the room I don't know
what but something happens and sometimes
that hap doesn't happen a lot but it
happens sometimes. Yeah. And then also
for sharing clones, you know, we give
number three or number four away,
whatever. Yeah. And number one or two we
keep in our library, you know, and then
number one, we make the weed for the
dispensary, right? So that's kind kind
of how we work. And then also with the
number one or two or three depend on the
whatever we kept it for, we do the
breeding, you know. Mhm. Or we cross
them two or we self one as one, you
know. It depends a lot on many things.
Yeah. But that's kind of how we work. We
would try to put a minimum of 200 seeds
out. Yeah. But preferable,500.
Yeah. For me, it's it's how well I know
the line. If there's stuff where I know
I'm looking for something specific that
I know I can find it in 50 or 40. Sure.
You know, and then also I'm working in
numbers. I'm limited with the amount of
space that I have to. So, my model's a
little bit different and I might I might
pop 10 of something and not find
anything that's worth revisiting. But
sometimes I'll just pop 10 to see if
it's even worth exploring more cuz some
of these crosses that we're making it's
like they have a lot of recessive traits
and you're looking for the recessive
traits and sometimes even within the
progeny you don't get any expression of
really what you're looking for. So no
but yeah but you understand America much
better than me. But that's also a little
bit the the the the bad luck you guys
have that you're limited to space. No.
And you see that with all the breeders
and most of the grows are spreadsheet
grows here in America. Yeah. So you have
to turn over whatever 60 grams of heat
otherwise the investors get really
angry. So you don't have any options and
you know also in in egg technically find
something new like salad and corn they
do 10,000 seats you know. Oh yeah. So
but they don't have near the diversity
that we have in cannabis. No that's
true. No but that even says we should
even put more. Yeah. That makes it more
difficult. You know what I mean? Like
find something new. Yeah. I mean it's so
tough to find something new and you know
we were going through a lot of stuff
where we we kept saying oh man this
reminds me of this or this reminds me of
this stuff that's you know 20 years old.
So you know we had the purple crosses
and then even with the RS11 crosses it
has this interesting structure that
reminds me of the Calio or some of these
old orange varieties. Yeah. But it was
nice to see at Turbami in the weekend
also that a lot of the hazes are back.
You know that was the best thing ever.
That
was I've never seen hazes in California.
Five guys came to me with three of them
with Penos Silver has one with Hawaiian
snow. Where do we grow this from? Yeah.
I don't know Hawaiian snow. I thought
hey [ __ ] you know your thing. Yeah.
That's that's funny to hear that. So we
progressed in a lot of ways in
California and this is a lot of the guys
were coming from Humboldt and Menesino
from the hills, right? So like those
guys are coming down with these
equatorial and sativa crosses hazes
yesterdaying on the ego clash. There
were a lot of those guys even more. Even
more I'm sure. The thing is that
everything has to be six seven weeks.
Yeah. Where really good weed is 10 11
weeks. Yeah. You know those kind of
varieties. You know there's so many
amazing I agree. There's so many amazing
stuff. Dave from Budelera that had the
the pearls that was at Turban. He's on
the podcast recently, but he only does
longer flowering varieties. And he's
breeding for effect, right? At the end
of the day, more so than anything, he's
breeding for the effect. And the effect
of those is so different than the stuff
that, you know, 7 weeks. Mhm. Yeah. The
stuff that's Yeah. We saw the Dr.
Greenspoon like uh strain. Oh, yeah. It
was a pheno different pheno of that. I
think that that is even longer, right?
You know, he's like one of the few guys
that that wants to grow that. Actually,
not a lot of people have very
attractive. It's spreadsheets. Yeah,
it's people are under scrutiny of Wall
Street guys. They have this big
facility. There's 17 owners and they
demand 6, seven, 70 g in 7 weeks, right?
Six crops, whatever. You know, this is
this is the main problem which kills the
industry. You know, I think anyway
listed companies kill the industry,
right? You know, I'm I I I I don't see
any really good things coming out of
there. If you look at Canada 2008 into
20 2024 and as you know we were partners
with Canopy you know how many money got
blown up a lot
six years Canada how many money went
into stock market how many hundreds of
millions big money
770 billion Canadian dollars wow which
let's say 500 US 500 billion roughly 500
500 billion just evaporated
and people losing two 300 million per
quarter. Yeah. How in the hell is this
possible, guys? Well, they were just
talking about Jay-Z and his brand, how
it lost a whole bunch of He was in our
shop last year and told him say, "This
is not the way to do things, bro." Yeah.
Get a guy like me.
Yeah. There's no passion for cannabis
though in the No, they're not into
craft. They don't understand the craft
model. And so, you know, I we both have
experience in as far as you had
Heineken. I have Logan. I used to work
with Logan. And they created a craft
product from the beginning with the
intention to scale and to the scale to
the point where they sold it to Heineken
for a billion dollars. Half a billion
originally and then 880 million. Yeah.
880 million. We were involved a little
bit. Our friend did the deal. Y and then
it came in the newspapers in Holland and
then Heinek and CO said, "Oh, we didn't
know it was CBD brand." Oh, really? You
pay $1 billion, you don't know your
[ __ ] bro. You should [ __ ] resign
immediately then. No. Totally. Yeah.
They they know the high five, man. That
was such a joke, bro. That was crazy.
Oh, by by the way, I think Lanita is a
great brand. I really like that beer.
It's one of my favorite IPAs to drink.
Great people. They did a [ __ ] great
job. And then Heineken, it was just a
bunch of idiots because And that is the
corporate thing that is against us, you
know, because let me You want to hear a
really funny thing? I'm not going to say
it was Heineken. Yeah. Yeah. So, let's
say it was a very big Dutch beer brewer,
one of the biggest. There's a few of
them. And um suddenly in 989 one of the
reasons we had to start the cannabis
retailers association. Yeah. In
parliament questions were asked about
the mix of alcohol and cannabis in our
shops. You remember we had so we had
five dispensaries in Amsterdam. Yeah.
With alcohol 20%. It was only 14
Amsterdam. So we had 20% of the license
in the country. And suddenly in
parliament Christian parties were
popping up. Uh yeah, we want to discuss
this. Poly drugs use. What the [ __ ]
Poly drugs use. So multiple drugs. Yeah.
Cannabis and alcohol. Yeah. This is a
really bad thing. We call it
crossfading. But yeah, that's make a
long story short, this started in 2000
and we lost everything in 2007. Yeah. It
turned out really great for us. I'm not
going to go into details. Sure. Cuz we
were making much more money when the
alcohol was out. So with no we were
panicking and then it was much better in
the end of the day for us. Yeah. And
later in 2016 or 17 I was on a party.
Yeah. And one of the main guys from this
brewery came to me and he said, "Aran,
we figured out that in a dispensary
there's 70% less consuming of
alcohol. So the only way to drink
healthy way alcohol is to also smoke."
Because if you're with your friends, you
drink eight or 10 beers and you have a
great night. Yeah. If you smoke one
joint, you're only going to drink three.
Correct. So, it is the best combination
in the world. It's the opposite what the
Christian parties made us do in Holland.
Ben, a really good idea. It's for me,
it's only good if I smoke before I
drink. If I'm really if I've been
drinking and then you smoke, it's all
bad. But as long as you do it first,
it's the best way to do both. Didn't did
the alcohol use go less than than uh the
marijuana use increased and o over
alcohol use I think in in America
definitely definitely in America so far
well I remember already when I was with
a party six seven years ago that I
walked into parties there was no alcohol
there was one guy drinking a bottle of
red wine and everybody was smoking and
there was a Nobel Prize winner there's a
professor from university you know the
diff it's changing but It's funny now
that the political party who is a
Christian party, so they have another
agenda. Yeah. And raising this in
parliament, making it happen that we
lose all our license. And then the end
of the day, it's a really bad decision
they made because it's much healthier to
drink and smoke at the same time. Right.
Which one is this?
Or double le This is our double lemon
cherry. This is the breeder. This is the
the one that
uh I really like. It's It's like a lemon
cherry gelato. It's a runt S1. Yeah. But
it yields It's a really good yielder and
it has really high turpps. And so that
combination that has the structure, it's
it's rare. Yeah. And it definitely
passes on the structure with the turpps
to a lot of Yeah. the things we breed it
to. And and uh if I can ask you, what
what are you looking for? You're looking
for more for more turpps or higher THC?
What do you look for also commercially?
We look for stuff I mean I think
commercial viability is super important
these days. Yeah. But at the end of the
day, I went back to the drawing board
after 420 when my friend died. He used
to only breed for a fact. He still is
totally right. If you're a craft brand
like and we are and you are, of course,
everything is high THC. People want 28
32. Yeah. But your 33 here in America is
not a real 33. I think maximum 25 is our
25. And our 23 sativas get you more high
than the 32 American couch lock one.
Right. you know because of the flavvenos
of the turpin profile there's there's a
reason to explain that but the sativas
that are early 20s are by far stone is
higher than than the 30s in America
effect is much stronger yeah longer
longer also
like hit you really hard and then you
come down and I I also find it much more
pleasant
you know it's it's less paranoia on the
end you know well and I think but a lot
of people in the states because they
haven't experienced sativas or really
good hazes. They think of the sativas as
the ones that make your heart beat out
of your chest that give you paranoia
that that's that's fentinyl. No. Yeah.
Well, no. I mean, but some of the hazes
you get some of the strong super strong
hazes. They will do that, but they're
not really strong. No, but you also have
that with strong indicas. Yeah. Yeah,
you do. Well, with strong ended because
they have this narcotic effect where you
just feel super tired or and you see
more people getting more slightly to the
paranoia side if you smoke too much of
that, you know? Right. You heard that
much more than with the sativas. Well,
then there's the feel-good weed, which
is what I like that no matter how much
you smoke it, you just feel really good.
And I think we So, so the guy that
passed away, his name was Dave Mesford.
He we did a podcast the week before he
passed and he was one of my good
friends, photographer. He gifted me a
seed collection, but he really was
breeding for effect, right, at the end
of the day. also flavor, but his
priority was how does it make you feel?
And he was, you know, he worked with
some Nigerian hazes,
some really wild stuff, you know, that
were pheno hunting that So, what was his
percentage of THC according to him?
What's the range that Oh, he was more
into the mild THC like 15 to 22. I would
say 15 to Yeah. 20 maybe even 15 to 20
to 20. Yeah, that range. But like that,
I think that's the best range for a
perfect workout and and a a turpin
profile, right? Cuz the higher you get,
the more tur the turbs get more
complicated to have this really nice uh
uh Yeah. And flavor, you know, flavor.
Yeah. Yeah. There's a trade-off. The
flavor gets not better, you know. Mhm. I
don't know how to explain that. Well, I
think there's a trade-off. So, the
higher the canabonoids get, there's only
so much room on the plant for for
chemical compounds, right? So when
you're looking at it like that then the
turppines a lot of times are less. It's
very rare that you have something that
tests in the 30s like truly tests in the
30s that has super high turppins. Yeah.
So so so tell me now this perception
here like
if we we both chefs yeah in the past and
we love to cook together. We did that
many times. How is it possible that
everybody is smoking this hydro weed
even the cocoa weed which we're smoking
now? Cuz I only grow organic. I try to
grow on soil. Yeah. Mostly on soil.
Yeah. If we go to a restaurant and we
would get organic food, we would never
come back. You and me, right? The
tomatoes taste like water. The cucumber
doesn't taste nice. The salad is not
good. Here in North California, you have
great food. It's all organic. Yeah. And
then you go to dispensary and all those
big guys, they're all growing rockolar
and cocoa. Why Why is everybody smoking
that? Because it's ridiculous. Well,
it's because of the way it looks. So
people have gone away for the bag
appeal, right? They don't give a [ __ ]
They're about the taste. Well, I think
it's it's something that we have to
reintroduce to the people unfortunately
that there's a lot of new smokers and so
they don't know the difference. So
they're they're educated on cannabis by
Instagram and social media and the hype.
And so that it's so important that your
stuff looks good on Instagram, right?
And that's what I love about the
pre-rolls and the hand rolls like what
we have right here, you know, because
then you don't have to look at it. you
smoke it if you can. I would love to be
able to have a product where people
didn't care what it looked like. I could
give them that and they trusted my brand
so much that they bought it and they
were like, "That's amazing. I don't even
care what the flower looks like." Yeah.
Cuz at the end of the day, it's all
about effect and flavor. Like those two
things are so important. But social
media has gone in this direction where I
think there's a there's a good side to
social media, a bad side. But definitely
with the cannabis, it's like about how
it looks, right? So it has to look a
certain way. But then there's things
like Oreos that have no turpps.
whatsoever. They look amazing and it's
nothing I would ever want to smoke and
there's a lot of stuff like that. But
back to your point about the hydro, I
feel like if you're going in rockwool,
you can grow okay stuff. There's the
guys that are doing it the best, they
grow okay. That's exactly what you say,
okay stuff, but it's not special. Yeah.
Well, sometimes the genetics, they work
okay for that. They work good for that,
right? But I would say cocoa is the
happy medium because you get the yield
and the consistency. Okay. Now, okay,
let's say we agree on that. Mhm. Next
next issue. Yeah. Is it healthy?
I don't know. I feel like smoking soil
is better on my lungs, but that's just
But
this is better in your lungs. It's a
non-chemical if you use organics. Even
if you put a mineral through soil, you
know, then you get away with. But the
real liquid chemicals that American
fertilizer companies throw on the
[ __ ] hydro. Yeah. and we are all oh
we're all so green we're all marijuana
we're all cannabis we're all smoking
this what's going on I don't think it's
a good thing but we won't know for you
can argue about yeah okay this and that
but this is again spreadsheets guys this
is the same people yeah that made
America and Europe obese yeah and
killing us with the wrong nutrients
well but and all those kids are going
with the baggie oh this is great bag
appeal is fantastic yeah the bag appeal
and hydro is fantastic Yeah, bet. But
now they're smoking a chemical turping
their weed, too. You've seen that they
had the turpp pouches next to us. That
was real. Those were real cannabis
turpps. But there are the fake turpps
where they have uh nonannabis turpps and
they're adding that. What are you doing,
bro? But that's just like McDonald's,
right? So, but that's nothing I enjoy. I
think unfortunately there's something
for everybody. No, but it's like testing
in America. You know, you're selling a
product is 35% but they're spraying THCA
on it and that's it. And then they send
it to the testing facility. You remember
in the beginning you guys had here with
it was a bit of a hype but you had the
PGR nugs, you know
very Yeah. Yeah. And then at some point
everybody does they're away from PGR.
But still it's illegal. It's illegal in
California. PGRs are now Yeah. But it
doesn't mean they don't use it, right?
Yeah. Cuz you still have it. It's still
around. But and uh but but but people
still want those really tight nugs, you
know, even after they know it's illegal
and it's bad for you. Well, I think PGRs
help people get bigger yields and that's
why they want them. But it's nothing.
It's not only PGRs that are a problem. I
don't know what else is in those
nutrients. But look, um, this coughing
disease. Yeah. You heard about it? This
this really bad coughing and puking.
It's puking what everybody has. I don't
know the name. What's the name of it?
Uh, I can't think of it right off the
top of my head, but it's the one with
the cannabis that basically makes you
sick and you make makes you want to
throw and really sick. Yeah. Yeah. So,
and my son-in-law Mhm. and my son have
it by huge coincidence. So we did
extensive test the last three years. So
my son-in-law have it a long time. He's
rushed into hospital a few times. Yeah.
And there we find the medicine that
stops the puking in half an hour. Yeah.
But the puke doesn't stop. You still
have the dry heaves or whatever. And you
hear you hear this really funny puke
where you know when people have nothing
in in them anymore, this high tone puke,
right? And we had to save him last year
in Rolling Loud in the middle of night.
Had to rush him to the hospital because
we didn't have the medicine with us and
we were smoking it all day. He got the
attack.
And he already figured out when he
smokes Dutch grown weed, he doesn't have
it. And when he smokes Kali weed with
hydro, he gets it. Huh. My son now
exactly the same. Interesting. So I
catch him one night puking. Yeah. He's
18. And I heard a sound and I say, "Hey,
you have the same as ego, man." So, we
went to the hospital, got the medicine,
gone. Yeah. And he was smoking kiwi.
Interesting. So, I don't know what's
going on there, but there is there is a
there is I So, we have the cure for this
because I saw some people talking in the
press. It's quite new this this this
puking disease. Mhm. And uh I know the
cure and I think I also think it has
it's related to kaliweed. You think to
the salts there must be something in the
nutrients. But you you have a nutrient
company too with your powder feeding. In
fact you are the innovator of powder
feeding to a degree. I'm sure they had
it in big a before you guys had it. But
you really kind of reintroduced it to
the cannabis market and now a lot of
companies have followed suit. Well, I we
started it 10 years ago and it's not our
core business, but uh I felt that all
the nutrients we're doing these big
liquid stuff. Yeah. Was going in the
wrong direction and I knew it was
possible, you know, but I was good
friends with Lario always general
hydroponic arian not possible. We tried
everything. Can't have a one component,
you know. Yeah. Okay. So, we kept
working and working and working until we
figured it out. No. So, I think the
organic one we have is the best one in
the world with the soil and and then we
have, of course, also the mineral line,
but we made it for a very reasonable
price. Yeah. And very easy access.
People love it, you know, because you
mix it through the soil and you walk
away. Well, you have a buffer in there
and everything. Yeah, of course. So of
and with of course with the salts with
the minerals you add uh if the water is
not good you add some calcium you know
and with a booster and stuff like that
but it's still one component you know
and it's very easy to to use but it's a
very fair product you know everybody who
starts it doesn't go away from it
anymore well and low carbon footprint I
think that's the big takeaway for a lot
of places like the Caribbean I think
it's super important to not transport
extra water to a place like the
Caribbean look You remember Jamie Oliver
going to the schools in England showing
the kids? You remember that thing? You
remember with the kid with McNuggets how
he did that? So I took the whole bloody
chicken, put it in a [ __ ] blender and
all that [ __ ] and kids were freaking
out. Yeah. So that's what you're eating.
They all stopped. Yeah. I think if you
can like go to a big grow and show them
like real soil and the grandmother is
there how she make a real pasta with a
good brand with real tomatoes from
outside, you know, tastes so much
better. Mhm. Or you show them the indoor
with the hydro with all these chemicals
and that goes through your lungs. This
is the reality. Totally. You know, and
for me, I want to smoke this really nice
indoor. And if you look now, I wish I
could do a large scale living soil
because I see all my little friends.
Yeah. With their closet grows doing the
living farmers out there for [ __ ]
tastes amazing. Yeah. You know, all the
stuff we've had in the last 3 days, you
know, four days. All living soil, bro.
[ __ ] worms and everything. It tastes
amazing. That's what you want to eat and
that's what you want to smoke. I would
already be scared to smoke every day all
this hydro, you know, cuz I would think
I'm going to get sick at one day. Right.
Well, so my next question for you would
be from hydro to indoor grows. Where do
you see the future of cultivation?
Because I know you believe in the
greenhouse model being Dutch and also
doing your thing in in Thailand. Do you
see the hybrid model as being the future
for the industry especially in the
United States? Well, it depends a lot in
what country we are for the climate.
Sure. Because you know if you're going
to need if you're in North Canada and
you have to heat up that glass house,
you're going to lose a lot of
electricity costs. Yeah. It also depends
on your electricity bill which country
are like in North Europe it's 25 cents
and in Argentina it's 5 cents. Yeah. So
already that you know is is what are you
going to do? I think for both is
something well for all say something to
say. I think outdoor wheat is great for
attraction. If you can do that why
should you not grow outdoor? Mhm.
Nobody's going to see the flower and you
have a great turpin profile. Yeah.
Especially here in North Kell where you
probably have the best climate in the
world, you know, like where I'm in North
Thailand. But then you have the glass
house which could be hybrid. Like my
glass houses have no light because I'm
on the equator. Yeah. So I don't even I
don't need light depth. You don't have
any assistance. I only have uh three big
exhaust fans blowing in and three big X
fan blowing out and one in the middle to
help out, you know. Yeah. And I have
great sun when you don't need to
dehumidify or humidify. No, because
between October and March, I'll be under
50. Yeah. So, I'm fine, you know. And
then you have, of course, the indoor.
Sure. You know, you could be in very
complicated areas like in north Canada.
Yeah. Or in Patagonia in the south of
the planet or wherever and you need a
lot of electricity, but there's no other
way, you know, right? In some areas you
can't grow. So and then you of course
you have the GMP story right like where
it gets technically difficult is glass
house of course is less stable than
indoor
so for us is to finetune that we are the
first in the world to go through that
process you know can we do that you know
because every crop you can imagine is a
little bit different for sure because
sometimes we have 7 weeks of sun but
sometimes we have five and a when the
light intensity changes throughout the
year clouds and this means your profile
changes a little bit. Now we have a
leverage of 20% in a GMP. Wow. So you
know if it's 20 it can be 18 but you
can't go to 17 because then the batch is
disregarded you know. Yeah. And then
also time of the year you have like in
Thailand you have a few seasons right?
Like in Europe we have four seasons you
have four seasons here too I assume.
Autumn. So if you have four seasons in a
glass house and you have supplemental
light. Yeah. But the third profile will
be different because of the sunlight,
you know. Sure. So, how far can you play
with that? And how far Oh, with spectrum
tuning now, I mean, I think there's new
possibilities, but yeah, it's still
you're still going to get a different
chemical profile because there's so many
micro variables that change. Uh, you
know, but your best bet is with a Venlo
or with these glass green houses. Yeah.
But then it's also our duty as as a or
as a community, right, to make sure that
we have certain kind of leverage in the
GMP. Sure. where we all accept that you
know the turpins this time of the year
are a little bit less than the other
time of year but it still qualifies as a
medicine. Yeah. And the only time this
comes into a you know it can be a major
issue is with cheotyping when you're
looking for that exact chemical profile
for like drug discovery or for medicine
but they can do a lot of stuff with
extraction as well. So I think Israel
has gone through a lot of you know of
that over the past like 15 years. Steady
Murray, I talked to him a couple times
and trying to get him on the podcast,
but uh you know the drug discovery and
stuff they're doing over there and
trying to keep the chemical profile the
same in green houses or even just in the
same environment because the plant can
change over time. And what's your
thoughts on Israel as far let's let's
not talk about
Well, I was there two years ago. I was
invited by a few different factories.
Um but for me personally and for our
company, long story short, we will never
go back. Yeah. No, we do not agree on
their policy. I think it's too harsh for
us. Yeah. And that's that's, you know,
like it's just a very complicated
country. Very complicated. They have a
different vision than most of other
people. And for me, it's a no-go. So,
what other countries do you guys have on
the horizon that you guys are thinking
about? Well, we're going to shoot a few
movies in a few very interesting
countries. Yeah. We never look what I
can say a little bit but for security
reasons we don't say where we go cuz
some countries are very illegal. So uh
we go in as a National Geographic team
with cameras and we're going to shoot
some whatever deer or bird you know
right we play that game sometimes. It
depends a little bit where it was you
know Russia.
[Laughter]
It is close to Russia. Nice. That's
good. There's going to be on horses. Oh
wow. I can't say where. That sounds
exciting. It's very exciting. So, that
one is uh that one is on the radar and
there's three more on the radar. I want
to speed it up the process. I've been
already fooling around with a camera,
you know, with with my camera guy to do
quicker things like 5 days things, but I
really like to make a documentary, you
know. Yeah. And that a documentary cost
time and a lot of money. Yeah. So it
cost you know
preparing preferably going the season
before to really see how it is. Yeah.
And then come back the season after or
have really good fixes in the country
which we mostly have because the
surprise is also really nice which what
we used to do with vice you know. So
like really surprisingly going to a
country where you don't know what's
going to happen and and everything and
everything happens. Yeah. Luckily in my
case, I always have a laptop with me
with my movies on because people can be
very skeptical. Mhm. But one way or the
other, they love to be in the film.
Yeah. Suddenly, I don't know, you know,
and of course there's always a few
exceptions. We protect everybody. You
can see my Swaziland movie. People are
all blurred in their faces so nobody can
see that or I do the interview from
behind, you know, so they speak this way
and I'm sitting there, you know, it
depends a little bit on situation. We we
learned a lot. I changed my group. Now
again, I have a new group. I have all
the camera guys from the rappers in
Holland. So, we're trying something new.
Turned out really nice in Taiwan. Um,
different angles and whatever. But there
was quite easy because it was a legal
country. But for example, the first time
we had a prank's uncle who won the film
festival of Venice as a camera guy.
Yeah. And he came with the big boom, you
know, in Africa. People freaking out,
bro. Yeah. Yeah. That didn't work, you
know. They said the boom is out, you
know, do whatever with mics and stuff.
Luckily, the cameras got much better,
you know, and what totally changed
everything is the drones. Yeah,
especially with marijuana. Oh, I bet.
You see, you see the South African one
we making that river. So, we did 100ks
and this was amazing. You know, the
South African one. So, I called this uh
I want to do South Africa cuz this is an
area where um besides the political
thing we're talking about, we also
helped a lot of communities in this
world and we can tell one is trans guy.
Yeah, there's millions of plants growing
from us. That's only full gas. Yeah,
actually times sherbet grows amazing
there. Franco's kids were born there in
the early 2000 when we worked there. And
the trans guy was the poorest country in
the world. One of the three like Sudan,
you know. Yeah. 60%
PBC, 40% HIV. Wow. And we were sleeping
in the tents with these people, you
know. It was quite tricky there, you
know, growing a lot of seeds. So well
make a long story short 20 years later I
said listen I need want to make that
movie there because also the American
helicopters the South African pilots
would teach like what they do in
Colombia spraying over the fields
spraying on the people oh wow very bad
so the people run to a big
river the helicopters it's very steep so
the helicopters cannot reach that you
know so they moved all there and start
growing and I know that story and it was
2021 and we're all quite bored with
doing all our shops in Amsterdam and I
wanted to do a movie. It was everything
was impossible. But one way or the other
through a friend of mine who's still a
friend of us, but he said, "Listen, call
this guy in Joberg. He's got a rafting
company. Maybe he wants to do it cuz we
had to do 100ks of rafting on a river
that has never been rafted before."
Yeah. And this is not two guys in a
raft. With big rafts with 300 kilo of of
of supply on the raft, 10 rafts. Yeah.
We have four actors, supporting boats,
chef, you know, the whole lot. Yeah. So,
I called a guy and he said, "Aron, I've
never been on a river. You guys are not
professional rafters. I can't take the
risk. People going to die." Blah, blah,
blah. You know, right? So, we kept
talking and at one point I was talking
again, but you know, like, you know, we
are quite cool guys, you know, we can
handle a problem, you know. Yeah. And we
start talking. I showed him my movies a
little bit more, you know. You know, we
train hard, we're very fit. You know, he
said, "Okay, Arian, would you are you
willing to sign a non-liable, how do you
say that?" Waiver waiver.
Yeah. I said, "Yeah, of course. No
problem, bro." He said, "I'm going not
going to lie to you. If you pay me, you
will also save my company because it was
corona." Oh, he was losing his money.
So, make a long story short. I said,
"Listen, I do all these things under one
condition. I want to have the best food
in the world on the trip this time."
Yeah. Cuz his wife was a chef and I knew
that. Oh, wow. So I said, "Okay, let's
do it." I'll make a long story short, we
went there and the first day was 12
hours in this canoe in his raft. And
then we came and then on the side of the
river on the islands, we put tents up.
Yeah. So we sleep in tents, you know, we
do barbecue. We went 8 days on that
river. We did uh 200ks. Amazing. From
the mountains, cold water. Yeah. To the
where the ocean starts. You go any
rapids or anything like that? Yeah.
Yeah. Many rapids. You can see them in
the movie. Oh Yeah, we went upside down
a few times. But where are we talking
about the drone? Yeah, that's why I'm
explaining this situation. And there we
and I said, "Listen guys, I want two
drones with us, you know, and and but
yeah, this and that." But he did um
Oscar winning movie with Mel Street that
was made in South Africa. He was a drone
pilot. Wow. Some Oscar movie. Maybe it
was not Merryill Street, but one of
those, you know, Gorillas in the Mist or
one of those. Well, anyway, he was a
drone pilot. He said, "Aran, I can do
it." I said, "We're going to do the
river raft in Cambridge and there's
drone there and then you go over the
raft and then you see the fields on the
side, right? That is a million dollar
shot." No, he said, "Let's do it." And
it turned out perfectly, you know, and
that we did in 21, you know, with the
drones. Wow. So there the perception of
making the uh film changing, you know,
also like not anymore with all these big
things, you know, like it's not
necessary, you know, you can make as
much and we have the 360 and the GoPros,
you know. Yeah. A lot. They're really
great. Yeah. Still sometimes a challenge
to get all the equipment in all the
drones and stuff. The drones is an
issue. Yeah. Yeah. So, I'd love to talk
about Franco for a minute if if you if
that's okay. But yeah, so my book was
dedicated to Franco and he was one of my
friends, but he was your best friend.
Yeah. And as far as his legacy, uh, you
want to talk about his legacy a little
bit? I know there's the Francoha
Foundation and I mean all the videos you
do. Yeah. Well, I started working with
Franco early 2000. So, we were 15 years
together. It was amazing guy. He was
really crazy. And I think in
2001, we got the first license in the
world, medical license. This was in Nwag
with an American guy called James
Burton. I don't know if you know the
story. We him is in the newspapers, but
of course, it was my place. Mhm. But no,
we were not allowed to say that because
the first medical marijuana license was
very legal to be affiliated to a coffee
shop guy. Yeah. So we financed
everything and then he was working from
99 to 2001 in my coffee shop and Vatlau
plant the little one. You remember
upstairs I was living and at one point
my wife said I said I need more growers.
I need more growers. He said go speak to
this Italian guy that's working in a
vatlo planter two years. He's very
passionate. I think he would love to
grow for us. So I go there, you know, he
just finished his hotel school in
Lelayw. I said, "It's my dream to work
for you. It's my dream," he said. So I
took him and then we start growing on a
small scale in Amsterdam. We were
growing, but he I put him in the sea
tents, you know, like the small two,
three light things, you know. Right.
Right. And suddenly James Burton came
who was already supplying me. He said,
"I can get a license for medical
marijuana." What? Didn't know it was
existing. No. Said, "Yeah, but we need a
guy in and we have to put a lot of
money." Blah, blah, blah. And I don't
know how it went, but Franco became that
guy. He said, "Listen, he's still
showing the pictures. We still have the
pictures, everything." He said, "Listen,
I have something really crazy now." And
you are the guy going to do you want to
do it? Of course, I'm going to do it.
So, you're going to be three years in a
glass house. It's 50° C inside, which is
130, 140. Yeah. in the summer and we're
going to grow medical weed and we're
going to sell it to patients. So that's
how the whole thing started. Wow. So I
teach him all the growing and how to do
everything, you know, and then in
2005 he became such a character with me
and in my shops and speaking the
language and he's like a real street
kid. He's a little bit like my son, you
know, like ducks. Yeah. Yeah. Friends
with, you know, Yeah. with the
underground very quickly. uh said and I
thought I was already working on a
strain hunter movie after King of King
of Cannibis was only in the shops with
the with the cannabis weapon [ __ ] and
that's okay now I need to go to the
jungle I can't do this on my own yeah I
needed and I learned from Hager you need
the characters cuz high times had all
these characters you remember the rock
and theas and the hager and so I said
okay this guy speaks five lang he spoke
five languages was big advantage I said
let's take him yeah it was a was a great
hit of course you And because he did
special forces now. Oh yeah. And he was
he was four years special forces in
Italy. That that tiger or line thing he
had here. Yeah. So he was What's the
special forces in America? You have two
of them. Navy Seals. He was with them.
Yeah. But then the
Italian version. The Italian version.
Probably the crazy Italian version.
Yeah. Yeah. So yeah. So we had great fun
you know and um he had a little bit the
same set mind as me you know go to more
difficult countries so that's how we
also winded up in uh in Africa in 2004
we didn't started in 2000 we started
there I think in 2005 and then went
Congo of course and that's where in the
beginning India and there and then Congo
the disaster happened you know Franco
was wild and uh I sent him a few times
to the doctor when he came back and he
said he went but He didn't. And the
doctors told him he didn't have malaria.
And they made that conclusion because he
didn't have fever. But in his family,
people get sick without fever, which is
a quite rare disease. Yeah. And the
doctor ignored that, you know, and then
Yeah. Then [ __ ] happened. Yeah. But he
was a great guy. I had [ __ ] so much
fun with that guy, bro. He loved weed
more than anybody there. Oh, yeah. Yeah.
He was I remember the first night the
first night I took in South Africa and
he was quite young and uh and where we
were I think I have footage of that
somewhere there's where is crocodiles
there's bull shark and there's black
mamba is the three worst things you can
have right exactly there where Simon
lives oh wow so we are there with Simon
Simon all time longtime friend of mine
of course too y and um we sleep together
in one tent you know it's probably 11
12:00 and we have to get up at 4 You
know, and you work in Africa, you shoot
movie, you have the golden hour between
6:00 and 8:00. So 4:30, you get out, you
know, you eat something quickly, a
coffee, and you go shoot. No. Right.
Right. But it's we're late and we only
can sleep 2 hours. It's like
1:00 and um and we're lying and the
[ __ ] puts the light on in the
tent. This little light. So put it off,
man. We go [ __ ] sleep now. Yeah. No,
no, no, no. I have to do something. So
what you have to do? Yeah. I have to I
have to roll two joints. Two joints,
bro. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. You don't
understand. One if I wake up at 3 and
one for a piss and the other one if I
wake up at
4:30 and I'm lying there. Okay. I'm not
going to argue with this guy cuz he's
mad. Yeah. Right. Yeah. So he walks out
also out of the
tent and he starts rolling the joints
there and he come back in the tent and
he closes he closes the put the lights
off 10 minutes later but he leaves the
door open. I
said you left the door open. Yeah, no
problem. I said the [ __ ] mother black
mama come in because it's nice and humid
in this room. We're [ __ ] tomorrow
morning. Yeah. Later we find like 20 in
our grow rooms. Yeah. You have never
seen a guy jump so quickly out of his
bed to close the curtain of the tent. I
had I had so many but we had serious
situations too you know with shooting
with soldiers and you know we went for
it you know getting chased in Colombia
bro we were in we were in I can't say on
this this part I can't say you know the
part. Yeah. Yeah. So we were in a rough
part. We were the only people white
people going in and out of that area you
know for many years. Wild times. Funny
thing. Yeah. You've had some adventures.
Yeah. Great ones. Yeah. But he was a
great guy. Unfortunately, he left.
Yeah. What to do?
Yeah. Some of the some of the best ones
die young. Well, we buried our partner
just uh two months ago in Thailand. I
buried my best friend seven years ago. I
buried five friends in the last seven
years. Yeah. But this happen when you
get a little bit older and when you are
in Yeah. I don't know, you know. Yeah. I
feel like you you get to 40 and then you
start losing friends and it just gets be
more and more every year. Yeah. Yeah. I
guess that's why we got to appreciate
each moment. I think it's the most
healthy thing, you know, appreciate
life. Yeah. Make sure your children
always come home. Yeah. The moment you
know your children don't come home
anymore, then you did something wrong.
Yeah. Now my parents come home. It's
great. Yeah. So, if you had one piece of
advice for younger people coming into
this
industry, I'm going to ask both of you
guys this question from your own
perspectives, but what would that one
piece of advice be? Well, the the
industry is quite broad, you know. Yeah.
If you want to become a grower, I would
be a organic grower. let it be normal
organic or living soil and make a craft
brand like I think then you have the
most chance in a few and and have a
dispensary like that you are vertically
integrated so you can build up your own
community I think that's our strong
point and in Amsterdam and in
Thailand this is us this is where we
grow and this you can smoke you like it
or you don't like it but you know and
there's nothing in the middle there
right that's how it should be you know
basically like you see really good
Michelin star restaurants. They have
their own grow. Yeah, they have their
own farms. Their own farms. They go pick
up their [ __ ] in the morning and they
make the best food in the night. Even
the ones that don't have contracts with
specific farms and farmers also people
that grow specific animals. How
successful any Michelin star restaurant
is successful in the world. Yeah. Cuz
there's a limited amount. And why are
they successful? Because they grow the
best organic food. And the only ones
that are healthy. Yeah. And that's why I
think my advice would be grow organic.
Yeah. Or at least on soil. Yeah. You
know, make a good product and see how
close you can stay to your customer by
selling it in your own dispensary, you
know. Or make sure it's marketed well
and then put on the shelf in another
dispensary really well, you know. Mhm.
But I think I think if you are small,
then you don't depend on investors, you
know, you can do your own thing. I think
that's the best advice I can give you.
Yeah. And then what would your one piece
of advice be for younger people coming
in the industry? uh well for any
industry or just in life basically cuz I
have two older sons as well going into
life you know and uh going into doing
some kind of business you know where
they can make a living is it's so cliche
but I'll explain a bit more is doing
what you really like they say you don't
work a day in your life if you do what
you love right but the people see for
for us is the whole package because
there's such a misconception sometimes
because what the people see on our
Instagram we get so many comments of of
course of almost everybody. I love your
life. I would, you know, like your life
is so fantastic. But that people have no
idea that for every nice thing you see
on Instagram, this is a message. There's
at least 10 or 20 huge big [ __ ]
problems that we have to solve and the
[ __ ] that we get every day and from from
a lot of different sides, right? But
because we have the whole thing and and
and uh we have these really nice things,
the whole package, I wouldn't do
anything different, you know? And um
that's what I said to my son too. He's
in business. He said, "Dad, I have to
solve so much [ __ ] every day." I said,
"Yeah, basically that's your job now."
You know, you're just a problem solver.
And at the end of the day, you have to
switch off and do nice things and make
it worth your while. Basically, that's
that's what I would advise. Do what you
love, but do it with a big passion, you
know. Nice. Yeah.
Yeah. Passion is you need passion.
Passion is everything. If you don't have
a passion, then nothing's going to
happen, you So, circling back to Franco,
passion for the sacred plant. That
hashtag that I used to use originally
and that I still use today. I started
with Franco like we were smoking and
that came out of that. Yeah. Passion for
the sacred plant. Oh, yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
That started with Franco a long time
ago. And then Full Gas is your one. So,
yeah. That that that'll live on those
Full Gas. That's, you know, he always
liked that, you know. So, that's why we
named it after him. And he always used
Full Gas. Yeah. Yeah. He never had he
never he didn't had a break, right?
Yeah. When he met Unfortunately, that's
also why he passed away, you know. It's
the reality of life, you know, like he
was too wild, you know. That's his life
motto was full gas, you know. We go for
all the for the for the hard stuff, for
the for the good stuff, we go full I
think if he never I think if he would
not be with me, he would have died like
three times earlier already. Wow. We had
some crazy. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. But yeah,
you know, sometimes you have to follow a
little bit the middle way, you know.
Yeah, some countries are quite
dangerous, you know. For me, for me that
day that uh because I don't know if a
lot of people know, but he first was a
few days in coma, right? So on the day
that
uh my my youngest kid was born, that was
the end of December uh 30 December. I
walk out of the hospital with my my
newborn baby and I call him up to tell
him the good news. Then Franco just went
into hospital uh in coma. So I traveled
to Barcelona also and a couple of days
later he died. So it was very bizarre
period always and basically it's also a
metaphor for life. No. Yeah. You know
somebody realize how prestige life is,
you know. Yeah. You know and then you
wonder, you know, why are the
politicians killing our own population?
Why are we smoking hydro? Yeah. Did it
go so far that we just [ __ ] up
everything now? And yes, because we are
all killing our own population with the
wrong foods, you know, all the seed oils
we are eating which are super bad for
your body, you know. Yeah. And all these
chemicals that are using, you know, and
like the overtone of sugar and gallons,
especially sugar, that's worse. That's
the worst one. Fuel for tumors and bad
cells, right? You know, it's the worst
product on this world. You know, that's
the it's it's worse than the drugs.
There's more people got killed through
sugar than through all the diseases and
all the wars together. Do the math on
that. Yeah. So more people got killed.
Yeah. From sugar than from anything
else. Yeah. It's wild. And we just let
it all happen. Yeah. Look at the
supermarkets. How how supermarkets are
made. So you walk into a supermarket,
which is a genius idea, but it's not a
good idea. Mhm. So you come in, you see
only beautiful colors. Yeah. Of the
vegetables and the fruits to make you
happy, right? But it stimulates your
eye. Then you walk and you smell the
bread. And then you wind up at the till
with your little kids with a candy or an
eye height, you know, the right one for
them, you know, and then you fill up
everything and you take only the [ __ ]
with you, right? Yeah. Bread is for
nothing. Candy is for nothing, you know.
Yeah. It's the bad calories.
Well, we have to fight the stigma though
because the association of the of the
retailers association, we got a letter
from one of the biggest sugar candy
companies, Haribo, don't know if you
know. Oh, yeah. And they and some
companies were making fake edibles, you
know, with their logo and stuff. So, in
the in the letter it it mentioned, of
course, we don't want to be associated
with, you know, this is cannabis. This
is a drug. So if you look at that
letter, you think but the problem in our
industry and that's why we're all
fighting is 99% of all people agree with
Haribo. Yeah. You know, and they don't
see the ridiculousness of that letter
saying, you know, cannabis is bad and
you know, we have to protect our deer
product. And also, you know, our own
communities are not within our groups.
We are not protected well enough. You
know, look in America, everybody's suing
each other in cannabis lawsuits every
lawsuits all over. I don't know anything
about those. I know only about lawyers.
We definitely don't want to support the
lawyers. We never had They're the only
ones that win in lawsuits. We can say
proudly we have avoided maybe 15
lawsuits that we all settled outside the
room really quickly with idiots mostly
with staff and stupid things. Yeah, we
always try to stay away. This is a big
problem of our industry, you know. And
then on the top of that all the listed
companies come in and blow the money of
the investors pop some mom's money you
know right and that is why also we are
not strong enough as like the NHL will
be or the baseball league or the ice
hockey league or whatever you know cuz
they're smarter together and all have
one goal. Yeah. In our industry there's
a few people who want to eat the rest.
Yeah. You know like the big corpse that
are coming in. Yeah. And then there's a
small crafted grow that's been pushed
out. You see the guys in North Cal
everywhere that's the worst. In humble
is the worst, you know. So, and that's
why there's also not enough unity in our
world. Yeah. To make that we are
stronger and we can fight as a big
group, you know, cuz there's so many
diversity and issues and politics and
whatever, you know, right? Whereas in
pharma and in sugar, they protect each
other really well. For sure. Well, those
are really long established industries,
too. So, I think we'll get there.
Hopefully in the right direction. Yeah.
Yeah. I think I think in a lot of ways
we are going in the right direction. I
just think some of this takes a lot of
time to stabilize. Let's finish positive
this podcast. Yeah. Exactly. Exactly.
You know, so if people are interested in
finding out more about greenhouse seeds,
strain hunter, powder feeding, uh where
can they Thailand. They're going to
Thailand. Where can they go? Thailand,
your next holiday destination, guys. I
think Thailand, let me say one more
thing because I would like to end really
positive about Thailand. I've been in
103 countries I've lived in. This is
number 10. Me and Yo, we have a really
nice house together in Sukumit. You're
most welcome to come there one day.
Yeah. Um, beaches, restaurants,
logistics, zero crime, great schools.
One of the best, maybe the best country.
If you look everything together, it's
maybe the best country in the world.
Wow. You can eat a great soup on the
street for $2. Even 150 him and me and
like a proper soup. There's a line of
people waiting. Yeah. Amazing. So that
is your next holiday destination.
Literally my next holiday destination is
one of them. For sure. And you can fly
to the islands everything with your bag
full with weed. Absolutely no problem.
You can open for security and then you
know and there you can smoke all our
products as they should be like full
sunrown indoor glass house premium
indoor whatever you want to call it. So
yeah, I think I would like to invite
everybody in this world to come and see
Thailand, you know, especially of out of
our industry like there's not enough
space for everybody because it's it's
already a little bit like Cali. There's
too many coffee shops, there's too many
growers. So there will be a natural way
that these things all will settle, you
know. Yeah. And uh but for for tourist
people, for people who'd like to have a
nice holiday, this is one of the best
countries in the world to come. Nice. So
Greenhouse Seedco at Instagram. Uh,
Arian Strainhunter at Instagram. Yo
greenhouse greenhouse at Instagram. And
then you guys also have greenhouse seed
company.com. Greenhouse Seeds. Yeah,
greenhouse seeds.com. That's our main
that's our main main main portal. Yeah.
Our main portal. You have greenhouse
brands. And then we have greenhouse
Amsterdam. We do a lot of clothing.
We're getting more and more into that
cuz my kids are getting into that. Yeah.
And of course we do collabs now with PA
which is one of the famous brands in
Holland. Nice. And with um Propaganda,
which is from No, the Italian rapper.
You probably saw some pictures from us
there. Oh, yeah. So, we're doing collabs
now with clothing. That's It's nice.
It's just a side thing, you know, right?
And uh that's also one of the Instagram
pages. Nice. Well, thank you guys so
much for coming on the show. I look
forward to filming with you guys in
Thailand. Uh yeah, let's get some
dinner. Yeah, let's get Maybe we do a
straight hunter one day together. We
should do a straight. I'd love We take
some American guys with us. Yeah, you
know, take to some funny country, maybe
like Peru or Bolivia or whatever. Sure.
I think up north you can make a really
nice and I think also one here up north
in Humboldt and Menoscina we could make
a nice one. There's some good ones.
Yeah, for sure. We go there August,
September, you know. Yeah, Humble's
amazing. Oregon going through. Yeah.
Just go visit 30 guys. Yeah. And shoot
some nice cont for the land race
genetics from Oregon. Yeah. Yeah. Good
stuff. Well, thank you guys so much.
You're welcome. Thank you very much.
Thanks.
Thank you guys for watching. Please like
and subscribe down below.