[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James loud
podcast today our special guest is
cannabis Chris from SF Cana how you
doing Chris what's up James how you
doing player fantastic man glad to have
you on the show we've been talking about
it for a while and uh it finally
happened we're I'm out here I'm I
appreciate you bringing me out to your
[ __ ] coffee table you know what I'm
saying you got a bunch of joints here
you got the James loud in a background
man people know what time it is yeah we
got a little project today that we're
going to do uh we're going to do a
little Game Show game show feel to the
show and today we're gonna we're gonna
taste test five different things okay
two of them do not have SF can of flour
in them the rest of them do so we're
going to test your skills we're going to
go through some flavors we're going to
talk about things that make joints good
and Joints bad and all kinds of fun
stuff so we we're going to do a lot of
smoking in the next uh hour hey I came
to the right place so yeah but let's
start off tell me a little bit about
yourself how you got started in the
industry you've been here a while been
here a while predominantly under the
table with it and uh pushing a brand and
we stuck it out through the whole covid
[ __ ] and I mean you know long long story
short is we're still here we're still
pumping we got a lot of [ __ ] in store
for y'all in the future um this year
we're making big strides to uh get back
some amazing flavors on the shelf and uh
you know share it with the world yeah so
you guys have been known for your top
shelf flower ever since you for a long
time yeah ever since Berner called me up
and said godamn you got some quality
flour man you know what I'm saying yeah
it's interesting and you guys are from
San Francisco you guys have made your
mark with cookies genetics like the
actual cookies with all the flavors but
really pushing flavor right so like TP
chasing yeah we got a good team that
definitely does some turp
chasing yeah got a lot of dope tpps on
our on our menu you know what I'm saying
from the Cherry guavas to the zerberts
we've been pushing I feel like you know
we perfected zerbert like we might not
have been the creators of zerbert but we
perfected the [ __ ] zerbert like
we blew that [ __ ] up to where I seen a
whole lot of movement in zerbert other
people were like pushing their zerbert
and you know it was a big thing and then
the more of the Cherry came out and uh
you know we killed it with our Lemon
Cherry lotos and just how we we got a
phenomenal [ __ ] cultivation
team so shout out to the cultivators and
it's easy to push a product when you got
dope the dope [ __ ] you know what I mean
yeah you don't have to sell it it sells
itself itself feel me bag of Peel
nose Ash all the [ __ ] it checks the
boxes you know man James Loud come on
baby yeah so you have uh a lot of stuff
going on besides that stuff Canada too
you got lyd in the city and you got kind
of other project yeah so we got some
events popping off litty in the city is
one of the cult followings which is a
[ __ ] session on steroids you know
what I'm saying yeah so your event in
Las Vegas was Next Level it was good it
was good you had a whole hotel the
bottom floor of the hotel was uh
completely decked out and it it was
amazing how many people did you have
show up it was incredible that one was
probably like 12 to 15 I think
throughout the night it was a pretty
dope turnout considering was like a old
school session on steroids yeah like you
know we have the [ __ ] entertainment
the cars out front I mean we spent a lot
on that event to make it happen because
Vegas will break your [ __ ] Pockets
honestly it came out Doper than we
expected you know first time we had the
oil wrestling
installment definitely not the last
time yeah it was good it was good a lot
of good flour Vegas you know I don't
know a lot of I guess people brought in
a lot of flour before but now I think
there's good weed everywhere Vegas is no
exception yeah it's definitely been
getting better we had a lot of wave
makers from Cali pull up as we usually
do we bring the [ __ ] wave with us
right and then uh we like to extend our
you know Olive Branch to the locals out
there that do their own [ __ ] to make
their own waves in Nevada and Vegas and
uh we had a lot of that so they brought
in a bunch of people as well it was dope
it was [ __ ] lit the whole night keep
it 100 I lost my voice I was supposed to
go on stage and do a rap and
uh just yelling over the oil wrestling
and everything else I was doing man yeah
you had so much going on so much going
on there was a lot to learn from that
[ __ ] event like let's not stack too
much on my own plate when I got to do
when I got to host an event and run an
event correcting my mistakes from the
last event that nobody would notice but
we knew we noticed it sensory overload
but that's what Vegas is anyway it's
like sensory overload so you guys just
took that Vegas brought it up a notch it
was great it was dope and I was at
Champs like few days ago or
this last Champs and uh it was it was
[ __ ] popping Champs is only getting
better I don't know about MJ biscon but
Champs is only getting better and shout
out to my boy Nick for getting me in
there with the media pass people are
walking around smoking trapping trapping
thca you know what I'm saying thca is
the big thing right now we'll see how
long that lasts yeah you know shout out
to the ztics crew shout out to Marty
Grimes and Marty mlan everybody that was
out there Adam ill all the [ __ ]
that I would usually see we got to get
Marty on the show with the missile yep
Marty needs to get on the show with the
missile man I'm going to make that
happen Marty I'm going to make that
happen well let's dive into some of
these
flavors let's start out with this first
one it's a little bit smaller but I
figure we could talk about what what we
going talk drip we can talk about White
Ash and we can talk about
flavor and we can talk about the refire
because to me those are all important
when it comes to smoking MH lighting it
up up properly these were rolled by
professional joint roller to Instagram
big shout
out who's that which one professional
joint roller professional joint okay I
didn't hear yeah yeah his Instagram is
professional joint roll he's been on the
show okay shout out to homie he does a
good job you gave me I think if it's the
same guy you've given me a couple of
these to smoke
um and they were rolling they were
rolled superb man cannabis Chris
approved you
dig shout out to the bartender oh yeah I
make some mean drinks got some fresh
squeezed orange juice oh [ __ ] we doing
it
right what do you think so what what's
SF Cana or not SF
Canon flavor's good though flavor's good
so off the spark of
it not too crazy but it's there yeah
it's like a nine out of
10 turp
wise I like it I like it I'd say uh oh
wa are we rating it or we just [ __ ]
we we can rate them you know this is
more so I mean yeah what do you think
out of 10 out of 10 we'll go out of 10
tur wiise probably a good solid nine yep
I mean what more do you want and the
[ __ ] joint if y'all could smoke this
with us man the flavor is amazing it's
got that long finish tap that one last
time oh yeah well you have your own show
you have your own podcast I you know I
do I'm slow with it because it's just me
as you as you got a team here it's just
me running that [ __ ] yeah so it's a
little bit more difficult for me to put
together a [ __ ] Team every time and
get the [ __ ] popping but yeah we we
we're gonna get back up and rolling yeah
we have a good team our team is amazing
these guys crush it they they do a lot
of work and if have put forth the effort
and I feel like the show's a pretty good
show yeah it is I've seen it and uh like
I said I had to um come on this
[ __ ] and strep my [ __ ] you know
what I mean yeah I got so many different
[ __ ] relationships now it's like how
the hell do I not bring somebody on and
talk some [ __ ] and taste some flavors
right
seriously number two we're up to number
two number
two so question for you when it comes to
Quality
what do you think are the most important
things with flour with flour pulling it
right knowing when the time is right to
pull it you know get it down cheering it
some dumbass important you know
obviously I've seen people with amazing
flour that [ __ ] up the Cure so many
times so many times I feel like that's
one of the biggest problems out there is
people don't know how to cure it right
is it is and these dudes are pretty I
mean when we first started like some of
our team was like amazing grown great
amazing weed and we just weren't curing
it the right way and you got to get over
that little hurdle and sometimes it
takes you know a little wind out your
sales because you're thinking your [ __ ]
is looking amazing but yo you got to get
it cured right but we've corrected that
are you talking about like on the
surface
wise yeah yeah like so if you're looking
at flowers I'm looking at tree gotta got
it gotta be sugary it got to have the
some amazing candy or whatever I'm
looking for at the time right now what's
the number one checkbox is that candy
smell I believe yeah I believe flavor
yeah nose looks you know Ash color Oil
ring yeah Oil ring is an interesting one
it used to not be a qualifier but and
same thing with white ash and I wasn't
sold on the White Ash until the last
like year and a little bit I'm still I
leaning into it like it's a serious
thing like white ash means
quity weed and all that buto let me tell
you there's been multiple times where
the joint is rolled a certain way and
it's just not burning a certain way yeah
and it's not as white as you would
probably expect it or want it to be
purple purple doesn't get his white ash
typically and someone else will come and
bar it up real
nice and the [ __ ] will just burn
perfectly and have [ __ ] white ash you
know what I mean so I mean there's a lot
of
variables into making this [ __ ] burn
right for sure but I believe yeah for
the most part if you got some [ __ ]
dumbass white assh you're doing
something right yeah and I mean I think
that certain certain genetics certain
flavors they don't get white ash just
part of it I think or or people struggle
to get it or every once in a while it
comes out perfect same thing like
Skittles it doesn't always drip but when
it does it's like [ __ ] I really like
Skittles you you're a big fan of
Skittles real
crushing with it yeah yeah no but uh SF
can been we've been
uh we've been killing it we you know our
Skittles our Skittles are winning it's
winning yeah we're getting good numbers
on our Skittles and moving a lot of them
yeah I'm person I'm
personally getting rid of a lot of the
[ __ ] yeah it's good and it it
checks the boxes it doesn't look like
your typical Skittles either I feel like
you know in fact there's a picture of it
breeding book You Dropped a book oh yeah
so you haven't seen my book tell me
about it dude so this SF Canon's in the
book come on man shout out to James for
holding it down yeah so we got a we got
a good book but look SF Canada zerberts
in there we got all kinds of good SF can
of flavors dope Canal Loops we did the
those Loops you guys feno hunted uh 100
seeds and got so much variation that's
right that's right tell them a little
bit about our partnership James
yeah so we do some we do some genetics
together we're feno you know I I'd say
that you guys did some feno hunting I'm
creating some genetics we're sharing
genetics uh yeah it's really exciting I
mean I think you guys grow the best
flower in California in my
opinion in in metric in the system one
of the big companies you guys grow the
best flow now there's other people that
grow good flour too I'm not going to
knock on them because I think there's
great flow on the
market I mean at scale SF can
has the best flower it's in California
not just San Francisco but recognize
that we got a case study on the Skittles
in my book come on man on Z there's some
Z that was grown by SF Cana and our
photographer Ben he did a great job
cannabis breeding James loud oh yeah I
need you know I need this signed bro you
know what I'm saying yeah yeah that's a
one kilo book I need a signed copy
baby hey the Art and Science of crafting
distinctive cultiv ours yeah so we're
excited the book just came online and uh
yeah I think it's a lot of fun it was a
big project really big project good man
it's a [ __ ] big book so looks like
you guys took your time and did it well
we did and we had the the best people we
working with the best people as far as
editing as far as layout and so many
people contributed so it's not just
about me I feel like this book has 20
other people that contributed something
to the book you know whether it's the
multiple photographers that we had the
graphic designers we had two different
graphic designers that helped out Daniel
from House of cultivar and our guy Mason
who's our Graphics guy and there's just
Dale Hunt wrote a chapter on on uh on
like basically on Law and on patenting
and on you know some amazing stuff and
we have so up some real game from that
[ __ ] right there oh yeah Matt
Schneider from apical biotech he wrote a
chapter on tissue tissue culture then we
have uh Reggie Gino from front rage
biosciences he wrote the yeah he he's
the dude so he was the guy at Steep Hill
back in the day uh we probably wouldn't
be here without Reggie so at least where
we're at you shout out to Reggie man
yeah so you're going to spanis too I
plan on being there yes yeah dude we got
a I'm working on this other versus this
versus event that go ties in with these
versus bags you know what I'm saying
yeah so tell us about it uh well these
versus bags are I always say are the
best way for Brands to collaborate cuz
you don't it doesn't take a 12- Monon
fenal hunt half a year and a half fenal
hunt whatever it is you can get on the
[ __ ] boards tomorrow just send me the
graphics and I'll pair you up with you
know if you don't already got a quote
unquote sparring partner or comp a
competitor you want to go against or a
brand a different brand right
um I'll pair you up with somebody you
know what I mean but it takes two Brands
to activate the bag it's a eth versus an
eighth TP vers TP uh your best [ __ ]
versus my best [ __ ] right here we got
turog Skittles versus SF Cana Cherry
guava and you just place a vote on the
back the QR code ones you like the best
quick public poll people know what time
it is I think we're still backhanding
turog um we got our foot on our necks
so
nice they would say different they would
say otherwise but I would say nah we
winning baby um but I'mma this into an
event this year nice five [ __ ] events
a year is it going to be like a cup
style event where somebody get it's
going to be a bracket nice and someone's
gonna get a [ __ ] belt I'm gonna start
pushing these belts right here yeah but
it's going to be a versus bag well it's
going to be a versus belt and it it'll
be uh it'll be
amazing [ __ ] though I did pretty sick
yeah I designed the whole [ __ ]
belt drew it up drew it up on paper yeah
sent it to my guy he lasered it out
clapped it on some leather nice yeah
that belt's been that belt has been
Making Waves baby big waves you you take
a picture with Mike Tyson in the belt uh
you know I took a picture of Mike Tyson
and Ric Flair with the belt but nice
tubes distribution been holding out on
my goddamn picture for over a year so oh
man what the [ __ ] man here try
this quick start of the oil
ring
yeah different different little perfume
is little harsh little harsh on there
come on man yeah that was different I
don't know if that was
sfk
H yeah so have you seen these new
pouches
that uh they're TP pouches you can buy
and they're they're cannabis derived
tpin and you can Infuse them like
sprinkle style but uh it's with natural
it's natural
style I have not yeah that's the new new
we got I've seen uh the humidity gel
packs that people throwing in there so I
got this cut of super silver haze ciss
you probably saw that from SF Cana Super
Silver Haze cap it was labeled Super
Silver Haze cap and it wasn't very super
silver his and it wasn't ciss the lab
that it was SSH I think they put it out
as SSH but uh you guys check that out so
that's
infused with the TPS it was uh that's
the candy gas he hold on you just said
it's a [ __ ] pouch uhuh that you
sprinkle on tree no you don't sprinkle
it on you put this pouch in your pound
okay right for four to six hours hours
or 24 hours or whatever you want to do
[ __ ] soak it up soaks it up it soaks
it right up and then you get it into the
into the joints which I think is uh now
is that sprayed I mean like is it sort
of like I mean it's comparable to spray
sprayed isn't real turp sprayed is like
I mean not always it could be I guess
but like these are cannabis derve tpin
there's an interesting story we're GNA
get the guy on the show that does them I
was like so but they're real cannabis
tping it's not like they're putting
orange or watermelon or any of these
okay you know these other tpin they're
putting actual uh TPS from flour TPS
from Cannabis flow
correct okay
so I don't know how I feel about that
yeah I mean because it's too scientific
for me and it's like comparable it's
really comparable to [ __ ] spray turps
you know what I mean well either way
it's it's not was grown in the garden
yeah either way it wasn't part of your
[ __ ] batch until you [ __ ] set this
little patch in your [ __ ] and it soaked
it up through the [ __ ] the first half
actually tastes pretty good of the joint
too like but then the second half it's
like you got them all rolled up look at
me I'm here about to light this [ __ ] too
yeah go ahead get the flavor it's real
interesting that is an SF can of product
minus the infused turps oh wow but uh
it's real interesting so the first I
mean you get to experience it I don't
even have to tell you this is amazing
all right let me try this [ __ ] you know
I got to try everything once but people
have beeny
weed for the long time you know what I
mean like if you say I would smoke
sprayed TPS sprayed tped weed you're out
of your mind but let me try some of this
soaked up TPS it's like TPS on
turps and I wasn't super impressed with
the turps on that flower so I figured
let's Infuse some and see what these
things do they're talking about real
cannabis turps it's
okay it's got a taste to it though for
there's a taste there is a taste that
it's
like I've tasted it before and I put the
joint out
immediately but we tried it I tasted it
it was wasn't hella bad but it's that
taste you know what I mean yeah yeah
that's sort of what I was going going
for like I'll yeah we'll go right here
take a couple of
rips
you it tastes
interesting I don't know doesn't taste
natural it doesn't taste natural though
no it doesn't I mean I think when you
get so used to having good flour that
anything that's like even the fake stuff
I don't want to smoke stuff that's that
[ __ ] that rubs up on you in a strip
club who's dancing for you and she rubs
her [ __ ] tits on your face and you're
like damn these tits are hard as [ __ ]
you know what I'm saying [ __ ] is fake
it's not natural fat ass is fake as [ __ ]
yeah I mean implants are turn reversed
the funny thing is is when you get past
the halfway point it still tastes like
that all the way down until it but like
you know how with Skittles Skittles
Taste like Skittles but it it tastes
like if you smoke a whole joint of
Skittles it gets more intense yeah going
down but it's real natural all the way
down this stuff is like you could
tell and maybe if you match the right
TPS with like let's say you put Skittles
TPS back on Skittles yeah that would be
cool that might be interesting it' be
worth trying you know but like when
you're taking two different flow maybe
and it you know and it's worth a [ __ ]
worth a try right but yeah maybe that's
the problem is that people are just
putting different TPS on other turpy
weed and there's this weird flavor
that's coming off it that people know
that are like hold on man this [ __ ] is
sprayed or you soak this [ __ ] up with a
little pouch that James La was telling
me about I'm always so it's it's funny
with different things like sprayed weed
or moon rocks or we we had you know what
is it the Snowballs now snow
I'm curious I'm always curious right
yeah but but besides being curious like
it's worth trying once and then it's
like no I don't know man I tried we us
to do every kind of dab we could
possibly do back in the day too yeah
shout out to snowballs I mean my boy
Zach and all them cast you know what I'm
saying yeah I mean it's we smoked the
whole Marty missile of the Snowballs oh
my God ly in Vegas Jesus and let me tell
you [ __ ] where dying
it wasn't bad weed I mean it was just
[ __ ] harsh you know the H snowballs
and [ __ ] right they used the thca
pattern they rolled the flower in it
yeah and make it stronger and you know
but there's a way for that so there I
mean you know whether you like it or you
don't like there's a lane for that like
AB it's all about being creative in this
industry like yeah I mean think about it
I put a bag next to another bag and
separated two AES in one bag and you
know it's not like rocket science or
anything like that is yo but it's
creative and it's kind of like the
Cannabis industry is so much room for
like creativity and growth you know what
I'm saying yeah so you can almost do
anything but make it creative and it
might work out but if you're spraying
your weed jump off a
cliff if you're spraying it with non
Canabis tpes yeah we still got one more
of these to roll or smoke all right and
then you're what are you rolling up over
there roll this [ __ ]
roll up this [ __ ] cream Leaf
guess what it's an SF Cana rolling tray
oh [ __ ] that's C I got one yeah those
are clean those are great they have the
little light on them and everything SF
can rolling tray
though it's been used and abused but
it's a good rolling
tray seems like it with the flower Mill
shout out to Brent flower Mill man yep
he makes a great product what do you
think the futures or the future of
events are I don't know a lot of people
are [ __ ] kind of had it with LA
events shout out to all the LA events so
I know there's a [ __ ] Bunch Every
week I'm just saying like what I've
heard is it's too much of the same event
going on yeah like there's not enough
thought that's why I guess lyy is and
not to blow not to blow my own horn I'm
just saying like we really try to come
with something different for ly that we
usually see at your you know your usual
events just like [ __ ]
oil wrestling and you know topless
rollers
and um you name
it it's about making it more of an
experience I like it yeah dope
experience I do like the bracket the
bracket events where they can have multi
bit of I I think that's pretty cool too
and I think that's only you're doing one
I think that that's why the versus [ __ ]
is going to work yeah and we might even
tie in uh tie in a local fighter and I
don't mean like anybody training I mean
like a Joe Schmo who
loves SF Cana who's like yeah I'll
[ __ ] go three rounds for SF can and
rep SF canana and we'll do like an open
registry I'll have all the brands that
are signing up do an open registry
because their deck will pay for their
[ __ ] fighter check this out
though and everybody that is number four
what number four all
right
good not bad not bad was right
here not bad you know what that is right
off
hand what is
it I might know but you might
know yeah so diving back into this
contest here yeah talk to me man look
this contest is going to be a bracket 16
brand [ __ ] bracket
contest five events throughout the year
look we got Skittles versus SF
Cana this was sort of like the Prototype
[ __ ] let's see if it's going to work
they threw us in High Time shout out to
John capetta do us in high times for
this [ __ ] nice created a dope Buzz um
I've seen other places try to emulate
this
[ __ ] not gonna happen because a it don't
got cannabis Chris on this [ __ ]
and B you don't got the [ __ ]
plug you know what I'm saying you got to
have a [ __ ] connections you got to
know the right people to make a wave you
dig what I'm saying so what's your
favorite 16 Brands 16 Brands 16
Brands going head-to-head bracket out
how many
events
five nice GNA be wild comes with a real
fight though with a real fight it comes
with a real fight
like part of your I'm going create a
deck for it people are going to [ __ ]
you know pay a premium because it's
going to come with a b c d of promotions
and all the [ __ ] that that you would pay
for with some exclusive [ __ ] yeah plus
you'll be able to sell your product for
$100 a
quarter you know what I'm saying and
[ __ ] that do vents events
throughout the year have no problem
selling that [ __ ] I know I was selling
them for 140 when they first dropped
crazy yeah but it's GNA come with a real
fight we'll have our SF Canon fighter
and ain't gonna be no Freddy big because
for Freddy got fighting experience we
can't do
yeah but he might [ __ ] give some
pointers to the person that's ready to
go [ __ ] three rounds for SF Cana
nice might be cannabis Chris I'm just
saying who
knows no I'm just playing uh but yeah
we're gonna have some real fights behind
the event Dragon House get Dragon House
involved get their cage it'll it'll be a
real ring yeah we're gonna have the
theatrics [ __ ] walking down to
the ring with the music playing in the
spotlights nice selling ringsize c's for
a premium but it comes with the bags
that you know of the [ __ ] and nice so
with our little game we're doing here
yeah we had five different joints that
was five right there was five yep what
do you well no there was four that we
smoked and then we smoked the fake one
with the fake tur okay so we did smoke
five joints but there's four here one of
these of these five was not SF Cana
absolutely
correct right here if you were to name
the strains from SF
can besides this
one would you guess Cher guava zerber
and
GX uh that was the the last one vice
versa mix the the gg gg that was a GG
number four which guava gas guava gas
okay not Gorilla Glue guava gas yeah
that was good that that came out nice it
burns that that burns white it's got a
nice Oil ring see I've been stuck in my
I've been stuck in my cherry guava and
zerber uh for the last few [ __ ]
months so I haven't been really on the
guava gas which is why I did
not even name guava gas
yeah otherwise I probably would have
been in my palette but yeah this one's
Cherry guava and this one's zerbert
yes absolutely and this ain't us so come
on come on man what can I say you feel
me put it there not bad piff that was
the piff it's cool it's you know it's
well it's just that it's just that but
it's not SF can it doesn't it doesn't
burn the same like that and you know
maybe grown a little bit better that's
cool it had it had a little taste but it
didn't seem like it burned too
well
no it's okay I do like the zerbert
though
yeah zerbert fire zert fire definitely
had a that's in this book come on man
know about it you feel
me yeah zerbert yeah your Z your zerbert
those are all good you guys crushing on
those the P5 come on man hey
yep I be telling
people we're smoking the best and I'll
smoking the rest it's going to be a
[ __ ] on my Tombstone nice
so let's talk genetics what are your
favorite genetics right now besides the
uh ones you just pointed out besides the
ones we just talked about zetopia oh
yeah it's incredible yeah zetopia is
good it's good flavor it's I feel like
it's new it's
different it's uh it's yeah it's got
good flavor got really good flavor and
it can get good color too but uh but
yeah flavor-wise I love it and an effect
too it's stronger than Skittles I feel
like Skittles has like the Z has a
ceiling somewhere around here and that
zetopia can go up a little further yeah
for sure I like that I like the um you
know the coffin candy runs that's been
popping out with the
pla yeah um I like I feel like the
zerial herps came out with like zerial
and [ __ ] like that yeah I had a zerios
there was a zerial milk yeah and there
zerial a popular name people love
Skittles can't go wrong yeah you know I
mean it's [ __ ] tested the [ __ ]
it's tested the [ __ ] uh it's still
here throughout all these years what am
I trying to say I'm high as [ __ ] see
after they smoking a bunch of [ __ ] I
think it was the spray turbs that really
threw me off here [ __ ] scramble my
[ __ ] um you know been around forever
those Skittles man yeah been through
lawsuits after lawsuits just got over
that whole wrigly [ __ ] yeah pretty wild
pretty wild they're still hounding them
about [ __ ] that other people [ __ ]
come out with and trying to associate
them with it and right look at this [ __ ]
the Z on there right skitt Skittles SP
yeah I mean [ __ ] well I thought it was
skittles is now Z formerly known as
Skittles or whatever it is it's original
Z the original Z
yeah good stuff though good genetics I
like the flavor
yeah yeah for sure for sure we done
[ __ ] made that [ __ ] pop off too in
our
cultivation yeah so when is greenweed
coming back green weed is coming back
it's already damn near back keep it real
good yeah that's that's my I I feel like
it's making a comeback it's not quite
there yet yeah but it's on the cusp get
some good ogs out there get some Sour
Diesel get some good flavor I mean
Skittles doesn't always have color
Skittles is amazing I mean that's the
top top shelf right now pretty much what
do you think a temperature of a good
cultivation flower room a flower room
yeah uh around 82 degrees around 82
degrees Yeah but it depends on like if
you're going for flower and it depends
on like nighttime temps and other things
like that you know so I think like your
grower he he gets it real cold and
crushes you guys have some of the most
purple flower too yeah he definitely
crushes crushes
I'm think no what I'm thinking is what
I'm thinking is like 82 you said yeah
yeah what point do you think it starts
turning color like a
65 it depends on the cultivar so some
cultivars start turning purple really
early on and other ones much later on
and some are right at the end and like
that but uh it's interesting what you
can do with getting getting purple flour
and how it's such a qualifier right now
as far as like it's worth more money to
have it purple if you had the same thing
it tasted better green and you had
better color and more bag appeel you
probably get more money for it right now
you know who's a green weed
Advocate Adam ill what Adam ill my boy
Adam ill man he's always looking for the
green weed he wants to be bring green
weed back yeah I get it but sometimes
you got to get a little color in there
man no we got to get Adam on the show
too it's I've known Adam since
2010 maybe hell yeah something like that
good guy solid individual man look you
got a book out is that gonna be a San
Francisco
[ __ ] best time seller what I don't
know we'll see the book is gonna go
where it's gonna go best time seller I
me San Francisco Times best seller yeah
I hope it's
uh you know I think it's a good book I
hope it does well I'm I feel like it
will do well I feel like I did good on
the book I made a good product I feel
like you know this book weighs a
kilo also one something pounds so it's
about a
kilo you throw that [ __ ] literally [ __ ]
someone up with it yeah that's what we
were talking about earlier oh you don't
like weed [ __ ] hit him with a book
hit him with a book put it in
pillowcase
[ __ ] you [ __ ] smacked the [ __ ] out
somebody in the pillowcase but it's got
that soft soft touch so it's like an
Apple box I really like that feel who uh
who decided that I mean when did you
decide you was going to come out with a
book so I've been working on this book
for five years uh and the last year like
since one year ago almost exactly yeah
I've been heavily focused on getting
this done it took a lot of time and
energy and and everything else and
patience and learning how to screw it up
but I wrote the book five times before I
wrote the final draft of it the final
not not the final final draft but my my
first draft that I gave to my new editor
which was five versions in so it was a
interesting process man a lot more
complicated than I ever would have
thought like WR WR writing a book what
this book took knowing now compared to
what I knew five years ago is a whole
different thing like I was like oh you
just write a book dude like you got good
information then you get someone to go
take the photos and that's done you know
in my head but really that's not it it's
way more in depth you gotta have a good
vision for it dude Angela Baka who did
the editing she basically helped
organize me she was up at 400 am and I
was up at 5: am working on the book for
the last
year um yeah we start we she started
working a little bit later but like she
would be she'd have questions every day
like do this this is needs needs to be
fixed or this needs to be Rewritten or
this needs to be this and
so
by five o'clock I'd be working on it and
I'd be done as quickly as I could
sometimes it' take me an hour sometimes
it take me four hours sometimes it' take
me four hours and then before but
typically in one day I'd do whatever she
needed me to do for that day right and
you know I don't think she she expected
me to do it in a day you know we got the
book done really fast it's rare that
people could work together and get a
book done in the short time that we have
so do you ever get Riders block I do
like [ __ ] what I'm going to put chapter
16 man yeah I talk about cold plunging
too much on my show so I'm not really
going to talk about it today but like
yeah that really got me talking about
cold plunging with a few of my guys I
was like bro this cold plunging [ __ ]
wave is hitting everybody everybody
wants to buy a [ __ ] I walk by some
Home Depot [ __ ] that wasn't even a cold
plunge it was just a metal tub and I was
like it was for gardening I was like
damn that could be my first cold plunge
yeah for sure I don't even I'mma tell
you something I'm not a cold type of guy
yeah I might have a [ __ ] full-blown
asthma attack if I can jump in a [ __ ]
Lake that's cold so the first time I did
cold plch I mean when I was a kid we did
cold we used to jump in ice water in
pools that were you know practically
frozen over after we went in the SAA we
jump in all that good stuff but like
what's your nationality I'm Finnish oh
yeah okay well yeah so so I'm big into
the C PL but but it's a whole different
story but yeah it g me you know I've got
a lot more mental Clarity from it that
what Happ and I do it pretty much every
well so I used to have brain fog pretty
bad last year and now the brain fog is
gone and I have knee pain that's doesn't
bother me for arthritis the real thing
some other [ __ ] and so I get good
benefit for me and it's not like I mean
I feel like maybe it's different for
everybody it's something everybody
should try to see if it works for them I
also don't get sick very often that's
[ __ ] nutty manate well shout out to
the cold plungers of the world ones that
are that seek Clarity from from smoking
too much weed dunking into some cold
[ __ ] water you know I mean slushy
temped oh yeah slushy temperature water
it's the best well you don't need coffee
and it creates this dopamine in your
system that is like equivalent of doing
cocaine oh [ __ ] for eight hours rather
than the 15 minutes you get from that
for eight hours you get this eight hour
increase it's like uh your dopamine
levels increase significantly for eight
hours 6 hours or something like
that all right well all I could say is
I'mma order one on Amazon [ __ ] it we
need to get a CO punch here so we can gu
test somebody all right we got the
shorts for you man here we go exactly we
got the James last
shorts that'd be hard hey that'd be
sick yeah our Lifestyle brand is loud
times the Lifestyle brand is loud times
yeah just like on the pre-rolls oh the
pre-roll we got the loud times brand we
got all kinds of stuff that's coming out
next year you got some [ __ ] James loud
staying
busy it's all about staying busy man
yeah you know I'm saying can you do it
or do you do it you know what I mean
it's all about yeah and then when you
get knocked down you got to stand back
up every time and the thing is is like
there's that Philosophy from jiujitsu is
like fall down seven stand up eight and
that that goes across the board I mean
you can apply that to everything we get
knocked down in life times are tough for
some people but you just got to get up
and keep fighting big
facts don't be a quitter so what do you
think the biggest problem with the
industry right now what do you think
people are missing the most that are in
the industry what are they missing to be
successful what what's your take on that
first let's ask you me I think quality I
think quality is missing the most I
think that quality has come up since
wreck in from where it was cuz initially
it was terrible and now it's gotten
better it still has a long ways to go
cuz you know I feel like well there's
only a hand handful of good cultivators
right so like at the end of the day
there's only so much good weed out there
like the one not even 1% but like the
0.1% the stuff that I like the stuff
that you like there's not a lot of that
on the market be great if there was
more uh or would there or would be I
don't know if there could be more
because it's like you you have the the
cream at the very top and it's like if
there's going to be more then prices
will probably go down you know yeah
maybe there should be less there should
be less there should be less yeah
because prices it'd be great if prices
went back up yeah we need prices up well
and prices haven't changed on the
streets or in the shops you know what I
mean like the problem with dropping
prices is now it always got to be that
price people don't know nothing about
fluctuation I think like okay if it's
dropped to 18 or
19 there's always going to be NorCal
Nemos
though
well nor Nemo's killing the game right
now killing shout out to [ __ ]
you know what he needs to write a book
on how he's doing that yeah feel me show
me the there's like magic spells
exclusive book signing where he gives
you the game right then and there it's
like
look here's a signature this [ __ ] is
certified game is in a book read it and
now you too could sell packs at [ __ ]
40 th000 a
pop well you know somebody's got to do
it I think it's amazing I think it's
great for the industry yeah no I mean
I'm not knocking it I'm just saying
like get it fit you know get it where
you fit in man yeah there's a place for
everybody killing it though we know you
know you like that [ __ ]
Skittles though from the SF Canada the
Nemo Skittles yeah it's fire so you grew
up in San Francisco yeah Sunset District
Sunset District Sunset boys shout out to
burner he just gave me a double little
shot I was
like shout out to Chris man Sunset boys
yeah so how was the Wii grown up when
did you start
smoking uh the weed growing up
was pretty [ __ ] good
considering San Francisco you in the Bay
Area so like I grew up in the bay I
didn't grew up in San Francisco but hey
I mean a my tolerance is
way [ __ ] smaller than it was right
now right so well it definitely was less
quality at C at some point early on when
I started smoking and then it only got
better and there was droughts when we
were younger all kinds of stuff there
was time where you couldn't get anything
there was definitely those once in a
while but um I knew cultivators from to
jump like yeah dude pulled back the
covers and was like the [ __ ] suitcase
on uh P fiction P fiction it was like
that I was like oh [ __ ] I heard the
angels I was like Hey tried to break off
a piece but it was like hella wet cuz I
didn't know [ __ ] about weed yeah he was
like whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa we
can't smoke that it's not ready I mean I
remember when we were younger when I was
younger there we would the weed was so
good from this one guy it was the Kim
bud and it was in grown in like lafette
at Walnut Creek Kim Kim K yep the Kim
Kim okay feel like it's and uh so Kim
bud
they would they would sell it to us
before it was even people we didn't give
a [ __ ] because it was so good we would
get it and it would still be wet so you
buy a 3.5 gram eth and it would shrink
down like you'd lose more than half a
gram right trying it out but this stuff
was phenomenal Kim Bud we had cat piss
back in the day the real cat piss uhhuh
they tasted like nothing else I've ever
seen right so cat piss you ever smoked
cat piss back in the day I have not
smoked cat oh yeah I smoked some cat
piss nice I'll smoke some cat piss
cool 20 years ago that cool that was my
favorite growing up that's what made me
like weed was cap his a ciss yeah You'
smoke it down to the roach like you know
the good weed we have now or whatever
but like you would smoke it down to the
roach and the next day you fire that
roach back up you smoke it again it
tastes like ciss tastes amazing and
ammonia and
skunk but yeah cheers man
cheers apprciate the uh we're drinking
on the show we're smoking on the show
we're doing all the good stuff what else
the [ __ ] next we got to eat some
mushrooms this is a hell of a show man
yeah tell you that I might be high as
[ __ ] but yo this hell of a show remember
Romulan oh yeah I remember Romulan
Jake's coming on the show here oh yeah
yeah Jake from Romulan genetics uh his
father contributed to uh creating the
Romulan back are they still pushing yeah
yeah doing good I mean he does great
work his photos are in my book as well
so romul genetics Jake from Romulan
crushing he's also an amazing
photographer yeah so the Jack herrer
right Jack herrer Jack back in the day
was amazing it was really good Jack
today isn't is I haven't seen the jack
that we had back in the day other than
one guy Brett from
terraform genetics did he terraform or
terraforma terraform genetics down in La
yeah precies he has a Jack that's like
old school funky super strong WR huge
[ __ ] buds he grows these huge green
buds I remember TR train wreck used to
get me so [ __ ] blasted that I would
always think it was in Indica because I
would just be high as [ __ ] train wreck
would [ __ ] you up yeah that was why it
was called train wreck too and the way
it grew it was all I mean pretty
wild yeah so chem dog I remember Kem dog
back in the day that was a good one we
had a Kem
dog off the
you know shout out to p man he's a good
dude yeah it's p gotta get you at the
litty baby The champelli Strain the the
champagne the real deal it would it had
crystals that would stick to the bag
like line to the bag good [ __ ] oh off
top yep definitely um a legendary
[ __ ] name in the in the industry yep
so Vietnam and Thailand Vietnam Thailand
amazing places to go with or without
your
girlfriend amazing yeah you ever been no
I still haven't been and I have so many
friends that are in Thailand right now
so many of my friends have been to
Thailand God everyone's talking about
Thailand we're doing Thailand later this
year probably yeah I mean live a little
bit you know I mean Go Thailand with a
bunch of your I do the European thing in
the South America so now we're going to
exploring as you know the thing is it
they got a it's a good thing to
experience cuzz it's a lot of [ __ ]
new sites new [ __ ] you know new
weather yeah good food tropical weather
yeah uh you land in Bangkok you could
tear up the city a little bit go to
different clubs nightlife is crazy in
Thailand yeah you know NTI is really
what a lot of people go out there to
experience go and [ __ ] all through
the night just partying and [ __ ] yeah
they got weed dispensaries out there now
now they got the weed dispensaries out
there you shout out to Josh yeah shout
out to Josh uh Strain Hunters they got
Strain Hunters Club out there Greenhouse
Strain Hunters those guys Crush Strain
Hunters yeah I'll be at the greenhouse
Strain Hunters Booth uh for spanis this
year right from nura right Josh from
nutura I think it is and Josh from
nutura yeah shout out to Josh from Nur
we show we'll cut that [ __ ] out we start
here be like hey shout out to Josh from
the turret because he got a lot of [ __ ]
popping in time land popping he's doing
good yeah yeah my buddy Al's out there
NorCal genetics you got some people out
there why oh man you should definitely
go out there yeah yeah I got a lot of
friends out there you'll have a great
time and then all my other friends have
already been and they're like dude why
haven't got to Thailand yet like no go
out to Thailand are you married
yeah perfect yeah perfect the bring the
wife bring her or don't bring her I mean
at the end of the day if it's a guy's
trip then it's a guy's trip but if
you're bringing her wife bring the wife
cuz yeah it's all fun and games
regardless like amazing [ __ ] visually
a stunning place to be you I mean and if
she likes to have fun at night bring her
out to the [ __ ] clubs and you guys
all tear up the city you guys are going
to Spain hopefully and then maybe we'll
make a trip into Amsterdam one of these
days oh yeah hit up on them coffee shops
yep I really I I enjoy Amsterdam it's
one of my favorite cities in the world
to visit people there are great I mean
my friends there are amazing mhm there's
a ton of them they're all good people
really yep no in Amsterdam I got my
friend s yeah he used to have like uh
the longest dreads ever N9 foot long
beard nice he is an OG in the industry
and created a bunch of good genetics I I
did one podcast with him a while back
we're gonna have to do one uh one of
these days over in Amsterdam killing it
killing it but yeah lots of good people
lots of good friends Amsterdam
Amsterdam good weed too there's good
weed there there's good hash the hash is
amazing yeah I love the hash I'm all
about
it I want to go to Amsterdam I think
someone needs to do another High Times
Cannabis Cup in
Amsterdam so they we need to bring a
lady in a city Amsterdam that' be dope
for sure we just lyd and Sin City maybe
we go to ATL ly and Magic City yeah you
try this train white Thorn Rose yet
white Thorn Rose I have not it won the
emerald cup it's really good yeah for
for bubble has when was Emerald Cup last
year Emerald cup where is it in Oakland
it's in Oakland oh my God you guys you
have to roll deep if you're on Cup this
year don't go solo yeah [ __ ] make sure
you got a group of at least 20 friends
suck your products your awards no
watches where the [ __ ] y'all thought you
was gonna throw this [ __ ] was be on me
probably by somewhere by the water
somewhere yeah I'm not
sure they did it at uh in Richmond last
night well they pulled it off in
Richmond Richmond's cool I like Richmond
on the water there mhm yeah was it the
craneway it's a good spot they've done
some cannabis cups High Times did some
events there that big spot nice spot
yeah yeah as long as it's not too windy
outside that's the only thing it's a
little windy but as long as oh you know
Emerald cup did that last year and it
was in May that's right yeah I was there
you were there yep we were there we have
photos together me and you yeah in
[Music]
Pelle yeah we got high that day I think
I SM smoked at least 20 joints that day
maybe more that was high as [ __ ] like I
was I was definitely there but who I
took photos with was oh that's right and
you had a uh your artist the regga
artist yeah Marlin I was with Marlin
that's right Marlin Asher crushing it
he's doing good what's up marlin man I'm
trying to get you on a beat on a track
let's make some music he do it he'll do
it yeah I mean he'll do it for sure let
stop playing no that Bob Marley movie is
out too I'm ready to go smoke some weed
and go to Bob Marley you should
definitely do that rent out of movie
theater too seriously where you can
smoke yeah shout out to Jay Kier Jay
Kier rented out of [ __ ] movie
theater and had everybody pull up dabs
were they taking dabs in the theater I
don't
know wouldn't I'm sure someone was if
it's a private showing I don't know why
not so oil wrestling yeah these [ __ ]
were Guillotine [ __ ] UFC choke
lock submitting each other crazy in oil
in oil [ __ ] were tapping
out yeah 200 [ __ ] including
girls were like oh [ __ ] is she taing out
oh [ __ ] going crazy it was tight nice
was popping if you weren't there you
missed out hemp and um hops are cousins
they're related yeah you can't cross
them together unfortunately but they're
related mhm you beer guy at all I don't
I mean I'll drink beer not nothing i' be
like oh this [ __ ] is good yeah so hops
you like hops I like the alcohol you
like the alcohol
yeah yeah I like hops I mean I like I
like Flavor in general I'm all about
trying to find new flavor experiences I
feel like there's so many out there
there's still stuff especially when you
get into subtleties the thing is is most
people you know there's all these
gelados and if you're an untrained
smoker it all tastes the same but as you
start tasting see like the different
gelato like you got the 33 compared to
the 41 yeah compared to the 45 compared
to the
47 what there was a 23 at one point I
think the gelados yeah there's 41 43s
[ __ ] it
yeah how many gelato there's like
there's a lot [ __ ] ton of gelato but to
the Unchained palette they all taste the
same no they're all G start tasting them
you're like okay this is different 33 is
way different than the 41 well yeah
that's why they I mean yeah like the you
know fenal hunting taste testing all
this [ __ ] they can't all be winners no
but to the untrained pallet and [ __ ]
ey it's like yeah oh this was that it
all tastes the same yeah it all tastes
the same you're like damn I slap the
[ __ ] out of you man you don't know what
I took to grow this one way better than
this [ __ ] [ __ ] right here yeah I mean
there's people that just want to get
high but the thing is once you introduce
somebody to really good flavor then
they're like oh that's what we supposed
to [ __ ] taste like yeah you got to
you know put them up on game and [ __ ]
yeah it's amazing when you smoke weed
with somebody that's older that hasn't
smoked stuff on that level and they do
it for the first time and they're it's
like a AA moment like ah like they
figure it out yeah trip uhhuh uhhuh
that's what it's supposed to be like
that's the good oh weed supposed to
taste good I see what's going on here
can taste like people tell me to stop
smoking Blunts and [ __ ] you know yeah
and after I backhand and [ __ ] out of
them I'm like I do smoke joints yeah
usually what do you think about hash
holes
you big hash hole guy I [ __ ] with hash
holes shout out to cgo you know what I'm
saying they're not harsh they're [ __ ]
they taste good and [ __ ] but it's like
sometimes me personally with hash
already inside some flower and [ __ ] like
that I got to put that [ __ ] out halfway
through yeah otherwise I'll just be
stupid I don't want to interact with
nobody yeah I'll be dumbass
high and these [ __ ] are doing
that [ __ ] 20
times with within [ __ ] the first two
three hours you know what I mean for
sure so yeah so the genetics of the
future man you see the OG and Bruno Rose
man shout out to Bruno Rose too man I
don't mean to cut you off yeah it's all
good but yeah so uh what' you say the
future the future what do you see the
future what are the future genetics are
people going to be going
for specific types of gelato still or
we are we going to go for you know
obviously we're getting gas back you
know gas I mean [ __ ] it's always been
there but it'd be if it made a real big
comeback what
abouto what oh god I hate
GMO i f did you go through a GMO phase
where you liked it and now you don't
like no I never really liked it I didn't
really like the smell I didn't really
like the
name and nothing against whoever grows
the GMO or came out with GMO yeah but
Kim D though Kem D was cool there's
people that did like it though yeah
Marlin Marlin dude he went through a
phase where it was like OG Kush OG Kush
knowing him and then all of a sudden it
was GMO and that's all he wanted was GMO
yeah because it's strong he likes to you
know he get you super ripped OG Kush is
always yeah a good one if you got that
popping let me uh twist me up on I think
we got some OG got some OG in here yeah
right here spark it man here go ahead
hey s dry hit that
one
nice who who's this from it is from
Brian at vital that is the last joint I
have of the strongest effect from uh we
did the loudest of 2023 that was the
strongest effect it also has great
flavor it's good yeah but it's strong
for sure big shout out to John Mikey and
vital Bryan This is that uh last joint
the last one this is the last one of the
OG Kush uh loudest effect of 20 2 we
should call them up to thank him bro
call him on speaker phone be like what's
up man we just want to thank you you on
our episode and uh hilarious This Is How
We Do shout outs these days yeah Brian's
been on the show we're trying to get job
Mikey organic living
soil I got that at the end of the year
too so that's you know six weeks ago six
weeks
ago the real deal gas though it's the
real
I think it's great Burns
good it's got good bag of Peel too tasty
but uh Burns and smokes and
hits It's gassy yeah it's got that piny
gas I like that Pine it's like Pine and
lemon and gas it
is shout out to them yep I I love pure
pine needles when you smoke it and it's
like pine needles your face yeah earthy
earthy yeah some of that earthy [ __ ] a
little bit of dirt in there yeah that
earthy flavor though yeah so I do music
bro you want to drop a 16 on one of my
songs James loud cannabis Chris
featuring James
loud I'm down for anything let's do it
CL you Trinidad James loud bro
Trinidad's amazing you got to Trinidad
one of these days the Caribbean oh you
been oh yeah for sure I I was with
Marlin and St Vincent we spoke with the
Cannabis Authority there uh we were
working on some stuff with genetics
discussing genetics and the stuff with
the Cannabis Authority wait where we
talking about the oh we were in St
Vincent but we were talking about
Trinidad Trinidad that's right I've been
a Trinidad as well I've been an
Enterprise Trinidad with Marlon Asher
and his friends and family Marlon Asher
okay yeah Trinidad's it's cool it's nice
interesting place bacon shark
yeah they have these sandwiches shark
sandwiches that are really good oh yeah
they a cat shark off the pier yeah they
use special type of shark and you know
people are like kind of anti-shark
eating or whatever but this is like
those are they're black tip sharp shark
I believe but really good sandwiches uh
dude the spice there is unreal though
they have some really good food though
and uh Trinidad in Trinidad yep got
it street food in Trinidad on point
Point really good same with Thailand
that's what I've heard some [ __ ] that
looks dumbass questionable is just
epic and then they come out with this
little [ __ ] bowl for you at like all
weird hours of the
night fix you up something right put it
together yeah nice and you're like this
[ __ ] right here I need to find remember
the name of this [ __ ] place yeah you
ever gone to a place and then forgot
where it was at find it later
mhm yep I do that now in my local
area like man that was so good and then
you go back to where you thought it was
and it's not there I'm like oh [ __ ] that
must have moved nah they didn't move
what's poping with James loud who's on
spab spannabis that's the next [ __ ] pop
it for you guys that's the next thing
yeah the next thing is spab bringing a
photographer we got a photography and
video so what's up
that's how you got to do it then you got
to get the flag flag hold up and walk
around yeah then you have like bunch of
James loud
[ __ ] that's hilarious no I'm I'm
super conservative those of it's super
funny I just do the booth we do the meet
and greet we're doing a book signing
there and uh we'll be selling book
packages with t-shirts and seeds seeds
oh seeds do great over there they do
great seeds do really well [ __ ] I like
the food over there I like the people
it's always an adventure and uh yeah I
have like a small group of friends that
we've been doing this for a long time
speak English yeah you'll be fine
speaking English be like what's up B
yeah and the food is really good you
like your cheese pizza there it's oh
don't get me started oh no you know what
pizza where's my cheese pizza James I
you got to wait yeah I mean we'll order
it supposed to be here we supposed to be
eating on camera like right this right
here
was definitely part of the show part of
the interview we thought cheese pizza
was code for something
but extra cheese right extra cheese you
know whatever yeah but I'm telling you
the pizza I mean Pizza is an art right
like some people are just like ah pizza
but they don't know Pizza Pizza is a
[ __ ] art yeah and the guys like Tony
in San Francisco that do it right right
Tony's Pizza kappos you go to cappos you
get that experience I love kappos see
there's the difference between a pizza
connoisseur and a pizza lover yeah Pizza
Lover will eat all that [ __ ] and then
throw in a bunch of other [ __ ] like
Pizza Hut and dominoes and whatever the
[ __ ] Pizza
connoisseur will only that like you know
top [ __ ] shelf Pizza spots there's so
many good ones there's so many different
style pizzas you got your New York
Detroit your Chicago your Italian your
Roman Pizza I mean Sicilian pizza
they're all yeah I'm all about it's so
funny you I love I love making pizza too
shout out to JP who just threw the uh
good
pizza event in Sacramento good pizza Day
event in Sacramento uh he had like the
Sicilians and the
[ __ ] you know the Italians and the
[ __ ] all sorts of different Pizza out
there at least three different
[ __ ] was was out there pushing
Pizza wow um and he was like yeah this
is you know this is what I recommend I
was like hey where where's the best
what's the best [ __ ] and he was like
well this is you know Sicilian and
they're gonna make it like this and nice
I ended up doing that but anyway shout
out to you JP nice good stuff so the
best pizza in California besides I mean
Tony's as good is Rip Pizza it's in
Orange County rip Pizza r iip p yeah
it's Pizza it was a brewery now it's a
brewery and a it used to be Straw Hat
yeah yeah exactly no straw hat used to
have the best Straw Hat when we were
kids when I was five I also like Straw
Hat the best I love Straw Hat bring
Straw Hat bag you know what it used to
be good but really tastes like pure ass
nowadays damn
chuckecheese it was it was fun going as
kids you know because you get to play
and there was games and all kinds of
stuff yeah the pizza is trash terrible
it was cardboard it was the worst I I
think chuckecheese had had the worst
Pizza when we were kids yeah all the
places that we I liked going it was you
know we like going to chuck-e-cheese's
kids but uh all right best frozen pizza
I don't do frozen pizzas I don't know
what all right well let me put you on
game if you buy this frozen pizza be
like you know what this one's all right
and it ain't Douro you I mean it is Red
Baron is [ __ ]
delicious damn good job about that
Redberry Pizza shout out to bearon you
[ __ ] are killing it I posted
that [ __ ] on the IG like oh look at this
pizza no box in a picture and somebody
was like Hey you eating that Red Baron
right now I was like
yeah best frozen pizza so I make my
pizza from scratch I do like I make the
crust I have a pizza oven at the house I
do yeah I do Woodfire Pizza Woodfire
Pizza I'm all about Woodfire Pizza dude
so yeah Woodfire pizza's good I just say
that
a one of them little [ __ ] restaurants
that are like create your own pizza five
minutes nice yeah we have like you know
eight people over at a time and small
little party but then you can make
pizzas and as they come
out uh which is only 90 seconds you
could just make pizza after pizza and
everybody kind of picks their toppings
and 90 seconds it's about 90 seconds
yeah to make a pizza holy [ __ ] about 750
I go about 750 degrees Fahrenheit
that's nice and hot comes out crisp you
got to rotate it a little bit but yeah I
mean we had Papa Murphy's growing up
that was like the Tak and bake or
whatever Papa Murphy yeah take and bake
I had a couple of those I feel like it's
better nowadays than it used to be back
in the days so when I was a kid we used
to get this guy who worked a Round Table
Pizza I'm not going to shout his name
out because he might not like it but he
used to put mushrooms on our pizza let's
set it out what's his name I don't even
remember but yeah so we put it on the
pizza the mushrooms and then it was like
pizza roulette uhhuh some of us got
really high people didn't get as high
but like oh nice good stuff yeah we'd
split the pizza evenly between everybody
and sick good stuff ways to get high
with mushrooms is there a brand that is
kind of like this [ __ ] could be
better much hype everybody everybody
here's the thing like I feel like we
need more of a farm to table program
where you get stuff fresher cuz I'll get
stuff from really reputable Brands and I
think the flour was good but then it
went past his expiration Point that's
why it's got to move fast yeah but uh
also there was a way to track it you
know after it gets us to a certain point
you don't want to smoke it you know
there's like a certain point but that
doesn't mean that
it's yeah that happens with every brand
yeah so that's more of the industry
industry problem than a brand problem
but it's still a problem yeah I mean
there's there's a lot of problems with
the Cannabis industry as it is right now
so you said backpack boys Jesus I think
they're doing pretty good I said
backpack boys yeah I heard backpack boys
ju yeah James said backpack boys bro
totally be go easy on them yeah backpack
boys has been killing a game bro killing
it um they're open up stores too like at
San Francisco I went to their uh what is
the Hollywood one the mansion that they
[ __ ] bought and turned it into a
goddamn dispensary crazy [ __ ]
are doing it shout out to y'all but yeah
it's interesting brand California other
states yeah people are going on like
thca people it's weird what the [ __ ]
everything is thca that's the case it is
everything is thca but it's what we're
smoking or what it turns into once the
Fire Hits it well it's just uh how the
farm bill was written It's Gonna Change
eventually that's [ __ ] that's
[ __ ] so yeah well [ __ ] thanks for
coming on the show today bro hold up
what else you want to do what do you got
hold up J I appreciate you bro yeah dude
good stuff good
smoke good blunt I just want you to know
I did a good job picking my own
[ __ ] yeah you did a good job we'll see
how you gonna run that test on Freddy
should we do the same test on Freddy
exactly definitely run that test on
Freddy we'll do it let's do it
definitely yeah we got Freddy coming on
in two weeks he he should pass it yeah a
smoker you're a smoker you got smoke you
get
it he should pass that [ __ ] yeah um that
[ __ ] next time they see us will probably
be at an event or uh you'll be on my
[ __ ] podcast yeah let's do it
we can smoke more weed on your show I
don't know if we could do it but I'm
pretty [ __ ] high yeah yeah probably
the drinks too uh at the end of the day
we will be getting blasted on the pot
one show we'll be operating with bongs
oh nice big bong bowls 10 different
spons
flavors 10 different flavors
predominantly getting better and better
yep have a white wall challenge with
like concentrates and you know ke and
whatever else we can throw in that bowl
yeah will you [ __ ] white out the bong
nice no [ __ ] hits you know what I mean
like real bong ribs real bong
ribs you do hot dabs too yeah have I
been on hot dabs or do I do hot dabs you
do hot dabs yeah
no no have you been on hot dabs not yet
I'm supposed to hit up Dustin and get on
there yeah and vice versa he's supposed
to be on my [ __ ] I don't do hot dabs
anymore but I used to well yeah I mean
when we were all young we probably did
the [ __ ] we did hot not knowing any
better KN you had hot knives right like
once in a while you would do it if you
didn't have nothing better but yeah we
used to get really good hash and hot
knife it and dry sift and stuff like
that they have a charcoal that yeah I
remember the Charco with the the hook
charcoal yeah yeah that you heat up with
a torch yeah yeah it used to be quite
the process it is it was and it is
people still use it I don't use it but
you use it no you were using it when I
came in here what are you talking about
yeah right yeah we got a hookah in the
back I mean I do have a hookah but we
don't use it no not here we need to use
it here say it just collects death [ __ ]
it's been a while since I used it I got
a burner and everything to fire it up
and we got we got all this stuff some
shisha yeah mixed with a little bit of
cannabis what's up yes sir so if people
are trying to get a hold of you where
can they find you you hit me up at
cannabiz Chris 415 that's cannabiz with
a z c an n a b i z Chris 415 c h r s 415
or you could find me at the ly in the
cityor sesh but don't go to the double
underscore anything because those
[ __ ] fake so Instagram fakes
man that sh crazy how uh you know
Instagram is so affected in our
community especially is so affected by
fakes on Instagram trying to manipulate
people to go to whatever site or to give
them money tegram links and [ __ ] and if
it if it didn't work they wouldn't be
doing it so obviously it's working so
people need to be really careful when
they go online yeah especially on
Instagram you have your favorite Brands
I wouldn't go there if they had a link
to go buy something that can't be sold
on the internet yeah you know these guys
aren't doing that kind of stuff right
CRA the fake cannabis Chris accounts now
man the [ __ ] the 415 and my [ __ ] they
switched the one to a l or a capital I
jerks ain't got [ __ ] better to do and
they got more followers than me what the
[ __ ] that's
crazy well thanks for coming on the show
I really appreciate it dude we need to
do this again sometime we'll do it on
your show sounds great yeah hey and keep
it 100 remember one thing you got this
cannabis [ __ ] confused if it wasn't
cannabis Cris
[Music]
approved