[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James loud
podcast today our special guest is
Lavana from the bases how are you doing
today I'm great thank you how are you
fantastic thanks for coming on the show
it was actually you know somewhat short
notice we met last week over at Steve
D'Angelo's house yeah uh you were
visiting Richard delisi when he was in
town and small world you have your own
radio show MH yeah thank you so much for
having me on the show as well I really
like what you do for the culture I've
been following the show for a while you
you know you I love the people that you
choose to have on here so it's like an
honor for you to include me as well I
got a show on 89.5 FM KCT oscat radio in
Vallejo really cool it's called the
basses I've been doing it for a little
over five years now started it um
Thanksgiving of 2019 wow mhm time sure
flies I got offered the show I was doing
some so decided I wanted to create a
brand within cannabis when it started I
could quickly see I didn't have the
resources to pull together for like
licensing and all that but I figured
what I could do was build sort of start
with like a Lifestyle brand NorCal
flower and then I was doing that for
about a year and I got offered this slot
on the radio and I've actually been a DJ
since 1998 when I got my turntables down
on Market Street wow so I wasn't
unfamiliar with that as well as like
having gone to film school and been in
film and post- production so I started
DJing
at midnight till 2: a.m. for about 2
years and that started as houses of
cannabis and I would play like Stony
music and talk to people in their cars
like are you out in your car smoking
weed you know late night or whatever and
um I just kept doing that I had some
guests on and then it became the bay
sesh wow and as the like culture shifted
into the legalization I saw a lot of my
friends that were just like sort of
stuck on the hill maybe didn't have a
lot like couldn't really promote
themselves so much on social media and
content and everything like that feeling
left out while some other people were
sort of taking that place and and
filling that hole so I wanted to make my
show about sort of holding that space
and like telling the stories of my
friends from the culture from like the
bay to Humble you know what I mean uh
and through music and growing a lot and
uh that's how I found like uh found play
myself playing a lot of meno Dope Boys
um highgrade all stars and I started
doing some videos too but like the core
like Foundation of it all is that show
in Vallejo nice I feel like there's so
much the culture people haven't seen and
it's great to be able to share I mean
people like yourself being able to share
audiences like uh you know they'll learn
about you and then maybe you'll talk
about me on your show and people learn
about our show and I feel like uh you
know it's it's an amazing time to be
alive it's an amazing time to be in the
industry it's changed and evolved so
much much in the last you know 15 years
especially definitely definitely has not
how exactly we imagined it no you know
what I mean I'm actually living in
Brooklyn right now I'm not sure that you
knew that um I'm still broadcasting the
show and I'm in the studio when I'm home
visiting here I've been going there on
and off for since 2022 and then I home
based it there because I just really
wanted to see where things went wow and
uh one day I was getting off the train
and there was like a taco truck next to
like a a girl had an ambulance that was
like a mobile dispensary and I was like
this is what I thought it was going to
be like in California right and so yeah
A lot's changed uh in the past few years
and I think we're finally like year five
into like recreational legalization here
in California turning a corner and a lot
of things are starting to kind of like
settle and like the ogs and a lot of
people the the real people from the
culture are finally getting their
platforms and their their stuff in the
dispensary or their dispensaries or
whatever right and so I'm glad to have
like held the torch for this long and
now everybody's sort of getting there
with it yeah we got a long ways to go
though we got a long ways to go and it's
really interesting all the stuff that's
going on in the industry New York and
there the the Bas that are in New York
and you know I feel like that's that's a
whole interesting I haven't been out to
New York to check it out but that's a
very interesting scene out there from
what I hear very unstable but uh with a
lot of potential indeed uh there's a
relationship there's always been a
relationship between us and you know
what is like the biggest consumer Market
in the world and the biggest what you
know was the biggest supplier or grower
cultivators of not just cannabis but
food here in California that's not going
to change too soon there's an obvious
relationship there right right um so but
now yeah with their freedoms and and the
way things are going it's pretty
interesting it's like La was right after
um you know with the gray area totally
there but it's like a threeyear long Ray
area and it's New York city so it's yeah
much much different different energy out
in New York than La even though they're
they're both big cities and amazing and
in the United States there's totally two
different energies and people are
different both both great I like people
from LA and I like people from New York
they they all have their intricacies and
uh yeah it's a lot of fun always yeah
for sure it's interesting to see people
like um buddies Bodega opening up a shop
in in La now and like the aster Club
opening up and bringing what they've
been doing there to the LA scene now too
and of course it could start in La maybe
there's a little more freedoms here I'm
more of a NorCal Bay Area person and I
love it up here me too you know but I
would hope that we could do like the
aster Club thing model is really cool
like we don't have anywhere here I'm
still getting weed and like hanging I
don't drink alcohol so I'm still hanging
out in my car and smoking weed after I
get it I don't really have anywhere to
go like hang out with people too much
right there's only a handful of clubs in
California that allow smoking right cool
thing about California is we got
backyards at a lot of bars and things
like that but like not exactly to go and
then in New York I experience these
lounges in these places like Metro Bud
Lounge is a place and you can just go
you know chill they got like video games
and couches and like meet other Stoners
and kick it with them and like have
those conversations you and chill things
you get to have for that nice so yeah
let's dive into a little bit of History
tell me about yourself how you got
started smoking first time I remember
smoking weed um I definitely like wanted
some dank right because I was raised by
rbl posi and no I knew all about not
wanting bammer I wanted dank right and
so I'm seventh grade mil Valley Middle
School I asked the kid from eighth grade
Dave Ross to you know to buy a twamp
sack from him of dank and I got that and
I had a bong I had a choire bong at the
at the flea market one of those old like
purple uh like plastic tube ones the
knockoff Graphics ones yeah basically
yeah the but these I mean yeah these
were knockoff graphics and uh we went
and smoked the bowl of that Chris and my
pipe bong together in the bushes by mil
Valley uh Middle School nice and uh I
don't know I don't I feel like I just
like loved weed ever since then and like
dank weed for sure um when it went legal
and everything here I think I started
like you know planting seeds and stuff
went in like maybe like 98 like around
when I could get my medical like around
18 nice then you know people I knew grew
I kind of found out that my dad Grew
From somebody from high school cuz he
was like oh my God like your dad grows a
hella good weed um but I didn't really
know I was a little bit sheltered in
that way and then I got um I think I
started trimming for people in like 2005
in the crest side in valo oh wow and
they were like hanging the trees like
whole mhm and we had we were just all
sitting around this big circle with like
the whole tree hung like that trimming
them with like paper scissors oh wow
yeah do you guys trim wet or trim dry
then I think I feel like it was dry yeah
we started trimming wet a long time ago
we trimmed wet first and then we'd H
hang it and then trim it off the bud or
off the stem right off the stem yep and
then we'd also have the fresh frozen it
was wet so all the fine trim we put that
in the freezer and make bubble hash
you're doing that right in the90s in the
'9
um you know originally we didn't do
anything with our trim but then once
somebody figured out how to do bubble
hash we started freezing all our trim to
make the bubble hash and amazing stuff
that's so cool yeah and we didn't even
have Bubble Bags originally there was a
silk screen right you use Solo cups and
you poured it over the silk screen you
you stirred it there was like this
recipe you know and you had to stir it
one way and then stir it the other way
and then scoop it out over the silk
screen and let it we we used to let it
dry on the silk screen who showed you
how to do all that so my body Micah
showed me some of the stuff who I was
partners with for quite a while and uh
we had a group of uh bunch of us that
just kind of shared the information
between the group and you know it's like
trimming we didn't pay trimmers we all
helped each other trim you know this was
in the '90s so like there was trim
parties yeah it was like we're going to
go party at someone's house yeah I
remember watching I mean the late 90s
early 2000s watching the the disc set of
In Living Color uh we watched those over
and over over and over while we trimmed
and I think I still have them and
they're sticky with resin so so from way
back in the day but yeah I mean it was a
different it was a different world back
then and you know we had knife hits we
didn't have dabs really right you know
we smoked we smoked extract on coal with
with a little tube and then we also did
knife hits and knife hits were what
would you'd smoke the you know old
school hash hot press it between two
knives it was like a super hot dab ruin
your throat good stuff yeah so hot I
think we I think us the generation of us
that did that have some pretty damaged
lungs from that D probably yeah and like
the hot I mean we were doing hot that
and then we're doing hot do gravity
gravity wasn't a question for a long
time yeah did you do gravity bongs back
in the day I did Gravity hot knife
gravity bongs before too did you ever do
that yeah yeah that'll wreck your life
the milk carton off and like put it over
the sink I had a friend who jumped into
a swimming pool with a five gallon
alhamra hit himself in the face with it
basically oh man and then had another
friend he had his gravity bong with the
two ler that was in a cooler in his
closet at his parents house oh my God so
disgusting super
gross yeah super gross you know but we
all had our our fun ways of smoking and
I mean the glass pipes back then
everyone had it was before all the
Chinese glass so it was done by like
artists and right yeah it was all it was
all produced by real artists and they
were sold at the head shops and you know
they were still fairly inexp expensive
but they were pretty amazing you know
the the work that went into them and
yeah I mean late 9s my one pipe for
hella long I remember the skull pipe I
had and it finally broke but I really
had that thing for years yeah they still
have amazing glass don't get me wrong
but there's a lot of Chinese glass and
before there was the Chinese glass there
was a lot of artists that made it from
everywhere from Eugene Oregon I mean
Portland Washington all over
Massachusetts you were getting stuff
from all over shs were so cool you know
and that's like where you would learn
things back in the day totally find
stuff out head shops and Grow shops you
know yeah and you can get them on the
lot if you went to a dead show or you
could go to Telegraph Avenue in Berkeley
and you'd be able to get some telegraph
was a big deal exactly I was going to
say Telegraph or ha Street yeah we had
seashell pipes back in the day that were
like resin on the there like a resin
material on a seashell and we put a
screen in there and oh the screen yeah
you have to go get a new screen oh yeah
you'd have to get new clean screen off
Telegraph there was a place called Gypsy
Trader and this guy raone Gypsy Trader
and he was a character he'd like to
wheel and deal yeah but we used to yeah
ride skateboards to Telegraph or uh
hopefully get a ride from somebody
before we even were able to drive so
yeah shout out to Mighty Quinn we got
Mighty Quinn and in Sandell and that was
all like really good smoke shop smoke
shops are so dope in Cali yeah there's
all there's like 10,000 of these like
smoke shops in New York mhm and they all
have just Amazon like it's all the same
exact thing
like Amazon runs and then these Dusty
you know like Bart Simpson like plastic
bongs like the ones I I started on in 12
but worse and like no supplies it's like
smoke shops are supposed to be awesome
you're supposed to go in there and find
all these cool little things and like
ways of smoke and yeah I mean I like the
hippie side of it for sure like the
smoke shops that have the tie dye and
tiey you got to get some nog Champa you
got to get some tiedye you got to yeah I
mean you got to be able to go through
list and if they have crystals it's a
bonus you know it's like exactly I'm all
about the crystals too like I have a
pretty big collection of crystals that
I've collected over the years and all
that stuff you know tapestries all that
you know it's fun and then the custom
glass and I have a wide variety of pipes
that are all different sizes and a lot
you know most of most of them I don't
use now I don't want to drop or break
them uh chem dog I have some hand blown
chem dog pieces the chem dog blue that
are pretty amazing I mean one of them
right
here The Grateful Dead Millies in it Che
it out oh
yeah gorgeous yeah they don't make them
like this anymore right they don't they
don't I mean they do don't get me wrong
they do but like and there's cool new
stuff there's cool new stuff and chem
dog still blows glass you can look at
his glass online people can still buy it
it's not as easy as it was back in the
day to get them from him I'm sure
because you know they're they're in more
high demand all these things that are
slowly going away and then we have China
who's producing glass hand over fist and
they're selling it for $5 just
undercutting the market and a lot of
people are okay with the Chinese glass
yeah I mean that could be said about
pretty much all markets pretty much
everything yeah yeah but I still go for
Quality you know what I mean I'll still
go to a farmers market before I'll go if
they have a choice yeah you know what I
mean over a Safeway anytime or whatever
me too quality over quantity a lot of
people eat McDonald's and drink Coke and
like you know there's a market for
everything you know what I mean so like
there is China can't undercut you I mean
they just can't do handmade like that or
you know buying artisanal glass if
that's what you might call it yeah it's
I mean even flour we go back into the
quality of flour it's like you can grow
at a large quantity and you can get a
pretty good quality but you're not going
to get the artisanal quality it's very
rare why do you think that is well I
think anything when you're trying to
replicate it at that scale it's much
more difficult to control all the
variables
um and so the guy who's putting his love
into the plant and it goes like tomatoes
in your backyard you can go buy a decent
you can get a Berkeley Bowl you can get
pretty good tomatoes but then if you
grow your own tomatoes in your backyard
you can pick them when they're perfect
you can grow each one exactly how you
want and there's also uh the secret
ingredient with all of it is love I was
going to say and energy right cuz you
were talking about how much you love
crystals and like why you know I think
that first someone couldn't be incapable
of giving all that love to a bigger grow
and all that but it's not the focus in a
lot of these places anyways I know a
couple people that do a really good job
at scale I do know people I worked for
like uh I wish I could remember her name
right now but one of the women
cultivators over at Flor Cal yeah um
would have us you know they they would
be telling each plant they love it it's
beautiful they would have us doing that
as we were bucking it trim it putting it
into the jar and sending it off like
doing that whole energy and it was
phenomenal yeah but yeah I mean I think
that there's got to be like an energetic
spiritual like thing with growing these
thca crystals on these plants it's yeah
present in tomatoes but perhaps even
more present because it's crystals in
this in the these plants you know yeah I
mean there's got to be alignment there
and I I mean I have my friends over at
SF Cana that crush it they do a really
good job fig farms in the area they do a
really good job there's a bunch of grows
that I think they do a great job for
what it is especially at scale but
there's still something to be said for
the Homegrown and to allow people
everywhere to grow homegrown weed I
think that uh it's it's also just such
an amazing experience because then
there's a story behind it and then
you're consuming something that you help
produce and so you understand pretty
much every day what happened in the life
of that plant if you're smoking it or
you're sharing it with your friend
friends and there's some alignment there
that's just amazing I agree I love
growing my own and I always make use of
it and you know a lot of times it's not
as good as what all my friends grow so I
ended up like sort of giving that to
someone that might need it and then
smoking the other weed from other
friends that I like maybe better but
it's always comes in valuable and the
experience itself grounds me love being
in the garden and like having something
to cultivate and grow like that and all
the little smells that come along with
it I also love juicing my cannabis raw
yeah um the leaves and the little nugs
like they'll juice the leaves but then
the little nugs I'll put into like
smoothies with some fruit from my garden
too yeah and that's something I can't
really like at this point get although I
hope down the line I could maybe go to
the grocery store and buy like a Frozen
pack of like baby nugs that were super
organic I don't want you know I didn't
spray these like either so I don't want
I don't want it sprayed with something
weird cuz it's so fresh and raw totally
but that and you learn learn that to
respect the people that or the root weed
that was grown so well you realize like
you you know I'm going to pay some money
for that cuz like I you know it's not as
good as my weed I think it teaches you
that too and to be like maybe I'm not in
maybe I shouldn't I don't have time and
energy and I'm not that good at growing
weed so maybe I should just buy other
people's it requires a lot of energy a
lot of time a lot of uh repetition to
grow really good flower and uh yeah not
everybody appreciat it either some
people are okay with mediocre I mean
mediocre everything I mean and also
there I mean mediocre what is that
anyways I think it's like you know
subjective subjective indeed I mean it
should smell good and taste good and
make you feel good it should but like
lots of people um because I did some bud
tending workout in New York got good
read on the on the you know the people
but a lot of people you know especially
uh they want they don't really want like
a it to be so strong you know they want
it they're actually looking for like
lower lower
THC weed some of the older people
especially saying that's a good Market
though if we're talking business you
know what I mean that's the big Market
the Baby Boomers they come in looking
for some stuff that reminds them of the
flower back in the 60 nostalgic weed my
mom always talks about the aqua gold
that's her nostalgic weed you know she's
born and raised in the Bay Area it was a
big deal Northern Lights even is pretty
nostalgic for a lot of us oh yeah for
sure piff piff I mean Cuban black Haze
piff yeah piff is cool uh is there a
difference between piff and Haze no piff
is definitely a tip so piff comes from
the Cuban black Haze and it's a I
believe it's an S1 of the Cuban black
Haze so it is definitely hazy but I feel
like it's on the more mild side of haze
and they get that characteristic with
the trinoline and lyine a lot of it
comes from places like Colombia there's
genetics from Africa that have that
characteristic in there and usually it's
associated with a really strong effect
but with the piff it's not that strong
and it's I feel like it's it's uplifting
and then it just kind of Mellows off and
it makes you feel really good and the
piff always makes me feel great it's one
of those ones uh my buddy Josh Freeman
from Sebastapol grows piff black yeah
and it's really great he's actually
rolling me up some right now oh really
and The Taste is good it tastes good
down to the if it's grown correctly it
tastes good down to the roach and it has
a unique flavor profile it's not purple
candy gas like everybody likes you know
like a lot of people like it's got a
little bit of the hazy but it's uh it's
really an amazing cultivar you know and
I would love to see us getting back into
more of the the varieties of cannabis
that are just outside the box a little
bit adding some more diversity some more
of the old school stuff you know train
wrecky stuff is good I like train wreck
but I also like Durban Poison and I also
like Romulan like going back to some
Romulan we that's a popular Bay Area
genetic that we had I mean it's from all
over but you know we definitely had it
in the Bay Area it was hot it was real
hot for a minute yeah you know and then
we had some European stuff and I really
like some of the European genetics that
they they they took California genetics
and molded them there way and there's
some really interesting stuff over there
like the Liberty Haze and but some of
the hazes are a little bit too strong
for people because they they they don't
want to take just a half a hit they want
to smoke like three or four hits and
they do and some people get heart
palpitation and stuff like that whereas
like uh I think the the stuff that leans
on the sedative side is more popular
right now more of the
indicia but it all goes in waves we talk
about it a lot you know I think uh 80%
more than 80% of the market is purple
candy right now and people want purple
flour right I mean I think that there a
lot of those people that think they're
smoking purple weed or smoking like hemp
sprayed I mean no I mean I think there's
runs and gelato yeah yeah yeah gelato 33
always runs and gelato I love those
though but it's my install it's like my
it's like I think it's like Regional at
this point almost like Regional tastes
what's your nostalgic flavor catpiss
catpiss catpiss from the Bay Area yeah
we talk about it a lot on the show we
talk I'm doing a documentary later this
year we're going to do one on catpiss we
have some great Stories We got some
great storytellers yeah um and there's
there's amazing history with cat piss
and it's there's a lot of argument on
where it came from who created it a lot
of people want to take credit for
creating it and I believe a lot of
people did create their version of
catpiss right and it's an aroma it's a
it's a something that smells like
ammonia yeah and people relate that to
catpiss and so it is very possible it's
not like the name blue dream where it's
like okay the Hayes Brothers they
created the blue dream that's we can
trace that back to them and that's a
very specific name we have something
that describes an aroma so anytime
someone in Kentucky or Florida or LA or
San Diego or the bay area which it was
very popular here they grow something
and it's got some ammonia you know the
first thing out of a lot of people
they're like catpiss catpiss and I
remember when catpiss came around yeah
the real cat SM like cat piss like oh it
really does it's kind of gross but it
smokes hella it smoked hella good and
the thing is is it it was the ugliest
weed and so I I love ugly weed yeah I'm
looking at ugly weed is like is like
catching my eye now after all seeing all
this like weird I had a whole revoltion
in New York I didn't know what TP spray
was I didn't know what was I've been
just on the hill trimming staying out of
that stuff for a while so I was like why
ises this like look like this but it
don't it's and I've smoked a couple of
of of these like sparkly purpley oh yeah
some of the stuff that's rolled in thca
where they they they toss it in thca so
it's especially if it's Sparkle thing
yeah so they have the they call them
snowballs or snow caps I'm not a big fan
personally it's like uh moonrocks 2.0
and I I wasn't a really big fan of moon
rocks and they had their Heyday and they
it went relatively quickly which I think
is going to be the same thing so I mean
I want to taste the real flour same
thing with the the sprayed turps where
they're infusing different flavors you
know I don't know how safe it is for one
thing but I want the flower to represent
the genetics and you know the effort
that the grower went through not the
person who's infusing the flavor yeah
yeah I know I mean there's uh it's a
market for the flavor stuff you know and
that's that but I personally no thank
you flavor is so subjective and all
these things are so subjective to the
individual from one person to the next
it's like I mean I think I can tell
somebody what good flower is but it's
all very personal and you know with with
your own individual relationship with
the plant and relationship with these
flavor profiles and at the end of the
day it's an experience right so yeah I
mean it's aroma therapy and but I think
I read somewhere that the Tarpin are
what inform our endocannabinoid
receptors which cannaboids to take into
the system to you know send out so I I
don't know if I'm right on that I'm
pretty sure I read that somewhere I
believe that is correct and I you know I
think we don't know so much more we're
just still scratching the surface you
know they just came out with the the
white papers on flavorants which are
basically th and Esters and alcohols
that are in the plant stuff like that
and so we're just still scratching the
surface of it we're getting a better
understanding um and I love the fact
that that's advancing but you know it
can all be traced back also to our
relationship to the data points that
we've experienced in our life so you've
smelled different types of Rose or you
tell different types of orange is it
Orange Blossom is it Orange Peel is it
orange U juice is it a
orange um extract I mean there's all is
it fake candy orange turps you know
there's so many different things and the
more data points we collect
over time whether it's with food or with
life experiences that's how we see
that's that's our lens we see the world
under right and so that's the pretty
amazing part is like all these different
Tes um and different combinations of
Tarpin I guess there's 40,000 different
Tarpin in existence that they know of
which is pretty
amazing um yeah and it's just the the
wide variety of stuff that we're going
to be able to experience over the next
10 years I mean I think that's to change
from the purple candy to hopefully some
other interesting things the the hash
burger if you smelled that SM like in
and out there some greasy there's a
bunch of greasy Donnie Burger's pretty
greasy too yeah um so what would you
consider nostalgic as far as genetics
what what what takes you back when you
smell um well I we talked before about
like you know the champal was the turp
that I was always chasing down but yeah
that's the like weed I always wanted to
smoke again and then um the the
Granddaddy Purple when it was good yeah
in the purple days you know perss and
everything oh yeah purple was trendy
back in the day before it wasn't right
and it wasn't purple actually the weed
well the we had real GDP that was dark
purple there was a Ken Ken's GDP some of
them they weren't super dark but then we
had a I mean I remember my friends going
super dark GDP where the leaves were
black and plants were real short and it
was super floral it was like the first
Floral for all the candy stuff it was
floral gas floral so like yeah I was
chasing the Ros around for a while cuz
this Ros that we that floral was
growing at a time was
so so good and like sexual Turks you
know what I mean it was really fun cuz
we had like 50 trimmers and they're all
super Stoners and so you can see like a
good data point of like what like
everyone kind of says and that was like
definitely one of those just like
everyone's like ooh ah like you know
can't get enough of it you're just like
oh my God
I wonder if it's related to creme Ros
from a fish in a they had this one Leo
had this one uh at least my buddy had
the phenotype of it that was rosewater
turs it was like rosew waterer amazing
it was it wasn't the most complex but it
was like it smelled like perfume almost
yeah like a perfume but like a sweet
undertones and then all that flavor in
your mouth we were pressing it and it
was like lavender rosin oh I bet it was
amazing yeah and then they had another
one over there called ra
which was like a a Nigerian land cross
mhm and like a
lemon and that that was a really fire
and also like super high like I miss
like weed that really does get you like
super Yonk like you know gu cultivator
smoked some of maybe his hello with me
his hello strain and that was the last
time that I really like hit some weed
and was just like I coughed so so hard
but it was like that cough that expander
cough where your lungs are like doing
things and then you're about to be
whatever yeah and then just like not
just bloodshot eyes but like blood red
eyes yeah and just that like I'm hella
high right now I haven't really been
getting that from for any bud too much
for a while that's why you dab that is
why I dab yeah right it'll it'll take
you there yeah but that weed took me
there you know back in the day I think
we took us there a little more and um
you know I don't know if we watered down
all of the land race genetics and we're
never going to have that potency back or
is there the potency going to bring us
back you know it's you got to convince
these people to grow some of these
longer
flowering uh these longer flowering
varieties well people got to pay for
that because if you think you know you
want to grow twice as long flowering
time that's going to cost twice as much
yeah and that's like you know definitely
feeding into the lack of I think like
more quality stuff on the market here is
like if you're going to push the price
down yeah that people I mean the math
isn't mathing in California right now
they really got to fix it well we were
talking about the northern lights and we
were talking about Haze and you know
just off the top of my head the the piff
is nl5 times Haze I believe it's
Northern Lights times Haze is what makes
the piff ah and same thing with the when
I smoked the PFF in New York it tasted
like Northern kns a little bit to me cuz
it is it's Northern Lights Haze okay and
same thing with the Fort Collins cough
it's another amazing that one's pretty
strong actually the Fort Collins cough
is pretty strong and it's it's got this
crazy flavor that that's unmistakable
that that's musky it's got a nice musky
characteristic to it that's that's
unique to the Fort cins cough but do you
think people can dial down the flowering
time or you think that's sure intricate
to the success of a really good like
psychedelic sativa cuz we're in the the
right you're saying yeah I think well I
think someone made a point the other day
that said the longer it takes the flower
the longer the high the longer the
effect but we can breed into I mean I've
seen stuff bred into shorter flowering
varieties for sure and it's a lot of the
stuff has gotten shorter over time uh
but there is a relationship to tpin and
structure tpin and flowering time you
know there's all these interconnected
traits and so through work through
effort like if you have breeding goals
where you're like I like this specific
flavor over time you can breed those to
Shorter flowering times Sour Diesel we
want Sour Diesel and we want to capture
this exact thing that tastes good smells
good has a similar effect but it doesn't
take 12 weeks it only takes eight weeks
and that that is possible I think those
things are possible but they take a lot
of work and they take a lot of effort
and you know some of these passion
projects don't pay out for a long time
right so it's something something that
you do out of passion and you know these
are all fun things but I don't know that
everybody wants to smoke Haze and that's
okay you know but I I think variety is
good too because there's a lot of us
that do like smoking Haze or do like
smoking interesting and different unique
experiences so because I feel like tpin
have a lot to do with the effect and so
oh heck yeah at the end of the day I
want to try different effects for
different time I like Skittles don't get
me wrong I love the taste of Skittles
Skittles is amazing but it also has a
ceiling so it only gets you so high like
for me the Skittles High it takes me up
to about here it never really like as
much as I smoke I could smoke it all day
it never takes me but it's a great
social flavor you know you can smoke it
with everybody and most people like it
it doesn't get them too high you know
and and for maybe novices it gets them
super high or whatever but like I think
for people that are experienced smokers
it doesn't take them above that
threshold whereas you take something
like some hazes and or some Durban
Poison for example you you smoke a
couple puffs it gets you here smoke a
couple more it gets you here and that
never ends you can keep smoking more and
it just keeps getting you more high so
yeah and those are fun experiences I'm
like where's that we he have yeah
there's Durban Poison there's people I
mean uh Redbeard's got his uh red
congales and Durban Poison and those
those yeah there's people still doing it
um there's some people in San Francisco
some people in Santa Cruz they're harder
to find though
but uh well I'm interested to find out
because a lot of these like psychedelic
sativas are Southeast Asian I feel like
the land races too and there is there is
some I mean I think southeast Asia is
where we got the interex traits the
hermaphrodite stuff from which that's
heavily been bred into the genetics so
we have issues with hermaphrodites now
so but yeah people just need to stress
test their weed more I think the
Breeders the guys growing and the guys
putting stuff out need to do more stress
testing right take that job like real
seriously and really like well if they
don't someone else will right at the end
of the day true what do you feel like
the stress like hardest thing to grow no
the easiest like the least stress e oh
the easiest the one if you want to feel
really good about yourself you girl blue
dream say wedding cake but yeah okay
blue Dre wedding cake is a good example
but I would say blue dream is the best
example it's the apical of structure so
it has the I mean in my opinion it is
the as far as structure GRS and easy to
grow it is it's very easy to grow if you
want to feel good about yourself grow
Blue Dream if you want to feel bad about
yourself you should grow some OG cush
yeah so and OG well I mean for me back
in the day it was OG Kush it was also
Girl Scout cookies was like low
yielding hard to grow very finicky I
know I was like so excited to finally
get it and then the nugs were like this
big same thing train wreck I feel like
another one yeah so train wreck had like
the really like these clusters and
really bad node spacing and
but Blue Dream is like this strong plant
just easy to grow you w you even if
you're not a good grower you can get
really good flower out of it it's really
really simple and straightforward I feel
like the more you push it the bigger
it'll get so what are the genetics
you've been smoking on lately I brought
some sunr fullterm sunr that I was super
stoked to find that my buddy grew that
was like a cross of Sunset sherber and
gelato and ice cream cake and runch and
O
nice I was like that sounds all good
yeah um I went and got some of meno dop
boy's he OG at the organic can which is
fire and I was stoked cuz it was like
$20 for eighth yeah which just felt like
Norm we've normalized again I'm like
sweet I can go get a eighth of like some
decent for 20 bucks plus tax um and
that's their outdoor and it's good too
and I was like excited to see it's like
kind of Shaggy cuz OG's Shaggy that's it
you know what I mean it's real OG okay
there we go and yeah tastes good um my
OG was just super dense and it didn't
have very many leaves it was really easy
to trim really pine cones yeah it has
the nested the nested Brack so it
doesn't have a lot of like crazy shape
it it look like pine cones and but
outdoor OG is like some of the best yeah
in the seven from the 707 I swear it's
it's definitely good good goes good with
that terar yeah yeah yeah OG's a special
one and it's making a comeback I feel
like OG's definitely making a comeback
along with all the other stuff sour
should make a comeback too thank sour
and this will be the year of sour and
Haze for sure people are gonna have to
switch over yeah to that for sure tell
us about your radio show so like I right
now it's um drive time which is super
cool it's 3:00 to 6:00 p.m. on
Wednesdays I'm actually going to reduce
it down to two hours because I'm broad
when I'm in New York I'm broadcasting it
from there so um when I'm here in the
studio I go in the studio studio and I
play like you know smoking music stoner
music music to smoke to definitely music
you could put on for your garden yeah
and um then I I we're an independent
radio station so I include Independent
Artists I always like try to give women
other like a open door like if whatever
you're doing if you're a woman you can
come in talk about your thing I'll play
your music or if it's like fashion
whatever I don't do a ton of interviews
though I do sometimes do that and I have
the YouTube channel where I've gone out
and about sort of like a I call like Mr
Rogers Neighborhood on weed like I'm out
in New York I'm down in La I'm talking
to people from other seses and like I
said I started playing a lot of meow do
boys gar cultivator highgrade Allstars
there's and a lot of cultivator music
Beyond like reggae that you would might
want to might think of as like the First
music there's a lot of it m so through
that and playing that music and that
station in that show I've got like the
people that listen to me in valo and all
the people that tune in to ocat online
too as my sort of community but I always
have meno do boys on every year we do an
interview they have they're going to
come into the studio but it's always
been you know covid and
everything um through like them and Gars
cultivator I've kind of grown the
network and my community on like my
Instagram right of Growers
internationally because they've got this
great community so that's the best thing
about radio and the internet yeah is the
International Community in right right
exactly like I love the Internet it's
tough with the shadow Banning obviously
and I and I love my YouTube channel cuz
I love to do the show and tell and
everything right um and I had like Mike
mey I don't know if you know who he is
he's saying I got five on it the hook
but he's also a third gen grower from
you know amendo family right and and
everything else so I had like play his
music and have him on and it's sort of
like the bay culture I represent like
I'm from you know Leo and uh mil Valley
also and but I've got connections in New
York from the Rave scene and being a DJ
and all that so I took the vibe to New
York of um like what we know to be our
culture of like growing and patience
like a so I call now I'm starting to
call it now the culture of compassion
nice I guess because it's a little bit
of a different view when uh when I first
started working in cannabis it was all
about like the patients and like
medicine and everything MH so yeah I
mean I kind of just like have this show
every week on the radio and I play the
music there and it's grown to be like
more artists and a lot of meno dope
though and a lot of like I just love
playing them I just love them shout out
to them um they're so dope totally and
the other people Associated and um then
I do the videos and everything outside
and now um in New York I met this guy
Jimmy young who does Pro cannabis media
and I'm the California correspondent for
that now um which is like we talk news
he offered it to me and I just decided
to take it um to be the person cuz I
want to be you know I feel like I could
I'm going to offer some good stories up
and tell the stories to the rest of the
audience cuz he's from Boston
Massachusetts and there's like all these
other correspondents on there from
different states so I kind of enjoy
watching the show it's just every week
just like everybody telling people like
me telling the news from their
states and by the way I haven't done any
of this for a penny so far
wow I've done this out of like my love
of the culture and to want to like be
the I'm like I was like I told you know
all my friends and they're kind of all
starting to come around and stuff and
people in their own time to have a voice
and to tell their story when it's time
you know what I mean so I'm like holding
the spot I'm doing the show every week
and some so I don't make new content I'm
sure with your your podcast here it's
you know it's it's a lot to create
content all the time and promote it and
post it and H honor every story that
comes on totally you know what I mean
well I see us as kind of storytellers
and we're able to get record some oral
history like for me it's all about the
oral history side of it and hopefully in
50 years people look back and be like
that was pretty cool these guys are
really weird that's I love you're doing
I mean these are great stories and
there's so many angles to it when I saw
that you were doing what you were doing
a lot of people that I was hoping they
might come on my show were coming on
your show but I'm like that's great he's
doing it like it's getting told I mean
and it is a community and that's kind of
what it's about too it's not about it's
not competition we're all in this
together and I feel like it's just it's
a it's a beautiful amazing thing right
now is just it's so great the industry
in a lot of ways is amazing you know in
a lot of ways it's also scary you know
but that's life with everything but yeah
to be able to record some of these
people like uh Richard delisi yes yeah
you having him you need to get him on
the show he is amazing he's he's a great
Storyteller he's got his adventures um
we filmed some good stuff yeah yeah so
and then both of the D'Angelo brothers
are characters right so yeah they
they've got their stories too yeah it's
time for the stories to be told and for
like that torch of compassion to be held
and I like so when I started B SES I
always called it like um a weekly sesh
to inspire our Evolution right meaning
like our Evolution from like traditional
to what it is now whoever wants to
participate and do what they're doing
let's support them you know let's invite
the ogs let's invite the new people that
are going to bring something new to the
table too
and like let's find ways to come
together over this beautiful plant this
thing we all love yeah totally well it's
an amazing thing that brings us all
together the you know people from all
walks of life that would
never she yes she is is amazing yeah I
think people from all walks of life can
can sit at the same table and have a
great conversation about something that
they love and you know it's something
that unites us all and makes the world a
better place does it BRS compassion and
empathy it's proven it's scientifically
proven like we are you know we are
really giving a lot to the world with
this plant and by cultivating it and
sharing it and it's that's you know we
don't want that to be forgotten in the
in the hustle bustle of trying to
survive in the industry or make a dime
or get you know right somewhere yeah so
how do you see the future of the
industry if you're looking five years or
10 years into the future what do you see
going on I think like the thing is the
economics of it right like Canada and
Mexico's been gearing up to the
everybody's going to have to go legal
yeah and right now the argument is like
oh declassify or and I'm like
unclassified you know I've been told by
people from DC that like cuz my whole
thing is like look it's reer Madness
it's built on a lie can they just give
up the LIE already and like but they
won't so we're going to have to go with
this like you know starting with the
classification or not but we're argue
we're going to reschedule instead of
Economics of it period it's just got to
be a commodity it's especially when
we're competing on the North to the
North and the South with you know Canada
and Mexico obviously there's got to be a
commodity there we've got to get
Interstate trading going or you know
opened up that's ridiculous it's
happening whatever um I think like
unfortunately like for the farmers I
think that it's going to just end up
being in the category of every all the
other AG you don't really know Farmers
aren't Ballers you know what I mean like
those are those days of farmers are
farmers you can be super successful
whether you go Tomatoes or corn or
whatever I mean if you love what you're
doing I think that's the most important
thing and the whole rockar thing it's
like whatever but like at the end of the
day if you're all about the plant the
whole a model where we can be
Farmers that is fantastic where you can
actually have a job doing it regardless
of everything else if you can have a job
doing it where you can make a successful
living out of yourself it all comes down
to how hard you want to grind anyway
yeah yeah but I mean it's not going to
be worth it's going to push once it's on
legal it's a regular thing it's not
going to be worth so much and so it's
going to be there will still be there
will be there will be and I think that's
also has a lot to do with freshness you
know and there's a lot to find out I
mean and and you know there's everything
else I mean there's all the medicinal
things there's the raw aspect of it I
think is going to be huge yeah um that
it's completely untapped you know what I
mean the Cosmetics of it everything I we
don't it's going to be integrated fully
into our lives it's a food it's a fiber
it's a building material you know what I
mean um so it's just like we're in a
startup Market here in California within
a startup Market in the country within a
global startup market so the the the
growth rates are going to just be going
up up up everywhere forever for the next
10 20 years who knows how long yeah yeah
in all kinds of directions yeah lots of
jobs could be created we start doing
hemp creete and some of these other
things it's like man we can start using
it for building materials and which are
some of the biggest carbon wasting Pro
you know thing issues that must be
addressed you know whether people want
to whatever I mean and peak oil was a
while ago that's getting done even the
Saudis are like gearing up for something
new you know there could be biofuel you
know I don't know sure soil remediation
all kinds of soil remediation you can
Harvest it three times a year so like
not just in like the Cannabis field or I
mean I kind of just like let's just all
the same thing is for kind of the same
thing it's not though guess you could
just but you know it's just that like
the greater economic system that's where
it's like we'll see you know other
things need to be corrected and fixed in
the in the in the regular economy before
sure Full Throttle totally agree but
yeah California has like I said like you
know there's the Cannabis thing and then
there's the greater issue I'm fascinated
right now I've been talking a lot about
the um Governor's United enforcement
task force that they've put together
here I think that's really interesting
it's like Camp part two yeah so it just
kind of got started the end of 2021 and
it's incorporating like all sort of uh
the DEA federal and state and local
jurisdictions and also administrative
branches too so they're hoping to you
basically hammer down on fines and
collect fines and and and um everything
to pay for all this enforcement wow and
I'm I I that just sounds like again Camp
2.0 Camp 2.0 and so I'm interested you
know I'm kind of been following that
they they they they reported for their
first year 312 million that They seized
I also interested to find I think it's
time for them to stop valuing the weed
so high if they're not you know what I
mean they're like all I'm like well how
many pounds was that cuz I don't know
are you what are you saying what are you
trying to say 1,200 pound 7,000 a pound
you're G to stop with those inflated
worths you know but it was like um
um 91,000 plants eradicated and you know
they do Target these like illegal grows
and all that but now they're starting in
this administrative Branch there's also
been a lot of like FBI stings where
they're posing as inspectors and even
posing as DCC um inspectors and they're
actually FBI to um and getting people on
bribery and stuff like that there's so
much going on here so much enforcement
still which I think is like a waste of
money and it's holding the industry back
in in that way because it's like they're
add they're like well you got to pay for
this too and it's just like unfair like
that other markets are being able to do
so much more already and we should have
been the leaders of it all right you
know life is strange long strange trip
but we are still leaders of it all
regardless we're 20 years ahead of
everybody here in California and we have
20 million Acres of farmland and we
Supply
all the strawberries and the blueberries
and the celeries from here to the rest
of the country yeah I mean it's a
beautiful amazing place we'll just see
what happens I guess going to be
interesting yeah so if you had one piece
of advice for your younger self that
started out in the Cannabis industry
what would that one piece of advice be
if I could do it all over again I would
have become a doctor so I could
prescribe people with weed nice period
yeah yeah that's a good one cuz I want
to convince so many people that are on
the fence I want to be able to help
people I want to whatever and that seems
to be like this barrier and people now
that it's recreational they think it's
just a recreation I'm like no it could
help your stomach it could help so many
things not everything but I feel it's
medical whether you believe it is or not
Dennis perone said that yes exactly so
tell us a story the most famous person
you hung out with tell us a story about
it the most famous person I hung out
with yes I know you got some good
stories ever oh my God I mean that just
more of like who someone that you smoke
weed with I really liked hanging with
kadana at the emerald cup a couple years
ago and and that was a good story too
because um so I come up and that that
that girl Anique I was telling you about
from Black Market certified right she's
got strains uh developing strains for
kadana and Havoc from Mob deep and a CLE
and um corrupt from the dog pound yeah
so she had all of them in this table at
the emerald C uh cup and my home girl
Carmen who's doing PR for Snoop Dog uh
or Robbie D presents she was like you
did me a favor for something else with
you you know helped us with made a
network I Network a lot of people with
like weed and the industry stuff so
she's like I want you to come meet all
these these guys with this girl at Black
Market certified and Nique so I go over
there and kaidon was so cool but he was
looking so hard he had like rolled like
he had like 50 blunts he'd already
rolled sitting there that he'd taken
like a few hits off of cuz he was trying
to find good skunk he was like so he was
it's a cup right all kinds of Growers
are there all kinds of people are going
to if you're capid donic especially or
whatever they're coming up to you and
they're like you know you want to try
this weed I grew this weed that weed
whatever so he's on the hunt for skunk
and he and I could tell by looking at
that pile that it was like you know
nothing was even close to what he wanted
cuz if you find that weed that you love
like that that flavor that you're
looking for cuz if you're a real real
Stoner you're that tur pound right
you're like this is the one you know
clearly he hadn't so we smoked with him
I smoked I had some like really like GMO
C back cross I was like well you know
it's not skunk but it's like in the area
of like Funk right so you might like
this and I you know he's he smoked it a
little bit more than the rest of it but
it wasn't what he was looking for it's
in the right family at least I feel like
that yeah that gas along with the skunk
I thought that was interesting yeah yeah
nice cool yeah there's it's funny
because there's so many people that
smoke weed out there but like my my big
like Superstar Gaga moment was smoking
with gar cultivator nice maybe he's like
my favorite
that's awesome and the weed matched the
the attitude and the music that he you
know I mean like I said I I still
remember like getting that high yeah
like off that and it's and I can't it
was at Thanksgiving up in and humble
nice so when you were a DJ what kind of
music was it house music you bring back
the DJ back in actually I was um my old
DJ name was baby panther and I was like
a I did hip-hop and before dubstep was
around I used to take drum and bass and
like turn it all the way down and put it
over like rap a so I played battle style
and like I scratched and stuff oh cool
vinyl totally different yeah that I love
the old school Drummond B we had jungle
music and drum and bass back in the day
most people don't even know about like
the Drumm and base was way different
back then right right like ground score
and everything yeah I worked at um
compound records back in the day um and
I you know I had skibby and like shy
effects I got real heavy into Raga
jungle so my show is actually very
similar to what I used to play back in
the day which was a mix which is like
the basses obviously like these are
events but I like I'm like I'm giving it
to everybody you guys can just blame it
on the radio show it's the bay s right
it's a radio show but uh I it was always
the blend of like R and reggae and like
storyville like underground hip-hop
stuff right so I kind of go funny people
are doing that now but you way before
your time yeah yeah really cool they're
bringing it back you know but that is
the bay culture it's really cool what I
learned about being in New York and like
immersing myself that much and and being
here is like we are like one culture
here like everybody it's like one cool
culture yeah yeah yeah I love the bay I
love NorCal and I when I say the bay I
feel like the bay all the way up to
Oregon yeah it's like still it's all
great I I love it all and La is its own
thing too La exactly La San Diego it's
its own thing there's nothing wrong with
down there though I I like I like
visiting I like visiting I have some
really cool friends down there I like I
like a lot of things about it but it's
not where I would necessarily want to
live so I just find myself gravitated
towards the Bay Area every time we leave
we end up coming back I'm coming back
I'm not I did a thing there I wanted to
bring the culture there I did I've met
some people I've enabled some people
that feel confident about growing I've
taught a lot of people how to figure out
what the the good weed is versus
whatever the weird stuff is it took me
like a lot of investigating to figure
that out and you know took some people
under my wing and then I'm ready to just
come home because New York's going to do
its thing and I'd rather just be a
visitor there in the future yeah nice
well if people are looking to get a hold
of you can they find you yet they can
follow me on everything at the bay sesh
you can find me there so it could be the
Bayes gmail.com or at the Bayes on
Instagram YouTube Facebook maybe
SoundCloud Wednesdays 3 p p.m Wednesday
3 to 6 you want to tune in on 89.5 FM
kcct oscat radio Vallejo in valo goes
like Richmond wherever you can also go
to the link on my Instagram or use most
FM tuner apps and tune in KZ CT oscat
radio I have some shows on the
SoundCloud
and I have some videos on the YouTube
nice well thank you so much for coming
on the show today really appreciate it
thank you for having me yeah it's been
really fun thank you again thank you
let's look this
[Music]
B yeah