[Music]
Heat up here.
[Applause]
[Music]
How's it going everybody? Welcome to
another episode of the James Loud
podcast and today our special guest is
Caleb from Connected. How are you doing
today? I'm doing great. Thanks for
having me. Absolutely, man. So, you're
one of the guests that you're on the hit
list of the original list that I made of
people that I wanted to interview and
we've been going down and checking the
people off and so I'm glad you're here.
Yeah, I'm glad I finally made it. Um,
the opportunity came up and I said,
"Absolutely." Everyone had I I haven't
quite frankly I haven't paid like a ton
of attention to podcasts in general. I
just listened to like my one or two,
right? And I asked around and everyone's
like, "Yeah, that's that's the biggest
probably if not one of the biggest, the
biggest in in cannabis. You got to be on
it." So, thank you. Yeah. Yeah. We've
we've worked really hard and I feel like
it's it's happened organically. I didn't
really I was on the Future Cannabis
Project and did the James Loud show. We
did 43 episodes there and I said I was
going to build a studio. I did that and
then we're at we we've done over 100
episodes now. It's pretty wild. You
know, it takes a team. It's so much
bigger than myself and it takes good
guests, right? At the end of the day,
it's all the quality of the podcast
totally relates to the quality of your
guests and we try to hit the mark with a
little bit of everything. So, we don't
go for just one style of guest and it's
it's been a fun ride. Yeah, I can tell
by the hats over here. You've got a
pretty varied uh guest list. So, sounds
like you're mixing it up pretty well,
which is great. I think podcasts run the
risk of, you know, kind of going down
one channel and getting stuck there and
then you kind of run out of things and
you replay guests or whatever, but
spreading it out amongst the industry.
You got vendors, uh, seed guys, flower
guys, we got OGs, we got Luke Scarzo on
here. He did 14 years. And I I like
redundancies for some things, but it's
like you can be you can have too much
redundancy with podcast guests. But the
beauty of the cannabis industry is now
as opposed to 20 years ago, you can be
an expert in your field, whether that's
breeding or whether that's, you know,
cultivation or extract, you don't have
to do it all. And back in the day, we
kind of had to do everything.
Yeah. I mean, it feels like I mean, as
the it feels like the walls are closing
in, not on us, but like on the cannabis
industry, right? And and we're finding
ourselves kind of having feeling like we
have to do more and more or at least
bring the people closer and closer. So,
I I wish that was more at least, you
know, for us, I wish that's been more of
the case where you don't have to do
everything. Distribution's a good
example like God's just like doing
something you never wanted to do. Run a
run a crew of trucks. I think we have
like 26 trucks. It's it's mindboggling,
right? Well, and I get that totally and
I would agree, but I feel like you can
hire somebody to run the trucks. You
don't have to run that like run that
department, right? You can have
departments. Before it was like where
you're electricians and carpenters and
all these things. Yeah. Like
individually individually, but like I
I'm totally under the I love the
umbrella model. I love the collaboration
model. I think anymore you have to
collaborate. You have to work with other
like-minded people if you want to be
successful. And you need some of that
vertical integration. You might not have
to be fully vertically integrated, but
you definitely need I mean, I think
genetics is a huge thing. If you can do
that in house, if you grow good
cannabis, you can do pheno hunting,
right? I feel like yes, that's the the
ticket cuz if you don't grow well
enough, you might as well have somebody
else doing that part, right? And if
you're just going to grow mids, it
doesn't even matter anyway these days.
Yeah. And you know what I've noticed? So
that question comes up a lot like why
like why is your genetic program better
or different? And it's not that it's
necessarily better. It's not that we're
doing anything unique. Genetics and
pheno hunting is not crazy complicated.
It's it's the whole thing, the whole
chain of events. It's it's the the
deciding what to cross with, then doing
the pheno hunt, making the selections,
and then probably the biggest component
of it is getting it to market and
finding the stage for it, right? And I
think that's where a lot of people uh,
you know, it kind of goes back to having
to do everything yourself. I think a lot
of people continue to try to do
everything themselves and they want to
name it or, you know, they want to
design the label. I mean, we've fallen
victim to that. I've I've had to let go
of more and more to give it more chance
of of success, right? Because what I
like in my narrow vision, especially as
as I've gotten older, you know, doesn't
always hit and and being able to pass
that off. But I think I've seen you I've
seen a lot of genetics that were really
good and worth, you know, quite a bit.
In fact, even though we have the vast
majority of what we grow commercially,
probably like 90% of it is something
that we developed in house, but that
other 10% is stuff we've either got from
some friend or whatever or so sourced
off of clone menus, just random like
weird names, you know, and we've brought
it in and we're like, "Holy [ __ ] this
is yielding, you know, high teacher."
It's like hitting all the marks and I've
never even heard of this strain. It's
probably something relabeled, right? And
it's something else someone made and
didn't wasn't able to to take it to the
big times. So much of that happens. I've
seen so much good stuff too that is just
not been in the right hands. Uh Gelato
41, I think you're kind of synonymous
with Gelato 41 to a degree. Yeah. Um we
I wish I could take credit for creating
it. You know, they they created it. uh
the Cookie Fam guys created it and then
but we were the first ones to grow it
commercially and and then Gelato 41
still to this day is one of the best
parents to breed with. I I' I've bred
with it myself. I 100% agree. It is the
And the funny thing is is like you look
at Gelato 33, you look at any of the
other gelatoes and there's a lot of
instability with the genetics. Whereas
gelato 41, it just it it basically
translates to the parents. you can put
it out in a field if you if you use it
as a as a parent especially as a donor u
you can cross it with stuff and you're
going to get a pretty consistent
expression whereas gelato 33 like the
S1's for example of gelato 33 you'll get
25 different phenotypes that are very
different right whereas gelato 41 you're
getting only a handful and I feel like
it translates to strength structure all
the it checks a lot of the boxes yeah it
really does and and as as the perfect
parent, I consider that to mean that
it's not dominating. Like it's a very
strong presence. It's very clear that
it's part of it, but also like when I I
think about gelade when people ask us
all the time when we crossed it with the
lemon tree and it's just the perfect
pairing of the two of them. It looks
much more like gelato but smells like
gelade and the flavor or smells like the
the lemon tree but with that hint of the
the gelato back end. It's it just really
it doesn't overpower anything, but it
never sees, you know, its presence. Like
you always it's very clear that it's
part of the package. I really like that
when we're breeding. Yeah. I love when
you can take two parents and then
improve upon them. A lot of times I see
this happening more and more is where
guys make a cross and it's not better
than either one of the parents and it's
like that that has a lot to do with feno
hunting, but also stuff on paper
sometimes sounds a lot better than the
reality of it. You know, Skittles times
gelato 41. It's it's amazing, but
there's a lot of work that goes into
finding good phenotypes. Um, and I think
some people don't have the
infrastructure set up to be able to do
large scale hunts. Uh, and it's like you
got to go through a lot of plants
sometimes. Sometimes you don't, but
sometimes you really do. What do you
think's the right number? I think it's
different on everything cuz I just
popped a bunch I popped a bunch of drips
that I made, which is uh zeruns and
grape gas and it's just absolutely
amazing. 20 of them my guys wanted to
keep out of 40. M right. And it's like
so sometimes you get lucky and it's like
and out of that we we narrowed it down
to five that are really special but
that's still a home run. Five out of 40
is insane. That's crazy. It's crazy. You
know what I mean? Usually it's one out
of 100. I like that 1%. I want the one
percentile because I think a lot of guys
they they go through 20 or 30 and
they're missing something. They might be
missing the winner, you know? But
another way I look at it as a as a whole
room, like if you're popping stuff,
you're going to find winners in that
room. Even if you were to pop 10 of
this, you know, you might not find
anything in that 10, but the next 10,
you might find something good. But I
really I like to keep it around 50. I
think 50 is a good number. 100 is ideal,
but it's based on our your
infrastructure and your setup, too. So,
for us, I think 50 is pretty good, and
we're constantly going through 60 lights
of plants. So, and we do that multiple
times. So, what about you? You know, I I
I agree with you. I think in a perfect
world, it's about a hundred. Um we we
have to catch cast such a wide net for
to keep that genetic, you know, that
fresh genetic uh launch uh calendar um
rolling in the wreck market. And now
that we've launched our third brand,
Smok and Promises, we don't really have
the I mean we do I think we do five a
year and one of them I think we go big
and we do three you know three 100. Um
but the majority of our hunts are
between 30 and 50. Yeah. and it's
produced a lot of good results, but I
often times find myself, you know, you
where you do a cross that, you know,
there's just no doubt in my mind that it
should and will produce something great
and then you just wasted, you know, 3
months because you did a 50 or a 30 and
you didn't get anything out of it or you
find yourself trying to nudge something
into the winning spot when it really
doesn't deserve to be on the stage, you
know? Yeah. It's so tough because I feel
the same way because I get attached to
like this cross being so good and then
all of a sudden we're looking at the
finished material and it's like so
sometimes we have to run stuff twice too
where it's like okay well we didn't grow
it that good this time we need to really
focus on these because I know there's
something in there and sometimes you hit
it and sometimes you don't but uh I've
been able to detach myself and you have
to callull a lot of stuff. You know what
I mean? I think that's a that's a sign
of a good breeder too. Someone who's
able to just get rid of it and make that
decision like this is not going to work
right. I had to pull myself out of a lot
of that process like because I have the
hardest time letting things go. I like
you know want to see the best in
everyone including the fenos. I'm like
but this I can tell it can be someone
totally you know and so I had to just re
remove myself you know we we have a
pretty comprehensive process. We've
incorporated a number of people and a
pretty uh uh a good system, a scoring
system. And if it doesn't meet the
scoring, I mean, I could pull rank and
be like, "No, this one this is going to
I don't care that people didn't like it.
We're going to give it another shot." I
try to not do it very often, right? Um
but we've we've we're in a pretty good
system that prevents me from keeping too
much and or putting things forward that
really shouldn't. And do you guys do
analytics as well with everything? Yeah.
Yeah, we we test everything for turpps
and um and TH and cannabonoids uh and
document everything. I mean our I've
seen some of your lists actually, so for
sure. Yeah. Yeah. I mean like really
extensive uh spreadsheets. Yeah. I mean
it's daunting. I can't even you know
they're like oh reference you know line
1,300. I'm like no I'm not looking at
spreadsheets that go that in that
indepth. So we have a great uh R&amp;D
department. Uh we have a a PhD out of
Cornell running the R&amp;D and he comes
from a data background and and I think
he was working in tomatoes before and so
just he was just like collecting data
and and so now he collects the data,
organizes the data and then helps, you
know, present it in a in a a way that we
can absorb it and then give feedback and
make quick decisions. And that's been
instrumental. That's allowed us to go
way wider. Yeah, you know, if it was
just me and Ted, you know, just knocking
our heads on the wall, we'd probably
still just be doing large, you know,
larger 50 to 100 feno hunts. Keep it a
little bit more simple and and less data
and, you know, a lot of a lot of that.
Well, let's smoke it and see how it
goes. And it's like, but you can't smoke
everything. And that's the other thing
people don't understand. It's like, I
would love to be able to smoke
everything. We have 60 lights. There's
just no way you're going to do it. But I
can tell a lot of times what's going to
smoke and what's not going to smoke. at
least I have a good idea and that
doesn't always translate but most of the
time at least we have a good idea of
stuff based on the nose especially
interesting so for us that has not or at
least me that has not rung true I've you
know I was I mean I came from brokering
wheat right and that's how I came up in
the space I was not a grower I figured
it out because I realized we had to like
that was an area that was underserved
and a lot of people weren't doing a
great job when I when I decided to
learn, right? But, you know, I'm just
look in the bag, smell it, looks, is
this going to sell and at what price is
how my entire mind worked. And so, I'm
still, you know, burdened by that a
little bit. So, I cannot I haven't been
able to adjust my lens. And so, I'm I
find myself picking I'm like this smell
and smell and looks smell and looks. And
then we have what we refer to as the
sensory panel now. It's like these taste
makers all throughout the state that we
make they get drops of of all the
different stages of the of the breeding
and and testing process. And I find that
I'm wrong more like what they're saying
translates like they're picking fenos
that aren't as good looking. You know,
the the noses are a little bit more
nuanced and you know, so I can after
they kind of explain why they made a
certain selection on the nose, I can see
it. But some of the, you know, the looks
that they're choosing are not, they're
not like the best bag appeal. Yeah. But
I think they are doing what you're
referring to. They've just they've just
they've trained themselves. And I grew
up with cat piss. It was the ugliest
weed on the planet. And it was amazing
in the effect, the smell, the taste. I I
thought it was amazing, but it was ugly.
When we used to get it, it was like
little bracks in the bag. A lot of times
it was just shreds in a bag, and we pay
$60 for an eighth of it. Yeah. So, I
grew up like liking ugly weed. And so
that really kind of has taken away to
where okay, how does it smell? How does
it taste? And how does it make you feel?
Uh my friend died last year, 420, and I
went back to breeding for effect. Like
really, cuz that was kind of out of the
equation. I'm a chef by trade as well.
So it's like, okay, let's go for flavor.
I want flavor. I want the turppiest,
most unique flavor that I can get. If I
can get some green tea ice cream, I'm
loving it. You know, something
different. Yeah. But uh he passed and
you know, he was questioning me the week
before he passed. He really was kind of
like talking about breeding for effect
and he gifted me his seed collection uh
which the money from the seeds that
we're going to sell are going back to
his kids and on 420 we're actually
starting to launch those seeds on our
website. But he was all about breeding
for effect and his stuff tasted good and
we're fina hunting through some of the
stuff right now and it's like wow good
flavor good effect but really trying to
get that focus back on feel good weed.
How does it make you feel? Do you want
to feel up? Do you want to feel down?
and having that as part of the equation
instead of it just like does it taste
good? Yeah. The whole effect thing is
just a daunting way to approach things.
Uh and that goes back to like what my
tastes and my experiences are. Right.
Right. And I'm and I'm going through it
right now with my wife. She I married uh
her. She she just moved here from Costa
Rica like three and a half years ago.
And she just, you know, she up until the
day we met was still just smoking
whatever, you know, was available. There
was no strain. she if there was she
never paid attention to it even though
Costa Rica actually has a pretty good
indoors a lot of old school NorCal
surfers down there that set up grow ops.
Um, so they have some pretty good weed.
And um, and so we're going through it
and we're we're trying to find out like
she didn't believe she thought it was
just [ __ ] you know, that that weed
had different effects. Like she claimed
she never I think it just she was never
paying attention or she was smoking
always in the in the similar mood or,
you know, occasion, right? And as she
started to go through some of the stuff
that I'm bringing home and actually
she's an amazing joint and blunt roller
so she sees everything and started to
pay attention to the names and started
to realize that biscotti and biscotti in
particular but the gelato heavy fenos
give her what I would describe as as
like what what a typical sativa like you
know upbeat like a little bit of anxiety
you know the opposite of what most
people exactly And so it's like it's
unfolding right before me. You know,
sometimes I'm always like, ah, you know,
it's it's hard, but it's an amazing
plant. It's a complex plant. Um, and I
think what we've definitely noticed is,
you know, you whatever, you know, we're
experiencing and what we uh communicate
that we or we think you will experience,
that tends to be what most people are
are seeing. But then you're getting the
outliers where they're getting the exact
opposite. Totally. It's so subjective
and people are like, "Well, taste isn't
these things are." No, they are very
It's just like with wine or any sort of
food. But then with the effect, it adds
a whole another dimension to that. And
it's like cuz our body chemistries are
so uniquely different from one person to
the next, you can have different
effects. White Thorn Rose, I think, is a
good example where across the board, a
lot of people get that same feeling from
it. It's just feel good weed. I don't
think it's strong. I wouldn't classify
it as uh you know narcotic or sedative
uh or stimulating, right? It's somewhere
in the middle that just makes you feel
really good. And it's one of those
things I could smoke in the morning,
evening, afternoon, but I can do that
with sour diesel, too, right? So, we can
go back to sour. I I love sour diesel. I
love the way it makes me feel,
especially uh sunrown sour diesel. I I
smoked on a bunch of it for the last
like few months and it just makes me
feel really good. And sometimes we just
connect with different genetics, you
know. Yeah. I haven't had uh a good sour
diesel. So, there's been a bunch of
[ __ ] that's come through in the
recent months that it's like, nah, this
is like some watered down cross of it.
We keep trying to get cuts through our
program and nothing is the real deal.
So, I've refused to smoke any of it
because I can just tell I don't want to
ruin that memory because that memory is
still there, but it's it's it'll still
be there because I smoked so much of the
I smoked so much of this stuff trying to
get the sour back because we had I had
to go back to my aunt and uncle get it
six times where I lost it and finally
they got rid of it. And so, it' been
several years and this guy Dave I've
told this story in my podcast a bunch,
but this guy Dave from Budilero came up
at Reagan on the River last year was
like, "Tell me what you think of it."
And it was the real deal sour. And so I
ended up getting a pound to smoke. Um,
and I've been smoking off it. You know,
I I still have a little bit left. In
fact, that's awesome. Yeah, I'll I'll
get you some of it. But it's the real
deal. And the thing is is like I thought
maybe my memory was lying to me about
how good it was or how, you know, that
all this stuff is maybe these are just
versions of it, but the thing is is like
when you remember it uh like I did
because I had it so for so long and I
enjoyed it so much when I was younger.
Once you get it again, it's like it's
unmistakable. And there was a point
where we only had one sour. There wasn't
all these different sour. There was one
sour and it was like it had it was fy,
but it was also sweet and there was like
a little bit of a lemon component to it
and and but it was very unique and its
own thing and no matter who grew it, it
was always like that. Now I think some
of the genetics probably have drifted,
you know what I mean? through uh
potential pathogen contamination, hop
plate and void or systemic bacteria even
stuff like that where I think it could
have changed the expression and so maybe
some people even have the right cut but
they just can't get it to express
properly. But Dave's had the same cut
forever and his express is exactly how I
remembered it. Yeah, that's one of those
ones that you know is clearly on the
comeback right now. There's a lot of
people breeding with it. I've yet to see
anything that I haven't seen a lot, but
the stuff I've seen hasn't I haven't
gotten super excited yet, but I am
excited for the comeback. I'm excited
for comebacks in general. Dude, the
green, what do you think about that? All
this purple weed and I feel like it's
time for the green to come back. We
embarked on what we referred to as
sativa revival like 5 years ago where we
started a breeding project and it wasn't
just specifically green, but I mean most
sativas, you know, tend to tend to lean
green. And so that led us down this path
of all this old school stuff, you know,
some of it nasty and, you know, yeah, I
remember this was never good and or I
it's not that it wasn't good, it's not
my preference, you know, some of these
hazes and, you know, but it's led us
down a path and um I love it. I mean,
look, dude, just cuz something the
funniest thing about purple weed is once
I learned, which I and I learned it
pretty early. Once I learned that purple
meant nothing to quality Yeah. it it was
in my head except I could not stop my
own preference. Mhm. In term because
it's so visually appealing like when you
look at a a really welldone purple bud
that's got that nice gradient. Not solid
purple. I don't like it when they're
solid purple. I like it when it's like
what I would say like 7030 or 8020 and
it's like got that nice hue. Yeah. Like
I think gelade has a really nice when
done really well has a really nice blend
of of green but but to this day you know
visually I still prefer purple even
though I know it means nothing to
quality right but in terms of what I
prefer to smoke right now it is greenw
weed all day long it's it's J1 any of a
lot of stuff from the Jack Carrera you
know whole family area there's a lot of
good jacks that's what people don't
understand is in California people hate
Jack hair and uh I got to say hair like
terror cuz they you know but uh it's so
funny because like in California I think
it's the least liked strain maybe on in
in the in the streets blue dream is
disliked but on the in wreck people love
blue dream blue dream is a number one
selling strain
in California I love blue dream too in
in its own in its own right blue is
extremely as as a grower and someone who
used to grow blue I loved growing
growing Blue Dream. It was It was the
best. It makes you feel so good. Yeah.
It makes you feel good as a grower. Yes.
As a grower, too. I can do this. I
crushed I crushed. Yeah. I mean, my
friends thought I was such a good grower
when I was growing Blue Dream and it was
like when it first came around and
everyone's like, "Dude, like thought I
was the best grower." And a lot of it
had to do with the genetics. My OG
didn't, you know, it was OG and it was
good, but I struggled with OG. I'd have
good harvest and bad harvest and every
single harvest didn't check the boxes
necess necessarily. But Blue Dream is
like every single one of them was good.
And sometimes it was a little more
sticky or a little bit, you know, little
bit brighter, but it it was loud. It
was, you know, when I used to grow it,
it was amazing. So, yeah. So, we're So,
I love bringing back old stuff. I love
that the green stuff's coming back
around. We, you know, we've been through
every OG that we can find. We finally
launched one that we thought was good.
It was Ghost OG. And um and and it's
pretty good. It's it's it's really good.
I'm really pleased with what we're
putting out, but it's still not that
that that original that memory. Yeah, I
think Blem's unruly OG. I think they do
a fantastic job. I've been wondering
that. I saw that nug. I was like, is
that really OG? That is the Florida
crippy. I actually showed Fletcher. I
was I was hanging out with at an event.
Fletcher was sitting at the table,
showed him. He He thought it was like
the Hawaiian skunk dog or the Maui skunk
dog. And I got it as the
crippy and uh it's definitely got the
nose burning gas and it definitely is
strong, but this washes and it grows
like a sativa. It's got narrow leaves
and really, you know, it stacks pretty
well, but it has really thin leaves and
uh you just don't see gas like this any
No, you don't. Um I miss it just like I
miss the sour diesel, but I do see some
pretty good OG from time to time. Like I
said, unrulies is pretty or blem unruly
is pretty good. Like the nose on it.
Sometimes their structure is a little
like, you know, the buds are a little
kind of weak like they look like
something might be wrong with the plant,
but the smell and the effect are and and
the and the flavor are what I pretty
close to what I remember. Brian from
Vital, he brings down some every once in
a while. He's got some freaking
phenomenal OG and I don't share it with
anybody. That's when you know it's good
is when I like keep it to myself. We get
some batches of the dirt Skittles that's
grown, soil grown Skittles. Oh, nice.
And I just keep that mostly for myself.
Like I'll get small amounts. I give it a
couple friends and then I just make sure
to pile it away. And I I just really
enjoy certain things. And Skittles is
one of those ones I still love smoking
Skittles. Um I I smoke everything, but
you know, Skittles I go back to. Uh and
I don't think candy's going away. I
don't think it's going away anytime
soon. People, it's just it's too easy
for people to smoke candy. Uh, you know,
people that aren't even connoisseurs,
it's like they taste and then they're
like, "Oh, tastes like something
familiar." Yeah. I do love the taste of
good green weed, though. Like I I miss
that part of it the most, I think. Yeah.
I mean, I'd say the J1 and and we just
recently brought it back and started
doing some breeding with it, but it's
probably in my top three strains of all
time, but also for sure my top my top
green weed. It's just it just makes me
feel happy, you know, and that at the
end of the day, like, you know, I'm
older now. I'm I'm got a lot of
responsibility. I've got three kids. I'm
busy. And I need something that can give
me like I need something that's additive
on top of all the other [ __ ] you know,
where even if I think I got a day on the
couch or a day just chilling by the pool
and something comes up, I'm like, I'm
there. And like the a lot of the green
strains are that for me right now.
That's why we've done so much with with
the sativas um the tropical Z we did
which is a uh Tom Hill Haze um by GDP
that cross then crossed by um Zeno and
it's just real light and fun and
flavorful and like no stress, no anxiety
and no nap time and I don't need more
than one burrito, right? you know, I'm
really enjoying that like that that
place right now. And that most purple
weed doesn't doesn't afford me that I
can't smoke anything purple on a Sunday
morning, you know, before I embark on
whatever we're doing as a family that
day. Um, unless I can convince them it's
movie day all day, you know, it's like
it's rainy day outside. I got ZDP coming
down that we got ZDP. ZDP. It's exactly
what you think when you hear ZDP. It's
like exact because it's it leans heavy
on the granddaddy and then it has a
candy finish to it, but it's very much
like nostalgic. I I'm bringing back some
nostalgic stuff like I got a dream
candy. We're calling it that's the
working name of it right now is Dream
Candy, but someone else has the name
Dream Candy. So have to call it Loud
Dream Candy. But uh it's it's a double
LCG which is a runt S1 and then we put
that with the Blue Dream. And the thing
is with Blue Dream, that's another
breeder that's very stable in the sense
that there's only like four phenotypes
that really expresses an S1 and then you
put that with something like Lemon
Cherry and you're going to get uh some
stable expressions in there and you're
going to get the real blue dream with a
little bit of candy. And that's what we
we we found three that we really liked
that lean towards different things, but
I really like the old school with just a
little bit hint of candy. So, so I want
to hear more about the ZDP though. How
have you grown it already? We've grown
it. We've grown. How does
that could something yield lower than
Skittles? Like, yes, you can cross it
with GDP. You can cross it with GDP and
you're going to get a low yield and
you're going to get a slow veg. Right.
So, it's it's everything that growers
hate, but everything that smokers love.
Right. Right. And I think this one
that's where it's trending right now.
Find that pocket. Oh, really? It might
wash better. It'll wash better than
Skittles. I guarantee you that cuz
Skittles is washing like one and a half
to 2%. So if it and I love I love rosin
too. So I still I I do more of the rosin
in the morning. Like I'll do dabs in the
morning before I go to the gym. Uh but I
don't dab throughout the day because it
makes me super tired. But if I do one
good one in the morning before I go to
the gym, I'm not smelling like Juan over
at UFC gym that, you know, he comes in
wreaking of his joints, you know, and I
I'm I'm I'm high, but I just I I take
the nice little dab. Yeah. I've the
reason I haven't gotten too much into
into dabbing is I don't know, call me
lazy, call me whatever, but I just don't
like keeping the rig all clean. Like
I've done it and it's like gets all
gross and and I'm just not into it. But
someone recently gifted me the um the
puff code like the the pen looking thing
where you flip and that thing has been
fantastic for me. Yeah, I got a focus I
[ __ ] love. I got a focus view one for
you today, too. So they're competitors,
but I like both brands for their own
things. Sam is a great guy. He's also a
good friend of mine. We do events, but
I'll give you some rosin. So I I
recently got heavy into understanding
rosin for breeding purposes, right? So
like I just I don't want to be an expert
in making it, but I really need to
understand it more. The different
microns, which ones to combine. Um and
then also when I'm breeding, what are we
really breeding for? What kind of heads
are we breeding for? All these different
things. And so I took a deep dive into
it. Uh, I work with SF Canana and so
they've been working on some rosin
projects with some of their stuff and
we're we're going to be producing some
washers and I felt like I had to educate
myself so I started smoking a lot more
rosin. Also hash holes and it brings
back to like I like hash holes. Yeah.
And it really brings back to like that
umbrella model where you have to have a
bunch of different product SKs anymore.
You can't just settle on flour. Now I'm
like okay well I'm not doing the
cultivating but with my cultivation
partners I want to be able to bring
flour. We want to bring joints. We want
to bring hand rolls and pre-rolls.
Something that's economical. Uh rosin,
hash holes. I think hash holes is a
no-brainer. And people love hash holes
for the turpps. So, but it's not the
most economical way to smoke rosin
because it's like I put a half gram in
there and it takes me a while to smoke a
half gram of rosin, but I can smoke a
joint with a half gram of rosin in the
evening.
That's a power joint, right? That's a
power joint. Yeah. But you know, and the
funny thing is, so I want to be able to
roll them because I want to teach people
how to my guys how to roll them so I can
QC everything. And so I wanted to learn
how to roll hash holes properly. And
there's a huge learning curve to that.
Yeah, I haven't tried. I I should say I
have tried. I have not rolled them very
well, very successful. I've actually
done them in blunts. I I really enjoy
blunts. Like blunts is probably my
preferred method. Um although it's
started to wear on the throat a little
bit. Yeah. And so and because of the
volume we're we're asked to smoke on a
regular basis because of our breeding
program, the joints are a lot easier.
Yeah. Um but I can't roll like Yeah.
Like these like these these beautiful I
can't do that. So I had my wife take a
class from from one of the h from one of
the hand rollers up in Sacramento. Not a
class. I was like which one of is it? It
was Christian from um Sacramento. He he
he taught her and I was just like cuz he
rolls some of our stuff for some of our
events sometimes. I'm like, "Hey, can
you just sit with her?" And uh and teach
her cuz she likes doing it. She's good
really good with her hands and and so
she does them when she's when she's
feeling up to it. So I'm just like I've
sort of backed away from it. I'm like
I'll let you do these. I I got a lot of
other [ __ ] I got to do. Totally. Well,
yeah. And I feel like Yeah. It's one of
those things. It's there's a pretty big
learning curve to all of it. And but
joints is it's the best way for feno
hunting to actually test your work,
right? I feel like if you want to put
the even playing field out there, you
can't just give people a bag of weed
anymore. You have to give them I didn't
realize that. That was a mistake. Cuz
then people take it put it, you know
what I mean? Are you smoking bongs with
it? What are you doing? You know, and
it's like if you give them a joint,
you're going to give them the same size
joint. It's gonna burn pretty much the
same depending on how they're dragging
it of course, but like they're going to
get a similar experience than if
somebody's taking a bong hit or
someone's rolling their own pinner
joint, you know? It's like cuz I feel
like there's the perfect, you know, I
like the 10 mm organ tips right now.
That's what I'm pretty stuck on with the
elements paper. And I I like a tight
grind so that you get, you know, it's
like it's one of those ones where it
checks the box, too, where you get that
nice white ash. And the ash has a lot to
do with how you roll it. people don't
understand that it's not just how you I
mean flushing of course you know I think
flushing is super important these days
but also how you roll it uh how tight it
is all those things and then the grind
on it like if you're going to roll a
blunt you want a really like a coarse
grind whereas if you want to roll a
joint like that and you want it to burn
perfect you're going to want a fine
grind yeah so you know Ted was really
beating his drum he's like we got to we
got to focus on the white ash we got to
focus on it to the R&amp;D department they
were like nah we're not sure we're
bought in that this is actually a thing.
And so they did a deep dive, you know,
interviewing people, talk, you know, we
went so far, we bought a smoke machine
because we couldn't smoke or we didn't
buy one. We made one this smoke machine.
So it pulses and it couldn't smoke I
think six or seven joints at once and it
like it has a hood on it so it pulses
and everyone laughs. Oh, I want to I'll
do it. You don't have to have that. Like
you have no idea. Anyone who said they
will do it can't keep up with the
volumet. end up quitting or they can't
give notes, they just can't keep up with
the program whatsoever. So, we did that
um just to be able to test that the ash
of stuff to to do it at volume cuz we're
looking at outliers of white ash, you
know, assuming that it's rolled
correctly. But in that whole process,
they realize it has to do with the roll,
the grind, the moisture percentage, the
paper that you're using, how the thing
was lit, you know, what what what did
you use torch? Did you use lighter?
Like, and there's all these things, come
to find out also that you can do to get
that really beautiful Instagram video.
You know, there's things you can
specifically do to get the white ash
looking a specific way. They'll hit it
with the torch afterwards just to I
mean, I see all kinds of stuff. And I
don't I mean, I've been smoking weed for
30 years, and we didn't really talk
about ash very much. I mean, black ash,
it was kind of weird back in the day. I
never thought black ash was good, but I
didn't see cigarette white ash or cigar
white ash until maybe four or five years
ago at the earliest. And now it's like a
thing where it's like, oh, this is a box
that has to be checked. And I'm not 100%
sold on all of it. I do understand that
it it's another one of those things,
especially if it's flushed correctly.
And you talk you talk about how it drips
and you know the the oil ring on there.
I think sure that's great, but not
everything has the same oil ring. It's
it's definitely specific to different
genetics. Um, but you know, I've been
taking deep dives in all these
directions to making sure we're ahead of
the curve with all this stuff, too. It's
like I feel like that stuff's important.
Yeah, we So, we got the smoke machine
and then they figured out all the
components. They figured, you know, they
homogenized, make sure everything that
we were rolling. We figured out the way
that most people were considered, you
know, it's in a joint like that, a
certain grind, certain moisture
percentage. And then we measure the ash
color to see if there's genetic
outliers, right? And so we were
collecting the ash and then putting them
in this thing that measures different
tones of of white all the way up to
black. And so we're actually able to s
assign an exact objective score. Wow.
Using, you know, this this this the
scale of of white is white versus black
is black and everything in between. You
guys notice a difference in what do you
mean in like equality? it. I mean, with
a white ash, if it's whiter ash, does it
translate into a better quality product
as far as flavor or
So flavor is the priority and not always
when it tastes really good does it burn
the whitest. Sure. But never when it
burns really white does it taste bad, if
that makes sense. So that the white ash
only helps it, but it is not a a a a
mandatory qualifier. Um it doesn't have
to burn crazy white to to meet to check
all the other boxes. And we do all sorts
of blind trials and you know, so we've
been able to figure out like white ash
is a plus. It's an it's additive, but
something can pass without having the
whitest of ash. And it's a huge genetic
component. Like RS11 as an example, and
it's one of the reasons it's bred with
so much. It just burns white, like crazy
white. You breed with it, it helps it.
Um and and then but the other thing
we've noticed is flower structure plays
a big role. So we have four flowering
facilities, three in California and then
one in Arizona.
And we're we started noticing there was
there was you know the flower from two
of the facilities was was burning whiter
than the others just consistently time
and time again. And then we were really
trying to because we're using same SOPs,
same everything. There should be no
difference. We started noticing minor
differences in the flower structure and
the brack size. And we noticed that the
smaller the brack the more of the bracks
there are Yeah. and the the smaller they
were um the better it burned. Um so our
our our flagship facility in in in
Northern California in Sacramento, which
has always put out like the best stuff,
doesn't have the whitest burning stuff,
but the flower structure is different.
Um the weed also gets more purple at
that facility. It's actually our oldest
of the modern facilities, so there's
some things that are a little different
at this one. Yeah. So, it gets more
purple than the other facility. Um, I've
also heard people say like the darker
the like when it's really purple, um,
sometimes it get ash. Yeah, I've noticed
that. So, it's all just exciting. Like,
we try to not come to any hard and fast
conclusions. Like a lot of pe folks in
the industry like just come down hard
and it's just like this is because of
this. wine is like and the reality is
like there's very few scientists in this
space and it's not to knock any of the
work anyone's done like we've all come a
long way with very little against all
against a lot of odds right um but I
think one of the most important things
is we all remain you know open-minded
that there's going to be information
that comes along that is counter to what
you've believed and preached and taught
for sometimes decades like blurals you
the the purple LEDs, they were so bad.
And and this is an example of just one
of the many things that I've seen over
the years where I'm like, I'm never
using LEDs cuz these blurals, it's good
though, right? Dude, got that that nose
burning, you know? It's nostalgic from
the 90s, right? I feel like that's what
I love about it. But I've seen so many
things over the years where I'm like, u
flowers suck. Now I breed autoflowers,
right? I've been breeding autoflowers
for the last seven years. About Yeah,
about seven years now. I said
autoflowers suck. I'd never work with
them. LEDs, I'm never going to use them.
I use LEDs now. Under canopies I was
excited about and now I I guess under
canopies originally Tim was Bobby Bags
worked with you and was you guys were
doing under canopies at your facility a
long time ago. Yeah. So Ian um Ian
Justice who's our our head of
cultivation and R&amp;D, he came from
Driscoll's background in controlled
plant agriculture
um or I forget what the term is. It's
not controlled plant, but something like
that. I went to school for growing
plants indoors. Long story short, and
controlled environment agriculture, CA,
I think that's what it is. Uh, went to
school for that. Done a ton of work on
genetics. Did a lot of work with
Driscolls. Um, did proprietary created a
proprietary technique for growing uh
blueberries in in pots like no one had
ever done it before. Said it couldn't be
said it couldn't be done. He did it
increased yield. So, he's got a really
interesting background. And in his first
few weeks, he's looking at the plant,
you know, one of our purple strains, and
it's like top two/3s is purple, bottom
third is green. What's going on? This is
not this is not right. Like, this
shouldn't look like this. Yeah. And he
had some LEDs uh from a project. They
were GE LEDs that he had from a project
from from sidelighting on blackberry
plants because I guess they go grow
blackberries really tall. Oh, wow. And
and so they they had experimented with
sidelighting. I guess it wasn't worth
the, you know, the output that it
additional output in blackberry. So, he
just like had them in his garage and he
brought them in, figured rigged them up
and put them under our plants and first
round was like 25% yield increase. Wow.
And it was like what? And you know,
everyone's like, "Oh, the numbers." They
were like looking back at the numbers.
We didn't have as good as data
collection back then. We're like, "Is
this real?" Kept running them and it was
like, "Holy shit." You know, it's more
purple. Yeah. And it was more purple. So
like the buds at the bottom, some of the
buds closest to the light were some of
the best buds where that [ __ ] would have
made it into trim or into pre-rolls
maybe, you know. Yeah. Or just gotten
rid of, you know, stripping that canopy.
I mean, I believed in stripping the
undercarriage until I met until I met
Tim. Until Faven, you know, he gave us
some favins. And I'm a believer. Not
only just a believer, but I I I think
through trials, we test everything here.
We're R&amp;D facility, so it's always okay.
Well, let's use a control and then test
this against the control. And uh light
lifts is another one. It's like I like
light lifts because you can basically uh
tune your lights down. You you're not
running them as as hot. So, you're
basically not using as much electricity.
You can bring them right down on the
plants and uh with the lights we're
using, it works great. So, and then
combined with the favins, now we're
saving a bunch of money. Yeah. Um it it
was a big difference, a big change. You
know, I think Tim or Bobby Bags, he was
working for us during that time and then
went off. I mean, we have no interest in
being in the light business. We It's
hard enough doing what we're trying to
do and across. He is killing it. Yeah,
we're stoked for him. We're happy for
them. Me and Kevin go way back. Like
Kevin's such a good dude. He's always
been solid. Like, you know, that whole
hydroponics world was so weird for a
while. It was just like you didn't even
you know you kind of like had to have
it's the weirdest thing where you walk
into a retail store and you have to have
trust with someone like a certain level
so you could talk openly right and like
some of the stores you couldn't build
that and so you really had to like the
guy and trust the guy and like start
talking talking about tomatoes. Yeah.
It's like [ __ ] stop. I hated that [ __ ]
It was like so ridiculous. And so I I
would really choose who I'd work with.
I'm like, "Okay, I don't expect you to
talk like that in the first few
transactions, but dude, I've been coming
here for 6 months. Like, can we have an
open conversation? There's no one in the
store right now. Let's talk business."
And some of them wouldn't do that, and
it was annoying. Kevin was just [ __ ]
he was just And I forget his partner,
but Kevin had a partner um that ended up
getting locked up and doing some time,
but we first dealt with his partner, and
that was like the coolest dude I had
ever dealt with. I'm so bummed I forget
his name. dude is such an OG, but he
went away for like four years on some
federal charge. But that dude was so
[ __ ] cool. But then I got to meet
Kevin because that guy went away and
Kevin had been running something else
and then came and yeah, Kevin was just
is, you know, we don't really deal with
hydro stores anymore. We're like a lot
of direct to supplier type
relationships, but he is he's the OG.
He's the goat of of the hydro stores in
Sacramento for sure. Yeah. Yeah, it's
funny the OGs that are still around is
like it's pretty amazing that industry
has completely changed too, you know,
with cultivation facilities coming
online because originally they were
dealing with people that had garages
uh maybe 8 10 lights at the most and
then it turned into 50 lights and then
50 lights turned into a thousand lights.
Yeah. Real quick. But yeah, and then
that whole infrastructure changed and
then you know you're and then prices
plummeted. So you're like trying to
competing with the internet, you know,
too. It's like wild. And then though and
then the suppliers are coming direct to
us. They started marketing direct to us
or not even marketing just straight up,
you know, cold calling like, "Hey, like
there's no, you know, buy in bulk, buy
our stuff, ship you a pallet, try this
out." Y Yeah. And then Ian had all these
contacts. Oh, so so anyways, we worked
uh with GE over the years and GE was not
interested in targeting the cannabis
community. They're like, "They don't
pay. they they're a pain in the ass to
deal with, you know, and we're not
interested. But Ian, because of who he
was and the language he could speak,
they were willing to talk to him. So, we
worked with GE over the years and we're
on iteration five that they since sold
the that component of their company to
some other, right, some other lighting
company who we have no relationship with
and now we're looking at all the under
canopies that have come up since and
we're going to, you know, see which ones
we want to move to. But you know it was
him and the l you know who he was that
allowed us to create that relationship
with GE at the time and go through
different iterations different diodes
you know spacing and and spectrums and
then created that and um yeah they've
been great for us and it's been I mean
it's the the most recent I mean I don't
know what's come to the hydro I I guess
like the the whole Aoya like the the
monitoring that's probably even though
that's been around for I think a long
time. It's it's now if you don't have
that it's like what are you doing you
know environmental control like that
crop steering. So I think aside from um
that I think that you know the under
canopy lighting was the biggest
revolution to happen to indoor cannabis
farming meaning in recent years. I mean
before those two it was what
double-ended bulbs and you know
seriously it was which was like
2012 2013 came online before. Oh my god,
I forgot about EPAPS. It's crazy that
certain names of products bring on a
nostalgic feel. Totally. I'm like, it's
just thinking about that time and that
excitement level like we're going to
make so much more money and then totally
you did, but it was also hard and there
was this whole learning curve and and
you know, we used to run ducted hoods
and now we're running, you know, bear
bulb and we had to re readjust all our
calcs on on everything. It was crazy.
And most people that were moving forward
from a long time ago, they didn't have
enough dehumidification. We didn't
calculate that correctly. We didn't know
any better. Um, but yeah, and I think a
lot of people still don't have enough
dew, you know, and that that's one of
the things that happened. So Ian came in
and we we introduced, you know, we did
small trials, so the yield increase was
a percentage of the room or percentage
of the canopy, right? And then when we
did whole rooms, it was like the whole
thing broke. And we're like, okay, when
you all of a sudden increase yield by
between 20 and 30%. Yeah. That's a whole
lot of transpiration that wasn't
happening before. And now all your calcs
are gone out the window. And you got to
luckily we had extra power, but a lot of
people just, you know, their rooms every
they put in every light they could with
their power service and an extra, you
know, 705 or whatever the the the
dehuses are. That's not there's no room
for that. you got to cut lights and
people don't want to cut lights and so
they're growing and they sacrifice
quality betritis and they deal with PM
and other other issues like that and
then they just they're in the cycle of
death you know and they they can't seem
to get out of it and no one wants to the
owner doesn't want to hear you know that
they got to cut lights out and it
doesn't believe the grower doesn't think
the grower is doing a good job or
whatever the system is and they just
they just circle down the drain. Well,
it's like once you get betritis or some
of these fungal pathogens in your air
systems, it's like then you almost have
to completely replace your air system.
You can scrub to a degree. You can use
UV. There's there's a there's ways you
can treat it, but man, if your drying
room has uh betritis circulating in it,
it's going to you're going to have
problems and it's going to be on the
surface of the plant. It's it's a little
bit different, but like it won't affect
you. Sometimes it's a couple weeks after
you put it in the bag, you have
problems. Yeah. I've seen a little bit
of that going on. Oh, yeah. Yeah. We've
we've seen it all. In fact, on on the
topic of of pathogens, you know, we're
dealing with aspiggilis right now. And
that sucks. It does because it's also
not harmful at the, you know, at just
any just the presence of it isn't
necessarily harmful. It's everywhere.
It's everywhere. Literally, it's it's in
this room right now. I guarantee it.
It's on us. It's I heard it's in your
nose. It's in baby food. like it's
[ __ ] everywhere and it's a non it's a
tech detect or non-detect test in
California which is just ridiculous. In
in Arizona we you have the option on
your testing to choose for I think it's
the presence of aspiggillis or the
presence of the mico myiotoxin or
whatever that it creates right which it
rarely turns into. We've had we're like
at
0.01% fail rate over the years in
Arizona and we're at like you know five
six% in California. Same weed, same
yield, same everything. And no one's
dying. No one has gotten sick. No one's
reported anything in in Arizona. Um in
other states it's total yeast and mold
and those are at different levels. But
it's a arguably a much better
measurement, right? Because total yeast
and mold can be a bunch of things. I
don't even pretend to know if that's
relevant. Yeah, but what I do know, what
we're dealing with in California is not
it's not practical. It doesn't make
sense. And not only are we dealing with
it, like we don't think that we have an
outsized amount of aspergillis fails, we
have become the target of of battling
between labs. We were working with one
lab and then we pulled our business
because they weren't giving us, you
know, their results started to vary
significantly from where they were and
we're like, "This doesn't make sense.
Either something's wrong in your
protocol or we don't know what's going
on, but it doesn't work for our business
anymore." So, we went to another lab and
we told them the reason why. Well, they
worked with some other labs who are also
kind of on that end of the stick where
they they're holding up some high and
mighty posture of they're, you know,
they're doing things one way and these
other labs aren't doing the right way
and they're all on this this war path
attacking the other labs. It's the
worst, you know, cuz there are haters
out there and they are just looking to
come after you and looking to come after
me and everybody else and it's like it's
so crazy that you can do that. And the
thing is is of course there's going to
be variance. thing is is you're testing
like if you have a five pound bin and
you're taking a random sample out of
there, you don't know if that was from
the top, the bottom where it was. You
know what I mean? Even if you
homogenized a bunch of it, which would
give you a better result, it's not going
to be 100% accurate. So, so they turned
us in and then it resulted in the dcc
going and pulling stuff off shelves.
Like, they're pulling stuff off shelves
that's been in market for 3 months. Like
it sucks that unfortunately our product
sometimes sits in market for 3 months
like what is the environment that that
store what's the temperature of their
storage like did their AC go out did you
know did it was it during rainy season
and they I mean it shouldn't penetrate
right but you never know what conditions
are there and it's like and not to
mention it passed DC it passed you know
COA and it's in market well now they're
going on a a witch hunt and they're just
they're coming they're pulling samples
and then they come back and pull samples
from the same batches again. We're
getting recalls right now from samples
that were p pulled in January and
they're just issuing a recall right now.
It's like if you're truly after the
health and wellness of the consumer
base. Why did it take you 3 months to
from the time you pulled the sample to
the time you What is your testing
protocol? Guess what? What is your
testing protocol? They were they were
given 15 million in the budget to build
a lab. Six years, no lab. There's no dcc
lab. We don't know which lab they're
testing with. Are they testing with one
of our competitors? That seems to be a
conflict of interest. Totally. Uh are
they, you know, meaning a one of the
competing labs. It's a competitor,
right? Is that that's a conflict of
interest. They won't tell you their
protocol. They won't tell you who
they're testing with. They say, "No, you
we will give you zero information. Pull
$100,000 of product off the shelf this
week. pull 200 off the shelf next week.
We're up to a million dollars of
embargoed product and zero transparency
into what is going on. We have initiated
every possible effort across our supply
chain where you know we're looking at
every single product that's out there
short of microwaving the weed. There's
no aspillus is [ __ ] I know. It's like
that's what Australia and these other
countries are doing. You get this weed
and it's just [ __ ] zapped. It looks
like a [ __ ] frozen dinner, you know,
that you let defrost in the in the sun.
It's disgusting. I'm not a big fan of
cryocured weed either. Just putting that
on the table, guys. It's not the I mean,
I think it has its purpose maybe for
extraction, but I hate astronaut ice
cream weed. So, it's uh it's one of
those things. But I got a question for
you. So, I see this farm-to-table model
that I would love to be able to execute
properly and I see a lot of companies
doing their best and I don't know what
the solution is. I I realize
distributors need refrigerated trucks.
They need to have a temperature
controlled environment where they're
storing it in. Similar to how Logo Logan
has their beer across the United States
and across the world. It goes
refrigerated till the time the consumer
gets it. I think that would be ideal.
But it's like how do we solve this
problem to where a consumer goes in for
the first time and they hear all about
connected then they go buy it and
they're not satisfied with the product
and it's not because it's not good. It's
because it's 6 months old. You know I
and I don't know what the solution is.
what's your opinion? So, we're working
on that. Not I mean it it's for multiple
reasons, but you know, for to have good
sales, good and accurate sales and
demand forecasting data. We're trying to
get these retailers. So, I'll start at
the retail level, right? Like there
shouldn't be six-month old product on
the shelves. Yeah. And for that, we need
visibility into the retailers inventory.
And in every other CPG product that is
out there, it's in the b it's in the
best interest of the retailer to give
the the the supplier um insight into
what is on their shelf cuz we don't want
six-month old product on the shelf. I
don't care how much money I got to lose
if that didn't sell. We want that
product. We want to replace it with
fresh. But the unfortunately the retail
network is is this hodge podge of people
that have you know some of these guys
including myself we've been in business
for 15 years. We started on a shoestring
budget and then you know we've developed
over time. Well, okay, you've developed,
but now we've got to, you know, we've
got to further develop and you got to
open yourselves up to to some of this uh
data and allow the the provider to get
insight into what's on the shelf cuz
that's that's a product quality issue
first and foremost. Um, but then it goes
in, you know, and it plays into some of
these other topics that we're talking
about aspiggillis and a lot of these
retailers are super resistant. It's like
as if they give up some of their data
that it's like, you know, giving up some
secret proprietary information. Yeah.
It's just like, but it's what's best for
you. Like, if we have data into what's
on your shelf, we'll come we'll swap it
out. We'll and and we can backfill. By
the way, if you sold out of something
fast, we should you should want us to
backfill it and put it in. Yeah. If if
it's empty, if that if the spot for
Biscotti is empty on your shelf cuz you
sold it so fast, you're losing revenue.
We're losing revenue. give us
visibility, we'll we'll get back in and
back fill it or take off the old stuff.
Yeah, more data is better for the entire
industry. And we see a lot of like
people like holding stuff real close to
their chest. Totally. That has to change
the the California retail the entire
supply chain in California needs to
mature and we need an overhaul. I think
for sure we we do and and it, you know,
the retailers play a big role in that.
Um and at the regulatory level, I mean,
I just like I don't even know. I mean,
they're they don't know what to look
for. They don't seem to be interested in
in, you know, communicating with the
industry. It's almost like they see us
as their opponent. So, it's like we
we've we've struggled to have like a
really solid voice, a unified voice. I
think a lot of people this industry
historically, particularly in
California, has struggled to find a
unified voice. There's a lot of egos.
people can't seem to get along and
people can't seem to, you know, it's
like we all have a lot of things we'd
like solved, right? But like we should
narrow them down to like three and
tackle those three as a group and we'll
get to the other 15 some point or maybe
never. But if we tackle the biggest
things together, at least we're making
an impact. And right now feels like a
lot of everyone's just like on their own
island and willing to stay that way.
Mhm. Um, you know, C Elliott at
Catalyst, he he started a trade group.
It's started as a retail trade
association, but it's already expanded
into brands and I think, you know, he's
got some really he's got some of the
biggest names in the retail space and
some really solid brands. We're we're
members of it. Um, I think that has a
good opportunity. He's got, you know, a
pretty good legal mind. He also
understands the regulators. He's not
afraid to, you know, shake a stick at
them. Um, and I think that's critical.
We've got to unify. We've got to create
a voice to try to get some of these
things. You know, what is best, you
know, for at the end of the day, if you
solve what's best for the consumer.
Yeah. You know, you probably solve a lot
of things. And it's not all about
safety. Consumer's pretty safe. Like a
lot of people have been smoking weed
from a lot of bad sources with a lot of
bad [ __ ] on it for a long time. And I'm
glad that that time's done. Yeah, but
let's not over right now. It's being
overregulated out of fear. It's react.
It's reactionary. It's the most
regulated agriculture product in
existence. There's nothing that's
regulated like cannabis to that level,
right? And it's definitely
overregulated. And you know, it's it's
sad to a degree. I mean, I think all
these things will get worked out over
time hopefully. Uh at least that's the
hope. It's just like how how many good
brands or how many good companies, how
many good products will fail to continue
to see the light of day or you know in
that time. It's almost like like I'm not
a big conspiracy theorist, but it's
almost like you could put on your foil
hat and be like if there was to be a
bigger play to really consolidate this
industry down to, you know, whoever can
who's ever really got the biggest wallet
and who can stand here the longest.
Yeah. You know, it feels like this would
be a pretty good way to do it. How
they're going about it just feels like
that's going on right now for a lot of
us and and it's really unfortunate. And
then you've got the hemp thing, you
know, which is like it's it's honestly
laughable really like what's happening.
It's like look at Texas, right? I think
that's changing in Texas, but yeah, it's
Well, they're trying to, but some people
think it's not going to go because
there's so much money behind this M
thing. It's like all of us in the
cannabis space have tried so long and
put so much blood, sweat, and tears and
so much money into this and then we're
just watching this thing happen.
Totally. You know, and a lot of us are
are playing a role in it. And look, I
don't fall on either side. I'm like I'm
like I'm a get money. Like if you can
get your money, you get your money. And
I'm never going to I don't want to hate
I don't hate on anyone in the hemp
space. I'm hating on the regulators.
It's like make up your [ __ ] mind for
sure. Like I just want I just want to
know what's what. And if that's if I
need to go play in that space to to
appreciate what full-blown legalization
looks like, fine. like that I'm going to
go do that and I'll keep this, you know,
this propped up over here. Problem is
they keep moving the needle. So the
second you jump over there, they're
like, "Nope, now that's not allowed."
And then you're stuck back over here and
then they allow it again. And I think
it's just such an unstable market right
now. It's really hard to tell which
direction. Someone who is a hard worker
and wants to invest their money
properly, it's almost impossible to
guess what's next right now. Yeah. And
and so once again, it like goes back to
the wallet and and the pair of, you
know, nuts you've got. It's like how big
and how crazy are you willing to go and
how are you going to push it? And time
and time again, it's those folks that
seem to like I've just always taken the
stance. I'm like, oh, you know, cuz I
[ __ ] dude, I used to do everything
illegal and I had all those sleepless
nights and you know, every van was
potentially the end of my life. like
every van parked on my street ever was
potential. I was always thought that
there could be someone someone in it and
I don't miss those days at all. And but
then it's like it feels like it's going
back to it's not quite like that but
it's like you got to be willing to just
take all these crazy risks and and just
put yourself out there. I mean weed is
being shipped internationally right now
on a scale and I'm not talking about the
legal shipment. So like what is
happening, you know, outside the legal
network that is coming from the legal
network is is [ __ ] mindblowing. And
it's wild. And the thing is is they
could be making tax money off this. So
much so much money in international, you
know, I I think there's all these
international markets and we we produce
the best cannabis in the world, right?
The United States. I think that's not
even a question. It's not even a
question. Yeah. It's And the thing is is
we could be exporting to Germany right
now. Everyone wants our product, right?
The thing is is we're not allowed to
export it and it just sucks, right? It
sucks for a lot of us that I think would
be benefiting from it, including the
government. Yeah. It's disheartening.
And I think there was it was either
today or yesterday there's a new article
that or a new, you know, mention says
White House does not see rescheduling as
a priority. Yeah. Big surprise. I mean,
it's just once again, you go back to the
tinfoil hat. It's like are we being
given like a about as clear message as
we'll ever get like this is not the path
like this will not the race to the
bottom and then everyone that survives
this race is going to be very successful
I and I'm I'm in it for the long haul.
You're in it for the long haul. I'm not
going anywhere. I'm not going anywhere.
I don't have anywhere else to go for one
thing. That's the I've come to that
realization. I'm like what? There's
nowhere else to go. This is the life
I've chosen. No. But it sounds like you
are. You're not going to go back to the
kitchen, but you're going to bring this
into it. I'm going to Everything I do
circles back to genetics, right? So,
everything we do, we are going to do a
cooking show. And I love I love being
able to cook on that level. But if I had
to cook every day, I'm I'm a workaholic.
So, if I cook, I want to if I own a
restaurant, I'm going to work there 16
hours a day, seven days a week. And I
don't that's not the life I want to
live, right? But I love cooking for my
friends. And I love being able to
provide an The thing is is like with
cannabis and all these things, I provide
an experience, right? If I can provide
an experience for people, that's what I
love more than anything. Especially for
my friends, because I feel like that's
what life's all about, too. If you break
it all down, life's about experiences.
Like, those are the things you can't
really buy. Yeah, you can buy a
vacation, but it's those experiences you
have on those vacations that make it
memorable. Yeah. And uh you know, I've
had some amazing experiences with
friends and I've cooked for a lot of a
lot of people and had great experiences.
I think they've had great experiences
from it, too. But I get personal
satisfaction from providing the
experience. And so doing a cooking show,
that's that's a lot of fun. Now, how
will we be incorporated into the cooking
show? Like, is it is the weed going to
be in the food or is it just going to
No, no, I don't put weed in food. That
is not, you know, I first of all, I
can't handle it. So, no. I I enjoy rosin
gummies from time to time or whatever. I
get the 10 milligrams and I bite a
little piece off them. You know what I
mean? I'm not I'm not really Everyone's
like, "Are you serious?" I'm like, "I am
the biggest lightweight when it comes to
edibles." Like, give me some mushrooms.
I don't care. I'll eat I'll eat the [ __ ]
out of some mushrooms. When it comes to
edibles, I go light. But the thing is I
smoke a lot, right? So I enjoy. So what
we're doing and my show was I was just
going to cook for my friends and of
course my partner, he's like, "Okay, so
how do we bring this back to genetics?"
I got this idea and so we're going to do
icas style and we're going to do like,
you know, five to seven courses and with
each course you're either going to get a
dab or you're going to smoke a joint or
you're going to try one of these new
devices that people have and it's going
to be with our genetics, right? So, we
pair the the food with the different
courses. It's all bite-sized stuff. And
then I got Cubone, who's Snoop Dog's
personal chef. He's going to come on as
my sue chef initially. No way. And uh
it's going to be a lot of fun. And then
we can have, you know, five or six
people in there. And uh we can mic them
all up and have good conversations. And
I feel like I like being able to set
people up with other people to where we
have great conversations. And then it's
like if you get a diverse enough crowd,
you can talk about some really cool
stuff. That's really exciting. I'm I I
refuse to use the word foodie, but I'm a
food aaholic. I just love food. I've
never cooked professionally. Yeah. But I
cook, you know, almost every single
night in my house and every single
morning I make my kids their their
breakfast every morning and I and I cook
for the family every night. Um I love
cooking for my friends. you know, as as
I've gotten busier over the years, I
found it harder to do like the more the
more complex longer, you know, longer
time uh you know, cooks or whatever. But
I a lot of people try to do like the
weed thing and they want to incorporate
the weed into the food. In fact, there's
a restaurant in Sacramento, Michelin
Star Localis, and like they did this
really cool dinner for us once and they
put weed in the food and no one's ever
done it as good as they did. Yeah. But
still, I was so [ __ ] high, it became
unenjoyable, you know? It's just too
much. And they had the they had the uh
the infused option and the non-infused.
And my wife was like, "Absolutely not.
She will not touch any weed, edible,
any." She's like, "I want the
non-infused." And somehow some of the
stuff got into it. And she was like
scared high. And it was like it's
dangerous. It's like weed in food is
dangerous. Um Yeah. Just the way it
reacts cuz everyone's body chemistry is
so different. And if you're not used to
it, it it'll give you that paranoia,
right? And smoking does not give me
paranoia. I can smoke the strongest
sativas and maybe I might get a little
paranoia for about a minute or five
minutes, but that goes away really fast.
Whereas edibles, it just like doesn't go
away. Then you want it to be over. Uh
and it's almost like a bad trip because
it doesn't end, right? And yeah. So, I
mean, I've I've eaten edibles where I'm
like high for eight hours or 10 hours
and you wake up the next day and you
have a weed hangover, which is absurd.
And then I got friends that need 1,000
milligrams like it's nothing, you know,
but they can't hang with the smoking,
too. So, a lot of them the way they
absorb it. Yeah, that's that's really
cool that you're you're going to do
that. Um hopefully we can uh link up
again on that. Um we'll get you down
here for sure. Yeah, we we want to do
we've I've been doing a little bit more
content stuff and we did like a a little
steak thing and I I I'm big on steak. I
think you know, we talked earlier before
the show that I'm I'm eating a lot of a
lot of red meat and uh it's all
encompassing, right? like we grow some
of the most amazing products and this is
it gets better and better looking and
tasting as we get as we hone our craft
and then tying it into the kitchen. I
mean, I love smoking when I'm cooking.
It's one of the nice things about having
a great hood. Oh, yeah. You know, you're
a good cook and you can cook a lot of
steak, you got to have a great hood, but
then you got the joint right there and
it just takes it right out. That's for
sure. That's the only place I'm allowed
to smoke in the house, right? Me, too.
Literally, cuz the house joints smoke up
they they'll make your house smell bad.
Yeah. Right. So, if you had one piece of
advice for your younger
self, what would that one piece of
advice be? Go harder. I I I remained
relatively restrained. Mhm. Like when
people are just throwing up more lights
and you know, you know, now that being
said, we were in Sacramento, which is in
the Eastern District, the Eastern
Federal District. Yeah. Where they
actually sent a number of legal cannabis
folks to prison, federal prison, you
know. So, I don't know. I don't want to
say I regret it, but you know, I would
have definitely encouraged, you know,
reinvest more of the profits. You know,
speaking of profit, Luke Scarzo did 14
years and he owned a dispensary. Yeah.
Yeah. He That's not why he did prison
time. He said, "Fuck the feds." Yeah.
So, I actually knew Luke. I met Luke in
I think 200 I think 200 I think either
99 or 2000. He came up to Chico. He was
real good friends with one of the guys
uh that I was living with and I met him
up there. He stayed at our house and he
was super cool dude. Um and and then
they opened that spot and the guy that I
lived with uh helped him run his
dispensaries for a while and we tried to
sell him a little product and he was
just like it was just so crazy. It was
so bananas and it was in Modesto and so
we stayed you know we kept our distance
not because uh you know for any other
reason other than it was just like a
little it was a little crazy you know it
was like hectic like this is this seems
a little I don't want to say I felt like
it was hot but it was like it was either
hot for getting jacked or like hot for
something. It just felt like right that
place was cracking a little too hard. Um
it was pretty unfortunate what happened
to him. I mean, it's probably one of the
worst, you know, worst cannabis uh war
stories. Um, I think him and Richard
Delissi, those two stories, I mean,
there's there's lots of bad stories
about guys that went away for something
they shouldn't they would never have
gone away today for, for one thing. But,
Right. But yeah, and then Uncle Rick did
32 calendar years for cannabis. That's
just with circumstantial evidence on
this the the long stint he did. Wow. You
know, it's really sad in Florida.
Yeah, that's super gnarly. Um, I mean,
we were It was close. I mean, you
remember that whole Hayward the the not
I think it was Hayward. There was the
what it was Operation Delta,
the the hydro stores that got busted.
So, you know, I didn't even know those
guys. I had never even been to their
store, right? And I when that happened,
the lawyer was like, "Hey, do you know
any of these guys? Read these names."
And I was like, "Nope, didn't know none
of them rang a bell." And
um then like three, four months later, I
get a call from my HVAC contractor and
he's like, "Hey, one of you know," he
knew one of the guys. He's like, "Hey, I
got a message from the electrician, this
guy Brian. You know, you guys are when
they raided him for that whole thing,
they were like, "Tell us about Caleb
Counts. Tell us about free health." Blah
blah. What do you know? And turned out
that electrician had done some work at
our facility through another contact who
was Bay Area, you know, right? And we
were like, "Holy shit." And that was
enough. My lawyer's like, "Yeah, you're
under federal investigation. They don't
if they interrogated him during a raid
about you and listed all the names and
all the the companies that that were
affiliated with you, you are under
federal investigation and you are likely
next. You should be out of the business
in 24 hours if you don't want to go to
prison." Yeah. And that was like one of
the most, you know, sobering
conversations I had ever had. And I had
to pick up the phone and make the call
like dispensary every gram of flowers
out of that place before close of
business and call the grows and say
every plant is cut down, pulled out of
the ground, thrown in the trash. Wow. 24
hours I was a ghost. I was out of the
cannabis business. This was in 200 into
end of 2011. I think it was 2012, early
2012. Mhm. I was out of the cannabis
business. And um yeah, like my my lawyer
said, he's like, "You should be a
ghost." And so luckily, you know, we got
that information. You know, I don't I
still don't remember his last name, but
if Brian's listening, he's from the Bay
Area. He was an electrician. Thank you
so much. I owe that guy pretty much, I
guess, in some ways, my life, you know,
cuz then they went and raided my next,
you know, one of my competitors who was
a friend of mine, El Camino Wellness.
They raided him uh three weeks later.
Wow. Wow. And then my lawyer was like,
"You were they probably just went from
you and realized you're out of the
business and then went to him." Yeah.
And luckily he didn't go to prison, but
they took everything from him. And he's
a real He's a real successful real
estate agent now. He's still a real
estate agent. And he would I'm sure he
would not have chose that path. He was
good in the weed business and killing
it. And uh it changed the direction of
his life dramatically. Yeah. So, I'm I'm
glad that somehow after all the [ __ ]
I've done, I remained unscathed until
the airport incident, you know. Did you
hear about that? I did hear a little bit
of that. You You're bringing pre-roll
joints or something like that. Yeah, I
was traveling from California to Arizona
and I was just bringing them a few. I
mean, it's like it was like uh
20 I think 20 jars of 2 No, it was 25
jars of 2.5 gram. samples of our of our
infused pre-rolls um to show them you
know what it looked like and you know
certainly if I would have have sold them
at full retail pop I wouldn't have even
recuperated the cost of my ticket so I
definitely wasn't trafficking in sales
which is what I got charged with for
sure possession with intent to sell
started as a misdemeanor they upgraded
it to a felony well yeah so they let you
go everything was all good and yeah they
just write a ticket right then and there
and say hey you know the cop even I
think He started he was a real
aggressive at first and I think he
started to realize this is kind of this
is a little much you know and he started
to like make excuses kind of which was
weird you know when they're like feel
like they have to justify what they're
doing you feel like they're kind of
feeling bad about it and then we ended
up being on the tram cuz I missed my
flight we took the tram back that
Sacramento airport and we ended up being
the only it was like 6:00 in the morning
we were the only ones on it he's like
you know in the future just check it you
know if you check this stuff we'll never
catch it. I'm like, the guy that just
busted me is giving me advice on how to
further traffic marijuana, in his words,
traffic marijuana and and not get
busted. So, it was surreal. And then
they when my lawyer went to go to court,
he was like, "You're not on the docket.
I don't know what's up. Give me the case
number again." Gave it to him. He's
like, "Dude, they upgraded you to a
felony." And then they just would not
negotiate. They were like, they were
getting a conviction no matter what.
They're like, "We got you dead rights.
We want this possession with intent to
distribute. If not, we'll give you
interstate drug trafficking. Drug
trafficking if you'd like because you
had a ticket to Arizona. Well, I just
had an experience at SFO. SFO of all
places. So, I was actually going
international and I had a little bit of
my personal and I I was going through
security and literally I was going there
to film Mila for her 80th birthday and
so I had a little bit of my personal or
whatever and I go through and I'm fine
through security going through the I
scan my ticket and I'm walking through
the tunnel and the guy's like, "How much
cash you have on you?" I'm like, "400
bucks and maybe some euros like 60 bucks
in euros or something like that." He's
like, "You smell like weed. How much
weed do you have on you?" I'm like, "A
little bit of personal." He's like,
"Okay, let's take a look at it." So,
they start taking out and he's like,
"What's this?" I'm like, "Uh, that's a
little bit of extract. There was a
little bit of rosin in there." And then
he's like, "Well, where's the flower?"
And I'm like, "Well, you'd put it on the
counter." He didn't even realize it was
in there. And like, so I'm like, "So, my
flight's about to leave. Am I good to
go? You know, what's what's going on?"
Uh, and he's like, "I got to talk to my
supervisor." I'm like, "You've got to be
kidding." So, I miss my flight. They
take me in the back. Where where were
you flying? Barcelona for spanabis.
Spanabis. So they probably are. So yeah.
And so basically I mean I don't know if
I was profiled or whatever, but
basically they uh went in the back and
they searched my stuff and that's all I
had. I declared it, you know, and it's
like I they asked me. I told them I had
it. Uh they let me go. They signed I
basically had Oh, the funny thing is the
first they took four tests on the
flower. It was some Skittles. It was
harvested early. It was super fresh. The
first three it didn't test for Delta 9.
It didn't pop dirty. The fourth one it
like slightly changed color so they took
a picture with that one and they
confiscated it and let me on my way but
uh and they were actually pretty polite
about the whole thing. Um you know but I
learned a lesson. I missed my flight. I
had to fly 24 hours later.
Sucked. Yeah. So, I think a bunch of
people got in trouble flying over there
with stuff. And it's like really I just
I have a hard time flying anywhere with
not knowing what kind of cannabis is
going to be there. I enjoy my medicine.
I treat it like medicine. I believe it's
medicine. Yeah. I have a doctor's
recommendation still. I'm one of those
people that still gets doctor's
recommendations, especially after that
incident. I have I make sure to keep
mine to date. And totally. And so, I
mean, I think I think of it as medicine.
And I feel like we should be able to
travel. We can travel with anything
else. else they can travel with, you
know, any sort of pills, so why can't we
travel with cannabis? And that that
really has to change. Yeah. I actually
just had an incident in uh Cabo's
airport and yeah, they profiled me for
sure cuz I pressed the button, it was
green, and he was like, "Nope, you come
right over." Oh, wow. They I watched
them profiling people. They're profiling
mostly people of color. I was the only
one that wasn't. But I noticed everyone
else they pulled over was someone of
color, which is shitty. But um they
searched my [ __ ] They're like, "Tell us
where it is. Where's the weed? Where is
the weed? Where is the weed?" And I'm
like, "I don't have anything. I don't
have anything." They're like, "CBD? You
have CBD? Huh? Huh? You have CBD?" I'm
like, "No, I don't." And they like went
in my I have like, you know, a little
pill container that has like a bunch of
mixed, you know, just random onesie,
twoozies of [ __ ] that I They're my
backup like in case I forgot, you know,
my vitamins or my medication or
whatever. It's like it's like the random
[ __ ] And there was three
uh the heavy hitters, they're my
favorite uh sleep uh the heavy hitter
CBN's. They have five I think they have
five or 10 milligrams of THC and and
they're like, you know, what's this?
What's this? Cuz it has no it's just a
pressed pill. It has no label on it. And
I'm like, fine, that's
CBD. And and they're like,
ah. And that was like the admission. And
then they went deeper. Then they pulled
my wife aside. Then they went through
her [ __ ] They're like, "Tell us where
the weed at." Like, "Fuck." And they
brought out a test machine and they're
breaking up the pill and they're putting
it on the thing and and then they uh and
it wasn't popping, you know, and so they
called over another guy. I I mean this
guy looked much more studious like had a
different machine and he just tested
they were testing a bunch of other pills
that I had cuz I have all these I take
supplements they tested and the guy was
like vitamina you could tell he was
annoyed at the other guy who was like
all gungho like thought he had a bust on
his hands and the guy was like vitamina
vitamina vitamina vitamina you know to
everything even the CBD they
acknowledged was they're like no it's a
he was like it's a vitamin there's no
THC which is funny it's
It's [ __ ] bizarre, right? What we
have to deal with. Yeah. It's wild for
something we believe in so so firmly
believe in that, you know, I feel like
it makes the world a better place. And
then there's people out there that are
like, "No, people should still be going
to jail for it." It's like those people
are going to die off very soon, you
know, in the near future. And I think
the younger generation starting to get
it. I hope. I don't even think the vast
majority of people that are still
putting people in jail believe that we
should be. Mhm. It's like some weird
power trip like upper hand. Like I think
behind the scenes most of those people
are like I don't give a [ __ ] about
anything. You know, I've just I've come
in contact with so many people who
they're, you know, you find out one way,
shape or form that, you know, off camera
or whatever. You know, not exactly off
camera, but like in the comfort of their
own home, in their own private circles,
they have a totally different stance of
what they'll say. But then they've got
they feel like they have to keep. It's
either like this power trip or this
image thing. And I think a lot of it is
image, you know, that they feel like
they have to for their voters or for,
you know, their peers that they have to
keep perpetuating that they don't even
believe anymore. Yeah. And they're just
doing it because they don't feel like
they could acknowledge that they were
wrong or that they have a different
opinion. I think that is the I think
that is a large majority of what is
still that and the people that feel like
they're just following the law. And I
feel like the guys at SFO that I was
dealing with, they felt like they were
just following the law. They were very
respectful, but also I was breaking the
law. And so you can't break the law. And
I I unfortunately the only way for us to
get legalization, the reason we're here,
why it's legal, is because we had to do
things illegally. Had we not done that,
it would still be illegal. There's no
doubt in my mind. cannabis would still
be illegal if it wasn't for the outlaws
that kind of pushed it forward. I think
about that often and it's like, you
know, I played such a small role in it.
There's people that like that you
discussed earlier that that they gave
their their literal lives, you know, or
big chunk of their lives and there have
been so many people that have laid it
down, you know, and a lot of them, you
know, it was for personal interest, but
at the end of the day, like they they
chose to to make their story heard and
to and to be an example and and to sort
of lend their story to to the rest of us
to to continue charging forward. It is
truly a war. When you stand back and
think about it, it is a war. There have
been many, many casualties and there
continues to be. And the casualties are
showing up in different ways now. Now,
it's just bu millions and millions of
dollars being flushed down the drain.
People that have tried to do it right
and weren't able to overcome the the
overburden overly burdensome tax
structure, regulatory structure. I mean,
it feels like they're trying to put us
out of business right now with this
aspillus thing. right? You know, and I
don't know if you saw, you know,
recently they recently changed the u
they recently did a major cut to the
number of the pesticides and and and IPM
uh stuff that we can use. I mean,
already we were stricter. This is what
almost no one knows this. We already had
stricter requirements than organic
certification like by a long shot. like
we already had significantly stricter
and they just took a an axe to what we
could use previously and now the list is
even smaller. I mean what we're allowed
to use to prevent, you know, crop loss
is ridiculous and it makes no sense and
it's not tied to science. That's the
thing. It's tied to fear. Mhm. And
unfortunately most things are. Yeah.
Yeah. That's a good point. But uh I mean
I I have positive outlook on on
everything. I'm I'm hoping for the best,
you know. It's like we can only hope,
but uh you know, it's like some things
aren't looking too good and other things
are looking great. Yeah. I the the way
cannabis is spreading internationally is
really exciting right now. I mean, it's
it's it's bittersweet because while it's
expanded in the United States, it seems
to have reached a limit. You know, it's
bumping up against that right now. But
what's happening on the international
landscape and the opportunity to do
business in all these other countries?
Like I, you know, having to do all these
calls at weird hours or talking to
people in different countries. It sounds
like you've been doing that for a long
time. Yeah. But it's like I I actually
took a step back the other day cuz I was
like, "Oh, these [ __ ] 5:00 a.m. calls
or you or I feel bad for them that
they're getting on at 8:00 p.m. where
they're at." And then I realized I'm
like, "Wow, how lucky are we? I'm
dealing with someone whose first
language is in English and we're talking
about doing business together. Yeah. And
they live, you know, they're nine,
eight, nine, 12 hours, you know,
different time zone. This is a [ __ ]
crazy world. Yeah. And we're talking
like and genetics can get there. Like
it's going to be our genetics grown in
their facility to our standards. someone
in Australia, someone in Thailand,
someone in Germany, someone in I mean
people have been smoking our weed in
Spain and UK for a long time, but these
other countries I I think very little,
you know, and that's [ __ ] that's
something to be excited about. That's
something to get up out of bed for,
right? Is like I'm stoking someone out
on the other side of the planet, right?
you know, that doesn't even know who I
am and they're smoking they're going to
be smoking my weed and like having the
best [ __ ] experience that they've
ever had with me. It'll be like 2010 for
them, you know, and and that 2010 those
were magical years for cannabis like pre
2010 to 201, you know, 18 even. Those
were, you know, it was very nostalgic
for for me like the early high times
cannabis cups. People were excited and
that's what I love about Spannabis going
to events like Spanabis. I'm going to
Mary Jane this year in June. I'll be
there, too. It's going to be Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. Well, I'm going to be doing some
live podcasts at the Grove booth with
the Turp Lock guys. Yeah. So, yeah,
we'll get you in on there and it's going
to be a lot of fun. But that that
reminds me of 2010 how it was here.
People were excited for what's to come.
We've already experienced and there's a
lot of jade. Everybody's like, "Fuck, it
was rough." Yeah. And uh you know, and
they'll probably experience that, too.
But I love the enthusiasm and they're
just excited about wheat. They love
weed. They love that. And it's the money
hasn't come in come and gone and come
and gone because we've experienced where
it's like we're rocking and then next
thing you know they're kicking us in in
the dick. Next thing you know we're on
top again and then they're they're
knocking us down and cutting us off at
the knees. And uh so and that's just I
think that happens with most businesses.
It's a cycle. Y and you just put it into
great perspective and I just thought
about that. We're just in a phase of our
of the cycle that we've been going
through. It just looks different every
time because it
feels that much stronger each time
because it it's we have more invested
now, more years of our life. We're older
than we were then and it feels
different, but we're just going through
a cycle and it's a down cycle and the
next up cycle will be bigger than the
last one. Yeah. And that's what we got
to keep uh keep in front of us and these
little bumps, these hurdles, no matter
how painful they are. I think the other
point you made earlier is the people
that make it through this Yeah. you
know, are going to really see the fruits
of of what they swed over the years and
all the hard uh hardship they've been
through. So, I'm excited. Yeah. I I
mean, yeah, the the horizon's still
exciting and I just love being in here
and watching this unfold and having
guests like yourself on my podcast. This
is why I do it. I love this experience
for me. You know, I talk about
experiences like this experience for me
is just so gratifying where we have the
opportunity to interview people like
yourself and all these other people in
the industry and hear their stories uh
and like also see their un story the
stories unfold and being able to get
these names out there for some of these
smaller people too. It's it's great to
be able to give people a platform. So,
thank you so much for coming on the show
today. It's been a blast. We'll get you
on the cooking show. I'll see you in
June at Mary Jane and maybe I'll be up
your way next month with some genetics.
If people are looking to find out more
about Caleb, where can they go? You can
go to
connectedca.com. Um, and our Instagram
account unfortunately is down. We're
starting a new one. So, it's connected.
Ntl. Um, connected. TL is our new
Instagram page. Please go give us a
follow. And then my personal iscounts c
o n ts. Nice. Um and uh like you said,
I'll be at Mary Jane. And I want to
thank you, man. Um it's very clear what
you've done uh is is really cool and and
this platform that you've created and
you've done it in such a professional
manner and your reach is vast. I can
tell that. And uh I'm glad to have met
you and I'm looking forward to
continuing to be able to work together
and exchange cool stories. Awesome.
Yeah, I look forward to bringing some
genetics by, too. That'd be great.
Awesome. Thank you very much.
Thank you guys for watching. Please like
and subscribe down below.