[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James lad podcast
and today our special guest is none
other than the famous Chad Westport from
uh Washington how are you doing today
I'm doing awesome man thank you so much
for having me down here dude thanks for
coming on the show we have known each
other online for four years you were
there at the very beginning of my
podcast Journey on the future cannabis
project yep that was great man it was a
great source of information so I've been
happy to be along for the ride and I'm
glad to see this new iteration of it too
just take off as it has yeah so you
spent a lot of time on podcast because
not only on my podcast but everyone
else's podcast and shows on the future
cannabis project you were always in the
chat I would jump in and you would be
there yeah and uh you've always been a
big supporter of the show and before you
had a podcast I remember saying Chad you
should probably have your own podcast
man you're really good at this stuff and
uh now you have your own podcast I think
you're doing big things yeah well thank
you man and you know hanging out in the
chat was fun because that's where the
kind of the community is built that's
where we learn so much from each other
that's where we meet new people you've
got a great audience so yeah it's always
fun hanging out in the chat yeah I mean
this show is built around greatness
besides myself I think our guests are
amazing and our producer the guy who
produces show he he does an amazing job
and then our our client base the people
that watch the show they uh they really
bring a lot to the chat to uh you know
they they're the ones the the guests
come on the show to be able to talk to
them and to get their stories out and
we've had some amazing guests and I'm
just a catalyst for this whole thing
really at the end of the day as as
podcast hosts it's not about us it might
be the James lad podcast or the Chad
Westport podcast or whatever the James
loud show but really our job is to be
able to help the guest tell their story
and that's the beauty of the podcast is
we get to hear these I get to hear in
the first person get to talk to these
people and they get to tell me their
Amazing
Stories um yeah and so I'm excited to
tell your amazing story today yeah thank
you it's always fun to have a front row
seat as the podcast host to be able to
raise your hand and get the question
anytime you want it you know I always
say I have a front row all the like
Freestyle right like so we don't we
don't record questions and give
questions out beforehand I'm not like
that we did that with the future
cannabis project when I did the James
loud show I'd give them some some
questions but what happened was I would
realize that I would ask them six or
eight questions and it would go way off
topic almost every time right some of
the science guys loved that but I feel
like uh when it's just fresh and off the
cuff it's just so much more fun and
enjoyable and it's like the conversation
can go anywhere literally it's like the
Grateful Dead with when they're jamming
you know what I mean like I feel like
we're jamming like the Grateful Dead
jams and it's like it's Innovation and
it's all over the place and the
conversation can go anywhere we know
what we're doing here we're telling a
story and it's like this is great that's
I mean that's a lot of what cannabis
brings though is really kind of a Vibe
and that really has kind of brought
together a lot of people that probably
wouldn't have hung out normally it's
that Vibe and I you know I kind of joke
too it's like younger generation will
never know what the Dealer's couch is
like right cuz where you know you met
people from like different schools or
different areas and different walks of
life um so yeah it's the plant brings us
together but it's all that Vibe so it's
cool to see it translate into the show
well yeah and it's all everything
circles back for me everything circles
back to genetics right like I'm a
genetics focused person and Company it's
all everything we do whether it's my
book whether it's the podcast uh whether
it's our clothing line it all circles
back to the gentics M and to the plant
right and I think it's our
responsibility as stewards to you know
as podcast host to to highlight people
that have experienced with the plant and
share their experiences with the world
with the future the people that are
watching this show 50 years from now you
know we talk about I talk about that
quite a bit on my show you know about
the future I think that's the importance
of podcasts and uh yeah and I love
interviewing other podcast hosts because
they know how to talk they know how to
have great conversations it's always a
lot of fun fun yeah well I'm glad you're
here and too sometimes in normal
conversation I I I talk to my wife and
she always cuts me off and I'm like
sweetie you need to start a podcast
because you learn how to talk yeah well
you really do I mean I think even the
way I project my voice is different than
the first episode when I first was doing
podcast I feel like I know how to speak
better which is a strange thing but I
you know I I I know how to conversate
better for sure and I'm I've always been
good at letting people talk and not
interrupt over some some podcast host
not naming any names but some of them
love to interrupt and talk over and you
know it is what it is but you get you
get a little bit of everything with
different podcasts and different podcast
hosts but I really want to hear the
story from the guest and I also while
they're telling their story I'm like man
what should I ask them next and that's
what gets me excited too like man so I
learned this about this person and if
you write the questions before you don't
get that right so like you can go in the
middle and you're like whoa well I want
to know more about this person because
you can always ask them well when did
you first start smoking you know right
generic generic stuff like that and
that's okay and sometimes you need to do
that to get into some of the deep stuff
but uh you know we've gotten to some
really cool stuff on this show we've had
amazing guests uh you know I think you
you liked our Christmas special so much
I love the Christmas special that you w
a hat I did you did i w a hat and you
know what I brought it all the way back
with me because I want to hand this hat
over back to you to wear again this
December and give out some more gifts to
people and who knows hopefully the
person that wins next year or this year
will be on your show next year that's
awesome so thank you thank you very much
we will be auctioning this off it has
some hair from Chad in here and one
Santa's Hair one of one one of one this
is the original one we're gonna have to
just keep this thing going that's that's
amazing y uh so thank you very much uh
yeah we have some stuff exciting going
on for Christmas I have some big
projects that I'm going to be working on
uh for the next year some big breeding
projects with SF Cana and planta okay uh
with both of those companies we're doing
some projects and then my buddy's
company hush so I'm doing some reversals
and sharing pollen and pollinating stuff
and so I think 2025 is going to be a
pretty freaking amazing year I'm looking
forward to it yeah you got to set
yourself up this year for the busy of
next year yeah I mean I'm always trying
to set myself up for the success of the
future I think if you're not planning
ahead than you're behind I mean talking
genetics and breeding I mean how many
years ahead are you in your head right
now as far as what you want to do I mean
we do so much more work than we can so
so we do like let's say we just do 300
outcrosses a year okay that's a lot we
can only test a small percentage of
those right to to properly test them
right it's one thing testing them and
just pop oh yeah we pop one of each one
they're good we pop 10 of each one
they're good but to actually pop them
grow them out multiple times and go this
is the winner from this this is the
winner from that we don't have time to
do all the work that we do every year so
like each year we get backlogged a
little more right but we can always go
back and revisit that stuff we store
seeds correctly uh and you you know you
got to spend time at the facility today
yeah uh at the Oakland facility and it's
you know what what's your opinion on
that I loved it man it's been a while
since I walked into a warm just dank
smelling room uh full of plants and
something that I used to do but I
haven't done for a while so it was
really cool to see that the way that you
have it set up again and um I'm I'm
primarily like a hom grower hom Growers
is where I spend the majority of my
focus the majority of my attention yeah
you're going to be doing things
different when you have a larger space
and it's always fun to come in and see
what is being done how it's being done
you know what plants look like I learned
so much working commercially of just how
to handle plants in itself right so
being able to come in and see a facility
like this is great because in my mind
I'm always like how can something that I
see here apply how it help somebody else
that's where we get a lot of the you
know a lot of the uh information we
learn yeah so yeah we put you to work
today we we were going sexing plants
we're in that stage of the feno hunt
where literally we're going in and
trying to pull out all the males from
the regular seeds and uh observing
traits we're looking for stuff that's
you know also stuff that's taken off
where the we got really tall plants and
really short plants and trying to
determine what's what right now and it's
an exciting time going stuff going into
flower because it all goes into flower
at different days even though it's
triggered on the same day mhm you know
the light is triggered doesn't mean that
that plant will actually go into flow
two or three days later some of them
it's a week later some of them it's 10
days later before you're really able to
properly sex them and like some of it is
with the stability of the plants some
are longer flying varieties they just
take longer to show their signs but and
then you know we're looking for
hermaphrodites that's the next thing so
we're going through those rooms every
day pulling males uh I found some real
we found a z mail today that was really
cool uh big shout out to Leo Stone of
fish a genetics uh Leo's a badass and I
love his genetics and I got a mail that
looks pretty killer like the structure
is great and the stem rub was really
cool yeah that you know that was fun
again kind of just going through the
room and looking at some of them because
there were there there was the
observable traits of some just weren't
there yet While others were fully
letting you know what they were oh yeah
yeah and some of them that are really
unstable you'll get 20 plants that all
look different mhm and some stuff they
look identical across the board they
look like they're the same thing and so
those and those plants are all really
healthy and I feel like if you can keep
your plants really healthy you can grow
them properly that's the best way to
make them Express so they show different
characteristics people that just grow
mediocre they have a problem getting the
plants to express properly then it's
really The pheno Hunt is that much
harder when you're not able to grow the
plants really well and there's a lot of
varieties out there that you know I've
heard of that if you don't grow it right
you're not going to think it's the real
thing yeah and so that that's Sour
Diesel it's a big part of it a lot of
people uh you know they they they rush
to uh work with something before they
get good at growing yeah and if you if
you're ever trying to do any kind of
selections you really have to get that
growing part down it's so important to
the end picture well yeah there's so so
many guys that want to be breeders and
they just want to make seeds and it's
like man that's great making seeds is
great it's cool and I think everybody
should do it but I also think it's more
important to be a good grower and
cultivator than it is to be a seed
producer like you'll be a better seed
producer and grower and breeder if you
know how to make the plant Express
really well you understand plant Health
optimal plant Health how to keep your
plant healthy all the way and then
drawing and curing that's so important
and if you don't have those things how
are you really going to be able to feno
hunt so building up those skills and
then breeding should just be a natural
transition you know it shouldn't be like
I need to learn how to breed so much
like I there a lot of that you learn on
the cultivation side when you're doing
that uh it's it's a trip though because
I think people get excited about
breeding and they're like oh I want to
be a breeder and it's it's not as
glamorous a lot of stuff also seems very
glamorous from the outside and you're
like oh man these guys are doing this
this or that and it sounds awesome and a
lot of it boils down to do you really
like data collection do you really like
like examining plants and comparing and
taking notes and you're doing at the end
of the day you're doing a lot of AB
testing and you're like okay is this
better than this and why is it better
than this and you you know so it's not
just I found the next winner and I'm GNA
be rich right some of there's like that
philosophy is kind of gone anyway yeah I
I see more people now that it's kind of
shaken out that there's more people
willing to put in the work reallying to
to recognize the work um but you
mentioned data collection too you know
it's like like on a small scale craft
scale home scale tent scale we have to
work with observable traits so when
we're pheno hunting it's like was it a
heavy feed or how did it like water
whereas you know if we were bigger we
could use things like sap analysis and
soil analysis to really determine is it
truly a heavy feeder and what it
particular is it heavy in yes but you
can just throw all those tests away
because at the end of the
day the effect and the taste are the two
most important things and you can have
data that backs up those things right
you can have you can have coas and you
get lab results for cannabinoids and and
tpin and you can you can find out a lot
of things from Lab analysis but at the
end of the day it's not going to tell
you how that it makes you feel and it's
not going to fully tell you exactly how
it tastes you might know the tpine
percentage is 5 and a half percent right
but does that mean anything what does
that translate into and the more you
know your breeding lines the better
obviously you know I feel like the more
you work with those same plants and you
breed them together you're going like
yeah the mother's if I if you use this
as a donor it's going to do this and if
I use this as receiver it's probably
going to do this and usually it's a
probably because you never know with
recessive and dominant traits unless you
know both sides and then you're like
yeah this is going to be the outcome
it's very it gets more predictable the
more that you understand the lines and
so the the less guessing you have to do
which is kind of great because a lot of
people are like well what is GMO times
Donny Burger going to do and it's like
well you're going to lean he more heavy
on that GMO you know and so it's G to go
more into that chmd GMO gassy side right
it's already kind of gassy and it but I
love Donny bur you know we've been
talking about this show quite a bit it's
it's a good one it's a good one I've
actually had that one so yeah I'm huge
into the extracts flora and Flame they
gave me some and changed my mind
completely he gave me some flour I
wasn't impressed he gave me the extract
I was like some of the best I've seen
okay yeah that that sometimes that
changes it sometimes the concentration I
almost think like the isolation of
things yeah can bring out the different
nuances um you know you're you're
talking about the effect being the most
important thing right and that usually
that comes after the fact though it's
like you've you have to grow it first
you have to be like is this one worth
growing is this one desirable but you
should be growing a plant multiple times
so you already know those things and
then you have the effect too but when
I'm initially trying to look at
something
I I'll get preconceived notion like if
it's kind of a beast to grow I don't
really like it maybe it's not going to
taste as good to me yeah I don't know I
kind of like try not to have too much of
an opinion on those things until I taste
them or you know I think there's when
you're when you're doing when you're
working with 500 plants there's also the
commercial viability aspect of it is
this something that because that's why
I'm doing it right like to license them
to sell clones how's this going to
perform for my friends or the people I
want to sell a clone to or license a
clone to yeah you know so there's that
we get get rid of some of the stuff that
are just runty but every once in a while
I'll find some little runty plant and
I'm like uh we're going to keep this for
breeding maybe we're not going to ever
sell this to anybody but I love the way
this tastes or I love the way this
smells and so we'll save that stuff for
something special but it's then this
purpose is really for the breeding you
know and there's some stuff that's a
real big yielder or something that's a
super fast finisher and maybe it's
amazing for the that trait that specific
trait it finishes really fast right so
has this amazing quality finishes in 45
days done yields three pounds per
4x4 gets purple and so but but it's
missing something right but that doesn't
mean you need to throw it away because
it's missing something that means that
maybe you could breed it with other
stuff to potentially you know especially
other fast finishers uh especially if
you get high can avonoids you know
there's there's so many things that
maybe they don't fit into the model but
they still have use and they still have
purpose and then when you have you know
like five to six or 700 plants in a feno
hunt you're going to find a lot of good
stuff and a lot of interesting stuff and
a lot of stuff you think is interesting
that's not so I see that a lot where I'm
like oh I get excited about something
and you you never know yeah and you know
personal opinions too some of some of my
favorite things that I've had um it's
not the first jar that's empty out of
some of the things that I put on the
table so that's all subjective as well
the jar test is always the true it's the
best test yeah sometimes it'll break
your heart but it's the best
test yeah and I mean it's like with my
friends too it's like which ones are
they coming back for which are which
ones are the which ones everybody asking
for yeah yeah so tell us a little bit
about some of the breeding projects
you're doing right now yeah so you know
I am just in the infancy as we all know
it takes time um for years I've been
working on just like selecting something
that I really liked something that works
with my body well um something that's
nice to grow and you mentioned
commercial viability that's also a thing
so I want to be able I know I know that
if I find something that works great for
my body it's going to help other people
and for me that's just the real intent
behind it so I I've found the ones that
I like some things that help me um you
know I'm sure as anybody in breeding
will tell you don't work with a plant
that you don't absolutely love because
you're going to be working with it for a
long time yeah so i' I've been working
on selecting things that work for for my
palette and then slowly working with the
Westport grape juice to try that against
a variety of different things to see how
that expresses to see what is
consistently coming over sometimes what
gets
buried in the infancy so I'm really
honing in on those right now to put that
forward in the future so in a few more
years hopefully I'll have it more dialed
but yeah right now that's that's what
I'm doing yeah well these things are
long-term projects it's not instant
gratification and that's that's why you
get so much Gra ification out of them
when they go well is because it's a lot
of these projects take a long time I
you've been working on the uh Westport
grape juice for a while yeah for at
least three years that you can document
so and that's you know that's another
really fun aspect to me is in the
ospring it's like when you're so
familiar with a plant and you do make
seeds with it and you're able to look at
The Offspring You're like oh instantly
that is you and oh that is you and
that's a fun part of it for me too
because ultimately with selection
that'll help you get back to what you're
trying to really get to feeling like
you're part of the family I love it
that's awesome you know what I mean but
it is like that too because you're like
oh where did this come from because this
is kind of strange I I'm not seeing this
from either one of the parents and all
of a sudden we got this weird plant or
today we found a really cool thing yeah
we found in a feminized seed lot we
found a male plant out of a progyny of
feminized seeds there was a full male
and it was my zbx times grape gas okay
okay and so that's the first time I've
seen that in a while nature will find a
way though nature will find a way or was
it pollen that came in on someone's
shirt or who knows but we're going to
send the test over to my flora and
they're going to sex test it for me so
we'll look at the chromosomes that would
be great I'm excited to get those
results and uh let you know how it goes
but yeah that's you know it's
like I'm glad we caught that because if
it was all feminized seeds I wouldn't be
as worried right now in the stage we're
in to look for males I'd be more looking
for Herms in the next couple weeks right
right but because there are males in the
room I go through every plant and we sex
every day we're going through there and
trying to find uh signs of males and I
love that part too because then you
really get to know your plants you you
do again Hands-On what is it that the
farmer Shadow is the best nutrient a
plant can receive I know I'm butchering
that but that is something somewhat
along the saying uhhuh but it is totally
true you know it's it's the more plants
you have the harder it is but it's still
definitely possible to get in there
every day when the more you put in the
more you get out of it like if you don't
spend enough
time uh you you might have time for
other things and then you neglect your
room but what happens is if you have a
mail and you have a 20 or 30 light room
you are going to have a lot of seeds a
lot of seeds and maybe you'll get some
interesting stuff out of there may you
know maybe but also when you're feno
hunting it's really hard to to say that
this is the expression that I'm going to
get when the plant's not seated because
that's just not the case you get a
different expression from seated plants
you know I I've I've heard that I I
can't conclusively say myself but yeah
you know I've kind of heard that and to
go back to some of the things that pop
out I did a S1 or reversal on the
Westport grape juice yeah and there
there's a a tuck Leaf feno so you know
you typically got your lease like this
they're all like this it's consistent
along that particular style all gas yeah
now where that comes from in the
Westport grape juice it's not present in
the actual thing so yeah again going
back with the S1 that was kind of fun
because there are things that popped out
there I'm like okay well that's
interesting to me yeah I love well I
love seeing recessive traits too mhm and
I love proving myself wrong or proving
myself right yeah so that was that that
was fun but that was kind of a kind of a
oneand done I think um I
like males have a lot more pollen damn
it they do but I can really get a ton of
pollen out of my my females my reversals
I mean you guys most people seen
reversals online and we our our
reversals dump and it's it's a genetic
thing too you don't expect me to get
those reversals on sfv or a handful of
other things but but on the typical
plant I can reverse them and get jars of
pollen per plant nice you know I I was
probably going to ask about what you use
and the ratios and stuff I'm sure that's
proprietary but do you think it comes
down to a lot of the mix you're using
versus genetics or environment or health
there's a bunch of things Okay so I mean
yeah you're interviewing me now that's
okay well so with with silver when
you're using ethylene blockers M uh
there's several Silvers that work cidial
silver will work MH true cidial silver
it's in my book too like we go into that
like I use nano silver that's from my
friend Tim humiston can Organics really
good stuff it I think it's the most
effective and I have the best results on
stuff that doesn't reverse really well
so it pretty much reverses everything
and that's why I use it there's single
spray one and done boom boom boom STS
you have to spray a few times but you
damage the plant damage the stamata
those plants look like death afterwards
look like they're damaged right and so I
don't particularly like STS but STS
works really well okay they still use it
in Europe I still think it's the
standard for people that make feminized
seeds but I do like the nano silver the
best and it's 1 ml per gallon stabilized
shelf stable you can make a gallon of it
it can sit for the the week that you're
okay using it for reversals it's really
really good and easy to use um but yeah
I mean there's even silver that you can
use in your your feet and you can put it
into the roots and then the roots will
uptake it and uh yeah you can get
reversals like that there's all kinds of
different ways to do it there's so many
different ways to skin a cat it's just
all what you prefer and I believe that
you need to test it out before you sign
off on it to do a run whether it's a one
light run or a 50 light run you should
have experience probably have a backup
plan in case your reversal doesn't go
quite as well make pollen in advance
Plus have fresh pollen and and those
combinations so it's always good
redundancies are good you've seen the
building we have redundancies here you
know it's like we got the dosatron on
one side and we're putting the agretech
uh irrigation skit up and I'm super
excited with that dosing system yeah U
and then we'll be able to do those tests
but also that's a redundancy what
happens if our dosing system goes out or
a dosatron goes out for the day we can
switch it over boom boom boom we're
instantly switched over to agretech same
thing with uh you didn't get to see the
controls in the room but we use groan
grow sense and we use the agch system
and we're
determining uh the root Zone temperature
with the grow sense whereas like we can
get environmentals from both and then
compare and go okay well why is it this
way or why is it that way what's going
on here it gives us a better picture of
the room and then if one fails it's the
fail safe we can always go back to it um
so yeah it's it's well it's a fun
project but it's like there's a lot of
moving Parts literally with those types
of things and it is fun that you you
know I like the A&amp;B mindset as well
because at the end of the day we're
trying to get to the best path somewhere
well and if I can figure the best way to
do something and I can Empower a
customer to get better results I'm
winning they're winning yeah and by them
winning they're going to to buy seeds
for me or genetics from me and it's a
win-win situation if I can tell somebody
the optimal way to get the best results
from what they're doing whether it be
lighting Spectrum under canopy how
valuable is it I'm doing some tests
right now with the favin we're doing the
faens with the light lifts and we're
doing for seed production but also do
doing it for flour and I really like
under canopy I think it's a game
changer uh yeah plant Health plant Vigor
also do you do less work but I feel like
the plants just look healthier and the
the bottoms and undercar that don't get
enough light now all of a sudden you get
a lot of light down there and you get
bigger yields are you gosh I'm about to
interview again I'm sorry but I I'll
just cut to saying like yeah I this is
the first run where I'm experimenting
with some sidelining and underlighting
as well just because I I typically I'll
lollipop pretty hard I'll get rid of
that stuff nobody likes to trim lar no
so yeah I mean the future's bright
literally especially with thunder canopy
so yeah yeah big big shout out to faven
and all the guys that are doing under
canopy faven who I use I like faven um
you know and then we got bug lights now
I don't know if you saw the episode with
uh Grandmaster LED yes y yeah so they're
they're sending some bug lights out
we're gonna be doing R&amp;D with them I'm
super excited um I think there's so much
potential and we're just now tapping
into some of this stuff the potential
for bug lights that'll kill spidermites
or help control spidermites and thps how
can you not want want that it it you
know that sounds handy and there was a
few years ago um a ring light that the
the guy would say you put on top of your
bucket now he said it was all
proprietary he couldn't tell you how it
worked it had to run at night so there
were a lot of questions about it and at
the time I remember getting it getting
pooed because there were a lot of
logical questions of like well how close
does it have to be to these bugs to
affect them how about the duration but
that seems to now actually be being
getting vetted out to something that's
really a practical system
yeah Thomas that was on the show
grandmas level Thomas yeah he's a he's a
OG and I think I mean I'll tell you how
the lights work when I use them I'm
excited to test them out you got try and
I think the potential for it and UVC and
all these different things are are great
we'll see you don't use it for that much
and the fact is is if I don't ever have
to spray my plants that's the best IPM
ever yeah uh but we you know we
basically Don't Spray be because we're a
closed loop system M until we have to
spray right you know hydrogen peroxide
that's we use a little bit of hydrogen
peroxide but other than the hydrogen
peroxide we try not to spray I don't
want to sell sprayed clones if I don't
have to spray them if it's part of our
IPM regimen and we find out that we need
to do that in the future we'll do it but
as of right now we're a closed loose
system everything's from tissue culture
so everything's coming in clean right uh
and that's the game changer I try to
always preach like cultural controls or
cultural IPM because that as you know
just like a hom grower um it's easier to
be well reactive than proactive larger I
understand proactive because you have a
large investment to take but I
personally would not want to put some
things on my plants and so that's always
what I encourage is you know again good
cultural controls um all the things that
you've done today um but you can get
very far with that and I think
ultimately that affects the outcome of
the flower as well right you know it's
not going through as much for sure
testing for hopl and verid is so huge
too and popping seeds anymore you got to
test all your seed progenies for hopl
and viroid especially if you're getting
them from other people if you know like
we're we're using tissue culture to make
seeds right so our tissue culture seeds
are not going to have hopl and ver I can
guarantee that like that's something we
will guarantee if it's from tissue
culture parents from both of them I will
guarantee that there's no hoplon in
there that's one thing we're committed
to and so starting in 2025 you're going
to see all our seeds are made from
tissue culture moms tissue culture
parents nice um nice and so that
potentially spreads less viroid and and
virus and there's so many other things I
mean we just talk about hot PL and and
that's one of 50 things that the plant
can get it is and you know ultimately
over time that that does kind of bring
down a crop or you know destruction
that's the the Beast of it is it's not
always immediate so you don't
necessarily know I mean how much of this
industry is actually infected with HL
you know huge more than 75% yeah yeah
and and we're all still in business
somehow but we're for a reason right so
it may Express on one limb it may
Express on one plant it may Express on
one section one row or the whole room
and until it's stressed out sometimes it
doesn't Express at all and so some
people are like well I got it beat
enough it's like you do until you don't
and that's what I so I have a couple
friends that basically were the ones
like ah it's not that big of a deal and
now my buddy's like [__] we're [__]
and now I got to pay I have 250 things I
need cultured or cleaned and it's going
to cost so much money and it's crazy and
those things happen dude and it's like
you're good until you're not right and
unfortunately a lot of people wait until
they're not before they try to resolve
the issues and so the the issues are you
know it's like how do I solve that
problem I I treat it before it's a
problem right so if you can do
preventative preventative is worth every
every bit of its weight in gold
especially with hot plate Andoid and the
potential we have for tissue culture and
banking in tissue culture and to be able
to grow your moms from tissue
culture that's huge and there's a lot of
people like tissue culture this tissue
culture that talking negatively about it
I hear some of those people now but it's
like they're not seeing the bigger
picture it's like we're talking about
virus and viroid prevention yeah and if
you can not have it in your system at
all all if you have a closed loop
facility you're never going to have
those problems right and if you don't
have those problems you're not going to
lose the money that you would have if
you had those problems and every
day the product gets cheaper and cheaper
it's more
competitive uh and I just want to
empower because we're a genetics company
I I don't cultivate I cultivate seeds I
cultivate for seed production and for
feno hunting and that's it I work with
people that produce flour right to me
that's a really the the flower side the
C ation side is is much harder to
monetize these days unless you already
have an established brand or you create
the best of the best flower you're in
competition with so many other people
that are producing pretty good flour and
the price is so cheap that they can
charge so little it's very competitive
and I I see a lot of people struggling
on that side you know the word craft has
always been tossed around for you know
as long as I can remember and that just
kind of small scale and for for a while
that seemed to be where some of the
quality was
um but those a lot of them at least in
Washington you know seem to be bought up
there there are still ones that exist
but there's a lot of
consolidation um there's a lot of large
players but hopefully as if if we do go
federally legal or at least the gates
are open I hope that's kind of like the
return to the craft it's almost you know
it's like what what was once underground
is now above ground and a lot of times
that will rebirth another underground it
didn't work for disco so hey EDM man EDM
well no but disco was in the 7s yeah
yeah Studio 54 oh yeah once disco was
they have that saying once disco was
gone it was never the same and I don't
think cannabis will ever be quite the
same I mean I love that you're positive
about it and I try to be very optimistic
and positive as well um and I don't
think Boutique or craft cannabis is
going away I hopefully it'll only get
bigger and better and hopefully they'll
allow interstate commerce cuz that's
like the biggest one it's like man some
of my friends they grow amazing flower
if they could just sell it in all 50
states they would be crushing it yeah
absolutely there there are there's a lot
of places a lot of regions that have
really good stuff but you know once it
becomes such a big commodity it's not
going to be as valuable as it is so
again you're G to kind of have M it's
not in the middle it's not on the
extremes there's going to be the
extremely cheap and the extremely
expensive yeah we see that with the
NorCal Nemo and some of these Brands
down in LA and New York the you know the
sprinkle sprayed whatever stuff you
whatever I mean I'm not I'm not one to
judge right like if people want to buy
it and that's their choice it's like I'm
not going to hate on them at all they're
doing their they've done it whatever it
may not be what I smoke but I'm not
going to like knock it because if that's
what you enjoy and you think that's cool
then [__] right on because it's weed
right yeah there there's all kinds of
people with all kinds of motivations
though and you you know you hopefully
you find the ones that align with you
but there's some that absolutely don't
align with you in the same industry
doing the exact same thing and to the
Outsiders you are one and the same right
so yeah there has to be a
differentiation but it it takes time man
it takes the lover it takes the true
connoisseurs to care yeah so I'm getting
my hats make weed green
again that's for the election 2024
that's awesome uh yeah I mean I think we
need to go back to green weed we need to
the green flower I can't wait for the
green flower to make a huge comeback
it's starting to people are starting to
get more into sativas I spent some time
in Humble so I'm like these people know
weed they like that they like stuff
that's not just Lemon Cherry stuff
that's not just purple and there's
nothing wrong with purple that's mostly
what I breed that's most of the stuff
I'm working on right now and that those
rooms you're in today 80% of that is
going to be purple candy okay right and
there's nothing wrong with that I also
have some sativas in there and I also
have some crazy CBG varieties and I also
have some really off-the-wall you know
rare canono stuff that we'll see what it
comes out like and so I kind of but but
the main focus is still
give the people what they want and right
now the people want candy and they want
color Y and I'm okay with that I'm all
about Flavor too so it's got to have a
[__] good flavor yeah I love good
flavor you know being a chef and working
with something that has the potential
for good flavor why would you not want
to select for that and for effect right
at the end we talk about that a lot yeah
I'm okay with there being I I breed for
effect but it's like some things I'll
breed for effect because they're
uplifting other things I'll breed
because they're narcotic and some things
I'll breed cuz they're right in the
middle and I like the effect of
something right in the middle well you
know I like to have something for all
times a day cuz I'm a pretty regular
smoker every day constantly throughout
the day I always describe myself as a
sipper though I don't really sit down
and just take one to the head I usually
have like a little chill them little
puff here so no hot dabs on the show
today no you know no hot dabs
right if you're offering though yeah
we'll do whatever you know uh yeah we
should probably fire something up I
would be game fire something up here you
know I've got to smell and uh taste a
lot of great things so far today so what
do we got
now these big joints man
these that was man okay I got to draw
the line at the eighth joint like only
eight today yeah one one of the one of
the things you know you always hear is
you know it tastes good the next day
yeah like if you're if you're rolling a
joint that big and that you have to fire
it up the next day roll a smaller joint
finish that [__] I don't know man I'm
okay with firing it back up it's like
something like this if if I'm in the
mood I will sit and puff it for an hour
right but if I'm not I might puff it for
30 minutes put it out sometimes I'll
come into work yeah and I'll smoke uh or
whatever at the house like I'll smoke
something that's already there and I'll
also do it just to see if it tastes good
and if it doesn't taste good obviously I
won't finish it I'll fire something else
up but if it still tastes good and it's
like so me candy or some good OG or some
funk I'm like oh yeah that tastes great
it makes me want to smoke because the
flavor is so good still yeah like the
the identification game that was
something that happened recently with me
um I was out of town I had a friend
taking care of things and doing some
trimming and they totally mixed up the
labels on the jars there's like here's
this here's that here's that I was able
to open the jar and be like no you you
got these mixed up that's an important
thing with flavor too like I always say
you know if if you do come back to it
you should be able to identify it and if
you can't maybe that's not worth keeping
around because that's you know all
killer no filler is kind of what I like
to try to get to there there's so much
average out there um there's a lot of
amazing yeah I mean I have so much
access to stuff I want to smoke the very
best of the best and you know it's
always like what can I get that's better
than that or what's you know and it's
like but I have usually like 10 or 12
things that I enjoy smoking at any one
given time now I I like to keep a
variety as well like in my in my drawer
I always kind of have at least 10
different strains that I can choose from
depending upon how I'm feeling what I'm
looking for um yeah variety is is really
key to me and that's kind of one reasons
why I I grow like smaller plants because
I want to try to do a larger quantity
how small um veg for about 30 days maybe
flip you know 18 inches 20 inches flip
at about that but I'm also have been
going when I've been going through
things I've been selecting for shorter
squater things things that don't have as
large of a stretch because again if
you're growing in a smaller environment
you're growing in a tent you don't want
things with large stretches I've grown
some sativas in there that just
absolutely took over the tent but I have
kind of a purpose and a specific goal in
mind so yeah I I I let them maybe get a
little bit taller than some other people
but I'm also looking for ones that don't
stretch a lot and this one is this is a
permanent midnight okay we got SE of
this so there's some interesting fenos
that is a
3.5 and uh also you can tell it's grown
to Perfection because it's got some nice
white ash and it's got a little Oil ring
there gotta love the oil
yeah but uh it's got good flavor and
this one this batch came out really good
it tastes good down to the roach I like
that yep I do too well these are ones
where like it's hard to put it down like
I can just sit here with it and talk and
take a hit talk and take a hit and talk
and take a hit for two hours or whatever
you know this was this is an hour joint
I think this is probably a 60 Minute
like if we do it nice and slow I used to
judge chairlifts when I go uh
snowboarding by how many how many
cigarettes you could have H it's a two
two smoke lift nowadays it'd be better
if it was joints I don't smoke
cigarettes anymore but yeah you you
could do it probably with joints these
days yeah for sure we used to smoke
joints going on the chairlifts oh yeah
or hot boox the gondolas I've never been
I've never had the opportunity but there
there's something special about smoking
at altitude like I enjoy so we used to
so when I used to go snowboarding we
also used to have a plastic bong that we
used to travel with and pack it with ice
and so we get ice bong RS back in the
day I mean this is like 20 years ago
over 20 years ago we used to just rock
it out with bong herbs right out of the
you know right in the beginning of the
day going down the mountain yep my
favorite we uh Stevens Pass is one of
the local Mountains in Washington and uh
decades ago I had friends that worked up
there and I went and stayed in the you
know kind of like the employee cabins
for a week and there's a little 420 cave
up there that always just had like a
bong just like permanently installed
there so if you knew where it was and
you could actually Traverse over to this
place uh you hit the 420 cave and the
420 bong and that was always fun there's
there's a big culture I mean there
there's a lot of people there's a lot of
snowboarders that I know that have been
involved with weed and that was almost
kind of like their their side hustle
they were Reps for certain companies
which brought them all around to
different shops and different people but
uh the they also had their own little
side hustle and it's fun sometimes
figuring these things out years later
because I did work in the skateboard
snowboard industry and so I'd meet them
in one aspect and then in the parking
lot I'd be like wait a minute you're the
guy with that
okay and that was actually the last the
last time I'm remember BR bring up a
triggering word here um but that was the
last time I really smelled a skunk yeah
was in the parking lot of Steven's Pass
I I looked for it but they had probably
walked off like half hour earlier but I
I had everything that I had with me and
I was goingon to give him everything for
a nug like just give me a nug of that
that's all I want no I could smell it
but they probably just walked off
already nice little $100 joint
there this is but these are this is what
I enjoy so like right I can smoke this
24 hours a day I I and have a good time
I feel like this is one of those morning
ones I could smoke in morning I can
smoke it afternoon evening it's got the
right flavor it's uh it's a big one
though but I guarantee you put it out
you come back to it an hour later 10
hours later the next day still tastes
just like this damn yeah okay that's
impressive that is it's an advancement
that's one thing that you know at least
I think that legalization has brought is
there's so many more flavors so many
more profile there's more but I remember
smoking weed that was like this good
yeah back in the 90s right the cat piss
to me was like this we'd smoke joints of
cat piss and literally smoke them the
next day and they tasted good no cat
piss roach ever went to waste we would
smoke them down we would take it and put
it in bongs at the end that last little
roach break it out of the paper and
smoke it in a bong R before we would
throw the cat piss roaches we and it was
$60 an a straight
up and that was the skunkiest weed back
in the day though it was like fowl skunk
ammonia did you did you appreciate it
for what it was at the time or was it
this hindsight of like pining for that
you're like I appreciated it so much at
the time it was so amazing and I was in
disbelief that it could taste so good
and all the way down when you smoke it
that you could have flavor like that and
it it really sparked my curiosity and
set me up for the person that I am today
because I also realized that I talk
about this a lot of my shows well the
ugly weed is not necessarily the stuff
that doesn't look good isn't necessarily
bad yeah it might have an amazing effect
but a lot of people today think it has
to look good too and we had the ugly
stuff ever was the best stuff back in
the day so I never want to like look
past any of the ugly one we want to go
through and smoke everything and yeah
the commercial viability side is cool
and important but sometimes some of the
stuff we want to keep just for ourselves
too yeah a lot of the product I mean if
we're just talking flour doesn't
actually make it to the consumer's eyes
right whether it's getting concentrated
or put into a joint like that like the
consumer never sees what that flour
looks like people that help me feno hunt
do they never see it either I give them
joints they get joints like this there
you go and the reason is is because I
know what the weed looks like I know
what the flower looks like I know what
the structure looks like I know what it
smells like too I would really like to
know what it tastes like and what the
effect are I think those are the two
most informative pieces of information
that somebody who's trying to help you
do selections can do for you yeah they
can be like oh this one's great but if
you can roll them a joint of it and they
can be like you gave me 20 joints this
one was by far the best or this one was
by far the best and it felt like this or
this one made me feel like this but it
didn't taste very good but the effect
was something special you know cuz those
are the kind of feedback that's that's
the kind of stuff you can't get from a
COA right and just because it smells
good doesn't mean it translates into the
smoke and the flavor and maybe it tastes
good in the beginning but then halfway
down it you don't taste it at all yeah
but when you get something like this
where we're getting into it right now
and it's still just amazing flavor
that's what I like you know and I want
it to taste that good all the way down
to the roach I would love for the roach
tomorrow to taste just as good as it did
today well that thank and that just
again that just goes back to the amount
of flavors and profiles that we're
seeing out there now because it for me
it has to be a smack you in the face
there is no more subpar like I don't
want to have to imagine what this is
like I want to instantly know I mean we
all have that influence of like oh you
know you know asphalt or whatever but I
want it just to smack me in the face and
there's there's a few profiles that do
that so it's funny cuz you're talking
about asphalt and earlier today we had
the asphalt pheno of the GMO banana
Skittles and that is the most asphalt
I've smelled in a long time where it
straight up smells like hot asphalt
that's just been poured and it's like
it's funny because when you're going
through different selections things that
remind you of childhood or past memories
those are the things that excite me the
most and that's why I love doing this
that's that's one of the things that I
love the most about going through rooms
is when you can find something where
it's like o fresh hot asphalt and then
in your mind it's like when you start
thinking when did I smell that last and
you know but it's like I've smelled that
a bunch over over time throughout my
life um and there's so many little
things like that green tea we got a
green tea plant the other day that's
spelled straight like green tea and I
love all that stuff I love it when
they're unique and I love especially the
different ones mhm Fried Chicken yeah
yeah that's that's a weird tur but it
does exist um I mean I was smelling one
earlier and it smelled just like the
rubber dolls like when you were a kid
not like the like like He-Man characters
but there's a dis You' been smelling
Barbies
I Barbie smell
different but uh yeah it's there's you
know a bit of nostalgia with it and
music too that's totally you know that's
oh yeah it brings you back man that's
such a cool thing when you get a
connection to the plant it Sparks
something in the brain and it becomes
special well and the thing like with
pheno hunting if if you do it right
you're spending a lot of time with those
plants so like as they're progressing
and as they're going in from a
vegetative plant into flower uh you
start seeing the subtleness and the
changes and it's it comes on very
quickly and sometimes in other things
it's very soft and subtle things that
you notice are like very subtle after it
goes into flow and then it's like okay
well we have this structure we have this
or that or these smells and where you
can have some that are you know you take
20 things from the same progy and they
all smell completely different and then
sometimes you find those ones where it's
they're all pretty much the same or
they're all they're all shades of almost
almost The Identical same thing you know
whether it's orange and one's a little
more rindy or it smell one's a little
more orange juice smelling and one
really smells like the fruit and one
smells like the fake concentrate M you
know because you can get that or you can
get some that are like oh this one
smells like burnt rubber and this one
smells like a completely different type
of gas that's sometimes the terminology
too I think gets into place as funny it
reminds me of of a friend he always says
nuances like that's his answer to most
everything but there are there's like
different levels of like grape you know
is it candy grape is it a wine grape is
it what kind of grape is it so is it
like wine grape sparkling is it you know
there's grape juice there's conquered
grapes there's a grapefruit rollup yeah
you know what I mean like there there's
all kinds of exciting there's grape
candy like a grape Skittles you know cuz
I think of grape Skittles think of
Skittles as all the just Skittles I mean
there's the can like when someone says
that I think of the the cultivar right
but if you talk about grape Skittles as
opposed to Green Skittles like that to
me those are distinct yeah so and then
with grape it's like there there's a
bunch there's a ton of bunch and and
especially when you compare it to want I
said a ton of bunch I'm making up words
but you know it's funny uh but with
things like grapes and with oranges that
are complex and there's so many
components of them you know because
there's even the zest right like yeah
yeah go into the zest of an orange or
whatever it's interesting I got um it's
a good joint by the way it's pretty
strong too it's it's it's ton a bunch
strong yeah ton a bunch strong T bun
strong it'll get you there I feel like
yeah and well so this is one that checks
the boxes right it looks beautiful
smells amazing tastes good MH the effect
is just over the top I feel like it's
good and it comes on pretty strong and
then it just kind of goes nice and even
yeah so you know the with the the um you
know like flavors there's um so John
gross based killer shout out um he he
backs up my Westport grape juice and he
he actually um this last Dabo that they
had he took second place with the
hachimaki grape juice um it was a
combination of his 818 headband yep and
the Westport grape juice
and interesting enough he was able
obviously he had to get analytics so I
have you know like data and stuff for
these now but their tpine profiles
exactly what they had the percentages
they matched so closely but yet when you
try them as individuals there is such a
difference but you know he's he's
starting to talk about the nuances of
blending to oh that's awesome I like
blending rosin yeah but if we talk about
nuances there's also you know we talking
about the white papers from abstracts
Tech that were released this year on
flavorant and th
and sulfur and these things and they're
measured in such minute amounts that
maybe on a COA it looks like they're
similar that's okay that's what I was
trying to that's okay not on the table
DNA that's [__] hilarious uh but yeah
uh with these things they're such small
amounts that they might even look like
it's very similar but like they can be
completely different but in different
concentrations and a lot of the coas
that we're looking at there's no dials
on there flavor or anything they're not
testing for any of that right so we're
not getting the whole picture no and
then compared with the canabo that give
you the effect then it's like but but
over time we're going to collect a lot
more data yeah and that's what I'm
excited about is all this data
collection it's like especially when you
can compare it to effect because a lot
of people their Labs or whatever they
can compare all this data to more data
but then can you really compare it to an
effect because once we can start telling
you okay it feels makes me feel like
this or makes me feel like that then you
can have some observable data
information that I think is very
valuable that's the key to a billion
doll industry though is when you can get
that single serving effect like they
figured out with beer how it can affect
the majority of the population you can't
do that with cannabis yet like we
haven't figured out single serving
dosage because because beer pretty much
does the same thing to everybody and it
makes you not very good at driving right
cannabis makes me a better driver I
don't drive high usually um never
allegedly never but but especially uh
when when we're talking about like being
impaired to impaired to drive if you're
a regular cannabis user you're not
impaired like in that sense some people
might say you are it's really hard to
measure for one thing but I feel like
some people usually if you're if you're
everyday smoker that smokes all day
you're fine driving and you're probably
more cautious uh and you're more aware
and the reason is this is what the
reason is is because alcohol Tunes you
out mhm and cannabis Tunes you in right
so it's making you more aware of your
surroundings your environment I feel
like the more that you smoke the more
tuned in you are and aware of everything
whereas the more you drink the less
tuned in you are you're tuned out and it
gets worse and worse and worse to where
your perception of reality and your
awareness is we down yeah so that's that
to me is why it's you know you it really
bothers me that they want to arrest
people for smoking weed for driving and
I feel like if you're driving bad maybe
you should just get a ticket anyway
right for bad driving no matter what
whether you're high or whatever but if
you're you're endangering other people
yeah that's a problem but I don't see a
bunch of putthe heads driving out there
that are endangering other people no and
and you're right A lot of people do pay
more attention when they're doing that
there is a line like there have been a
few times where I'm like I'm not going
to drive at this moment but I'll wait
until I get there if anything it has
just made me more aware
of what I'm doing but there there's no
again you can't quantify that sort of
intoxification like a grandma smoking
that you know not a regular smoker would
be hurting somebody who is a regular
smoker is going to be just fine so if
the same amount of THD is in the blood
how you how do you define that and
that's a big problem I had a friend
recently in another country um get
pulled over and they do blood draws
there that's something they can't really
do here at least in Washington no but he
was smart about it he said please give
me your sobriety test because he gave
him the field sobriety test he passed
with flying colors but he knew that his
blood was going to indicate he was
intoxicated do you know what country
This was um I I do but I don't really
want to say okay yeah Canada for sure it
was can no no I'm kidding but uh but
yeah it's it's interesting because there
are countries like that where I've heard
of people getting arrested for having
marijuana cannabis in their blood mhm
yeah yeah which I think is absolutely
crazy I think it makes the world a
better place not a worse place first of
all that needs to be the first point of
discussion yeah second of all it's a
hell of a lot better than alcohol and
tobacco for you so those two things that
it's we those are legal and those are
very widely accepted by people
especially in the US but cannabis the
majority of people I think is they think
it's okay but there are still some
people that are like oh man that's just
the worst thing ever
yeah but those people will be gone
someday they will and they're getting
closer every day um you know I really go
back to Charlotte figgy and the sanj
Gupta special like I really think that
special changed the minds of a lot of
people or at least it made it harder to
deny once somebody
sees there's all kinds of ways to use
cannabis yeah but when there and there's
a lot of medicinal ways that people can
use it and that was one of them and if
you can kind of watch that and think
that it's a bad thing I just think
you're an a-hole yeah so yeah you're
just a bad person yeah I I really go
back to that that point because that you
know that's when we got a lot more
Medical but sorry I cut you off there no
that's all right but yeah I mean it's
it's interesting that to say some
someone shouldn't be able to heal
themselves or heal their children yeah
there's something wrong with that person
that says that it's not okay for plant
medicine to do that if they're not
hurting other people how can you say
that's bad you know but so many people
saw that and if if you haven't seen it
you probably should go look up 60
Minutes in sanj Gupta and cannabis you
type that in Google you're going to see
it and it's just a life-changing thing
it changed my parents mind about
cannabis more too yeah for more than
anything I think that that one interview
changed my mom's look at the whole thing
yeah and I don't know her views on it
weren't great before but definitely
after that it's like hard to deny that
you know it's not a bad thing and it's
again it's how it you used too we've
discovered the endoc canabo system
through this in the 9s and the
endocannabinoid system is probably one
of the major targets for most
pharmaceutical companies right now for a
range of different things yeah if we
didn't know about THC and we didn't try
to figure out where it was working we
wouldn't know about that so there will
be Pharmaceuticals that come from the
discoveries that we've made because of
cannabis there already are if that's
yeah if that's I mean Marinol and that
but if if that's what people want to
take then fine but give me the right to
have the origin yeah plant medicine you
know just plant itself GW
Pharmaceuticals you know they they're
definitely on the cusp and have been
working with Pharmaceuticals and making
what's the CBD THC the the epidex so the
epidex is the one that came out for the
J syndrome which is what Charlotte figgy
had um I think they're behind satex as
well which was just I think it was a
sublingual yeah but um Jazz Pharma in
the UK has has since bought GW
Pharmaceuticals and yeah again they're
coming out with all kinds of stuff Dr
Ethan Russo who was I think I don't
think he's with them anymore but and the
GW Pharmaceuticals he's the one who ran
like the clinical trials and the the
double triple blinds for the epid
dialects right um lives up in Washington
and I've been lucky enough to be to at a
place where he was speaking and kind of
got to listen to him but it was The
Taming THC the T paper about tpin in 200
yeah that's what really grabbed my
attention to all these nuances of the
profile and how they impact what we're
going after so nice yeah to bring that
full circle totally well let's go even
more full circle and I want to hear
about your past so let's let's talk
about your or cannabis origin story I
would love to hear it so I was just kind
of always you know the rebellious kid
tell me not to do something I'm probably
going to do it skateboarder just hanging
out with the older kid kids that's kind
of how I got into it um as far as just
kind of cultivating myself that was I
always point back to uh when it went
Medical in Washington state when it was
easier for more people to get cards I
did a little bit before that but it was
not very good or successful but that is
really when I kind of dove into it and
again getting the effects that I get
from it um just I could do it and I just
never stopped and I won't stop so that's
that's kind of how it got started there
nice yeah favorite
cvar chem 91 chem 91 that's awesome did
you see the chem 91 I got here it's yeah
it's chem 91 cross yes yes from flow
Gardens yes there were there was a lot
of very nice smelling things yeah yeah
yeah for sure uh yeah chem 91 Game
Changer the article I just wrote
actually there's a big chunk of it
that's in soft Secrets it's about chem
91 and the important importance of chem
91 and yeah I think people need to hear
that story over and over so we don't
forget it because a lot of times people
forget history for whatever reason a lot
of history has been forgotten you know
and we're on the shoulders of giants all
of us all of us that are here today
every single one of us is standing on
the shoulders of other people's work in
this industry if you're in this industry
working for cannabis as a steward of the
plant you're working on the shoulders of
the Giants that came before us people a
lot of unknown heroes from the 60s and
70s people that were doing the Lord's
work because they loved it yeah that
we'll never know their names you know
some of these people that did the real
stuff but yet we are able to work with
their plant and things that they created
that help push the plant forward pretty
cool thing you know when you put it into
perspective like that it absolutely is
and it's important like podcast to
record this because so much bad
information gets repeated like I do
writing for a few different companies
and so I'll do my research and they
always will send me links of you know
like basically what the competitions
article looks like so look at that do
something freaking different yeah um a
lot of times I see the same spelling
errors like there's a lot of copy paste
out there and unfortunately that is the
information that is most front and
center to a lot of people who are
looking for that type of information
yeah so it's important to really nail
down these details and talk to these
people and preserve those stories
because I always say AI is going to suck
at cannabis because there is so much bad
cannabis information out there that's
what it's going to scrape and that's
gonna that's how it thinks it works so
cannabis I don't think it's gonna get AI
or AI is not g to get cannabis it's a
really good joint in the beginning it
won't right but in the end it will when
you train when you train Skynet with
your system man then then we're in
trouble but uh yeah just don't turn to
the I mean I don't think it's a bad
thing I think we just need to know the
true stories and I think we are
all you know in the in the we all have
the opportunity to do amazing things
with this plant whether
it's being a producer for the James loud
podcast or whether it's being meno dope
that sings about cannabis or podcast
hosts or people that are cultivating or
extrack artists or the writers like uh
like Angela Baka Jimmy Divine yeah um
Greg Z and he's another great author and
these guys are just just amazing authors
but they are doing their contribution
that all is working synergistically what
with what we do and we're part of this
bigger Community but even
like it's even bigger than just the
community right so we're the Cannabis
Community but we're part of this
something something that's so much
bigger and it's you know and it's like I
love talking about that kind of stuff
because it makes me feel good yeah to be
part of something so much bigger and
kind of know my place in the world or
what or or at least feel like I know my
place in the world it's it's it's part
of the culture and it is when you know
it's it's fun to see other people
succeed and and when we work together we
do we succeed a lot more that there
there's something about the collective
just like the collective Consciousness
kind of working together yeah cuz you
know like being going back to being a DJ
like I was I was listening to a song up
here uh you know driving and there
there's like some songs every time that
just like give you the feels like you
know that like the arm you know the hair
on your arm stand up but there it goes
back to that moment as like the DJ who's
just like about to drop a record for the
first time yeah the crowd kind of like
hears it coming in they kind of hear the
tease you like hold it off for a second
then just drops and like everybody in
that room regardless of where you came
from like what you're into for like that
Split Second yeah has that just [__]
yeah just like have it moment like that
is so priceless
yeah and that comes from kind of the
culture and that's kind of what we're
trying to do and a lot of people are
doing it don't pay attention to a lot of
the negativity out there it's always
going to exist that's just kind of life
but there are good people and yeah
working together to the to sum it up
quickly but working together is a great
thing man for sure well yeah and I love
the Synergy of collaborations and you
know Synergy is a great thing like would
like having you in the chat and then
having you on the podcast right and
seeing you back in the day like
supporting the James loud show it was
like you were a big supporter of podcast
and you were the reason that I did
podcast back in the day people like you
that were watching that were tuning in
we had like some crazy 4,000 people live
on some of those episodes from all
around the world and you got to give
credit to Peter for doing such a good
job with the future cannabis project I
need to get him on the show yeah that
would be a rad interview that would be a
rad interview yeah he's a good dude and
uh but yeah I mean we have a we have an
amazing opportunity now all of us
because the thing is is times are going
to get better mhm times are also going
to get worse and then they're going to
be better again yeah and when they're
good we need to remember that they won't
always be good and when they're bad we
need to remember that they can be better
and they will be better and uh but it
takes this this whole Community this
Collective Consciousness to really put
forth the effort to make it better but
there's so many good people yeah there's
there's some Bad actors of course with
whatever you do there's always going to
be bad actors yeah but as a whole
there's still a lot of good in the
community there's people that believe in
this plant for the right reasons y uh
you know and that's why I'm here that's
it keeps me motivated and happy to work
every day you know and it's like I have
a great place where I can come work and
enjoy my time and I've set this place up
to where I come and I like being here
all day and I don't feel like I need to
leave to go somewhere else that's more
fun right well you know it's it's the
same reason too why like you know I
followed you the entire entire time it's
it's you going back to the vibe thing
you know you try to you try to catch
that same wavelength but there's a lot
of people that were there with me on
those shows that are still in your chat
today and that's like a community you
know that you've built and that we've
all connected to with overtime as well
so we got a lot of new ones too man we
got some really great people in the chat
you know it's like and then Rue he's
amazing he came we went out to rig in
the river you know it's like I I love
that you know it's like these are
legendary stories that you know be ble
to tell our grandkids yeah and so but
yeah just part of this community that's
so much bigger than ourselves yeah so uh
what do you have on the horizon uh on
the horizon just um the Chad
westport.org uh that's that's my website
but the Chad Westport YouTube channel
that's where they'll find most stuff and
uh I do you know a lot of live shows I
try to talk to a lot of Home gardeners
because I want to answer some of their
questions I always say I just want to
get people growing there's a million
ways to grow um I just want to get you
growing and then we can talk about other
things so that's what a lot of the live
shows are I've been doing the dope
history which is kind of like we're
talking about talking to some of these
people who might not be known by today's
people but absolutely should be um I
mean key stro Tom Alexander wolf seagull
I mean we've had Jorge santes Ed Rosen
people that oh yeah people that you know
they know those people but there's other
people that they don't know but this
preserving the stories are so important
and then uh I always like doing the seed
collector show too and we're seeing more
and more James loud packs pop up on that
so it's awesome yeah we we love genetics
so what was the best interview that
you've done since you started doing your
show wow um that's a great question uh
it's hard to really pick a favorite
there there's so many that I learned
from you know earlier I said it's nice
being in the front row able to raise
your hand and have every question
answered yeah I take it AG of that um so
everybody from like breeders to
different
scientists um people smarter than me
basically yeah
uh dang I can't pick one I don't know
yeah I'm sorry it's okay M mine I think
the Reggie Gino interview was really
good Maya from M was the my favorite one
this year but I've done so many I got
one that's coming out by the time that
people watch the show the Derek from
planta that was a great episode but yeah
the Derek from planta episode was really
freaking amazing I feel like we had a
lot of synergy we he's he sees the plant
on the same level that I do and I think
he does an amazing job with cultivation
as far as he's one of the best out there
awesome and so I love that and then Maya
fromom it's just you can't go wrong with
Maya she's another one that
like we've hung out a couple times we
know each other from events and stuff
like that but getting her on the podcast
to be able to talk talk to her in depth
like that she sees the world in the same
way that I see the world in a lot of
ways which having guest that you can
like connect with on that level and I
have a lot of guests that I connect with
but but hers it was like the
conversation I feel like was really
great and uh so many other ones there's
so many other there's just been so many
isn't it yeah I mean you know having
Jeff from further come in on the Sarah
pin he was great she's great that was a
fun interview and you know the funny
thing about podcast is I really like
interviewing two people almost more than
individuals and I feel like there's
something about that energy where like
you're just shooting around and you're
talking to both people and it's just a
little faster paced and it just can go
in different directions too because now
instead of two ideas we have three ideas
and that can take us anywhere especially
yeah when they when they buy well as
well I I do like kind of having guest
and I used to do that a lot more too is
just have kind of two people to bounce
things off of cuz it is stimulate the
conversation three minds are better than
two sometimes I agree and it's like uh
well and cuz when you're asking
questions people want to ask questions
and it can just go the conversation can
go in so many different
directions um but yeah and I feel like
we've grown as a podcast like from our
first episode to now it's like nobody's
even seen the episode that we filmed
before the first episode that our
current producer Ryan wasn't a part of
and it's not that it was bad it was was
just different and Chris Castle was the
guest and so we have that hidden maybe
we'll release it one of these days
easteregg it was a good interview and I
feel like and and I've Ma I've been made
friends from people being on the show
now I'm friends with a bunch of people
that were guests that we were just kind
of I knew them or maybe I had their
phone number but I wasn't really good
friends and now like I feel like I have
a lot more friends yeah absolutely a lot
more people like-minded people and it's
always great to feel that because
there's so many good people in the
industry that are like that too though I
mean there's so we have so many good
ones and there's so many that haven't
been on the show that are great that I'm
looking forward to getting a lot of a
lot of the nice guys are shy guys yeah
or girls oh yeah you know it's like so
we had I was up a canif Fest and there
was like a couple people I really wanted
to interview and like they're on my
bucket list of people to interview and
they're a little shy some of them yeah
yeah where they clam up yeah they're
talkative without the red light on some
people some people are like that they
the camera they don't yeah they they
can't open up on the camera but it's
just practice cuz I was a little nervous
the first time I did it and now I'm I'm
definitely not nervous from filming
although at canif Fest I [__] was
nervous yeah that was the first time
I've been nervous on camera for a while
but it was because every time I would
get too close to the mic or too far away
from it either you couldn't hear it or I
get close and then we'd get feedback
right and it was just it wasn't that I
was nervous as much as I was annoyed by
it and it was like making me cautious of
how I was having to talk yeah well you
cared for sure you cared about the end
the end consumer about the quality so
yeah I get that we had Johnny and uh so
Johnny from Huckleberry Hill Farms and
we had Jason from Ridgeline on a panel
that I did when I was up at canest 2024
an event nice hopefully I see that
sometime the interview is really good
and those guys are super passionate yeah
yeah that's awesome I mean out outside
of the studio things are really out of
your hand
sometimes yeah you know that's what
impresses me the most about these stereo
systems that I've been to like at
festivals over the last like year and a
half two years how much better the sound
systems have gotten good I'm all for it
man I I like as the audio engineer I
don't like bad sound so I'm all for it
me neither and I've heard plenty of bad
sound in my life at events I mean I us
to go to Raves back in the day and
concert a lot of a lot of concerts
throughout my life and there's been good
sound and bad sound and sometimes you go
and you think it's going to be amazing
and it's bad and other times you think
it's going to be bad or not have any
expectations I like the no expectation
to be honest in life I found whether
it's going to the movies or going to
shows like that I'm not sure about
having no expectations is so much better
than somebody said it was going to be
good or somebody said it was going to be
bad because a lot of times when they say
it's bad maybe it's okay or if they say
it's really really good I have these
high expectations and I go to this event
and I'm just like eh right it was all
right you got to judge it by the source
too movies a lot of times are like that
when somebody's like oh you you got to
see this movie and it's like if I don't
know that person I know some of my
friends when they say that for sure I'm
like yeah I need to see that movie y but
sometimes if somebody's like oh man you
got to see this movie and it was
amazing uh maybe we don't have the same
taste always there's nothing wrong with
that but I always try to go with less
expectations and stuff yeah that's good
you're less disappointed that way yeah
you get less disappointed in life for
sure yeah you set yourself up for your
mind to be blown as well right so it all
depends on how you look at it that's
happened a bunch in my life too you know
with weed too yeah where you're like
someone says it's good and then you're
like oh well good to you and good to
me or holy [__] what was that I can't
wait to smoke more of it oh there's no
more available that sucks I know I'm a
little Bunch little sad about the sour
tea I'm just gonna say that yeah I wish
I had some right now if you were here
next week you you could try it because I
will have some to taste it's super
special that sourd is something special
I bet but no really in all reality that
sourd is some the best stuff I've smoked
in a long time and it made me realize
how much I love Sour Diesel still even
though I talk about it a lot until you
get to experience it again it's the
conversation is much different than the
reality and then when you see it you're
like ah I was right all along it was
this good yeah so and sometimes I think
our minds can be fickle or our minds can
you know deceive us we think we remember
things a certain way and maybe it wasn't
that way I mean I hear some of the
stories from my friends and I've seen
them change over time I hope that's not
the way with me too you know what I mean
I always think [__] I hope my stories
don't change as much as some of my
friend's stories and I don't know if I
think a lot of it's accidental but your
mind maybe REM stuff differently as we
get older and yeah and a lot of this we
weren't really thinking or the people
weren't thinking they needed to remember
it it wasn't important at the time so
yeah I mean we were drinking way too
much at the time you know or whatever it
is right or high on this or you know
I've definitely done that that was a
very good joint I think I've said that
three times so ity at least three stars
that's yeah that's five star yeah we
didn't have to put Ros in it it's it's
the size of a hash hole without the hash
hole very nice that would probably
destroy me if I went for one of those
again like back in the day that was all
I could afford for like two weeks at a
time yeah like you got to make that
eighth get by just a little bit here a
little bit there take a couple hits a
night or how would you do it you take a
pack bowls of it and then smoke like a
pipe yeah yeah I mean protop pipe
flashback to that um the little chamber
pipes that you would have you try to
keep your resonated piece in there I got
my protop pipe over here nice I'm all
about protop pipes oh yeah they still
make them I the real ones they also make
the knockoffs which suck okay I wouldn't
smoke a knockoff how can you tell well
don't order it off eBay order it from
protop pee.com like literally if you
order it from prototype. comom you're
not going to get a knockoff if you order
it anywhere else you're taking risks
yeah uh even in head shops I don't know
that I would trust it I would order it
directly from them protoype decom
Classics I love it I love supporting the
brand they're OG small business they're
the type of people we we need as a
community to support and I'm trying to
get them on the show because you know
they have the best stories company like
that it's like they've been around since
the 70s they were in San Francisco they
were they were up north uh in NorCal
which I think they still are cool and
those pipes are made from brass and
they're legit that little poker that's
on those and you need the poker you know
you have to yeah yeah the little rubber
tip on the end totally we used to have
screens in them right and uh I don't use
screens in my pipe anymore any of them
whether it's glass or whatever I don't
like screens but did you go to the
hardware store and take the screens out
of the sinks no I took my parents
screens and they don't they still don't
know that I took the screens out of the
sinks of the house but I took the
screens out of all the bathroom why is
it run so funny yeah yeah but yeah I
mean that's where we used to get screens
when we were younger all the things we
put into our lungs yeah you no I think
and we're okay it turned out okay turned
out fine we're doing podcast so we're
okay reasonably intelligent today yeah I
don't know about that but for me but I
have my moments and as long as I'm cold
plunging typically you know been taking
a break from cold plunging by the way
you're taking it yeah I'm taking I moved
to a new place and so now we're at the
new place and I'm waiting to figure out
what I want to do for cold plunges but I
took about the last two months off okay
which is a big step for me so especially
since the very first show that we did
I've been doing cold plunges and then
all the way straight till about two
months ago yeah like almost every day
are you excited or afraid to do the next
one no I'm not I don't I don't get
afraid of that like cold water doesn't
scare me at all it okay neither does
heat none of that stuff but I do like
cold water and I I mean I could go in a
cold punch today and I would feel great
right now like just thinking about it
makes me relaxed come surfing up with me
come surfing the real cold water you
don't need a wet suit you'll just you'll
love it I'll without up there I can do
out for like a good 10 15 minutes and
then freeze in place yeah cuz the how
cold is the water out there you're
looking at 50s probably probably at
least I I don't know specifically but
yeah I if you don't wear booties up
there like I've gotten frostbite on the
top of my feet before because I didn't
wear booties that is the most painful
thing for three weeks every step felt
like a sledgehammer on the top of my
feet oh that's all bad yeah it's not
good so wear booties if you're you're
wearing pretty thick Mill wet suits y
yeah yeah full full with the ring so
when you get done you just have this
like tan ring if it's a sunny day it's
great that's hilarious yeah it's awesome
really cool you got sharks up there too
we do we have sharks I swear I was
stocked by one once but I'm still here
so uh yeah surfing surfing can be
dangerous definitely you got to respect
the ocean you got to respect nature but
uh you got to respect everything that's
the problem with the younger
generation shake the fist lack of
respect damn lack of respect for the
ocean and everything else y respect is
huge for sure yeah it's amazing that the
older you get the the I don't know the
more you realize your impact and how
treating things a certain way is better
not only for yourself but for other
people as well but if you want to be
selfish about it just do it for yourself
yeah it's the same end result yeah yeah
some people don't respect how strong
cannabis is and then they eat a 500
milligram edible dude that'll ruin your
day that'll teach you some respect like
literally Okay so people are looking to
find out more about Chad Westport where
can they go thanks man uh Instagram
chad. Westport there is the website Chad
westport.org aw so you go there pick up
some stickers pick up some t-shirts
whatever you guys want to do uh that's
where you'll find the beans though
fantastic we're going to be giving some
of his seeds out and some of my seeds
out on the episode so I hope you guys
enjoyed the chat and uh thank you for
tuning in thank you for being the guest
this is great having you on the show
thanks for having me on your show yeah
dude this is a dream so seriously thank
you for letting me be part of it thank
you for having it here for me to be a
part of and all the people in the
background doing their thing that's
making this as special as it is so
big thank you much love man it's been
Anon thank
[Music]
you thank you guys for watching please
like And subscribe down
[Music]
below
um it's not just
dude we got way we got way too high like
yawning on the
show like yawning on the show because
I'm too high that sour d yeah packs a
punch