[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James loud
podcast and today our special guest is
Chad from Canada how are you doing today
Chad good I'm doing good thanks for
having me dude thanks for coming on the
show we've been talking about this for a
while yeah I'm excited yeah so chat's in
town for Emerald cup so we're both going
to be at this amazing event that that's
been going on forever uh it's the 20
year anniversary I think I think that's
right yeah but the way they promote the
culture is so exciting dude yeah so I'm
and there's the first time in Oakland
we're going hip hop it went from like
Grateful Dead to uh to hippie outside
too short we went from we went from
Grateful Dead to two short in a short
matter of time so I'm excited to see
what they do with it I I uh I love
Oakland obviously uh been working in
Oakland my whole life on and off we were
talking earlier about how you had a grow
right down the street from where I had
to grow when I was in Oakland uh you
know and those those big basements yeah
when I you know this is a while back and
we had a 50 lighter it it was almost 50
lights in a basement I had 12 in a in a
in the like supposed to be the second
living room wow and I you know I
camouflaged it off and uh every was like
this seems larger from the outside I was
like oh yeah I we were pulling so much
power the the line was buzzing coming in
the house no one ever complained well
and I you know I hate to admit ad it but
there was also a time when you could get
pg&amp; to recognize you as a lowincome
person right because you didn't have a
job sure so you just qualified as low
income and so they would subsidize the I
was like don't they see that I have a
$1,200 power bill and they're
subsidizing it so around 2 14 they
started giving uh breakes for people
that bought electric cars and so
literally that year all of my friends
bought electric cars they bought Nissan
leaves right uh that were you know they
they basically you got 50 % off of your
power bill and so use the plug you still
you just just rewired that plug well one
of my friends he bought three of them
for three different houses and put them
in different people's names and then
power bill in their names and was using
that but no names we don't want PG come
and trying to get their money back right
yeah totally even though they they seem
to uh take advantage of the customer
these days yeah man the power bills are
a lot higher than they used to be that's
for sure for sure everything's gone up
though groceries yeah that's another
podcast though right yeah yeah
absolutely for sure the only thing that
hasn't gone up is our our favorite
commodity right well no I think the the
price on the streets is the same the
price in the dispensaries is the same
The Growers are making a heck of a lot
less they are so they are the inputs
have gone up yeah the inputs like
electric well I mean if we're looking at
electricity and then we're looking at I
mean everything Warehouse if you
warehous if you own Cana or you own
whatever it is you're paying more to
keep the lights on you're paying more to
pay your employees you're paying more
for those ingredients whatever you need
every and then and then and then of
course you know with the way the state
treats it like the best analogy we were
talking about my friend who runs uh High
Fidelity shout out Chris Garcia but
basically it's like they'll charge you
for the baln the lettuce the bread the
cheese and then they tax the sandwich as
well yeah and you're like so every
aspect you know the bread maker gets
taxed the the bakery gets taxed the you
know the cheese maker gets taxed and
then of course then it's the sandwich
maker gets taxed well my favorite saying
is Uncle Sam is your silent partner so
that's don't own your property you're
just renting it from them with their ta
property taxes right so yeah yeah it's
pretty wild yeah yeah yeah I hope sooner
or later that uh you know that it it
becomes some more more not considered
like uh cigarettes or alcohol but more
like cinnamon or turmeric you know what
I mean yeah I mean I think it you know
we're just starting to normalize it
right now as as something that you know
as far as like that's probably safer
than alcohol or tobacco of you know of
course yeah but I think for the longest
time it was like oh man the devil's
lettuce is bad stuff well you got it we
all know the story right of DuPont and
uh and Herz right the P the paper and
plastic people who demonized it with uh
Reef for madness watch it watch re from
Ms and that's a awesome it blow your
mind it'll blow your mind especially if
you smoke and then you're like wait how
did they get there what is going on here
yeah it's it's mindblowing how we went
from that and then it took us so long I
mean alcohol prohibition was very short
in relative to how how cannabis
prohibition has taken so long and there
was you know there was generations of
people that believed that it was bad and
now your your mom your mom's generic not
your mom but you know my my mom's always
like so what about this and I was like
oh here's a salve you know for your
arthritis or whatever she like you know
my parents are on with the whole thing
they get it they have no problem you
remember when you they they didn't know
what you did for a living well yeah I
mean some people had that luxury of
having those parents but my parents the
whole time were like so what do you do I
was like ah gardening yeah I'm in the
gardening industry yeah so you know even
with this job and you know even though
the name you're like what so did you
grow up in this area no I uh so I think
a you know I was a somewhat of a
military brat right and then I settled
down in my grandparents owned a Ranch in
Malibu so I lived there for a long time
while my parents still traveled and then
uh uh went back and forth between there
and DC and then uh senior year high
school I went to Palisades High School
in La that's when I started really
getting into you know buy buying the
product on the streets and then like I
can make I can do this All I need is
space right you know I grew up
Agriculture and so then I moved
uh went to uh went to high school went
to college in Texas started there that
was a real hard what part of Texas
Austin Austin San Marcus Austin's all
right oh it's a cool town but like yeah
for sure trying to figure out in 92 93
on how to grow indoors without buying
more air conditioning or growing
outdoors and once it hits about 100 90
something degrees of plant goes I'm not
growing anymore right you you're you're
wasting your time and money so then I
moved to San Francisco and uh Game
Changer yeah yeah and then you know you
you do two jobs to rent the other in the
flat you know what I mean sure and then
as soon as that that room pays off then
you tell the other roommates they can go
cuz you're going to rent out their room
nice you know and then no one the
landlord's like I don't you're not you
know you're not doing all the other
drugs that are in the Streets of San
Francisco sure so and then you're a good
landlord I mean a good tenant you know
to the landlord and so then I grew there
and then uh I did acquire a small uh
issue living in San Francisco you know I
did seem to party a little too much I
don't want to get too one day my kids
might watch this so I don't want to know
go too de too de yeah yeah I can tell
off off camera but so I had to get uh
get my life in order I moved to LA and
that's when I just put my head down and
I was like I'm not doing anything else
for me La is like I think of as a Party
City and I think San Francisco is more
like Zer but you can party anywhere all
I needed was uh no assistance I needed
to get away from the people I knew and
so I moved to Pasadena and uh and uh got
a duplex and then lived in the living
room and then went to the landlord and
said I need another another duplex and
they didn't ask you know yeah so I had a
couple duplexes and then uh then I I met
a woman got her pregnant and then she
became my wife still to this day and uh
I had to uh I had to I had to change get
it was it's stressful you know yeah it's
stressful being in the black market and
uh well the the it's a lot different
than it is today you know it's like in
California it's it's a misdemeanor now
back then you know back then and then
you can say you have hemp yeah you know
totally yeah well I mean it all falls
under T not all of it but a lot of it
falls under thca which is is hemp I mean
we have the DCC and then we have you
know that that's the big oversight and
then we have hemp licenses and you know
it's funny because like I mean that that
stuff is all as far as we're talking
hemp license not for flow not in
California they don't they don't that
that one doesn't work here D States
Oregon Kentucky Tennessee Tennessee and
Texas are the two that I know and
they're all CBD
dispensaries but they're selling flour
they're selling flour that you can smoke
and it will make you feel different I
don't want to blow anybody's cover but
the new game is is false
coas yeah I'm sure I wouldn't be
surprised yeah and I'm just like whoa
whoa you guys are [ __ ] messing with
Federal uh State documents yeah I guess
criminal yeah yeah I mean but even still
I think if you know what you're doing
and you're growing the right cultivars
and most of them are the right cultiv
you can Harvest early and it will show
up as thca it's not going to be Delta 9
THC right you know and if you're not
heating it up you're not going to get
Delta 9 THC If the product doesn't start
so as long as you're not heating it up
you're going to have a product that's
thca uh maybe some CBD some other canabo
but you're not going to have you know
the the bad one right the right it's so
funny because you know it's we live in
an interesting time we do it's exting
cuz the whole world the whole United
States should be like that where you can
go to any store and buy it as long as
you're an adult right you know I feel
like I mean I I still believe in the
whole adult thing you know even though
when I was a kid I got cigarettes when I
was you know I got other people to buy
my cigarettes high school was Al alol
cigarettes you know and yeah yeah no but
I I do think that uh I think adult you
know this is my libertarian point of
view I don't know if I get too any you
know but I think adults should be able
to do whatever they want to do yeah long
as they don't hurt anybody else exactly
if only you know what I mean you can
hurt yourself it better yeah I mean but
even still I mean hurting yourself to a
degree right like there's some stuff I I
don't think meth should be legal 100%
And I think that that that uh
fortunately for
us
the uh Fentanyl and other hard
narcotics has so overshadowed us that we
can kind of get a little room to breathe
you know what I mean so look at Oregon
yeah they had it everything was legal
you know they're going back they're
going back on it and which is which is
you got to try it out you got to figure
out somebody has to try it out how do we
know if it's going to be good or bad
unless we try it out and it worked in
Portugal so yeah places like Portugal it
it works you know and I think but it's
not cookie cutter all over every
situation is different that's the
libertarian to me I don't like the
federal government I like the state and
local governments going no I mean if you
live in Nebraska you be able to smoke H
but if you live in downtown New York you
should probably shouldn't you know
there's just it all depends right so
because each City each Town each state
is different yeah and I mean I think
there's a lot of things you know like
that California could have done
different
and but every state every state we look
at Oregon they gave out too many
licenses right right I feel like
Washington Oklahoma oh they've had their
own set of problems Oklahoma is a
nightmare right like there you know and
I California did it pretty good but we
still have our own issues the taxation
is the worst part and they've kind of is
it over 100%
now on the final product I think it's
over 100% it's rough isn't that crazy
but but uh yeah I mean just from like if
we if we look at it I think they just
rolled back some of the taxes too good
in June June 1st June 1st June 5th
something like that so I think also 40%
of the revenue going to the police to
the law enforcement is probably a
mistake as well considering I don't
think that makes sense no not for in I
mean not for enforcement in my opinion
yeah yeah I feel the same way so so yeah
we're in a strange time but and you know
this is this is the it's like building a
small business though you gota there's a
lot of trial and eror that goes on and
if stabilization it's not going to be
stable for a while we're gonna we're
going to go through this period of
uncertainty for quite a while and then
it's going to stabilize and we're going
to figure it out I mean look at the
genetics are all over the place right
now too it's like a lot of the stuff is
the same people don't even understand
what's different they think they have
this but really they have this there's a
lot of the we were talking about that
earlier the name game right right the
the yeah the the hustle we call it cut
fishing also that happens a lot so
they're like oh yeah here's the rs11 but
really it's Lemon Cherry
gelato talk to some of these uh man
these LP manufacturers and how they will
cu the metric will allow you to change
the name of course so if you're if your
wedding cake isn't selling all of a
sudden you can have something completely
different and it's the same product and
and no one you know there's no
verification well there's no
verification and that's the biggest
thing is like how do you verify it now
my flora DNA out of Sacramento they're
doing some amazing stuff I mean the
fingerprinting technology that we have
now we can identify stuff that's exactly
the same right right based on markers
that's it's just like there's what 30
something odd purples and it's all just
basically in my opinion from what I've
seen in the last 35 years of we
cultivating it's just a some Granddaddy
Purple now you you you know more than me
about this but but I you know oh I see a
lot of I mean you can breed that trait
into pretty much anything over time uh
but yeah and I like Granddaddy Purple we
had Jimmy from Myers Creek talk about
how he brought it to the market you know
awesome amazing story a great story yeah
it's a great story and I'm not you know
I was actually giving that you know
props I'm like dude it's yeah it's from
them you know I like GDP but but GDP and
then you know cookies came along and
gelato and sunset sherbet really you
know it blew up and now purple is a
qualifier for good cannabis which is so
silly that's not that's not that's not
true right it's not true it's not true
but people people are a I can just give
you I can just drop the temperatures and
make the phosphorus deficient and boom
there's your purple sure so anybody else
wants to make a purple strain out there
just get your water temps to about 58
degrees or lower and boom you cuz cuz
temp drop your nighttime temps drop your
nighttime temps there's a temperature is
just as important as pH it for nutrient
take yeah people don't realize that you
know once you get your pH but then if
your temps are off you know too high it
just won't even take anything right
right you're basically cooking it you're
killing it and if it's too low then it
won't it won't interface with all the
macro and micronutrients that are in
there so you you you'll have
deficiencies which then depending on
what time you harvest in the plant you
know yeah so you can go a little longer
with the plant I get more purple too
right right well just the same with
Golden Goat you know Golden Goat the
reason is cuz it's 110 day strain and
it's basically turning gold yeah like
aaal gold so that's you know a lot of
people like oh I'm like that's not
Golden Goat it's like you didn't let it
go long enough right like I don't have
110 days in flower you're like well
don't grow that strain grow your La your
LA Confidential or your crack your green
crack and then I really like LA
Confidential and I like green crack yeah
IO yeah for sure I like the LA
Confidential that was it's it's got this
unique nose that's unmistakable and it's
got this nice gas to it it's it's not
the gassiest thing in the world but it's
got great gas it's got like the perfect
amount of gas it's very well balanced
what is your one of your let's not I
don't want to put you down favorite
strain of flower to inest so people that
watch the show they all know this sorry
sorry it's okay but I will tell you that
my favorite is cat piss of all time
really yeah and I I don't know now how
long have you seen cat it's been a long
time since I've seen it okay but I I
just saw Sour Diesel in fact I'm going
to have some Sour Diesel this week in
Emerald cup yeah uh dude
the real Sour the real real the real
real Sour Do there do they still do like
pre98 is that what they what do they
yeah there's a pre98 Bubba I mean that's
still I love pre98 Bubba too I love the
soapiness of it I love the uniqueness of
that you know I I can spot that in a
grow room too there's certain there are
certain things that I've grown over my
life where I'm like just by looking at
it I'll tell you that's Bubba Kush right
that's just one of those ones I know the
the bud structure the the top how the
top grows it's very unique
um same thing with sour diesel when I've
I've grown a bunch of sour in my life
and same with confidential I can still I
see confidential in my head right now
I'm like oh because it's so it has a
little bit thicker hairs too the
confidenti has these yarn hairs a little
bit I mean not to like the Durban that I
grew back in the day had yarn where it
covered up the crystals yeah it look
like like a hippie chick but the LA
Confidential would they would start out
as bigger hairs but then the the the uh
bra would start to swell up and when the
bra swelled up they would make the hairs
a lot smaller yeah yeah yeah so but yeah
LA Confidential that's that's one of my
yeah Classics yeah yeah I'm uh I was
talking to you about this before uh you
know I'm really into the you know I
guess it's the uh older person in me but
uh train wreck yeah the uh headband yeah
headband like so that's a the headband
is another one that depending on who you
ask you can get 10 different opinions on
what real headband is and the names cuz
some people like uh you know humbled
headband and then some people like 707
Headband like I've seen both of those
and those are two totally different La
headband there's all these different
headbands I mean I yeah I mean the 707
versus there was an OG Kush Headband
that's the one there yeah that was the
one that I liked yeah I mean that I got
from yeah n is the this guy null he's
from nectar's okay nectar's Collective
and he was part of the holy water crew
back in the day I know yeah yeah yeah NL
is the one that brought that headband up
and I you know IC Collective had it and
dude that thing is amazing uh 2013 cup
loud seeds I was part of loud seeds and
we won the first place with IC
Collective with that and yeah that was
the cut from null amazing yeah yeah yeah
and then uh you know it's been fun to
see like uh you know how what four years
ago cap in his Mac one was the The Rage
yeah it's funny how that was the some
people still think of it and love it and
I'm I'm not the hugest fan of the flower
I think it's very interesting a breeding
book and in my breeding book I there's a
case study on on it because it's
extremely special right as as far as
genetically it is extremely it's Unique
it's extremely special I think it was an
accident right it's a partial tripl
sometimes there an accident I don't want
to insult no no I I think he
intentionally bred that he worked on it
he he did and I think the he did some
real selection on it too because if you
if you work with any of the the
lineage uh it comes out hazy if you look
at the other like there we had a Mac 69
it's not that ha the Mac one not
but so Mac 69 that I got for first class
genetics who's one of my good friends my
buddy Ray he gave me this this other Mac
which was the Mac 69 and that was hazy
very hazy I'm excited you could see how
they were related yes you could totally
see how they were related but it was
like whoa this is haze and this is like
totally missing the haze yeah right do
you think the haze craze is going to
come back like I I remember it's already
back in certain circles for sure okay
okay good good good yeah so I would say
the equatorial sativa whatever that that
category is definitely slowly making the
comeback it's big over in Europe I got
some super silver in my bag that's
mindblowing that you'll be like what is
that I can't wait till the end of this
podcast yeah yeah I mean it's super
silver Lemon Haze yeah Super Lemon Haze
Super Silver Haze those are great those
are making a comeback we have those uh
you know those Greenhouse Seed Company
my good friend Arian oh yeah yeah yeah
yeah yeah he's Dutch yeah yeah yeah well
he's all kinds of stuff but seed company
is from over there and yeah just
speaking of that him I was uh talking
about Adam Dunn the other day yeah he's
a character speaking of Holland we might
as well just throw Adam's D Adam's name
I mean listen he was the one you know
one of the very first that said I'm just
going to go over there and then you know
he heard what's happening in Denver you
know yeah four 15 years ago and jump
[ __ ] yeah I's like I can go back home
now yeah yeah but that MK Ultra that he
did you know that was good yeah yeah
yeah yeah I really like MK Ultra you
know those are nostalgic for me and
that's that's what I was back to my
point is that that's the kind of stuff
I'm yeah you know I really like yeah we
were talking about Romulan I really like
Romulan back in the day I think there
was and Romulan right aren't they aren't
they a generation so similar yeah
similar years and so that but that white
white widow there was different
expressions of it we only had we we got
this stuff called The White Widow that
wasn't anything like the European White
Widow but it would make you sweat like
like crazy we called it the sweat the
sweat we got it from Richmond and these
these guys grew it it was expensive it
was like 4,000 a pound or something like
that here Richmond here yeah yeah these
guys used to grow killer but Richmond
still the scary neighborhood that it um
there's areas in richm that are still
bad yeah of course sure of course of
course Romulan and white widow oh man
what about you what's your desert island
strain I think it's Shoreline I think
that's so f is it okay so now there's
this is another great topic for
discussion so I work with
I am the I am one of the few the Texas
Shoreline or the not me like like no
that that I know the devil the uh what's
his name yeah that guy so he had he only
got half of it those are my boys yeah
but so they they bred that with uh
lavender okay okay so they it with no no
it was some's lavender so I
believe that the real Shoreline I can
get that I had it I read with it yeah I
it's really good but I would say that
that's from the skunk family it is it's
skunk number something yeah yeah it's
skunk yeah yeah it's from a it's from a
bag at a uh
1980 1988 1989 dead show at the
Shoreline Amphitheater the guys my boys
got a bag and they had one seat in it
yeah and then they started in their
closet and then another person uh Paul
Hansen got rest his soul uh he blew up
with it and then Houston which is a huge
consumer Market made it uh commercially
viable yeah then so then I got a hold of
it because I knew I knew those guys and
yeah and uh yeah Shoreline yeah I I made
some crosses with the shoreline in fact
uh we call one of them bies ah yeah you
know and if you're from Texas you know
what bu is you get the inside joke right
yeah I like it I like it a lot I love
that Shoreline cut and it's strong it's
got this unique nose I did some work
with the Fort Collins cough too that's
another one that I really like yeah yeah
yeah but it's a
you know and I costed it with the banana
skitt the fours cough has still got uh
you know still got people making money
off of it up there I think so and it's
it's hard to get not a lot of people
want to grow it it's a big tall plant if
you grow It Outdoors it just wants to
grow straight up yeah I think the one I
had in my backyard was 11 feet tall or
something like that so have you grown
train wreck Outdoors before because I've
only grown it indoors no so train wreck
is one of those ones I a lot of my
friends grew train W yeah that's what I
that's that was my first Money Maker it
always looks funny it never never looks
like the happiest plant no and
the and I think the Adam done said
basically it was called train wreck
because it turns your grow room into a
train wreck that doesn't surprise me at
all you know instead of like there's no
like you know a train hit something or
some story it hits you like a train W no
cuz it's a it's a daytimer it's a work I
call it work weed yeah you know but it's
strong too it's strong that's why I
always thought it was called train wreck
because you feel like a train wreck but
you can tap bang out some emails or some
reports on that you know you know what I
mean yeah yeah so yeah train wreck but
yes I think Shoreline is uh is my go-to
the older version I think you know the
problem too you can talk on this is
the the genetic drift this so shine
Shoreline never had uh not too many
people put it back to seed right so
you're taking you know a cutting of a
cutting of a cutting and 20 something
years later it's different than you
remember it from back in the day if you
happen to ever acquire the first couple
cuts right which don't exist because
either they've turned to to trash or you
know or mold or yeah we have this little
thing called tissue culture which I I'm
so excited about now yeah we'll talk
about that after the show but yeah
getting that through tissue culture and
then a lot of those things I think you
know I was thinking Sour Diesel had a
lot of that going on and I thought you
know these because I've I've seen Sour
Diesel
from 10 15 different people over the
last year people were like oh this is
some Sour this is some Sour a lot of
people have given me Sour Diesel samples
like oh bro here you go I know you're
looking for the sour and they give it to
me and it's like it reminds me more of
chem 991 than it does of Sour Diesel
it's got that burnt tire but it doesn't
have that like strong do you think what
is the relationship between Kim dog and
Sour Diesel Sour Diesel I me is a
predecessor I believe it's a it's a bag
seed of chem 91 now we can argue this
because everyone has their
different I think my the people watching
the show will argue this and they'll be
send in type it right now huh I I went
and I tried to source as much
information as I could as possible and
we believe is there any relation to
Hell's Angels on either one of those I
don't think so CU that's the story I
heard Hell's Angels yeah and the cross
between that and some dead heads yeah
which back in the 60s was they were yeah
weel well I mean maybe from the you know
I mean I there's the whole chem dog
story we don't need to go into that
right now but that was another dead show
like that was yeah Deer Creek yeah that
was Deer Creek 1991 I still have yeah
it's it's I have someone gifted me
tickets from that show gotcha so I got
the tickets that are mounted and framed
yeah but yeah friends are at the fish
show this weekend in the east coast
right now it's crazy nice well you know
Billy strings is playing on Saturday and
Sunday at the Greek this weekend yeah
yeah I know I'm I love Billy strings his
music's amazing dude so how did you get
involved with Cana so let's see I had my
grows in La uh uh
2002 3 4 five uh and I got a woman
pregnant one
wife uh and she's like you need a
job I I got two duplexes going we're
good she's like no you need to get
health insurance and you need to get uh
a reputable you need a paycheck to put
in the bank yeah so that we can borrow
money MH so I went to go work for better
grow in
Pasadena uh and I worked for them doing
the warehouse uh he was the first guy to
do internet text like reviews and stuff
you know so we're talking five and six
2005 and six and so uh I was working for
him got my grow and I started using Cana
in 2000 when I moved to LA I was tired
of uh the General
Hydroponics I felt that I was missing
something uh which I was you know yeah
you know it's I had to make the next
step up so uh the guy who worked at the
store that I finally worked at uh I said
have you ever tried Cana and I was like
No And it was you know relatively new to
the market I think you got here in 99
yeah it's in Holland for 30 years
forever as long as I can remember yeah
yeah so and that's pretty much you know
the staple of Europe that in uh Believe
It or Not biob Biz are the two big yeah
can's been around forever like as long
as I can remember we've had Cana it's
you know yeah yeah like I said it's 30
it is as old as GH yeah just not in the
United States right so so I was using
that and of course that changed that
changed my I became a better grower yeah
and so then uh I moved to Texas back to
Texas because I couldn't afford to live
in California with a wife and a kid so I
bought a some duplexes there and I was
about to do the same thing and I just
told myself it's not going to work out
so I started a trucking company you know
with all my my uh Investments and uh
then 2007 and8 happened and the
construction World died yeah so I was
like I need to go back to makeing money
so the the bubble burst yeah the housing
market just crashed crashed no one was
buying materials I I had so many friends
that lost their houses because of their
the loans the mortgages yeah basically
that was the year where well that was
also the that was also when everybody
went to they had gotten the loan six
months to a year before and they were
adjustable rates so the first six months
yeah you're at but then they jacked up
the adjustable rates where you couldn't
afford it you couldn't afford the
monthly if you didn't refinance out of
that loan then you just default yeah you
know but you got to live there for eight
months or a year yeah but so uh that
happened sold my trucks parked one of my
trucks sold one of my trucks and then I
bought a rental house uh and or turned
the rental house back into a grow and
then uh did that and worked at back at a
retail store and then my old friend who
worked for Cana said why don't you come
work for us so in
2011 I started subcontracting you know
contract work and then in 2012 I got a
full-time job cool yeah so I've been
with them for 12 years nice yeah yeah
and it's it's been great so yeah yeah
yeah it's a good company I feel like you
know I work for a Dutch company you know
so it's not a typical they have
different you know health insurance and
there's less oversight with the company
over there yes yes yes and so uh yeah
I've been dude and it's I think it's
sort of like you know we're talking
about our friends at Royal gold working
for a quality company yeah is half their
job they telling you you know what I
mean when you're just like oh what do
you know when you feel like you're part
of the family too you know I was I sat
with my guys down today and we had this
conversation and I said it's I I hope
it's always like this but I don't think
it's as we grow it's going to be
different right now we have a tight team
and I have the best guys working with
like literally I have the best guys yeah
we're a tight team everybody's you know
on board and everybody's happy all the
time and when you get a big company
together as you grow it's not always
like that second you have 20 employees
it's different right you can try to make
it it it takes a lot of work right and
it's a different culture well then once
your priorities change and everybody's
like well let's make some more money
right no longer is this just my passion
but now I want it to be a
financial uh productive Endeavor yeah
then you have to sort of start with the
handbooks and the protocol right and you
know the streamlining and you know we
use Sops for everything but like we've
tried to incorporate the the culture
early on you know it's like but also I
want my guys to feel appreciated because
I've worked for big corporations I
worked for small companies I've been a
business owner before yeah and you know
I my parents were business owners so I
got to see firsthand you know where what
it was like with 50 employees and I've
worked for companies that had thousands
of employees I work for Charles Schwab
back in the day okay so yeah I've done a
little bit of everything and and you
know I think it's great to have
employees that want to come to work
they're excited to come to work they get
treated well they get respect D the
productivity and the product quality and
your ease of management yep is is
facilitated on how happy the employee is
to be there and how much they want to
come back the next day well they're a
representation of you so if you train
them correctly right right then they're
going to represent you in the best way
possible exactly how you would want it
done you don't you know and there's a
line where it's like um where you're
over managing or micromanaging and that
that's bad but it's also if you train
them from the beginning and you train
them the right way and you're able to
spend I'm able to spend a lot of time
with people right you know it's it's the
uh professional the read this about I
don't know if it was Nick Sabin or it
was another college coach but real co uh
maybe MC Brown college coaches
don't they don't pick Place yeah they
don't design they may have a system or
whatever but most of them are just
culture yeah just the culture of the
program yeah and then they they instill
every day whatever aspect of a culture
of a program they want I think that's
too true for positive businesses yeah
you want to have this this culture and
then you let the people you you've
hired do the management and the jobs you
know what I mean once in a while you
know more more than anything you're just
solving inter inter problems you know
what I mean right and if you have
systems in place the employees fall back
on their systems and that's how they do
their job it's based on the system so
it's like I have to do this this this
and this and this today and this is what
I have to do for this week and you know
if you can help them with time
management like this is what's required
this is what we need done and a lot of
times it's just reverse engineering the
problem right so like or the solution
you know so exactly it's all reverse
engineering we look at the end product
we want this amazing clone how do we get
an amazing clone well we have these
steps that it takes and we have this
window to sell them or we need amazing
seeds right and they we want the most
beautiful looking seeds and how do we
get the most beautiful seeds and the
most amazing seeds that are going to
germinate for everybody that not only
look great but they grow well they have
minimal interx traits right all these
things you know and it goes back into
you can dive back into the pheno hunting
aspect of it and testing are you
thoroughly testing stuff right you know
and are you testing it and then also are
you testing it before you sell it right
cuz that that's that was a trend I hope
it's changing that I saw about three
ammo cups ago was where these guys were
like I like there's no way you even you
even grew this feno like where did how
do you get how you selling these oh yeah
people would just get stuff make seeds
and then sell the seeds and not test it
and never grow the plant never grow that
pheno or that we make you know we make
over 300 outcrosses a year and we
release a very small portion right right
cuz it's they're not all win it can't be
all winners no we don't and even Beyond
that we don't have time to go through
everything if I do release stuff that
has interex traes it's because it's
special and if you pop a 10 pack of
seeds you're going to find special stuff
in there and I try to let people know
online so if you look on the website and
you go to that specific uh cross it'll
say that this has potential for inter
Tendencies right and and as long as
you're disclaiming it as long as you're
disclaiming it and people are still
really interested because a lot of
people are like I gotta have this I got
to have a cross with this in it yeah you
know and you know slowly but surely
we'll move away from that stuff we're
about to do uh clone sales as well right
which is exciting we talked about that
it's exciting to be able to do clone
sales I think uh domestically and to be
able to get clones that you're on your
doorstep that are from tissue culture
that are yeah you know certified clean
Pest and P authentic verified we do
fingerprinting on everything that we're
going to be shipping out so like you'll
be able to test well you'll be able to
see our test results you'll be able to
look at everything that's went through
is a hopl and viroid clean because
that's a really big topic right now man
have you talked about that yet we have
you know and one like the
boogeyman it is and the thing is like
it's about aw the first thing is
awareness right you need to know you
need to be aware what is it how how how
do you transmit itally transmitt what
does it look like what are the symptoms
first of all because there's also a lot
of symptoms that are not hopl and that
are other things so you need to know a
lot of signs of different things but
also what are the signs of hop lant uh
how do I treat it do I just get rid of
the plant do I do I tissue culture is
that that important that I need to clean
it yes you know because there's a lot of
genetics out there is it really worth
cleaning that thing or or are you okay
with losing 10 to 30% of your yield
right I mean well and it varies because
it can lay dormant yeah and then all of
a sudden you have some stress and you
lose anywhere between one plant a whole
row y half of your crop yep you know and
and you just never know and the think
people had the blindfolds on for a long
time and didn't want to believe it no no
i' I've seen denial I've seen denial
it's it's sad you're like dude you you
got H rers like no no it's just I like
okay well you're buying clones from
other people you're bringing those in
and are they really testing for it no
now let's say you use do your own clones
and you know but like you've used clones
from other places then you're using the
same drippers that were in plants that
were infected what do you think is to
happen you're going to infect your plant
of course right and so there's so many
different ways to get infected we use
clean tools on everything so even our
tissue culture plants between the plants
we still use clean tools with with every
plant right so we'll use on the same
it's worth it's worth it just to have
just peace of mind a case a case of this
instead of you know well and it's like
if one plant is infected we can pull it
yeah but we don't get infected plants
because everything's from tissue culture
right so but we still take precautions
what if for some reason something you
know it tested negative and then all of
a sudden it's now positive because it's
that bad it's honestly that bad to where
you can have a negative test and it's a
false negative or the viral load is so
it just hasn't had chance to all and you
know I mean we're talking about there's
people that are treating it there's
there's uh chemicals that you can put on
the plant and I think those are mostly
Band-Aid fixes right right they sound
good in theory but they also need
specific application right I mean you
can't you know our our industry's always
had that you know the super Mite yeah
how we we we
Californians created are the worst and
the the the laxidasical half ass uh
procedures uh that people used well and
it used to be like we're just going to
spray this this and this on it we got
the trifecta yes it's the Avid the Judo
and the I don't remember the other one
was I always forget but uh forbid I say
forbid yeah it was Avid Judo and forbid
back in the day it was like oh the
trifecta you just rotate through them
but I mean who sprays that stuff Nobody
Does that anymore and if you do there's
something wrong with you you don't need
to do that that's why I usually don't
consume other people's cannabis yeah I
mean seriously unless I know because
you're like what the yeah and I mean I
think that's one of the beauties of
testing what I really like that's the
good side of the regulated market yes
you know that is absolutely the
essential side right where it holds
people accountable for that kind of
stuff I've talked about this with a
couple other nutrient companies but back
in the day with the nutrient companies
most of them if you followed the recipe
that was on the bottle you would have a
subpar product right there wasn't a lot
of R&amp;D going done on on their side
because it was illegal for one thing
right there's a lot of reasons that's
that was one of the things that
separated us from from most people over
there is that yeah you know we did we
did uh specific
nutrient application studies for
specific plants you know there is no
such thing as a really as a as a crop
specific nutrient that that is a lot of
people like to believe that you know
what I mean but there is a crop specific
application right so you know yeah I
mean there's specific recipes that work
and pH ranges that work with different
plants right and uh cow mag you know
that's always the big one that's the big
one yeah I love a friend of mine's uh
did the uh Satur night life skit he goes
I grow we like like everybody else one
pant leg at a time but you're going to
want more cow mag you're going to
definitely going to want more C mag
you're going to want more calag it's
almost for sure yeah yeah that's an
important one and I mean I think
uh across the board though there's lots
of decent nutrients available there's
lots of really good decent decent right
there's a difference between I've always
preached this because people go hey that
works and them all there's a difference
between something that works so that's
the opposite you know there's there's
failure and then the next thing after
failure is Success the only definition
for me of success is not failing yeah
but then way down the line on a graph is
production is quality production M so
you know there there is there are a few
out there that don't get you all the way
to a quality production unless you heav
heavily manipulate the application and
in that point you're sort of just not
even really using as an intended you
know what I'm saying yeah so and there
is no other crop that
is consumed and combusted at the same
time tobacco would probably be be the
you know and it's still not the same not
even close so but everybody's like oh I
just grow this like like like big
everybody's worried about Big Egg coming
in which is it is already here it's
already here it's already but but at the
same time you don't smoke cotton yeah
you don't smoke corn not
yet you know so I always think that
that's the difference you know what I'm
saying when big big big egg comes in you
know it's just sort of like the the
difference between uh Hot House tomatoes
that you see in the grocery store and
heirloom tomatoes that you grow at your
own house yeah we know that there is
there is almost it's almost not too one
is not a tomato right an airlo tomato
that doesn't look you know that funky
that you grew in your garden that from
Heirloom Seeds is a
tomato well there's more varieties of
cannabis than any other Agricultural
Product out there there's way more
variety and availability of different
varieties than anything else you look at
Tomatoes how many types of tomatoes even
if we talk about heirloom tomatoes that
available to the general public in
grocery stores there's a very limited
amount there's only four there's only
four at the most in every grocery store
yeah and we talk about bananas there's
one right there's one you might get a
plantain or one of those miniature
bananas right right and then pineapples
I was just GNA just GNA say there's like
four well there's four what what I just
recently realized is the varietal
strands of sugar cane oh wow yeah and
and their characteristics which is
exciting so I like sugarcane I think
it's it's really amazing I love rum so
yeah yeah I like
sugar that's the uh that was back to
original topic about you know uh
prohibition and stuff and our parents uh
and the generations before you know
looking down on that but you're like but
they would make you sweet tea or
Kool-Aid yeah you know until this day
sugar doesn't you know doesn't get the
bad name it deserves the cancer causing
dude it's the worst sugar is the single
worse yes that is worse than alcohol it
is worse than tobacco it's more
addictive than heroin yes sugar is D and
what it does to your body and how your
body body you diabetic it kill you it'll
cause cancer it feeds cancer cancer
cells that's why you got a cal plunge
it's extremely important Cal plunging
builds Brown fat cells Brown fat cells
need uh glucose they require glucose to
maintain and so if you do coal plunging
you build up that brown fat cells the
glucose or even just a cold shower the
brown fat competes with your cancer
cells right exactly cold showers were
good too just really that cold PL will
get you that the brown Fates you sit in
there 2 minutes 5 minutes 10 minutes 30
minutes I can't do more than about two
and a half it depends on how cold it is
I just I go five minutes has been my
go-to okay right I like the five minute
threshold but I feel like the I get the
most benefit because it takes me two
minutes just to relax fully like where
I'm breathing and I got my breathing
down and then I can get three minutes of
breathing in to where I'm fully relaxed
and I get out and I feel just amazing
it's awesome so and and I also do the
SAA so I go oh yeah you know I do that
four times a week yeah love I love the
uh post-workout cannabis SAA combo yeah
that's yeah sometimes when I smoke if I
smoke too much and then I try to go in
it's 10 times hotter than your brain is
your brain is like what are you doing
well and then I sweat like crazy I mean
I like the sweating part but man
sometimes I just overheat yeah I became
a fan of foam insulation and I
definitely think Grow rooms could use it
I've been big promoter I built a house
in Texas you know Austin a couple years
ago and the guy introduced it to me it
was pretty much new then and the only
thing that we are concerned with is off
gasing you know it's a chemical process
sort of like rosin or or anything like
that so but uh it basically turns your
house or room into a Yeti cooler oh wow
so I've been trying to promote that I
like Yeti Coolers right well they work
really well I also like rockwool did you
know the same rock wool that's in the
Grow rooms are installation it's in
listen as a as a person who makes media
yeah Coco is our is our go-to we're one
of the first you know because was the
first yeah right you were one of the
first people with Coco out there right
right we were one of the first to
realize that uh one you have to have uh
you have to Quality Source the Coco you
can't just go to Sri Lanka or India
which a lot of people do and that's fine
sure but you're going to have
inconsistencies so you're going to want
to do your own cocoa just like you do
your own nutrients or your own tra or
your own Coco farm right so we we worked
on that and we also realized that you
know Coco has been around as a meeting I
think it hit a World's Fair in 18
something it was like introduced in 18
like one of the F you know over aund
something years has been known as a
reusable media right but it has these
unique properties that nobody really
quite understood that we put a lot of
research into which is one it's it's cow
mag deficient so it needs to be buffered
for sure right so your nutrient either
either you need to pre-buffering
to the nutrient mix to get a higher you
know uh or you need to use hard water
right that's what we relied on when we
first came into the States was people
were going to use like LA or or Arizona
or they're not using RO water they're
using hard water hard water so we sort
of which has cow mag in it sure mostly
you know some right so so we we
supplemented with that but uh it's also
it's basically like banana peel it's
it's got potassium in it and and as it
degrades and breaks down as you grow it
starts to kick out potassium yeah so you
don't need a high a high
potassium uh By the time it's flowering
it's all depends on the media size you
know whether you're using a one gallon
five gallon or anything larger I don't
know I think that's gone away now right
are we are we done using the 10 gallons
in
production I don't know I mean I think
at scale yes yes it's scale yes right
Seven's too much for the house no but if
if you want to outside it's a different
story I'm still talking about indoor
production cultivation no I don't think
if we're talking about production I
think 10 gallons G been gone for a long
time right my aunt and uncle used to
grow living soil 10 gallon pots used to
crush it yeah and they would have four
10 gallon pots per light so they'd have
less plants they would veg for longer
they top two getting amazing yields you
know they they were getting amazing
yields yeah you're doing a two-month veg
on those and you're topping them and
you're really yeah scrogging them yeah
um but I for for commercial I can't
imagine you know unless you're doing
living soil and you were reusing them
but then you just do a bed right oh dude
raise beds Y in if you can manage the
maintenance and uh you know the protocol
on a raised
bed you know now we're talking headier
stuff than production stuff right I I
saw this in the grape world in the wine
you know wine grape world and I
definitely believe it the competition
for nutrients in a raised bed gives you
a smaller yield but a higher quality
product yeah depending on the genetics
obviously Flora flame in Oakland I don't
know if you have time to go check them
out and yeah they they're organic living
soil low till yeah uh you know at scale
they're doing amazing stuff and they're
in Oakland go figer you know yeah yeah I
and I I love that I love that that's one
of the guys I I taught me a little bit
in San Francisco he had a he had a spot
right off cap yeah in the hood and uh he
bought the house you know in the mid
late 80s but he had this grow in there
and he was just doing raised beds the
living soil raised beds technique and it
was some of the best fire I'd ever seen
and I was like he's like yeah but it's a
[ __ ] to clean maintain you know but uh
you know I think I think and more and
more I see I was first I saw the Dutch
method which is one day veg two- day veg
right and you're you're sea of green and
you're going like yeah because it's
based off the Tulip uh we're just doing
floriculture yeah that's all we're doing
is we're growing flowers and there is a
whole industry that's been around for
decades uh excuse me centuries yeah and
the Dutch are the kings of FL Flor
culture absolutely so I saw this this
method back early on and I was like oh
so you I would put 49 in a
4x4 you know uh try to get half gal pots
you and Ed rosenal dude every
everybody's like you know I get more and
I was like no no no no not only do I get
more per 4x4 I use less light yeah and I
get more cut more rounds down in a year
right and everybody's like you know no
because I I knew a lot of guys who were
doing four on a 4x4 yeah you know that's
closer to what you you know you you were
discussing yeah and I was like you're
just you're listen you're putting a lot
of time and money because everything is
everything in this world's based off
time yeah everything's basic basically
based off the 30-day mortgage payment
the 30-day rent the 30-day electric bill
the 30-day the two 15-day pay periods
right so that's how you should dictate
everything is by time and the less time
you can more out of less time yeah the
more productive you're going to be
moreit you make it the end of the year Y
and the more you're going to be able to
facilitate other things right so but now
and now more and more I'm seeing
everybody go to the one gallons and I'm
just like finally like great job one
gallons you know 16 plants per I mean we
do nine right some people you know we're
doing crop steering so everybody's got
their own way right but the less veg
time you do in a smaller pot the more
plant matter you're waste you're not
wasting because if you take a third do
you if you do your one one month veg
okay and then you flower and then you
harvest and then you take all the root
yeah and all the stem and all the fan
leaves that you can't get more money out
of right I mean sometimes you can get a
little bit of a fan Leaf 4% or something
right so those turs you can sell turps
off your roots right I don't know who
buy them but there there's turps in
those roots I know uh I just buy Chinese
turps it's a joke right I do love the
smell of uh turps in the roof there's
something special about that if you guys
don't know smell your roots next time
especially if you always do a good stem
stroke man I am the I am the king of the
the stem stroke yeah dude y that's
that's the IND the oil the indicator
yeah certain well certain plants just
Express differently too you know what I
mean and like it's that's their jam some
of them are like God damn this thing's a
baby so uh but you know getting getting
away from that you you take all that
product that you can't turn around that
you have to destroy in Most states right
and you weigh that and then you also
take your you add in your another time
factor is the trim time right now you
know most people are throwing a green
Bros or or a twister you know they
better not be but they are they
shouldn't be hand trimming okay dry
triming what dry my my opinion I used to
trim back in the day wet but I do
believe in dry trim right I do believe
in hanging humble taught me that if
anything humble and coalo taught me cut
the cut cut it down into big big sizes
let it your hands off let it hang hang
in the in the barn yep and and you know
get that two three week drive because
the moisture the I saw guys I think 14
days is the perfect drive but it depends
on what how close to the coast you are y
it also I mean I think style control the
room 100% for
sure but don't do it uh aggressively
there was some guys who were dehiding
and I was like you're a cheat just dude
no one you know why no one's buying your
stuff CU you got dehumid in your [ __ ]
dry room okay right so but you know you
want to you want to you want that cure
process to happen you know yeah you know
and so then that's why I still am
against Colorado weed because it's 10%
humidity and unless you so rough it's
terms powder Washington's the opposite
where it's too humid then we got
Colorado that's too dry but anymore you
can have a controlled environment if you
can afford it right I think it depends
on how how important it is to you you
know it's s like a cigar I think you
need a humidifier and you need a
dehumidifier yes I think air
conditioners have a little bit of
dehumid in them so you can you can cheat
a little bit there a little bit but you
still need you want to be able to
control prely through the whole CLE you
know and then some people go 50% the
first day and then bump it towards 63 or
whatever you want to do you know there's
so many different ways I saw heads that
were Ivy dripping uh big big plants oh
wow yeah they would stick they would
have water dripping it so that they'd
get like a 21 like you know there's the
up on the hill there's some crazy [ __ ]
going on you know you know you know
they're they're probably doing drugs
could be you know or you know or drugs
to their plants dude one of my yes well
that was one of the one is is period
blood somebody one of the go yeah I got
I I take my girls period I like dude
what a [ __ ] hippie dude I don't want
to smoke that no smoke that and then one
mind blower
was growing to the moon cycle indoors
and at first I scoffed and then I
realized gravity is everywhere yeah even
in the room and the pull of the moon and
and anything that it affects you know
people like you're crazy that's crazy I
was like no no I mean harvesting by the
cultivating by the cycles of the Moon
germinating seeds all that stuff I think
there's a lot of Truth to that yes and
so not that uh it's a GameChanger but it
is uh a factor right that you could
consider you know and it it all depends
on how much you want to put in into that
but right I think that nobody should be
in something back to the original point
no one should be in something larger
than a two gallon container if you're
indoors on a production level yeah back
in the day I used to buy those Dutch
pots oh yeah five gallon the square ones
on the bottom or the Dutch leech trays
yeah and you put a 6in slab in that
Dutch leech tray and then you put 4 to5
DM the 4 iners yeah the DM 10s MH I
think that's right yeah yeah and that's
the jam I still think that's the jam
yeah you you veg that uh you know for a
couple days and then you put those in
the Dutch you you cut the little in the
slabs right and then uh you know and you
do that and uh two three days after that
you flower and because you're only want
one flower per plant you know what I
mean you you're trying to get one butt
right and then your trim time is
like you know instead of on the green
Bros or the yeah in the Twister where
you're just like oh you just killed it
yeah so I I I understand commercial
people y especially with a trimmer is
now I mean it used to
be 200 bucks a pound up on the hill but
Christ now that that's half your profit
right some trimmers can do better than
others you know yeah I don't like any of
the trimming machines I I think it ruins
weed I think it knocks off tricomes
there's nothing you can do about it I
like panel brush I like finger trimming
I like
scissors uh this is how I used to trim
yes that that technique though you can
tell that's the tech right there for
sure like soon as you get about two
plants in two two buds in you got all
that resin and some of my best my
favorite product to smoke scissor and
finger hash of course you can't go wrong
with I know I think it's holistic I
don't think there's any proof to that's
but it's like it's like live rosin it's
like the first you're capturing those
live turps yeah it is live Ros yeah but
it's live live finger was the first
first version right of oh I mean and
those turps were amazing and you put
those in your joint and it'd be like on
your bowl you put that on your bowl yeah
to match the weed yeah I mean that was
those were days you that's sort of like
Veno Verde you know what Veno Verde is
green wine it is the wine you drink to
when you make wine so in the spring yeah
they take a certain amount of young
grapes yeah and then they harvest them
and they process them you know let them
sit and it's only at about four 5%
alcohol sure because you're just but
it's the wine you drink while you're
making wi blood light of right but
that's sort of like how scissor hash is
you know that's the hashy smoke while
you make hash I love it yeah so yeah
it's interesting
um but trimming I mean I used to all my
personal I used to keep in mason jars
like my personal I didn't even really
trim the the Sugar Leaf off it I'd put
it in mason jars when I smoke it I would
trim it and smoke it I I still think
that's the best way to do it now
commercially yeah you know you're going
to get a consumer who's not going to
want to pay for that right all my Sour
Diesel I used to have like that so like
when I gave jars to my friends like yeah
Leo from aish the first time I met him I
gave him a jar of sour it was freaking
you know it still had all the sugar and
that is a a lot of the time I'm all
that's still a consumable product I mean
it's sort of like you know I can't think
of any other kind of product like that
it's like the crust on bread or you know
what I mean like it's not the best part
but it's no and the thing is is like I
think the the leaf the Sugar Leaf and
some of those leaves protect all the
other parts of the bud right to a degree
and if if you put and I was getting buds
where they were like big buds and I put
in the Mason jar and it's like one bud
or two buds in there they weren't
getting smashed you'd have this big
beautiful Bud that had all these this
great shape to it and all this stuff
that was untouched right and we didn't
peel off the banana and you've got a
perfectly good banana right exactly we
never really touched the tops I didn't
want fingers on my my buds ever you
touch the stems whatever you smell it
you can smell it but don't be pinching
my people walk through the room don't
pinch my butts do you know so uh now
it's not a big deal but well I got
introduced to this technique you know
I've seen a lot of people do a lot of
crazy [ __ ] and half of the time I go
you're just a c and the other half time
I go you're you got to be a [ __ ]
genius like I don't I I'm you know and
what is that saying you know every every
genius just called it you know a lunatic
until everybody goes oh he's a genius uh
shout out to Tyson Redbeard at root
Celler yeah he uh he's somewhat of a
recluse and the way he tested Bud was
he'd grab your bud right out of the bag
or out of the jar yeah take a little
butt and he
go walk into it I like just an [ __ ]
right you're just [ __ ] destroying Bud
right and then I realize no he's kidding
the like there's a part of me like still
wants to go just being an [ __ ] right
you're just [ __ ] with people and the
other part of me goes I think you're
really getting something out of that I
think there's a little of both right a
little bit of both you know and anybody
who knows Tyson out there zest it's like
the lemon zest of your weed he's zesting
your butt yeah
exact you know but I think he was also
just trying to see how you'd be like
dude you know back in the day that was
money now you're just like fine yeah you
know yeah that's so with can you guys
make all kinds of different products you
make stuff for hydro like uh water deep
water culture you have uh organic you
have you have everything so we were one
of the first nutrient companies to
figure out that different Medias require
different um micro and macro and
processes yeah right so we've got your
basically the first one that we have
ever came up with before we were really
a manufacturer when the when the owner
uh was just making it for himself which
a lot of Dutch guys did that's the same
thing as Vander Swan uh of House and
Garden the old man was growing flowers
and they were BR you know they were both
growing you know that's uh the same uh
several people in Holland were
legitimate flower Growers yeah and then
illegitimate flower Growers on the side
as well yeah and then they would make
their own nutrients sure and then you
know finally one day the father or the
son or the uncle would be like the
brother would be like well we can sell
these nutrients and so they would get
into that game and that's basically what
happen with both house and G and Canada
no relation but just both so uh the
first was our substra we called it h
they called it Hydro over there but it's
a run to I say run to drain the the
traditional is run to waste drain to
waste or run to waste run to waste but
no one in America likes that cuz they're
like the waste of wasting you're like
yeah it has to run off and then you
don't use that anymore yeah it goes away
yeah it's called runoff so that was uh
what we call our substra that was our
Flagship original and then he was like
well people are recirculating you don't
you don't have this you can't use the
same nutrient right you need to have a
you know a pH buffer stabilizer you need
to have the nutrient somewhat time
relased because the first and drain or
right so dwc flood and drain uh dwc I'd
stay tell anybody to stay away from dwc
really I know a couple people that crush
crush it crush it with here's the
problem here's the problem as soon as
you get introduced to the s
it'll fall apart yeah water Can Only
Hold 60% oxygen yeah right in order for
a plant not to have issues it has to be
in at least 18% oxygen so you are on the
threshold of [ __ ] up and temperature
uncontrolled that's why most need to
either be in a cool basement yeah or the
current culture works because they've
got full horsepower chillers right so
that they can keep the temperature down
especially with the movement of the
water heing up warm water is also the
issue we talked about that earlier so
that's the aqua series is for
recirculating deep water culture uh nft
n which is gone by the wayside right
have you ever seen an N table not really
it's been a long time yeah deep water
culture nft uh drain way uh flood and
drain and then uh we realize soil is
different a Charged soil is going to be
different so uh uh because there should
be something in the soil like if you use
our substra on you can use it on rock
wool that's the Run drain you can use it
on rock wall you can use it on uh any of
the uh Pete Moss mixes you know I think
Kings mix is close to that doesn't have
a charge too much of a charge in it
right right so and or any of the Kings
mix is amazing I D It's amazing yeah
vital Kings mix those are the ones I
can't and I'm so I was so surprised that
that wasn't that it took him a minute to
come out with that product but you know
well that was organic for the longest
time and then they took it away it's
still in I don't care I in my mind I
really you know I think I also think
that they were dealing with 707 uh the
707 bag from Roots yeah cuz but and it's
a way fall out from that yeah it's a
superior product by the way uh and if
you're outdoors and you do a short crop
you just use a bag that was you know so
uh we use that you can use the substra
in that you use the aqua and the
recirculating uh cocoa and Coco uh if
you use our cocoa nutrient the liquid uh
I would prefer you use my cocoa bag but
if you don't you because there are other
uh Royal gold mix of Coco out there I
think tuer I think the tuer is superior
to their Coco I think it also in sales
is superior it has a charge in it though
yeah but you know uh but uh you want to
stay away from perite you're basically
you know people always
like why you put dude and it's
destructive it's not res it's not Reus
it's not you know I always used to use
perite back in the day I know but it's
stay away from perite yeah say just
whatever you use vermiculate and perate
back in the day I was taught you know I
went to cowp San Louis for a while and I
was taught by the botanist and the
ornamental hlist there how to cut how to
do cuttings right there's no s plus
there's no such thing as a clone there's
a
cutting in the a world in the a world
they call cuting they're like that's not
a clone it's just a cutting you know but
things are interchangeable strain is
almost on the same wave exactly thank
you so the original cutting
and high producing agmx was 75% perite
25% vermiculite constant drip because it
basically just goes you know yeah goes
away yeah and so uh and then we have the
cocoa for the cocoa I'd stay away from
perlite and cocoa because the properties
of the cocoa are what we researched our
cocoa nutrient to be and the more
perlite you put in there the less Coco
you have and so the more likelihood our
nutrient isn't going to be optimized not
that it doesn't work totally okay and uh
we have an organic but that's going to
be pre-charged or and then soil soil so
soil cocoa soil for pre charge bag
something like the roots or the basement
uh basement mix from those guys or or
meno mix right right I think the meno
mix has got better is better for our our
our soil so that's the uh what we call
um Tera uh Coco for
Cocoa uh Aqua for Reser and uh substra
for run to drain yeah and then we've got
we only have one additive the rest uh we
call uh
either uh supplements or not really
supplement but something that just helps
but it's not needed you know y uh and
the only additive that we suggest is a
PK because PK is a time sensitive
nutrient oh we got something special
here oh yeah I want to talk about yes so
let's talk about this product I think
this is amazing we're traling this right
now and I think this is special
underrated and the problem not the
problem here here's the deal is we most
cultivators
home or uh commercial just take quarter
strength that was the original GH mix
right quarter strength of each right and
that's your baby formula yeah the
research that we did uh was that the
micronutrient ratio in quarter strength
full nutrient doesn't have the same that
the plant needs so this product is
specifically for seedlings right popping
seeds and the first two weeks of a
rooted uh cutting yeah and that's
because that plant needs for it to
become a mature plant it is going to
require different
micronutrients and so that ratio is way
different this is very underrated the
problem I have with this is most people
don't think it's worth it because
they're lazy and they don't want to buy
another bottle right but if you're in
the seed game or in the cutting game
this is a GameChanger that's what we do
so so yeah I'm excited to test all this
stuff out I mean yeah this with our
generous I I got some bottles of this
stuff I I can't wait to get your
feedback on this because I'm excited
because most people just don't they
they're trying to save money right and
they're trying to save uh protocols
right you know you I gotta add one more
step in you got to add another nutrient
and another like yeah but you're going
to get you know yeah but I think also a
lot of people don't collect data so
they're like well it's not that big of a
deal but it's like okay okay so if you
can have your clones to Market sooner
your cuting you can have those to to
Market sooner so instead of it taking
two weeks back to our time thing yeah
exactly back to the time thing now if we
can save three days on that or two days
or even one day over the per imagine if
you didn't get in charge rent for the
first three days yeah you only had to
pay 27 days worth of rent you know
that's the now I like to use or mortgage
or or you know well and and talking
about if you're using seeds like let's
let's say you're growing from seeds at
scale you I mean and you get a higher
ratio of seeds that not only germinate
but that thrive once they're germinated
I think that's what I'm excited about
that's what I'm excited about now we
collect the data so we'll be able to go
side by side I'm really excited about
that I'm because you are absolutely
correct it is amazing to me how many
people out there they know what the root
temperature of the room is yeah they
know what the nutrient mix is they know
what their dosatrons at or whatever they
know all that but they're like but what
did you did you look into this did you
look into
no no I I know it already yeah how do
you know it well how does this compare
to this or how does this compare to that
and we have to have that mindset now
it's not like it used to be it can't be
we just do it because we do it right
like there's nothing that goes on in our
facility we don't just do it because we
do it we want to do it in the best way
most efficient way possible and also we
want to be able to give feedback to our
customers on how to get the best results
whether it's with seeds whether it's
with you know cuting clones uh whatever
it is to get the best product for them
so they can be successful because it's a
tough time in the industry so the more
time everywhere like the more you
Empower me the more I Empower my
customer the more they get better
results and so that they can hopefully
make more money and continue to buy
seeds or continue to buy clones right
I've always said that I you know the the
the more I make my the more I make my
customer make more money the more they
will have a likelihood of buying things
for me right so uh you can foler this
just like our ronic uh you know
everything I have has to for its
application to work no matter what
liquid I'm selling you has to have Roots
yeah all right but there is there is uh
there is uptake in Le in foler it's not
of the same ratio and so a lot of people
who do cuting and do not have Roots at
The Cutting you can foler certain things
like arizo or this but the minute you
see Roots you want to start feeding the
roots it's awesome so yeah dude this
this product is inexpensive uh easy to
use you only use it for the problem I
think also too is most people are like I
only use it for two weeks like that's at
the longest like you know because then
you're going to want to start putting in
a mature uh nutrient solution yeah
higher higher ratios Y and with
different micro and macro uh ratios M
that's the other thing too is I I don't
know if the world knows quite knows why
the people you know I think luckily due
to people like you and me and other
educated people out there there's a
reason there's three numbers on a bottle
yeah because it's the ratio MH right
it's not I like of people it needs more
nitrogen well you know anybody out there
Google uh nutrient wheel every nutrient
has at least one other nutrient effects
so if you add more nut more nitrogen you
may affect the calag uptake if you had
more phosphorus you're definitely
messing with the PK and iron uptake and
as you know so I I suggest anybody go
out there and Google nutrient wheel get
that image and see yeah just for their
own piece of Mind knowing that you can't
just add one because there is no even if
it says 5 Z yeah there's other things in
there besides nitrogen yeah and the
other two numbers phosphor and potassium
aren't 100% like one's at 35 because
it's potach and the other is at
phosphorous Rock which is 65% right so
yeah people have to I I just like to
educate people on that you know and I
think it's confusing well a lot of stuff
is counterintuitive and people don't
want to ask and no and and that's why
there's things called soil science
degrees and botney degrees and or
there's also you know we have Google you
know there's Google and YouTube I mean
you can learn a lot on YouTube YouTube
for sure go ask your AI program you know
it's like there's you know now stop stop
stop you might not get the right
information okay bat in B out remember
yeah yeah but I think there's all kinds
of places we can get information besides
like the show the show and and other
this
show I I is is just so awesome that we
can do this I really appreciate people
like you doing this so that there is the
ability to get data collected years of
experience information
without you know going to school or
trusting you know we used to I worked at
a retail store and one of our shirts
that I wanted to make was on the front
it says your buddy and on the back is
full of [ __ ] yeah you know how many
times Well my buddy my friend you're
like why are you asking me right he
doesn't even know what the [ __ ] he's
talking about you know what I mean so
yeah and shows like this which is tried
and true tested you know you're you're
spending the rest of your day trying to
figure out what the you know the
protocols and the procedures and the is
it a half a m is it four Mills is it
once a day is it every other day is it
twice a day is it every week is it you
know is it at night is it during the day
you know do I use under canopy lights
too you know to whater one of my
inventions that uh you can go ahead and
have was the tent made out of
t5s really I was going to have a t the T
all three all surface was just a t5s
yeah yeah dude under canop be light for
sure or I wanted to do like I always
wanted to do myar on the floor yeah but
it just gets dirty totally you know what
I mean so yeah under canopy light for
sure yeah you know and uh this sounds
like something for Burning Man
too for sure uh you know the T5 room
exactly make it all red light right
that's that's the jam Right Far red yeah
uh I think I think the other thing that
I want our industry to discover is what
this scientific C uh indoor cultivation
needs more UV yeah it just does out
that's why sungrown is some of the best
weed it it has the disadvantage of
environmental impacts like wind rain
animals other you know uh not so much
sun well there's more variables there's
there's less you don't control control
right and so but that sun yeah well
that's my God first of all you know and
the power of that sun and it's one of
its aspects is UV the future is mixed
light yeah for sure uh PL lighting is
coming out with that I've always said
that I don't want to knock any uh and I
know I get a lot of push back from this
on LEDs but LEDs have a lot less UV than
any of your double-ended or your Mogul
based HIDs and so we've lost a lot on
that and I think that you need to
supplement UV when you use LEDs so
there's still a lot of things that we're
learning about light light spectrum you
know we have Spectrum tuning now which
is really cool yeah but uh you know we
had uh Grandmaster LED Thomas from
Grandmaster LED on the show and he's
talking about his bug Light that helps
eradicate thrips and mites dude you
using UVC it it it works it's really
cool it works and it and it's but it's
just the beginning it's just the
beginning we're just scratching the
surface of all this cool stuff right I
think every year there's innovation made
in certain places we've been kind of
stagnant on some of the stuff well I
mean we fighting the uh on the LED
situation the culture and people like us
who have been doing it for a long time
with the I get off my lawn old man thing
is there was four to eight generations
of LED uh LEDs that were gimmicks oh
yeah I mean I talked about for long it
started with the blur Poes and I said
I'd never use LEDs UFO yeah I mean these
are examples of why I so open-minded now
because I've seen I've been in the
industry long enough to where I was
there when femin seeds were first
sitting the market and we were like no
dude they're gonna ruin the genan pool
autoflow then it was autoflow and it was
like they're going to ruin the Jean Pool
and now I breed out of flow and then it
was the LEDs and I was like no now I'm
like well let's see what happens you
know I'm I would rather just instead of
saying no that's not going to work I
want to see the future that once they
have it dialed in right with everything
and and it's it's never like I mean
listen uh it's unfortunate but a lot of
the stuff comes from other Industries
you know we knew about uh metal uh metal
Hy uh the uh high pressure sodium metal
halides and way before they were ever a
consumable product in the in the in the
you know indoor cultivation and I was
like what I want one like they're
they're still one of the best Mogul
bases right or plasma lights they still
have haven't seen a you know plasma
lights you know and plasma lights have
been around forever and they have you
know Wonderful applications that you
know of course A lot of these things
create heat and everybody's trying to
that's the that's the L LED stick but
then I realize that their de their you
know their dpd was way off because they
didn't quite get it that you actually
need that heat yeah and that moisture
from the plant or you know so now you've
got to mulate that when you use LEDs and
that's not a negative that's just
knowing and not knowing right you know
so you've got to because you're like
well at least you have the opportunity
to control the situation and and and be
in charge of the inputs right yeah cuz
for the longest time the first LEDs
people were like and not and not you're
like oh you're missing a factor You're
missing two or three factors yeah one is
heat one is moisture yeah and you know
you're going to have to somewhat
supplement how those you don't have to
add heat you probably have to add
moisture and take out moisture at
certain times sure but you know and so
yeah our our us the open mind thing is
is definitely you know just it's like
uh it comes with age too it does when
you're in your 20s you think you know
everything and then by the time you get
to your 40s I don't know a goddamn thing
I don't know you realize that you don't
know [ __ ] yeah and if you still think
you know [ __ ] you got something wrong
you know because you've learned that
you're not as smart as you thought you
were in in every aspect right you might
be focused and and expert in one thing
yeah but there's a gazillion things that
you could focus on and become an expert
so you can't be an expert in everything
yeah and and and I also think that uh
you know I
think the uh I grow the best weed is got
to be one of the worst things I've heard
well so so this is an ego thing and it's
also a pride thing right you you take
pride in it and and the thing is it'll
blind you arrogantly yeah I mean this is
like ego will blind you because you've
grown this thing and you've been part of
its life through its whole lifespan
right from the time it was a clone or it
was a seed and you've grown with this
thing and it's they were babies right
yeah and then you harvest it and you you
have it and in your mind you're you and
obviously some people are are much
different than other I think the guys
that are the biggest critics usually
have the best weed they never think
their weed is good enough right uh you
know sfk my buddy that grows for sfk he
he's always trying to grow better weed
and he still thinks he doesn't have it
down even when it's the best he's like
oh no he knows when it's good but he's
it's like he's one of those guys that
every time he has a harvest he's like
what could I do better next time it's
not like I nailed it and I nail it every
time and some of these guys are like
dude my wheat is the best and they'll
come up to me and they're like dude the
best Harvest ever man you got to smoke
it mine is the best or or my other
friends Pizza this is the pizza thing
that we have they oh everybody thinks
they make the best pizza we're gonna
have a contest between my friends yeah
yeah but uh cannabis
guys but yeah I mean ego is a ego is a
you know there's harsh reality that goes
along with that too it's like can you
sell the product cu because if it's so
good then why aren't you selling it
right right and I think that right it
comes down to being able to do a lot of
AB testing and finding out what works
best for you and for your room and
really being able to uh distill all the
stuff that you're doing down into Data
that you can analyze right I think that
has a lot to do with it I mean that's
why these nutrient companies are so
successful with testing out their
recipes now because they can because
it's legal and they have no problem
testing on cannabis I mean some of them
did it before anyway yeah but now you
can do it legally pretty much and you
can do it with your clients and you know
I mean a lot of these guys have
chromatography that they're using for
stuff you know and it's like pretty
amazing pretty we're in an amazing place
you guys are doing amazing stuff oh yeah
thank you thank you I I I think I also
this is uh one of
the platforms that I want to talk to
Growers about is that uh price per
gallon of nutrient yeah no one
cares and you shouldn't either MH
because cuz that's that that has been
the last two three years and we we all
know that came from there's some crazy
expensive stuff there is there is and is
it better does it give you the same
percentage like if so if it cost you 20%
more are you getting 20% more yield
right right and then you know and people
would point to me and say well you're
the most expensive nutrient on there I
was like I'm not the most expensive
nutrient in fact in fact if you run Coco
in a bag of cocoa and you buy one of my
$4.95 lers of
PK I probably will cost you 50 bucks a
4x4 yeah people like no no I'm like then
do the math do the math yeah you know
now now do I sell boost that's uh
somewhere around 100 bucks a liter at at
full retail
yes but it does it increase uh
concentration production yeah are you
getting banged for the buck right so at
the end of the day it's all about bang
for but but you know things like uh I
always stay away from mentioning another
product but there were products out
there made by uh manufacturers one that
changed the game that had 13 bottles
when it first came out and it did change
the game it did change the game and but
some of its uh stuff I was like that's
just [ __ ] like sake oil there's a lot
of a stin oil there's a lot of nutrients
out there there's no reason no and then
there was dark energy well and listen
and you dark energy and was the other
one they had they worked were they worth
the price liquid Karma and dark energy I
love those things so so for me Dark
Energy was 100% worth it they still so
they banned it in California so
basically seelp is now banned because
it's a a natural pgr so pgrs are banned
so because it's a pgr even though it's
seelp it is banned in
California go figure but dark energy for
me 25 years ago maybe even a little bit
longer made by American hydroponics in
it was such a game changer for me though
it was like I didn't know what I was
doing before that's how I felt like when
we harvested and it was done and we
smoked it it was like what were we doing
this is where it's at right right and
it's you have those aha moments
throughout your life it's like you
figure it out you know and then that was
like whoa this is what really good we
when you're growing this is but really
this is the this is the next I've got to
the next level and then that's when as
someone we were talking about ear who
recognizes that you don't or puts that
on yourself that I may not be growing
the best weed because there is no such
thing as the best weed right right it it
can always be a little better and once
in a while you'll see that from like the
worst grower you're like you're like
what the [ __ ] did you do and he's like I
don't know yeah well even from Harvest
to harvest so there's if you look at
flower there's 70 days in the life of a
plant if you equate it to like a human
that's like a year for every day that
plant is alive is like a year in a
human's life right and so there's so
many little micro variables that can go
on within that room within the dayto day
hour the night the the temps the
humidity all those things that you can
control to a degree indoors but at the
same time from one Harvest to the next
that's why it's hard to create constant
you know chovar that are consistently
expressing the same chemical profile
it's a lot harder than people think
watering alone yeah you you just can't
like the situ situation may be different
that that morning and then the retention
of the media may be different well if
you're using hard water the water
changes throughout the year so there's
nothing consistent about hard water
water coming from you know if you're if
you're in the city and you're using
water you're not distilling it or you
know if if you're not using R right
reverse mimosis removing removing get it
down like you know Z to five yeah you
know at least you
know but you know I mean there's
benefits to ro but it's very wasteful um
I you know and like we have a RO system
for the misters got yeah yeah so you
don't get clogs and right yeah yeah
exactly yeah but if your water is at
160 which is like Colorado is less than
that you know all that snow melt that
they get and even in Denver you know but
if your water is 160 or less I would
have to see some hard data on why you're
going to take the extra 160 out you know
unless it's got a spe specific uh heavy
metal in it like it ran through some
weird lead pipes and it's pathogens if
you want to prevent pathogens and you
know you you're susceptible there's
stuff that gets brought in through the
water for sure right but uh you know I
mean clean room practices and but a lot
of times all you need is a decorin nator
yeah you know and which I would suggest
everybody who's getting water from a
city a
municipal uh Source yeah should
definitely at least get a small boy or a
large boy or any other product made that
dechlorinates it cuz chlorine especially
if you're doing the living you know I
don't I don't soil science one it will
change your EC though for sure it will
change your EC as it's pulling stuff out
as it's cleaning the it yeah and you
won't get chlorine which is good I mean
but at least let your water sit 24 hours
if you're not doing that you know the
problem what I have with that and I
agree with that is that most water
treatment places now use several
versions of you know chloramine
chloramide not just
yeah and those
don't intentionally don't just dissipate
through through uh just you know sitting
there yeah so you they don't evaporate
like like Corine does so you you you
know I would always and especially if
you're in soil you know the thing we're
a synthetic company we do make an
organic bio you can't get it in
California uh it's unfortunate but you
know in the rest of the states most of
them I think all all the others you can
get uh the
bio but if you're using anything in soil
you're definitely want to get cuz you're
and if you're using any sort of sugar to
feed uh any of the cultures that are in
there you know your traderma and your
all the bacilus right the chlorine kills
that on purpose so that's why You' want
to if you're in a soil mix you you you
you know and you want to reap the
benefits of having a Charged soil yeah
and organic happy soil yeah yeah yeah
you don't want to put poison in there
yeah just like I suggest a lot of people
in the in the hydro game like to use uh
H2O2 in a routine maintenance and I
think that's like treating a cold with
chemotherapy if you if you can keep a
clean system without constantly adding
H2O2 because H2O2 is is H2O2 is H
chlorine dioxide right it's no it's uh
hydrogen peroxide it's hydrogen yeah
okay yeah yeah yeah which basically
kills any organic material it comes in
contact with because the radical yeah
you're right yeah so but if you you know
it's it's excessive it's hcl2 is
chlorine dioxide right right so which
which iside is good for certain certain
application right CLE cleaning um clean
all your trays with with chlorine
chloride a bleach right and do all your
if you're G to you know if you're I used
to clean hydren yeah and I would do that
with h and you don't need a lot of H2O2
that's the thing is you don't need a lot
but it's only cleaning for maintenance
same thing with chlorine dioxide like
CO2 we only use that to clean the lines
dri it it'll go absolutely right but you
you you know it's pretty destructive if
you use it as a routine a routine thing
no you don't use it for anything else
you know so but it's great for eating
all that stuff that's in yes you know so
that's another benefit of ours is we
have a low salt index you know I just a
couple more plugs on Cana is we have a
low one of the lowest salt indexes yeah
uh oh and that's huge for using driers
right you it's like I think think a lot
of pro and using Organics you don't want
to use drippers obviously because they
clog I think that's the problem with a
lot of salts that people are using a lot
of salts have a lot of problems because
of that you know Fallout d da and I'm
not I don't like to bash because salts
have their place but you're you're going
to run into issues but they will build
up they will build up in your L and then
that that that influences your your your
pennies per people go you know I can get
it for four 4 cents a gallon I'm like
did you include labor did you include
the stock tank did you include the space
that you could have been using for
something else did you include your
dripper maintenance did you include all
the other factors and they're like I
like can I see your spreadsheet on 4
cents a gallon because if it's really 4
cents a gallon I'd [ __ ] like to see
that because I'd like to sell that yeah
and people are like no I didn't do a
spreadsheet so you're just doing the
simple math of a 100 gallons and how
much it cost to make you 100 gallons and
you didn't include any other [ __ ]
external factors that are involved in
that you're like then then no right and
and no one cares you don't put that on a
back this is [ __ ] you know uh runs
made with [ __ ] three cents a gall and
[ __ ] they wouldn't buy it no right you
know so people just don't care no but
what they do care about is the quality
of the end product and The Branding
Unfortunately The Branding kind of I was
just at my friend's dispensary and we
were talking and this is an age old I
feel somewhat
sympathetic for and sad for the brand
new generation of consumers who care how
shiny the myar back bag is they get
duped into buying inferior products by
high-end marketing right all the time
that's what I love about H Huckleberry
Hill Farms dude that guy Johnny yeah
it's like yeah same thing I'm a little
en I'm a little envious like which is
good you know what I mean like Jason
from Ridgeline Johnny up there like
those guys are doing it and they're
doing it the right way I feel like with
with good ethics right right and they
have a good product that goes in and I
love their flower I I love everything
about their brand yeah Sun Sun uh
sunburnt sunbolt sunbolt is the same
she's a old hippie chick up there who's
who's uh yeah doing it so so if you had
one piece of advice for your younger
self that was just getting into the
industry what would that one piece of
advice be I Pro I locked out by being uh
osmosis information and adjacent
information but I would suggest to
anybody who wants to get into this to
take a few courses at a college in one
in soil science and the other is in a
botney maybe organic chemistry those
that
knowledge uh will separate you from all
the other cultivators yeah just that
couple semesters well maybe maybe three
you know soil science 101 yeah B
whatever botney classes is and biochim
like and you got to put yourself you got
to that's the hard part is you're like
and I locked out and the other advice
that I would give to anybody is I forgot
I always forget the name because it was
such a jarring experience but those
two-day seminars in management God
what's the company called there's a
there's a guy it's named after him and
but he sends people around and uh I
can't remember what it is but Tony
Robbins yeah is it Tony Robbins is it no
it's somebody else but
basically learn how to man if you want
to you can't be dude having a couple
duplexes or a couple bedrooms or
basement okay but the minute you get
into your position or any other position
yeah you got to learn management skills
and and and sometimes you don't like
what the management skill taught you
like you got to like you got to fire
your junky friend right you know what I
mean yeah it's it's tough hiring friends
man that's one of the toughest things
ever is hiring friends working with I
love working with my friends get me
wrong but hiring friends is it's tough
um classes I think classes that I would
I you can take classes I love the work
culture and also you know being a chef
you were also a chef we didn't really
talk about that on the show but you were
a chef in San Francisco I was a chef in
San Francisco you that and that's you
want to talk about a pressure situation
yeah those were uh you know I can't even
watch my wife is watching the bear and
halfway through I'm like I'm going to go
I'm going to go outside so funny most
chefs I know don't want go outside this
is this isst PTSD yeah I I worked as a
line cook over there and I worked on the
grill you know some restaurants and and
you know that that's a high pressure
thing but the one thing I really love
about the restaurants is basically it's
a mentorship program right like you you
Mentor the people underneath you and I
feel like our industry is very very much
just like that like if you if you're a
good manager what you do is you Mentor
The People Under you you teach them
everything you know so that they can be
the best person that they can be and
then hopefully they grow up to be like
you and do that with other people and it
goes on for Generations yes and carry it
on carry it on yeah yeah so carry on the
torch you know it's like um because
you're that's another product you're
making yeah you know everything that
you're doing as a cultivator isn't just
about the plant right it's about other
things you're making that become
valuable out in the world well in some
ways it's making the world a better
place right like same thing with food I
feel like making good food you're doing
the Lord's work but you're making the
world the better place because you're
making people happy yes right and same
thing anything related to cannabis if
you're you're involved in that stuff
pemp cannabis this plant is special and
you make the world a better place just
by being a part of the industry yes a
good part of the industry yeah I mean
you and I you know we've experienced the
the criminality of the
industry yeah I mean there's people that
have taken away from that right right
but uh you know I I love being a part of
this this thing that's so much bigger
than myself right like yeah just being a
part of that makes me happy and makes me
smile it's like and and that's
contagious oh yeah that happiness is
contagious it goes around and people
pick up on that and they even if they
think you're weird they might be
interested what does he love about this
so much it's it's crazy that's why the
shoreline is always something like oh
Shoreline is like yeah the shoreline and
it's special yeah and the the way the
the blades they has super sharp blades
on the leaves so yeah it's a special
plant oh yeah so yeah so if people are
trying to find out more about you how
can they do that or where can they go uh
you go to uh
can.com okay uh that information will be
there uh and you uh go into your local
retailer if you want uh but kindergarden
got Tom and you can you can reach out
and one of us will get back to you you
guys have an Instagram too it's uh
official Cana official Cana yeah yep and
you can reach out you guys got some good
content on there official we' worked
together on some stuff with can I love
you guys do a great job and uh yeah I
mean I look forward to seeing you again
sometime in the future appreciate it
thank you so much for coming on the show
thanks for having me you guys have a
good one
[Music]