[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James loud
podcast and today our special guests are
Horizon lift we've got rod and we've got
David how are you guys doing today I'm
doing good James doing great James for
having us dude thank you guys for coming
on so we've become friends over the last
six months uh originally we were
introduced through grow world and I
thought you guys had an interesting
product you guys came down toward the
facility and said that you thought you
had a good product for us I started
getting all these ideas on what we could
do with your system and you guys had
these ideas and you met with our our
main grower and we kind of came up with
a concept that worked and I feel like
you guys have something really special
Thanks James I mean we think that you
know products shouldn't be pitched they
should be proven you know so we created
a product and we're trying to get it out
there and let people find out for
themselves how well it works yeah so
let's tell everybody a little bit about
what you guys doing in the lift my story
goes back to 1981 yeah so um well before
the lift um I was involved in the um
retail sales of products um in Portland
Oregon right um little place called
light Manufacturing Company there was
two of us in the whole town um spring
forward you know I got on Craig hard
Graves radar and endered up at Sunlight
Supply and I've touched over 2,000
products in this industry today amazing
yeah it's been it's been a fun run so
I'll interject and say that's how
actually we got introduced to Rod is we
used to sell we call xrt but you guys
probably know it as a rope ratchet and
we started selling those through Rod he
found us and contacted us said I think I
could sell a lot of these for you and we
did and had a great time with it and
then he contacted us again this was
probably close to like eight years ago
now and he said hey this is going from a
garage and a closet to a corporate
commercial facility how do we take it
from going from selling our rope
ratchets in a closet or in a small only
four to 12 lights to a thousand light
facility how do we actually make it
easier for the consumer he said can you
take what you guys have created with the
Rope ratchet and automate it and then
that's basically what started our
relationship and uh we've been trying to
perfect it for eight years now and took
about five but we've been selling it for
the last three so um yeah that's how and
the ratchets have been around forever
that was that's what we all used
ratchets are versions of rout some
people use chains you know but like I
think that what you guys have is very
Innovative in the sense that you've
automated something that we've all used
uh that actually can improve the quality
of the product uh improve efficiencies I
think it's great well the evolution of
light hangers was Jack chain yeah you
know completely through the 80s it was
Jack chain
nobody moved their lights you know and
then it was the grow yo-yo I think we
all remember the grow yo-yo with the
spring inside and after about a time one
side would go down and you'd walk in
your room and the lights sitting
sideways in your room over your canopy
um so the grow grow yoyo was just an
unefficient product yeah um we went to a
sales meeting and the owner of the
company brought this product from Bart
and handed it to me and said what do you
think about this and I said don't say
another word let me contact the patent
holders so
found out who the patent holder was
these gentlemen and we cut a deal and
became the exclusive vendor of the
product um first time the industry's
ever seen this product and we called it
sun grip yeah um and we all know what
happened after that I mean Sun grip went
crazy um everybody started coming in to
compete the knockoffs started showing up
and you know unfortunately it's really
tough to stop the knockoffs you know
when really tough when they start coming
um there's just too big of a Floodgate
you know you just can't poke all the
holes fast enough right and you know
it's like whacka all yeah exactly and
people that deliver free to your house
and stuff didn't help that at all you
know so um you got a lot of direct sales
happening in today's environment yeah
the direct sales have really changed the
industry I mean as a whole yeah where we
used to go to grow shops and buy
everything from Grow shops and we had
you know vendors that that sent products
to these Grow shops that were real
knowledgeable and then you had people at
Grow shops that were extremely
knowledgeable and they would help you
select the best products for your
environment now everything is online and
people want to go direct with everything
and I think that's actually kind of
taken away some of the beauty of our
industry yeah and I think you know the
one thing they they Overlook is you know
customer service versus price point yeah
it's great to get a great price but if
something fails with the product who's
going to support it right there's nobody
at the other end of the phone well we've
seen problems big problems in this
industry with the lack of customer
service from lighting companies to other
products where there's a phone number
and nobody ever gets back to you and
what do you do if you have lights that
you've spent you know especially with
these larger facilities where you spend
all this money on lights and then you
don't have customer service or you don't
have this or you don't have that and
it's like it's it's changed the game
completely and you know it's less
personable yeah and it's funny you say
lighting you know I mean without
customer service you know lighting's got
a whole bunch of holes in it yeah so I
mean it's hard to repeat a light over
and over and over and hit 100% you know
all lighting has a failure rate we just
hope that's a small one um so knowing
that all lights are going to fail at
some point customer service is
imperative right it's a disservice to
just hand somebody a box and go good
luck when you guys are like gortex for
lighting right so you guys improve the
efficiency of a light uh I I think that
there's a bunch of different uh
interesting ways you can utilize the
lift but yeah we're using it here and we
veg in a small amount of canopy and so
that saves us light and then we're we're
lowering them way down and then as the
plants get get taller we expand that so
we're saving money right out the gate
right and then we're able to dial the
ppfd in U and then change it from
day-to-day as the plants grow we can we
can raise it up or we can concentrate
the ppfd I think uh it's a great product
for that and I will say sorry Rod but I
will say that we initially how Rod
proposed kind of this project was how do
we get people off ladders how do we make
their lives more efficient how do we
save them customer or employee work
hours that was kind of the start of it
and we didn't even really think about
grow increasing your yield um you know
having more THC you know that wasn't
even a part of our equation when we made
this and this was almost just like an
added benefit of being able to
constantly have the ppfd in the perfect
position then it Growers who know what
they're doing have already been doing
that but the average let's say newbie
grower doesn't do that uh properly per L
I don't know what the word is a lot of
people don't even have par meters in
their house yeah that don't even do that
and they're just going off eyeballing or
even temperature readers which is also
super important so uh we feel like if we
took the ppfd reader with the surface
Leaf temperature reading uh we found
like we found like the sweet spot to
grow which was an added bonus on top of
not having your employees get on ladders
anymore and and etc etc for safety right
it's all run from an iPad I love it
exactly or your phone yeah or your phone
yeah now it's a it's a world of
efficiency now you know when I started
hearing people go you know how much can
you grow a grand of weed for yeah you
know it's like well we never really
cared about that you know if you really
think about it wow a guy's got to get
really efficient if people are going to
start playing that game you know because
there are some people that are pretty
crafty yeah you know and they they
lessen the inputs um and still get a
great product you know Horizon lift
doesn't add cost to the grow you know
you're simply moving a light up and down
you know and it's four to five movements
a cycle at most
you know for 2 seconds so you know it's
a product that came into the environment
made it a better environment without
adding cost um or additional labor yeah
um because we all know labor is a huge
component of a grow now huge um
electricity and labor and like you
talked about electric labor if you can
save on those two things then you're you
know I think at the end of the day
people want to grow the highest quality
product possible at the cheapest price
possible yeah like abely right
absolutely without sorry but without
taking away from the quality is the most
important part right that's has to well
now there's this race to the bottom and
so 10 years ago before all this
commercialization like this really
increased commercialization of the
product uh you could get away with
selling an average quality product but
now today there's plenty of average
stuff out there but it doesn't go for a
lot so if you're and also how much do
you produce that pound for you produce
that pound for $600 and you can only
sell it for seven that's a problem right
and you produce it for three and sell it
for seven that's a different story but
there's so much product on the market
like especially in California we have
this surplus of product yet we only
consume so much so in metric especially
with the recreational Cannabis it's like
recreational and medical there's there's
only so much product that we need people
want the best product they can get for
the price so unless you're growing the
best you might as well just quit I mean
that's my opinion right now and so
quality has to be the leading Factor whe
and it starts with genetics but then
it's also inputs and all these other
things that that happened over a period
of the life of the plant you know and
you back in the 80s and 90s you know the
indoor environment was the only
environment you know for multiple
reasons you know so I think there's more
study and more time on the indoor
environment than any other environment
you know there's a lot being done now um
but I still think today um all the is
really from an indoor environment I mean
people are kind of feeling their way
through hoop houses and green houses and
double teers and you know everybody's
kind of finding their way through that
right now to where there's 35 years of
indoor growing out there and we probably
wouldn't be growing indoors at the level
we're grown at if it wasn't for
prohibition of marijuana you know I mean
I think abely we were grown outside and
then people wanted to hide from the
police yeah helicopters over your fields
and all that stuff and that was what was
going on right yeah and so we we went
indoors and then they did were not
allowed research it right federally it's
like you can't research because it's a
bad plan it's illegal all these things
and you know we've lived in this
backwards world and now indoor is
fetching the most price it's you know
it's supposed to be the best I don't
honestly think indoor is the best in in
every regard I think there's a place for
outdoor there's a place for Greenhouse I
think there's a place for light lifts in
a greenhouse you know I think we
actually are in a greenhouse up in
Oregon that's helped out actually them
quite a bit so yeah but supplemental
right like so exactly cuz you have the
sun in addition to and I think that's a
great thing and you know what I ran into
and you know when you introduce a
product all sorts of things come out of
the Woodworks green houses aren't always
structured the same right so you have an
amount of weight that you're going to
put on that ceiling in a greenhouse um
some of them can't take it because
you're using Unistrut you know you're
adding too much additional weight to
that structure some grease houses can
yeah so you know in that environment you
would have to certify the weight you
know make sure the structure is going to
hold the weight um and then go because
it is huge advantage in Greenhouse
environments yeah um I I'm just cautious
to go hey everybody put these up in your
Greenhouse um because there is going to
be structural Integrity problems well I
think the definition of a greenhouse is
so broad yeah right so what there can be
so many different types I mean some
people consider hoop houses green houses
right and it's like yeah but these Dutch
green houses the venl like these glass
houses they can support you know they
they cost more than indoor GRS typically
yeah so you know especially for the
nicer ones yeah I think Rod's talking
about like up in Oregon the green houses
that have been there for 30 years cuz
like we've actually sold to a greenhouse
in Texas and I mentioned that about
structure and they're like we're waited
for a hurricane so this thing's not
going anywhere you know difference yeah
all these cutf flower green houses that
you converted into cannabis and all
these things they're not all suitable
for the lift and some a lot of people
people don't have power anyway not
everybody but you know power has to be
consideration too but I'm a fan of
supplemental lighting light lifts I like
under canopy I think they all need to be
explored we're exploring them together
we're doing a trial with the under
canopy we're doing a trial with the
liift and then together for seed
production I think we're the only ones
doing that right now I'm excited for
that yeah me too and I think the results
that we get from that it's going to be
really telling because I know that we're
going to get more from the Light Lift I
know that we're going to get more from
the under canopy now if we combine them
what happens yeah what happens I know so
that's a mystery but we're going to
explore that yeah I love it yeah yeah
it's fun you know I think I've got seven
years into this product yeah um and you
know every product that I ever put
across a goal line I personally test it
you know it was just a rule that I had
with myself if I'm going to tell
somebody else to use it then I got to
know in my heart that it works right
yeah you know that this isn't snake oil
and you know there's been some products
that people just absolutely scratch
their head at you know I mean I'll take
you back to frequency water
right I mean my sales staff wanted to
freaking shoot me they're like Rod there
is no frequency water and I'm like well
you tell me why I sprayed that on a bug
and the bug is gone right and I tested
it and it's water right so I mean if you
can tell me what I'm missing here you
know I'll go a different direction but
for now I think I got the Holy Grail you
know I have no chemicals no residue I'm
spraying water on bugs and killing them
yeah you know with frequency and
I'm not a technician do I know that
there was frequency in there no but
whatever was in there I tested it and it
was water and it was killing bugs yeah
so along my path I've run into some
really strange products that you know
went this is super beneficial for this
environment but people go I don't
believe it it's snake oil well there's
been so much snake oil out there and
then also we we get these things and it
takes a long time to actually perfect
them right so like purple LED lights
that's a reference that we've used on
this show so much but it's like
something that I did not believe in when
I heard LEDs and I saw purples the blur
I was like no way am I ever going to use
that you got a six inch tall or one foot
tall plant this looks like trash I I
don't want any part of that autof
flowers don't want any part of it but
people are creative people are
persistent people will figure out how to
improve stuff and sometimes for LED
lights example there's a standard down
everybody uses LED you know that's you
and and that's the beauty of this
industry too is that we are Innovative
and we are creative you guys have
Innovation and I think right when we
think we've got it all figured out
something else new comes out yeah always
and you see that especially and it's
just being a steward of the environment
you know I mean you go you know I've
done this the same way for over and over
and over how can I make it better right
you know and my job was to create
products to make the environment better
um and when that when the ratchets all
the data we collected on the ratchets um
showed us that people move their lights
yeah you know people tell me today it's
like why do you need to move your lights
and I'm like I don't know but I've
collected a shitload of data and people
move their lights there's a reason
they're buying ratchets and not Jack
chain yeah right so they wouldn't buy
the ratchets if they weren't relocating
their lights and then I went around to a
bunch of rooms and said how often do you
move these people move them a lot more
than you would think yeah so knowing
that I went well let's make this easier
let's automate what if a guy could stand
in his doorway with his phone and
readjust his whole room I mean how long
is that to take versus standing in the
room with a with an application right
you know and so then I went to them and
said is this possible you know and we
revved it and revved it and revved it
with weights and motors and on and on
and on I mean it's not a simple process
it was about five years of R&amp;D five
years R&amp;D seven revisions you know is
what you're looking at today and and I'm
really happy with it yeah you you know
we get the comment you know why did you
go
Bluetooth not everybody's got Wi-Fi
right it's line of sight and I don't
want the thing to move lights in every
room yeah I want them to move them
within a certain distance so that I'm
looking at the room that's moving and
not the one down the street right so you
know it made more sense for the
environment that we were in there's a
lot of confusion in that environment I
will add sorry I will add to that is
that the few questions we've gotten
about Wi-Fi versus Bluetooth was some
want to have a just a completely
automated place they want to be able to
sit in a computer room at their house
and be able to see a video of their
facility and be able to touch a button
they want they sensor that changes that
so we've actually looked into that and
the difference is is one is sensors
aren't perfect two your height of your
canopy is never perfectly even it's
always going to grab the top one so we
felt that it was just in the best
interest of the grower to be in the room
if you're growing the high quality you
know marijuana that you're hoping for
you're going to have to be there and be
Hands-On you can't do it from a separate
control room well and I think there is
some future that does include stuff like
that where it's 100% automated and you
have a sensor and every day as the
plants are growing taller it could move
it up if you're trying to keep the
perfect you know ppfd you had it y or
Leaf surface temperature or however you
want to monitor that I mean I think
maybe someday that's going to be the
next Evolution yeah yeah we do have that
capability and we could actually do it
but we haven't seen that it's worth it
at this point but I do think that it
will eventually go in that direction
yeah I mean I see the future is there's
going to be places where they don't have
a lot of employees because the thing is
is what we need to do is you know save
money as much as possible create the
best product possible at the lowest
price and so they're going to take away
labor cu Labor's expensive expensive if
we could take away electricity or you
know Turn Down the Lights make the
lights more efficient that's another way
but either way the the cost of the
product is extremely important and
everybody is very aware of every penny
that they're spending these days the
ones that are still here yep yeah and
I've Ted a lot of facilities in Europe
yeah Europe is very very cautious on
price points yeah so I mean they have
some of the most efficient grows I've
ever seen um as well as I toured a lot
of RADS facilities over there yeah and
you talk about green houses you know
they got roller structures in them to
where when they change the lights they
put a dolly up on top and they roll
across the top of the greenhouse
changing bulbs yeah so I mean they build
structure into their green houses to
make them more efficient um some of the
most amazing grows I've ever seen in my
life over there yeah I mean the some of
those Dutch green houses are just
unbelievable you know and I mean the
technology that goes into it it's like
uh you have the full control of an
indoor with the light of the Sun and
supplemental lighting M yeah and their
technology is amazing too you know them
having the largest flowers in the world
yeah um obviously comes from their Bloom
stimulant I went over there and kicked
tires on Bloom stimulant and some of
their technology is just out of this
world well they have so many years of
R&amp;D you know they've been r&amp; ding this
stuff forever plus they have a really
good environment for r&amp; ding in the cold
in the winter extremes you know like if
you look at extremes it's a great place
to test stuff out in extremes how how
well does it do when it gets zero mhm
yeah you know House and Garden yeah you
know I mean very successful European
nutrient and you know I sat down with
that team you know and they were
completely happy with the distribution
they had and shaked my hand and said you
won't be selling ours wow so it was a
bold move you know I thought I had the
world in my hand I said you know we're
National distributor you know we can put
you all over the United States in 24
hours um and he shook my hand and said
no thanks yeah you know I well back to
home I gold that's how it goes not
taking the bag of tricks home this time
you know but you know I've seen some
really neat stuff over there I mean
Europe is an amazing place to learn you
know about growing yeah um not that
America is you know that far behind them
but right and but it's different it's
different over there like it's just like
it's different here there's a lot of
great things if you want to learn about
genetics there's good things you can
learn in Europe especially Dutch Dutch
and and over in Spain and over in in
Holland but also here I mean we have
amazing scientists here and I think we
have people pushing the envelope in
every region of the world right now yeah
and if you think about it you know the
one example I would use is gavita yeah
you know hey Twan jer what's up Bros so
you know went over there there were some
of the first people I met and you know
developed a really good relationship
with them and you know was able to bring
that back to sunlight yeah um we did
really well with that yeah I mean they
made a great light too especially the
double-ended gavita when it first came
out was a game fantastic you know there
and the the first one I remember that
was double Ed was the epap that papon
right and so that came out and that was
great that was a greenhouse light and
then gavita is like just put all these
indoors people tried putting the eaps
indoors but really the gavita kind of
changed the game uh as as also as far as
like the quality that it put out you
know I was pretty impressed the first
the first harvest with the gavita and
there was some big players involved with
epap yeah you know I thought epap was
going to be the platform and uh
everybody I'll tell you Twan and J ear
outworked them yeah you know they came
to the United States and just flat
outworked them yeah so they they did an
amazing job yeah it was impressive it
was impress that that whole period was
really impressive because that was kind
of the beginning of the
commercialization of cannabis right
where it really took on a whole new it
was like this whole new momentum that we
were experiencing that we' never seen
before and it's like what's next what's
next and everything was bigger than the
the previous move and people were
getting these big grows in Colorado and
it was just the scale that people were
starting to go at was like holy [ __ ]
this is really becoming big business
yeah because it's one thing where we had
these hydro shops and there's these big
manufacturers and they're selling and
it's all going through hydro shops the
next thing is is like we're talking
about Farms that they're running acres
and green houses that are acres and you
know even the first time I walked into a
20,000 SQ foot canopy I was like holy
[ __ ] this is crazy yeah now 20,000 ft of
canopy in a greenhouse is nothing you
know that's that's not very big yeah and
what do you do when you harvest that
amount of Wheat and you have no way to
preserve it yeah you know I mean that's
that's a huge amount of product that is
decomposing well yeah and I think the
thing is is like a lot of people were
like we're just going to goow and figure
it out along the way and it's like
there's so many components you need to
really dial in as far as storage drying
and curing properly how do you store it
how do you preserve it how do you make
it last as long as possible even if
you're able to sell it you still want
have those things in mind absolutely for
sure and you know I mean dispensaries in
the Pacific Northwest you know with the
testing process and the time it takes to
actually get it into the jar and get it
for sale yeah you know you've got
products that are two months old you
know and if this wasn't preserved
properly you know you got brown frown
well that was the beauty of the medical
days Pacific Northwest Portland I was
born in Portland I'm a big fan of
Portland yeah you know in Washington and
Oregon and California I spent a lot of
time in those three states my in my life
and with medical the product was really
fresh right like it was sold compared to
now yeah absolutely right it was like
you bring your stuff down you're a
vendor you bring it down you show it to
them they want to get it sold and you
know your money back or if they paid
cash they want to you know get their
money back for the cash that they paid
right away and uh so it was a whole
different model there wasn't the testing
I like testing I think testing is great
I think testing is important uh you know
it's tested more than any other AG
product out there yeah but uh I think
that that's a beautiful part but the
problem is is like the farm to table
experience right like how fast are you
getting two months old if it's preserved
correctly can still be a really good
product but if it's not preserved
correctly right uh like the seeds in the
mail or what whatever happens sometimes
these things like if if the seeds get
hot and they go in the mail you could
have bad seeds if the flower gets hot
what's sitting on someone's shelf or
waiting to get packed packaged that
flour is a bad product or it could be an
inferior product to what it would have
been before if it's sitting in a one gon
glass jar and the sun's hitting it from
the window um you've got a problem yeah
there's a lot more to this it's that
still needs to roll out and and
preserving the product I think is one of
the big ones it's one of the most
important ones in the shortest period of
time that you can screw your plant up
you know you have this whole life of the
plant where you can screw it up and it
can it can take away from that big pie
right but that preservation period where
you're drawing it you're curing it
you're trimming it and you're storing it
for sale or selling it that's the in my
mind that's one of the most important
periods you know that's as important as
starting with good genetics yeah and I
hear it from a lot of The Growers you
know they're going you know hey I I wish
my product could get to the Shelf faster
yeah you know because my reputation's on
it you know and because it's not
properly handled you know I pick up some
bad reputation because the product's not
what I gave them yeah you know I want to
see direct sales that that's where I
would really love to see direct sales is
from the farm to the consumer where you
can go up you can talk to the grower or
the hash maker or whatever and you can
talk to him about the love that he put
in that plant and how much he cared
about those plants and you can go buy a
fresh ounce or a fresh eth yeah uh I
mean I think that's the future that's
the you know we've done that with
breweries and wineries forever I say
that's yeah that's the standard there I
heard of in New Mexico where they were
growing in the back of the building they
were drying in the middle of the
building and the dispensary was in the
front they had two glass windows to
where people could look through and see
the product drying and it had a list of
the fresh product available next week
yeah and I went amazing platform you
know I haven't been to New Mexico to see
it um I've seen some pictures of it but
I went what a great platform yeah
Califoria I mean it that is as quick as
you can get it there yeah California
just came out with the new law right
that you're allowed to actually have a
facility that you can smoke and have
food and drink now I believe that just
passed got signed in right I'm excited
for the future that for smoking lounges
yeah that's what I mean I think it might
change kind of like what you were
talking about I hope it does I hope it
does because we you know I feel like
cannabis is a lot healthier than alcohol
I agree and we're doing it with alcohol
why not do it with cannabis and I feel
like uh it's the perfect model
especially because there's so many
passionate people there's passionate
people with alcohol with
people
Canabis talk invested you know and then
that just makes it more of an experience
too like the second you can get it's
just like meeting you guys and using
your product I get to I get this
different experience it's one thing
buying stuff but then when you meet the
people behind it then you start to
understand really what the product's
about what went into it uh customer
service is so huge too yeah yeah for
sure we've had a lot of people pour over
the fence you know from you know
different industries that yeah didn't
cut their teeth there you know and you
can sense that see you had conversations
you know like cat hasn't been around a
long time yeah you know and there's
really nothing you can do about that but
you know you know the guys that have
been here a long time yeah um and
they're knowledgeable and the old school
guys like me you know we've always
talked about it right you know I mean we
didn't hide our secrets and you know hey
I'm not going to tell you how I do it
and you know we wanted everybody body
have good weed CU if we ran out we
wanted someplace to go get it totally so
you know it wasn't about you know hey
I'm going to be better than you and I'm
not going to tell you anything and it's
gotten really competitive now it used to
be so much more Community Driven
Community Bas yeah and I I love that
part of the industry that's Community I
feel like my show is all about community
and bringing to light different people
in the community they're doing great
things like you guys I mean the early
burning man you know the early reg gays
on the river you know mean they're
amazing really amazing they were totally
different I mean today's environment is
great um but it's it's it's not that
relaxed you know Brotherhood it used to
be no but everything good has an end and
it changes things more disco we missed
disco I miss disco I don't know about
you guys but I miss around during the80s
yeah yeah so I you know but but like
Studio 54 and disco it had its day where
I bet it was so amazing and I wish I
would have been able to experience it
but you know things change and you know
we grow and evolve and the one thing
constantly Chang for sure yeah and you
know I go back to the beginning when
this guy goes come check this out and he
had taken two buckets and filled one
with PE gravel and was pouring water on
it and there were cucumbers there
Tomatoes were huge I mean this thing was
blowing up in his backyard you know and
he says I think we could sell this wow
you know and that cut my teeth into
Hydroponics I ended up making assembly
line we were assemble them in his
basement and out to the UPS truck they'd
go and next thing you know we had our
retail store and
the police would park across the street
and they'd put cameras on the telephone
poles and you know the 80s was was a
tough time you know Nancy rean was out
there swinging that bat you know she
says yeah I picked it up when Richard
Nixon dropped it and I'm gonna Club way
more people than he did right and uh she
rre Havoc a lot of people did a lot of
people did and I think a lot of some
people unknowingly were doing the wrong
thing and now if they were to look back
they'd say well cannabis wasn't so bad
yeah regardless of everything else you
know it's like uh it's it's a strange
thing that we went through all this and
and people suffered so much uh yeah you
know it's just it's really unfortunate
yeah you think about a time when you
know people got five years for 100
plants yeah or for seeds people got
prison sentences for seeds yeah you know
for this plant it's not a crime no it's
seeds are considered hemp we can ship
them anywhere you can give them to your
friends you can ship them in the mail
it's it's hemp they there's no makes
sense to me me too yeah absolutely
that's great for you yeah yeah so you
started working in hydroponics in the80s
in the 81 or and 81 a friend of mine
created the system and had me come over
to his house and um we we got kicked out
of this house because we had too many
UPS trucks coming for for deliveries and
ironically enough everybody stared at
each other and go you know how do we
sell this thing it's it's a hydroponic
system and ironically enough we took out
a little tiny ad in Popular Science
magazine yeah um Popular Science was
huge back in the early 80s um ad comes
out first of the month and phone starts
ringing every time we set the phone down
there wasn't call waiting back then so
every time we set the phone down it
would start ringing again yeah and we
sat there and took orders for almost
eight hours straight off of this phone
wow and we went my God people like this
you know and so we went how long is this
going to last maybe it's a fat so we
stayed there making them out of his
house until we got the letter from the
city saying you guys got to move you
can't run a business in a neighborhood
my friend started light manufacturing
company and we started buying rock wall
for the the system and we upgraded the
tubing we upgraded a lot of the fittings
for it you know we we revolutionized it
and out it went and sold a million
dollars the first year wow and all of a
sudden you know people started paying
attention like man there's a grow shop
over there you know and it was us and
you know American egg was the other shop
yeah there was two of us in Portland and
ironically enough if they didn't get
they wanted for our store they said well
I'm not shopping here I'm going to shop
an American egg and then guy would come
in the store and go I'm never shopping
an American egg I'm shopping at your
store so we swapped customers for years
back and forth because you got one
choice or the other right you know and
uh system did really well and I started
getting into product development you
know we we uh got that nutrient handbook
out by Rusk right way back in the 80s
way back and we all read that right we
all put put in our two cents and uh we
built a fertilizer called Golden grow
and what we found and no one's done it
to this day is you know the
micronutrients are tough to blend into a
200 pound batch of powder right so
you've got very small amounts you know
other than you know you got decent iron
but we went you know how is this working
you know how do we know that every scoop
is going to give that same micronutrient
kick we couldn't so we created an A and
B and we created a micronutrient liquid
yeah so once we liquified it we have now
divided it equally so we had you know
golden grow golden Bloom and micro gold
yeah um and we sold it for 20 years and
absolutely made a fortune from it all
from that book I have a question for you
because I'm real curious as to what you
just said made me wonder did nutrients
start out as a dry mix that then went
into liquid and now we're going back
into dry again or was it always liquid
well it was uh cuz I know there was
three- part for a long time General
Hydroponics was around in 1976 right um
their distribution range um wasn't huge
you know you kind of really had to pull
some teeth to yank it all the way up to
Oregon right um but it was on the Shelf
there was another liquid that we had
that was came out of the commercial
industry when EG had commercial e yeah
um there was a lady out of Seattle um
that had Eco grow and so she had her own
powder and so we went you know hey look
you know there's room for us in this
game um so got that book and trial and
error trial and error oop killed that
one you know too much of that um we
finally got it figured out and you know
we had the hydroponic system we had the
hydroponic media and we had the
fertilizer for it yeah and Off to the
Races we went I mean it was a very very
successful business um all we had to
worry about was you know people pulling
in with covered license plates and cops
burning down the street after them when
they left and I mean it was tumultuous
time everyone had to talk about tomatoes
they couldn't use the word weed cannabis
anything like that I mean that's how it
was even when in the 9s when we used to
go to G shops it was Tomatoes or you
would get kicked out of the shop people
would lose their [ __ ] you know and and
they would put Undercovers in there all
the time you know and that we would have
a really good conversation and all they
said well yeah I'm growing weed I'm like
well dude you gotta leave the store yeah
oh no no no I'm cool you know and that
was the I'm cool no he's a cop he's
gotta go right so I mean it was just
crazy how they would just try to
infiltrate us week after week well in
Portland they really cracked down on it
and they made huge arrests and it it was
it was pretty gnarly for a period of
time yeah Green Merchant green Merchant
yeah wolf seall was part of that too I
believe they got stuck up in that Alex
from throw's Edge yeah yeah it it got a
lot of us I know yeah um I'd like to say
I got away scotf Frey but that's not the
case but that's a story for another time
yeah totally so David yeah tell me how
you got your start with cannabis were
you smoking in high school I did yes so
I probably started smoking in high
school and just have been a you know uh
what's the term for it just a casual
smoker for for that but uh literally I
met Rod like 10 years ago and just
absolutely loved like this space like
came from the hardware background it's a
different category definitely a
different vibe and a different culture
so once we actually hooked up with Rod
and Sunlight Supply at the time it was
like oh H how do I get into this because
I like the people like meeting people
like you meeting people like Rod like
every person I've met I've really
enjoyed and curious people intelligent
people always trying to find the next
best way where I was coming from a
different category where it was a race
to the bottom how do we take as much out
and we don't really care about the
quality like you spoke about earlier
about cannabis you want to take the
money out but you also need to leave the
quality well this was the exact opposite
we're taking out quality to try to
basically get it as low as possible and
it gets tight and it gets hard and it's
not fun so once I actually came over to
here and kind of been poking around and
looking into things it was like oh this
is this is where I should be and uh it's
been good ever since so I'm on a big
steep learning curve like I said I've
been in it for eight years but I am not
a professional grower I am learning
daily as we go so which I also enjoy as
well like I ask you stupid questions all
the time like when I come see your
facility I ask probably the most basic
but I'm try those kind of questions are
never stupid in my opinion those are you
those are the kind of questions that you
should be asking because if you don't
know the answer you might as well ask me
or ask somebody who knows the answer
because and then sometimes we stumble on
some crazy ideas you know with the light
and with with the system that you guys
have love it because we could we've
customized it to our own specs right so
we took the unist strut and we painted
it white and we wanted to match the
building and then you know the unit
start up top that used to just be
stainless we we've covered that you know
it's not stainless but yeah Ste this the
steel we we basically painted it white
and then it Blends in the room and it
really fits and you know and depending
on the type of light you can really
customize the system yeah which I like I
feel like you know my partner is all
about Aesthetics I'm all about fun
functionality and quality and he's like
how can we make this look better cuz you
already have all that stuff covered so
let's make it look nice too well if you
marry the two then you have the perfect
equation right so so you obviously need
to have your quality and your and and
that but Aesthetics is also a very big
component of it and I will say your
facility is beautiful I mean those rooms
you have in there world class I mean
yeah it's a showroom too right at the
end of the day it's a showroom and it
it's also it's a showroom for me but but
companies like yourself it's a showroom
for you so we can share with the world
our ethos how we believe the plants
should be grown you know how how the
different genetics work together and and
specifically genetics it's like we're
focused on genetics so it's like how can
we grow the plant to the best of ability
so we can show our genetics the the true
potential of our genetics maximize your
potential of genetics yeah yeah so at
the end of the day it's a it's a great
showcase for everybody that's involved
we you know I'm I'm a very big fan of
all the products that I use and we're
constantly r&amp; ding stuff so I want to
test everything
get as much feedback as I can and make
my decision on what I want to use for
the future you I think that's the best
way to R&amp;D is really get everything in
the pot try all these different things
out and then come up with the the
solution that works the best yeah I
agree and I think the way you also do it
is another thing is like you have it
down to such an exact science right
you're we talked about you're only
changing one variable for each test
right we're not changing nutrients so
whatever it is you're changing one
variable and I think that's going to
give us the best honest assessment of
how well this would do and I like you
spoke about earlier I'm really
interested in combining our Horizon lift
with an under canopy light because we
have done testing in facilities in the
past and not to be a snake snake oil
salesmen but we've seen a large increase
in the yield by moving your lights right
and so they've also seen that with the
under canopy lights now it's coming out
that they've starting to see the
increase of the yield and the the plants
on the bottom are kind of getting a
little thicker and just kind of
strengthening on the bottom that was
photosynthesis occurs of the top it's
not supposed to work but yet trial and
error it's working right so I'm really
excited to see the difference of under
canopy lights are Horizon lift and then
the combining of those two to see is it
too saturated is it too much or is it
going to be like oh wow this is like the
the best or just the answer getting
sorry getting the answer for that's
going to be big for me I'm always
excited about the answer right like what
are what's going to happen it's you know
you're kind of like an explore going
through you know Christopher Columbus
probably not the best example but these
days these days these days come on SM
know Christopher smoke totally and but
but being able to explore different
things I mean that keeps me excited to
come to work every day and it's like
yeah what are we going to find out today
well we already have a whole bunch of
fires to put out what else are we going
to learn about the plant or about the
way we're growing uh you know these
different spectrums with lights that's
what I'm always interested in is all
these different spect spectrums you know
we can do Spectrum tuning uh which I
think is great but that can totally be
abused and you can totally screw your
crop up when you start experimenting on
your own if you don't know what you're
doing yeah and so many people are like
oh I'll just do this this and this that
sounds about right yeah I think it's
much easier to test um with a fixed
position product yeah you know um when
when you're creating your own variables
um you're kind of skewing your own test
totally um so I'm a firm believer in you
know here's what it's supposed to do
well let's make it do that or at least
use that as a starting point you know
it's like let's start here and then
maybe tweak this or add a bunch of far
red and see what that does or you know I
think some of these guys they just want
to go all over the board and they don't
understand how to experiment it's like
to really get a good trial you need to
grow it out and see what it does and if
you're comparing it you need to compare
it in the same exact way that you
compare the first thing and you know I'm
not a lighting technician but you know
what I see with the under canopies is
they're getting really red you know so
they're taking a full spectrum light yep
right and and they're basically jamming
red up into it yep putting a whole bunch
of far red and does far red make it
bloom better well absolutely it does you
know it also more yeah I'm seeing more
purple with the LED abolutely right so
now the the sides are actually more
purple than the tops and I think that's
really cool you know for me I think
there's a demand for purple flow I don't
know that it it's always going to be
there but right now the demand is to
have purple it doesn't have to be all
purple but people want purple look yeah
they want that look in the bag and you
know or or in the jar or whatever and
with these under canopies they have that
far red now we're seeing an increase
also we're talking about saving labor
because you're not having to strip your
under canopy you're getting flour there
and you're getting more of a yield so
now you're saving labor you're getting a
bigger yield and now what happens if we
put light lifts in there that's that's
you know still the question is to be
answered but I think that's exciting for
me it's like okay well everybody else is
getting the same results we can all
agree that under canopies are doing this
we can agree that you're getting better
results with the Light Lift you know as
far as everybody's getting better
results they're getting bigger yields
they're getting frostier weed they're
getting you know I think there's
benefits that we can prove and now but
nobody's combined them yeah so nobody's
combined them for seed production now
are we going to get more seeds right cuz
now every every penny counts the value
of seeds has gone down now if we can
push that uh we're increasing profits
but we could possibly be increasing
quality because a lot of times on the
under canopy you know you get better
penetration if you're using light lifts
too right so now the question is we get
better penetration plus we have underc
yeah are we going to get 100% yield in
seeds because a lot of times I used to
get a lot of white seeds below okay
right where the light didn't penetrate
proper oh gotcha so yeah I think you're
going to do really well now
having line on both sides of it and
being able to compress it right um I
think you're going to you're going to
have control of the throttle well and
now okay the other question is so so
we're going to do one run one way but
we're going to have to continue to do
this because I really want to see okay
so if I veget a little bit longer and
have a taller plant okay now we have a a
wider canopy so can I yield more that
way maybe
interesting more on the bottom cuz you
have more we got more on the bottom and
then we have the power from the top and
we can really dial in the ppfd makes
sense uh and I don't know I don't know
what the answer is but I I know that
it's worth exploring and if I can get
more seeds if I can yield more uh and we
can translate that into flower
production too it's like who knows yeah
do panels out produce bars yeah I mean
we don't know any of this yet you know
we're getting a bunch of data from from
people who manufacture lights yeah um
but like you said the proof's in the
test yeah you know it's like okay prove
it yeah everybody talks I'm all about
the proof is in the pudding because I
hear so much noise from people right
there's so much noise in this industry
you got to mjbiz and everybody's got the
best light everybody's got the best this
everybody's got the best that but it's
like I need to go around with my friends
and go what do you use what what gets
you the results from the people that
grow the best flowers that grow the best
stuff right at the end of the day it's
like the people that are growing the
best what are they using and how are
they getting those results yeah I'll
tell you that um years ago gentleman
named Neil Anderson came to me with a
product called micro Rising
yeah never heard it before you know I've
heard Whispers you know from a guy who
was playing with it um he actually
brought it to me and says try this you
know and I what is it going to do and he
explained it to me and I was like what
that's snake oil yeah well micro riz's
real you know and after multiple tests I
went oh my God this stuff protects the
plant the plant grows better I mean once
it colonizes you know and getting that
colonization you know is is a little bit
of a challenge itself but on once you
understand how to colonize that on the
root on the root Zone yeah an amazing
product yeah um and
so welcome RTI yeah and I mean it's it's
something that's in nature too it's not
like we're creating something in a lab
this is something that occurs in nature
yeah you know and it's like there's so
many things like that yeah you know
that's it's just you scratching the
surface of all the different products
but there's so much snake oil it's hard
for the consumer to go to a shop and
sift through all that information
everybody's got the everybody got the
new latest and greatest and
so you know but as we mature as an
industry all these things get picked
apart and people slowly start learning
what the the better products are oh yeah
I do feel like that in in you're in the
industry is it does eventually get to
the best product quality all of that is
where everybody's aiming for right like
like I referred to is the other category
is no one's aiming for Perfection and
the other category and I feel like in
cannabis everybody starts out to grow
the best highest quality cannabis out
there yep yeah ego will lie yes that
gets ego will tell you that yours is the
best right everybody thinks they've
grown and I think there's this
attachment that we have with this plant
where we've grown it we put our hearts
and souls into it and it's like this is
amazing and it's hard to look beyond
that and I have a lot of respect for The
Growers that are like this is good but
I'm going to do better my next round or
[ __ ] this isn't as good as the last
round yeah got it people are just so
fixated on dude well being honest with
yourself right yeah it's really
difficult it's hard to do yeah and we're
human I think it's just there's human
nature involved with that always uh but
even like the flower market like you
look at the flower market and what's
available now it's like it's slowly in
in metric in California Oregon
Washington Colorado all these places it
gets better and better and better uh and
I think may maybe that'll change but
what I've seen in California is was
terrible in the beginning it's slowly
gotten better over the period of uh four
almost five years now and I you know
it's like in the beginning it was all
hype and there's still a lot of hype
being sold people are like oh there's
branding there's all this and I'm going
to sell it but slowly but surely The
Branding has to support a quality
product you know absolutely we've seen
that with with all kinds of stuff over
the years you know I'm sure with
nutrients too like all the hype with the
nutrients some of these companies where
it's like whoa those look like cool
freaking labels but you got to have a
quality product to back it in the bag
yeah yeah we found you know and I'm not
going to mention any names and stuff but
celebrities don't necessarily sell
nutrients right you know and uh we found
that out the hard way they shouldn't be
selling nutrients The Growers should be
the celebrities in my opinion we should
make those Growers the celebrities right
the ones that are grow the best in the
simple product development brain you go
well this guy's a celebrity that's known
for smoking cannabis Snoop Dog we're in
yeah totally Snoop Dog nutrients man
everybody's going to want these Che and
Chong right they're the work out that
way I would buy B Real's nutrients and
try them be real I think he's in a
different level because I feel like he's
more connected with the plant on the
growing side Dr Green them but but
there's very few celebrities I feel like
would be good representation for a
nutrient company you know there's only
so many things you can do with a
nutrient you know it's NPK yep you know
and you know how many how many ways can
you twist NPK around right um and the
additives start coming
yeah are the additives good or bad for
what you're doing you know cuz the guy
who ask you know what's the best way to
grow this you know I just start laughing
you know it's like there's a million
ways to do this you know it's smoke your
stuff if it's high quality you're doing
it right yeah if it's low quality you're
doing it wrong how does it taste one way
to go hey this is the best way to do it
you do it this way and you'll be the
best right um I've seen people grow
these plants aund different ways if
there was way we would all do it that
way we all do it that way but there's
not one way and it's a very uh it's a
live product you know we're growing
something that's alive that takes a long
time I mean relatively to grow and to
perfect and from one batch to the next
it's agriculture you know from one batch
to the next it's going to be slightly
different even with the best indoor
environments you can still get different
variables where you get a slightly
different end product yeah stuff's
getting more standardized but yeah you
know then you get the guy that goes you
know hey I jammed a bunch of stuff into
a cow's horn yeah buried in the ground
and that's how I grow yeah and you go
it's good to me yeah you know that works
for me your weed's great yeah I mean
we're fixated on the the look of the
product too which is I think is you know
it's always going to have to look good
but I think we're going to go more back
to the effect and The Taste yeah uh
Instagram is really screwed that up cuz
that's what you see is those beautiful
pictures right looks ridiculous but yeah
and at the end of the day maybe you do
but I think most people if you showed
them what they what you thought they
wanted and they tried it they'd be like
wow you know some good old school weed
like the the flower that we had in the
90s I never got to experience 80s weed
because I started smoking in ' 91 G13
yeah but uh like literally the stuff in
the 90s was amazing the flavor of it the
effect the way it made you feel yeah
that's when oi Kush knocked on the door
yeah you know OJ Kush came hard in the
90s and it's like pushed everybody out
of the way right I mean it stayed as a
staple for a long time um and then you
had some you know side stuff coming in
there was a strain in the Pacific
Northwest called Wacom weed you know and
people would go the hell's Wacom weed
what came from Wacom County yeah right I
mean people didn't make names back then
they're like well what do we call this
[ __ ] well we grow in wam County go at
wam weed right and and and that's how
simplified the industry was you know and
I don't think you know throughout the
whole 80s there was more than five or
six drains wow um it was very limited
huh um and they were you get some
one-offs once in a while but as far as
you know Regal stuff right can you get
some weed and it's like yeah I get G13
yeah you know oh can you get some weed I
can get OG kush yeah you know but or
alapa gold or like I mean maybe that was
a little gone by then that was 80s but
they had some Regional stuff like we
used I mean we used to get Mexican weed
but that it could have been from
anywhere it could have been from
Colombia you know I me for all we knew
we got Mexican weed and it had seeds in
it and but there was even some good
stuff some that the higher end Mexican
stuff was actually pretty good you know
you get Hawkin Spears and yeah um that
was good and you know you would get the
blonde Lebanese hash you know would come
in big patties and got you real high got
you really high yeah that's the stuff we
used to smoke with hot knives you eat
the hot knives up on the stove stove I
burned a whole bunch of my parents
knives like that yeah you go to make a
sandwich every damn butter knives burn
where the hell are all the butter no I
just hit them from my parents I I didn't
want them to see any burn kniv I wasn't
I guess I was too stoned I put them back
yeah I would my parents would have lost
their [ __ ] over burnt knives in the door
like I just kept them so then it was
like why do we only have four knives
yeah where all the knives go you know
there used to be 12 there's only four
what happened because you can hot knife
with scissors or with forks yeah exactly
probably could used spoons we never
tried that though oh you probably could
have got away with spoons y didn't L
represented something was uglier never
ran out of knives though never ran out
of KN kep and there's more at the store
if you need them oh yeah had good times
for sure so yeah so let's talk about
your your past with weed in the 80s when
did you start smoking the 70s late 70s
yeah I was about 74 74 wow 1974 I think
I was 14 went to my first concert David
Bowie oh nice um and I was like these
people are cool they smoke weed and go
at concerts yeah and I was sold you know
and from that point on it was Ted Dent
Leonard skinnard get sales pitched
though right you get to concer you see
all these people having fun like how can
you not relate to that you know it's
like I think that's just an easy sell
for a lot of people especially younger
it's like it changes your perspective of
going to Dead shows going to whatever
seeing good music and I think music in
cannabis just go hand inand yeah and if
you remember you know people would stand
up you know they didn't sell you seats
so everybody would get down crowded and
stuff and then you could pass around
fifths and joints and everything because
they couldn't get in there it was too
tight
right and so concerts were totally
different you know I saw lad Zeppelin
from 10 feet away in the Kingdom that's
amazing you know absolutely epic yeah
you know and uh life memories well
cannabis really Tunes you in which is
what I like about the music with the
Cannabis uh smoking getting high on that
level is you really get tuned into the
music whereas alcohol yeah other drugs
alcohol Tunes you out right like but you
take some
psychedelics you take some you smoke
some weed eat some edibles whatever and
get that experience you're tuned in like
you're hyper sensitive to all the music
and the environment and it's such a
great feeling and a great experience and
really they're all experiences and not
one of the experiences are quite the
same like you could go to thousands of
concerts you might have similar
experiences but not one of them is going
to be exactly the same it's like
something that happens in time and it'll
never repeat itself exactly the same
well there's one thing that stayed the
same the old time every girl you walked
into in California was either Bob Marley
or Grateful Dead really every one of
them was playing yeah you know and you
know I got to be a pretty big fan of one
love you know like dude that's our Vibe
you know Grateful Dead pushed our Vibe I
agree The Grateful Dead had a huge
impact on the Cannabis industry yeah you
know still does Marley yeah you know Bob
had his place yeah for sure and the
impact that he's left is just huge right
huge you know and his message you know
his message just never got old right um
you know some of the music today you
know you listen to it once it's like
that's enough of that song yeah you know
I mean I never get tired of listen to
either one of those bands yeah I mean
that stuff's Timeless or lead zeppin or
I agree yeah that music is timeless it's
the still you know in the lead Zeppelin
lead Zeppelin was before my time for
sure yeah me but I still love that music
yeah you know I feel I'm very attached
to that music I Still listen to Le
Zeppelin regularly of course Jimmy
Hendrick Grateful Dead a lot of Grateful
Dead you have Grateful Dead going all
the time there's a hard drive that has
every Grateful Dead song on it right
nice like literally yeah literally all
all the music recorded there's a whole
terabyte of grateful de did you go to a
lot of concerts I did I did go to some
and then dead and Company I've been
going to dead and Company for the last
five years uh my good friend Ben has
been getting me really good seats for
dead and Company and sweet uh you know
my my wife never got to experience
Grateful Dead got to go she didn't get
to go to any parking lots on the lot
there was always adventure oh yeah and
craziness yeah I got to go to I was in
Portland Meadows in the 90s and that was
amazing seeing the dead out there and I
got some crazy stories I'll tell you
later but yeah I mean I'll tell you
heart played out there and was amazing
also I bet heart did an outside thing
and they had uh dog and the Butterfly
yeah it was a big um butterfly that
flapped in the wind behind them the
whole time dude communal showers you
can't go
wrong yeah I mean it was it was an
amazing thing though uh another
community based thing like that was very
Community
Driven uh and everybody was kind of on
the same vibration you oh you talking
about their concerts oh yeah Greatful
yeah like they're almost their own
separate like town like their Community
like it was like its own ecosystem
within their that parking lot and very
accepting of everybody right it was it
was inclusive and not exclusive I think
a lot of the communities now try to be
exclusive and yeah Grateful Dead was
very inclusive of everybody and very
accepting of everybody for for who you
are you're allowed to do your own thing
whatever you want you like you like good
music you're okay with us right yeah I
mean these are people that had passion
for the plant not for the money yeah um
well that's where all this stem from
we're we're here because of that passion
right like at the end of the day started
that's where it all stemm from you know
at some point we all had to make a you
know a living but beyond that it's like
my my passion for the sacred plant still
exists heavily I still am just super
grateful for all the things that have
happened to me up to this point in my
life The Good The Bad and everything I
wouldn't be here talking to you guys
without all mix of all that yeah I I
agree it's you know it's been my whole
life yeah you know from 14 years old
yeah you know I went wow I feel good you
know I'm not all bummed out you know way
I went right I never understood why
cannabis was
illegal because it made me feel good it
made me feel and and once I started
smoking it was like I felt like I was
home like I found my thing and the fact
that they've arrested people the fact
that they've ruined lives it's it's
crazy that it was so accepted to do that
for as long as it was you know and we've
moved beyond that I think our
memories uh unfortunately people's
memories are shortterm they they start
forgetting all the crazy stuff and
people especially the younger guys that
are they never experienced the stuff
that we had to go through uh even in
Grow shops where you had to talk about
tomatoes I mean it sounds crazy when you
think about it like if if you were to
tell people 50 years from now it's going
to sound even more crazy yeah yeah and
with all the bad things happening in the
world why did you put mandatory minimum
sentencing on marijuana yeah I mean
isn't there worse things you know and
it's what well it's the Gateway and I
was like let me tell you what the
gateway to heroin is heroin yeah right
it's not
OD start calling stuff gateways you know
it's like man that first sip of freaking
beer was the Gateway well and the most
most of the people that murder people
they're not smoking weed they're not
smoking weed murdering
cheeseburgers but they're not murdering
people I think the weed Mellows people
out it also makes you reflect upon
yourself yeah makes you think cannabis
isn't for everybody because I definitely
think it makes you look at yourself in a
different perspective and some people
can't handle that yeah right and so hard
to look at yourself it's it's hard to
look at yourself and it does kind of put
things into perspective and that's what
I love about it though that's really at
the end of the day it's like puts life
into perspective you know it puts The
Good the Bad and the Ugly into perspec
perspective yeah and you look at that
last can of green beans in the cupboard
and go man that's going to be good
totally yeah I remember college College
days you know and I used to be a chef
just speaking of college but like before
I was a chef in college we used to do
the wild Top Ramen mixes we all kind of
cheese whz and Top Ramen you got gourmet
dinner yeah I mean I lived in an
apartment one bedroom apartment with
three guys we would mix uh tunic can
with whatever to get the we have to get
that protein I love the you know the
tuna but it's like you got to get
creative sometimes yeah you do where did
you go to college was it up here I went
to diao Valley College in 94 and '95 and
then I went to culinary school okay in
San Francisco San Francisco uh but yeah
I you know it's like uh the bay area has
been great yeah so and we we have this
huge Grateful Dead influence in the Bay
Area too so we've always had that well
People Like Us you're appreciate you
being a steward of this industry you
know somebody's got to take it and you
know open their arms and you you know
make it not such a bad place I'm just
one guy trying to share everybody's
stories you know and I feel like I'm
just this Catalyst that's able to get
guys like you guys on the show so you
guys can tell your story you know my
show is so much bigger than me and I
just try to really highlight the guests
and and get their important stories out
really at the end of the day it's like
we're part of this bigger bigger thing
that's so much bigger than any one of us
individually and to be part of that is
really special and I think the more we
can all recognize that uh you I think it
warms my heart but also it's just I
think it's our duty to do justice to
this plant and do justice to the other
people in our industry yeah and the fact
that you went to culinary school and now
you're creating flavors in marijuana
yeah hand in hand yeah a lot of things
in my life have kind of tied in I you
know I work for Charles Schwab was a
computer uh not an engineer but I was a
Testing Engineer I did software testing
distribution I learned a lot about
business I worked at Bank of America
Charles Schwab back in the day wow and
I've done a little bit of everything I
RI houses in Portland when I was younger
I'll be Dar and uh yeah Portland and
Washington over in Vancouver I've done
so many different things to get me to
this point but they all kind of circle
back into what I do now so even the
cooking kind of goes into with the
genetics and the flavoring and adding
flavors to different genetics and and
what I like uh it's it's this this uh
mass amount of knowledge that I have
that I try to push into my business so
it's a lot of fun fantastic work and I I
I really enjoy what I do so at the end
of the day I really love this I love
being a part of it uh you know being
able to work with great people we got a
great team I just I enjoy coming to work
every day when I don't maybe I won't
come into work but I really love what I
do and I I enjoy the stress I'm one of
those people who believe it or not I
love stress even though I hate stress I
love I feel like stress is what made me
and I'm able to handle stress on a a
higher level than most people and I
function I'm a high functionality high
functioning person with stress where
some people they they crumble and I feel
like the more stress you can put I'm
just I'm not giving up I'm just going to
keep fighting keep pushing through yeah
I found it you know there's definitely
different levels of stress that people
can handle yeah you know um I had the
you know Fortune of working for a
gentleman for 10 years at Sunlight
Supply that I'd never seen anybody in my
life take so much stress yeah and just
chew it up swallow it and go forward
yeah I was like there were days where I
looked at him and I was like man my head
would just blow yeah it's like all the
things are coming at you right now um he
was brilliant he was a genius at what he
did and that's what made that play
successful he built a team that was
second and none and so when he came and
offered you a job he went well I'm
either against them or I'm with them
yeah and it's going to be a hell of an
uphill battle if I'm against them so you
threw yourself onto the team and it was
a great opportunity you know being
surrounded with that much talent um was
absolutely amazing um we used to call
him Stein brener yeah because he he
hired talent for the position and you
know we could walk in and just devastate
environments well that's how cannabis
has changed before you could do it at
your house by yourself have a good
product make a living at it now it
requires a team and I love the team
right so I love the team mentality I
love the thing where it's much bigger
than yourself whatever but like there's
something special about forming a good
team and you becoming
another uh piece of the machine right so
like when when I'm a component the
machine and I have these guys we all fit
into place we all win together we all
lose together there's just something
special about that there is for sure so
have a very nice team too so yeah our
our team is really good but that also
translates to when we work with you guys
or we work with this other company or we
have these collaborations you know and
then we all win together it's like such
a amazing thing when we're all winning
right sure and if we lose we all lose
together we can talk to each other about
it but when we win we win together and
it's a great feeling yeah and it's a lot
easier to win together than it is a part
it is and and we can so there's no one
person that can do it all so finding
people with their strengths and
weaknesses and finding the things that
are going to make you more efficient
it's like those are so important but
yeah working with people that you you
don't want 10 head Growers you need one
head grower yeah you need guys that can
pull families you need guys that can
water you need guys that can do this and
that and then
then you need media guys and you need
the one guy that handles a lot of stress
yeah someone's got to do
it got take that stress and if they
enjoy it it's that much better because
it's like and you know what some people
are like you can't enjoy stress well
it's not that I enjoy stress it's that I
deal with it and I enjoy the outcome
after yeah like and I'm willing to over
I'm willing to wake up in the morning
even when [ __ ] seems like it's falling
apart completely get out of bed go to
the gym and live my life and know that
we're just going to do the best we can
do today even if shit's [ __ ] up we're
going to handle it the best we can Y and
you know and I think that's what builds
good companies yeah I think that's the
best way to go about at least I hope
that's what's building our company it's
like I agree with you on that James yeah
and it's it's a lot of fun you know it's
a lot of fun meeting new people too like
the podcast we do a bunch of different
stuff so it's not like we got the book
we got the podcast we got the seeds we
got all these different things we're
doing R&amp;D all the time so we have all
these different things in these
different directions but at the end of
the day it's a lot of fun and you really
learn about yourself a lot more by doing
all these different things like what you
like what you don't like the type of
people you like to work with the type of
people you do not like to work with
because there's a handful of those right
and the suits you know I can deal with
some suits I don't mind dealing with
business people and I don't mind dealing
with guys that are hippies you know like
classic hippie you know it's like
because some of those guys have the best
ideas and stories and you know it's it's
all about being able to interpret
people's information too MH they're
generally not
overthinkers you get a lot of of of
corporate environment stuff and and they
want to overthink things a lot yeah um
Stony guys are always simplified I like
Stoners because I'm a stoner me too
right been fond of them since I was 14
absolutely and I think that in business
I like dealing with people that smoke
cannabis that use the product right they
that smoke cannabis we're in cannabis
let's smoke if you don't that's okay I'm
not going to judge you on that but
really like we can relate on a different
level if you're also a smoker we can
talk about the flavor of way it makes
you feel and somebody like then it
becomes more than money too right yeah
it becomes something that we're both
passionate about something that I've
dedicated my life to and uh you know
it's it's a beautiful thing yeah I've
never met a person that a grow that
didn't smoke I mean people are in it y
you know for the passion of the plan
usually yeah usually yeah yeah there's
there's I have a couple friends you've
been a couple places I haven't yeah you
know they all go hey we can't smoke here
but we can go over there right no I mean
we're in this we're in this commercial
world now and I have friends that are
really good Growers that don't smoke but
I have friends that are really good do
Growers that do smoke and you know a mix
of inbetween some guys smoke a very
little and but but like I love the way
it makes me feel I love talking about it
247 yeah some of my friends can't handle
how much I like talking about it all the
time but it's like it's what excites
yeah well you know it kind of relates to
the wine industry yeah you know it's
very similar and you know this this is
my forecast I think you're going to see
wine and weed soon yeah right I think
wine and weed is going to be a staple
together because there's they're such a
perfect marriage right it's a pairing
yeah right what pairs with this p o r oh
this indicia right I mean it's a natural
progression you know I actually have a
question on that related to the wine so
like someone said this um your old
friend um about the wine industry
creating like the bill yeah creating
basically the Cannabis industry creating
the same type of thing where there's ter
or there's regions and like uh you grow
the best whatever strain you want up in
Humbolt and then up in sowa county is a
different strain so you think that's
actually oh it's happening it's already
in the process of happening I think it's
a great thing I think however we can
support The Growers that are still still
around in Humble mesino Trinity Sonoma
especially because I'm California all
all over the United States in wine they
have avas uh viticultural areas right
and so in cannabis but based on Tero and
location I think it's great because if
you grow sour diesel for instance I love
Sour Diesel yeah if you grow that in
mesino on the coast as opposed to Inland
you're going to get a different product
same thing if you were to go grow it in
Napa County versus somoma yeah you're
going to get a different product right
and especially with outdoor where you
have one cycle a year it's heavily
influenced by the environment the
minerality all these things these are
all conversations we all need to be
having but then also going to the winery
and tasting right yeah I want to go to
winery and I want to taste different
yeah like where that's grown around the
area and like you go to the actual
facility and get to see it up go some
personal I think that would be a big
thing for the canas industry and the
winery the winery model has already been
established right it's already the the
the brewery models like the the micro
Brewery and the the brewery model where
you do the tasting and you get the tour
like that's already been done like the
footwork has been laid for can right by
the alcohol industry now we just need to
take bits and pieces to make it make
sense for us and to be able to push that
forward because everybody wants to go up
to Humble I I don't know about everybody
but I definitely do and I think a lot of
my friends would love to go to to a grow
especially harvest season where you can
go talk or watch them harvest the plants
and it's like you're seeing the fresh
stuff come down and it's like wow this
is cool or some breeder we got Jackson
uh mean jeene from freeorn I would love
to go see his farm where he's harvesting
his genetics and see his new stuff for
the year where he's either feno hunting
stuff or he's breeding new things yeah
got it you know I mean there's a ton of
guys in the industry where it's like I
would love to go see what they're doing
what they're doing white Thorn Rose we
talk about uh Huckleberry Hill Farms
okay I had yeah yeah I I Johnny's great
I would love you know you could go up
there and you get the tour and you can
get a different version of what I think
is coming but I would love to where
that's you know you just basically have
a reservation just like with the winery
where you get a reservation you call
their number you got the T the private
tasting room tting room you get your
smoking jacket in you know I mean
there's all kinds of ways they could do
it yeah yeah I've heard rumors you know
so in California yeah in California with
this new law maybe that fastpac that a
little bit yeah yeah well they really
need direct sales from farms I mean I
think that's just a no-brainer yeah yeah
I think we're aways from them being
mixed together yeah um but I don't think
we're far away from having them
separated in the same environment yeah
it just makes sense yeah totally and
what do you mean by that well I think
you know you'll have wine and cannabis
in the same environment but you won't
have cannabis in the wine no I don't
want canis in my wi personally I love
good wine and I love good weed and I do
not want any of that good weed in my
good wine I just I think you just
negated both how do you know you didn't
create a better product again we haven't
test it I mean I hope somebody does I
hope they win I hope that person wins
but it's not I'm not going to test it
I'm not even interested I put tobacco in
beer one time when I was brewing beer I
used to I used to brew beer back in I
used to make saki I brewed beer now why
did you put I figured I wanted tobacco
beer cuz you know this is back I used to
smoke cigarettes and I was like and it
was okay like the beer was okay if you
smoke cigarettes but if you you get sick
yeah you would have problems both
ends so that didn't go very well go if
you grab um tobacco with tomatoes it
makes a poisonous tomato I believe it
really it's uh got to be careful what
you tobacco is a pretty strong product
nasty stuff um and it has a tendency of
taking over what it's hooked to oh yeah
um so years ago guy mixed and came out
with a poisonous tomato nice killed some
people not a few people out two Tomatoes
right not a good outcome interesting you
know but everybody's gonna try
everything yeah you know well so if
people are looking to find out more
about you guys where can they
go uh well our website's Horizon
lift.com we're also on YouTube we have
all of our tutorial videos installation
videos pretty much anything that you'd
want is either on our website or on
YouTube at Horizon and left nice yeah
yep we got a great program running with
grow world as well yeah um yeah you know
grow world's a a great company to bring
people together yeah um we've joined
grow world and grow world runs a program
to where you know they'll sample our
product out um capture you know what the
person thinks about it and if they like
it you know they keep it if not they
return it you know so um it was a great
platform you know I've known Nick for a
long time yeah um and uh I appreciate
him taking us on and yeah that's
actually been been nice so we actually
have our first trial going with that we
just signed up with them and we have
someone in Southern California and it's
a great feature right you get a free
lift to try for your first grow cycle
yeah so you know whether you get to put
it through it all of its Paces
everything's done and then you can tell
us how it is and so this is a way that
we can actually get a little more
documentation to by showing people what
they're doing on their weekly grow how
the Horizon lift is so we feel it's a
win-win right we feel like every person
who's going to do the trial if they do
it properly and right they're going to
end up ordering more and it's a sale for
us and if not we at least get to collect
that data and and prove our concept more
we're trying not to do it ourselves we
want people in the industry who are
actually going to be doing it from not a
biased perspective really I mean that's
what I'm trying to avoid well you get
people from girl world the beauty of it
is they're interested in your product
already yeah definitely and so if
they're interested enough to try it and
then they get good results they're going
to or more I think it's pretty their
model's pretty straightforward I like it
I like the other ambassadors on like
myself I'm an ambassador for girl world
I like their products I I the beauty of
what girl world does with me is I can
pick and choose I can I can say yeah I
want to work with this guy no I don't
want to work with that guy U because
there's some products I believe in and
there's other ones I'm like no I I don't
believe in that so I'm not going to put
my name and attach my name to that and
so you know and I think they're they do
a pretty good job of you know filtering
out most of that stuff anyway yeah but I
like that I have the indecision and it's
like because I think uh the podcast is a
great platform for people and fantastic
you know I think I can do uh a lot of
good research and development for some
of these companies and sharing the
information because I'm all about
sharing at the end of the day I want
everyone to win the people I work with
especially defitely yeah generally the
manufacturer is not the pipeline right
you know you've got people that are good
at making products yeah um and the
person that makes the product is
generally not very good at marketing
because they're product development
people yeah so you know you run into
some issues sometimes when you've got
one effort going and you don't have part
of the other effort so you know our
introduction to you and you know the
help we've gotten from you is imperative
um because we don't do social media yeah
you know and social media as we know is
what's happening today we try we're
terrible at it and we're not very good
at it so that's just being honest yeah I
mean everybody has
not as good as you exactly so we are
going to be at MJ Biz together uh you
guys have a booth there and I will be at
the booth every day for a couple hours
yeah nice I'm looking for people want to
come see me and hear about my
experiences with the lifts I think the
videos that we make here in the facility
we'll be there at MJ with you guys yep
we're going to have a couple of lifts at
the show that we're going to be showing
and operating and we're going to have a
par meter with the ppfd reader just
showing you how little you have to move
your lights to drastic Al change your
ppfd that part was really amazing by the
way you know the fact that the very
slight slight movements can completely
change make a big difference yeah so the
other thing that I found interesting is
what one inch of movement can do to
least surface temperature yeah you know
one inch of movement can be four degrees
you know and I'm like wow that is
extremely sensitive yeah you know and so
then you start playing with your
distances and and you go wow here's The
Sweet Spot yeah um so it's been a fun
product um I've had some really good
success with it in multiple environments
um but like we said you know hard to get
the word out I got one last question for
you what are your thoughts on turning
your lights down from 100% to 50%
25% what are what are your thoughts on
well as you know I'm not a lighting
technician y you know um I have seen
some testing done y um and it does not
just equally go down yeah so um in these
units there's multiple drivers and when
you're turning them down some drivers
turn down further than other drivers um
spectrums change um a lot of things can
happen yeah and in no way whatsoever are
am I saying they're going going to um
but the chance is there yeah you know
it's not an exact science I mean when we
started looking at LEDs three years
before they came out on the market you
know and we just kept shaking our heads
going these don't grow plants you know
these don't grow plants um and then
fluence came along and fluence was the
first light we got a hold of put it a
bunch over some plants and went they are
responding yeah they are responding and
so there was the Breakthrough yeah right
everybody went that was the game changer
they broke through yeah right and so now
here comes technology storing I mean I
think 86 manufacturers first show I went
to First MJ Biz 86 rck and lighting
manufacturers one ship 86 business where
those lights are made yeah there's not
86 factories right right so you've got
you know factories making multiple
Lights under different names and you
know there's it's kind of a crapshoot
right now to sort through the good and
the bad um but the funny thing is that
has a way of surfacing itself yeah um
the bad have tendency of fading and and
they good rise to the top right so we'll
see that over the next couple years um
and I think there's a lot more light
technology that's going to be out I
think it's it's the early cell phone
right now yeah um and I think in a few
more years you're going to see some some
really neat stuff with you know
variating Spectrum we're like right
beyond that Motorola flip
phone right there yep we are right there
with a big Motorola phone yeah and I
think it's a you know I think we've made
strides huge strides but we still have
some really big strides to go yeah light
tuning wouldn't be necessary if they had
the right frequency yeah and you know
you've got some other things to look at
going forward you know we're running out
of pee right and you know Coco's
expensive to move what about
cork so I've heard cor you know I don't
know anybody that wants to use it no DNA
I think DNA genetics they were launching
it I can't remember who they were
partnered with but they're going to Cork
cork is a substrate but cork was also
there's like a limited amount of Cork
Wine
industry you know that being said the
growth of the industry is going to have
an impact on on the Renewables yeah you
know you know at some place will out pay
them you know so you used to go by so
yards and stuff and you would see the
big black mountains that have been
sitting there for a couple years yeah um
and those aren't there anymore right you
know they're the the raw material is
moving much too fast um to keep
replenished and you know it's making a
hole somewhere in the ground yeah you
know so I think you know going forward
there's going to be sustainability um
efficiencies I mean there's going to be
a lot of things that come into this
industry and all of a sudden it's like
you grew it for how much um and we'll
all scratch our heads but you know we're
not there yet you know and I still you
know raise my hat to the craft Growers
yeah you know the craft guys are out
there for a reason man they're generally
the old hippies and they're growing for
flavor and taste and and all the things
that we want you know it it's not an
issue of this is the only way I got to
pay my bills right so bless them because
you they're still doing it because they
love it and there will always be those
people I hope the grow this plant just
be out of love Yeah devotion differ love
and keep in mind the craft farmer is is
is having a child and and and he wants
to be you know grower like his dad so
there's going to be that generational
grower that I think we're going to see
for a long time um but you know you're
you see other entities pushing and
shoving and you know changing the game a
little bit Everything Changes you know
you got to change with it that's what
I'm doing a guy from the 80s doing a
podcast you know you got to change with
times this is great this has been a
great podcast man thank you guys so much
for coming on you got it man it's been
our pleasure look forward to doing this
again and doing it in Vegas maybe we'll
get you guys up there when we're talking
at the girl world Booth yeah that'd be
great definitely yeah coming up shortly
coming up just by the time this airs
yeah it's going to be right there
right appreciate it James y thank
[Music]
you thank you guys for watching please
like And subscribe down below
[Music]