[Music]
you
[Applause]
[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the jamesl podcast
and today our special guest is Dave from
preferred Gardens how are you doing
today Dave doing amazing thanks for
having me absolutely so you've actually
been on the show not in person but we've
had your flower on our blind tasting oh
no way no and it went really well
actually it was amazing uh cuz I think
you they were even Smalls and I think it
was the
$108 but uh you blew everybody's mind
everybody that tried it was you know
even the people that were in the room
that smoked it afterwards were like wow
this is amazing for the price um I feel
like you guys do a great job you have
mix light you uh you take pride in your
work and uh yeah I can't say enough good
things about your brand for sure
appreciate it no that's dope I I have
never seen that so I'd love to see it
but yeah yeah I'm sure it was like a mix
light bag or something you guys bought
from a store from cookies okay nice it
was it was really good burned good all
those things that you don't think about
we both next time but that's good I love
that because wreck needs to be put on a
spot a lot more there's a lot of issues
of course with uh stores and not pushing
things and pushing their their house
brands or whatnot and package dates and
you know things that have sited on the
shelf for a long time where people
discount were all flower kind of
degrades right but uh that's dope I love
it yeah I think that's the biggest
problem with wreck today is that the
consumer isn't getting the flower fast
stuff there's a surplus of product and a
lot of times it's not stored correctly
and then they buy it one time and they
don't like the brand they're like oh man
this is garbage but if they looked on
the date it's like six or eight months
old or or even older than that in
certain cases or the you know especially
with joints and pre-rolls it's like you
can't have an old joint or pre-roll it
has to get consumed fairly quickly yeah
there's a shelf life and people don't
understand that it's like what we do now
is we try to we try to you know do our
best to pull things off the shelf and
buy them back if they've sat for so long
or find the specific partners that are
actually pushing and selling through the
weed and they know the time where it has
to get discounted to move but right
California wreck is like a crazy crazy
situation right now it's it's really
hard to track what's going on yeah it's
a beast and it's really hard to tackle
and I feel like so many things were over
looked in the beginning people just
wanted to get their license and wanted
to get product out there and there's all
these things that go along with that
where if you want to maintain high
quality which is what is going to get
people to come back and buy your flow
you know I think it's it's really it's
really Technical and there's a lot of
trial and error that goes along yeah
along with that yeah I think uh I mean
I've learned I've scaled I have you know
decent size grow so that's the trickier
part we got to sell all the weed right
and we want to sell to more stores but
finding right partners that actually
understand the brand and push it in a
certain way it works well so it stays
fresh right they're not over ordering
we're not over pushing you got to kind
of control you know the narrative with
the team and my team's been on it heavy
lately especially well and then how long
do you have ways in house that you you
store and and uh protect your weed
before it goes out there how long does
it typically sit before it goes out to
the consumer so it's it's kind of varies
of course you know it's it's all about
how fast the store moves it but we get
it to distribution and out out on the
Shelf as fast as possible taing in in
about seven days right now it's like a
record breaker wow you know we make sure
we have the testing lined up as soon as
it drops it gets picked up from the farm
drops to distribution third party gets
tested packaged shipped to you know the
distributor that's going to push it to
the stores and it's already kind of sold
wow that's the fastest to get it to at
least to Dro yeah but uh as soon as it
gets to the shelves you never know a lot
of these retailers now they have like uh
dros that are you know like a big chain
will have a specific drro that
distributes the product to each of the
stores which I really hate to be honest
because you can't control what's
happening with that product and when it
gets to each of the stores you don't
even really know you don't have a date
like exact date when it's going to land
on shelf right so we can push or see
what's going on and It's Tricky they're
all you know everyone's kind of of doing
their own thing there's the mom and pop
shops there's the Big Chain shops right
so there's so many variables yeah so
many variables and then what are your
thoughts on on curing because a lot of
people they're like oh some stuff tastes
good after two months I hear that
sometimes I like it fresh but I think
it's cultivar specific as well it is I
love fresh weed yeah is the thing so My
Philosophy is I want to get it out to
distribution and testing a little
fresher than normal like right now with
mix light we use Grove bags I really
believe in the Grove bag you know it
keeps it keeps it it keeps it in a
better spot so you can you can put it in
there a little bit fresher and by the
time it makes to the to the Shelf you
pray that it's exactly where you want it
yeah turp blocks are the best I love
Grove we're doing some collaborations
we've done collaborations with them I
think it's a great product and I was a
jar guy I mean we talk about glass jars
it's like I I use jars my whole life and
you would have to twist my arm really
hard for me to even try the turp blck
but but I tried it and the the product
speaks for itself you know we put stuff
on the Shelf we do AB testing with
everything that was another one we did
AB testing with yeah we tested the
turkey versus the glass jar versus the
big Grove bag like the pound yeah yeah
and I they come in so many different
sizes they have tote liners I mean you
know and I have friends that are putting
Bita packs in with the turp blcks now
and I've never liked the bitas I feel
like they pull TPS but you know it's
just personal preference everybody has
their own little way right so we
normally trim fresh we do put it in a
turkey first then we move it over to a
Grove bag when we think it's right I
feel like when you gets in a Grove bag
it's locked in right it's exact it keeps
it in stasis for the most part right
it's exactly where you have it so if you
get to the perfect cure and you get it
in the Grove bag you're solid for two
months but it's still going to go I mean
if you keep it colder it's better it'll
last a heck of a lot longer but if you
don't then it's like yeah that stuff can
go yeah but how do you control when
you're in hundreds of stores how do you
control which Dro van it goes in who's
using a HB in their Dro who has a
freezer van right which store is storing
it properly it's rare to be honest
summer yeah I mean people talk about it
as if it's not rare but it's rare it's
[ __ ] rare sadly rare yeah it needs to
be you know exactly to get it exactly
where you want it is tough yeah it's
really interesting the model um you know
C California is its own unique Beast as
well it's like going from medical where
it was completely different to to wreck
and then the brands that came I mean a
lot of the brands that we saw were big
with cultivation before you know it's
like those Brands aren't around anymore
you've been around quite a while yeah
for sure because I think I chose so I
had the options everyone in the
beginning had their options everyone you
know cannabis is sexy especially then
all the investors are up your ass
they're sitting at your gate at the farm
if you have any kind of cultivation
license they can get a hold of you right
yeah then that's how it used to be now
no one's invested in cannabis really
right you know not in not in California
it's very rare too it's super rare so
like then I
decided I watched you know a lot of the
bigger guys and I had conversations
they're a lot of my friends right thank
God I had like a lot of this inside
information right that when they got the
$25 million loan when they partnered
with the the people that were great in
the beginning and and the devil in the
end they they it always went bad you
know all the stock deals all this crazy
thing it always went bad so I've had
like probably the biggest opportunities
in my lap in the beginning and I've
turned them all down just because I knew
it was too good to be true yeah I mean I
think that's the best it's like I have
one partner and that's it you know and
we if we fail it's on us for sure at the
end of the day but yeah I had so many
friends same thing probably mutual
friends
that have gotten burned over the years
with some of these deals from whether
it's Canadian companies or big investors
and then getting diluted out of their
shares exactly you know it's it's really
rough you know and I think we're just in
such a volatile industry too it's just
so volatile on on every level um you
know and people are like well what's
next what's next is candy G to go away I
don't think cand is going away I don't
think that's going away anytime soon but
I do think gas and sour and things like
that are coming back I agree I mean I
think they're coming back in small
spurts candy I've I've basically refused
to grow lcgs and and runs for the
longest yeah now that a bunch of people
backed off I put a handfuls of them into
the garden you know but
um I don't love them I grow what I like
to grow I grow a lot of green weed you
know it's it always works for us it just
if it's high quality doesn't matter yeah
we grow Z for sure that's what we're
that's what we want to smoke yeah I mean
I like z a lot well I think OG Kush it's
like you know that's people can't sell
it they say it's just you got to put in
the effort it's got to be the right
batch you know it's not easy to grow you
got to be patient and I feel like it's
not for everybody it's not for everybody
to grow or to smoke I mean I feel like
the high isn't for everybody some people
can handle it yeah I'm not going to grow
10,000 pounds of of Z or OG cush but I
grow a good amount yeah and I mean I
would grow that stuff just for myself to
smoke too because that's what I like you
know I love good OG like that piny
lemony gassy earthy that's what I like
yeah and I sell all my own weed for the
most part so like if I truly enjoy it
it's pretty easy for me to sell it you
know so if like it's a batch of OG or Z
or something and I'm very proud of it
I'll put a high number on it and sell it
easier than a candy that I don't like
and I'm like yeah you know if you want
it you can buy it yeah but when you do
mix light too so you're on a different
level completely and your mix light is
competing with indoor somewhat yeah well
I think it competes with it especially
with flavor yeah mixl light I think is
the future it always has been that's
that I'm I'm known for mixl light mixl
light is the hardest to grow too also I
feel you know it's like uh controlling
that kind of environment is a big
challenge now at scale I have a positive
pressure Greenhouse that's even more of
a challenge I bet you know looks super
cool but God that thing's a [ __ ] every
day well in those kind of green houses
people don't understand they can be more
expensive than indoor grow yeah and
don't they yield less they no one no
one's hitting the same yields they hit
in an indoor facility in a greenhouse
like that it's just it is what it is you
can't control the environment perfect so
you know it's cheaper to grow yes right
more efficient yes it's more natural yes
it's better weed yes
yeah yeah and then uh what's your take
on Coco soil rock wool ston wall
whatever you want to call I'm a Coco guy
I mean I've grown in everything I mean
deep water culture every single thing
rockwool I still do Trials of things all
the time you know I trial different Coco
too I trial Pete Moss was like my
favorite for the longest yeah but at
scale in my opinion cocoa is is the best
like a one gallon cocoa B Coco bag is
you still get almost the same control as
a rock wo cube right but you have a
little bit more forgiveness there yeah
run you run a good lean crew you can run
coco no problem and not have an issue
yeah I mean I feel like Coco is the nice
mix same thing you you mix light cocoa
you're right in the middle with the with
the soil and the rock wool and you're
you're getting the Best of Both Worlds
and you know I have no problem we use
Rockwell for certain applications here
you as far as Nursery applications I
think it works course yeah and same here
but and then soil I really love the
flavor of soil you know when it comes
down to flavor but as far as if you want
a product that yields really well and
you know I think the effect of soil
might be a little bit better but you can
get amazing tasting cocoa you can get
amazing effect with
Coco check the box there's just so many
variables there you know and every
facility is different in Florida we use
rockwool yeah right because the head of
cultivation is is a rockwool guy and he
can steer the [ __ ] properly and the weed
is phenomenal yeah right the best
Rockwell weed that I've ever had for
sure is out there in Florida and we did
Coco at first and it you know it's not
his thing he's so used to steering with
rockwool I'm not gonna be like hey you
have to do Cocoa in my rooms yeah and it
the wheed is super fire and it gets you
super high and it has mad flavor and
it's undeniable so we use rockwool there
and certain facilities I've used
rockwool and had you know better results
it's just the environment was different
and you know there's so many different
factors it's hard to really pinpoint why
right soil too you know a lot of people
argue soil is the greatest you know and
I've grown in a lot of soil and had
amazing batches but for me like overall
Coco has been the best like overall
overall yeah for sure yeah and you know
I got away from Coco because the first
time I used Coco it came in these bricks
and you know we got these bricks and I
had to break them up in a kitty kitty
pool with the shovel oh yeah and I was
like I'm never doing this again I hate
this stuff and now like 20 years later I
ended up going all Coco I was using Char
cor yeah um and I've tried Cana Char cor
I'm doing trials with K right now but
you know yeah we're testing out some uh
some cocoa with pearlite too you know
like a 7030 mix yeah I I like the 7030
mixes I think those are good I feel like
the the dryb backs are good on them very
good yeah so yeah and then even we we're
doing some trials with moms using the
Big 10inch Blocks so you know I'm trying
to compare that to Rockwell to really
see what the difference is I mean I feel
like with Rockall you have total control
you get perfect dry backbacks uh it's
very consistent uh but I feel like
there's more of a buffer with Coco so
we'll see we'll see where that goes yeah
with Rock Wood I mean you can really
steer every inch of it oh yeah and I
love that factor but there's always in
in like a large scale facility for
instance my Greenhouse is 50,000 square
feet so and there's a large Bay like 18
20,000 Square ft Bays with Perpetual
Harvest inside so something goes wrong
you get some sediment in the line or
something we're letting lean you know
you can't just take out all the drippers
mhm you know figure out what's going on
and you got to have a little bit of
buffer also we did trials back toback
indoor I did tons of them with rockwool
slabs Rock wo cubes right cocoa one
gallon Coco two gallon different brands
of cocoa you know twice washed chippy
cocoa ground up cocoa and what I got the
best flavor from is what I'm really
looking for as flavor of course or
weed's going to get you high yeah um was
Cocoa yeah nice yeah so you're working
in Florida you're working in all kinds
of other states as well yeah yeah how's
that going it's going great I mean not
all of it is great but it's like when
you find the right people to work with
that's that's what really matters it's
it's amazing I mean we're really
successful so yeah if that's what we're
shooting for it's that's working right
um and we found out you know certain
Partners not to work with it's just a
lot of like learning happening right now
I feel like like it's so early still in
the game that we don't know what's going
to happen so doing licensing deals
Consulting Partnerships in other states
right we got to try it all right for
sure yeah so with Florida what are some
of the challenges you guys faced over
there I feel like they're still medical
medical yeah I mean that's the biggest
challenge they were supposed to you know
was about to pass wreck everyone thought
was had to be like a 60% Vote or
something and it didn't happen right um
that would have been huge for us but I
kind of like where we're at right now
it's working really well right but it is
medical and you have to get a medical
card and a medical card cost $0 and
something dollars everyone's on a budget
it's harder to get a card in Florida
it's not like California how it used to
be so there's a lot of challenges where
people want to get our product but can't
um but also there's still a good amount
of people that do yeah it seems like
there's some really big Brands and some
really good brands that are in Florida
you know some California brand and you
know it's it's and some guys that are
transplants that have moved there and
they're doing really good sunburn
cannabis I talk about them a lot yeah uh
peab he's over there people for sure
hell yeah so yeah and I mean I think
it's exciting they're all about the gas
they're all about the green weed they're
all about the green weed I love that I
love I know those guys they support us
too which is you know this Mega
competition it's way more competitive in
other states especially the east coast
is what I've noticed like California
we're all collaborative right like you
have your own grow I got to grow we're
not trying to kill each other at all
we're all trying to help each other
boost up right it just depends all day
yeah and I'll like you can give me some
knowledge I'll share some knowledge with
you no problem gentics yeah a lot
different right it feels like companies
are way more Cutthroat and there's a lot
more money being thrown around and and
it's kind of a monopoly in places like
Florida so it's kind of understandable I
guess it's more business you know but
Florida has like a serious culture
there's a lot of like good smok out
there Growers and people know their weed
yeah honestly it's our best Market
better than California well they used to
get their weed from Colombia and Mexico
and now it's being produced there yeah
yeah yeah pretty amazing yeah I'm
partnered with the flowery out there
though so I don't know if you know much
about them but they're they've just been
nothing but amazing partners and like
really great people to work with and
that's been I opening to me to want to
do more and more projects other places
to meet people and you know collaborate
like that yeah collaboration's key these
days it's like it's so hard to make it
by yourself but then collaborating with
other people you could both Brands can
help lift each other up I mean there's
and there's so many ways to collaborate
there's on the genetics level like we do
I feel like working with with
cultivation Partners uh you know we're
we're working with flow Gardens in hemp
in uh Tennessee nice we're about to do
some big projects with them Eric was on
the show a little while ago green houses
uh he's indoor okay he's indoor doing t
not a great place for green houses yeah
yeah yeah yeah but but they do really
good quality stuff I feel like that you
know it's like working with other brands
that are like-minded is always great um
and then when the focus is on quality I
think that's the big thing that's that's
the big thing and everyone that does
that which is kind of a smaller Circle
you know because the big msos they have
the option to do that they have the
money to like hire the people
Consultants or bring in like good
Growers that care but a lot of them have
like a different mindset and a different
game plan and there's no problem with
that because it's all about just getting
money whatever they need to do to get
money it kind of makes sense it's it's
expensive to grow like fire weed it's
very challenging right so do they want
the headache of that right now when all
their weeds selling anyways it's and
it's easier and it's cheaper for them to
sell right it's just a business model
you know so I I can play I play with
like I cons I'm a consultant too you
know because I've been growing for so
long and I can like help facilities turn
things around if they want to get to
Quality right so I can sit in the room
with these suits and I know like a lot
of them are cool people too sure you
know to be honest but their mindset is
how do we get the most money out of this
because they're trying to build a
massive company right now and maybe in
the future they'll convert their
facilities to a higher quality but right
now on the sprad rad sheet it
actually better for them to just sell
weed right mid quality is important I
mean my focus is always on quality but
I'm also genetics right so like genetics
you have to have the best quality I so
competitive I mean you even do your own
pheno hunting yeah for sure and some
breeding I mean s1s f1s I've been doing
that for years too pheno hunting is my
thing though I've been feno hunting
since I first started growing yeah I
started with seeds you know what I mean
and all the all the homies the bigger
breeders and stuff too would always send
me I was the tester guy right you know
and it's like I just love seeing new
[ __ ] always yeah every one of my
facilities has an outrageous amount of
feto hunts going on at all times I just
know how important it is it is it's so
important moving forward and to find new
things that kind of resonate with people
and just because I like something
doesn't mean everybody else is going to
like it but I think I have a pretty good
hand on the pulse of what everybody
wants to and I think that there's a lot
of alignment there I mean it's like with
yourself it's like after you've done it
for long enough you understand quality
and I can appreciate quality but there's
so many different things and it's very
subjective very and all of a sudden you
know wedding Cake's no longer popular
yeah even though it's even though it's
fire especially right ice cream the one
thing I just don't understand there's
ice cream cake gets a lot of hate it
yields too much so everybody grows it
and then there's an abundance of ice
cream cake and ice cream cake is amazing
especially the rosin from ice cream cake
it's a winner you know in my opinion
it's also a good breeder I think it has
a lot of breeding I made millions of
dollars off of ice cream cake so and on
it yeah people trash it online and it's
so funny it'll come back it's all you
know eventually it'll come back once
like the MSO started growing it that's
what happens and then there was a ton of
mid ice cream cake yeah I mean throw
punch away but keep the ice cream cake
for sure yeah kill kill that one kill
the fake turps and it's like there's the
Oreos and the purple punches that have
made their rounds too and like m i you
know I think they're one one good cross
from away from being good I think like
you cross it with the right thing there
good potential yeah I agree I think we
shouldn't get rid of them I think they
have they need some power give them
power they need TS put some C in the
moros yeah so some GMO some chem some of
that yeah some of that dies I agree for
sure and people like it and the and what
PE like all right this is how like we
look at things right now we're a really
small team we have like a lot of like
close meetings but we're looking at
things as in the wreck market and all
these other states and everywhere else
right we have this heady Circle yeah
that we all we can think of is This
heady Circle right this 1% not even 1%
of the market yeah then there's this 99%
that loves weed but they don't know weed
like we know weed right right they're
going to buy the Oreos they're going to
buy the and be happy with it and be
happy with it and they're going to get
high from it even you know but like
we're so [ __ ] heady and stuck in this
1% that we can't break out of and be
successful with this 99% yeah go to a
dispensary and do an event we do them
all day all the all the time so we we
have data for days I've had dis I've had
delivery services we know what people
are buying right right it's not what we
think like us right here we know too
much yeah we have to find people new
people in weed to test them out yeah
test them out figure out what they want
look at the companies that are Mega
successful that actually grow good weed
it's just like pretty it's smells good
yeah you know what I mean but like the
Mad heady like Z no [ __ ] chance yeah
it's all Street weed it's yeah it's the
Trap weed or whatever it's the Trap weed
it's the 1% yeah they'll pay the most
for it but it's not even 1% it's not
even 1% so we all need to be successful
somehow and figure out how to merge this
99% with the 1% yeah and we're pushing
it as much as we can I'm in this circle
where we can kind of dictate what's good
and what's not in the he side yeah right
we can say we can bring up a strain a
cross or whatever it is and a couple of
guys that you know I'm with can say it's
amazing and it's amazing right but only
in that heady Circle not in not in what
really matters in the in the stores so
who's successful in the stores I look up
to that too yeah it's really a challenge
blue dream blue dream crushes it we just
dropped blue dream and it [ __ ] sold
out in like two seconds I'll have to
show you some of my blue dream crosses
that I made that are very blue dream but
also something new I feel like yeah we
have dream candy and we have different
fenos and we're kind of renaming the
different fenos because we have one
that's really candy but it's very you
smell it and you're like it's straight
Nostalgia blue dreams fire it was the
same thing msl's got a hold of it it
pumps out four lbs of light with your
eyes closed outdoor there was Millions
and millions of pounds you get sick of
everything but when it was still craft
in small where only a handful of people
had it it was top shelf that was so loud
it's got so much flavor sticky it was
sticky the buds were perfect you didn't
have Smalls everything was we grew Blue
Dream for like a long time yeah had to
call it Platinum Blue Dream because
everyone had blue dream totally then it
lasted another year and then it died
yeah it completely died yeah Sour's
making a comeback though I see a lot of
people growing sour again I'm excited
about that I love sour it's something
that I've I've Loved for a long long
time yeah Sour's great yeah it might not
have the best structure but uh the the
back in the day some of the ugliest weed
was also the most expensive weed cat
piss was the ugliest it was like when we
got it it was shreds in a bag and it was
$60 an e all the way up yeah for sure so
before Instagram before people had to
see what it looked like New York
dictates a lot honestly and that sour
was like I started from soil you you
know in outdoor in the Hills so it was
Sour like when all my sour was sold you
better find the neighbor sour you know
what I mean because New York would just
eat everything alive somehow whoever was
getting it in Sacramento or whatever I
guarantee was getting to New York
because no one really cared for it in in
Northern California that at that point
yeah and it's still I mean I'm sure they
still want it back they have that taste
for it they do so I I was just came from
New York actually and and I just pulled
a bunch of data stores flowery and
partnered with them they have they're
going to be like the biggest chain in
New York they have like five stores
right now they're going to have eight in
like the next two months and then 10 or
11 real soon they're they're just good
yeah um but what's the top selling skew
of flower is sour I don't know if it's
real Sour I doubt [ __ ] it's real Sour
but it's sour name yeah I just started
seeing real Sour come back it's like uh
you know we had one of the guys on the
podcast Dave from bud budalo and then my
friend Josh he's growing real Sour again
and it's like in California and it's the
real real Drew green dog had a real Sour
for sure yeah and then uh we we were
growing a a sour bx1 that definitely had
like the sour smell and structure but it
wasn't it it's hard to say it's been so
many years so like we're always like
that's not it that's not it's not the
same I wish I had some here to show you
because when you see the real Sour again
you squeeze it you're like oh that's
it's
unmistakable what real Sour is once you
see it again if you experienced it for
enough time in your life yeah just like
super Cil Haze and stuff like that I got
some of that here actually I love super
silver me too yeah Crush I love some of
those yeah me too I Crush I love that I
love the TPS on that I love the strength
of it and maybe it's not the first thing
I go to every time but I love the flavor
yeah it gives you some anxiety I mean
now it just depends on what you like but
it's better than candy yeah some of
those good hazes you got to switch it up
I feel like they have amazing candy out
there but like it's just it's it's just
one thing we it's just one color in the
whole uh I think people like candy
because goes back to New York too is uh
it cuts through a blunt for some weird
reason even even if it's like not great
yeah and it it doesn't even have a great
smell or nothing yeah you taste it
through a blunt better than you do
through a joint well that's why a weird
strain tped weed people it's cuz it's
those blunt smokers yeah with the grabba
and they're mixing tobacco with the with
balance and yeah that TP weed that
shit's garbage though yeah I mean I
think czy the concept it's like oh well
they they TP uh carts and it's like I
wouldn't smoke those either it's just
not my thing but it's like the top mover
and people are making you know $5,000 a
pound for that stuff and it's like it's
cool whatever like no I mean like the
carts oh yeah yeah I don't know what's
going on I don't stay I don't even
listen to the TP sprayed [ __ ] cuz that's
I want native CH most of it's probably
poison you know who knows what the hell
they're doing with most of it some of
it's done right I know there's
facilities that use like some crazy
machine to do it but you're still
smoking some something weird that smells
like bubble gum I'm straight I'm all
about the Rosen carts I I I didn't like
carts for a while I mean I go back and
forth with do I like carts do I not like
carts but the Rosen half gram carts
that's I think that's the magic number
right there is half gram yeah and good
Rosen carts are amazing and I feel like
it's a more natural product uh the cryo
trimmer I don't know if you've seen that
but they have the resonator does a cryo
trimmer where they pump liquid CO2 in
and I hate trim machines I absolutely
hate trim machines and then I saw this
the other day and I'm I've heard about
it for a long time and I don't believe
anything till I see it and going and
seeing the demo it changed my mind uh
for a trim machine because I'm I'm just
so anti you still got to finish it by
hand but it does a really good job and
then you can actually press rosin from
the Keef you separate they have they
have bags to go on so you can separate
your different layers so you have your
200 Micron your 150 and your 50 and you
can capture the 50 to 150 then press it
and it's a pretty good Rosy yeah um you
know and I'm not endorsed by them or
anything I just think the products is
really cool and especially if you're
doing some sort of hand rolls or
pre-rolls yeah yeah I mean there's
there's a place for machines too yeah I
mean there there is Big scale large
green houses that you're not going to be
able to get the quality you need out of
if you're doing pre-rolls if you're
doing like cheap half ounces and you you
can't make a margin off a hand trim I
mean it's the biggest expense in every
cultivation facility is the trim for
sure you can do 400 lbs a day and I
think the trim it cost it ends up
costing you less than $20 a pound yeah
crazy it's crazy that we've gone that
far yeah i' played with the Mobius a
million times and a bunch of different
facilities I it's like the best of that
from what I've seen of that situation
but I [ __ ] hate trim machines for
sure I mean they're they [ __ ] it up
every time no matter what when this
doesn't cut it it actually has a net
that looks like like fish uh like
fishnet that women wear and it's
stretched over this thing and it gently
tumbles the stuff and it knocks the
leaves off and we looked in the
microscope before and after and then I
smoked the weed I mean we're sending lab
results in now to make sure that like
we're not losing anything off it but I
think my friends are super stoked on it
and I think potential for it great yeah
I'm glad you said that because I I'm
licensed in uh Pennsylvania and they use
am Mobius because they it's just so hard
to get employees out there MH and they
use a Mobius right and testing results
it's so weird in every state right
testing is all [ __ ] for the most
part no one's really like landed the
proper testing yet to this point there's
no consistency but there is consistency
in each state for whatever that
consistency is if you know what I mean
right so if everything's hitting sub 20%
for the most part coming out of this
trim machine so I had them do some hand
trim pass in the hand trim stuff yeah
scope it of course there's a lot of
heads knocked off from the trim machines
yeah and there's damage and there's
there's also like chunks of leaf stuck
in the bud from the from the trim
machine right and they're doing super
light pass a little hand work on the
outside and you know the most expensive
trimmer or whatever the Mobius yeah and
it's test results are much better when
you hand Trim in Pennsylvania just FY it
was just something that we did just to
see if it you know totally and it's kind
we kind of hit trimmed it too just to
try to not touch it as much as possible
right and that was we got better results
from that yeah it's interesting all
these things coming online I mean new
technology comes out every year I
haven't seen a lot of innovation in the
last little bit I mean other than
lighting yeah under canopies has been
probably the biggest Innovation and
cultivation that you know I have friends
in green houses that over this winter
are just using under canopy with the low
low ppfd from the Sun and they're
getting really good results yeah hell
yeah for sure I under canopies in my
Greenhouse now yeah um I'm a huge
believer in underc canopy lights as much
as I [ __ ] hate looking at him you
know what I mean totally I love those
faven you know it's like uh yeah Tim
Bobby bags yeah yeah he's great those
are the homies yeah and I mean the game
changer right there I mean the under
canopy for yield especially and I think
with LED lights you're getting more
purple now on the bottom than you're on
the tops mhm yeah it's not even not just
the bottoms that you benefit from that's
the cool thing about under canopy and
the thing that people don't even really
understand about it is the yield comes
from the top yeah it's the plant is
absorbing light and it just even if you
stripped off everything on the bottom
you're going to gain from under canopy
lights yeah and I think more lights
different Spectrum I like the red less
labor less labor I like the less labor
Factor so you're only pulling fan leaves
and you're not having to completely
clean out the undercarriage yeah I think
that that'll save you some money and
over the period of a year five years
that can be significant yeah we did a
lot of research you know we' we've had
them for a long time at this point I
don't know couple years you know when
craft farmer first kind of dropped them
faving like right at the same time we
did them all bunch of side by sides and
stuff honestly it's more labor for us MH
because I wasn't like a proponent of
like heavy de leafing and you know
stripping anyway anyway yeah I was not
to an extreme I found the even medium of
having less plant count right you know
gaining more getting higher yields from
less plant count still having my solar
panels on the leaves if you look at my
plants they're always pretty full for
the most part I don't believe in like
stripping the dog [ __ ] out of them
because I did it for so many years and
when I did side by sides with less
plants and leaving them alone a little
bit more I got better results wow in
quality in yields all the way across the
board like non-top plants mhm but uh
it's more labor for us to do the under
canopies but it's so minute yeah that
and you get such a gain from it that it
doesn't matter wow yeah and more
nutrients more water use more
dehumidification there is things you got
to consider for sure but it's yields are
way better the quality is the same if
not better yeah same if not better I
would agree so per 4x4 how many plants
you put typically nine right now at most
yeah yeah yeah we're doing nine too I
mean I think that nine is a a sweet spot
yeah a lot of guys do 12 15 20 one PL
per square my buddy that was doing
Skittles was doing 25 to get three
pounds of light yeah and you know and
that's cool for what he more issues come
with that for sure now he's doing under
canopy and I think he uses nine and he's
getting we do like six in Florida six
plants per in Florida and every nug is
perfect yeah my buddy you know what I
mean when you do that every butt is
perfect you might you might lose like a
little bit of yield but every piece of
it is like perfect pble totally it all
depends on what you're what you're
trying to do if you're if you're pushing
bags like turkeys yeah then you might
want to put a little bit more plants but
not too many where it causes it depends
on what your calculations are on
dehumidification HVAC all that how's
your room setup but um package Goods
less plants is way better because you
can package like every bit of it right
you know that's that's huge yeah I think
the biggest part of cultivation where
people screw up is their
dehumidification they don't get enough
for sure so I see that time and time and
time again always and you add a du and
you try and you're out of
power still not enough and then yeah
that's normally the problem yeah I mean
it used to be the guys with the
reservoirs in their rooms and wondering
why they couldn't dehumidify their stuff
properly it's like you got to pull that
out bu rot and everything yeah yeah that
was pretty standard like 10 years ago it
was for sure it's evolved a lot I mean
shout out jungle boys to be honest
everyone kind of took what they were saw
what they were doing took that and try
to better it now it isn't evolving much
from there if you know what I mean just
like you said like what's what's the new
innovation in this space is not a ton
everyone's so [ __ ] busy right though
like every
second every second counts so how do you
we've thought about it do we want to put
energy into these things well like we
got to put energy into the brand we got
to put energy into the grow when you
stop putting energy into the grow yeah
you're totally [ __ ] so totally you
know is it worth like putting energy in
these other things it's a lot to
consider yeah I mean I like the Light
Lift I think that for dialing P ppfd you
know we used to use yo-yos and so it's
nice to be able to have it on iPad where
we can bring it up and down yeah it's
cool I mean it's another trick and toy
it can do I mean if you if you do the
proper research it's worth it for sure a
lot of people just have light lifters to
have them because it was kind of cool to
put them in in the beginning DPS was
putting them in a lot of these big huge
massive grows and they mango has his own
version of The Light Lift yeah I'm sure
he's doing his research like he's all
about that so like if someone did if
someone's will if you got someone to put
in the work and spreadsheet it out and
see if you can get you know an extra
five grams of square foot and it's worth
it all day then you can move them around
and it's worth like the the headache of
you're going to have to fix them here
and there it's just another piece that
can break too exactly exactly so I don't
I don't build them with them just FY but
maybe I would if you if you prove to me
that it was worth it you'll see the data
here soon enough I mean and then also
with the faven and versus the faven and
also combined with the faven so we'll
have both we're going to do seed
production on that as well so I'll be
able to get some numbers on what kind of
seed production that we're doing and I'm
excited about getting my numbers up
really high I mean we're at 50,000 seeds
per light for 4x4 now we're talking see
now we're talking about something
different that no one really thinks
about much other than big a but in
cannabis who's actually like oh this is
how many seeds I'm getting per square
foot I've never I've don't think I've
ever heard that yeah with autoflowers
it's like we do Autoflower seed
production too but it's like we do photo
period and that's it's very cultivar
dependent but with autoflowers I'm
getting really high numbers across the
board and it's like how high can I push
that gets me really excited because you
know it's like with the indoor
environment you can really control
everything yeah you do it in a
greenhouse you can you can almost
control everything yeah you can't
outdoor you can't control any of it you
can get pollen from somewhere you you do
an
acre in the middle of a regular season
more than likely you're going to have
some sort of cross-contamination
somewhere MH yeah so depends on the
county depends on the region depends on
a million different things if you want
to grow it for cheaper you would
probably put it in like a mix light or a
greenhouse facility right yeah it but it
depends on the volume you need if you
can push through that amount then you
need to get as much yield as you
possibly can per square foot right
exactly with seeds and they're going to
be quality seeds you're going to get
really good quality seeds and the the
favin and I believe this is my first
time running favin with seed production
but I believe we are going to get even
seeds from top to bottom typically the
stuff on the bottom they're not as nice
as top yeah you get lighter seeds and
then we got to separate them and all
that stuff so if I can get even seeds
across the board I mean I think that
could be a big game changer smart I love
that that's uh that's cool I like new
[ __ ] that's the thing with me in
cultivation and all that is that's why I
feno hunt so much because I wouldn't
grow weed if I couldn't feno hunt to be
honest if I can't see a new strains like
on regular basis yeah and I just have to
grow like [ __ ] acre of candy mhm it's
not for me I'll go conso do something
different yeah no it's so hard like why
not you know you could if working
working this hard you could you're G
make money doing anything right yeah
yeah I I feel you especially if you're a
hard worker you can go to almost any
industry and figure out how to make it
if you can make it in this industry with
as hard as this to work oh yeah for sure
but and there's something special about
seeing new stuff stuff and that's not
the stressful part either finding new
stuff it's like I find weird stuff I get
I get excited about the strangest things
you know we had one that smelled kind of
like vomit and and it's like so
disgusting but at the same time you want
all your friends to smell it because
it's so out of the box the thug pug all
the thug pug work before he'd always
have like some runchy like weird
smelling stuff that was either like like
rotten chocolate or totally that's cool
different turps would be awesome
everything's kind of like what's new now
you know there not a lot of new stuff
but there there still come you know
we're still seeing new stuff I think
we're going back to the drawing board
with some land race varieties and and
basically germinating him here and then
taking them out to everybody else and
seeing what we can do with them but uh a
lot of stuff is like we get so
bottlenecked especially in the United
States like candy candy candy everyone's
got to have it has to be candy and it
has to have
color I mean that's great for the people
that like that but there's so many other
things that you can share I love like
Florida yeah they [ __ ] know good weed
and they they like green weed more than
they like candy and purple weed to be
honest that's where the turs are too
like [ __ ] yeah they like stuff they just
like turps that's the main thing I feel
like they want it to taste crazy yeah
and it doesn't matter like like citrus
is like probably most popping thing in
Florida wow so and C was like dead it's
the least yeah Jack Herrera is the least
like strain in California I would say h
yeah and it's also something I really
like if it's done well yeah um but a lot
of these guys that are newer they never
got to experience the good Jack because
you know in the 90s and the early 2000s
there was amazing Jack herrer there was
amazing Jack crosses Jack Flash that was
some of the best [ __ ] I ever seen in my
life yeah small badge people cared for
it real Farmers putting in the work and
actually like focusing on their plants
now when you know the msos are growing
massive amounts of Jack it's going to be
hella mid Jack and all they're going to
be able to get at store for cheap is
Jack that sucks right but it smells good
regardless I mean it still smells good
yeah wind XE smelling Jack yeah H yeah I
like I don't like the high that much but
no I don't I don't either from Jack but
there was um I can't even think of the
brand that's down in La I think they're
still there but they have their own Jack
Herrera and it's it's not it's funky
Jack it's like nose burning but like
really high on that trinoline limine mhm
and like like a haze but it's definitely
that cleaner like where it burns your
nostrils every time you smell it it goes
to burn your nostrils and then the high
from it was really strong Jack typically
didn't have a strong high like
especially the stuff I see now yeah but
Jack Flash it was like this funky lemony
amazing stuff and and it looked it had
the bag appeal and it was so sticky you
could take a you could thumb a bud onto
the wall you know yeah that was so that
was the good times California kind of
[ __ ] that up with the smoke ability
and the burn and the you can't have like
cracked out stick weed that you can
stick on the wall is not going to ignite
the way that you want it to ignite at
this point some of that stuff won't even
go through the grinder you know it
sticks to your grind that's how the
Florida weed is right now so like uh
Brian out there he's just [ __ ] super
heady grower yeah and this guy Trent
he's he's like the Cure guy so like when
there's a cure guy who's focused on
[ __ ] dry cure like this guy is it
changes the game yeah right and the
[ __ ] weed out there you we stick it
to the wall all the time like whenever I
get my samples I'll be in the hot Hotel
I'll stick it to the wall I'll leave
I'll come back it'll still be stuck to
the wall yeah it's crazy that's when you
know it's good that the thumb test yeah
but that's that comes with a lot of
babying right and it's 100,000 foot
facility how do you like burp bags 12
times a day and make sure like check the
exact humidities and make sure and
you're in a challenging spot too and
like near Miami like the yeah outside is
ruthless well that's the beauty of the
tur loock I mean they basically eat up
CO2 they they absorb CO2 through the
liner so now you don't need to burp them
anymore I mean that's but you still you
bring that outside in in Florida oh done
and it's done even the tur block stands
no chance you know what I mean the the
best thing there is stands no chance but
a jar way worse it gets crushed like
that like that yeah yeah so you brought
some interesting flour today yeah I
brought some flavors for us to sniff
through I don't know if you want to look
at some things now here's the the mix
light Z that's in a big competition
right now I don't know if you're
following along let's talk about that
proper doinks competition I think that's
popping off really quickly proper doinks
those guys are all about their indoors
right like highend indoors and they they
have never supposedly had any like mix
light or outdoor or any sungrown stuff
that's been any good at all that that
burns you know they like things that
burn clean they specific thing that
they're looking for they're they're
really [ __ ] good with with like what
they're you know what they do and what
what defines quality to them at first I
was like I'm an old school kind of
farmer guy at first I was like [ __ ]
these guys they don't know what they're
talking about now I'm like these guys
know what they're talking about honestly
and they're they they stir the pot a lot
which is kind of like important to do in
their space yeah and they're also very
strict about what they like right and
it's and they're not like we're homies
and they're going to be like this is not
it trash everyone like they'll bring on
all their friends and it's all batch to
batch so you're going to get clowned
here and there and you got to be willing
to take it and it's kind of hard for
people to grow weed well you guys are
having fun with it too it looks like um
you know and then you got the thing it's
with be easy right yeah so uh someone on
X said have you ever tried Dave's mix
light they've smoked a bunch of my indor
you know and certain things they love
other things maybe not so much cuz it's
probably like a a stickier more you know
what something that I like a little bit
more is maybe not what they like yeah
but I was like yeah I got some I just
got back from New York I was like I got
some mix light for you guys right now
and he's like you want to go up against
some indoor Adam said that and I was
like yeah of your choice pick the brand
yeah and then he's like what strains you
got and I was and I heard they had this
Z competition I was like oh actually I
got some Z mix light Z and they're like
oh well Bey put $110,000 on his mix
light or his indoor Z yeah up against
anybody I was like done let's go we want
to prove that mixl light is just as good
if not better than you know weed is weed
is weed fire weed is fire weed I've had
outdoor that's mad flavor smokes amazing
totally I've growing it mixl light I
stand on pretty heavy I feel like it's
it's the most challenging weed there is
where people think that it's like depths
you know but it's I think it's the best
of both worlds indoor plus is what we're
kind of talking about because it we have
HPS lights right we have environmental
controls we're we have benches drippers
we have everything that indoor facility
has that I grow indoor too everything
that my indoor facility has but I also
got the option of the Sun so I got
another spectrum that you can't you
can't mimic yeah right so and sun does
something special so let's go you know
what I mean [ __ ]
that I I stand on a lot of mix light
honestly some batches I would choose
over indoor any day yeah I'm a huge fan
and I feel like it's the best of both
worlds in it's also the most economical
and best as far as like if you want to
indoor product it's better for the Earth
we wasting yeah there's a lot of pluses
there but we don't even need to talk
about that in a competition like this no
not at all for sure but now everyone's
you know oh you're putting mixl light in
I could beat that all day 10,000 10,000
10,000 they just messed me it's at
60,000 I love it
yeah that's amazing Dave actually won
$60,000 in the proper dinks contest now
back to this episode with Z I feel like
Z is one of those ones where the turps
really you know it's like we were
talking about Coco versus soil Z
especially the soil brings out something
special you know feel like Z you can you
can get these different expressions and
it's very noticeable some of the
genetics out there you don't see as much
uh with the the different uh substrates
and the different uh lights and stuff
like that Z is very noticeable with each
one yeah I was wondering because Z was
probably breed outside yeah in soil
right under the sun mhm right and I was
thinking about that when you just said
the seed thing and I've always thought
that there's specific like things that
need to happen with breeding too like if
you're breeding under LEDs and you're
pheno hunting under LEDs and you're
choosing things under these because when
I feno hunt in my Greenhouse at now I
can kind of find tune and figure out
what I think will do well indoor but it
always isn't the truth right and when I
feno hunt indoor it's so controlled that
everything's [ __ ] good yeah right and
it doesn't have too much variable and
less like hermaphrodites happen a lot of
lot of things happen when you have like
that controlled of an environment I love
feno hunting in a greenhouse yeah
because of tomorrow it's freezing balls
next day it's raining there's no sun
it's cloudy you're stress testing at the
same time all day yeah so
I wonder with breeding though because
you know I've always bred in like a
[ __ ] shed or outside or in a
greenhous like a shitty Greenhouse right
right but I wonder with breeding if
there's going to be some adaptations
right there's going to be some things
that it's a baby it's it's used to this
right and it's not always going to work
in that way and when you feno hunt it
this way I know for a fact for sure
hunting for sure yeah and I think you
know it's like if we're doing stuff so
don't even use that seed start I get rid
of the seed start and I take a clone and
weo hunt starting with the Clone right
so I don't even I don't want to know
what that seed start expression looks
like if I can't have it it's not even
the same strain uhuh you you clone it
and we're we're looking for stuff to
license we're looking stuff that we're
going to take clones off of I want to
know what that looks like but now if I'm
gonna sell the seeds for outdoor
production like flower production I want
it grown Outdoors where we're feno
hunting Outdoors where we can go this
one's this good for this reason or this
one because it's totally different ideal
of course yeah that's ideal so you're so
when you pheno hunt you pop your seed
germinate your seed you germinate it in
a substrate or you do it in a towel or
put it in water what's your process I'm
curious because you got a lot of seeds I
want to know oh yeah I mean I think it's
different depending on what we're doing
but typically with pheno hunting um if
they're from somebody else I'm going to
take hydrogen peroxide and I'm going to
do a six to1 ratio with water to
hydrogen peroxide and then I'm going to
take that and I'm going to soak it in
there typically overnight
peroxide it sterilizes the seed so I
think that it can kill a lot of bad
stuff yeah yeah but we basically take
that and it gives it a little bit of
Head Start you're working now with a
clean environment y right and so we'll
go into uh rapid Rooter root Riot so you
like it in a clone plug right away I do
like it in the plugs I feel like it
works the best when you go into a plug
you can control it better and then once
we have a roote shooting at the bottom
then it goes right into wherever we're
going got it yeah so and it's pretty and
then you take one clone from you build
the mom up for what 20 days or 30 days
maybe even exactly depending on the
cultivar some go faster some are super
vigorous and we could take them in two
weeks you know but typically it's you
take the top though and then you take
that top you plug that top you root that
top then you feno hunt with that top and
a lot of times we'll go till we can get
two clones we won't just take the top
yeah so you might go we might go a month
we might go five weeks depending I like
to get to three yeah found that in green
houses was stabilizing for some weird
reason maybe you can explain why MH
first cut well seed you're going to have
way more hermaphrodites than normal it's
going to be a different plant it's it's
a beast the weed is different it smokes
different smells different everything's
different about it it's pointless to
feno hunt with the seed in my opinion
yeah the the first
cut I find that I get a little bit more
not stable things happening also from
that top right right second cut might be
the same as the third cut but I just
have a process of liking to have the
third cut be the feno hunt yeah well and
we do cut from the third for we fenal
hunt that one as well but usually from
the second we start there for the well
so from the first cut we can start there
and then from the second and third uh
but you will get sexual maturity so the
plant is going to change over time yes
and you will get more uh Expressions
hermaphrodites stuff like that uh pheno
you know gets more stable kind of over
time or it doesn't if it's going to be
that what it is you'll find out and it's
going to it's going to be that solid
expression then you get for a longer
amount of time what you're going to get
Forever After that's how I feel is what
it normally is is what you're going to
get forever off of that third third
sometimes third generation yeah the
third and fourth clonal generation is
where you it stabilizes I've randomly
had things like Herm for since they
probably had they were in the spring
they probably had a nice environment and
then winter came came around and they
hered out of nowhere you know something
that was still kind of early range but
normally like if it's stable it's stable
for the most part right yeah the one
exception for pheno hunting from seed
would be if you are selling seeds to be
grown out in a field so if I'm going to
sell 100,000 seeds to somebody I'm going
to want to know what a hundred of those
seeds or a thousand of those seeds do
when we put them outside uh and so we
will put them outside and grow them out
test them that way I feel like if you
are going to sell your seeds in bulk for
someone in Morocco someone in Germany or
wherever wherever it is and you're going
to sell them and they're doing outdoor
field production you really want to know
what that does outdoor in the field yeah
so that's the not many people have those
options and I think you're kind of ahead
of the game so it's like that's probably
like you're talking some some scientific
algebra right now to some people that
are doing but that's the right way to
you that's what they do in a too you
know I mean I think uh but but for what
we're doing where we want to license
aeno or we want to sell clones of
something it's obviously that's the best
way to do it yeah yeah yeah for sure
yeah but it's hard to have that option I
feel like I'm one of the only people
that has an indoor an outdoor and a mix
light right well and so we work with
cultivation Partners all over right so
we work with people in multiple States I
have guys that are just itching to test
something new because we always have
weird stuff or fun stuff or different
stff people beg to do that it's awesome
you put it put it in the closet too it's
like cool to give it to those people and
they find stuff and we have a ton of
people to love hpe it up yeah but yeah
that third and fourth clonal generation
is really where it's at and so we'll
grow it out and I like growing things
out at least three times before we run
with anything because we've seen stuff
that it's amazing and then the next time
it's [ __ ] and then it's amazing again
and we've also seen the opposite where
it's not that great but it's it's still
it might not be the best of the best but
we grow it the second time and now it's
the best yeah and then we grow it again
and oh wow it's the best again even just
on its own it kind of just like picks
that to get to production it takes three
kind of rounds anyway so like we always
do the test the second test is like you
might start with three plants then you
get up to 10 plants then you before you
get to 100 plus plants exactly you don't
want to go too big too quickly with
stuff and and the other thing is is what
I like sometimes isn't what everybody
likes um I get excited about some weird
stuff and you don't want to put that
into production you got to see what kind
of response you get from people too yeah
because you know I'm jumping up and down
about this new thing because we've never
had this before and it's like this crazy
floral thing that I think is going to be
great but then you give it out to guys
uh you know guys like Freddy you know
that they have like the the amazing
palette Freddy big big shout out he's
one of the guys that gets to see stuff
before it even goes out and he's the guy
who he's got a palette too he has a real
pallet and he's some of the sometimes
he'll be like nah that's I don't like
that that's not it and I can't sell it
maybe if it is it I want one bag yeah
you know well and he's just super honest
about what he likes and he knows what he
likes very black and white like I like
this I don't like that that's the circle
I'm talking about those type of guys
dictate what is good and what isn't for
sure you know and it's you have to have
them around or you're just blessed to
have them around like thank God they're
around you know what I mean give them as
much free weed as you possibly can
exactly yeah my guy from hush same thing
he has like this he's the pickiest
person I know and you know he works with
Beezy and those guys too it's all part
of the same circle of of connoisseurs
yeah you know and these guys are so
picky you know on the way it burns and
the way and it's like yeah the stuff
looks good and all these things but when
you roll it in a joint it just doesn't
burn quite right yeah and it's like to
me it's some super gr a triple AA a plus
I love it but it's like for the streets
maybe it's not what the streets want
yeah everybody's different that's the
thing is everybody's different and like
they all have different pallets and when
you get to that 1% that most extreme
palette sometimes they they [ __ ] it up
for everybody you know I mean like some
[ __ ] is actually really good and it's
amazing for the market and it's has like
the most medicinal Factor yeah and we
think about that a lot too cuz we're in
the medical Market again started in the
medical Market in California in the
medical Market in in Florida now in the
medical Market in Pennsylvania like it's
the same Market as before and people
like treat the weed like it's more like
medicine which I like you know there's
reasons for certain strains that are
extra powerful and they take away pain
and we start talking about the effect
more I mean I think even in it's still
medicine but we're calling it wreck or
whatever like whether you like it or not
it's testing medicine right so 100% so
and I I love that about it but I feel
like the conversation needs to come back
to like how does it make you feel you
know it's like how how does it taste
yeah that's great but how does it make
you feel at the end of the day is it
something you want to keep smoking all
day long and you want to wake up
tomorrow and keep smoking that because
then you're on to something for sure
yeah that's what Z has done that for a
lot of people I feel like Z still does
that for especially like business people
they're it's like something that I don't
know it's like a upper echelon love Z
and it isn't I think that they would
like it anyway it's just it's the
feeling of Z it isn't NE yeah it tastes
great but the feeling you get from it
yeah is the best and you like you still
be very creative and it doesn't like
knock you out either which is a plus
when you're trying to run like hundreds
of employees and doing other things you
can't just smoke hella OG you know my
lawyer used to my lawyer my lawyer yeah
those guys are whack jobs yeah guy used
to smoke only OG yeah and that's all he
would smoke and he would smoke it all
day a lot of people are different
there's some people that are like the
most successful ever and their brain is
like two wired and they need something
to crack them down yeah just weed is
weird and it works with everybody
different that's the thing it's so funny
because yeah the effect can be
subjective to the individual mhm always
it is every time yeah let me smell that
Z you have right there this is that's
the soil grown Z huh this is the dirty Z
I think that'll win you harvested really
let's put this in right now we need it
let let's make it
70 oh yeah how big of a sample do I need
because I really think e an eighth
that's it yeah you call them right now
you got
10K because I need I need another I need
another 10K I bet you do I don't know if
you want to I we can smoke this right
now yeah for sure no this is this is
smells amazing yeah and this is the old
batch is okay I was wondering yeah when
was it Harvest is yeah so this is from
November right so it's a couple months
it's still good Skittles is one of those
ones but the funny thing with Skittles
is when it's done and it's dried it is
the best right away it's one of those
ones there's like I like some people
like oh two weeks you need two weeks on
it maybe for the smoke or whatever you
want to say but I think that it's the
loudest you open a bag of Skittles
that's like just freshly trimmed and
dried perfectly it pops like nothing
else yeah yeah you know it hits you with
that candy yeah for sure especially a
pound like a pound bag a turkey bag yeah
TPL loock bag and it just punches you in
the face and I love that about flow and
you don't get that with a lot of the
stuff now where where it hits you in the
face like where like literally it sticks
to your face that's that's the main
thing we hunt for is is that but yeah
you're right and there's a lot of
strains that people like want really bad
that doesn't do that which kind of sucks
you know I don't know if you know Mark
from Green shock but uh he had some it's
called the double Lantern and it's
outdoor and it was the best out I saw
last year by the way big shout out to
Mark hell yeah and it was gassy in he's
out here in California yeah he's in
Grass Valley oh Grass Valley is cheat
code that's like the best spot to grow
dude it's so dry if I had a greenhouse
out there game on so I had I like
Growers out there too people like oh
yeah they're all about that life yeah my
Christian's out there he's a man I love
Christian Christian I love Christian too
he's a good mutual friend of both of
ours you know he's amazing I've known
him for quite a while and just a solid
dude oh yeah um but yeah my buddy used
to he had kickass Farms was his brand
but he used to do stock splitting where
You' grow the plant up and You' split
the stock with a buck knife we've done
that yeah you can only do that in like
some weird kind of super cropping yeah
dude it basically you don't need to top
your basically it does the it
distributes the hormones evenly across
the plant and you get all these extra BR
science though that's what I'm still I
still don't know I think it's a real
thing I mean I saw his plants were huge
too he'd have these big 10 Pounders with
all the small buds rather than one big
and they were like big trees yeah that
was the best for outdoor he used to also
water his plants from the top in the in
the a no in the morning he'd water them
from the top in the bottom in the
afternoon he'd water them from the
bottom to cool the canopy got it and he
was doing that all the way into flower
and I I'm like shaking my head like what
is this guy doing he's got he's
reversing the magnetism of the water and
you know it it was pretty wild and he
grew some of the best flow I've SE
Grass Valley and ESP special because
Grass Valley is so dry if you tried to
do that in Humble or in Mendo on the
coast you would be toast you would have
the worst rot yeah for sure with all
your breeding and stuff you're pretty
heavy on
like Vigor and you know mold resistance
and all those things even a major factor
yet for for sure I think commercial
viability is extremely important
uh although it's not the only thing
first I go over the other things then
it's like okay well I have a lot of
people that are like I need something
that's commercial it has to yield for
one thing these guys and I have some of
my best stuff doesn't yield right some
my favorite things don't yield yeah this
[ __ ] dude this this thing although my
friend gets over three light with
Skittles Savage so but he also does set
up dude the secret is seven we the [ __ ]
out of seven we he does a preeg in a veg
we're about to crack the code we're on
to something I think yeah we're working
on cleaning it somehow I don't know
we're just playing around with whatever
Weird Science we can do yep but uh I
know some people that have that are
doing pretty well with it but I don't
know if it changes like anything in the
quality that's my worry but we're we're
going to over veg it now yeah over
vegging topping it and then keeping it
even I think keeping the canopy nice and
even yeah yeah we'll see I don't know
patience and I think every environment
is a little bit different where is this
Z grown this is some special stuff
growing in the city SF can big sh yeah
for sure yeah I know they kill it so
we've been working
on
collaborations and uh I love organic
tips that's my my choice I don't like
the glass tips personally glass tips are
okay but I I prefer the the bamboo yeah
I mean these guys are the homies we we
uh we do these joints in uh Florida too
but yeah paper wise what do you prefer
paper wise elements are my favorite I
have some OCB XLS right now I mean
they're they're cleaner I think they
look like like when you roll them they
look nice and super tidy elements don't
stick that well it's one problem that I
have with them but I feel like they burn
the best in elements I do too I like the
you know if you you know we Tri we Tri
all the different papers yeah and I feel
like elements burned the best they do um
I didn't have OCB in the trial really uh
that was a year and a half ago these are
probably the the expert double XXL this
is probably the one that goes up to them
the best yeah I know proper doinks and
them just did like some weird tests with
it and had some problems with them but U
I don't know they're they're good most
of the rollers use those or elements
yeah you know we got Mike and Main I
don't know if you know them they're on
the squad they're a professional rollers
they crush it but they mainly use those
ocbs yeah we work with hustle Hawaii
professional joint roller to Instagram
Chris he does amazing stuff but then you
know I'm a fan of Bruno rolls and yeah
Bruno's dope cgo Sacramento has all the
best [ __ ] rollers Growers everything
it's just like a lot of headyy [ __ ]
going on in Sacramento yeah I like sack
yeah we stand on I'm born and raised so
nice Sacramento is uh is home but it's
pretty cool that it's become like super
[ __ ] famous for fire weed and dope
rollers and you know a lot of culture I
mean people got a lot of [ __ ] from the
police back back in the day like they
were no joke in Sacramento they were way
harder on people than everywhere else I
agree for sure they're electric not like
not like the East Coast those in
California it was pretty [ __ ] up uh
for sure SoCal you could right around
1,000 PBS would get pulled over and get
a ticket yeah when they were [ __ ]
taking people to prison NorCal was super
weird it made no sense over there
whoever the power company is they were
basically working with law enforcement
people I know yeah tell me about rated
but for that same reason yeah and it's
like I mean we obviously PG Oakland it's
like they don't they don't give a [ __ ]
they don't give a [ __ ] want your money
hell yeah pay the bill as long as you
don't let it lapse like once or twice
then then you're hot then you're hot
yeah but yeah NorCal is different
I'm glad you noticed that because uh I
felt like you can get away with whatever
in SoCal and La for a while oh dude the
warehouses people that's where the real
Warehouse CRA right yeah thousands of
Lights yeah literally thousand lighters
you know people were way before anywhere
else in the world jungle boys jungle
boys and they were doing it you know
scale
quality really kind of pushing pushing
it Forward setting the ground for it
yeah showing it you they had a million
followers before anybody else too on
Instagram thank God they did though
because I feel like we wouldn't be
here doing that if they didn't do it you
know for sure been a journey it so where
is it going next you going uh hon yeah
so I'm in the morning I'm going to um
Portugal to look at a facility yeah so
I'm like last last second yeah it's all
GMP
certification so I feel like from what I
understand yeah is everything if you
want to get producted like
Germany and you know the EU for the most
part it has to go through Portugal yeah
so I'm trying to figure out uh P who
needs help in Portugal because that's
where I'd like to you know make my way
out there from uh from Portugal so I'm
going there in the in the morning
actually nice yeah it's a good time to
go I think Portugal's hot right now I
think I think a lot of people paved the
way so that Portugal could happen I
think Greenhouse was in Portugal I think
they're still in Portugal but yeah you
probably have your finger on it more
than me because I feel like with the
seeds and you were doing stuff with a
lot of those guys that are out there in
Europe and oh yeah so like we have a
name in Europe and people have somehow
found a way to get our products in
Europe but we don't really have a place
there yet so you know we're going to
spend some time out there we were going
to do spannabis but I think we're going
to do Mary Jane
will be at Mary Jane for sure I should
be at spannabis I love I love
spannabis but I'm excited for Mary Jane
yeah yeah I didn't go last year I missed
out on Mary Jane I got fomo yeah I heard
it's it was the biggest and best totally
so that's why we decided we're going to
do like a booth and go yeah we'll
actually be with uh Grove well we're
doing we're doing an activation out
there we're be doing a big seed drop we
yeah so we'll be doing dinner parties
and lot fun stuff so dope so yeah let's
uh let's link out there definitely yeah
good people cuz that's like our first
time being in Europe oh really yeah well
yeah it's you got to go to Barcelona you
gotta Amsterdam Barcelona those are the
places to go for sure if if you go
before after at least one of them yeah I
hear it's a must yeah Amsterdam's still
experience oh yeah it's all getting shut
down in Amsterdam for the most part or
no I wouldn't say it's getting shut down
I'd say it's not what it used to be same
thing with Barcelona Barcelona used to
be just popping like crazy you could go
to a restaurant and roll a joint up and
nobody would blink twice yeah now you
can't really do that you can't be
smelling like weed everywhere you know
they'll they'll mess with you a little
bit more really uh compared to 10 years
ago but they do have social clubs there
they do you know both places you know
they have coffee shops in Amsterdam they
have amazing coffee shops there they
have amazing Social Clubs in Barcelona
oh yeah uh and people are really
passionate about cannabis they have good
you can find good flour in both places
if you know where to go so and there's
all kinds of great
food forward to it I feel like this
stuff is extremely special it's two
months old we're smoking the old stuff
so you can get an idea on what it would
taste like if it was super fresh indoor
grown Bay Area indoor grown Bay Area how
big are those batches they're small
they're small small small batches this
is not grown at scale this is grown
Boutique s after too what's that I know
it's sought after G the second there's
it doesn't even sit it's
gone it might be so good you might not
want to smoke
yours oh yeah no but I I love the
competition and I love the friendly
competition you guys are doing with
proper do I feel like posting it all on
Instagram and I feel like you guys are
having really fun with it yeah I mean I
got uh Phil Emerson on the team we're
[ __ ] good no one wants to no one
wants to start that [ __ ] want to mess
with Phil no one wants to start [ __ ]
it'll cook you up in a second but yeah
the back and forth is great yeah so yeah
and I believe you know there's there's
some guys that take themselves just too
seriously and I feel
like you know it's like we're just
having fun exactly I agree because we
should be able to have those
competitions and talk [ __ ] and all that
and that's part of it you know no one
needs to get butt hurt ex it's all in
good fun yeah hell yeah no one needs to
throw punches yeah good weed is good
weed I'm sure all the Z is good
one of them is going to win yeah for
$110,000 I we can light them up side by
side well 10K buy it not everyone can do
that you know yeah got to be pretty
confident and at least stand in a chance
right yeah you got to be really
confident throw 10K and something like
that yeah 10K is 10K I don't care how
much money you make yeah not everyone
has a batch at the right time is what it
really comes down to in competition
exactly is who has the batch at the
right time who's the best that day that
day exactly and it could be like who
everyone thinks is like the smallest or
shittiest grower I mean that would be
cool so Alfred Master Yoda told me this
a long time
ago uh when I won my first Cannabis Cup
yeah he said and I was in Amsterdam in
2012 and he said it's it's not always
the best it's the best that day that day
you know and
so some of these guys that win it's like
at least with the fair competitions you
know what I mean like the real ones
which I think are getting better and
better I agree I mean I like the reason
I did it with them is because I I like
how they judge things too I know that
they H they have a pretty distinct
palette and it's
extreme what they think about quality
and I've seen them dog like their own
person who grows their weed I've seen
them dog their own weed online so like I
trust
what they do they do it in your face you
know what I mean for sure you're
addicted to the soil Z though sound oh
this stuff is super special you'll be
addicted to it too the second you taste
it you you smoke a lot of OG and Cam and
I smoke a lot of everything but I like I
like Skittles I like OG I'm smoking on
some crippy right now that's like a old
school OG cut yeah yeah it's gassy
what's your favorite though cat piss but
there is no cat piss anymore but yeah if
if I had to pick my favorite thing in
the whole world that'd be ciss when the
last time you had it a long time ago and
I've had so many imposters over the
years and it's like the ciss I remember
was a I would say it was super silver
haze was was in ciss that I had you know
but it had the worst structure and it
was ammonia and skunk and it wasn't
gassy like OG it was like straight skunk
tenth of a gram would smell the whole
room up and it's unmistakable you know
cat piss was fire then a lot of strains
were fire for I feel like the TPS were
better then not better but right more
distinct from grow to grow yep because
everyone wasn't using [ __ ] Athena or
whatever the whatever the hottest the
cheapest salt brand there is I feel like
that's a big play on it and you can only
get so many different substrates I mean
it's cool to see some soil but I you
know at scale that's a little tough to
be able to steer and and you're going to
be super batch to batch with soil that's
the one thing I would say yep
okay I got this down about a half inch I
think it's the best part yeah I want the
neck
bone we got some decent Ash we got some
really good drip feel like this thing is
dripping like crazy for flour yeah and
for Skittles a lot of guys their
Skittles don't drip yeah
yeah well that's you I think I feel like
you can get an oil ring on anything or
I'll take this yeah
yeah it tastes great T pretty good right
for sure hell yeah yeah and it's burning
kind of dark like in between you know
but it tastes really good I like the
fact that it's burning not not bone
white and tastes good
yeah if I would have rolled that a
little tighter it might burn a little
wider but yeah and the thing is is this
is going to air after the proper dinks
yeah yeah so definitely like it it's
good
nice but yeah the ash isn't perfect I
definitely get critiqued on the ash on
this one guarantee yeah I'm not 100% on
that always I mean I oh [ __ ] I just
lost but OG's from back in the day we
didn't care about the ash as much I
didn't want black ash I don't think that
would be like weirded out maybe but it
was like ash wasn't a qualifier with the
stuff we used to smoke and I've been
smoking since the 90s we've been rolling
big joints since the 90s you have to
hold that on the
paper nice looking Ash nice smoth
burning clean yeah you got a nice drip
yeah it's got the it's got the ring for
sure I mean you can get the ring out of
everything I like smoking inside that's
a big factor yep smoke that
outside it's going to be more peppery
and less uh resiny I
mean see why you're entering this this
is great yeah
it's hard to go Z side to side and just
pick you can tell me I'll I'll let you
do the talking on this one but I think
they're the flavor
profile yours definitely looks better
and it's it's turpy but it's
hard going to compare Z to
Z good smooth it tastes
great and it's burning dark that's the
funny part yeah it's got a lot of turps
though it does
yeah similar for sure I mean it's about
the grind and the tightness and all the
things too is the trickier part
interesting concept though yeah but yeah
we need proper in them on the on the
show to actually to have them tell you
when and why you know yeah they be like
yeah you didn't Ru it quite tight enough
and TPS wise they're both tppy
yeah yes
sir hard strain to beat the funny thing
is with the dirt Skittles it's so
[ __ ] strong and Skittles is you so he
pulls around between effect effect yeah
and turps obviously but with effect
Skittles is not normally strong yeah
yeah right I think probably when we
smoke these two it's even going to get
us more high for whatever reason but I
get super high I get super high from
mixed light more than I do from my own
indoor of the same strain I get a lot
higher from mix light yeah I don't know
why but I do get higher from it yeah and
this dirt is the first time I've got
Skittles in my entire life that was both
strong and turpy where it was like candy
because usually if I want it strong I
could go day 63 yeah yeah but if I want
a turpy I want to go if I Want Candy Day
51 day 52 day 53 do you know when that
was harvested it was on day 53 yeah
that's kind of right around the range I
think
yeah LED HPS
Led Led and you know the thing is is
like I think a lot of the ogs growing
under LED aren't very good I've seen
some lately and I'm just like not that
excited I've seen a handful of stuff
that's like CMH HPS yeah it's awesome
but the LED ogs just don't cut it for
sure I uh I think it's too intense so
like with OG I have some OG here it's
like you almost got to put it on the you
got to put it on the edge of a grow yeah
or in the back corner or you know what I
mean you can't if you put that [ __ ] in
the center right it's going to blow out
it's going to lose turps it's it's OG
mhm it's icky it's going to ask for
things that you can't give it in the
middle of the room right if you look at
OG wrong it's not going to be the the
best OG batch that you had yeah I got I
got this cut from Christian oh nice yeah
Christian knows really good weed he does
for sure he went through the feno hunt
with me too here that we just recently
did oh yeah that's really
nice it's OG it's definitely OG that's
un I don't even see OG like
this that's why I wanted to give it to
you I was like you're you're going to
respect that yeah because there's a lot
of OG crosses and there's a lot I don't
know just not many people are growing
like original OG like this dude this
definitely checks the boxes on the White
Ash you got nice clean burning good
burning really good got a good drip
burning even burning even it's got It's
got the resin yeah right definitely it
definitely I mean we're halfway down and
it still tastes great that's when you
know it's like the further down it gets
if it still keeps tasting good collect
the check seriously you g to put this
one in though I mean you you definitely
get critiqued on Just burn but they they
roll I think with flavor it stands a
chance against anything dude like that
flavor if I wouldn't get knocked for the
I would enter it except for I I think it
would win on flavor but it feels it
feels strong too you know what I mean
like it has some good expansion for Z it
does it's uh it's good I like those guys
too so I know it's I know it's coming
out of a clean facility that's an
important piece you know what I
mean yeah it's hard smoking stuff from
other people when you don't know what
the [ __ ] they did with it or who they
got it from I prefer not doing it I'd
rather it's like we're we mainly smoke
our own
weed we we're qcing so much that it's
like really hard to get a hold of
everybody else's weed yeah which but we
do it we got to be sure that we're
standing up to
people that are doing well and making
noise that's you know that's the main
reason I feel like California everybody
likes sharing their stuff too like we're
super inclusive uh and I mean there is
exclusivity but also between in the
circle it's like yeah dude you want like
let's smoke you're in that's the thing
that's what you have to do it's like a
it's like a mandatory
thing for sure and everybody likes
showing the weed sharing the
batches I mean you can really tell a
person by their weed too like who walks
around with weed what kind of weed do
they walk around with I think yeah at
least the forward- facing people that
smoke it's like they have good weed on
them it's it's usually an obvious one
for sure these are
uh this was something from a hunt that's
like a skittles cross where it was like
a mystery
strain
also permanent marker times candy fumes
nice I bread this feno hunted it chosen
really nice do you like perm I do I did
some breeding with it with the grape
soda that I got and super dominant it
when all so dominant perm everything's
perm we got some really cool purples
with it too that was one that was like a
little bit lighter on the perm I felt
like but it's fire strong too I got
Perman marker double Lemon
Cherry purple marker zbx this is the
snacks this is like a candy gas nice my
boy first class if anything's candy
that's about as candy as you're going to
get for me it's not that candy yeah yeah
first class genetics did a permanent
marker headband that we feno hunted yeah
headbands like that's that's my go-to I
can get a hold of that cut yeah 707 yeah
because we had the OG cut in the bay and
then I learned the 707 is like sour and
OG whereas like the the Josh D was also
renamed headband and so there was an OG
cut of headband
yeah G's got some fire dude he got real
fire for sure he's with us in Florida
dude that's
amazing um dude this is special this is
like bubblegum this smells like straight
up bubble gum but it's if you get in
there it's gassy it is it's a little bit
gassy but dude this is like more bubble
gum than the fake bubble gum stuff that
was going around I mean there's a strain
bubble gum and this is way more bubble
gum than that and it's super powerful
that's like the most medicinal strain we
have
honestly this is some of the be this is
not even some of I would say this is the
best smelling thing I smelled this year
D we're only in January but this smells
[ __ ] amazing yeah we're only in
January literally we're only in January
hold that though we're gonna hold that
you know and I'm a big fan of uh coffin
candy and 11 coffins yeah those are dope
dude those guys yeah it's
like yeah this is special I can't quit
smelling it but the coffin candy is a
Duke of BB yeah DOA right good breeding
hella good all of his shit's great I've
pheno a ton of his stuff fire M for sure
that is Extreme
special what else do we have the Z yeah
you got through them all OG smoke the OG
you tell me I will I will I'm big on
OG OG's one of those ones when I get
good OG just like I mean I've gone
through the sour kick since I got I got
a personal stash of sour a nice big bag
of it that I've been tapping into and
damn you have that here I need to test
that out I have that at the house I'll
have to get some for I was supposed to
it was in my shoulder bag and then I
left that and I left my my super silver
the two Sour's like disappeared from
what I saw it's all kind of diet sour
you know it's like you don't see a lot
of good OG or sour anymore but I mean
I'm seeing it here
yeah
um yeah so this is that Florida cppy cut
DN tuer Wares but we go to Old School
Tupper
Wares just my personal right now my tur
blocks are I think they showed up
not bad right oh yeah that's dope and
then this is our from our pheno hun
right there uh that
is S1 of the cookies oh no way yeah and
I think I have a I have a big huge jar
from back in the day that my friend gave
me from a cut that I gave him it's sorry
D I get that high and I'm like off the
mic I'm off my own mic here that a mix
light dude seriously that stuff is
strong
and I think just the combination of two
different RS but I think this is going
to make you come back this year I think
this has potential yeah hell yeah no
people have been people have been
begging for some cookies honestly some
and people the cookies I've seen is all
just like it's hard it's hard it's a
hard strain to grow now too like I've
had uh I had the thin men and it was
just like honestly it's a struggle in
these type of facilities wow it's kind
of like OG you know I don't know if you
got to what you got to do with it but it
doesn't grow I grow like I used to grow
the most fire cookies for years and
years and years and that was like my
thing when cookies was popping we had
them but in the big facilities it's just
not the same yeah really tough yeah I I
low light level low EC it's just missing
something you know what I mean so but
it's a lot of trial in ER I bet you
could get it it just would take time
yeah yeah dial it in yeah I miss cookies
back I mean now it's back but I I missed
it for a long time it's been a while
since I've really seen any good cookies
so well let's hope you have it let me
get that cut oh yeah we can definitely
work something out we got we got we have
other fenos too so nice yeah excited and
so I have one more question for you MH
if you were able to uh give your younger
self one piece of advice what would that
piece be work harder I guess I don't
know that's just what I'm like blue
collar work [ __ ] get it done you know
what I mean so just that just that alone
it it stands out for everyone especially
nowadays like people are getting lazier
and lazier so get back to the old way of
working and getting it done the younger
generation man it's insane yeah so if
people are interested in finding more
out about you where can they go social
super rough right now honestly our
website gardens.com is the spot to be
honest so you can get a hold of us
through that y my main social has been
deleted for the last two months I feel
like it's probably Gone Forever you
never know though it might get it back
uh X is good for social but you know I'm
not as in tuned yet so as soon as I get
dialed in I should be able to figure it
out right U but our website that's the
best spot to get a hold of us nice well
thank you so much for coming on the show
today uh yeah look forward to touring
your farm getting you some genetics
we'll figure some stuff out H yeah thank
you for having me
absolutely thank you guys for watching
please like And subscribe down below