[Music]
so we're here day one in spanis I'm at
the Greenhouse Seed Company Booth with
dust he over here we got the greenhouse
guys we're having a lot of fun we're
signing books we're selling sceds it's
mindblowing this year spus is crazy
there's so many people here you know I I
haven't been to a spab buus this this
crazy in at least 10
[Music]
years
hey hey
hey
he
[Music]
so we are here at Spirit and I'm with
Simon from Syria seeds he's one of the
big Inspirations for this book I want to
personally give this book to you and I
thank you so much for all you've done
for the industry you're a real breeder
there's not a lot of real breeders in
this whole building and you're the one I
live up to the most wow man that's
impressive thank you for sure yeah yeah
and thank you for the respect you were
showing in the book for yeah absolutely
you've done so amazing work over the
years and you're very humble yeah and
you a lot of these readers they got this
ego but you know the real deal
so b
c there you go thank you man you're very
welcome thank you yeah I'm impressed all
right thank you again thank you Dan so
this is osar from greenhouse and Strain
Hunters friend you also took photos of
my book man some of the most iconic
photos in the book were taken by this
guy right here thank you so much you I
really appreciate every you know like my
brother I'm really happy you think they
are good enough to be there oh your
pictures the next level the I mean your
eye what you see stuff is so amazing
than I'm so blessed to be able to work
with you Bel one more huh yes for sure
appreciate
[Music]
that
James uh what was it 4 months ago we
were sitting on our couch in beg is was
crazy yeah that was good well and you
just came out with a books finally
they're out I told you it was coming out
you were prising it to me and you're
bringing it here cannabis breeding I've
been waiting for it for four years I
think yeah yeah I was I saw you were
coming out with a book on I got to get
that book of James there's no way I'm
not going to get that go you know so um
it's great to see you how's everything
going how you been it's been fantastic
we've sold out books pretty much through
the day I think we have like three books
loud be tomorrow we have more books
coming it's it's just a little surreal
so yeah the all spis event has been
great we won best podcast of the Year
International cannabis Awards cool
that's man I really love your podcast
really great show I love the whole setup
you put so much passion in it really
great Stu I love it we love it it's it's
a team effer we have so many people that
help us out and it's like it's a lot of
fun it's fun being here wife producers
in town
Ryan we're fun we're killing it so you
know the book signing all this stuff is
just you know it's exciting spab buiness
year it's the 20 year anniversary
everyone's hyped everyone's CED
everyone's here by see if they have a
good time at smoke Halloween so there's
some fire here guys there is some fire
here I really really uh tried some stuff
I'm sure you got some loud stuff on you
as well we always have something loud I
know loud to see throughout that's
amazing man
yeah I think you also carry up with a
bunch of new crosses start I did I did
some fast Bud crosses we're talking
about those we up to do a whole 30
minutes on the fast Bud cres we yeah
let's let's do that schedule something
on the Skype or something like that like
like record that put it out to the world
was busy as hell yeah during during scan
Abus exactly and I will tell you more
about our brand new cross the one which
I finish in less than 8 GRE it's the
first time ever nuts that is nuts
congratul the fastest buds the fastest
Buds and L to fast
bus oh man that's CH J thanks for
everything thank you bro and always
remember man it's 420 somewhere it is
[Music]
perfect
we're here we're representing hard Big
Ups James loud podcast James loud
genetics James loud publishing
[ __ ] James loud everything big
respect my brother see you back in Cali
Barcelona 2024 represent DNA genetics 20
year anniversary
[Music]
respect
James has created a podcast that
resonates deeply with audiences around
the world James L has set the standard
for excellence in cannabis podcasting
his passion for sharing knowledge and
promoting positive change within the
Cannabis Community is evident in every
episode we're honored to recognize J
Cloud's outstanding contributions to the
podcasting space with this prestigious
[Applause]
[Music]
award thank you guys so much for the
award uh this is the producer for the
podcast his name is Ryan he also does
editing our podcast is so much bigger
than one person I may get a lot of
credit for it but it's so many people uh
in the the effort and work of Ben we
have Brandon who does the clips we got
Eric who contributes our wives who've
done a lot but the oral history of
cannabis in the form of podcast is so
important you know 15 or 100 years from
now people can look back at these
revolutionaries that were interviewing
and get their stories and you know I
feel so blessed to be part of
this so how's it going everybody I'm
here with Luna St congratulations on the
win
you yeah good stuff really amazing I
mean I'm so I'm so excited and I'm so
grateful for being part of the community
people like yourself I feel like we're
trying to push
boundaries we are the re revolutionaries
of the future you know I I interviewed
Steve D'Angelo we we were talking about
revolutionaries and I didn't realize
that that's what I wanted to do my whole
life was be a revolutionary and I feel
like you're in that same boat absolutely
I was born with it it's coming from
social justice everything has a lens of
how can this be better more Equitable
and add to a a more beautiful world and
it doesn't just have to be cannabis it
can be outside of even psychedelics like
there's so much healing that needs to
happen internally and externally with
our Earth and with our planet with our
bodies that you know plant medicine has
so many different Realms where you can
be a revolutionary and have
revolutionary change totally and we need
more women in the industry Amen brother
I mean I think there are a lot of women
but we need more yes there's not many in
ownership or decision-making positions
that's what we find is that there's when
you see the statistics of women in the
industry a lot of times they're Junior
positions they labor um base but they're
not really influencing change and really
adding their Brilliance and knowledge to
the pool cuz you know this thing's been
cultivated by women and Indigenous
people for thousands of years wasn't
always a a
colonialism a lot of women behind the
scenes don't get credit agreed and so
that's going to change yeah absolutely
and some women don't really even need
the acknowledgement right or like the
prestige but just even just equal pay
you know the way the the the facts that
we you know we do the same jobs as men
and we got different titles things like
that where it's like even the women who
are like I don't even need the Kudos
just like don't pay me 60 cents on the
dollar and let me actually sit in on a
board meeting and give my ideas for some
people that's enough you know it's just
it's it's about B respect is respect is
so important though for everybody that
just goes without saying yeah and we
want to welcome more women in and make
sure you know it's like come in the
water's fine like it's oh you can
succeed here you can be safe especially
here yes you know with this plant the
plant is so special and it just means so
much to you all the people in this room
all the people that have got to bring us
to the point where we're at in our lives
I mean it's just Collective effort it
really is yeah I've never seen another
industry where people rely on and
support and up lift each other even in a
competitor sense yeah there's a little
bit of ego but at the same time healthy
it's like healthy competion yeah no one
wants to see anyone do poorly you might
get a little jealous if they're doing
well but you'll still go to their events
you'll still support them if they need
it that's how it is the clubs here in
Barcelona when one gets R and the other
ones go and support them that we know
that we need each other we got to lift
each other up yeah absolutely and that's
the beauty of the industry and there's a
huge Market we're not fighting over a
market share right like we're only
growing more cannabis curious and
intenders of use of cannabis yeah we
don't just arue over especially now that
there's for you know in a lot of Senses
there's the seed um and the hemp and the
things you can do online now it's direct
a consumer you don't even need to funnel
it through some of these regulatory
Frameworks you can just talk directly to
your customers totally yeah it's
exciting well I would love to get you on
a podcast here you a lot of fun so yeah
congratulations for having me yes shout
out to the international cannabis Awards
and for ice fire for having me out here
yeah awesome stuff thanks
congratulations thank you feels good to
win in Spain it does what do we get
James show show the hardware podcast
award it was a honorable
mention they just gave him to everybody
that showed up actually best podcast of
the Year
[Applause]
[Music]
so I want to gift you a special copy
this is the king copy for the king of
gabis I really thank you so much from
the bottom of my heart your
contributions to this book were
immeasurable your advice over the years
your friendship all that stuff I really
appreciate everything from you guys I
just I tday from the day we met man
you've always given me B advice you've
always told me the truth you've always
been a straight student not stuff I
always want to hear but the truth from
we don't to friends you should not lie
but I want to say I'm very proud of you
that you made this and uh it's going to
be a little new Bible for all of us it
is coming from a breeder which is not a
book writer which is great so probably
one of the first books on the market
written by a real grower which is for me
really really important that we could
have a helping the book is just an honor
for us so yeah very happy very proud of
you I know you had a rough time the last
five years but we are here now look how
amazing spunner this is amusing we're to
make new collabs and you come out with
this book so you can be super proud of
yourself congratulations on behalf of
the greenhouse family and uh I hope you
signed for us
absolutely we're WR a king copy right
here
listen know you're not even getting a
number of cop you're getting the kid
copy but one of
one thank you so
much de full
gas d
man yeah this book is for frankco thank
you guys B it's a Franco eBay $300 yeah
yeah King coping 3,000 start
the there so I'm here with Marcus Dr
Green he's from Trinidad so big shout
out to my friends and family in Trinidad
St Vincent and all over the Caribbean
man so glad to be hanging out with you
here at spanis we've been for a long
time time James James actually gave me
my first dab back in what 2011 I think
it was something like that 2011 yeah
yeah yeah I I I took it like a on strong
one you know Game Changer yeah yeah yeah
definitely dabs back then we did odd
dabs they were all game changer
definitely definitely and you gave me my
first real hot sauce I I tried hot sauce
many times but not like your hot sauce
your hot sauce is uh nuclear yeah
Trinidad has the the real maruga
scorpion peppers and then of course we
we we use that secret ingredient that s
cand you know you we yeah yeah so what
have you been doing for spanis H spanis
this year uh I've been well not uh have
a lot of friends with boots of course
most of my friends are out here as you
know and as you've just said with the
hot sauce uh I bring hot sauce to my
friends out here it's not easy walking
with three gallons of hot sauce all the
way from Trinidad and then making a 100
little jaars for for all the friends and
it's still never up right right but uh
this year it's just been a little more
relaxing no hot sauce this year uh had a
a little event in Trinidad back in
December conference Expo and Cannabis
Cup it went off you know really smoothly
really well having another one in July
August so this year I brought some as I
brought to you a little ruling tree and
you know handed it out to all the
friends and just seeing everybody
rekindling all you know Vibes and making
sure everybody's good awesome yeah good
stuff what's the rest of you smoked man
uh
I this Californians like yourself you
know you guys always have the best stuff
Califor how about SP what's the best
thing you sp from Spain from SP let's
talk about from SP what's the best thing
you smoke I I think I got to see
grounded genetics my guy I can't say his
name but my guy gr the genetics um I
took some stuff from him yesterday just
to sample his flower and so and wow you
know I to I was in California so really
brought you back to the States yeah yeah
really um you know
it it has been elevated for the last few
years you know everywhere you see better
strains at the different uh uh clubs and
so forth different cannabis clubs uh but
but my guy had some special stuff for me
you know so I think his stuff overall
was was some of the best I spoke some
great Skittles and Strain Hunters I mean
I've tried Skittles over the years in
Barcelona I love that flavor uh but this
year they added that amongst about three
or four other trads that I really like
from them but uh that one really really
really really good you know so and
prices much lower this year in Barcelona
on everything on everything than they
were few years ago so definitely a place
to visit you know for those who have de
right how do you feel about the energy
this year man I thought uh yesterday
would be you know way more crowded than
uh than it was in a few years before and
it was just we still got a little space
to move and today at least is a little
more relaxed Friday was bet Friday was I
think this year the most busiest which
is not regular for span right usually
it's Saturday right but Friday was I
mean most of uh my friends gave out all
their sample stuff and stuff and so on
on Friday so Friday was definitely busy
this year right but uh everybody so you
know doing what they do at spanis as
usual they they take things to the
highest level in terms of uh uh
Exposition and what they're showing I
mean if you look around the greenhouse
boot you'll see you know everybody goes
all out you know that's something you
can really appreciate about fibis uh as
an expert is the uh one of the largest
in Europe one of the largest in the
world right so definitely somewhere that
we need to be and everybody who is
within the industry should at least
visit once awesome yeah well thank you
for taking your time to speak with me
and man I can't wait to hang out just
before you go your book you know I I've
been wondering about your book I know
that you you i' saw on your your post on
social media all that you've been doing
so I just want to congratulate you on
all the years that you've uh uh taken to
compile this all the work you've put in
I say you've made a dedication to Franco
from Strain Hunters which is you know
just amazing we know that he was you
know one that had real real fashion for
the plant and I know that for for both
of us you know he was kind of a a mental
role model different aspect to be
friends with him definitely definitely
you know so for all those who haven't
gotten it yet I definitely suggest that
you get a copy of this book cannabis
breeding it will have some of the best
information some of the best of every
part of the industry you know Jamesy has
been well around the place you know and
knows everybody within the industry this
is definitely one to get your hands on
recommended by me also thank you stay
blessed everyone thanks for having me on
all brother
[Music]
bless
so brother we got stuck the so good to
see you brother yeah so this is Nils
from Sticky Buds I have a special book
autograph just to you much love brother
passion for the Sacred Plan so what on
my H yeah for sure brother so this is Mr
Greenhouse from Argentina
repping the brand killing it they're
doing their thing in Argentina next
level dude this is really
[Music]
Good's
we got a little bit of everybody here in
Barcelona we got Mr Bubble Man from BC
yep BC bubble man in the house 20th 20th
spanis 20th span yeah 2004 it was uh
this is
the even all of them except for the one
it didn't happen that's right amazing 20
years in a row do it's AE it's aome supp
to see you year what are your thoughts
on the year compared to like the last
couple since literally in 2004 y the
hash and the rosin has gotten better and
better every year that I've come here
which is pretty impressive the local
stuff is amazing these guys so [ __ ]
passionate about everything about the
flower the flower is a lot better here
too I mean honestly the flower drone
here is really good I mean obviously in
this is the state so it's good the bad
the other yeah they have good soil biome
here in Spain they Haven killed it like
we have in North America for sure so the
bile is like it's in good shape it's
living it's alive and it's you know
that's why all of the ingredients of
food in the Mediterranean are
exceptional tomatoes and you know basil
and all of these different you know
vegetables and fruits Express themselves
so much nicer than they do in Canada
that's for sure yeah and I find the
resin not to be too different especially
when I meet outdoor Growers right you
know it's just like Super Choice super
on point and there's so much variety I
mean there's so much variety and I it's
unbelievable spis you get the best of
both worlds so you get a lot of European
stuff that we don't see in the States
you Haze you still get a good amount of
haze oh yeah I got dude I got some sh
this this is Jack but
still right like M it's nice I love
turkey the leag yeah I'm a big fan I am
too I like the I don't like it all the
time I don't like any the time it's
definitely not for like 2: in the
morning yeah in the 1 in the morning 2
in the morning I remember uh Scott from
R anus came by one time and we were in
Amsterdam and he brought like ghost
train a or something ghost TR it was
like midnight or 11 when he showed off
we thatch since 4:30 in the morning yeah
it keeps you
going like a bunch of tweakers or
something dude so how many times you've
been to Europe actually first D first
trip across the big F yeah first trip to
Europe first trip to Barcelona first
spanis so a lot of lot of first this
week awesome it's funny cuz I feel like
spanis can ruin Europe for stutters Asal
well and uh I'm glad it's my first stop
and I'll make many returns so hopefully
uh it's just a beginning of a long
tradition so what you been doing this
week this week man we did ICBC uh we're
staying in the gothic District so
there's so much to see been a few of the
clubs and trying to keep up actually
judge the Autoflower cup how was it
World Cup I was pleasantly surprised uh
to be honest I didn't have very high
helps but man they brought some nice Stu
awesome what's the best thing you smoked
to
Barcelona the best thing I smoked in
Barcelona was uh uh a hash somebody
brought from Michigan
so wait hold on one second R yes it's in
the it's in the cut yes I've been wanted
one of these since he show bro yeah this
is some local oh yeah dude thank you so
much I appreciate it I'm sure this will
be the best I smok in Barcelona now know
yeah good stuff dude great to see you
great to see you what's good family it's
Nick T over here at spannabis you're
watching the James loud
podcast
[Music]
hey what's happening to kect community
Sergio picazo here out in Spain we got
spanis Barcelona 2024 we're here at
chirps Army thank you guys so much for
having us James a podcast is in the
house congratulations to the James o
podcast uh podcast of the year last year
so proud of you guys this is amazing we
got Legends in the house chilling
chopping it up talking game leveling
each other up with some very interesting
topics we're soaked to be here thank you
so much for having us guys much
[Music]
love
check microphone check yo we're in
spannabis James loud show at the
greenhouse booth and we're all just
chilling it's a good vibe come through
how's it going everybody this is Aladdin
from genetics and he's a contributor to
this book this book uh wouldn't be what
it was without people like Aladin we
have two I think over 22 contributors
who B the STS recipe is from this guy so
if it does
people on right there no I I I love your
your social media presence I love your
videos I feel like you're very
educational and you're very serious
about it and but you have fun well
likewise thank you so much man but your
podcast I love it you know you've got a
lot of great players and and you ask a
lot of very relevant questions on it too
so I wanted to talk to you about this
book and I wanted to ask you a few
questions about it sure so what made you
want to write it and is it is you told
me well we we we had a little
conversation before and you were telling
me that you wrote a book before but you
didn't publish it I wrote five five
times I've wrote drafts of this thing
all right we even pre-sold copies on
Amazon in 2019 but the first round of
editing by an editor I wasn't super
excited about and it wasn't his fault I
I was learning how to write for one
thing right and these things kind of
happened but that's what makes things
great is when you fail you get back up
you do it over and over if you want to
do something bad enough you can do
anything I'm so convinced especially
with cannabis it'll guide you the the
plant will guide you the plant helps if
you listen the plant will tell you what
to do and I feel like I've done that my
whole life and I've been through a lot
of failures and I feel like that's
what's made me stronger and better than
I was before and I don't take it too
personal you know I know that you make
mistakes you just get up and do it again
if you do it the right way and you turn
on to repeat the same mistakes but
breathing I love breathing you love
breathing too I love it man you know and
it's so great to be able to talk with
other people about genetics and about
the plant and how it benefits their life
and there's so many benefits to this
plant and we're just scratching the
surface of it even scientists don't know
about it they just know a little bit
about it for now like they're still
learning a whole lot totally and how
long have you been writing this book for
if you take everything into account uh I
mean 5 years and I brought probably
hundreds of thousands the words to get
100,000 words in let's and so I mean the
first version was I think 30,000 words
and this is 100,000 wow that's a lot
more yeah and we got really high-end
photos and if I had released that first
book I would have really been
disappointed with myself the rest of my
life I okay I know but this is something
that I feel you know this does the
subject Justice in my opinion right and
it's evolving so fast that I feel like
even though I wrote this book and I try
to stay current there's some stuff like
dou hloy breeding that like I'm talking
about it in the past not in the past in
the future it's actually something
that's being done right now by a lot of
people right so it's already information
is becoming obsolete that's why so you
think you're going to have to update it
yeah every two years I'm going to update
it and I think at least through right
now until it's more stable cuz we're
learning so much and I want to share
with the home girls I appreciate the H
girls those people are the biggest fans
of us and the biggest supporters are the
people that grow the plants in their
houses and their backyards you know the
guys that have a few plants and those
are those are all real fans so who who
is this book for home goers or this is
for everybody you want to learn about
breeding it's an indepth dive into what
breeding is there's case studies on
different genetics you want to make
femin it's all in the book and that that
was the biggest thing so for
me I had to go to so many different
places for the information I wanted it
to be accessible to anybody that wants
to learn how to breed and then Angela
helped me put it together and make it
really easy for people to read yeah it
was very easy to work with her she's
awesome yeah she's so great and then in
the back there's like a grossery but you
can go there's QR codes so you can go
through the QR codes in the book there's
a the glossery terms oh actually if you
want to learn how to pronounce these
gloss I have a section you go to the
website and it has me pronouncing the
words so going into into the industry
without as scientific a background as
some other people yes pronouncing words
can be difficult so it's nice to have
somebody that can tell you it's theity
and not yite you know I for example but
and why write a reading block cuz
there's already a few you know marijuana
botney but it's old it's very old that's
from 1980 and then so green wrote a book
25 years ago the Cannabis breeders Bible
yeah and I feel like those are outdated
they're good books for their times like
you were saying before yeah and for
their time they were great books and I
have so much respect for both Greg green
and Rob Clark for writing about breeding
or I feel like we need a modern update
of the the breeding world and kind of
what we're doing and there's a lot of
misinformation so if you can get rid of
the misinformation cut through all the
[ __ ] and bu all in one place people
are going to benefit and it's going to
make the world a better place and it's
much easier to reach than marijuana bney
marijuana bodney was like a little
tricky you know some parts of it and
this is like it's an easy read so so
you've read the B what do you think yeah
well I haven't read the whole thing I
read maybe about half of it cuz I I was
you know contributing to it a little bit
and I had to write it but read it and
what what I think I love it because you
didn't just talk about breeding you
talked about land races as well yeah and
you talked about like many other aspects
of like cannabis growing so it's it all
like comes together it's not just breing
it's like growing all you talk about the
Seas the sea quality right and the
different strains cultivars and the land
races and all that yeah the proper turns
well and then I had people like you
reading the book and reviewing it and
keeping it real bro like I don't know
about that and I got that from Reggie
Gardino I got from you I got it from a
couple Mojave Richmond where they were
like do you really mean this and you're
saying this or do you mean that and that
tour really makes for me it's like okay
now these guys will help me make my book
better so how many people did you
collaborate with and oh if we talk about
everybody there there were 22 people and
you know we had an editor we had someone
to do the layout we had two graphics
people two photographers all right you
know we and then and then Dale Hunt a
contributing chapter on intellectual
property and Matt Schneider did a tissue
culture chapter and there's just so many
people that contributed a bunch the guy
right here this is Lance he's from gr
bags yeah what's up man how's it going
it ni JJ actually from from Grove BS
helped me write the BR uh the section
that's about drawing and caring and so
we have a lot of really detailed
information so it's a it's a DP effort
and it's a beautiful thing I love it I
love being part of things that are so
much bigger than myself I feel like you
know and I feel like that's why we're
here is to be be part of a machine part
of things that to improve the world and
do better things and things have come a
long way you know like 10 years ago
everything was different like you said
right like autoflowers for example they
were not nearly as good as they are
today and there's so many things that we
haven't been able to improve yeah so
yeah and how long have we been a to
breeding I've been here breeding for a
long time now I was messing around in
the early 2000s but I got serious in the
late 200 like 8 n
10 and so we won our first Cup in
2012 but I was breeding more for I
wanted my own version of this or my own
version of that and now I have a lot of
different goals obviously I do a lot of
white labeling for other companies make
I make a bunch of genetics for yeah
handful of big companies and they like
the quality of it they like the quality
and the consistency and you know it's
like when you can have consistent
results that's what countes with
breathing you know it's like it's super
important so yeah speaking of that what
do you think about Paul in talking orus
stabilizing lines and breing I think
they both have their own place and I
don't I think there's a lot of egos
involved with this and people should
worry about what they're doing and as
much about what other people are doing
long transparent about it
long you know if you have interex treats
you should tell people you have interex
treats if there's her aphrodites you
should tell people that's so important
right and if there's a bunch of
diversity that's a good thing too I mean
there's nothing wrong with that and some
people want stabilized and other people
want the new hpe have one absolutely and
they're both good things all right for
the right person so it's just like you
like banana and I like chocolate chps
but banana and cholate chps are work
well together too yeah so yeah thanks a
lot for your time Matt for sure
appreciate it bro yeah thank you Ro to
get some food so yeah definitely so
we're here with Lance from I used to say
Lance from Bova but it's Lance from
Grove now it's Lance from Grove now yep
yeah you're in my phone is Lance from B
so many people yeah I've got around weed
maps Boga green Ros green throw throw
bags where throw bags I Manion do good
this is you know you and I have done it
several times now it's the 20th
anniversary um you know the more things
change the more they stay the same
that's one thing a lot of the ogs are
like wow it's like it's like Groundhog
Day every year we come and it's very
similar to what it was the year before U
but yeah it's definitely good man lot of
energy a lot of people from northern
Europe I don't know about you guys but a
lot of the Germans austrians uh a lot of
them coming down from up North obviously
a close to adult use legalization up
there so stoked on that looking forward
to marry Jane in a few months cuz that
is in Berlin in West Berlin so for that
to happen after legalization up there
which I think is inevitable is going to
be dope too awesome yeah yeah killer
show best turnout in years I love this
place I love seeing my friends a lot of
friends came out a lot of friends and
you and I both man for we were just
talking about a friend from Thailand a
lot of friends from around the world
friends from Australia Thailand
Argentina fuay all across Europe in the
North America side of things wow it's
crazy man this a one place we get to see
old friends so we only see maybe once a
year totally so well dude I look forward
to getting you on another podcast I did
too man ground Emerald cup maybe perfect
timing dude that your show yeah thanks M
[Music]
for
so I'm here today on the last day of
spanis with my good friend Barry we've
known each other for a long time he's
true can of bliss online he has the true
can cast podcast he's been crushed it
for years he grows the fire he smokes
the fire we smoke so much [ __ ] weed
didn't answer I don't remember every
time I it's making a hand stand up on my
arm because we do have so many my
greatest memories n
interrup a good guy to have around he
can attest to my flower as well he's
someone who always finds me when I've
got heat and gets to appreciate
something how's the show been been good
it's been busy I I've been busy I you're
always busy though you're always busy
there's never a don't know that in your
life dud I EJ since late night s 600 in
the morning underground Vibes wow
definitely follow me next year cuz this
[ __ ] lit yeah and then how's your R
spiderus has been amazing in I live in
Barcelona so for me this is like the
buildup for the whole year is for this
this is when I get to see all my friends
from the industry I get to talk about my
genetics I get to show everyone what
I've been doing and it's just the most
fun I ever have like I love spannabis so
nice to see what everyone is loving new
Innovations new flavors new directions
people are going in for sure friends
like yourself I'm always watching and
inspired by and it's beautiful when I
can get everyone over and have those
conversations and get the real insight
and what I like to learn from you guys
in any way that I can so for me this is
a big like a big time to catch up for
sure learn from you guys' mistakes find
out what's H what's not what to avoid
Lord knows we make a lot of mistakes but
bro if you if you can't help each
other's friends and try to learn from
each other's each other up exactly
that's it so for me we always give you
SS like a boost in like the feeling the
love that everyone shows to have
everything
appreciated every person see with
genetics and tell them about stuff
seriously tell us about your new
genetics all right so the things I'm
really excited about is I've just
released a strain called Filipino Queen
which is a Filipino land race cross to
my strain km baly Cooks which I
previously won I think it was third
place spab as well the km B Cooks is
four cookies cross San Fernando Valley
OG cross chem and I've hit that to the
Filipino land race and the Philo land
race I I dubbed her love sick uh and
when you cut her she bleeds red she's so
rich in anos silins that she bleeds red
and what I'm finding is that she adds so
much Vigor to the to the Jean C like
pwder milder resistance I flowed until
Outdoors
until November in Barcelona completely
resistant to powder mil amazing Ts that
are just wor in describe of it you know
when you can't love it pluck a
comparison out of the sky and anyone
that smells it is like they're confused
they're looking for aners but they can't
him Point what it smells like so yeah
that that the Filipino queen I'm super
excited about and our intro released the
chem Valley Cooks f2s to coincide with
that drop so those two I'm super excited
about at the moment really cool man
awesome seeing you again bro dude for
sure we need to do a collab podcast
together one of 100% bro and genetic wi
as well let's do some love to do
something cool with you bro we got
similar taste buds but differences as
well so sure I think we could combine
some ideas yeah sure bro pleasure is
always amazing seeing you aome what can
seeing you she push so I'm here at the
last day with
Nila one of my friends my Idols my
Inspirations she's written an amazing
book as well and she's done so many
things that have had positive impact on
our community so I want to give you this
book I thank you so much this thank you
you give me I going to give you a b back
so than you how's span of his day
exhausted exhausted yeah you you had a
Dabo and You' been going to events every
night I'm glad we no not every night no
it's been doing it's quite popular yeah
yeah yeah no bad you're the final then
tell us about the final event that
you're going to you're going to what
club is it no they was ask me where are
you going tonight I say oh I have a very
small private club oh I say what's it
called I say B where is that up to yeah
nice say yeah mark
p it's so amazing I feel like the energy
here is like 10 years ago
yeah so yeah and you haven't aged your
10 years I feel like you keep getting
younger whatever it is I need that maybe
more smoking no I brown rice brown bread
and brown sugar organic vegetables and
see where out nice that's exent and I
cycle a lot and you cycle a lot but yeah
I know well yeah you guys yeah it's
amazing the country the flat country you
got to worry about other bikers a little
bit but other than
that yeah I've been hit by a biker
before thank you for our amazing
contributions to our
industry much love Ste on 101 you get
the special numbered 101
car thank you so much
I'm so I'm here today with th Caesar
we've known each other for a long time
we got through some [ __ ] together I seen
you grow up in this industry you know
from being young uh man it's very
amazing journey thank you yes it's we
thank you very
much know each other for probably like
at least a decade yeah more than for 14
years so what are you doing here as fous
you doing the SE thing uh yeah so right
now I'm just backpack teching this is my
first year in spannabis with uh my SE R
so I missed out on last year uh but this
year I'm out here just uh promoting my
brand slowly try to get a bunch of my
genetics in a bunch of people's Gardians
right now so you started out as a writer
for High Times loving weed yes I mean
obviously you still love weed but that's
where you got your start was with high
times then you kind of you did the seed
brokering thing for a while and hustle
you were the guy to go to for rare and
Elite genetics uh more than
anybody and uh then you started doing
breeding which you're doing now and
hustling and hustling and hustling and
you're in New York yes I'm back in New
York full time now nice how is it it's
culture shock it's uh definitely
something that I didn't think was going
to happen like the way it is but I'm
going to take advantage of whatever's
happening right now because if it's not
me it's going to be somebody else making
that money so I might as well be what
it's a nice time to be back in New York
with a bunch of popups cannbis being
sold pretty much everywhere pre-rolls
can be sold pretty not can be sold but
they are sold everywhere ain't sold
every like it's pretty cool like people
can literally set up a table like this
in the city sell weed cop thing will't
bust you it's almost a free fall or Neal
right now when it comes to Caris sort
yeah I mean
I feel like you're synonymous with New
Yorks and you're back in New York you
belong there uh you know Colorado was
cool you did your thing in Colorado but
New York is really where you're going to
thrive that was home I went to Colorado
to learn it was uh what back in 2012
when they voted it in uh Colorado in
Washington I went to Colorado to learn
as much as I could but now that I built
up my resume and knowledge well I'm
trying to take all that back to the up H
well dude thanks for coming out thank
you for having me
[Music]
appr
I'm here with Arya rosam the king of
spanis how you doing man king of spanis
king of spous I'm doing great thanks for
having us man it's been a great show
dude thank you for inviting me listen
it's always great to have friends on the
show and gather up and and mingle mangle
and create new cabs and Barcelona is one
of the best shows in the world besides
the one in one iser I think yeah this is
nuts yeah this is nuts I think we
probably have 50 60 70,000 people here
again it's crazy on Friday know I've
never seen anything like it's one of the
well not in 10 years I feel like the
energ is yeah the energy is also back a
lot of good things happening and yeah no
just awesome what can we say dude your
booth is amazing you guys always get uh
new booths big improvements this is
crazy yeah yeah and the all Thailand
history there yeah I mean that's amazing
that's amazing you guys are doing big
things in Thailand how's that going it's
going great we are now uh finalizing the
GMP facility so we got 52 glass houses
and po houses we got a tie
indoor now we're doing the GMP and we'll
be finishing August and at the same time
in the north we're finishing the sea
Factory which will have around 35
breeding rules it's amazing and the big
advantage of the Green Seed Company now
is that we besides the big Seed Factory
where we can produce like tons of seeds
we can also try out all our stuff indoor
poy house glass house and outdoor you
know so it's great to see genetics
growing everywhere you know we can e
even try under LED under HPS optimize
very great specific optimize everything
perfectly amazing I can't wait to come
see here yeah when you coming well we
come in a couple months yeah the best
time to come because the glass houses
are empty now because we grow between
October and March yeah cuz now gets
really odd so I don't want to grow in a
really really OD season you know so we
preow our plants again a few months wow
and then when they're ready in September
we put them in again you know yeah so
you what up two hours a year yeah we do
two Harvest a year then when we cut down
we make new moms and we build up the old
base in the north as you can see there's
19 glass houses and then we go to the 32
po houses starting September
well pre grow 12 weeks and then November
is the first harvest and then there's
another harvest in January February
that's how we rotates when you are fully
integrated in tand you have the coffee
shop model you've got the grow you have
everything it's basically as you guys
call from SE to sale yeah and we prefer
to say from Farm to Table yeah like a
proper restaurant literally Farm to
Table you're getting fresh flour the
freshest of the fresh flour right from
the people that grow it there's no
middlemen between and anymore who can
make mistakes it's us growing it's us
drying and curing it's us transporting
it to the shops and it's in our shops in
Bangkok amazing so I hope to see you
guys in one of our three shops in
Bangkok was one in China Town is one
one1 road and then we're opening next
month uh in Japan Town in toor and then
in two months we're opening in Kumo on
the island amazing so yeah we have five
this year maybe a few more we don't know
yet and yeah looking forward to all that
and uh let's see what we can do bro yeah
for sure I can't wait to get you on the
podcast of the states yeah that would
been great thanks for having me and guys
keep watching James loud podcast one of
the best podcasts in the world great
friend of mine broken roll guys so I'm
here today with mud from Dutch passive
man how you doing five been see again
good to see you too man so I I just
finished my breeding Bud he released it
just recently and you guys contrib some
amazing photos thank you for all your
help yeah was our finish very very happy
to see the book
finish it's really a group effort for so
many people to make this book what it is
I feel like it's really special and the
mutations and all the other stuff you
guys contribut as to contribute and
thank you so much for the for
sure I'm going to sign an autograph this
with you guys awesome fashion for the sa
plan perfect man thank you so much for
remember well in thank you so much I
appreciate it for sure en enjoy enjoy
[Music]
I
oh
[Music]
he