[Music]
oh
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James lb podcast
and today our special guest is Eric from
flow Gardens in Tennessee how are you
doing Eric doing great James thanks for
having me thanks for coming on the show
this is the first time we get to meet in
person we've talked a lot you know
you're an ambassador for the brand
you're growing our genetics in Tennessee
uh you're doing the hemp license thing
and doing some really cool stuff yeah
yeah um doing the best we can in a state
where it's still illegal to grow uh you
know marijuana so yeah it looks like
you're growing sometime and it doesn't
even look like I've seen your flower you
sent me flower uh thca flower is
phenomenal you you sent me some chem
cross that was just super amazing and I
love seeing gassy stuff cuz like a lot
of people don't grow gas these days I
know I'm I fell in love with that strain
I actually brought some more for you
today um it's a chem 91 cross with sour
bubble we named it Chemtrails and uh
yeah that when it was like day 20 of
flower it was already stinking up the
tent you know so uh it's definitely one
of my favorites right now it's got that
foul chem it does the one you just have
to keep on smelling even though it's so
bad not everybody likes it and it's like
one of those ones to where like if you
don't like it that's okay CU I like it
you know it's like one of those ones
it's something that's super nostalgic
for me that that I grew up on that smell
and i' I like it just reminds me of the
year 2000 yeah year 2001 chem dog when
it was first hitting the market and it's
like not OG it's got that chemy gas
where it's like a little bit foul but
really loud where like a jar of it you
open it up and it really burns your
nostrils exactly like you can't pinpoint
the exact flavor but I like to describe
like it smells like the 90s like like
the way I used to get back in the 90s
yeah yeah I love that and then you
you've grown some of my genetics you've
done some really cool work with the ours
with the Mystic Mountain blueberry which
I haven't got to try yet but the
pictures yeah the pictures sell it it
looks great yeah so I'm growing that
actually in the backyard in my little
shop I got a six lighter back there and
uh that particular feno just checked all
the boxes and uh I'll be harvesting I
think in about a week so when that's
ready to go I'll definitely send some
your way yeah we just had humbled seeds
on the show and so I'm glad you got that
you know I'm excited to show them the
flower cuz feel like uh the blueberry
muffin is extremely special I think that
if you get something that's not
blueberry muffin that has some of the
blueberry muffin in it but it's
different that's a great thing because
like blueberry muffin is its own thing
and it it's basically it sets some
really cool Trends up in Humble you know
especially with it well so we had DJ
shorts blueberry originally right and I
think that got wide spread there was
other blueberries too but then the
blueberry muffin is very blueberry
muffin oh yeah like you smell blueberry
muffin it smells like straight blueberry
muffin almost like a rotten blueberry or
something yeah but it's it's amazing and
it's like it's super sweet the structure
of it good it's got nice color it checks
a lot of the boxes MH yeah this one has
a lot of the blueberry but it also has
uh like a creamy I guess it's coming
from the double Lemon Cherry maybe over
gas and the bread a little bread it's
got a little bit of everything yeah yeah
it's special for sure I'll tell you what
though the permanent midnight those are
probably one of my favorites right now
every feno is just phenomenal in its own
way
yeah I brought some today I want you to
try it it's lit been my smoke that I've
been smoking on for a couple weeks now
it's yeah we've been getting a lot of uh
praise for the permanent midnight I
think it's just when you put two good
things together usually you get good
stuff but when you have so many
Expressions that are good that then it
you know stands on its own oh yeah
there's so many different things that
you can look for in it I think there's
something for everybody you know and
some people the the ones that don't have
color I feel like are pretty loud
yeah exactly like you want the purple
ones to be the best ones but sometimes
that's or usually that's not the case
you know it's not and it's okay you know
I mean I think color is like this
qualifier right now that I don't think
it's going to be there forever I want
the loudest the one that tastes best and
also the one that has the best effect
exactly uh color is kind of secondary
although right now it's very prioritized
MH so yeah I think like the flavor if it
can resonate in the smoke that's the
last check box for me you know that's a
tough one to get it's like when you
refire that joint and it tastes amazing
exact I'm all about that yeah 100% so
yeah especially if it's the roach like
if it's down to the roach and you're
like I don't know if it's going to taste
good or if it's GNA taste bad and you
fire it up you're like wow so yeah we
did some sour d we had a while back that
was really amazing I'm biging the sour d
so I haven't had that in a minute well
if you're running into the next couple
days I think I'll have some I'm a huge
fan of sour d and fresh batches coming
down nice so yeah I just I I like all
all different flavors I like stuff
that's gassy I like stuff that's
floral uh it just depends on what kind
of mood I'm in I love Skittles yeah yeah
so yeah but even especially the floral
stuff the the old school gdps stuff like
that stuff that nobody wants to grow
because it takes forever to veg exactly
it doesn't yield that much although GDP
has its place for sure oh no doubt yeah
I'm actually growing one of those right
now cross with Northern Lights number
five nice so still early in blower so
we'll see but yeah that's that's a good
one yeah that and Bubba Kush I haven't
seen a lot of good Bubba Kush coming
back although
budalo Dave Perkins from budalo he's got
a really good cross that's very
bubushonok
like our customer base is just going
back to that nostalgic feel of cannabis
and people know those names and I think
there's expectations when you buy Blue
Dream you should expect to get something
that's loud too but it's not what checks
the boxes in California maybe yeah but
overall you know it's not the purple
candy gas at all right and it's
something that's more
uplifting uh sativa whatever you want to
call it they they're longer flowering
varieties too yeah and there's something
special about longer flowering varieties
too especially effect wise where it's
like super functional you can do
anything on Blue Dream exactly like
literally you can do anything Go pass
your driver's test on Blue Dream because
you drive better yeah and that's kind of
how that chem 91 cross is it's just very
clearheaded very uh euphoric in a way
yeah it doesn't get me tight behind the
eyes M but uh it's also it can be strong
if you keep smoking it it definitely
doesn't have a ceiling like some of
these things it has a creeper effect
like you're fine and then all of a
sudden I have trouble talking I'm like
oh yeah I'm definitely there yeah I I
like the creeper effect sometimes but
other times where you're not gauging it
and you're just in conversation you're
smoking a joint you just keep hitting it
and then 15 minutes later you're like
wow exactly so yeah certain things will
get you there and then autoflowers have
come so far I'm not sure if you've
tapped into the Autoflower Market at all
but I haven't really you know I mean our
facility is a little like yours where
it's a research and development SL
production in a way so I haven't really
I don't have a room dedicated to Auto
flowers um I've done a little bit in the
past but I really haven't messed with
them too much
yeah are they getting more stable as
they are getting I mean there so there's
a handful of people that produce amazing
autoflowers and then there's everybody
else and I think it's like that with
most things yeah but yeah with autof
flowers there are people that produce
stable autof flowers that Express pretty
even across the board and there's other
people every single plant grows a
different uh size that different shape
you're getting a lot of phenotypical
variation right and then there's the
guys that are growing stuff that's
pretty straight across the board that
they're all very similar or almost
identical Goa and
so over time you're going to get better
and better better Expressions more even
Expressions especially but a lot of
people are focusing on aut flowers now
too so I'm excited for autof flowers I
love autof flowers outdoor there's a
handful of guys that are crushing it
indoors uh Rue that you I think we met
on phone calls before yeah yeah he's
crushing Autos he does he does a lot of
our testing for autos and nice yeah he's
doing a deep water culture you know he's
doing some cool stuff yeah yeah he's a
good dude man yeah he's a character
loves weed yeah absolutely definitely
yeah I guess with me the autof flowers I
had a trouble I didn't even know you had
the flower I'm under 18 hours of light
for a minute and so that was one of my
issues and then I finally figured that
out but yeah I guess I just struggle
with the stability of it in production
yeah I think it's one of those things
like for you your your Market is a
little bit different too going with
Autos is kind of a tougher Market mhm
but uh it's one of those things I feel
like we've overlooked them for so long
and now they're starting to get good and
they're they're not for everybody yeah
but they definitely have their place
exactly so they get a lot of hate you
know but people don't don't always
understand things and you know there's a
lot of hate on all kinds of stuff oh
yeah no doubt so yeah and you're doing
breeding now too uh yeah so I just
started dabbling about six years ago
Crossing and then um reading your book
has helped me quite a bit you know as
far as reversing them now and then I've
been selfing some of my better venos
making seed with those um and then
mostly like I focus on type two flowers
which is like CBD and THC and so I've
been finding like my best like chem 91 I
just crossed with some of my best CBD
plants yeah to make some type two seeds
so that's that's my big focus is type
twos I really it's a good medical
product it is it really is and for me
I'm a little older and sometimes the
type ones are too much for me those type
twos just hit perfectly especially
during the day you know when I'm trying
to get stuff done totally and CBD is
just good for you in general feel like
oh yeah I eat CBD I I don't smoke as
much CBD as I'd like but I definitely
have been eating a lot of CBD at night
no it definitely helps me with sleep
I'll eat two gummies before I go to bed
inflammation yeah for me it's
inflammation exactly uh yeah I take like
an antihistamine sometimes I take badil
but I don't want to get addicted to
benad dril because I think benad dril
can be very addictive uhhuh especially
for sleep yeah I don't like Ben because
the next day I'm like a zombie you know
as good sleep I'm okay with Bene yeah
but CBD there's never any like you don't
have any side effects from it it's ex
it's always like you feel great yeah so
yeah and you just got on a trip to
Europe how was that we did uh we went
out to can ofest in Prague and um it was
amazing Prague was gorgeous it was a
magical City yeah uh the festival was
was very nice got to meet a lot of uh
seed breeders some from Italy some from
Switzerland and um a lot of flower
people got to meet the people that W
spannabis for CBD yeah last year um
really nice guys nice which guy from
Norway or no they're from uh Italy it's
called like we need and they spell it
weird like weeds in the middle or
something nice yeah Europe their
brandings real caricature kind of
cartoonish is what I was noticed you
can't do that in the States you totally
can't get away with that in metric
especially you know
cnia there's no cartoon anything like
that typically they're starting to do
that with the hemp side as well like all
these new they're regulating it with uh
the same stuff no cartoons you know all
that so yeah no animals no animals no
unicorns yeah yeah I mean it's it's
still you know they're behind us in some
ways in Europe and it's interesting
because I feel like they're not jaded by
the the wreck that we've you know the
wreck Market uh all the stuff that's
gone on with the farm bill there's still
it's still like uh 10 years 10 years ago
and there's people they're still super
excited about more excited than they are
in the states yeah so and I just went to
the Caribbean and they're even more
excited down there like their you know
their flower isn't as good as what we
typically see in the US but they love
wheat they love cannabis they love
cannabis on a medical level on a
spiritual level all these things and but
they're excited about it like that's
awesome the smiles on their faces and
how excited they are in St Vincent and
the gred is pretty amazing hell yeah
that's good stuff and I have noticed
that like in Europe when I go over there
I feel like yeah like you said like 10
years behind in a way is far as maybe
genetics but and their laws like the
laws uh we've been shipping flour over
now to UK and Switzerland different
countries they're all different you know
like Switzerland I think is 1% D I heard
Germany just switched to 1% too oh
really I didn't know that Czech
Republic's uh 1% but then you have UK
that's like 0.2 which you can't get
anything but like a CBG plant in there
right um very gray area I kind of
compare that to the hemp industry back
in maybe 2018 yeah so it's kind of you
look at it almost like a fortune teller
like I see where that's going I feel
like hopefully it'll take off you know
you'll dial it in I think everybody's
kind of dialing their stuff in the fact
that Germany went recreational huge huge
yeah it's just such a big step for
everybody you know it's like it's its
impact is so big on countries like the
United States that are holding out it's
like well Germany's doing it exactly I
think we really need to re-evaluate what
we're doing over here on a federal level
U
especially going I mean the funny thing
is is like you can't even go state to
state if they're medical you know or
state to state if they're recreational
so interstate commerce is off the table
right now and it needs to be a big
conversation because we have so many
medical and so many recreational states
that could be working with other states
and there's you know there's a lot of
money there for these states and you
know I think it would add a lot of value
to the states that aren't able to
produce as much exactly um and
especially places like California and
Oregon where they produce so much more
than they can consume exactly and I
think that might be where the hemp
industry kind of came in and you know
now they're shipping it out as thca
right and then but yeah that does suck
that that that yall you can't do
interstate commerce you know well I'm
just happy I'm focused on genetics and
not flowers exactly like I I keep that
focused it's like it's rough being a
cultivator in a licensed St right now e
even you know some of these new ones
that are coming online I mean that some
of them they have only a handful of
licenses and that makes it more
competitive um to a degree but I think
that if we're looking at States you know
and the future of where it goes it has
to go interstate commerce yeah um and
you know I like the fact that hemp is
legal everywhere I mean look at Texas
it's their big loophole for having legal
flow exactly and a lot of the east coast
states are that way you know Tennessee
is one uh
yeah Kentucky just now went medical we
were looking at getting a license up
there yeah but the regulations weren't
solid so we kind of backed off that one
but like States like Virginia North
Carolina are just you can still grow as
long as it's under3 Delta 9 right which
we all know doesn't really growing the
plant so you can get away with a lot
more a lot lot more in the hemp industry
yeah there's a lot less oversight for
sure yeah and just working with people
in other states and everything else you
by the books you're safe I know yeah
which is really it's really unique you
know being from
Tennessee I always wanted to do this for
a living you know and I knew one day I
would I KN never thought it'd be in this
fashion you know where we would still be
illegal in Tennessee and I had to move
and pivot over to the hemp industry so I
could grow because I've always been an
indoor grower right um and then once I
figured out I could grow you know CBD
plants the genetics were far enough
along so you like that Tennessee whiskey
too oh yeah yeah that's super close to
us actually Kentucky bourbon's probably
uh a little little better for me yeah
yeah I like Japanese whiskey yeah I mean
I like it all I don't drink that much
alcohol but I do like good whiskey I
mostly drink mcow and I drink tequila
yep that's me too I switched to Tequila
right five years ago getting older you
know that's what happens when I was
young I drink Everything Wine Coolers
yeah occasionally occasionally yeah
craft beers and now it's like all of
that gives me headaches yeah I don't
drink any beer and I love beer I
absolutely love the way it taste uh yeah
I mean I was drinking sier Nevada and
Lanas when I was like uh 18 years old so
I love that stuff I used to love Lanas
yeah me too yeah I worked for the
company I worked for Logan yeah I did
all kinds of stuff with Logan I was a
chef and did their Beer Circus okay and
so we traveled all around the United
States that was when they were starting
to become a bigger company is that when
they moved to Chicago and opened up a
spot there moved to Chicago they did
some beer circuses out there okay we did
them in New York Los Angeles Seattle all
over that had to be a good gig it was
amazing uh you know flying around with
these guys and these performers and it
was like I did the backstage food nice
and it was it was amazing it was just
you know it was like disco though once
it was gone it was gone yeah so yeah it
was fun while it lasted it was and in
the beginning it was I volunteered for
it uh I did it for 10 years okay and in
the beginning it was a volunteer gig and
I got my Chef friends together and we
basically went up there and put out food
for the volunteers and put out food for
the performers and it was a blast and it
was like it turned into something where
they were like okay we got to take care
of you now that we're with Heineken it
was especially around when hinin merged
with yeah and H hinin acquired them uh
they decided that they couldn't just
allow me to do it for free I got and so
they had to cover my expenses and all
these other things and it was just a
blast and it was like the company was
just accelerating so fast and then just
the energy was so good at these events
it's like a lot of cannabis people too
yeah I went up to pedala years ago and
got to tour the brewery and everything
it was it was very neat yeah I mean they
are the most cannabis Centric beer
company in existence definitely and yeah
big shout out to to Tony and Jeremy
Marshall and H Ron and Jimmy and those
those guys just we go way back
especially Ron and Jimmy and it's like
we the 420 parties that they're brw were
always a blast yeah they had like that
Pavilion out there where they'd have
music and everything oh yeah and even
before that they had like a in in one of
the in basically where they brew the
beer there was an upstairs area where
they did they had a bar up there and
they had a 420 party um the first
Tuesday of every month at
420 and yeah it was it was always a
blast and we used to smoke a lot back
then too yeah but yeah and good beer I
mean just really good beer and I feel
like they kind of saw beer how we see
cannabis too like Jeremy Marshall
and Tony
McGee uh they had that Vision you know
as far as like they they they visualized
how we visualized cannabis they were
visualizing beer way back then way ahead
of their time that is so cool and now
everybody kind of sees beer like that
they all these different flavors you
know it's like just like cannabis we've
got thousands of different flavors
exactly when it comes to beer it's like
there's also everybody's got their own
you know micro brew or craft beer you
ever get into like sour beers or
anything I do I like sour be I like
Belgian I like all kinds of stuff like
goas you ever heard those are good oh
yeah yeah yeah I mean I I like it all so
it's funny in the Caribbean we drink
warm Guinness oh really and uh yeah they
they make a special extra bitter
Guinness for the Caribbean okay and you
drink it warm and it's it's just the
thing to do and it's like uh I've been
out to the Caribbean I don't know a
dozen times or something like that and
it's just part of the adventure you know
it's like that's what everybody does I I
drink warm beer when I'm out in the
Caribbean no problem is it good it's not
bad it gets you buzzed pretty quick but
it's also not actually I think it's like
7% out there because regular Guinness I
think is yeah lower yeah so and then I
like dude like traditional beer in
Munich you can't beat the Bavarian ale
you know all the different beers out in
Munich I've been October Fest it's a
blast yeah heck yeah I always wanted to
do that my dad was born in Germany so
it's been on my bucket list I think I'm
going to go there this year for their uh
I think it's Mary James
we're definitely going to Mary Jane
Germany as well uh spannabis you got to
go spannabis yeah I'll definitely be
there with Strain Hunters and the
greenhouse seed company I think I'm
gonna enter a couple of the cups and
spanis this year I might do your Mystic
Mountain blueberry you should yeah I
think I am yeah I would love to promote
it out there for you yeah D that would
be awesome I think it has a chance for
sure it's special yeah you know the
extracts they've really stepped up
especially Spain is Rosen
is amazing they have rosin out there
that's really really top shelf I love
rosin too M uh smoke mostly flow smoke
mostly joints but also rosin yeah love
rosin now hash holes I for a while I was
like n I'm not smoking those hash holes
and now it's like I had a surplus of
rosin people have been giving me rosin
so I've been mixing it with joints and I
love it I love Skittles with different
kinds of rosin I've never tried a hash
hole I've always wanted to try one of
those I bet they're phenomenal well the
day is Young so so yeah we can totally
get into hash holes it's like that's one
of those things you can go down the
rabbit hole with because it's like
pairing flavors it's a lot of fun and
it's like that's a good call I like
Skittles because I feel like it's a base
candy flavor and then you can take that
and you could put almost anything with
it you can go gas with it you can go
more candy you can go any direction you
can go some of these papayas taste
amazing with it uh the super boof Cherry
which is one of my favorite
extracts uh that stuff tastes great and
it's like a little bit of Tangi rind but
also cherry and all these other flavors
and it's just really loud nice I love it
I got some bubble left over from the
Dabo very small amount yeah think I got
like a half gram but those make some
great hash holes too it's good Stu what
is that dabad do I saw a couple things
about it on Instagram so the dabad do is
this great event for Mila Jansen um
she's the hash Queen okay yeah and she
started it and I was part of the one in
San Francisco and basically what it is
is a competition hash competition we had
three categories we had a rosin we had a
we had a a bubble like ice water and
then we had a traditional SL Temple ball
category okay and so people enter and
then before we used to give little small
samples to everybody and Sam jur from
Focus V and rosent Tech and he helped
put it on with me and we decided to
instead of doing it the way where we
everyone got like a 0.1 we were going to
have jars where people could get a
sample out of the jar that would be
better they could they could grade the
visual appeal they could smell it they
could get so many more things out of
seeing a big jar of it so we had five
gram jars that basically got passed
around and they got to try all the
different entries nice and so yeah and
then we had some awesome winners it was
a great time we did we filmed a little
documentary a little mini documentary
for YouTube Sweet you guys should check
it out if you haven't already uh but
yeah and it's a blasted so she does
those all over the world and this was
the 10 year anniversary this year of San
Francisco but which was actually in
Oakland it was it was still amazing yeah
uh good times and you know it kind of
fell together last minute and sometimes
those are the best ones where it's like
you're not sure if it's going to be good
you're G to do the best you can and you
have a really good team exactly and yeah
and those guys dude Sam's team is just
spectacular like those guys really put
on a good show uh even though it was a
lot of last minute stuff it was like
nobody knew that it was last minute it
felt very put together put together very
well produced I feel like uh the whole
thing was a blast I hate I miss this
year's Emerald cup yeah I was really
wanting to come out I just couldn't make
it with work yeah they did in Oakland
this year it was interesting it was
different so yeah you got to come out
for re on the river okay and California
canif Fest okay that's another fun one
what time what part of the year uh so
reg on the river is in the summer it's
in August and canif Fest is in September
and canest is in Humble and it's it's a
music event too where they they makes
music in cannabis reg on the river
there's cannabis stuff there but it's
very music okay I got you you know I
think they got royal gold and some other
people there but yeah like the music
lineup is amazing the sound system is
great like the ree artists are
phenomenal and uh you know we're in VIP
camping we have a great time I do a lot
of cooking there too heck yeah so yeah
it's it's a blast and then canest is
great because that's in humbled uh super
far away from here but yeah it's a trek
but it's you know it's a beautiful time
of year it wasn't too hot out there and
uh yeah I I had a great time I'm going
back next year for sure heck yeah I'll
have to make that trip for sure um you
know Kevin and John from Cutting Edge
absolutely yeah I think I almost met you
back in MJ biscon last year at their
booth and I missed you I was at their
Booth last year for sure yeah those are
some good guys man Kevin Sean and John
Big Sean and John yeah those guys we we
do events together party together and I
love those I could listen to John
forever just yeah sit down with him and
he's got he's just a wealth of knowledge
he's the best yeah he's he's the best
he's an OG I I I love hanging out with
him uh he's just a lot of fun and same
thing with Shawn Shawn is like we had a
blast with sha at rean in the river and
hanging out on the river you know Sean's
just he's he's a lot of fun and he's
smart and I I love he's like the Next
Generation coming in if you look at JN
and then we got Shawn uh you know right
behind John and he's just it's great
having people like that in the industry
that care so much and that are not all
about the money they see the value in
the quality right quality of nutrients
quality of what they're doing and it
stems over to everything else the
quality of their friends uh the quality
of the food they like the events they go
to it's just uh those are the kind of
people we need more of in the industry I
couldn't agree more definitely yeah and
they make some good nutrients they do
they do I yeah it's they're they're
great people when they make good
nutrients um we're fortunate that
there's a ton of people in this industry
that care slowly but surely they've gone
away but that's a whole another
conversation but yeah know I there's
there's a lot of big business and
there's a lot of people that still care
and it's been tough as a cultivator it's
tough right now it's tough to compete so
you really have to focus on quality of
your product right I think that's the
most important thing I know you do
because I smoke your product so it's
like I mean we have to in the CBD world
you know it's like it doesn't get you
high so it's got to taste good it's got
to smoke good so we focus on quality
above everything yeah I think the the
visual appeal of your product is great
and some of the packaging like you did
some packaging with you did the Mac one
with cap yeah and you got the little
hats on the the jars and I'm like this
is this is I brought you one totally
yeah that's that's awesome I love that I
love that side of the industry where you
can be creative and it still is
functional um and you know I'm sure cap
loves it he's I still got to get him on
my show yeah he's incredible man that
guy is a character he's like once we
started selling them you know across the
country he's like man this is historic
for me you know because I mean and it
makes sense being in the hemp industry
we can sell all over and for him his
brand is California based and to have it
Go all over the country I'm sure that
was a really good uh good surprise for
him for sure he's another one that cares
oh yeah he's super passionate and
anybody who says the cap doesn't care
they don't know cap because at 20 in
2017 at Emerald cup he wore his little
disguise mhm and he had the longest line
there was probably a 400 foot long line
to meet him and he spent time with every
single person yeah and I don't know
anybody else who does that on that level
that is out there and wants to spend
time with the people that want to talk
to him exactly a lot of people when when
you get you get to a certain level they
they act like they're better than other
people and I'm not naming any names or
specifically talking about any one
person but a lot of people they start
getting this celebrity status or
whatever and they start feeling like
they're a celebrity and really we're
just all the same yeah right we're just
all people trying to do our job and yeah
none of us are special I I think if we
can get over that whole thing that we're
not special we're just here to do what
we're here to do and if you can get over
that thing then you can really do
amazing things in this world I know and
it just cracks me up that he still hides
his character like there's not many
people in this world
you can't find the face for the name you
know what I mean and it's just he's like
wiie Wonka in a way oh yeah it's part of
his image right and it's great you know
and he's got his Mac one and he's you
know I think we wrote a case study in
the book for with the Mac one and I
thought that was extremely valuable as a
partial triploid uh natural partial
triploid yeah you can't really breed
with it very well no it's a it's an
interesting cul ofar and it it is a
beautiful plant yeah you know all it
really is like I've grown many of plants
and that one's like one and a million
it's just so different and just so and
you're right like I have a pretty good
story about the Mac one I tried
reversing it uh probably like six eight
months ago before I knew that it wasn't
really good as far as good luck yeah so
I took 22 of my best strains in the
building my favorite ones pollinated it
after pollinated all of them and then
after they were done I found 10 seeds
out of those 10 seeds one sprouted and
I'm growing that one in at my house
right now and hoping crossing my fingers
like it's it's a good one and it's
turning out to be decent but you know
it's just so hard I didn't realize how
hard it was to and probably
self-pollinated it's not even it's like
exactly that would be the funniest thing
ever is you go there's no Mac in it I
know and that happens you know and it's
just one of those things but it's a good
learning experience all these things are
good learning experiences exactly what
do you do for your reversals for your
reversal spray so we use uh is it sodium
thy sod th sufate with silver nitrate
nit yeah yeah sorry and uh yeah we spray
them I do it three times a day um until
they're basically start producing male
flowers three times a day and you use a
very mild concentration one let's see
what was it like 100 milliliters to
about 500 milliliters something like
that yeah so one to five maybe
interesting yeah I believe so can't yeah
everybody has their own recipes there's
a good recipe in my my book from Khalifa
genetics I didn't include a STS recipe
that was my own for liability purposes I
use a nano silver myself okay that
really works well for me and my friend
Tim humiston makes it it's awesome
stuff uh but everyone has their own way
and there's several ways to block
ethylene in the plant so you can get a
good reversal yeah uh so yeah it's just
it's all about trying different things
and figuring out the one that works for
you there's some that are like one and
done you spray it right when you flip
boom you have some you have some male
flowers right and you have poll sacks
you know so and I've experimented with
some different stuff and I keep going
back to the same thing I just I like the
way it reverses the plant I feel like
it's super healthy and I get these crazy
reversals where they do dump a lot
different than regular pollen you know
regular pollen you can poll one little
plant will pollinate a whole room you
can make 100,000 seeds yeah more than
100,000 seeds with one male it's crazy
and one female you you probably it's
five to one but it just depends on the
cultivar some reverse really easily some
reverse a lot you they're harder to
reverse yeah I'm finding that out as
well yeah no plants the same when it
comes to that no and you have to almost
have a specific sop for each cultivar uh
some of them I found that you have to
start spraying a lot earlier on and
other ones you could probably start
spraying the day before flower and
you're going to get a reversal just fine
so you're just spraying one time no no
no I start two weeks before okay on
certain cultivars if they're really hard
I start two two weeks before M if I know
the plant and I know that I can do it in
one week because a lot of them all do
that and you can start a week before and
then you go until you see flowers but a
lot of time you start two weeks before
with the nano silver I get the results
I'm looking for I gotta and then if
you're introducing them into other
plants you basically flip your your uh
donors two weeks before your receivers
that's what we're doing yeah yeah and
it's not always I've had them where you
flip them the same time and they come
out perfect certain cultivars basically
they'll produce male flowers a lot
quicker and then they dump quicker but I
like short pollen windows so I try to
keep them separate mhm introduce
intermingle the plants and do that with
as short of a a window as possible so
the seeds are as even as possible so
when you introduce them to a female say
you're dealing with a early finisher
like 50 56 days is there a certain day I
guess you could say or days like what
okay so like a 70-day plant would you
still introduce it around a 21 or day 21
to 28 it just depends
on uh like the bud size may it depends
on the bud size it depends on how
developed it is certain things you may
have to wait a little bit longer you
know longer flowering but then some of
the longer flowering ones finish faster
when you pollinate them okay right and
so but you have to wait until you have a
substantial amount of bra and you have
the pistols that'll pull that pollen
okay uh so it's all very unique to each
individual cultivar yeah you can you can
generalize and say okay you know the
three and a half weeks on day 25 that's
when you introduce your pollen um you
know and I also love having redundancies
the other thing is having a jar of
pollen along with those reversals
because those reversals don't always go
as planned yeah so having backup pollen
is one of the most important things with
breeding as a
redundancy and a lot of people you know
you learn that from [__] up that's
how I learned it I learned it from
[__] up because i' I tried to reverse
some stuff that didn't reverse well and
I didn't get good reversal but I think
redundancies are one of the most
important things when you're doing stuff
like breeding I gotta So speaking of
this totally off topic but speaking of
like early finishing I read somewhere
about flowering 11 hours on and 13 hours
off and them finishing earlier have you
ever heard anything like that is that is
that just some R science no that I mean
there there might be some truth to that
I don't know like equatorial varieties
apparently if you flower them 11 on and
13 off definitely get them to trigger
faster I know for a fact you yeah that
makes sense so like with triggering them
faster there's all kinds of stuff you
can do but definitely like the longer
flowering they don't want sometimes they
don't want to flip like so these 16 week
varieties if you're doing them indoors
you might have to do a few things so
sometimes it's lowering the light down
to eight or 10 hours and then they're
only getting eight or 10 hours of light
and the rest is darkness and then also
basically changing your temperatures so
your daytime temp there's a bigger swing
between daytime and nighttime temp okay
that helps and if nothing else you can
go hit them with some PK I got you yeah
that'll get them going yeah avoid the
nitrog hit them with some PK some some
and you can foler them uh that works
really well um and those are like the
three things I would say if you're
trying to get them to flip faster if
you're making seeds okay all right good
tips yeah I mean those are just trial
and error you know I've had friends give
me advice and tried it and it seems to
work pretty
good so and I like longer flowering
varieties you know my my buddy Dave from
budalo he's kind of got me back on the
path of longer flowering is good and I'm
like you're right longer fling is good
it's also stronger a lot of times but
stronger can be good too yeah exactly
you know and it's not always stronger
sometimes it's like uh these ones they
they lift you up and then they you just
stay there you know but you feel good
it's not like stronger like heart
palpitations yeah I'm not really big
into the anxiety weed I can't stand it
like I got friends that tell me I'm like
I can't stand that one they're like
that's the one I want some people love
that the heart Racers I'm like I got
heart issues as it is I don't mean to be
you know faking myself out yeah so yeah
I feel you and I do like I like some of
the upside you know sativas I do like
you know I do like a good sativa I like
the strawberry cough I love the
Strawberry Cough a great one yeah as far
as like effect it's like a stronger Blue
Dream we've talked about Kyle kushman on
the show it's a good one it's like a
stronger blue dream has that uplifting
effect where you feel really good yeah
it's like borderline panic attack for me
it is but it's not it's like right under
yeah yeah whereas some of the super
silver haze if you dab some super silver
haze that can get you your imagine yeah
I think Tangi might have been the
strongest C I don't even know if it's C
but as far as panic attacks go really I
tried that back in um it was probably
2016 in
Denver interesting because I've never
got I I felt like 10 wasn't always as
strong for me really yeah but that's
depending on when you harvest it too
that could be like okay they took it
freaking two weeks past where You'
normally harvested that'll give you
panic attacks yeah that'll totally give
you panic attacks yeah
autoflow autoflow will do that too if
you go like 90 days on autoflow to try
to get it to yield more or you feel like
it's going to produce more and you just
watch it and you should have harvested
on day 65 it's going to be way stronger
typically think it's it converts Maybe
it does and sometimes they go up and
you're getting more Delta 9 probably but
also you know it changes the whole
cannaboid profile yeah tarpine profile
and and with the Entourage effect you it
can be you know especially going like a
week longer sometimes it can go up and
then drop right but a lot of times I
feel like that's where you can get Delta
9 in too especially in the flower is if
you go longer with exactly you if you
harvest it earlier it's going to be hemp
but all these hemp varieties almost all
of them if you you go longer with them
they're going to turn into Delta 'll
start all of them yeah right they'll all
get like they all go past that 3%
threshold there's nothing that won't go
past it and that's why it's so hard for
the government to make rules and
regulations around it because it's like
dude like if you harvest it you have
this Harvest window and you test it a
month
before it's hard to say what could
happen you know it's like and it's just
so hard to actually put it into numbers
on a piece of paper where it's like okay
these are the rules for this Reon
because every situation doesn't fit
exactly and every plant's different you
every plant's so different like I've
done thousands of tests coas looked at
them I mean that's what we have to do in
our industry and certain plants you can
take all the way to term like Mac one
for example yeah and then just do an
early test when it's not all the way
cured out and you'll get a compliant
test yeah whereas um Dante's Inferno I
believe is another one you could even
take that a little early but it's going
to fail every time just because the
Delta 9 spikes Donny Burger yeah we
don't have Donnie Burger on here because
it's like one of those ones is just test
dirty it'll test past that three
threshold from the beginning exactly
yeah it's like so and there's nothing I
love Donny Burger extract shout out to
Floren flame for growing some of the
best Donnie burger and making the best
rosin with it phenomenal stuff but that
stuff tests hot from the beginning we
don't have it you know it's like I do
hemp research and development we keep it
on the building yeah yeah so yeah it's
just easier so I got a question on like
drying and curing U what's your sweet
spot like when you're drying and get
like when what day so 660 is a rule of
thumb but like sometimes you can go that
60 to
65 uh you know as far as for humidity
yeah right like when you smoke like when
you pulling it down like I'm an early
like I like smoking when it's you know
mid teens like of hanging like I don't
like waiting too much farther now we we
usually go 10 days and then we trim it
down like that's what I leave uh you
know and it's just depending on the
situation but like around 10 days it
start you know but I feel like 14 day
it's we do a 14-day dry that's what we
do yeah I think 14 days is the normal
dry period but sometimes we'll trim it
at day 10 depending on how big the buds
are and all the other things you know
you're looking for that crack with the
stem yeah uh that snap you want that
little I guess what I'm saying is I just
like the buzz better when it's early you
know I think the Tarpin and everything
Oh you mean when you harvest early yeah
so not necessarily harvesting or but
smoking the flour before it's cured out
some people say one month cure two month
cure yeah I mean I've been a lot I've
been so the funniest part that's great
that you brought this up because I've
been going back and forth I do feel like
especially with the Skittles that we've
been getting that my friends are going
so we have cultivation partners and
these guys over SF can are crushing it
on a whole another level they did some
dirt Skittles recently and grown in soil
dirt Skittles dirt Skittles I call it
dirt Skittles but it's just so oil grown
Skittles right I got you but side by
side with the Coco growing in the same
environment with the same nutrition same
lighting everything else same flush and
the dirt Skittles was [__] amazing
and the thing is is they harvest on day
53 but it's a fresh product and if you
harvest it right correctly you dry it
cure it right when it's done after the
two weeks that's when it was the best
right yeah week three it was still good
week four it was still good week five it
was starting to be not as good but like
literally it's phenomenal like that and
that stuff it's the first time I smoke
Skittles where I'm like damn the
Skittles is strong and it was so floral
that it would coat your teeth like from
a joint nice and it's like I I have some
of that we'll smoke some of that later
hell yeah it was just it's like one of
those ones where it's like and that's
when it you know the like connoisseur
flower it's grown at this level where
you can't even get it that good every
time you grow it that's what's so
special and then like fresh fresh is the
best turp loocks are great for
preserving it you know we got Lance
coming on the show soon again um but
yeah I mean I think there's ways to
preserve it where it's good but the best
is that fresh fresh product especially
if you like TPS yeah and I just feel
like the effects are cleaner and uh yeah
not as heavy I guess is the word maybe
and I think it's cult ofar specific too
no doubt yeah so some of the stuff last
great for a long time and but the the
stuff I really like like that Z mhm it's
just when it's the freshest is the very
best I don't know if I've ever tried
straight Skittles uh it'll change your
life like I've grown a lot of your
crosses with it yeah but I've never
actually tried it well the funny thing
is a lot of those traits that you're
looking for with the Skittles are
recessive so if you smoke it like a lot
of times in the progyny of the seeds
that are crossed with it you're not
going to get it right out the gate you
have to do work with the breathing and
like some of the back crosses have some
of the Skittles stuff where it's Skitty
but then the Skittles has the shitty
structure right so it's always the ones
that look the worst
where you're like no that's not a good
one but then you're like [__] it smells
good so yeah that's it's like there's so
many times where you like you go through
the room you're like that's the that's
the one it looks like the one but then
you got to smell it um and we go through
rounds for feno hunting we go through
the the rounds on the plant where we're
like smelling them we're looking them a
lot of times the ones that look the best
aren't the ones that smell the best it's
just that tradeoff yeah and then once
you dry and cure them and then you have
them in the bag that's when that's the
real test right day it's like okay well
let's line them all up and let's smoke
them and compare them isn't it so much
fun favorite thing it's totally amazing
Christmas every day I love it where they
it all lines up where it's like [__] it
looks amazing smells amazing tastes
amazing it checks all these boxes and
it's like wow and you go through 600
plants and you might find 60 things that
are worthy and then you might
find five or six of those that are that
are pretty stand itish that you want to
keep running and so it's funny with F
hunting so when you feno hunt is what's
your typical seed like how many do you
usually do per variety is it it depends
it's every year we're doing different
we're doing tons of stuff uh Outdoors
we're doing stuff in different places
I've been working in the Caribbean now
and so next year we're going to be doing
some uh variety testing and feno study
down there to see what actually performs
the best and I'm excited about that too
cuz now we're looking at you know more
of a tropical type climate where it's
high humidity uh so stuff that has
powdery milde resistance and petritis
resistance it's going to stand out a lot
definitely yeah anytime you're in that
human environment that's warm it's like
that's just a recipe for ruining your OG
cush and that's basically the opposite
of what y'all have here pretty much is
it it's it's the opposite in a lot of
ways you know it's so hard to dry and
cure and store the flour correctly in
those places it's totally possible right
but you need a controlled environment to
do it you can't just do it in a hut you
have to spend some money you have to
take some time and you have to do it
correctly yeah and I think St Vincent
and the Grenadines is this amazing place
and they have this really amazing
opportunity within the Cannabis space to
impact the quality of life for the
people there and it's being you know
supervised by the government they're
very supportive of medical cannabis nice
and it's like great when you go to the
government and they're like H how can we
help our people instead of you guys are
just annoying exactly over here we're
just more or less annoying to the
government you know it's we're not going
away they know we're not going away but
we're more like this thorn in the side
of the government yeah whereas you know
they they wish we could go away the
redheaded stepchild oh absolutely
whereas you know down in some of these
places in the Caribbean and not not to
say there's bad people in the government
or there's not people that care because
there is yeah right but down in the
Caribbean the government and they have
the the medical cannabis Authority the
MCA and they are very very supportive of
medical cannabis and how can we make our
people healthier how can we take this
plant and use it as medicine you know
and I feel like they all recognize that
the Island was built on the shoulders of
cannabis Growers and how can we support
our traditional Growers as well and so
there's this different mindset down
there and I love that I love the support
by the government and the people in the
government that talk so highly of
cannabis that's beautiful you don't see
that very many places you know no you
know I think a lot of politicians are
afraid CU they're lose votes you know
and so that's got to change slowly but
surely there's there's guys that we're
not young anymore but there's guys that
are young coming up that have very
positive outlooks and I feel like slowly
the old guys that are anti are going
away and it's becoming normalized and
it's not normalized fully but it's
definitely becoming more normal yeah
blows my mind it's 2025 almost I know
it's we're still I'm still in an illegal
State dude and then places like Texas I
never thought it would be legal and they
got CBD shops everywhere and they're
selling flow everywhere it's wild that
was something else I noticed in Prague
when I was out there they had these
cannabis shops all over the place yeah
and it's only 1% but it's not really
regulated so it's kind of like a wild
west out there it's like a free-for-all
totally but it's all the same flower too
and it's all basic garbage well and
these are steps to getting it normalized
yeah right and so yeah even though and
the Caribbean the flower that I saw for
the most part was not that great mhm uh
and also controlling the temperature and
humidity in when you're storing it and
you know like people carrying around
showing people and using it it's like
every time you open that jar you get
humidity in flow and all of a sudden
your turps are gone yep and you're left
with something and a lot of it's Sun
grown and not grown with proper
nutrition
typically and so you're not getting a
super resinous product anyway but some
of it was good and some of it has
potential and I think the whole country
has potential
you know the whole island has potential
to do great things that is such a neat
project man yeah well it's like all we
have to do is be right one time it's
like we're going there to work with the
government to do these breeding projects
and I feel like we can go learn a lot
about the plant I can learn a lot more
about the plant working there than I
could doing stuff here right you know
it's like we can do a lot here too but I
can do it here and do it there at the
same time and you know the potential for
collaboration with other International
Brands is huge I think there's other
people that are in the same mindset that
we can go in and we can make a
difference and I love working with
people that have that same belief like
it's doesn't have to be about money it
doesn't have to be just about money it
can be about making a difference for the
people and building the community from
the inside exactly give them the plant
medicine you know I'm not going there to
sell them seeds that I make here I want
to go there and I want to help them
breed seeds so they can create seeds on
the island for themselves and Infuse
that money into the community and I
think that
there's so much benefit I'll get so much
benefit out of doing that too it's like
oh yeah you know besides feeling good
besides you know feeling and knowing
like that's what you're supposed to like
I feel like that's what I'm supposed to
be doing here I know that that's part of
my reason that I'm on this planet is to
do good things and do things like that I
agree totally yeah I feel the same way
like feel like this plant found me in a
way you know I've been growing for
almost 30 years now yeah and every
everything from crawl spaces to attics
to basement you know wherever I could
find a space when you're on the right
path you know it I feel like start
things start to line up yeah and if if
things aren't lining up you need to
re-evaluate your situation and see what
you're doing wrong but like when you're
doing the right thing a lot of times
things will start lining up for you out
of nowhere all these things are lining
up you know some of these long shot
things are like wow this is really
coming together like 100% I was on stage
with Marlon Asher at the ree Festival
can Bliss in front of thousands of
people presenting the head of the
medical cannabis Authority and
presenting for the minister of
Agriculture and other people presenting
an economic plan that could
hopefully Infuse hundreds of millions of
dollars over the next 10 years that's
incredible yeah and it's great and it's
like but it takes more than just
presenting them you know I mean it's not
like I can just present them and then
they're good yeah it can't be here's
some seeds it has to be okay here's a
game plan now who do I have that's GNA
help me with this game plan down here
and how are we gonna execute this thing
yeah to make it work you know so yeah
and people get excited about that stuff
I feel like just talking to the people
they're excited about it you know it's
like some of these companies down there
too that are already in existence are
excited about it yeah that's one
beautiful thing about this plan is it
brings people together you know totally
it's like nobody gets this excited about
tomatoes but Canabis is tomato Farmers
yeah well you don't know any tomato
farmers do you yeah but I think actually
yeah I've made similar jokes around
tomato Farmers they're like actually
actually tomato farmers do get this
excited about tomatoes and I get so I
grow heirloom tomatoes right every year
I grow heirlooms in my backyard and this
year was no exception um and we grew
some awesome awesome tomatoes and I get
excited to eat heirloom tomatoes I love
fresh heirloom tomatoes that have never
been refrigerated you just can't get
that quality in the store and uh for me
it's like I don't know where I'd be
without tomatoes I know and not only do
they taste so good but you feel like
when you're eating them it's just so
good for you you know all the flavors
when they're so clean the flavors are so
clean and they're sweet and they're not
mine aren't very acidic the heirlooms I
get are very flavorful they're very
sweet there's a little bit of acid but
it's not like when you refrigerate them
that you get this uh acid that comes out
of I can't remember what the chemical is
called but Ryan's going to put it up on
the screen for you guys right now no no
but they do use ethylene to ripen yeah
okay okay yeah but with the you
refrigerate them it creates this this
chemical compound that changes them okay
chemically and so they have a different
flavor oh I didn't know that what kind
of varieties did you grow we do some
purple varieties we do
uh we always do a cherry we do uh
kamanche I believe it's called okay we
do uh then we do like a hybrid beef
steak but typically it's heirlooms have
you ever done a Cherokee purple Cherokee
purple that's what we did okay yeah
that's a great one that's a really good
one that's actually out from where I'm
from out in North Carolina that's a good
one so those are great and they grow in
most places and they they yield pretty
good I think they they've been around
forever and I think they're they're one
of the most flavorful too and if you do
with a little bit of Bara a little bit
of fresh basil that you grow on your own
property oh yeah some fresh olive oil
and fresh balsamic yeah that I could eat
that every day I know so yeah and then
uh you're in Tennessee mhm you are
expanding to Europe too as far we are uh
cuz so the th CA Market here that uh we
created kind of like two or three years
ago um since then the CBD market for
flower has kind of gone downhill in the
US so being that's all we can grow in
Tennessee at our two facilities we had
the branch out and so I've been focused
on finding other outlets for a flower
yeah and fortunate enough we have in the
last six months I went to London for a
Expo out there met some people and then
um slowly but surely I don't know if it
was the emerald cup wins or what but in
the last 6 months flow Gardens has
developed quite traction out in the UK
especially but also in Europe so that's
awesome yeah we're trying man we're just
trying it's a family based business my
mom works there you know my sister runs
the other facility so that's the best
trying to keep everybody fed and going
yeah it's not easy no it's not no a lot
of people don't understand it's not it's
not all roses no we actually we're
starting up another facility uh up in
Virginia where we can grow the thca
because they're starting to change the
laws in Tennessee now oh wow so I mean
it's it's tough It's like if you don't
like roller coasters yeah you don't need
to be in this industry because it's all
over it is and you if you don't like
stress I feel that that's just also
owning a business there's always stress
you got to of course you be the master
of stress but not having a clear Runway
is the worst yeah you're basically just
every month na they keep moving the
needle and it's like okay you're
compliant and then you got to do this
new thing to be compliant again
keep on you know and I mean that's just
part of the business yeah and it's
always going to be like that exactly and
it's a vol business yeah yeah but I mean
I love the plant so much there's no way
I could ever think about doing anything
else at this point well it's great when
you can wake up in the morning and be
excited to to work even when it's
stressful yeah it never gets old like I
said every day is like Christmas you and
it's there's always something new to
learn and [__] breaks every day yeah
problems there's always problem floods
floods you guys get floods yeah I mean
we're known as flood Gardens half the
time you know it's just uh it is what it
is it's part of it yeah I mean in the
yeah it's it's interesting well how's
power out there is it expensive you know
it's not that bad we're out in the
country uh I want to throw out a number
I think it's like 11 cents a kilowatt or
something cheap yeah not as cheap as
Washington some areas in Washington are
like I think seven or nine cents yeah
but even still that's just so cheap
compared to here yeah it's definitely
I'd say so like San Francisco is super
expensive we went out to dinner last
night and I was like wow yeah it's like
20 bucks for a salad okay yeah and it's
about that big yeah exactly but but yeah
and the food's good I mean it's all
there and I feel like that's the thing
with food though there's there's a price
point for everybody you want to go spend
$100 on a salad I know a spot yeah for
that same small salad well not same it's
going to be different probably less
ingredients
more organic and $100 and $100 yeah and
that's just the salad jeez yeah the
bread is probably $20 so you were a chef
right oh yeah yeah I was a chef for
years um on and off and I mean I still
cook I still cook for my friends so much
more fun cooking for your friends uh I'm
not a cannabis Chef I don't do the
infused dinners it's never been my thing
I just just because I'm not I prefer
smoking and eating me too and I'm not
big on putting a whole bunch of th in my
dinner so that I'm high an hour and a
half later exactly that just doesn't for
me it doesn't appeal to me putting tpin
in or frying some fan leaves that sounds
cool you know some deep fried fan leaves
yeah never tried that panko crusted fan
leaves I mean sure or or even just
frying them crisp like there's all kinds
of cool things you can do with cannabis
that I think would be great but as far
as infusing like infusing dinners aren't
my thing yeah no I get that so I'm a
lightweight when it comes to Edibles I
love rosin yummies I love the T I've had
some of those before I think they're
from out here I had them gifted to me
they were delicious rosin does they they
did these white Thorn Rose ones and it's
like they they added no flavor it was
the flavor of the turpins and it was
that white Thorn rose that was just so
can you tell me a little bit about that
I've heard so much about that strain
like what's the flavor on it I've been
dying to dry it so yeah it's Unique it's
got like a a nice floral character but
it's like it's not just the flavor that
makes it so special it's flal floral
it's vanilla it's it's purple flower
right a gorgeous plant it's a gorgeous
looking plant it's about the effect it's
special it's beyond special because I
call it Feelgood weed you can call
whatever you want but for me it's that
one I could smoke in the morning the
afternoon the evening I can smoke it
when I'm in a good mood I can smoke it
when I'm in a bad mood and it still
makes me feel good and I feel like if
more people were able to try it they
would all like cannabis like I feel like
some people they might get a experience
because they got too high or whatever
this is not one of those things you
don't necessarily get too high but you
get you get the right High you get the
right effect yeah and there's only a
handful of things I've experienced in my
life that have that where it's like you
smoke it and you feel amazing almost
like euphoric it's almost euphoric but
you just feel really really good and
it's you're not tight behind the eyes
you're not you know your your face isn't
tight in any way shape or form you it
relaxes you if anything you feel really
relaxed and you feel happy
and I think the world needs more of that
100% I agree you know and there's
nothing wrong with the anxiety we
there's somebody who likes it you know
there's definitely people who like that
stuff yeah but uh you know and the the
further along we get with these these
breeding projects that people are doing
I think the more we discover what's out
there and there's people that are
prioritizing effect I think there are a
lot of people that prioritize the way it
tastes or the way it looks but a lot of
people need to go back to that effect
how does it make you feel all right I
agree totally because I've had venos
like that that were just you know
beautiful but the effects just weren't
there you know so therefore I don't put
that one in production yeah you know it
has to have that feel like you said to
feel good we don't need another Oreos
like that that just looks good doesn't
tastes great purple punch same thing
it's like I'm I'm super anti-p purple
punch but again these things are one
step away from being great you just need
to be worked you know and I think purple
punch makes some great crosses that have
great effect but as far as by itself
like these things where they're they're
we call them cardboard TPS yeah
cardboard you fire it up and it's like
you almost taste flavor and then like
for Oreos it's just not a good flavor I
don't I don't enjoy the flavor I love
the way it looks I think it looks great
it's great Instagram flow yeah just
muted you know nothing special yeah
nothing special nothing special about
the effect or about the the way it
tastes I'm uh growing some ice block
from Third Coast it's Oreos and
blackberry blockberry yeah yeah that
blockberry is pretty good it's got some
special traits super vigorous plants
like huge fan leaves um haven't tried it
yet we just harvested a couple plants
last week but and yeah they're good it's
um real like punch breath have you you
tried that one before it's just like
fruit punch
overtones really good I don't think I've
tried punch breath another one Cadillac
rainbows that one I've never had
Cadillac rainbows sounds Co it smells
like garlic and onions and it just fills
the room it's probably the most pungent
flower I've smelled in a while that's a
good one nice but once again anxiety
right yeah yeah it's funny and there's
so many directions you can go with
effect too it's like it's not either a
cative or stimula it's not just I mean
we can people box them in these things
Indica sativa it's like no there's all
these different effects exact some give
you the munchies like crazy like there's
specific things I've been dieting right
and I lost a bunch of weight there's
things I cannot smoke there's specific
cultivars that grown by my friends I
love the way they taste I love the way
they smoke but then they make me want to
go clear out the fridge literally raid
the fridge at 2 in the morning yeah you
know so I can't do that I can't do those
ones and some of the yeah I mean I think
GDP is the one it's one of those ones
that always made me hungry all the time
and so I prefer the other but then I got
this boost pen that's thcv I don't know
if you're growing any thcv uh a little
bit not really though so there's this
this pen that my friends gave me from
House of coltivar and and it's this new
thcv pen it's got some other stuff in it
too other canono uh T specific turpins
and it made me have not only did it make
me have anxiety but it definitely didn't
make me hungry it made me feel sick and
I was thinking it was something else
that was making me sick I thought maybe
I was getting sick my stomach was
twisting and literally went in the
bathroom and like dry heaved a little
bit and I'm like oh man couldn't figure
out what it was well I felt better after
a little bit and and then I went and
took another hit and I'm like [__] it's
it's the pen damn pen it's the pen this
thing's wild and it's like a to it's a
weight loss pen so they've they've
they've got this pen and I think
probably I was hitting it like I was
trying to feel better when my stomach
was obsess I'm hitting it more thinking
that it's going to help and it was
actually making me feel sicker that's
crazy and I don't think it has that
effect and that's the other thing with
cannabis it's there's like this effect
that because our body chemistries are so
different like how it affects me and how
it affects you could be completely two
different things I know it's wild 20
years from now hopefully they'll have
all that figured out you know what I
mean once they can do some research yeah
there there's so much to it but there's
that Feelgood weed where I I think most
people with the white Thorn Rose there
is the Blue 13 from Dave mesford we're
going to get those seeds on my site so
by the time you guys are watching this
podcast the Blue 13 seeds from Dave
mesford will be on the site they'll be
available jamesl genetics.com nice and
it gives you it's it's that feel good
it's that Feelgood effect okay and I
feel
like sometimes it's like that for me but
not for my friends right they don't get
that same effect but but this stuff
person after person after person gets
that same like wow this stuff makes me
feel really good then you know you're on
to something exactly exactly yeah so do
do you know what that cross is the b113
yeah so the Blue 13 is blueberry Haze
times King Louis the 13th from Kevin JRE
okay and Dave mford passed away on
420 um gifted me as the steward of his
seed collection we are gonna slowly be
releasing his seeds on our website his
kids benefit from the seeds beautiful um
it's another good you know he was a good
friend he's a good guy took photos of me
back in the day we became friends over
that and he passed on 420 he was the
weed of ficado guy who loved flour loved
cannabis you know sad he he lost a
battle with cancer yeah like a lot of
people a lot of people yeah yeah as you
get older more and more people you
experience losing their lives to cancer
unfortunately one more reason why we do
this you know yeah I mean I'm not a big
tobacco smoker one of my friends died of
esophageal cancer and that got me off
tobacco for the most part yeah I'll
smoke a good cigar every once in a while
but I'm not a cigarette smoker can't do
it even even when I'm drinking I won't
smoke cigarettes just see I used to and
that's what it was my crutch when I was
drinking i' I'd want to SM smoke a
cigarette you know finally got past that
yeah I got off most of the drinking I
very rarely drink I got I got a bunch of
clean and sober guys in my circle Rue
he's another one from Texas he uh yeah
he's he's a good influence on me he
doesn't drink yeah that's good to have
him and elanur those guys are both sober
nice you know it's great having guys
that are sober uh you know because it's
it's one of those things you know peer
pressure whatever but when you're in a
circle of friends and everybody drinks
and you're the guy that doesn't drink a
lot of times it's harder sometimes it's
easy if you have a medical condition or
something like that but if you don't oh
well what's a beer going to do or what's
this going to do for me it's like about
health and I'm trying to like lose more
weight I feel like I've lost a bunch I
still have a bunch to go yeah I love
that the older we get that's we have to
focus on that you know dude Health you
can't eat cheeseburgers all day anymore
health is wealth although I do love a
good Smash Burger no doubt so yeah yeah
defin then you got to watch out for gout
when you get older that's the other
thing God will kill you exactly so yeah
it's funny it's like you you can't win
for losing I know man we can try yeah
for sure so yeah so if you
had one thing that you could tell your
younger self what would that one thing
be just be patient and and know you're
going to fail and just keep moving
forward yeah you know no matter what
yeah sometimes that's all you can do
yeah I've done it my whole life
and can't believe I'm sitting here
talking to you right now and I'm in the
hemp space you know it's it's crazy so
it's a beautiful thing that the hemp
space is a thing it's even possible it's
like uh you know before 2018 it wasn't
even possible no and so and then even
200 it was Rocky for the first couple
years it was weird like that's when I
started was around 2017 I remember them
passing it in 2018 and yeah all my
people were like yeah yeah you know but
we still at that point didn't even
fathom thca being a thing you know we're
just glad to sell the CBD
under3 and how it's evolved it's it's
kind of funny to sit back and look at it
now you know it's just well then Delta 8
got wild minute that stuff is like
garbage it's terrible well I think the
Delta 8 by itself as a molecule is just
fine I think that the problem is is
people take their [__] and they process
their [__] into delta8 because they
can't do anything else with it right and
so they have the [__] distillate delta8
yeah and then they put that in gummies
and all these other things it's like but
by itself delta8 is a great molecule
like as far as the effect it's it's a
fifth as strong as Delta 9
THC uh I think it has value but I think
that we're not focusing on it in the
right ways yeah I mean for me I took a
gummy once of Delta 8 and it hit
extremely hard it was great giggling
like the first time you ever were high
yeah and then the hangover set in and it
just it basically the next day I just
felt like garbage and that was just my
experience yeah I'm big on like the 25
milligram Delta 8s that I know where the
delta8 was sourced through
reliable source and I felt good from
Delta 8 I I I feel like it's very mild
and it helps me sleep whereas Delta 9 I
cannot sleep on Delta 9 for myself right
or I can but it's after I've been high
for a bunch and then I crash right yeah
so yeah I like the mild effect of Delta
8 U but there's so many other canabo
that are great yeah so thca is a good
one it is CBG is I like CBG a lot I have
a great CBG variety it's like
19% I need that so B I'll send it to you
I need that for smoking for myself okay
yeah I'll send you some I have not found
super turpy
CG I've yet to find stuff that's really
turpy that holds high levels of CBG but
I think that's that's on the project
list for the next couple years I worked
on it for a minute doing different cbgs
um I tried Crossing them with THC and
then didn't realize that all the CBG
would just convert over because it's a
stem cell um but I did finally find um
this particular feno CBG we named it
white cheddar because it it had a tpine
profile not a crazy one but yeah
probably the only one I've ever found
and it does smell like kind like white
cheddar popcorn yeah uh great effects
though it's like a cup of coffee or
something very good I'll definitely send
you some yeah I'm all about that
caffeine weed too as long as it doesn't
make my heart race exactly yeah no this
one doesn't and it's good to mix with
other flowers as well so what's
interesting cuz like rosin I can smoke
rosin first thing in the morning I'm
super clearheaded and I go to the gym
and I work out and I feel great and I
don't feel high but if I was to smoke a
big joint right before I go to the gym
I'm not as motivated to work out hard
for whatever reason maybe it's the smoke
maybe it's it could be it could be but
it's for it could be the smoke my lungs
I don't know but like one good dab and I
feel like I'm on nice GNA try that yeah
that's the way to go we got our dude so
like this thing right here this is the
ays from Focus V with the new atomizer
okay this thing's great uh is that a
flower is that dry no this is this is
rosin extract yeah this is this is my
rosin it's a instead of a rosin cart we
now have a mini dab rig that you can go
super portable nice uh there's a handful
of them on the market that are
good has packs I think packs they came
out with a little small one yeah yeah
yeah I mean then there's like dip device
has this flower one too we we'll show
this on the show give these guys a shout
out and it's like a volcano in a pen
which is kind of cool like if you're all
about that old school volcano yeah
actually have a ventti from stores and
bigel that I use that's pretty good yeah
I like that one a lot and this is more
convenient this I mean this is just like
pack and go super easy I like the size
of it too very convenient yeah but the
temperature control of this thing is
great that's what I love about it
temperature control and it's like having
a dab rig without the water um okay
which I don't need water for my dabs but
I love this and I can sit in the car
right when I go into the gym take a nice
fat one exactly and feel great start
your day it's a great way to start the
day I think good rosin 2 is like it
makes me super clear-headed especially
if I'm doing something in repetition
like I'm lifting weights then I can
really focus on the muscles that I'm
trying to Target nice or the cardio and
I can get into the music and not have to
worry about my feet moving or whatever
you know nice I'm gonna try that yeah
makes sense so as far as breeding you're
making seeds now you have some available
on your website yeah yeah so we have
have um mostly type two seeds some type
three seeds uh and then a couple type
one seeds so I mainly focus on type two
seeds breeding a CBD genetic and then a
THC genetic together um yeah I'm getting
a lot of different profiles and for me I
feel like the effects are really
clear-headed no anxiety no paranoia so
the people that are THC sensitive this
these type twos are kind of where it's
at really cool you got to get on on some
of these distribution websites
definitely I'm not quite there but we're
getting there yeah North Atlantic big
shout out to North Atlantic thank you
guys for carrying my seeds I'm a big fan
of North Atlantic Seed Company the seed
distributor okay yeah check them out so
if people are interested in finding more
about you where would they go uh they
can go to our website flowg gardens.com
or our Instagram flowg Gardens 420 and
uh we also have a Facebook flow Gardens
420 you can check us out excellent well
thank you so much for coming on the show
today we'll have to do this again
hopefully I'll see you at all these
events next year definitely looking
forward to it awesome and uh thanks
again for having me James I really
appreciate it for sure and if you're
looking for James loud genetics in
flower form flow Garden there you
go thank you guys for watching please
like And subscribe down below