a
[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James Cloud
podcast and today our special guest is
Chris frell the author of this book 100
gram per square foot amazing how are you
doing today doing well man doing well
thanks for having me thank you for
coming out uh we met originally at
Emerald cup earlier this year and you
are also self-published correct uh so
you and I can uh talk about all the
crazy things that it it means to be
self-published and the the process I
think there's a lot of stuff we can pass
on to people that are interested in
publishing but also I wanted to get into
your book and talk about 100 grams per
square foot let's do it that's pretty
amazing we both have books that came out
around the right time because I feel
like there's a need for someone to write
a book on how to get better yields right
and just like for breeding I feel like
we're way overdue for a breeding book
that had a lot of detail on breeding um
that was detailed you know I was excited
to write a book and then self-publishing
I was like I'm going to do it I thought
it was going to be a lot easier how you
feel about it very very similar
experience you know what we thought was
going to be a year and a half two-year
project you know quickly unfolded into
three and a half years and then you know
trying to pull things together at the
end and you know we're still trying to
work on marketing for ourselves so it's
still just a you know it's a long
process so three and a half years from
start to finish correct yeah that's
really good mine was five five years and
I thought I could do it in one because I
had like this big ego in the beginning
I'm like dude I could knock this out in
one and originally I thought it was
going to be uh 30,000 words and we ended
up with
115,000 and I had over 20 people that
contributed to the books whether it was
photographs videos chapter on tissue
culture a chap chapter on uh
intellectual property and
law uh so it unfolded and turned into
this thing that was much bigger than
myself uh which I think a lot of times
books do 100% man yeah same same over
here you know uh what we thought would
be a short process you know took a lot
longer especially when you start getting
other folks involved you start getting
those critiques it makes you think and
you honestly end up learning more
throughout the process yeah I learned so
much from start to finish about breeding
and a lot of things changed uh with
cultivation and L DS and stuff that had
I not taken five years and put the book
out five years ago would have been
outdated by the time 20124 rolled around
you know there was so you know with LEDs
and doing reversals and my
experimentations I I did a lot of
experimenting with LEDs and HPS and you
know I wasn't getting good reversals
with LEDs whereas HPS I got this amazing
reverse like reverse plant that looked
beautiful right and and dumped out
pollen whereas I get 20% reversals with
LEDs and so the difference is the far
red right that's one of the differences
the heat the far red there's a couple
different things but uh HPS for the win
especially for reversals now in this
modern world a lot of us are using LEDs
I use LEDs for uh pheno hunting because
a lot of my customers that buy seeds use
LEDs so what's your take on LED versus
HPS H I think that you can grow a great
flower under both lights honestly I
think there's also something to be said
about having you know more sophisticated
LEDs you know take the company fo for
example they're really taking things to
the next level with the Spectrum tuning
capabilities I mean there's a couple
companies doing it but I work with them
and I work with science so you know it's
like yeah Spectrum tuning is legit like
it's great the potential for spectrum
tuning and the future of spectrum tuning
we're just scratching the surface with
it and it's like there's so much
potential for it oh I agree man I agree
completely so and I think some of the
stuff is really going to be cultivar
specific which lighting is kind of
anyway because you can just look at HPS
versus LED and you go Blue Dream HPS all
the way you put it under LED and it gets
a different expression same thing with
like the ogs now I I haven't run that
many ogs but I've heard from a couple
people that are growing the best OG that
I smoked that CMH is actually the best
Spectrum yeah I've had similar
experiences I've got some strains some
cultivars rather that you know they'll
dump uh you know 80 90 grams of square
not finicky at all under HPS before I
made the transition and now putting them
under you know more intense lighting
they just they just don't like it
they're they're super finicky yeah they
just don't take as well Skittles
Skittles I feel like the Skittles that
my friend grows under LED is way better
than my HPS Skittles that I was growing
in 2018 like leagues above it it's also
he just experimented the living soil we
smoked it a couple podcasts ago we're g
to smoke some today really good stuff
but I feel like it it just and it's like
dialing in the cultivar for the
environment yeah different nutrient
regimens uh regimens ppfd is comes into
play I think you go into that in your
book quite a bit uh the importance of
ppfd is and basically crop steering
absolutely man yeah there's I mean crop
steering is everything that's happening
in the room right from climate to your
fertigation and substrate
management uh literally everything
surrounding the plant is is crop
steering it's not just you know a lot of
people get this confused it's not just
you know what are you doing in the
subrate it's you know how are you
tailoring your VPD right you know your
light levels it all comes into play when
you're steering something as certain way
in that either high stress environment
or that low stress environment to you
know promote uh ripening flowering fruit
development and then uh vegetative
growth well and VPD is a tricky one too
because I think a lot of people they
have the troll master and they're like
well it's in the range of the VPD and
then they're not accounting for surface
temperature of the leaf right and I
think that's the big thing right I mean
at least I think it is yeah and you know
so there's so many things that are you
know there's a learning curve still
where people are like oh I just used
this chart and it it's it's all UNC in
it works and it's like well it'll work
but you're not optimizing the VPD in
those situations for sure yeah there's
definitely no one siiz fits-all and
having those IR sensors going into the
canopy which not a lot of folks use will
definitely help you dial that part of
that process totally yeah it's like the
technolog has just come a long ways in
the last 10 years it's pretty amazing
and then guys like Josh and Ramsay that
have kind of uh moved the needle forward
and you know especially with crop
steering and then books like this coming
out to where the information's
accessible you don't have to just know
the right person now you can buy a book
because I think in the beginning it's
like oh well who do you know that's
going to share their secrets with you
yeah yeah literally I mean that was the
whole uh thought behind the book right
it's like we all since you know starting
getting into what we all do now is it's
always been this search for for good
information you know because it's 90% of
it's bad right and bringing it all
together in a digestible manner where
you can look through it's very textbook
style but wanted to give it coffee table
Vibes too it's it's very easy to go
through and figure out out you know
which one of these Cardinal parameters
am I having issues with and then you can
just go through the steps of your
troubleshooting right yeah I've had two
friends steal the book already and I had
to go back and get it from them but uh
yeah it's a great book I feel like it's
it's easy to digest whereas like some
textbooks are like super complicated and
they go over your head and you have to
keep on going and but you can actually
pick it apart chapter by chapter or you
can go to specific stuff that you're
interested about I feel like I wrote a
book similar in that sense where it's
like there's a lot of Gable information
and there's something for everybody in
there and if you read it you're going to
learn something 100% I actually started
reading your book recently too man I'm
digging it so far you could tell that
there was a ton of work put into it
thank you yeah yeah yeah we we really
did you know so I wrote the book about
five times and threw away the first four
versions of it and then the last time
the last draft was kind of a start to
finish and I wrote it pretty quickly
based on the other things and then I
brought an editor in named Angela Baka
she basically picked it apart and was
like no we need to rearrange it this way
I was like well I want to do and she's
like no no I think it would make more
sense if we go from here to here to here
so it's very linear in that sense and
then people can understand it better and
she she had a lot of good points and so
sometimes it takes the outside
perspective looking in to go okay well
this is how you should do it 100% I did
the same thing I uh I brought in a bunch
of former colleagues uh steuart wiox
former COO of cure Leaf I wanted that
high level
perspective you know does it read well
for for folks that are you know at that
upper Edge Lawn of companies is going to
be you know able to provide value to
them I brought in some folks uh my
buddies at groan John jerich kovic went
through Reddit gave me good feedback
yeah uh Liam Spencer who's actually
working for a science LED for a while I
think he's actually a crop specialist
for a Roy and now real good kid I love
him probably five other guys I'm
forgetting right now but yeah that
alternate pers or additional perspective
is what really turned that book into
something great yeah totally yeah I mean
the more people that touch the book The
the bigger it becomes in a lot of ways
and then it just outgrows you and you're
part of something so much bigger than
yourself and it's like and these books
you know they have value they could last
a lifetime I feel like there's just so
many things but let's talk about yield
for a second because I love the title of
your book but also what is the largest
yield you've gotten largest yield I've
gotten probably around 130 grams a
square which is like five pounds of
light give or take yeah yeah so pushing
that five pound envelope with quality
yeah I believe it's quality man we uh we
use great inputs we've got a great team
we do all our crop work on schedule we
don't you know we don't cut Corners
anywhere throughout our processes and um
I think that goes a long way with the
final product at the end of the day
right totally most recently don't mean
to interrupt we hit 110 grams uh two
weeks ago that was really exciting
anytime we we do something good like
that we always take the team out you
know got to make sure the team's taken
care of because those are the folks
really making it happen and what kind of
scale is this at I'm sure a lot of
people are curious about that so this is
right now I'm running, 1500 foot rooms
of canopy wow I've uh you I've run 100
of thousands of square feet of canopy
working for cure Leaf in different
states right but uh currently I'm
running, 1500 foot rooms nice that's
great just small enough to still kind of
be craft it's not too big to control and
then rockwool is your substrate of
choice uh love rock wool we're running
that in our perum gr right now and uh
seeing great results there but I do like
Coco I love Coco there's a bit more I do
too I think cocoa flavor I mean rockwool
probably has the best look I think Coco
probably
is the most dynamic and soil I think has
the best
flavor uh and you can get great flavor
out of rockwool don't get me wrong but
and rockwool is you know Rockwall is
probably the the as far as like being
able to control you can have a lot more
control with rock wall 100% yeah smaller
substrate to manage you can get quicker
responses yeah and feedback and if
you're going I feel like it's a little
bit more accurate too when you're trying
to like uh you know because we do like a
10% dryback overnight and then 3% per
hour and then you know at least that's
what we do here uh and everybody has
their own way of doing it but I feel
like the rock wall you can really die
that in Cocoa it's like it'll it'll vary
from pot to pot a little bit more for
sure yeah a lot more variability which
sometimes requires more sensors but yeah
yeah to get more averages and then once
you have the average you can dial it in
a little bit more exactly you're only as
good as the or your decisions are only
as good as the data sets you have to
make them from so right well how many
sensors do you feel like you should have
uh in a room uh in a room I don't really
go by per room per se but I go about you
know per square foot I'd say about One
sensor per 150 square feet of canopy
okay there you go yeah nice and then
what sensors do you think work the best
uh it depends on the substrate right
like you have the gross sense which
obviously probably you know that's what
I use is gross sense I use gross sense
for dryb backs right but then we also
have agretech so we have redundancy so I
use more than one redundancy is key yeah
yeah I like a Royo though I've been
working with them for a couple years now
uh great platform easy to read and
interpret the data to make adjustments
and then you also have the redundancy
builtin with their climate stations and
such so you can compare that to whatever
your uh you know existing building
management system was before you
implemented that into your uh operation
right yeah and actually have a royya
sensors here too we just don't have the
aoya system anymore but like I feel like
I would like to go back because we all
about AB testing so I want to I would
love to compare the data between aoya
and grense because I feel like they're
both good and so you know it's like how
how much off is each one what's the
difference is am I getting better
results with one than the other know we
do that with everything from the
irrigation skid that I showed you
earlier that's what keeps me excited
every day I come in I'm like okay well
it's almost like I can play with this
stuff but it's also data driven and so
I'm trying to do it in a productive uh
scientific way to where we get actual
data that's valuable instead of just
playing around right right so because a
lot of people they like to play around
yeah thousand ways of skin a cat you
know for sure well with cultivation it's
like harvest date depending on the
cultivar uh what do you like do you want
more candy do you want more gas do you
want it stronger do you want it more
mild are you using it for extract yeah I
mean all those things come into play and
we're planning our rims out so it's for
for us at least it's always a
collaborative effort right like what's
doing well at the retail level that you
know goes back to the lab our production
team our extraction team what do we need
to formulate different products whether
it's aive or as a gummy that we need a
specific flavor profile for so we'll
make sure we have an allocation in the
room for things so we'll send just a
fresh frozen yeah what cartridges are
doing well in terms of live resin pens
same thing there allocations for that
and then you know what finished flower
do we really want what which one of our
stores right well yeah and you're in the
cultivation space so you're doing the
Lord's work it's a challenge these days
uh I just do the nursery we we don't
have any we don't sell flour or anything
like that but we do feno hunt we do
testing uh and the nursery model which I
love uh licensing genetics clones all
that stuff we're about to go direct to
Consumer with the Clones I can be a
consumer I'd love to get some ear Cuts
yeah absolutely and I feel like we're
we're looking for people to partner with
in other places so I think that that
could be an interesting conversation
should have an R&amp;D room coming online in
a couple of months up in perum so nice
yeah should do some fun things out there
yeah and I love testing things in
different environments and seeing what
kind of results people get and comparing
coas but also comparing opinions on
flower you know because I think
different regions and different places
have uh different desires as far as what
kind of end product works like
California the Bay Area La purple candy
gas is like really what they want and it
can go more gas it can go more candy it
can go more or less purple but it's
really kind of in that like you might be
able to sell some Sour Diesel or some
blue dream these days it's surprising
blue Dreams made a huge comeback uh and
maybe it never left completely but like
now it's it's popular everywhere again
people really love it I think it's
interesting because the effect yeah it
definitely lost some steam and I
remember buddies you know running all
their garages and houses and up up in
the pter canyon just blue dream never
had any problem getting rid of anything
for years you know then probably two
2016 2017 came around and then that's
when you guys the readers started really
getting creative with stuff and yeah and
I mean we had it in the early early to
mid 2000s and it that's when it had its
day and then as soon as the Clones got
out the price dropped on it you know it
was like one of the worst years of my
life because I was like so focused on
growing blue dream and then Christmas
came around and I had all these packs it
was a long story but uh once the market
got flooded with it it was so easy to
grow and that was the first thing that
was kind of like oh it was easy to get
over two pounds of light for almost
anybody you know and then now people are
like oh two pounds of light isn't good
enough we need to hit three to be
successful not everybody but like at a
commercial scale I think a lot of people
are looking for that three pound of
Light number yeah that that all boils
down to your margins and costing right
like taking that lean approach
eliminating steps and I mean having a
plant that can yield heavier is just
going to bring your cost down across the
board yeah I mean I have some friends
that run double stack in they they have
a wreck road down the street and they
have a double stack and their cost per
pound to produce it is they get over
three pounds of light is like $280 per
pound indoor and that you know 600 was
the average for the longest time I think
the average is now probably five maybe
475 or something like that but in wreck
we have high electricity here too it's
super expensive you know we're not like
Washington State at s cents a kilowatt
we're like 39 cents a kilowatt yeah
we're at 12 cents a kilowatt up in uh
Vegas areas yeah nice we're also Hing I
think right around dollar per gram after
dry trim cure testing everything yeah
not in the package but no but that's a
good that's a good number to hit I feel
like anybody is getting below that is
doing some Miracles you know to be able
to get those numbers and you know the
double stack plays a huge role and then
cul of our selection is huge everything
boils down to genetics genetics is now
and will forever be the backbone of
every operation you know you're only as
good as your your weakest guy right so
if you have strong genetics you're G to
have strong crops Pest and pathogen free
good genetics it's like and it's such a
big thing now I think uh for the longest
time we really didn't talk we were
worried about spidermites and then it
was rude aphids and maybe
some uh broad mites and russet mites uh
but now it's like we got to worry about
pathogens like significant they do
significant damage oh yeah and uh if
you're if you get your blinders on still
you're gonna get burned you're gonna get
you're gonna get hit oh yeah you know if
you're trading Cuts with everybody like
it's no big deal you know that's like
having sex in the 80s without
protection that's right man it's all
about getting that good quarantine
having them come from reliable stores
going through all the pathogen testing
and yeah yeah viroids are a problem like
uh you know if you're not managing your
stub straight correctly you know you can
get real bad fum Moxy sporum problems by
just giving him that perfect
oversaturated environment yeah and I
think ferium is a thing we don't talk
about enough because we're so focused on
Hop plate and ver but ferium is a big
problem and it's out there everywhere
that's another one that I'm seeing
everywhere with stuff and a lot of
people will say no that's H plate and
it's like no it's not you could it looks
like feran yeah yeah cut it open totally
exactly so yeah so how did you get your
start in cultivation and everything that
you're doing now yeah so I was I was in
the Marine Corps infantry for five years
and uh I mean prior to that I was a
river guide on the shanado and patomic
rivers and uh just always been real
fascinated by plant medicine you know
mushrooms fungi adaptogenic herbs
cannabis obviously yeah grew a little
bit of weed sold a little bit of weed
back then nothing of scale or anything
of note but uh that that was the initial
thing that kind of perked my interest
and then after getting out of the Marine
Corps moved out to Colorado had some
buddies that were running caregiver
operations did a lot of work with them
was real fortunate to learn a lot from
from those guys and uh that was my start
I probably spent about 3 years uh
growing in Colorado up in the pter
canyon Fort Collins native roots and uh
Denver Colorado nice then uh East coat
Market started opening up took a move
East did some Consulting uh rewrote some
curriculums for the Cleveland School of
cannabis for their commercial
cultivation operations course and their
cannabis cultivation course then I got
picked up by cure Leaf helped them
design some facilities start some
facilities uh kind of in a regional
capacity there for about a year and a
half while the first facility in Ohio
was getting built and uh yeah was with
them for about 3 years and then uh
wanted to move back home to Colorado and
then ended up uh being reached out to
for the company I'm working for now Deep
Roots Harvest and went out there met
with the team the executive team was
super cool the grow was great team was
awesome and uh ended up you know going
out there working with them and have
been with them now for three years wow
done a lot of good things so when you
were in Fort Collins did you get to try
that Fort Collins cough the Fort Collins
cough where is that coming from Fort
Collins Colorado a specific store
breeder no it was so that's a nl5 haze
cross that's uh extremely special I I
did some breeding with it a couple years
ago and I love it and it's just thing is
is like the outdoor Growers they
struggle with it because it gets so tall
it'll go right over your fence line and
it just keeps getting taller and taller
and taller even even in the end it's
still you know it's still growing
throughout flower and uh but yeah it's
it's it's hazy it's funky it's got a
real strong Funk to it sounds like I
missed out on something yeah yeah that
that's a special one and I feel like I
haven't seen I haven't seen it grown
indoors I've heard about people that
grow in indoors I've seen pictures on
Instagram of it grown indoors but most
of the time I've seen it is outside and
I grew it outside myself nice I was
running uh probably three things
predominantly out there uh you know
outside of the you know bigger Ops that
I was running but uh space queen from TJ
or subcool yeah love space queen 303
seeds uh I think it was Sasquatch it's
like Hindu Kush Grape Ape and beckan
hash plant cross gu I haven't heard of
Sasquatch in 10 years beautiful pink
flowers man like the bag appeel unmatch
you just don't see things like that
today yeah nice and then uh Golden Goat
one of my alltime favorit you can't go
wrong with some good Golden Goat I funny
story about Golden Goat so I in my
freezer I still have Golden Goat uh BHO
from 2018 that I've been saving and I
still smoke it every once in a while
Bust It Out warm it up and dab it it's
you know extract just stays good forever
especially good sauce oh yeah so sauce
and diamonds it's actually from House of
cultivar my good friends uh yeah and
I've just I've just saved it ever since
I got I was given it an emerald Cup in
2018 and I still have it that's a good
one D I love golden go yeah it's special
it special and the turps on it are are
loud uh it's like got that nose burning
lemon to it oh yeah oh yeah yeah F fills
a whole house yeah totally I yeah I I've
never grown it or anything like that but
I I really like the cultivar I like the
expression I like the effect too oh yeah
great plant structure great yielder and
great great flower yeah yeah Colorado's
got some good stuff I don't think they
get enough credit all the time I don't
either man now they got Adam done in his
podcast ruining it all for everybody so
yeah he's a good friend of mine but yeah
he's uh he's got some good genetics he's
do did some sage and saour Crosses
together and that's another one that's
my favorite or one of my favorites sour
is my favorite catus is my favorite
don't really get to see them too often
anymore they catus definitely not sour
I've just reconnected with sour uh the
reg on the river this year so that's
that's one of our local favorite
varieties all right so you have any here
um no but we do have some Skittles you
like Skittles I do like Skittles nice
yeah we got some Skittles and then we
got some crippy uh we're calling this
stuff Uncle Rick's crippy and it's like
this old school OG variety that's super
gassy super special in my opinion
different than everything else that's
going on right now super Frosty but it's
sticky loud like extremely like pungent
where it burns your nose but it's OG and
you just don't see gassy stuff like that
anymore not really not really we've got
uh we probably have two I mean we get we
get a little a little bit of gas from
our uh our gorilla goo but not not like
the old we talking about that yesterday
it's funny how we have these reoccurring
things like Gorilla Glue keeps popping
back up and you know I like Gorilla Glue
for what it is it it kind of like came
in and I'm one of the guys who got the
cut from uh Josie Wales in
2013 and I believe it was 2013 at the
cup in La it was either that or 2014
right at the end there of 13 or early
part of 14 at the cup in San Bernardino
and they were they did the best thing
ever was they gave the cut out to
everybody and that blew it up they had
won the cup and they gave out clones to
everybody and then it just spread like
wildfire I gave it to a bunch of my
friends uh we made moms of it and momed
it out and gave cuts to everybody and
then it replaced Sour Diesel within
about a year of all the people that were
growing sour diesel for not not all of
them but a lot of
them uh especially up on the hills in
somoma meno humble that were growing
sour it was like get something that's
gassy it's better yields and finishes
earlier so you don't have to worry about
rain you don't have to worry about
Bettis and PM and all these other issues
big big flowers on that planet big
chunky and it's like it's got some
chocolate notes in it too it was like
really funky gas with chocolate notes it
was complex oh for sure for sure and
strong and like the effect was strong
yeah you can't you can't really find
those cuts anymore not at least not the
the stable ones I've tried the a few
times now and most of the ones I picked
up just Herm for gorilla yeah oh dude we
I can get you a gorilla cut we can get
the gg4 no problem like that's that's
another one that's it's in culture so it
takes a few months but yeah that one's
around uh we got we got a good amount of
stuff chem 91 is coming out of culture
right now I'm about to give that back to
Greg uh yeah good I like chem 91 that's
that the 91 chem dog is extremely
special in my opinion it's like it's got
its own kind of gas you know it's that
burnt Tire chemi kind of you know the
structure is not the best on it it's got
decent structure but it's it's soft the
the buds are soft and they're they're
nice big buds it's like open bra but
it's not like uh not like sour diesel
where it completely fingers out where
you got these stacked bracks or fox
tails that you know and Sour Diesel
doesn't always fox tail like that but a
lot of times it does yeah I feel like a
lot of the uh not a lot of them but a
fair amount of some of the older
genetics fox tail a good
bit yeah and I think that can be a
quality thing too I'm okay with fox tail
as long as it's fire yeah
like but I come from a time where it
didn't matter as much what it looked
like it was all about the loudness and
the effect which I think people are
going to start going back towards I feel
like with white Thorn Rose hitting the
market as strong as it did this year I'm
not sure if you're familiar with that
one but white Thorn hit hard and that's
from Huckleberry Hill Farms and it's one
of those feel-good strains it's not the
strongest in the world but it just makes
you feel great it's all about the effect
the the trips are good too but man that
effect is what's up yeah I I'm
anticipating something similar with with
a market shift like that most bang for
your buck mentality you know how much
can I get in a bag with the highest THC
with the lowest cost I think that's
going to you know I'm sure it'll always
be there for certain consumers but I
think there's going to be a different
you know demographic that's going to
come out similar to folks that like wine
and you know good drinks like good mixed
drinks where people are just looking for
specific flavor profiles things to pair
things with flavor Chasers we got lots
of flavor Chasers out there and now with
the potential I mean we're kind of
talking about making salads the other
day about mixing up different flour
definitely rosin can be easily Blended
where you can take 25% this we're going
to do Skittles 75 and we're going to
throw in something else to make it
special you know or whatever 5050 you
know I think you can really you know the
options are Limitless on the directions
you can go with blending especially with
stuff like rosin or
extract tell me what you think of
that should let you dry hit it that's
the dirt
Skittles uh soil grown so we did an
interesting test where we took Skittles
grown in soil and Skittles grown in
cocoa that was the only difference
throughout the whole cycle same light
same nutrition United
nutrients and uh the only difference was
the
substrate so versus cocoa and then we
smoked them side by side we did it on
the show with hi from Humble seed
company and it's like so significant
flavor-wise I I agree this the best best
food I've ever smoked was definitely
living soil blueberry diesel like
probably 2016 or something yeah I like
that blueberry diesel that's a good one
too so good so that's the best thing
you've ever smoked nice yeah it's funny
cuz like from batch to batch I've smoked
amazing things all over Skittles the
best batch of Skittles that I ever
smoked was this one right here um yeah
and it really dude this stuff coats uh
the ash yeah I rolled this one too this
is a fatty i r four four gramers I feel
like you get better flavor if you're a
flavor
Chaser not the bigger the better always
but there's that sweet spot it's
depending on the tip too you're using
like a 12 or a 10 uh it it hits
different you get better air flow and
you get more
TPS so and everyone's got their own
thing going on you know some of and this
this ash isn't looking as pretty today
as it did yesterday but we'll smoke some
of the other ones too I mean dirt
Skittles something special about it love
Skittles oh yeah this one's
coats it's got a good coat but yeah I
think I R so the thing with that I'm
learning with hand rolls we call them
hand rolls instead of pre-rolls but with
the hand rolls uh you want to smoke them
fresh too after you roll them they start
to even if you put them in a joint
tube they're not quite as good a week
later as they would be for the first
couple days and they're good this is
still amazing but it's just a little bit
more mouth coating I feel like you're
getting more TPS yeah yeah they're
volatile you know evaporate off at room
temperature yeah so and each cultivar is
different some cultivars are good for
months they're exactly once they hit
their Peak they're good and you could
put them in a tur Block Bag or whatever
we just have those guys on but love
those bags me too I absolutely love them
they're they're a game changer in my
opinion uh they change my life and also
I'm like one of those guys who doesn't
believe things are good A lot of times
and there's so much snake oil out there
I'm like yeah right another myar bag
that's better cool it's thick but no if
you actually do your your homework and
you you do any trials with them you'll
see that they're better especially
better than turkey bags better than
mason jars I mean mason jars your buds
don't get smashed that's the only
benefit um and I think using a
controlled environment where it's cool
then you don't have to the guesswork you
pull the guesswork out if you're using a
trip blck especially like in that curing
phase where you don't have to burp it
because a lot of people they screw it up
within that you know post Harvest uh for
the week after two weeks after three
weeks after they're not releasing that
CO2 out of the bag and uh if you don't
release it then moisture gets trapped in
the plant and that's what tur blocks do
exactly exactly and you know from uh you
know operational perspective it just
makes sense for you know efficiency
right because then you're not having you
know a couple of guys that are strictly
just running around depending on the
scale right popping toads popping
buckets popping turkey bags well and
that when we were talking about this
yesterday but then it be when you got
people man manually doing it uh it
becomes an art where you have to be
skilled you put it in a turp blck it's
it's uh mechanically done instead of
manually done and then okay it does it
itself like you just you don't have to
worry about that that's one less thing
you have to worry about and the less
things you have to worry about that you
know we're going to be successful the
better your end product is probably
going to be oh yeah 100% then you could
focus the you know your efforts you
would have spent on that somewhere else
totally yeah I'm all about efficiencies
it's all about efficiencies at the end
uh especially when you're getting into
scale and cost efficiencies where you're
trying to save money because at the end
of the day you know especially with guys
that are producing flour it's like such
a competition and race to the bottom of
you're in the middle if you're creating
a superior product not so much the race
to the bottom but you still have to be
conscious of your price absolutely I
mean price compression is hitting
everybody you know at a national level
you know with the exception of a few
states that are just you know opening up
with medical markets but just a matter
of time being cognizant of that from the
very beginning having the right you know
mechanical equipment in place the right
workflow having the right people there
to get things done the right way goes a
long way it goes a long way having good
staff is everything and good work
culture like
you know that's that's everything too
people want to you your people want to
come to work they enjoy working it's
like they wouldn't want to be anywhere
else that's when you got to a winning
recipe oh yeah yeah if you're not
involved in the Kickball the Kickball
teams the softball leagues and the the
mud volleyball and all that stuff with
the team you should be yeah yeah well
it's those little things like uh that
make a huge difference because it's
stressful a lot of times even you know
the little jobs can be stressful at
times you know we don't do any hand
I'm done with hand watering um we will
handw water in a tent but like that's
another one I I've had friends that were
hand watering forever and finally have
switched over in the last couple years
and it's like man you just have so much
time for other things and it's one less
thing you you don't have to worry about
and you don't have to train somebody on
and hope they're doing it correctly
exactly you get that consistency yeah
and it's repeatable like it's one of
those things is repeatable time and time
again and if you're doing five harvests
a year out of that room you know the
watering is going to be successful
because you got sensors it makes life
easier I want it I want those things to
be easy because there's so many other
things that'll stress you out yeah no
kidding so yeah like the market yeah I
mean everything's kind of volatile right
now but what state are you in again
Nevada Nevada nice so yeah and Nevada is
volatile too and you guys have you know
wreck has been introduced for the past
couple years but you guys have like one
of the largest dispensaries in the whole
world Planet 13 out in Vegas
yeah yeah they're they're a partner of
ours oh nice yeah they're crushing it oh
yeah Planet 13 does real well they also
have a great breakfast spot right across
inside that same building nice highly
recommend checking that place out yeah
so tell me one of the biggest things you
learned from writing this book probably
adjusting uh my own expectations of
things like uh you know kind of going
back to how we uh we started our talk
just being being patient with the
process more or less
yeah you know cuz and that and you know
don't let good get in the way of uh or
don't let perfect get in the way of good
right like me me and my co-author LC
Journey went back and forth a few times
like oh it's ready it's ready and then
I'd like you know sit down read a
chapter be like we could do better we
could do better yeah or I'd read I'd
read an article and be like H I feel
like I feel like I should you know mix
something from this into a certain
section just because I think it's super
important so it it's just like every
time we thought we were about done there
was just more and more and more I know
that feeling yeah and it's funny cuz if
you've never written a book you probably
wouldn't relate to it as much but like
mine I feel like there was information
coming out at the last minute where we
abstracts tech for instance wrote a
white paper actually multiple white
papers on flavorants which are they they
did a bunch of research so flavor
molecules like THS and sulfur based
compounds volti surfur compounds oh yeah
and so I had to include that in my book
so we had to like add this to the Bild
right before we going to layout we're
like no we need to add this this has to
be I talked to Angela and I'm like what
do you think about this she's like yeah
we should probably figure out how to
include it it's like pretty gamechanging
and you know I I actually read all the
papers I showed them to a couple other
people and we were like yeah this needs
to be in the book like if we don't put
in the book it's going to need to go in
the next version but it's out right now
and we haven't finalized everything even
though we felt like we'd finalized
everything and there was a whole bunch
of little things like that and then
photo placement where are we going to
place all the photos that was kind of
tricky yeah that that's a lengthy
process man and then picking those
photos too you know like you'll probably
have five for each section you want one
and then going through and well I like
this one but she likes that one and you
know Paul likes this one and then you
know trying to come together and figure
out you know what what's going to be the
best for each section yeah I mean we had
two photographers that did a lot of
heavy lifting and then on top of that we
had Arian from Greenhouse we had a seeds
contributing photos we had so many
people contributing photos um Kevin
jodrey got me some uh there's a bunch of
people in the industry that kind of were
very helpful that we like yeah I'll help
contribute to your book and uh you know
Mojave Richmond is another guy
contributed some really cool stuff we
did case studies in my book too nice
nice yeah we we tried to keep ours as uh
as tighten it as possible you know a lot
of previous books we had read not going
to name any had uh you know tons of
advertisements you know use this use
that use these lights use these
nutrients I won't do it yeah for that I
feel like that it be it moves away from
being textbook to being a magazine
exactly we wanted to like preserve the
authenticity and just have like you know
raw you know usable information that's
going to be applicable to you know the
reason why folks should buy that book
not like a hey you know shout out to
this compan yeah where you're pushing
people in any One Direction for products
I just want to put the facts out there
and let people make their mind up and
yeah we do talk about some products but
I I try to make it as non-biased as
possible and just telling people the
facts and you know that's that's the
best way with the textbook it's supposed
to be information for people to digest
it's not supposed to be a magazine
exactly I love that about your book too
thank you thank you yeah I mean we
mentioned a few products as well you
know like Flor flex and Jack just for
Simplicity right like from a costing
perspective yeah can't beat you know one
and a half cents per gallon start to
finish on average Jax is the blue stuff
right uh it's yeah white blue it's blue
blue uh powder right yeah yeah yeah Jack
I my buddy used Jack for a long swore by
Ja I haven't used ja but uh I've seen
some stuff growing with it it's all
right yeah for for Simplicity yeah I
would agree that's it you can't beat a
one part yeah
exactly and and the costing too you know
like a lot of the nutrient lines
nowadays 7 to 14 cents a gallon
depending on you know how much you're
ordering but yeah you just you know it's
like that's why dry rather than by the
gallon it's like using dry is like so
much more economical and also like the
carbon frit we got sold the idea that we
need liquid fertilizers I mean it's so
crazy CU you look at any other form of
bag they're not they're not loaded up on
these liquid 5 gallon concentrate
bottles that they can you could get
powder of oh yeah you know when you're
buying a thousand pounds of salts versus
uh you know the equivalent into liquid
you're talking about you know tens of
thousands of dollars and like Freight
charges associated with that too not
crazy yeah it's crazy once you start
penciling it out like the difference in
price uh just by the weight of the water
exactly so yeah and I mean they have
stabilizers and and the thing is is
maybe we didn't have as good quality
stuff before they didn't done all the
R&amp;D for uh buffers and stabilizers and
things like that and now we have that
technology so it's very easy people
understand it a lot better I mean
there's only a handful of companies that
actually make the dry powder for
everybody anyway yeah so yeah and then
there's the Cannabis tax because a lot
of times you can go to the a world and
get stuff for a that's Pennies on the
dollar from the Cannabis stuff right I'm
not hating on any nutrient companies I
love you guys all I love I love all of
the nutrient companies I agree I agree
you used of them from advance to House
and Garden to Cana uh yeah front row
front row oh yeah I I like front row I
like yeah I like Cana I got the Cana hat
on today I I do I like uh Cutting Edge I
like United is what we're using now uh
Athena's
fine uh dude I've used so many GH I've
used GH I've tried a bunch I still use
GH ph up nice yeah for the longest time
I was doing this uh Botanicare with
Floren Nova was the secret recipe it was
like this super complex recipe that you
could never use with dosers it it would
because there was 18 different things
and it's like uh yeah and it was
complicated and it grew really good
flour but uh man it's like those old
recipes is the weed better or was the
weed better back then with 18 things I
don't think so no I don't either no I
think you're over complicating stuff now
I get at you know certain flesh recipes
yeah you're going to have some different
stuff and we have a special flush recipe
that we have that was developed by one
of our friends that that works
phenomenal and it's got a bunch of
components in it I was like looks like a
lot we have to hand flush everything but
but you get white ash and you get really
good flavor so at the end of the day the
proof is in the pudding yeah it's all
about the flavor yeah so what do you
think about flush flush uh I I talked to
Bruce Bugsby about this actually before
speaking on a facility design at the
Cannabis business times conference like
a year or two ago yeah and uh you know
from a plant physiology perspective it
doesn't make any sense to deprive the
plant of nutrients up until Harvest and
when people do flush depending on what
you are flushing right if you know some
people who do just Ro or just tap water
or phed water you know if you de your
plant of calcium you know that'll result
in Bettis you know if you do it for too
long are you actually flushing the
flower anyway like when you look at the
plant what's deficient the flowers
aren't deficient the the foliage is
deficient right so you'll see that fade
in the foliage but it's not really
affecting the flow yeah so there's a you
know 10 ways to look at it and break it
down is it's something you're doing for
a costing perspective you know in terms
of a year you know 56 chops cut out you
know four days that could be some
savings depending on the uh the scale of
the operation but yeah as far as uh you
know quality of the finish product goes
I think there's something to be said
about like uh you know how the
chlorophyll can break down and uh you
know how that flour can cure Yeah by
removing some of that well and then
calcium I think a lot of people are
using calcium to get whiter Ash
um and I think I hear different opinions
on calcium and the benefits of actually
calcium is it uptaking a bunch of that
calcium is it not but I'm seeing better
better Ash with
calcium so yeah and then you know I
think molasses is another big one
putting sugar in there oh yeah carbal
some carbal load some sweet oh yeah some
of those simple and complex sugars yeah
I I think that's great I think it's
great I mean at the end of the
day if you can improve the flavor why
not do it yeah I agree so and also make
it more smooth if there's ways to make
it more smooth increase the flavor I'm
all for it same it's all about that that
end user experience right right well
because at the end of day you're
providing experience for the customer
it's just like a chef would for uh
someone dining at their restaurant you
know and flower is no different it's a
fresh product and it comes out slightly
different even at scale even the the
best environments there's still uh
slight variation because there's so many
things that go on it's not exactly the
same product that comes out every
Harvest um yeah you can get a lot more
similar the more dialed in your system
is especially like using like rock wool
you know you start talking chemotypes
you can get tighter chemotype
Expressions uh but it still is a living
product it can change from time to time
and also you get some systemic bacteria
in there you can get a totally different
expression or you get some stressors
some thrips some mites whatever it is
you know it's like induce those jasmonic
Pathways get some different responses
mhm yeah stressors will make the plant
more turpy that's just a known fact oh
yeah so I have friends that have thrips
and their their stuff is super turpy and
they're like what's cool and I'm like
well don't ever come to my facility but
yeah yeah I mean they might have a point
to a degree so and I think there is a
couple there is a couple compounds or or
uh brands that are making uh things to
foler that actually act as stressors
yeah yeah harpon proteins yeah yeah
really cool definitely yeah and I mean
we're still learning about the plant I'm
excited about Innovation always learning
about the second you stop learning
that's that's where you know your
improvements of uh any kind of quality
stop right so as far as data collection
how much data collection do you guys do
uh we do a lot I couldn't off the top of
my head probably give you a data point
number but I mean many different data
points from the substrate the
environmentals the climate ppfd readings
uh we get a lot of data points just from
like an efficiency perspective with our
shift reports from all of our
supervisors you know what's getting done
how long did it take right we're also in
the middle of building a very robust uh
addition to our uh cultivation
management software now where we're
adding costing in so we're going to
actually be able to you know apply true
cost to to everything like how long did
it take you know down to the milliliter
of everything used to the to the hour of
Labor yeah that's a yeah I mean that's
how you get efficiencies you improve oh
yeah more data points do you guys
measure your plants going
into for for for growth on a weekly or
daily basis ever um I used to for for
different things when I start new things
out you know like measuring inter noal
spacing and stand diameter all that
stuff but I've kind of moved away from
that to where it's not as beneficial
information after a period of time
exactly yeah and then dialing in your
ppfd what is the best way to dial your
ppfd in really looking for plant
responses you know as you're photo
acclimating things if you you know see
an adverse plant response where it's
like oh you know obviously the plant's
got too much light because you know it
has that slight it's not turgid right
the turgidity of the plant with the
water pushing on the S walls just isn't
happening they're not praying as
everybody calls the leaves you know you
you want to see that turgidity like if
your VPD is dialed in a room you'll see
your turgidity like if your light's good
your BPD is good yeah you know you got
good pressure in the root Zone that's
what you're going to see yeah you want
happy healthy plants right whether
you're cutting clones whether you're
flowering whatever yeah you you want
praying plants yeah that just being
cognizant of those those light levels
right like certain certain ones can take
more than others and just knowing that
going into the game you know not trying
to use that cookie cutter to every
single one of your rooms every single
part of your room going in and knowing
that you know old school limits if we
can get over 600 micromoles in here it's
not going to like it yeah then your gush
M you can hit with you know 1,00
micromoles it's wild you know it's gonna
throw down five a light yeah yeah you're
going for that same thing with the super
boo yields like crazy exactly so yeah
and do you see the future of people
pushing even higher uh numbers per
square foot it depends on how you look
at it I actually had some conversations
with some of my uh my gran buddies
recently and they were talking about the
setup in Amsterdam where they
essentially had like these it was like
Ean flood style clone tray where it's
like right from clone flipping into
flower right and they were boiling down
the cting per square foot with the yield
you know if you look at it as like a
stacked square foot you know I'm sure
there's creative ways to go about doing
it yeah you know if you you bed your
plants you know anything longer than
three and a half weeks I'm sure you can
get more but then you know you're have
to account for that in other ways in
your room like you're have to increase
your deification capacity your cooling
all of that so there'll just be other
things set have to grow with that yeah
what are your thoughts on underc canopy
underc canopy I think it's great for uh
for a lot of uh applications you know
like there's a lot of different parts of
the plant that can accept light that can
benefit the plant you know and a lot of
the lights that are out there now don't
get as much penetration through the
canopy right like uh certain ones do you
know like the uh the fos 3 eyes I'm
using now I can get you know upwards of
three to four hair micro mols after a
good defa down run those lowers you know
I'll get soft balls top to bottom but
you know if you don't have something
like that under canopy would definitely
be something advantageous to implement
and you typically thin uh multiple times
throughout flower and and through veg or
what's your process for thinning
typically so for for def falling I'll do
like a light Def and uh like veg and
then day 21 between days 21 and uh 28 we
go through do a light skirt pull the
lower third off and then uh hit about a
60 65% def top to bottom nice yeah and
then we get a final deall probably you
know seven week seven nice yeah really
strip them oh yeah like if it's not
Sugar Leaf it goes at that point yeah
well makes harvesting easier all that
stuff and it's not necessary to have
those leaves on for a yield at that
point exactly yeah and then for you know
anything biomass and makes it to
extraction you know we're not going to
have you know 14% testing trim the trim
is going to test just as high as the
flower and that translates into you know
improved costing for everything
Downstream in our production lab as well
totally yeah that's a good way to look
at it for sure let's talk about drying
and curing because I think uh you know
what is your preferred method for
drawing and caring low and slow man 6060
tried and true like I know a lot of Ops
might not have the real estate to to
hold things this long right but but if
you do loan slow is the way to go yeah
and some people don't have I've I've
seen this a lot where their AC's don't
go down to 60 they can only go down to
65 or 62 62 is fine 65 is pushing it
yeah you don't want to you don't want to
let perfect get in the way the good
sometimes things like that you know if
you have an extra day yeah not gonna not
going to defeat you yeah and then curing
TPL blocks you guys use Turlock bins do
you guys use 100 like the we have the
liners and our our 37 gon tots throw the
Bas in there you know just for
redundancy and then once we actually lot
things out they go into the five pound
lot grow bags Turlock so yeah with the
Bita yeah that's great I've never heard
of that before that's actually that's
new to me that's that's an interesting
concept I like redundancies though I'm
all about redundancies so that's you
know it's like my life is built on
redundancies oh yeah yeah gotta think
about that when you're planning the
operation out too you know if something
goes down you know how are we going to
make sure all these rooms get watered
gotta have a
you know female pipe thread that you can
know throw mondai pump on with a couple
55 gallon drums if you know your whole
fertigation system goes down you're not
going to be able to get support till the
next day yeah and cry because everything
died which Happ I've seen that happen
before yeah oh yeah I've seen nuk DS oh
yeah so yeah or the power goes out and
then it comes back on and the fans don't
kick back on or what I've seen all kinds
of stuff in my life or one of your units
trips and get stuck in heating Mode come
back in the next day today and looks
like everything caught fire yeah you got
some golden Golden Goat but it's it's
not the right not the right kind of
Golden Goat exactly yeah completely
golden plants it looks like a a field of
wheat literally crispy crispy that's the
worst not even not even biomass worthy
that makes my stomach churn a little bit
just because I've seen it before and it
just yeah I feel for the people that it
happens to
MH we're not even touching this thing
have to put some work in yeah yeah tell
me about the first time you started
smoking cannabis I was living in South
Carolina at the time my uh was one of my
friend's older brothers he uh had had
some weed uh we tried it didn't get high
the first time tried it again like a
week later and just I love the way it
made me feel you know I had a bit of
anxiousness to me kind of always have
and every time that I ingest smoke
cannabis you know whether it's an edible
or tincture like it's it seems to
mitigate that completely for for me so
it was uh it was love it second smoke
for me yeah yeah I feel like a lot of us
do the same thing it's like the first
time you smoke you don't know how to
smoke or you don't know how to inhale
properly and you get caught up in
everything and then you don't get
high and uh Edibles can fix that real
quick oh I've been humbled by some
Boulder bars oh man I've been humbled by
Edibles too I just I like raos and
gummies I don't do too much the Edibles
these days it's just uh they're for me
they're so strong but I can smoke all
day long no problem but then when it
comes to Edibles they just they take it
seems like they take forever to kick in
then once they kick in I want them to be
like more
mellow sometimes or I take too much 50
milligrams is too much for me which a
lot of people that's fine you know I'm
more of like the TW it it depends too it
really depends on what it is and who
made it and time of day time of day what
I'm doing if I'm at a concert I'm not
thinking about it yeah it's totally fine
or if I'm flying and I'm going to sleep
exactly yeah I think my sweet spot's
probably right around 40 to 50 as well
but I got some friends that are like 500
milligrams give it to me I'm ready you
know and I'm not I'm not that guy so but
roll me up a fat joint and we'll smoke
it we'll smoke two you know hanging out
uh and that's what I enjoy I enjoy
sitting I also enjoy the experience of
hanging out with my friends and smoking
you know it's
it's part of the whole experience where
you can talk to somebody you can hang
out and smoke and you get to know new
people people feel like over a period of
a big joint in an hour you can learn a
lot about
somebody you know and there's funny
things like you can tell about people if
they gum the joint and get it all wet
you know what I mean or if if they make
the joint run because they hit it too
hard it's like all these little things
it's like character flaws I can spot the
character Flaws by the way they smoke
The Joint true
so you know I don't hate on anybody but
so it's gross to have a joint it's all
wet oh I agree are you going to be
working on another book or another
version of this book in the near future
I I would definitely like to I think uh
my
biggest imp well the biggest Improvement
that I think that we could make you know
uh for me at least is uh the
illustrations I spent uh probably weeks
reaching out to different Botanical
artists on LinkedIn trying to you know
try to network and find folks had a
couple artists with them my friend but
it just like wasn't their their ballpark
oh I got the guys and uh I got the guys
when you're ready perfect we ended up
going with uh I forget the website but
is essentially like you know one of
those uh like workb type websites where
you have folks that have different skill
sets you go on they're like hey I need
these made by this and ended up paying
like you know 50 bucks an illustration
and I think they came out well they're
very practical and it's easy to tell
what we're you know depicting with
different sections but right I think a
Botanical artist that was gifted and was
C passionate about cannabis could put a
whole different been on the book and it
would change it yeah and now with
technology it's amazing what you can do
with with art and with incorporating
those type of things in books so yeah we
got a really good layout hery did the
layout in our book and she's just
amazing but then we had we had multiple
people do illustrations which was great
because we were on a deadline to get it
done I was told by somebody not going to
name any names but you know who you are
said that there's no way I could get
this book done in a year and so that lit
a fire under my ass and I was like
there's no way I'm going to listen to
this guy I can do whatever I want and I
can get this book done and so I got the
book done in way less than a year um I
had my draft and it was done in into
print uh you know it didn't get done as
quickly as I was hoping but it was done
in less than a year how long did it take
for you to find the printing company for
like the page the quality the you know
binding well I wanted to go with the US
company and yeah we had to go through
you know and see what I knew I wanted on
the cover was I wanted something
different I didn't want another grow
book I wanted a they had a big plant
with a black background because
everybody had that and that's why I love
your book too that's another thing is
like okay well this it's not just
another grow book that has you know a
beautiful Bud on the cover with a black
background so we put a seat on the cover
of mine and then I wanted soft touch
those were like the two things that I
knew that I wanted and then it was like
thickness there's so many different
thicknesses and the first printing I did
we got a smaller run we did a run of 420
and it was a thicker page and so it was
a thicker book and I like the thickness
of the book but when it comes to
shipping we had talked to Khalifa
genetics and a couple other people U and
decided to go with a thinner book that
it was easier to flip through the pages
and it was slightly it wasn't it was
still it's still a heavy book it weighs
a kilo right or or 1.75 pounds or
something like that so it's not quite a
kilo but it's
heavy but for shipping it's cheaper than
something that weighs 2.5 kilos so we
went with something thinner it made more
sense for shipping and it's easier to
read so yeah and your book was put it
feels like a textbook it feels like
something I would buy in college for
$300 uh but yeah I think your your book
what is the retail in your book oh it's
retailing at 200 we went with like the
highest quality materials for everything
we we tried out a number of different
things including Amazon Printing and so
for me I I really thought Amazon print
on demand was going to be the ticket or
uh there was a couple other companies we
were looking for I don't need to name
names but I thought man that was going
to be the way to go I could just pay for
it but they'll give me a percentage by
the each but it was way too expensive it
didn't make sense that's the other
reason self-publishing it's like a lot
of times these Publishers will give you
you know like my book 55 it's a little
more expensive than it probably should
be but I self-published it and so we
have to buy smaller runs of it same
thing with yours it's like it's maybe
more expensive than people think it
should be but it's because you had to
pay so much more because you're buying
smaller runs and you're doing it all
yourself exactly right and so I didn't
want to only make a dollar a book and
probably not make any money for two or
three years till the book had paid for
itself uh and that's why you a lot of
times what happens guys when you use
Publishers is you go to the publisher
they pay for all the books they do the
heavy lifting in that regard with the
money and then you get a royalty on your
book and a lot of times it's a very
small royalty or you might not get any
royalty if your book's not good enough
to ever pay for itself right but if you
do it yourself it's all on your
shoulders if your book fails it's your
failure it's not the fail failure of
some somebody else or their money it's
your money and I love that it's like I
I'm willing to die for my book y same
same yeah it just didn't make sense to
work with anybody else cuz you know the
book cost to print you know would be
more than whatever that percentage would
have ended up being as well so it was
almost a yeah as you were saying yeah
you would have had to charge 150 or 175
on Amazon just to be able to make a
profit exactly and that doesn't make
sense and not that there's anything
wrong with that some people might be
okay with that but it's like you want
something that's somewhat affordable to
people but also you're you're putting
good information out there so and your
yours does work as a coffee table book
um also as a textbook you know I think
there's GNA there's going to be a need
for textbooks in colleges on cannabis
you know with the way things are going
and the amount of jobs that are out
there as far as medical and wreck in how
many states are legal yeah I agree
there's uh there's definitely not a lot
out there like it that's for sure so if
someone's young and they're coming in
the industry what's the the best way for
them to get started in your opinion best
way to get started uh you know without
any experience at all no hom grow
experience or you know any kind of
relevant transferable skills like uh you
know working in a kitchen I would uh
either you know try to apply for an
entry-level job with a with a company
that has a good reputation for having a
positive working culture and they you
know compensate and take care of their
employees fairly and well that route or
alternatively going in uh one of those
different programs they offer you know
Oaker Dam or uh Cleveland School of
canibas I know both of them work at with
placing individuals that graduate from
their courses in position so if you're
not able to do it on your own working
through one of those Avenues or Channels
with one of those businesses that are
very established and have a great
network with a lot of different folks
we'll definitely be able to want you
know teach you how to do what you're
going to be doing and also help place
you somewhere where you know you can
grow your career and yeah go from there
yeah I mean it's funny because I'm not a
big fan of culinary schools but I do
like xer Dam I just taught my first
class to Oaker Dam a month and a half
ago or something like that and uh yeah
and we're going to be doing a breeding
course through Oaker Dam eventually here
with the book have you taught at oer Dam
yet not Oaker Dam no you should yeah
they would love to have you there I'm
sure I would love to man so I can make
that I can make that happen I can make
the connection happen at the very least
uh they're always looking for good
people and there are a bunch of good
people there they're another group of
people that are doing the Lord's work I
feel like they're really passionate
about the plant and passionate about
education and finding a way to make the
world a better place and so we need
people like that yeah I'd love an
introduction man yeah for sure and
they're local they're local here perfect
okay so let's talk about the genetics
section of your book since I'm a breeder
I do I work with genetics I think your
genetics section is great I feel like
it's a good overview you go into uh
phenotypes and genotypes a little bit
how do you feel about the genetic
section of your book who's really one of
the funnest parts of the book to write
you know just trying to put a foundation
for people to have a good understanding
of why it's so important how it came
about what to look for yeah you know
it's like I said before it's the
backbone of you know every good
successful cannabis cultivation
operation so yeah it's everything's
built on genetics that's our our slogan
is everything has a beginning genetics
are so
foundational uh to what you do and I
feel like it it could not only could it
will make the difference between great
and good flour and you can't have good
flour and be successful anymore you know
10 years ago you could have mediocre or
good flour and you would still be able
to sell it for a good price and still be
able to make money whereas now you're in
with the stuff that nobody wants that
they won't pay a lot for and you're
competing for price with people that can
produce it for a lot
less so and as far as genetics what are
you looking for in a good
our yeah something uh commercially
viable you know it's got to check all
the boxes for uh you know not just yield
quality bag appeal you know from a
Grower's perspective is it something
that's easy to work with is it something
that we have issues with in the Clone
room you know issues with it anywhere is
it pest resistant is it you know disease
and pathogen free yeah I mean going into
commercial viability I think commercial
viability these days is extremely
important especially with the business
and its scale uh but as far as like like
bud structure where are you like nested
bracks you like open bracks you have a
preference on that yeah I mean I like to
have open bracks right because when
you're growing you know thousands of
plants in a single room yeah you don't
want to have things too too close
together I mean I don't mind tight buds
for some stuff but I like my buds to
have shape you know at the end of the
day too and I feel like trimming those
it's low Leaf to Bud ratio is super
important I think trimming being able to
trim the weed fast if you grow it proper
and then as far as trimming what do you
guys do for trimming do you guys use
traditional scissors are you guys doing
any advanced stuff mechanical separation
or we do a combination of things so we
have some uh some tumblers some
Terminator XL dries which uh certain
strains we can push through and it
doesn't look any different from a
handrim flower there's other things that
uh you know break up a bit easier and
for those well you know old hand trim
those yeah I'm I'm a big fan of the
canab brush so and finger trimming I
think that there still uh places and
applications that work really well even
though it's not generally used by
everybody but I think the can of brush
and finger trimming is a great way to go
if you can do it but that's another
controlled environment you got to be
able to go around 6060 let's talk about
cloning for a little
bit what do you feel are the best ways
to execute cloning um and the important
things to watch out for uh you know
starting off with good robust vigorously
growing healthy mother plants yeah you
you know obviously having good genetics
goes without saying uh keeping things as
clean as possible you know starting off
with something like rock wool that has a
good you know oxygen to U water ratio
with inside within the the stone wool uh
using a good rooting
hormone uh maintaining the right light
levels you know what do you consider a
good root hormone uh the the rooting
hormone is is there ones that you prefer
over other ones yes I use uh I use
clonex IBA the endo3 betra acid you get
a high five for I'm all big on clonex I
use clonex too but I do like hormex as
well okay uh for for different scenarios
but if you're trying to get really fast
Roots hormex is great clonex is the most
consistent yeah I agree I've been using
them for you know almost 10 years now
and yep grodan Stonewall with clonex
great combo works really well together
it does it does how about domes and
humidity and temperature humidity domes
with vents you know typically it'll
start hardening off around like day
three you go like open them a third open
a little more each day start burping
whole trays for like 30 minutes or until
a sign of wil after like day 8 yeah
should have uh you know fully rooted
trays day 14 completely hardened off
temperature- wise humidity wise you want
like you know 7580 inside the Dome have
a room that's at least like 65 and then
uh temperature you know 77 78 degrees
Yeah we push ours a little warmer and
but everybody's got their own Tech and
then maybe like uh 100 150 micro moles
yeah right there you don't want to push
them too high no you can get away with a
lot less too and get great results but
totally yeah I mean we're actually
testing uh mats right now heat mats to
see if we can get more roots or faster
Roots um just as my partner believes my
my TC partner Justin we'll have a future
episode where we discuss if the heat
mats actually worked but uh he wants to
do trials he claims that they'll root
faster they're better uh I'm open to it
I want to see the side by side we're
going to do side by side racks and
really compare cultivar to cultivar heat
mat no heat mat uh and yeah we'll see
those are like some of the things I love
doing with AB testing yeah love it man
gota always always be traling things
figure out uh best practices right yeah
for sure well and never never rest on
your laurels and expect that what you
have is the best that you can ever get
oh never I mean that's how we go to
these these conferences you know totally
everyone yeah there's so many and
especially the size of mjbiz there's
always someone who's got something new
something Innovative I mean I'm looking
for a new rolling machine this year that
can provide me with a partial hand roll
where we can at least get the shape or
something like that to speed up the
process because I really want a hand
handrolled joint but I want to be able
to automate part of the process or speed
up the the process if we can to where we
can get something quality but as as I've
seen so far there's nothing that beats a
handrolled joint that's 100% handrolled
no I agree a lot of the uh the Packers
that they have now there's you know
always something wrong with them even if
it's a small amount of them at a out of
a large batch you know one a run yeah
yeah that won't happen with a good
handroll yeah it won't and consistency
is so important especially with a
product like that that's going out to
the market you can ruin someone's
experience if they get a big old run
halfway down their joint that's the
experience I want to share with the
world is like the experience that I get
from smoking if I can share that with
everybody I feel like more people would
smoke you know especially when it tastes
good it Burns right you get the effect
you get the the experience it's all
about the flavor and the experience yeah
well and then that makes you want to go
back for that experience again you know
just like if you're cooking a good meal
and it's it's great they want to come
back and they expect to get a great meal
the next time and so consistency is just
so important consistency and
repeatability yeah for sure well thank
you so much for coming on the show today
if people are looking to find more about
chrisop farell where can they go we have
a website collab
cannabis.com I uh I'm also on LinkedIn
and I have some links there as well to
my website I'm very responsive on there
yeah Instagram Instagram as well is just
my name chris. lastname oeral o f r l l
nice so yeah so thank you so much for
coming on the show today look forward to
doing this again um I'm excited about
your book I hope uh you have great sales
over the next year and through the
holiday season likewise brother thank
you thank you guys for watching please
like And subscribe down below