[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James loud
podcast and today our special guest is
Matt from Terra International how you
doing thank you very much James for
having me on here I'm great so you're a
terrorist I I am a little terrorist you
know we are here moving a lot of
products and helping out this industry
and trying to bring a community back to
where it needs to be glad to have you on
the show we've been talking about this
for a little while uh we met not so long
ago but I knew about your product for
the last year and a half good flour that
I've seen coming from uh your nutrient
line yeah I thought you were running it
about for two years now I was just under
the impression I was like oh man so just
the last six weeks it's the SF well been
running it I've known about it for a
long time uh SF Cana my my buddies over
there they've been running it yes and
crushing with it so yeah I was I was
excited to uh test it out and see how it
does and so thank you very much we're
we're running it right now for in our
veg no thank you it people like you in
this industry is what we need James you
know research development and get better
yeah you know this whole industry that's
what we have to do is get better as the
industry yeah I think a lot of research
and development goes goes on here and I
think a lot of people really need to do
side-by-side testing I think that's so
huge to determine what's good and what's
not good and there's a lot of stuff that
maybe uh works for a certain person and
another individual something else works
for them and so you know even cloning
techniques stuff like that
and because it's a plant and it's so
Dynamic not every recipe works for every
situation uh Light Recipes you know you
know you name it there's so many
variables involved and that that's what
I love is being on the cusp of trying
new things and cutting Edge uh nutrients
Cutting Edge
techniques um Cutting Edge ideas I I
love that stuff being on the on the on
the edge of what's new and what's
upcoming and some of it's amazing some
of it's terrible some of it's everything
in between you know it's it's an
interesting time to be alive but you
learn something through all of it that's
all that matters you know like great
thing that you brought that up I'm
actually joining a group of about five
or six guys that are coming together
which all different walks of life but in
this industry um we have a grow two
Growers involved in it a genetics guy
involved in it a hydro store involved in
it myself um and we're just trying to
come together as a unit and build a
research and development facility yeah
exactly kind of like what you're saying
we're going to have some that are double
Stacks we're going to have some that are
single Stacks we're going to have double
stack mother room double stack baby room
just to see all the different angles of
the this industry and how far we can
actually push this envelope because
realistically we've only been pushing
the envelope about 5 six years you know
where we can actually come out of the
shadows and show our talents you know so
I look at this industry we're only five
six years old so our goal is to hit 10
pounds in a couple years per light 10
pounds per 4x4 you heard it here first
hey we have to do it you know because
cost per pound once corporate comes into
this industry full-fledged in
our Sops need to be about $200 a pound
per 4x4 vertically you can get that
that's realistic I guess or per 4x4
stack three high no talking about
single what's your thought on uh the
Double the two-tier the double
stack uh what's what's your opinion on
that because me personally I think some
of my friends do really well with it I
prefer uh High ceilings with tall plants
it all dep depends on your building yeah
you know environment is the most crucial
thing for your garden you know there's
some places where it allows a double
stack um we're actually in talks with
another building on top of what we're
already planning on moving into in the
near future is a triple stack yeah and
that one has 210 lights per room there's
a there's a 12 rooms in this facility as
well so those are the things that we're
looking forward to is to continue to
evolve and continue to get better you
know that's honestly what the group The
connected guys and grow world and that
whole little group I love that group I I
went there like a year and a half ago to
the connect event and I just seen all
they're doing is pushing education into
this industry you know girl world a is
great I mean it's I'm glad to be a part
of it I think they're really great
people we're working they've connected
with really great people yes uh yeah and
it's just it's a nice Community same
thing with Sergio what he's done with
the connect events yes I mean that's
just it was his calling and he's really
owned it and taken it on and now he's
doing them all over the world that
events and I just I love seeing my
friends win and it's great we've had him
on the show and him and I have became
friends over the last year and he's just
a great guy and you know it's like he's
on this upward trajectory and love it is
good people want to surround themselves
and good things actually come out of it
when that happens you know and first
thing for me as well I seen Sergio and I
was like oh my goodness who is this guy
you know and just continuing to listen
to what he's doing and I just told him
hey how can I help you you know I see
your business I see your philosophy but
there's other angles that might be able
to come in and help and turn on a couple
light switches for him you know and he's
going to be probably a part of the whole
R&amp;D facility you know because he brought
this up and he said hey are you guys
interested you know and I had talked to
one of the Growers that's going to be a
part of it two years ago I said listen I
need a R&amp;D facility because I'm coming
out with our nutrient line and I want to
know everything about it you know like
we're still two years R&amp;D our nutrient
line because nothing's to be set in
stone until the Growers say that's what
we need you know and we'll still
continue to make lines you know we're
going to have a line that we have that
comes out which is a standard line but
our expert line we're going to continue
to evolve and innovate with the Growers
right I'm not a grower anymore I had to
let those days go you know but for me
I'm about sourcing the right people the
right products and putting it together
as a unit you know custom mag
formulators in Fresno that's who Blends
it for us and I have zero problem
letting everybody know that because you
build a relationship with people and if
you have a relationship with people they
don't want to burn you you know and
that's kind of in dealing with the good
ones don't at least hey the good ones
don't but guess what yeah you learn
something even if someone does burn you
as long as it doesn't take everything
from you you know and so that's kind of
the philosophy that's what I learned
from Sergio is trust people you know I
don't like to trust people especially in
this industry most people don't pay
their bills it's difficult at this time
it's tough dude it's trusty I mean the I
have trust issues with this industry as
well especially with genetics and seeds
and and you know it's like uh giving
people terms on stuff that that gets me
very nervous and I I've done it with
some people and gotten completely
screwed there's people out there that
have screwed me yeah and but but you do
have I mean there is a certain level of
trust with certain people where you know
especially after repeated business we
are in an interesting industry
and it's everchanging it's very volatile
um there's not a lot of stability so I
still have trust issues it is and
everyone's getting divided right now
yeah that's what's going on so some of
us are getting divided and some of us
are getting together and I feel like
I've been in this industry a long time
and I'm always one to want to join
forces with other people and try to do
it bigger and better and you know and
there's a lot of talent left still
there's a lot Talent gone uh the
industry has changed but there is a lot
of talent out there there is and so I
mean with within our circles and I know
some of the people in your circles and
some of the people in my circle we have
a lot of talent um is and it's not just
genetics or not just cultivation it's
everything correct and how big can you
be by yourself right and so that's what
I'm preaching now it's I'm deal I only
sell to hydroponic stores right I have
the ability I have everyone's addresses
to sell direct but I believe in people
that have helped me get to where I am
you know so why am I going to go and go
around their backs you know like back in
the day hey if we used to go to your
Hook guy guess what happens you don't
get those phone calls anymore you know
and so as Growers believe that they're
selling more than the hydroponic stores
or they buy more than a hydroponic store
does yeah that's correct in some cases
but now if you bring a group of a couple
hundred hydro stores together you bring
a group of a couple hundred Growers
together now you actually have leverage
and that's numbers is power you know and
that's where you'll end up being able to
leverage things so a lot of Growers are
out there and they don't buy at hydro
stores anymore we understand that and
the education at the hydro store needs
to get better you know and that's going
to be it needs to get better the
dispensary too it does and but but these
things they can be improved they can be
you know you know and so that was one of
my things that I was speaking with a
couple guys in the group is hey when we
go into the hydro stores let's make
reals let's make every product that
we're displaying a reel a two-minute
reel and let the
manufacturers express what they want to
express about their product to get it
into the store you know to where you
don't have to rely on the store but you
know like I'm going to end up building a
group of stores together and bring them
as a unit and say hey log in to the
connect events listen educate yourself
get better you know because that's where
we got to go toost a connect event at
your location you know I feel like the
Sergio is going all over with connect
events too I do love the sack location
though those are great I love sack and
i' except the traffic except for the
traffic that's horrible man yeah there's
there's some good food out in sack too
surprisingly you it but yeah I I got my
you know my my buddies out there and I I
love going to dinner with them too and
but the connect he has food there too so
if you haven't gone to the connect event
it's great there's mingling with people
that are intelligent that know the plant
that are passionate on all levels and I
feel like it's that that part about it
is great because I feel like there's
this mix of of vendors and people and
it's very casual and it's great yeah
honestly when I went to the event for
the second or third time the first
couple were still growing but the one
that I met you at the favin one yeah
there was 3 400 people there you know
and it's like everyone wanting to come
see I understand underlight was a huge
Topic at the time and everybody wants to
come see that but still is it still is
you know and fav's killing it out there
killing it they're killing it and I mean
the yeah it's just everyone wants to
know more about it and I mean that the
proof is in the pudding with the fav and
that's what I like about it is like
there's actual we I have friends I have
friends and I can see firsthand the
results that they're getting and I love
it yeah you know that's what I like
because everyone says they have
something good you know there's so many
people out there that are like oh I got
this this is the best of this or the
best of that at the end of the day the
proof is in the pudding show me the
money show me the product then we can
talk about it you know you have the best
flower let's see it I you know it's like
I I like good flower I want you know but
everybody thinks their flowers is good
too so there's this ego when it's your
product as well and and these hydro
stores have to push their OS aside you
know and like perfect example like you
brought up faven right FV was from a
grower it started in a facility yeah but
guess what the facility didn't have it
dialed in correctly he ended up going to
a hydro store and the hydro store had a
couple more ideas that put it together
yeah and that's the communication that
we're talking about come to a hydro
store and transfer education you know as
Growers CU most of us are most of the
Growers ended up learning how to grow
where normally at a hydro store you know
maybe your buddies here and there but
they the origin came from normally a
hydro free internet it was all from
either your buddies or the hydro store
and a lot of times you had to talk about
it as like tomatoes Tomatoes Berkeley
under Garden I used to go there and it
was always referenced to vegetables you
can make vegetable references but the
second they wouldn't talk to you anymore
if you want to talk about wheat yeah so
and that's that's how serious they were
it was a lot of places were like that
yeah I had a hydro store down in Gilroy
and uh I think it was
2010 and we didn't talk about marijuana
it was a very closed lip situation you
know so but now it's growing you know
we're allowed to express ourselves we're
allowed to show each other but now in
this time what are we doing we're
closing up some some people are closing
up you know I see a lot of these large
Growers and they buy direct from every
single manufacturer which I understand
that philosophy is to cut your price
down we get it but if you can look
bigger and understand that you're never
going to be bigger than corporate yeah
and you should start to join a team to
an extent you know and that's what's
going to Keep Us Alive instead of being
a part of the race to the bottom right
because a lot of this is that race
especially if you're a cultivator you
know and I'm not I'm not a cultivator I
do cultivate okay but I'm not a
cultivator uh I'm a genetics guy yes and
so I have cultivation Partners I have
cultivation friends that do amazing
cultivation but I I'm blessed that I'm
not doing cultivation because it's
really difficult you know and it's like
the prices keep going down the inputs
keep going up in cost yes and same at
the hydro stores yeah every store is
challenging each other $2 doll cheaper a
dollar cheaper there has to be an end of
that you know and so what we're trying
to do is come out with branded quality
products that people know about and kind
of set a presidence of hey I would
rather fight my brother than my dad you
know and that's kind of what's going on
in our industry behind the scenes is hey
your hydro store is your brother the
neighbor you know it's okay to fight
that guy some days you know but are you
going to beat him up to where you can't
see no more no but when your dad comes
in he hits you one time and you're done
you know and oh my dad still like that
I'm not I won't fight my dad you won't
fight your dad why because you know in
the back of our mind you know
manufacturer they control everything in
the long run now is it their Duty and
their job to also help the stores it is
you know and so that's where I'm coming
at an angle um we have our United
Products um and Royal gold Sunshine we
we distribute for a lot of Manufacturers
Quest there's a lot of them out there
and so what we're trying to do is speak
to them and let them know that the
Growers are hurting right now yeah the
hydro stores are hurting right now the
only ones that aren't hurting as much
the
manufacturers and so it's time to kind
of depending on the manufacturer but
yeah correct you know the manufacturers
that are still doing well right now you
know there's margins that they're
holding on to you know and so like for
our nutrient line I'm going to cut out
all the margins yeah to give it to the
stores to actually make some money and
still give it to the end user cheaper
than what pretty much most the uh salts
out there on the market are you know so
that's just it's my give back back right
my stores every single store that's
supported me through this whole journey
that I've been on since
20145 you know I can't leave them right
it's loyalty you know and so those are
the things that I believe full-hearted
in is
actually supporting the people that
support you you know well let's talk
about your nutrient life for a little
bit okay so yeah it's Blended at custom
mag formulators um so I used to
distribute for Athena um ended that
ended that relationship about three
months ago with them just our views were
different and so what I tell all my
stores is hey it's time to get better so
what I did with custom a was I said hey
give me the highest input you guys
possibly can for this three-part
Baseline and I'm going to sell it at the
cheapest price possible and see where it
goes you know and the guys at custom a
are extremely brilliant at what they do
that's their craft their manufacturers
and so I have three groups working with
custom mag right now to do what research
and develop other products so we're not
done we're going to continue to take
this to another level so you just have
the three-part right now we have no we
have a full line yeah yeah so we have a
full line and so there's a PK powder in
there as well and we'll have a ph up and
then a finisher as well and then we're
actually for
our um hyper chloris acid we're working
with a couple companies uh one I'm not
going to divulge but another one is uh
clean grow um he has water Max and
that's kind of where a lot of products
were gener generated from in this
industry you know so with his and we can
go make it ourselves you you know but I
don't believe in that I believe in
helping people that are in the circle
you know and there's a there's another
uh hypochloric acid which isn't
hypochloric acid that's going to come
out and show a lot of people some things
so we're happy to have that in our
product line as well really cool yeah so
there's a lot of product on the market
and there's not a ton of quality I mean
I think it's gotten better through wreck
uh as as far as in California you know
because every state is so different are
you talking about flower or I'm talking
about flour okay specifically flow I
mean we can talk about extract extracts
the same thing okay we can talk about
the end product okay what would you
say uh the biggest problem with the
flower out there is you think inputs you
think uh drying and
curing back in the day drying and curing
yeah it was huge you know um but I would
say now it's more
it's grown to instead of doing 20 30
lights in a house it's grown to a, 500
lights it's very hard to manage
that size of rooms um but I would
say actually probably lack of education
for that size you know just having
Growers understand
that when you scale up to those levels
there's going to be change you know and
so the evolution of technology is
helping us you know because back in the
day we used all hand water you know like
I heard on the podcast couple that you
still hand water outside so do I you
know I just don't have marijuana plants
in my backyard anymore but I like to go
outside and that's my peace and my calm
and so but when people are in the garden
you know they're used to handw watering
now we're using drippers so things have
changed and as things Chang we sensors
now now we have sensors you know it's
like those things are game changers they
are you know and that's what's going to
make us better yeah you know but right
now is there a transition period yes
yeah is there's still some fire that 5
10 years ago we would have never seen
yes there is you know I smoked some the
other day I don't smoke too much anymore
but I got a cut from or one of one of
our buddies got a cut from you the
poison gusher yeah wow yeah yeah that's
a good one that's a great one no that's
not a good one that's a great one and
that's going to bring gas back yeah
that's that yeah so floral Flame's
growing that SF Canon's growing that yes
I got it from the SF Canon guys yeah
yeah yeah yeah it's good like they just
do a good job with everything they do
but I was floored I was like oh man I
need a uber home you know and I did not
create the poison gur okay but yeah so
but yeah it's part of the TC library
that that my partner has access to stuff
but yeah that's it's so you're in the
minority and I'm in the minority I like
poison gush I feel like not everybody
has turned on to poison gesturers why
it's not candy enough oh man same thing
with the you know the what is the the
new one the so they have a the new
strawberry banana they have a new
strawberry banana Skittles and it's not
candy enough for people and it's like
come on man it tastes amazing super
complex it's it's got a lot of funk to
it you know I like the poison gushers
for the same reason it's got fuel and
Funk it's it's special for that yes you
know and it's it's also one of those
ones that still burns down to the roach
and tastes amazing yeah and I I opened
the bag and I said you don't smell that
too often you know in this industry like
I was at the connected event with the
candies and I looked at all 20 jars you
know because I had the VIP pass to go in
the back and I looked at them all
fantastic all of them not going to knock
any of them you know but someone of them
were missing a nose I was knocking some
of them absolutely but you know and
there's some stuff and I feel like a lot
of that some of it's drawing some of
it's uh too much heat in the room I
think that's another problem is like not
getting your temps down and then when
you have a little too much heat that
that's a that's an issue there's a lot
more light than what we used to have
back in the day a lot more light
absolutely the light's different that
you know we I didn't even like LEDs at
first and I talked about on the show a
lot but HPS I'm still a HPS guy I love
HPS we got some HPS here we love r&amp; ding
stuff under HPS I like doing my
reversals under
HPS so there's nothing wrong with HPS
there isn't and I think in our facility
at our R&amp;D place we'll have HPS as well
yeah we're going to what we're going to
do is basically open it up to
manufacturers if you want your product
to be displayed here use the room well
and you got to use HPS because you love
it because it costs more to run than LED
it does but uh but if you love TPS and
you love the way the HPS makes the plant
Express then there's nothing wrong with
that yeah flow is going to sell you know
and if you have the turbs and you have
the smell that's what I think is missing
a lot in this industry right now is the
smell for sure for sure a lot of it's
missing the smell and flavor it's like
when you when you smoke it and we talk
about how Instagram's to blame for this
because you get these plants on
Instagram and it's just based on look
but at the end of the day it's like
really like what does it smell like what
does it taste like how does it make you
feel all those things you can't get from
a picture yeah and if you're not getting
the smell from it you're not going to
get the taste from it yeah you know they
go hand in hand they do but sometimes
the smell is more like I feel like
Skittles it smells good but it smokes
even better than it smells I and there's
a handful of things out there like that
but I started smoking again because of
the Skittles I hadn't smoked in about 3
4 years I just from our mutual friend
you get that skill it's like it's a game
changer I seen that and I was said okay
I guess I got to break it you know so
good it's so good I the problem with it
is when that's the if I have 20 or 30 or
40 different flavors that I'm smoking on
I get to that and I end up smoking all
that before I go into anything else and
like I might have a bunch of stuff that
might get old because I smoke the
Skittles first I like trying all kinds
of different stuff all the time and
depending on the day but that Skittles
is just sometimes when it's a good batch
it's like it just tastes amazing for me
when I see a good batch and I'm at the
right place at the right time then
that's where I'm I'm gonna smoke you
know normally it's in San
Francisco they know where I go and
that's you know it's a great place for
me to go hang out in a cool environment
and I get to see some of the absolute
top-notch weeds in this world yeah
that's there and there's so much good
stuff besides Skittles but Skittles has
a special place in my heart yeah but
yeah and there's so many genetics dude
that that are good and there's so many
that are just average you know I feel
like there's so many that need more work
to be done purple punch is one of those
ones it's one step away from being cool
and being good but by itself it's just
kind of eh but you can cross it to stuff
and you get some interesting expressions
and some really good stuff uh Oreos is
another one like people don't like Oreos
but you cross it to stuff you can get
some good stuff so it's like one or two
steps away from being amazing see and
that's your lane that's where I let you
go crazy and that's what we need is
people in our IND indry to kind of stay
a little more in their Lanes we got we
got Builders selling products but they
have no facility you know genetic guys
are going out there selling Rockwell and
their genetics and so that's kind of
what we want is to build up you're the
genetics man right let's build you up
let's put you out this is the beauty of
the White Market this is the beauty of
being able to do stuff legally is now
you can stay in your own lane and you
can be successful at it you can be
extremely is successful and you know if
you're at the top tier of your industry
of whatever you do whether it's genetics
or nutrients or you name it rock wool
you know whatever it is if you're at the
top you're going to be successful and
you can really hyperfocus on improving
genetics or improving but the guys that
try to do everything man they they end
up losing something yeah like right now
we're working on a 7030 I shouldn't be
saying this but we're working on a 7030
compression and everyone's like like how
can you can press perite you can't yeah
you know so guess what you got to go
outside the box guys you know just like
what I did with Sunshine way back in the
day yeah hey let's go outside the box
you guys gave us a bag of sunshine that
weighed 12 lbs the black one it used to
weigh 60 now it weighs 120 nobody can
carry this upstairs anymore you know so
I told them let's change the narrative
you know let's make it a white bag give
it to me at 60 PBS and see what we do
with it right we ended up you know
selling more White Sunshine than you can
imagine you know it's just changing the
narrative understand your lane stay in
that lane and focus and do the absolute
best you can do you know so what do you
prefer Rockwall what's your favorite
substrate cocoa soil or it's just I'm
one of those guys that likes all of them
I I like everything for different uses I
believe different uses cause for
different things if you're going
Outdoors you should be in some Pete Moss
you know because need to hold that water
and retain the water um if you're inside
it's whatever you feel more comfortable
with me personally the reason why I want
to build a team is to educate people I
personally think Rockwell is going to be
gone in two years I know it's a crazy
subject for people to C I don't even
know if people can wrap their heads
around it but I really think it might go
away and you have to kind of look at the
not in years okay give me give it four
okay when Federal legalization comes
I believe it's going to be around four
years from now yeah I think there's
going to be a lot of changes you think
they're going to change that so no more
rock wall because it's environmentally
unfriendly right you know just like with
our LED lights if you don't know your
efficiency on your LED light in a couple
years you're probably going to have to
switch them well that's why HPS will
probably be going away unfortunately but
it's because
it is not efficient it's not not as
efficient and it creates more heat and
so you it creates more electricity and
you know I mean I I get that part
Rockwell we'll see it's it's used in a
so so much so heavily
used everywhere it is I went to a uh
Disney Disney World yeah and you go
through a little boat ride and there was
Rockwell in there and I was caught off
guard I'm like you know but there's
going to be a time and a place where we
have to elevate and get better so for me
I would say Rockwell is going to get
switched into Coco H interesting in due
time yeah I mean I like rockwolf for for
certain uses I like rockwolf for my
mom's and I like rockwool for
clones uh I'm always open to change but
yeah I mean we're working with grodan
right now too interesting outlook on the
industry because stuff can disappear
just like that and what are you gonna do
if you're buying all your stuff just say
you're buying everything from grodan and
grodan goes away you're lost as a a
cultivator you're going to have to go
back to the drawing you mean there's
going to be a learning curve when you
switch correct you know or just in
general not to be able to go to a hydro
store or bounce ideas off people yeah
hey what's everyone going to just like
in Oakland we were all told we were
allowed to use uh generators diesel
generators you can't use those anymore
uhuh none of that you see what I'm
saying and so the more you're around
people that are in this industry and
communicating you're going to educate
yourself to go to another level it's
being on The Cutting Edge it is and it's
about around right people that actually
care about furthering the industry you
know and that's what when I went around
the connect Community that's what I seen
I seen the next Evolution right where
the where it's going to go because that
for me as an owner of our company I
can't think about today even though the
day-to-day task I'm there every day yeah
myob two years down the road you know
and if you can't see two years down the
road then you should just probably not
own a business you know because things
change and if you don't know how to
Pivot at the right times then you'll end
up falling backwards the last two years
for us has been the most successful and
not too many people can say that yeah in
this industry so it's being around the
right people that have the right
direction yeah you know yeah I mean we
plan for the future and prepare for the
worst for the worst yes but you know we
still are yeah it's it's one of those
things you got to be creative and ready
to Pivot at any moment um but we pivot
with inside our realm just like you do
I'm sure some people want to Pivot from
this thing to this thing to this thing
they're going to do extract then they're
going to be breeders then they're going
to be stay in your lane yeah stay in
your lane and that's the beauty of you
know the times that's you know and we
are in amazing times it is amazing to a
degree you know the fact that cannabis
is legal yes to a degree it might not be
fully legal but we are talking about it
right here which is amazing yeah and the
path towards legalization like Federal
legalization we're we're on the way when
do you think that's going to happen uh
seven or eight years from now would be
my guess wow what do you think I think
four you think four yes well I think
interstate commerce is going to happen I
think baby steps right okay and so we'll
may maybe four maybe five that'd be
great I'm okay with that but I think
baby steps I don't we we have so much
red tape with everything that we do and
we're talking about rescheduling when we
should be talking about descheduling
well we're they didn't really reschedule
it that's a we've had a conversation
about it now there's actual a pathway
that we have to go down before that
actually happens it will happen for sure
it will it's just to where we can put
money in the banks and same thing with
State Commerce I mean Germany just went
wreck and so that's going to be huge for
Europe so all these dominoes have to
start to fall and in the United States
things take a little bit longer but the
fact that we are going schedule three
they're going to be a lot more research
and the fact that they can do research
and studies and that opens up a bunch of
money and I think that's an amazing
thing there's a lot of things I don't
like about the rescheduling I'd prefer
descheduling and I think most of us
would I would say descheduling yeah
but at the same time you have to
understand it's
still about money everything's about
money you know in with politics it's
politics politics and money Guess What
guys this industry makes a lot of money
yep guess what government's going to be
in here for sure you're uh your Silent
Partner Uncle Sam hey you gotta pay for
sure that's one guy you can't mess
around with you know but at the same
time just like Amazon Prime you can
research and develop things and that's a
tax write off guys you know and so those
are the things that we're here to help
educate this industry yeah we're here to
further into a business not just hey I
go to the hydro store learn how to grow
a little bit and then take your packs
back to the hydro store and ask them can
you help me get rid of this those days
are five six years ago they're gone you
know hydro stores we got to get better
you know we have to educate our El to
the commercial level well and the
mediocre weed that was so easy to sell
10 years ago or 15 years ago that's long
gone man it's it's very competitive yeah
so you really need to constantly be
trying to improve what you're doing even
if you're the best yeah it has to be
constant like that has to be in the back
of your mind that I need to make this
product better whether you're making
genetics whether you're growing flower
whether you're making extract it doesn't
matter you have to have that mindset
that my product is good but it could be
better and I think that's so huge across
this whole industry and if you can
really keep that mindset you're going to
do well yeah uh at least you're going to
survive because the guys that were like
I'm just going to keep growing this
mediocre flower and you till the wheels
fall off well the wheels fell off like a
couple years ago yeah and I used to
coach football with the drill sergeant
and his motto was day by day we get
better and better till we can't be beat
Y and that's the truth if you wake up
every single day and try to get better
just like today I was only 15 minutes
late coming here better than the first
time you know but you know every grad
Improvement gradual Improvement just get
better every time you know yeah I've
been getting up early I get up early
that's always good what's your time you
get up 5:30 to well I try to get up at 5
I've been getting up at 5:30 set my
alarm for 5:30 but I've been traveling a
lot yeah so but I still try to maintain
that time even if I go to bed late yeah
it's a regimen yeah yeah it get you on
your p's and q's and then it tells you
those nights that you go to bed late you
should be going to bed earlier you know
your body tells you regret them the next
day but you force yourself to regret
those days yeah it's like when you go
out and you drink too much you know the
next day there's no sleeping in uh
anymore I wish yeah those days are done
I don't get to sleep in but that's okay
I mean there'll be time in my life where
I do get to sleep in if I want to but I
really enjoy waking up early and you
won't it'll be in a regimen you know you
see these old guys that are 80 90 years
old they still wake up at the same time
every morning
get their it's a it's a schedule and if
you have a schedule you actually end up
what living longer yeah well my my
father he's one of those guys he doesn't
sleep a ton he's never slept a lot there
was times in my life where I used to
sleep like four to five hours a night
yeah I did that I can't do that anymore
never um I used to drive a bus and do
that I drove a bus and a hydro store wow
in the very beginning and like city
bus VTA I used to drive the VTA bus from
3:00 in the morning till 11:00 and then
I jumped out and I started doing soil
deliveries wow you know and that's how
everybody knew me the guy in the truck
you know and you know we've grown and I
learned a lot in the last couple years
you know I learn that a team is what you
need this eye can't go that far you know
and so we're building a team that's the
best and it feels it not only feels good
to be part of something so much bigger
than yourself but it's essential
moving forward in this industry it is
you know cuz realistically one grower
they can change any laws at any time
yeah you know but now if we have 200 300
400 500 Growers doing this way and then
they change it also affects the tax
dollars yeah if you group up as a big
enough
entity you have more leverage to where
things don't change on you as fast yeah
you know because it's still about the
almighty dollar it is yeah you
know well yeah and I mean I I like
focusing on quality at the end of the
day but it's still you gotta have pay
your bills you have to if you don't pay
pg&amp; for six months you're not gonna have
your lights on yeah there's no more no I
mean there was a time where you injuring
Co and stuff like that where you could
go without paying your you could go six
months but they don't play around
anymore PG and you know they've taken
some big hits because of problems of
internal problems at PG and problems
with equipment and fires and campfire
dude that my drill sergeant we actually
went up to the campfire victims that
year yeah we took 20 of our kids we
loaded up my truck at the time with
supplies we had a food drive and you
know it's all about helping people that
need help you know the Marines he was a
marine and then he jumped out of the
Marines and went to an army nice so yeah
he ended up being an Army Ranger guy's
badass the first day of practice Yeah
man
I get parents cussing at us left and
right he he believes in team you know we
would have one kid on a gurnie four kids
holding the gurnie and go around the
whole track and then when that guy's
done get off until we're all five of
them are done we don't touch a football
we don't we run run and he
goes all these parents look mad at us
and I'm like they are and he goes give
them a couple weeks as long as nobody
quits give them a couple weeks these
kids walk in military fashion we would
go to Florida and couple years uh
coaching these kids single file lines
two lines everywhere we walked you know
and it all these kids hated us for the
longest time and now they're all about
17 18 years old and they come back to me
and they're like coach Caputo you know
and they come give me big hugs and it's
cool because they understand what hard
work is you know and that's what this
indry is going to take to get to the
next level it's hard work between
everyone as a team you know
right yeah it's it it it's funny because
I feel like hard work skips Generations
sometimes and with technology life has
become easy and all this stuff it has
you know I tell my kids every single day
I don't care what you do in life I don't
just be the best at it right strive for
it you know I understand
that the video games I got one son that
thinks he's a video game expert and I'm
like okay well then join one of those
leagues you know but he won't you know
because he's not the best at it so I
might go back to school and get better
you know right
so well I think that's one of the
beauties of today and being alive in in
this era is that you can kind of keep
Reinventing yourself no problem back a
hundred years ago if you're a cobbler or
if you're a tailor or or whatever your
father did a lot of times but you had to
do but now you can keep Reinventing
yourself if if you want to re I mean I
I've done it a bunch in my life you know
Reinventing myself learning things that
all kind of have tied together to lead
me to where I'm at now which is nice not
everybody does that some people jump
from thing to thing and but food and
cannabis go hand in hand but uh if if
you don't get it right the first time
you can have another career you can have
another career and you can keep trying
uh if you're if you're a hard worker and
you don't enjoy it move on and try
something else there's there's no shame
in that and you're learning new skills
you're just going to hear the word no
more you know when you first start
business you hear the word no a
lot yeah and what happens is you learn
to accept failure and realize that
failure it doesn't end at failure you
just got to get back up and keep trying
uh sports are like that yeah martial
arts are like that I tell my kids
cannabis industry is definitely like
that like I tell my kids the word no you
actually get something out of the word
no yeah when you're told no as a kid you
can't go outside what do you do you
start doing the dishes you do whatever
you can in the house right to get that
to turn to a yes you know and so guess
what the word no isn't that bad when I
first started my company everybody told
me no yeah our friends Royal gold I love
those guys to death I Tred to become a
distributor for them they told me no wow
it took me he said call me back in six
months Michael and I said okay so I set
a date on my phone I called him exactly
six months he goes dude you didn't bug
me you didn't bother me for six months
and you called me on the exact date he
goes now here you go we're going to give
you 50 trucks at this price 50 trucks at
this price 50 trucks at this price love
those guys and then you'll be a
distributor right yeah and we did it the
first year we sold 188 trucks of Royal
gold and then
we lost money doing it but but guess
what we learned a lot from it you know
and we built a great relationship with
those guys and they got one of the best
products on the market you know yeah for
the longest time I thought Michael was
the owner I finally just met Chad in
Vegas for the first time nice yeah yeah
good guys they were just on the podcast
freaking amazing people they're yeah
they're fun guys to be around and uh
they they love the industry they got
their own podcast who was it Rick and
Mike uhhuh Rick and Mike it's the
perfect yeah it's the perfect store the
three of us talking you know you get us
going and yeah it was like a I don't
know how long we filmed for but it was
it flew by like it was it was nothing
you know those guys you know those guys
like talking and they enjoy talking
about cannabis I love it yeah we're out
in Vegas with those guys and had a good
time so yeah good people man yeah really
good people you know then we got
Huckleberry Hill I don't know if you
know those guys I don't but yeah they're
amazing as well the white Thorn Rose is
one of my favorite favorite flowers it's
feel-good weed is it it's feel good like
feel the best you want to feel the best
you've ever felt smoke that stuff
because it just keeps making you feel
better every time you smoke it no way
well give me a nug of that yeah yeah
yeah we got some we'll smoke after the
show Okay cool so yeah I there's this
blue 13 from my friend Dave and then the
white Thorn Rose and they're just see
for the genetic side I stopped after it
went from to train wreck did you like
train wreck back when you were smoken I
did but then we grew too much of it we
didn't like it no more it's super strong
yes yeah everything that I normally
smoke is pretty much strong I want to
smoke it and then eventually go to bed
you know well when I was 18 teen I would
smoke everything you know we ended up
starting with some good stuff you know
it was $480 an ounce though you know and
you know but that was at 14 you know you
start to learn and grow up and find out
that hey you're not going to continue to
pay $480 for an ounce you know you're
going to find a way not to pay that to
smoke every day yeah you know and that's
just the the side of the hustle you know
and that's what our industry does have
our industry has a ton of hustle we just
need to refine it into a business guys
yeah that's it for sure yeah I mean do
what you're passionate about at the end
of the day just do what you're
passionate about you're going to be
happy you're going to be successful yeah
and it's like what is success is Success
being rich I mean success is defined so
so differently by each person it's so
subjective you know is is money success
is being happy success is there some
point in the middle of those things is
that what success is owning a lot of
[__] some people want to collect this
and collect that and I I was kind of
like that when I was younger a little
bit but uh success to me is happiness I
feel like happiness to be able to do
what you want to do I think that's
success I went through all three of
those in my lifetime so far and I'm
starting to figure out to me success is
when I pass away my funeral will be
full
have enormous amount of people at my
funeral nice you know because that means
it's not easy to go to a funeral
normally people have moved away or
whatnot but if you mean enough to
somebody in someone's life yeah they
come to the funeral you know well unless
you outlive all your
friends that's the tough one I've seen
that W you know it's like that's not
such a bad thing but yeah it's you know
and I've had a couple friends die of
cancer in the last month two days ago my
buddy just found out he died of cancer
and these long battles with cancer it's
kind of wild it's crazy man my uncle had
stage four cancer that he found out this
was about 12 years
ago guy does hardwood floors right they
said hey we got two options you're going
to pass away in two weeks or you can
come up with
$164,000 and take these two shots and
see what happens he's still alive took
the shots or took the shots yeah he's
put those two in him and 164
$4,000,000 for Two Shots yeah but now he
gets to watch his son be on amateur on
the PGA tour and he wish he probably
died now no but you know it costs a lot
of money to help his son right now
medicine shouldn't be like that though
it should not uh it makes me
sad uh I think it's wrong personally and
there's a bunch of that going on all
over and that's to me that's greed yeah
um and I understand people you know I
understand people have to develop drugs
and they cost a lot of money to develop
but that's a tough one
164,000 it's 82,000 a shot I was kind of
I was kind of feeling like that with
this whole covid thing man I thought it
was bad you can't profit off people
dying I don't believe in it you know
like all the people that made the um
shots during covid you know they told
all of us it was free it was not free it
cost us $40 and 20 it cost the
government and it cost the taxpayers $20
to the government or $20 to the
government $20 to the taxpayers which
this the toilet paper
Hustlers those ones piss me off man the
guys that would buy all the toilet
dude what are you doing you you go the
store there's no toilet paper you got to
be kidding me well that happened in our
industry yeah and I was probably at
fault for that I told everybody hey CO's
going to happen you guys better go out
and get your nutrients because it's
going to run out yeah it did and they so
we had people going to the Bay Area
loading up on every single thing that
they possibly could and then driving up
to Sacramento and grabbing whatever else
they could it was a day for the hydro
for the
industry was was an amazing time if you
were in the industry of Co and you
weren't successful you you should be out
of the industry you're probably doing
something wrong yes because it was very
easy to be successful during covid there
was a lot of people with money and they
didn't shut down the dispensaries and
people were excited to smoke people were
excited to be growing uh drinking and
all that good stuff but the hardest
thing was trying to find products for
The Growers yeah like they would switch
anything at any time like if you're used
to using groan I don't care if it's
Calene give it to me and that's how it
went you know it was whatever was out
there I'm going to take every single
thing off this shelf and put it in my
grow room and we'll figure it out later
you know so yeah that was we sprung
sprung board into success through covid
which is now it's time for us to give
back you know yeah
yeah it's always the right time to give
back that's the beauty of it and
honestly since covid it's been a
whirlwind for this whole industry it's
been up down down down now it's starting
to come up a little you know there
there's been hot spots and a lot of cold
spots yeah it's been rough it's been
rough for a lot of people and then the
problem is is during
covid uh on the cultivation side I L I
saw a lot of people expanding expanding
expanding thinking it was going to be
like that for a long time and so then
they either had to get rid of their
second spot that they just built out or
third spot or 100,000 square feet never
got fully built out but they it was a
great idea the concept was good but the
market
changed it does and I think you know
going back to when it's federally legal
that's when the boom will come again I
was thinking four years because
presidency you know yeah it's gonna be a
president that is politics is in in our
industry you know and to get somebody
voted in I think Federal legalization is
going to be on the next ballot not with
the two that are going right now but on
the next one after on the next one after
that we will see yeah so you said seven
to eight years seven to eight years yeah
I'm thinking that we're not ready for it
I mean I'm ready for it I've been ready
for it since 1996 do you think
exportation at that time is going to be
legal as well export Federal exportation
to other countries yeah that's what I
think I can't imagine us missing out on
all this import
export uh you know
opportunity that Canada gets to
experience potentially Mexico will get
to experience before look like they
might get to experience it before us
Columbia gets to experience it now
Germany
Portugal um South Africa all these
countries have import export
so or or at least export yeah and uh I
mean for us to miss out on this
opportunity is silly because dude we
have the best flower we have the best
growers in my opinion yes we can argue
this with some people but I think we
have the best Growers and the best
product in the world we should be able
to export it so now but think about the
liability or the viability of it is
shipping say pounds from here to Europe
they can also grow it in Europe too
though but what thinking is it's going
to be more your business genetics for
sure that's where the springboard is
going to happen I mean genetics can
already be shared through yeah shared
through tissue culture internationally U
phytosanitary export yeah so all that
stuff is already good to go gotcha
especially on the hemp side yeah so it's
yeah I mean we're the genetic stuff is
already done but I think you should be
you can go buy a Hershey bar in Europe
that's from the United States
why you know it's like why yeah
McDonald's is there McDonald's is there
that's way worse for
you I mean in our reality you know it's
like yeah we're talking about what's
healthier and what's better for you you
know there's still people that believe
that cannabis is bad and causes lung
cancer and stuff like that I mean I show
me the money show me the proof so um you
know I was reading this article the
other day that psychosis and younger
younger people if they smoke too much
uh or smoke and and you know maybe
that's true we're learning about it more
but I feel
like cannabis does more good than bad so
as a plant I think it it helps people I
think that for so many conditions it can
be a alternative to something that could
potentially cause cancer or get you sick
or or be a lot worse off for you or
strung out on drugs or strung out on
drugs or yeah I mean pain pills dude
like as a as a substitute for pain pills
I think it's great great and maybe it's
not for everybody for that but the ones
that are they deserve to be able to use
that you should have an option you know
when you force somebody to do something
that's what we're going to do when we
come out with the stores we're going to
have good better best when you force
someone to do something they're going to
revert and do what they want to do right
nobody likes to be forced to do anything
in this world don't tell me what to do
exactly that's the new world you know
cuz it all came from our telling us this
is what you're going to do Mom and Dad
my way are the highway we used should
tell that to my mom all the time Mom
this world is not your world you know
but well so much of this world is
counter in so much of this reality is
counterintuitive that you think it's one
way but really it's the complete
opposite once you have the full
perspective yeah you know it's like you
want your kids to live a easy life and
not to suffer I think a lot of people
you know and I'm not generalizing with
you but just you know a lot of people
don't want their kids to suffer and
unfortunately they give their kids too
easy of a life and that causes suffering
and so it's it has the exact opposite
effect but we're so often
looking at a symptom rather than the
problem so we look at this is like this
is the the problem but no that's just a
symptom of a much bigger problem and it
it's happening all over the place and
most of us just focus on what we can see
and not what took it to bring that issue
to be a problem yeah it's codling yeah
it's coddling coddling because we want
better for our children yeah you know
but at the same time that hard work has
paid off for us you know the Sweat The
Tears sleeping four hours having a bus
job as well as selling soil you know
right those are the things that make you
as a person yeah you know yeah and
they're going to make you appreciate and
the other thing is is like if you don't
experience a hard life and to some
degree not in your whole life but if you
don't experience the opposite you don't
really appreciate the good life it's
just you know the the sour and the sweet
you know if you don't ever experience
the the sour the sweet will never be as
sweet that's crazy I say this all the
time I tell everybody this is my line
you know why we have bad days so we know
what a good day is yeah if you always
have good days you don't know what a bad
day is and and then if something hits
you out of nowhere that it's going to
take you for a tumble you know
hey we're all resilient you know we can
get up we've all been punched you know
stand back up yeah fall down seven get
up eight hey jitu the whole nine
everything that's what this industry is
about business being an owner in a
business you're going to he hear the
word no yeah get used to it and learn
how to take that word no and pivot it
into something you want yeah unless
you're
Jazelle that's aitsu instructor yeah I
mean did you see that uh the roast of
Tom man that was hilarious hilarious uh
yeah you know I like Jiu-Jitsu and yeah
um it was so funny how they roasted him
on his his wife leaving him for a
jiu-jitsu instructor oh yeah they made
it known a couple
times yeah it it was good and yeah I
mean I thought it was hilarious and then
to find out he made $25 million from
Netflix that's what they paid him to do
the roast I mean there's not a l of guys
that wouldn't do the roast for 25
million that's why he's sitting there
smiling thinking about that 25 million
yeah I don't think I would do it if I
was him though man that guy got too much
money Kevin Hart made how much did Kevin
Hart make I have no idea and then you
know Brady lost all that money on
bitcoin so oh did he you know I'm a
Niners fan but I got a lot of respect
for Brady as being the goat you know
it's pretty impressive what he's done as
a
quarterback uh he's he's quite the
character you know what you lose $40
million in crypto I don't honestly don't
follow that yeah so he lost a [__] ton
of money in crypto no way so yeah they
in fact there was a couple jokes about
it on the roast so oh yeah I watched
most of the roast but yeah I'm a diard
Michigan fan so I love Brady yeah I love
the whole story the underdog br's from
the bay area he is Sarah High School
baby they keep beating my son's high
school every year in football right now
those guys are stacked over there yeah
yeah well everyone wants together
probably because of Brady yeah so if you
play football you you'd know they got
like four varsity teams pretty much you
can put together four teams huh easily
amazing yeah yeah the Bay Area is
special I love this place it is you know
and it's some place I move away from and
I end up moving back I always gravitate
I I'm it's like a magnet and besides
having good friends here there's just an
amazing array of good food experiences
to be had um so much I love Seattle too
and I'd love to spend part of my time in
Seattle and same thing with
Barcelona uh you live in Seattle or you
have I've spent a lot of time in Seattle
with my good friends big shout out to
all you guys up there uh yeah I love
Seattle I would definitely spend part of
the Europe in Seattle if I wasn't
focused on this right now so much what
I'm doing with genetics I would be up in
Seattle for a third of the year I love
Seattle especially during the summer yes
Lake Union's amazing uh the food the
people and I just have some really
amazing friends up there that I enjoy
spending time with that I could hang out
with more I lived off the Lake
Washington Boulevard dude that's amazing
I I love yeah I love Seattle only lived
there for about six months my uh Grandpa
was in the uh he was a the president of
the union for Boeing oh nice so he was
up there yeah my father used to work for
Boeing a long time yeah crazy world
small world everybody in Washington
works at Boeing it's weird for sure it's
all you hear up there is Boeing Boeing I
Amazon Microsoft now I haven't been
there for I was man 20 years now it's
been Wow since I've been to Washington
but yeah rains a lot the music scene up
there is nuts yeah the food up there is
fantastic I just every time I go I have
a great time and it's just it's a
beautiful city and especially in the
summer it's like the perfect it's not
too hot it's perfect in summer winter
when it's raining kind of it can suck it
sucks if you're there the whole time
yeah if you're there I I lived up there
for 6 months and I hit most of the rain
it takes a toll on you you know they
have things called happy lights oh yeah
it was like a little light and you turn
it on because it rains so much up there
the high school I went to was all
indoors I was like this is weird you
know CU out here everything's open right
you know the high school I went to is in
California it was wide open but it went
up there is everything was Halls yeah
you know a lot of good salmon up there
fishing up there good good weed too good
weed now for sure I mean I guess they'
had good weed for a long time I just you
know I had family up there um and their
their weed was good but it was it was
few and far between and it's really
since they started really dialing in
where like you harvest it you dry it and
you cure it in under the correct
conditions and then you seal it under
correct conditions yeah I mean house
cultivar those guys crush it can
Organics another brand those guys crush
it um fireline another brand they do
great you know it's like there's some
really good flower up there for sure I
found out real quick that tws in
California were different than tws in
Washington the guy wanted two grams for
a twamp in Washington down here was one
gram you know I went up there I was 16
bought a little quarter I was like you
know I'm going smoke a little get my
money back you know yeah hey man and
this was the guy looked at me like this
is short and I'm like no that's what we
pay for in California he goes yeah but
it's cheaper up here and I was like oh
man well sorry I ended up smoking the
rest of that to for myself so totally
yeah so two grams for 20 bucks two grams
for 20 bucks and then I ended up coming
down California later on and ended up
making a holiday two grams for 30 that
was the going thing so in school yeah
back in the day the weed was real wet up
there it was more SP
that I remember that I we had genetics
we brought genetics up from the bay for
up there so they had Sour Diesel chem
dog Bubba Kush Larry Bubba a lot of good
stuff a lot of good local stuff and I
remember some of the stuff up there the
permafrost senx was up there that was a
pretty popular one they had Alaskan
Thunder [__] that's where I saw that the
first time I think that's what I ended
up driving back up to Washington with
four of my buddies in a S10 truck nice
it was it was more of a trip but we went
up there to go pick up a little QP of to
Washington and we were 16 years old you
know come back down and cuz the prices
was was different from up there to down
here it was cheaper it was a lot cheaper
a lot cheaper I think back then we paid
$700 for a QP wow now or down here it
was probably like ,100 at that time yeah
yeah I remember those it was like that
for a long time 1100 1,000 1100 1200 for
QP we pretty much doing what all the
Growers are doing now driving from hydro
store to hydro store we probably spent
the same amount of money on gas driving
up there you know but it was for the
experience you know for sure so it's a
good drive I just made that drive did
you it's a long drive day did you one
day that's a long day I drove all the
way up in my truck to um Port Orchard
yeah did a delivery eight pallets and
then drove all the way back down and I
made it to little place in Oregon and
just crashed out for about two three
hours and then drove back I've done some
crazy [__] driving yeah I mean I when I
was younger I used to do the Riverside
from Seattle to Riverside so I go stop
in the bay all the way down in one shot
yeah stop in the bay drop my buddy off
drive all the way down to Riverside boom
boom boom drive back to the house which
was another [__] six hours yeah from
Riverside long long days yeah my worst
one ever was was I drove down to I had
like eight pallets of soil on me drove
out to Anza out in the desert out in
down La drove back to a hydro store in
La picked up eight more pallets and
drove back out to Anza and then ended up
driving home all in the same day made a
home 24 hours so wow I would never do
that again never you learn you grow up
and you learn you grow up and you learn
and when you're younger you're
invincible so you're like whatever take
I'm taking on the world I don't care I
probably almost died coming home on the
152 yeah but hey the things you do to
feed your children right well I remember
being in my early 20s and we drive to
Mexico on Friday and home Sunday and get
go back to work on Monday uh you know
those were crazy dude that's like a 10
hour from the house it was like 10 hours
to inata to the hotel to go party for
the weekend and man those were you know
and it's like those a lot of driving 10
hours and you know it's almost a day of
driving to go down for the weekend to go
to Mexico I I can't do that anymore D
can you imagine doing what we used to do
we can't like no that's that's getting
older you know and understanding I maybe
we we just have these mental limitations
maybe we could do those things maybe I
don't I know I don't have any time
anymore like I had a buddy ask me the
other day he goes you don't smoke that
much I said I don't have time yeah and I
and honestly I don't like to forget
things I have a lot on our plate you
know so if I forget something I feel
like I did someone wrong you know so I
really keep keep smoking to nighttime
for now until I can take a little more
workload off me you know yeah it just
depends on the day for me every day is a
little different up in Washington I
smoked a lot going there memorial for
one of my buddies yeah and uh yeah so we
smoked a lot yeah no I from 14 to 22 I
probably smoked every single day but 20
maybe 30 days you know and it was sick
with yeah maybe you know or I couldn't I
didn't have money that day or something
you know but from 14 to 22 smoking every
single day it's hard you know 14 to 22
we had droughts where we couldn't get
weed some days it just wasn't there like
nobody had weed everyone was looking for
it and they don't have that anymore
there's no such thing as a drought or
having it's been over a year since I I
didn't have it's been a lot more than a
year but since I didn't have any weed in
the house it's like I've always got
something to smoke you know could you
imagine having to call four or five
hooks again to get a 20 sack cuz this
guy doesn't have it you know it's like
what we're calling four or five guys to
see the quality now it's not the
availability availability is there you
know now it's quality well and then it's
hard yeah I mean quality is still not
accessible for everybody most people
don't like the stuff that we're able to
get from our mutual friend most people
don't even get to see the stuff on that
quality on a daily you know that's why
it's very easy for me not to smoke cuz I
go to a lot of other facilities and they
try to give me stuff don't get me wrong
wrong it's still good you know but
there's a huge difference between good
and wow night and day and then effect
you know it's like most of his stuff is
has a good effect yeah some of it's
really
strong that the Cherry
guava is that a strong one it's good
it's strong yeah I like it because it it
has a good effect to it okay so yeah
it's strong it burns clean it tastes
gray burns down to the roads but yeah
it's it's got It's it's pretty potent
yeah yeah the one before the um gushers
was uh g41 I don't know if there was a
cross with it or not but that was the
last one that I smoked and they said a
cut came from you and I was like oh wow
you know but see what you're doing with
upping the genetics game and it's
actually helping the flower at the end
you know so that's kind of what we're
trying to build in this whole Community
yeah is a to z right we want Builders we
want advisers we want genetics we want
Growers hydro stores everybody together
as a unit yeah and that's where we could
see ourselves furthering this industry
because without you going and having
conversations with another genetics guy
James yeah you might not learn something
for sure you know well we always got to
learn it's constantly evolving and the
more we communicate with each other the
more education that comes out you know
and that's what I see the hydro stores
going back to being eventually is like a
Transportation Hub for Education yeah no
more packs guys you know education a
grower is going to come into there and
he's gonna say something now you can be
the person that transfers it to another
grower you know I kind of see the future
you in my weird way but going into the
grow shop they have the big screen like
in Back to the Future when he went into
the library and it was like was it back
to the future I can't remember it was
one of those movies where they went in
the
library anyway I could imagine going in
a grow shop where they have the AI and
it's fully trained in whatever questions
you have and it can answer the questions
it's gonna be there yeah I we're not too
far off yeah I think the whole reason
why we're paying fast food people $20 an
hour is because they're going to be
taking our order pretty soon yeah you
know yeah AI is wild computers are you
know really evolved and it's only just
going to keep getting more crazy
genetics breeding with AI is the future
for sure cuz I went to a vertically
integrated in San Francisco it's a
produce
facility no one's allowed inside of it
but robots wow and it's it it it opened
up my eyes if you know to a whole
another level our industry isn't just
going to be cannabis it's going to be
the traditional side all coming together
we use the same products yeah that's why
I see some of these stores turning into
like igc's independent garden centers
why not I grow tomatoes with age old and
Royal gold you see what I'm saying I I I
have a I have a a crop of uh corn yeah
from Royal gold and it was the best
tasting corn that we've ever had my
daughter has a picture she was like four
years old we geek out in a garden
together me and my daughter you know
yeah I use vital I use Royal gold and
for for vegetables like for sure and a
they get age old too
yeah it's going it's going to kind of
cross path and it's okay look at like
BFG they came into our industry they're
a traditional distributor now they're
coming into the hydro sector and now
they're merging with Hawthorne you know
all this is showing you the writings on
the wall guys this industry is coming
together and instead of it being a
billion dollar industry it's going to be
a trillion dollar industry well that's
only because the dollar is getting
devalued so much yes I
agree but that's what inflation is
correct it's not
that the money's worth less as the
dollar is going down the product's still
worth the same it's just valued
differently yep so if you had one advice
for your younger self that was first
coming into the industry what would that
piece of advice be not believe in myself
but
more understand you
have a key to a huge Co-op
and listen more to what the people
around you are saying you know for a
long time I was running the business by
myself so I was kind of narrow minded
and just driven on what my task was
because I couldn't really look outside
the box I had I first company that I
really started dealing with in this
industry was crop protection services
they they now changed their name to act
nutrient but this guy Mike Johnson
coolest guy in the world man he came in
and he said how much is this Cal Mag and
it was one gallon and I I don't know
know it was 25 30 bucks he goes I can
get you 55
pounds of dry fertilizer that can make
thousands and thousands of gallons for
the same price you know so I ended up
going to all the hydro stores and I said
hey guys look it dry fertilizer and this
is 2013 yeah and everybody said no
nobody's ever going to come back we're
not going to be able to make any money
now you know but now I turn to them and
I look at them all and I'm like how much
money are you guys making off these
products now a couple dollars yeah
everyone's going to Salt so just believe
and trust in the circle around you
there's educated people around you and
stay open-minded to all aspects of their
kind of critiques you know nice yeah so
who was the first salt company that had
salt nutrients I know there so G had
Flora Pro
and then but even think uh over in
Europe I think uh was it front row front
row EG had one they had one too but I
think F they they came for veg Bloom
right so V Bloom yes I'm sorry ve Bloom
might be the first first but uh you know
Aran and Greenhouse they've got their
Greenhouse feeding I believe Greenhouse
feeding was the first but I mean the
concept is great it's like it's so silly
that we mix these powder nutrients with
water and then they have this [__]
crazy footprint and the the carbon
Footprints way bigger when you add water
than if you ship powder and you can kind
of ship that anywhere of the world yeah
and the concept's beenin around we we
had some po powder additives and stuff
like that but you know it's it's funny
it took us so long to go all the way
back to the beginning because it you
know that's where it started and now
it's amazing with these buffers and all
these other things where you could just
use I mean I've used some one part stuff
that you know mediocre results there's
an array way of things that we're trying
right now it's going to evolve and the
people in the aide have been doing this
for years it's picking some of their
brain getting away from the name brands
that we're so stuck on well there's the
Cannabis tax right so if you look at the
a products that are the exact same
products sometimes they are 4X of what
they cost in the a world uh and that
just goes across the board and that's
what we're doing with our nutrient lines
we're taking out the margins if you look
at the a industry there's only a couple
nutrients out there yeah and they're the
ones that understand we're not selling
Secrets no more guys we're selling
convenience we have to allow these
strawberry Growers to do what grow
strawberries and put it on the table you
know that's the same thing as our
industry now you know it's it's evolving
to where we're not selling Secrets no
more guys these liquid fertilizers these
other name brand fertilizers you can get
them for a lot cheaper at your egg place
you know it's reality well and cannabis
Farmers the the glory and all this stuff
it's like they're becoming tomato farmer
yes they're becoming strawberry Farmers
they're being they're be they're going
to become part of the the egg model to a
degree you know wineries wineries Cut
Flower business has gone out of business
for the dude that's where all the greenh
houses came from is cut flowers I've
been walking so many green houses trying
to get all the rickety ones are from cut
flowers cut FL man there's one up here
in Half Moon Bay but it has a Aqua Duck
and they grow butter lettuce and they
sell it to the Ritz Carlton so I was
really intrigued by that because that's
where I see our business going we are a
couple steps ahead of the a side when it
comes to cultivating inside you know
outside no they still have the upper
hand on us you know so it's just how to
take out the margins in this industry
streamline it to where you you can have
a really reliable product at an
effective price that's what we're
looking for totally well you know the
double Stacks they came from lettuce GRS
yes and now there's like triple I've
seen triple Stacks at mango
spot and I just that's a long that you
got to go way up to it's a little it's
not safe can it's not safe it's not safe
you know but everyone's got their own
way of doing it there's there's no two
ways to I mean there's so many different
ways to skin a cat what do you think the
timal
price per
pound best quality product where is that
going to come from your opinion I think
there's still going to be the boutique
product that sells for top dollar that's
not produced there's going to be the
either limited market or the false
limited market on it that they control
the amount of product that goes out so
it's very limited and it just sells like
crazy uh which is like the DOA stuff
right now yeah you know deep east the
stuff that they're pushing it's like
that it's very limited and I think
that'll still fetch a high dollar no
matter what whe you know especially you
know wreck where it's top quality
product but if it takes $300 to produce
a pound which I don't see that changing
much unless the dollar goes down more
which it will but yeah but uh if we're
looking at it from that perspective you
know take take cost 300 how much do you
need to stay profitable before you go
that business you know and so where's
that where's that line especially with
taxation yeah and everything else so I
don't know I think substitute Lighting
in a
greenhouse I couldn't agree more mixed
light is the best I think it's the
future you know I think I talked about
it on my last podcast but I think that
mixed light is the future I think you
can get a amazing quality product and
for for a lower cost yeah and you're
using the Sun and so you're getting the
the lights's amazing there's drawbacks
on both sides but I see
the large scale going that way
eventually I've been walking Farms all
through Selena Watsonville Half Moon Bay
and I've got a better understanding you
know there's some really high quality
glass house projects out there dude you
know what those cost per square foot to
build it's crazy the venos like the
Dutch green houses are it could be more
expensive and a lot of times is more
expensive than an indoor facility
buildup but you're going to save money
in the long run on power you are and a
power is a lot cheaper than commercial
power in the city yeah if you got an
extra 10 million or 15 to throw at it
it's no problem you but guess that's
where corporations going to go so that's
where us coming together as a team and
figuring out how do we get a sop at $200
a pound that's where communication and
challenging each other yeah to get
better right that's where we have to go
or guess what you might as well just
sign over the keys to corporate
you know and let them take it but we're
resilient we're Fighters and we're not
going to turn it over that easy I
promise you not my group no I guarantee
you no and those glass green houses are
pretty cool you can tint them with they
they have like uh the the planes that
that spray you can have them spray your
your tint on there yes the different
seasons they have different sprays and
stuff like that it's really cool and
they have misters that go back and forth
oh man there's some really cool things
so that's what I'm trying to get a
couple guys from our group into a couple
facilities like that yeah and they
there's one down there it has 70,000
square ft has 1300 lights in it to see
the difference right see the what your
Roi is figure out what's a better
situation for you financially because
everybody might want these boutiques but
one day it might not fetch that dollar
anymore there there will there's always
going to be Boutique but there will
always also be the middle range and
that's where the race of the bottom
occurs yeah so you either want I mean if
you're a small boutique company you got
to stay small boutique you can't because
you'll never compete on Price ever ever
you know it's like these guys will be
able to produce stuff for 200 and
they'll be able to sell it for 400 500
yeah I mean they'll be able to put out
you know $ five a decent quality if they
want to buy them at 7-Eleven dude you
think that's the future 7-Eleven I do
the face recognition and the screen
where you just put it in there and it's
a dispenser that or delivers no I think
drone deliver is definitely going to
happen there's there you're going to see
it on normal shelves eventually like
drone delivery probably already is
happening I just don't know about it
it's probably going to be like vending
machine yeah to an extent like you're
saying that a 7-Eleven you know but now
how long can you really gauge the shelf
life inside that vending machine now
dude once they dial it in it's
refrigerated inside there then it mon
later you see that's ution of this
industry but I'm looking forward to the
day where they don't even get like the
consumer doesn't even necessarily want
to see the weed they don't care they
want to get that pre-roll that burns
amazing and so then you can give them
the stuff that necessarily right now it
wouldn't fit the bill because they they
have to see the product but if it was
put in a pre-roll and they smoked it
they'd be like this is the best thing
ever so or the rosin you know I mean we
already have that with rosin but I feel
like with pre-rolls and we're getting
there but it takes it takes consumer
trust that's what I was just going to
tell you you know how you gain that
which would be a great idea let them
know what substrate you're using right
on those pre-rolls because a lot of
people think a pre-roll back in the day
when cannabis places or dispensaries
just open they used all the BS for the
pre-rolls you know and it was like
nobody wanted to smoke that you know but
if you
can detail a map for them to where they
can actually trust the source where it
came from what the plant is what
nutrients were used in it yeah I think
think that's the education level on
which people will actually really enjoy
well and I think if you want to know
about my stuff I think the information
is mostly there and even more so the
stuff that we're working on like with
grodan and and Char cor and some of
these other brands um we do publicize it
we do share with everybody what we're
using what we're doing to create the
genetics if we're using a tissue culture
plant or if we're not using a tissue
culture plant we stated you know in the
future we will be doing everything with
tissue culture as far as genetics M it's
just going to be the standard that
everything's clean and uh Optimal Health
when we're breeding with it I'm Gonna
Get You On Kaya too nice you got to try
the Kaya I'm down I'm down there's
nothing I won't try to see if it
improves what I do correct there's a
couple things but for the most part it's
it I'm always down to try stuff and I'm
always looking to improve and I I feel
like you have to get rid of your ego
when you're looking at stuff and
sometimes the guys with the ego are the
ones that have good products and
sometimes it's the quiet guys and so
corre I'm okay working with the big guys
and with the little guys but I want the
best product I can possibly get you know
and we're trying to United right now and
you know we'll see how that goes and I'm
excited you know I'll be able to share
the results with everybody online so and
and I'm one of those guys that if I
don't like it I don't talk bad about it
yeah because I try so much stuff I I
don't want to be the guy that like hates
on a lot of products um I like a lot of
products and and I think they have value
and and they have value maybe not value
for me right now but I could see the
value for this person or this person or
that person and so and there there's so
many things to try there is it's just
like everyone's environment's different
yeah and and exactly everybody's room is
completely not completely different but
substantially different enough to where
you could be right next door to somebody
else they could have the same nutrients
and get completely different results
100% agreed I see that all the time
actually do you yeah see I don't go into
many Gardens I'm still stuck behind the
desk working on the phone all day long
you know networking sourcing taking care
of the stores you know right so I'm
still in touch with those guys all day
every day and eventually it's G to I'm
going to use those stores to then expand
it to where then they're talking to
other stores you know cuz it's Evolution
you got to grow and get better and get
to manufacturers so we can leverage down
the price to get the price a little
lower to keep the grower growing that's
what the manufacturers are missing is if
the Growers stop growing they're out of
business too right you know so let's
help each other We're All in This
Together We Are it's a community it's a
team and if people can see the word team
you know and fight for that that's the
objection that will make it in the long
run you know well if people are looking
to find out more about you United or
Tera International where would they go
go to your local Hydro Store ask about
Tera International they can reach out to
us and we'll make sure that they get
them their products you can also get us
on Instagram it's Tera
DOL good stuff man thank you so much for
coming on the show look forward to uh
hanging out and uh yeah thank you very
much thank you James I appreciate it
keep doing your God's work love it I
love it I love this stuff this is great
[Music]
n