[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James loud
podcast and today my special guest is
Andrew D'Angelo how are you doing today
Andrew I'm great James thanks for having
me in your beautiful Studio thank you so
much for coming so Andrew you have a
long history with cannabis yep you and
your brother Steve founded a bunch of
projects and Ventures like
Harborside and but you go back into uh
cannabis even further than that I would
assume and also I I've read some stuff
about you acting years ago yes so I'm
proud to say 2023 is my 40th anniversary
in the Cannabis trade I started in high
school so in those days we were
underground man everything was
underground and so my brother and I
started working that market and did it
pretty well in our hometown Washington
DC and um my brother had an old friend
out in San Francisco named Dennis Peron
and Dennis Peron was working to legalize
medical out here first in the city of
San Francisco in '92 and then Statewide
in 96 yeah so in those days you're
listeners might not know but there was a
little split in the Cannabis movement
some of us split it over into Industrial
Hemp because Jack Herr's book had just
been published and and we're like oh wow
we can make all this stuff out of hemp
let's start hemp company so me and
brother started a hemp company and then
cats like Dennis Peron was like no no
it's medicine let's start let's start
the medical cannabis Revolution it turns
out Dennis was
right and we were wrong um uh but
eventually you know because we had a
robust wholesale business underground we
were able to send Dennis a bunch of
money for those initiatives you
mentioned me being an actor I was in
acting school here in San Francisco um
when those initiatives were happening
early 90s and I would buy and sell
cannabis to Dennis because he was
basically the only dispensary in the
world at that point and he had opened up
different storefronts and
different I remember the one of the
first ones was above the transfer bar on
Market Market Street um and it was a
little gay bar right right there at the
mun stop right in front of the Safeway
there and above there was like this
space and Dennis rent at that space and
you could fit I don't know 50 or 100
people in there and it was always packed
wow um and you know they would buzz you
in in those days you get buzzed in uh uh
to the dispensaries and you know and
everybody Dennis my brother and I
everybody a lot of people in the
movement I can't say everybody but a lot
of people in the movement wanted to get
legal we were tired of getting busted
Dennis had gotten badly busted my
brother gotten busted I got I had not
yet gotten busted busted at that point
but I have of course a couple arrests in
my in my career too and we didn't like
hiding from the world we didn't like
being criminals we didn't like getting
chased by cops um and it was a really
hard way to live so once we
legalized uh in California my brother
and I did the same thing in our hometown
in Washington DC two years later
1998 uh the federal government would not
allow us to implement that law the the
the the way the District of Columbia
works the federal government funds the
District of Columbia so they would not
appropriate the funds to implement the
program well and then a year or two
after that my brother got busted really
badly and you know we knew it was time
that we had to leave our hometown and
come out to
California um my acting career was going
pretty good in the 90s um but there came
a split in the road for me you know
there was no way that I could acting's a
full more than a full-time job
right you know and cannabis is more than
a full-time job they're both Lifestyles
and they're just brutally hard
professions that require you know 18
hour days being on all the time and and
so I I I realized I was also getting you
know Hollywood's a very young town I
mean once you get approaching 30 if you
haven't made it yet you know you have to
start thinking about different ways to
be a Storyteller maybe um and so and you
know we had had this bus and my parents
were elderly I had to take care of my
family that was that was the most
important thing
so then we started Harborside in' 06 you
know that was a medical dispensary I'm
sure we'll talk a little bit more about
that yeah and um and in those days there
were no Labs there were no investment
groups there were no packaging
companies so we started all those as
well the ark View group Steep Hill Labs
canaline packaging um to try to create
infrastructure for the industry to use
in those days the city of Oakland and
most places in the state were barely
licensing retail they certainly weren't
licensing Growers and breeders and you
know those folks were still getting
busted you know by the state by the Feds
all over the place and um so we wanted
to build that infrastructure we knew the
day was going to come where lab testing
of a cannabis was going to have to
happen just to make things copesthetic
with the general public for a while
well we knew that elected official of
politicians were going to need that so
we wanted to Pioneer these things same
thing with the child resistant packaging
right and you know Harborside and other
of those first movers that did well we
didn't have any couldn't raise any money
it was a nonprofit model during the
medical and you know you go to investor
and like
nonprofit and they're like
bye-bye we've got other places to put
our money but um but I like the
nonprofit model because it really served
our community well right Growers and
breeders and Traders and Transporters
and manufacturers I mean we had most of
the products on Harborside shelf in
those early years came from very small
businesses people that were making stuff
in their kitchen people very Boutique
very craft and it was high quality stuff
I mean we didn't put anything on on our
if you didn't you know lot 90% of what
came in the purchasing door got rejected
yeah um but we would also give feedback
to folks so they can improve and get
better because you know when you tell
somebody no they get a little upset um
and so to say hey we think if you did
this that or the other you could improve
your products to to the point where we
could feel good about buying them we'd
even go to people's Farms you know and
and give them pointers we had some
brilliant brilliant subject matter
experts that we hired that that ran that
whole department and and so that was
harbor side and then you know the adult
use framework came along long time after
that right and that framework of course
is much different so had a big impact on
everybody in California so back in the
early days of Harbor Side you guys had
like the boutique Walmart of cannabis it
was it was a wild experience and you
guys also put a lot of money back into
the community you guys had massages and
you had other things that you know a lot
of places didn't have
free massages free uh you know and free
education you know you guys were
educating people for free but the
quality of the products I mean you guys
had really good quality flour right from
the G I can remember the sage and sour
that you guys had was the best sage and
sour I've ever seen yeah you know came
from a dispensary so and I I think a lot
of people think of it the opposite now
where the craft stuff is all it's true
it's the opposite now CU all those folks
had to go underground yeah um because
they couldn't comply with the 64
framework some a lot of people tried to
comply yeah and failed and then they
went back underground a lot of people
you and I know this man they got one
foot in both markets and that's how
they've managed to survive this
framework which is really broken in
California you know it's a really sad
thing that we have this tragic man
tragic well it's like the whole Let's uh
reschedule instead of deschedule that's
the whole you know it's unbelievable
that we're even having this conversation
yeah it really is I mean descheduling is
the obvious choice for anybody on the
policy Spectrum unless you're just a
hardcore prohibitionist right right and
um the the science is there the studies
are there yeah there's proof yeah
there's all kinds of proof you hear the
elected officials especially at the
national lever say oh we got to study it
more we haven't studied it are you
kidding me what's been studied more than
cannabis in the whole world I mean I can
think of very few things that have been
studied more than cannabis maybe
petroleum um or mining or something um
but it's been a very difficult Road and
and a lot of people couldn't make it um
and and and folks are not going to just
let their businesses die right if
they're able to they're going to play in
both markets and a lot of people are
doing that in in in California right now
yeah and people are going to do whatever
it takes to survive at the end of the
day yep yep so so don't get too famous
don't come on James show if you're doing
that right totally all eyes on the
show but yeah it's it's really
interesting the the uphill battle from
the
beginning from from the early days to
where it is today and it's changed a lot
it still has a long way to go y long
long way to go and it's really
interesting because I feel like the
general consensus if you ask people all
over the United States is more than 50%
are okay with it so I think we're at 65%
for adult and 95 for medical in the
polls right now well it's hard to argue
the medical that that's the biggest
thing is like I don't get that 5% are
just bad people that they don't want
people healthy well yes and they're they
they have a lot of stigma and they they
still feel that get the getting high
part is more harmful than the medicinal
part yeah and so that's they're just
super conservative people and you know
we I don't know man the mainstream
population of the United States is
pretty conservative yeah so you know we
have to do a good job policing ourselves
um and and whether it
be how we brand our products you know
make sure that they're they're not
appealing to kids or they're not
knocking off other mainstream products
that are in the marketplace okay that's
a recipe for disaster for everybody um
and because there's all kinds of ways to
tell our stories and you know our
stories are amazing they're phenomenal
stories very few
people live the kind of life we do okay
very few people take the kind of risk we
do very few people have the adventures
we do the experiences absolutely the
experiences right and so it it's a very
rich life to live and
and but we that are in that bubble we
have to be mindful that it is a bubble
and the folks outside of it have a lot
of concerns man I've been all over this
country building dispensaries and grows
and other things and the local people
really H still have a hard time with
this okay in most places um and it seems
absurd to us because it feels like we've
just been educating and educating and
educating for years and years and years
um but we just have to stay on that and
and make sure that we're not just
policing ourselves but providing good
solid
information cuz I I don't know how you
feel about it James but the consumer
seems very confused to me right now I
agree I mean it's the markets aren't
stable you know for one thing California
especially you know me being from
California but also I work in Washington
and I go to Colorado quite often and
those markets a little more mature than
California there's a trust with Brands
more so and I feel like we need to get
that trust as Californians we need to
get that trust with our consumers you
know and I think running it like a real
business is one thing but also having
good quality product so they can have a
reliable source they can go to I mean I
think those things are huge but also
just running these things like real
businesses you know I mean that's that's
what's going to make the difference
right you know professionalism goes a
very long way and just being excellent
you know is you know when I look at your
facility here it it's been you've cared
for it you've put a lot of effort into
making it look and feel and be excellent
and as long as we do that we're going to
be okay because the the the Baseline in
the mainstream Society is not excellent
I mean look around so um you know you
can count on a few hands you know
amazing experiences Apple Stores or
perhaps one of them right amazing they
didn't have to do that they're Apple to
sell it yeah you know but they did it
they spent you know tens of millions of
dollars on the Apple Stores um I'm lucky
enough to have one of their leaders who
did that in my cons in Co-op but um but
you know if we can create experiences
that allow people to say wow wow wow and
then when they get home and they hit the
weed or they take the edible or whatever
it is that pre-roll and it tastes
amazing and it gives you a great effect
wow you know I love the pre-roll so
that's that's just my thing is I love
the pre-roll because you're not looking
at the flower you're looking at it from
a taste perspective and you're looking
at it from an effect yes right and so
you can get rid of the hype to a lot of
the degree it doesn't have to look like
this amazing thing it could be the
ugliest butt in the world but if it
tastes great if it gives you a good
effect that's really what counts at the
end of the day so and it's about the
experience we start talking about
experiences and I love that because I
feel like cannabis is such a great
experience but anymore you used to be
able to get by by giving people a
mediocre experience with cannabis it had
to get people High pretty much and if
you grew stuff that got people high you
were okay now you have to have the best
[ __ ] of if you want to survive you have
to have some of the best cannabis you
know and it doesn't matter whether
you're black market or White Market if
you're in wck you have to grow the best
stuff because the price is so much lower
that to be in that upper echelon you you
got to grow quality yeah there's always
room at the top there's always for
everything and there's that 1% rule as
long as you fit into that 1% you're
going to be okay and that almost
transcends everything yeah I I I
couldn't agree more that's what I work
really hard with my clients on is let's
get to that l level it was going to take
more time to get to that level it's
probably going to take more resources to
get to that level but when you get to
that level when headwinds occur in the
market because the supply chains are
fragile yeah uh and they're being you
know you're building them while you're
flying the airplane right and so
sometimes airplanes crash when you're
building them flying them at the same
time and and so those Market headwinds
if you're at that top 1% and people just
are loyal to your product yeah they
might buy a little less of it during
hard Economic Times and you know
supplement their purchase with something
that's more value centered but they will
not abandon you ever right because one
of the
things I've learned being a stoner I'm
sure you've learned it too we always
want to put the best cannabis in our
bodies that we possibly can we will
search long and far uh to get to get
something that really pops right and um
so that's what and when more and more
people become cannabis enthusiasts that
same Dynamic is going to happen right
they're going to want something that
really pops eventually right eventually
once you get on that spectrum and you be
go from Cannabis curious to full-on
Stoner right then you then you're like
okay um let's let's see what what what I
can do with this a little bit more on
the quality scale right well it's just
like with everything I feel like data
points as as you've experienced it more
the more times you've tried cannabis or
food you really learn more about
yourself and what you like and what you
don't like and so that's kind of what's
going on in California in my mind it's
like they go on Instagram or social
media and they see these Brands and
they're like oh yeah that must be good
because it's Snoop dogs or whatever and
you know I'm not saying anything bad
about Snoop dogs brand but I think
people are attracted to hip-hop or to
things that they can relate to so they
associate well maybe that's good but
really you you need to try several
different things figure out what's right
for you what kind of experience you want
to have all those things yeah why
wouldn't you have fun with that I mean
certainly try the celebrity Brands see
see what you think if they don't meet
your expectation you should let them
know yeah right um because all these
celebrity brands are licensing deals
basically um the the celebrity is not in
the garden snoop's not actually trimming
this week you know he's probably smoking
it though I should hope so I hope he's
smoking it um and even if to say go back
to the drawing board this doesn't
deserve to have my name on it yeah which
may happen I hope happens um for sure
but um but check out the craft Growers
check out the craft cannabis um because
one it's a community that deserves
support right and is worthy of abundance
they they Carri this plant through thick
and thin for 100 years and we have to
honor and respect that and plus they
grow great weed I mean they create great
products and it doesn't have a bunch of
fancy flashy marketing sometimes it may
not have an instore display they might
not be able to buy a shelf right but dig
around a little bit because it's not
hard to find um these products and you
can get now there's Sun and Earth
certified products that David Broner has
that program and and and that that goes
beyond Organics right so if you really
want clean cannabis check out Sun and
Earth certified cannabis right so we're
starting to get our act together in
terms of providing differentiation in
the marketplace between craft and
celebrity and also bigger companies
scaled companies like glass house or
something like that well and then we go
into terroir yes and that excites me too
you know it's like because I see what's
been done in the wine industry and I
think cannabis we've talked about it for
years but really it's gonna it's gonna
happen where you're going to be able to
go and I would love to see that as a
vertically integrated model where you
can go to the farm you can talk to the
guy who grew it you can hear about his
you know his parents who maybe grew it
or whatever and he can tell you the
story of why it's grown and why it
tastes like it tastes and yeah how it
feels and I mean I think that's just
such a beautiful thing that you know
this is like the Legacy that these
people will be leaving to their children
potentially and also a legacy for the
you know the Giants that came before us
in the industry yes and we're starting
to see the folks up in Humble Mendo in
that Community diversify themselves so
you're starting to see glamping models
on farms now where they where you can go
glamp and cut weed and consume weed and
be with weed and being a beautiful place
doesn't get much more beautiful than
humble or Mendo in the whole world so
we're starting to see that I think the
hospitality models are going to be big
and and and just like wineries right
wineries they have two ways that they
have three basic revenue streams one is
they sell wine in bulk to Distributors
right the alcohol industry has this
three- tiered system right you're either
a producer you're a distributor or
you're a retailer you can't be you can
only be one of those things unless
you're a producer you can sell direct at
your Winery to Consumers so that's the
second yeah um Revenue stream they have
and then the third Revenue stream is um
just you know all the extras that come
with the EXP experience of The Tasting
Room or you know some places do tours
some places do the glamping some places
um and and it's really some places have
a little food a little bit snacks you
know and so I think what we've seen with
wine tasting is an excellent model for
and terar I mean I'm a big fan of Swami
select Swami select is you know and he
grows in Mendo he's in Mendo and he
grows in the terar he actually puts his
plants in the ground they're not on a
they're not in a pot with bunch of soil
he brings from the outside totally he
regenerates that land he puts this you
know the melum in there and he just
creates the soil and then he it's right
there and that's the Appalachian and
they're close in Mendo and humble to
getting that done they've been working
on it for a few years now there's a lot
of constraints and issues with with that
program totally but it is a lot further
along now than it was three or four
years ago when people were first
starting to talk about it and you know
one of the constraints is a lot of that
land up
there wouldn't pass the lab tests if you
put Plants directly into the land
because it's a little bit dirty or it
has heavy metals in it or it's been
farmed or it's been loged or it's been
whatever right um so there's some work
that needs to be done to remediate that
um um because the Appalachian for me the
Appalachian thing doesn't work unless
you're planting in the actual ground and
soil of the of the region um and but
they've done a great job I mean there's
all these tiny little Appalachians
they're all next to each other they've
been named they've been mapped for the
most part right that that took years um
and it's all trying to get the community
again up there the craft producers to
have something that differentiates
themselves right because a big company
like my former company now called state
house or glass house they're all called
house for some reason I don't know why
um um but
they don't grow that way they they can't
grow that way they can't they would
never grow that way and so they'll never
get a Appalachian sure you know
designation on there and and and so if
we if the consumer starts digging this
right just like the wine people Bordeaux
yeah Bordeaux is Bordeaux Bordeaux is
Bordeaux absolutely it can't come from
anywhere else it's got to be C young
Mero and C Frank very strict rules very
strict rules
right it's serve them well okay to have
those strict rules um and so that's how
other Industries and I don't really like
comparing cannabis to alcohol very often
but I I I do see we're in California
we're talking about California the wine
industry is a dominant industry here I
don't know it's got to be top five
Industries in the state um and we have
to find these models you know because
we're building something from scratch
you know never been a 100 years of
Prohibition is a long time you know to
there is no muscle memory there is there
isn't anyone alive who was around you
know um who could go into a drugstore in
San Jose in 1910 and buy a cannabis
tincture there there's just nobody that
that's around that that could do that so
it's up to us really
to Pioneer all of this and and protect
ourselves at the same time I mean one of
the things we've certainly seen is the
colonization of California cannabis in a
big way right so you know that's
something that has been one of the more
painful parts of the adult use framework
for everybody certainly for me and my
family but um but for a lot of people
and um you know it's been hard so
whatever advantages we can get we should
create for ourselves you know right yeah
so let's talk about the last prisoner
project you know I I'm good friends with
uh rich he's been on the show Steve's
been on the show and i' I'd love to get
your history of last prisoner project
and well my brother came to me one day
with a vision like he does with a lot of
things he did it with harbor side he did
it with all kinds of things in our
lives and it was great vision we were
still in the last year or two of our
Harborside Journey but we could see that
things were getting very transactional
in California and kind of effed up um
with everything so we wanted to get back
to Our Roots so we and at Harborside one
of the free programs we had you could
write a letter to a cannabis prisoner
and in exchange for that we'd give you a
free gram of of medicine uh so and you
know one of my earliest memories in the
and with cannabis is visiting my older
brother in prison when I was 9ine years
old uh so so we have this history and
this roots with cannabis prisoners me
and my brother and and as we wanted to
get back to that the the we wanted to do
something that was transcends
transactions and we had people that were
still locked up I mean my brother got
the idea because one of our friends was
locked up in Pennsylvania and called him
from prison in the middle of a big
investor meeting he was having and the
contrast between these investors talking
about you know billions of dollars worth
of weed cultivate it and transport and
sold and Chuck our friend he was I think
it was 16 pounds or something he was in
prison for um so that contrast was like
we got to do something about this and so
last prisoner project is a it started
about five years ago my brother and I
you know he came to me with the vision I
said yes let's do it yeah um and then we
got to work and you know what you need
when you build out an organization like
d you need a great team you need money
right um and you need a really tight
Mission um and you also need ongoing
support right um it's we started lpp
with our own money but that was not
sustainable given what was happening
with Harborside and everything else so
so we thought of different programs to
fund it we put together a team of people
from our Network that we loved and
thought were terrific pretty much all
women right um and and we got to work
and and and it the first year two was
brutally hard we almost had to fold the
organization on more than one occasion
wow
then 420 happened during the pandemic
2020 yeah and we did a fundraiser for
that with weed maps and some other folks
it was Big A lot of people saw it Willie
Nelson we did several fundraisers and we
introduced these programs roll it up for
justice and partners for Freedom roll it
up for justice is dispensaries can sign
up for that program and the change that
customers have 50 cents 20 cents
whatever the change is at the end of the
transaction gets donated to lpp doesn't
cost the dispensary any money right they
sometimes they put a little bucket by
the register and the chains goes in
there sometimes it's digital on the POS
system right um duy is our partner um
with that and they are matching dollar
for dooll or they were I think they
still are um and um that exposure we had
at 420 2020 and announcing those
programs and then our business
development team hit the streets after
that and we started to sign people up um
people we didn't even have to hit the
streets people would call us up and say
how do we get how do we do it you know
so the industry it was one of those
ideas my brother
had that everyone in the whole industry
just said yes yeah this is a good thing
it's easy to get it's easy to relate to
yeah I mean let's get let's get our
people out of prison man we legal come
on now so and there's thousands of
people just in federal lockup I think
it's 3,000 or 2900 something like that
yeah um State lock up a lot more than
that right and it's you know I talked to
a young man who served seven years in
Illinois Illinois is legal yeah well why
why is this guy still in prison makes
doesn't make any sense you know um
you've got some of the biggest msos
based in Illinois based in Chicago and
this guy's sitting in prison you know
for seven eight years um and so it's a
moral call it's a moral shout outout
it's a call to action it's a moral call
to action and I'm proud to say even
during a very difficult moment and I
can't tell you that our donations
haven't gone down a little bit in the
last year but all things considered the
industry's really supported lpp and if
anybody out there wants to you just go
to last prisoner project.org get
involved and you can learn about the
programs um again you can do a letter
writing program just like we had at
Harver side we we've transferred that
program over to
lpp that's a freeway you don't have to
give any money for your listeners who
have never been locked up when you're
locked up especially doing real time
right years in prison letters are a
Lifeline they are a Lifeline okay and
it'll really help people's day because
Prison is something you survive minute
to minute hour to hour hour day to day
week to week it's it's a very hard thing
to survive so um getting a letter from
somebody that's encouraging you and
saying hang in there we're out here
we're fighting for you we're trying to
get you out keep your head up um that is
a Lifeline for people that are locked up
in prison so that's how people can get
involved in that and I'm just grateful
to the Cannabis Community for being so
supportive of of last prison project
yeah really cool
yeah it's amazing what you guys have
done I mean thanks thanks yeah I'm just
I'm blown away and then Richard was one
of them he's one of them yeah and his
stories are great you know I I just he
was the longest serving prisoner I think
that we got out I think it was 36 years
or something over 30 years yeah 32 36
something like that and Michael Thompson
was also a long serving prisoner almost
30 years I think he was 28 or 29 so yeah
doing the Lord's work so the plant
teaches us this for sure know I I I or
at least taught me that yeah the first
time we met was at the Harborside Farms
with with SH Brooks I think maybe Ed
Rosenthal I brought Ed Rosenthal to the
farm to take pictures and I got him so
high I I just got my puff Co oh yeah and
so he's like well can I use it I'm like
sure it fits in the cup holder and so
the whole time Ed's smoking the puff on
the way on the way down there and it's a
good drive man yeah so Ed smoking the
whole time he gets there and he's like
almost Kos you know good old Ed with a
big smile on his face going there to
take photos and yeah and Sh wasn't
really happy with me so at the time but
but yeah we got some good photos in and
uh you guys had a beautiful Farm there
so tell me about Harborside Farms you
know how that got started and then where
it is today h that's a a great
question you know we've always been
traders of cannabis my my brother and I
we weren crowers right and I think it
was 2012 or maybe a couple years after
that the city of San Jose where we had a
very popular shop mhm changed their
framework and they required everyone to
be vertically integrated oh wow they
required everyone to be vertically
integrated so we didn't want to give up
that shop um and we started trying to
figure out how we can become vertically
integrated and it led us to Harborside
Farms what's now called Harborside farms
in the selenis valley at that time there
was not a single cannabis farm in that
entire Valley
and and so again Steve and and and and
and Harborside were pioneering something
in in a place it's too bad we couldn't
buy a bunch of farms around there and
and flipped them to some of the bigger
players that are down there now but um
but we were we were first down there and
um and we had to raise money you know we
had to raise money it's expensive to
grow cannabis in green houses or indoors
well they required you to retrofit if I
remember right it wasn't like you could
do new build outs it had to be
retrofited you couldn't do new build
outs unless yeah you had to get
permission for that and that was really
hard to get and we eventually were able
to build uh Dutch style Veno Greenhouse
there I remember when you guys were
building them they looked awesome what
our investors wanted to do was a little
different than what we wanted to do um
they were very interested in scale um
and we were
more oriented towards craft right um we
thought maybe you know the opportunity
down there was to to be almost more of a
nursery because we didn't need that much
weed for our own shops that you can grow
that's gigantic facility um that was one
area we diverged from our investors a
little bit and you know when we got
shored down there the farm was
struggling you know pretty bad um
unfortunately that little piece of land
is just inside the fog belt down there
and so you have a lot of issues with PM
down there powdery Milo for those that
don't know what PM is and um and we we
struggled with that I mean we struggled
with it for a little while and that's
that was the impetus for getting the ven
L um was you control that a lot better
um so you know the farm like all Farms
the first year or two we struggled um
then it got better um now Harbor Side
Farms you know is now St House State
House is a big company where several
different companies Harborside Urban
Leaf Sublime loud pack all came together
um and formed a bigger even bigger
Company by that time we had left Steve
and I and um and now all those brands
that are within loud pack or sublime or
I think dime bags another one they have
Harborside Farms produces all of that um
uh for those brands and then they put
those brands on the Shelf of their
stores now I think we have 15 stores
throughout the state now and that's what
Harbor Side Farms has become now um and
you know sh's not with us down there
anymore he's he he he definitely turned
things around I mean he was there for a
couple years and um and then he moved on
to other opportunities and yeah he's
doing some preservation work right now
with you know old school genetics and
yeah he I think he's out of place in his
career where he can have more autonomy
of what he wants to do
because he's very good at what he does
as a as a farmer and he gets paid very
well I can tell you that um so I think
he's done well and now he can do what he
wants you know um and good for him man I
love sh short I and his whole crew
they're wonderful people and I know I
feel very grateful and blessed that they
were with us for as long as they were
yeah yeah really good people yeah I'm
friends with all the guys yeah they're
amazing yeah now you guys have started
out well you started in California but
you're also working in New York and all
over the US tell us a little bit about
that okay thank you I appreciate that I
I am a consultant okay so that's how I
make a living lpp last prison project is
a volunteer job um and harbor side
doesn't pay me anymore um so um so
that's how I make a living and you know
I have a passion for building things I
love building yeah I noticed you've just
built something here right and it's
really fun to build things and then to
see them come to life and to see the
ideas and Visions leap off of paper into
reality yeah and then you know it's even
more fun when you're right and you're
like okay we plan that correctly we
don't have to redo anything um we can
just practice our craft right um so so
that's what I love to do I'm I'm I'm
mainly known for dispensary build outs
and Consulting for people to get
dispensaries but I like to be there was
close to the beginning when the
entrepreneur decides to either start up
a dispensary or fix the one they have
yeah I do both of those things um we've
consulted with grow and manufacturers
too I have a co-op model so I've got
folks like that in the co-op um I even
have Industrial Hemp um so I'm I I want
to build a lot of industrial hemp models
that transcend
cannaboids that are food and fiber um
based and hemp creete and things like
that I think there's a big future in
that huge yeah huge yeah I mean we're
going that direction yeah so it's it's
it's just an obvious direction to go and
I mean the cost benefit for one thing is
huge but also it's it's better for the
environment and you know obviously we
love cannabis and we love to plant yeah
so it's definitely better for the
environment and and you know that's kind
of a big deal right now um so I'm I'm
excited about that so so you know
entrepreneurs that want to get a hold of
me for help just reach out to Andrew
DeAngelo decom yeah there's all kinds of
buttons on there that'll get you an
email to me and you know it's it's it's
a it's a real passion I have what I like
about Consulting is unlike harbor side
where I had to build just one thing
right you know I can build like you said
across the country and the world I got
clients in Europe too amazing so you
know it's it's it's no doubt a difficult
year okay for everybody including
Consultants but that's what I love about
it is that you know it gives me an
opportunity to take everything I've done
and just build the industry you know
throughout the country and throughout
the world it's enormously satisfying
when you work on something as a
consultant and the clients not only are
expectations met but expectations are
exceeded and that's when it feels really
good um because I go in and out of jobs
you know I I get hired for three months
six months maybe a year and then the
entrepreneurs run their own businesses
right that's what they love to do and
and so I'm having a real good time with
that and yes trying to build some things
in New York right now it's it's a really
difficult moment in New York they have
all kinds of litigation and Licensing
problems it's wild over there it's sad
to a degree yeah I mean the whole
dispensary model that they've set up
it's you know and they've got all these
um black market shops oh my God hundreds
of them um hundreds and hundreds of them
so which is much different than we you
know that we experienced in California
but well you saw that in La a bit um bit
a bit um uh and we you know I remember
dealing with measure Z clubs measure Z
is this
thing in Oakland where the police have
to treat cannabis as the lowest priority
yeah I was called measure Z and I don't
know it was almost 15 or 20 years ago
that got
passed and so all these measure Z
dispensaries opened yeah and it was hard
because they don't lab test their
medicine they don't do anything with the
packaging they you know and um it was
hard to compete with them and I remember
struggling with that a little bit um um
so it's not as dramatic here in
California
outside of La really um as it has been
in New York but New York's just one of
these places if the city of New York
does not like a vacuum it doesn't matter
what the product is doesn't matter what
it is if there's a vacuum and people can
make money in New York on it they're
going to fill it yeah and The Regulators
just didn't even come close to
understanding that Dynamic and now they
have to enforce and maybe
it'll be a little easier to enforce
against a storefront than a delivery
service or something like that's less
centralized but it's still gonna be hard
man because they go in they red tag it
then they have to come back there's a
hearing then you come back again it it
you know there's like several steps
before you can like shut it down right
um and of course the owners of those
shops are suing of course of course
they're suing um they're like what do
you mean you made it legal um
uh
so it's just such a mess in New York I
thought I thought California was the
poster child for how not to legalize
weed but New York's definitely a run for
the money we should have a flag you know
you know New York and California right
next to each other uh on the flag uh and
you know it's it's easy to joke about it
but these are human beings that are
suffering um at the end of this you know
on the on the on the on the tip of the
spear is somebody who's ass is getting
cut you know
and it's
just you know I work on public policy
it's not something I like to do because
I'm frustrated because nobody listens to
us the elected officials the boards the
they don't listen to us at all I mean I
was in the who who is now the director
of cannabis control in California I was
in her office I don't know 10 years ago
maybe or maybe maybe it a little more
than that like 2018 right when we are to
flip yeah and I whiteboard at her and I
was like I put a big line in the middle
of the Whiteboard and I wrote lab test
on it and I was like and then I put an
arrow pointing below that line and arrow
pointing up below that line you don't
need any
regulation what do you need regulation
for the lab's going to catch any nasties
regulate the labs absolutely okay
regulate the labs we've had a big
problem with that because now uh you
know the labs have been doing some you
know Shady things with pumping up
potency results and shopping their
results around and and there's no
consistency at all there's no protocols
the labs don't have a specific um sop
that they all have to follow you know
right like if there's an outbreak of bad
beef B beef if you tried to lab test
every pound of ground beef that American
consume go broke and you'd starve and
you'd starve okay so they can't do that
there's too much beef going through the
pipeline you cannot spend a day or two
or three lab testing all that beef so
they unless they don't do anything
unless there's an outbreak now once
there's an outbreak then they then they
do
the uh the recall and they they have all
the they know where the beef came from
right they have that in the RS yeah and
so they can trace it all the way back to
the producer and then they lock down
that producer and try to figure out the
problem okay eoli or anything right and
they recall all the product so nobody
gets sick totally um you could do that
with us yeah you could totally do that
with us right um um I think maybe it
takes a little while to get there okay
because there's still it's still such a
money grab right now that people will be
not as honest right um uh but
but if if if if she would have listened
to me more yeah right the framework be
would be much different right and you
know and we would be able to compete and
create one market instead of dual
markets yeah right we almost have three
markets now with the hemp derived uh and
it's like how many
markets can
we have before our knees give up you
know and it just Falls it just collapses
right I mean so my vision is to get all
this into one market the only way to do
that is with good public policy and it's
very hard to do after you've screwed it
up like New York and California yeah
right if California would have just
licensed people that were already in the
supply chain yeah and made it pretty
easy for them and made the lab test more
intense made the lab test the thing
right that you had to work towards um we
would have a lot closer to One Market it
doesn't mean you wouldn't have quote
unquote bad criminal elements growing up
in the forest and selling it back east
or whatever you probably would have that
but law enforcement would be able to be
focused on them right they wouldn't be
worried about Swami they wouldn't be
worried about and the same thing with
The Regulators they would have been
focused on the labs right um so and now
we're working backwards now we have to
fix it and it's hard to do because it
you can't get consensus even from our
own industry it's very fragmented um and
so what I hope for California's and I I
haven't been able to make this happen
but I've been talking about it since
2018 2019 I want I want a new ballot
initiative yeah I want a new ballot
initiative man um because if we would
have had a new ballot initiative in 2020
M when turnout was so high in that
election we would have won we may want
to wait till Gavin Newsome's out of
office after this last debacle yeah
probably yes yeah you're mentioning his
Vos yes of the Psychedelic bill and the
Cannabis Cafe Bill really sad you know
really sad in my especially the the
Cannabis Cafe psychedelics too I mean I
think you know I like psychedelics I
feel like they should be legal I feel
like they do more good than they do bad
yeah and the the cafes are gonna support
small business so how can you go against
something that would support small
business and you know he was being a
politician man you know he's probably
running for higher office and yeah I
think you're right maybe we wait till
he's gone you always have to worry about
some of them worse than him but you know
it I'm with you I I feel very betrayed
by Gavin Newsome um the Cannabis Cafe
Bill the the reason he said cited for
vetoing it didn't make any sense he said
I'm worried about smoke in the workplace
yeah are you kidding me man um
everything's vaporized you know pretty
much even daad bars are vapor okay and
the only way any local person is going
to let you do combustion is if you have
a courtyard yeah right if you have a
courtyard and people are doing
combustion there's no threat and we know
from science that secondhand cannabis
smoke doesn't hurt anybody right okay so
it was a lame excuse um it was a
terrible decision because that will
invigorate the entrepreneurial Spirit
here in California we already have have
all these chefs doing these infused
dinners we already have these tour buses
going around we already have yeah this
Hospitality thing is emerging without
any support from public policy you give
us a Cannabis Cafe bill yeah right and
we can sort of come out of the Shadows
with that whole thing and you know
California is about food okay it's about
food it's about producing food it's
about gourmet food it's about organic
food it's about vegetables it's about
all that and pairing food with cannabis
is as ancient as Humanity I mean it it I
think we ate cannabis as one of the very
early things we ate you know seed right
um um it's super nutritious I mean this
is enough to feed a family for a long
time right you know and cannabis and
food have a great future in California
the guy who ran that bills Hanley is his
name he's a assembly person I think from
San Francisco so he's going to take
another run out at it MH they'll
probably put some stuff in there to
protect workers from smoke which you'll
probably what you always worry about
with these bills is they write it in
such a way that no one can make money
yeah right and so if you write the
Cannabis Cafe bill in such a way that
nobody can make money well No One's
Gonna open a cafe exactly and then you
know the people who don't want to see
this happen we'll be very happy about
that um um and you know they're all up
there lobbying in Sacramento and who
knows what the restaurant Lobby did who
knows what the alcohol Lobby did who
know so much stuff goes and happens
behind closed doors that we don't ever
hear about oh yeah almost it's just how
a lot of it works anywhere but
particularly in Sacramento I mean it is
anywhere and everywhere but yeah
particularly in Sacramento it's so
corrupt it really is I mean you know our
political system is pay to play
unfortunately um uh and I I think a
little that is probably inevitable in a
democracy because money is speech to a
certain degree but but it's out of
control it's gone too far you know with
with with handcuffing everybody in the
supply chain all these entrepreneurs I
mean there's some brilliant wonderful
entrepreneurs you know in California um
that are still trying to make all this
work you know and a lot of us were
looking at that Cannabis Cafe Bill and
and we're like okay if this passes I'm
back in right I'm back in I'm not going
to be a consultant helping people
outside of California build their thing
I'm gonna come home and build my thing
here right um isn't that what we want in
California as Californians don't we
want right now most of the industries
owned by people don't even live in
California yeah or the United States in
some cases in some cases I mean I know I
won't name names but I know of a big
company in California one of the biggest
their CEO commutes from the east coast
to California yeah doesn't even live
here and he's running he's the CEO when
we owned an operated harv side I lived
three blocks down the road from the shop
I mean I I had to be able to get there
like that the alarm goes off whatever I
had to be able get there man and and you
know my style of leading people is to
embed with them yeah it's not like in an
ivory Tower you know sending memo down
um which unfortunately is what what
we've seen a lot of um and I want I want
the California industry to benefit
Californians right um that's it it
doesn't mean we're not going to have
people from outside of California yes
they're here and they're welcome and um
but let's not throw the baby out with
the bath water right okay and I hope
that we can get a little bit better I
mean to his credit Gavin Newsome did
veto that packaging labeling build that
was terrible right absolutely so that
was one good thing and that was a big
effort by the industry you probably
signed the petition I signed the
petition and you know that would have
been a disaster okay because people like
Swami would have had to Rebrand um
totally you know Rebrand his faces on
there you're not allowed to have a face
um um in that bill so we got that done
and you know like with all these things
in California public policy you get like
one quarter of a victory and two defeats
yeah
and then okay next year maybe we'll get
another quarter and and you know you do
the math after 10 years you get a little
farther ahead but it takes 10 years
we're five years into the program now
yeah okay and Gavin news's big line when
we passed it was it's going to take five
years it's gonna take five years to work
all this out well year five year five
year five dude and you know what are you
doing except vetoing bills that'll help
other than the the the labeling bill
which which you know again give credit
where credit is due but right but you
know and here in California you have a
super majority right the Democratic
party is the one to blame now I'm
certainly not a republican um um but I'm
not a Democrat either I'm registered as
an independent um and what they've done
I'm really really angry with the
Democratic party here in California um
because they've really really messed
this up and continue you to and then you
know spike the ball in the end zone
publicly and say we're great and we're
not great yeah you know so well I'm
registered as a republican but I'm very
moderate in My Views and you know my
mother's the same way parents are the
same way they live in Texas okay but uh
I feel like I'm you a Democrat dude I'm
more of an independent I would say I'm
more of an independent than anything now
with the times but it's really sad
what's going on in the world where we
used to just get along and now it's like
well I'm a republican you're a Democrat
and it's it's such a weird thing to me
because I feel like there one party
doesn't have all the answers it's it's
not like that one person doesn't have
all the answers you know we got to pick
and choose what makes sense and and all
these things are subjective to our
experiences the whole debate about you
know the biggest thing that drives me is
abortions I don't even want to talk
about that I feel like it was we we set
this stuff up in the 70s we ended it
there now we're bringing it back up and
it it bothers me you know so that kind
of stuff really bothers me about the
Republican Party well I mean there's
things that bother me about all all both
parties of course I mean but one of the
things I've I'm pretty good at is
working with all kinds of different
people I mean most of my clients are
conservative Republicans right most all
of them are um but we have a great time
together and we build things together
because we keep our eye on the prize
right and the prize is is we're building
a business together right um and you
know and we're taking a lot of risk and
we're spending money and you know those
things are far more important than you
know who I voted for who they voted for
you know or you know what we might feel
about some other issue that's not
cannabis right um the thing about
cannabis that I love is it brings all
kinds of people together yeah um and you
can be
pretty
conservative um and you can be pretty
Progressive and those two people can
share cannabis together and share a
mission and values with their businesses
together and do very well together you
know and it used to be like that you
know it it used to be rude to talk about
politics at the dinner table it used to
be rude to uh tell people who you voted
for yeah those were things my parent
when I was growing up you weren't
supposed to share those things you never
ask somebody who they Ved yeah you never
it was considered very rude to do that
well nowadays you don't even have to ask
somebody you know um and with social
media and everything um it's it's been
Amplified right all this division um and
tribalism and partisanship has really
been Amplified I'm hoping that weed and
psychedelics will get people off of that
and sort of break that Loop um um
because that's that's what did it for me
you know that's what did it for me the
reason I can get along with anybody is
because I learned how to do that from
these plants well you came up with a
concept that I love uh C sober yeah and
and that is just an amazing concept and
you know you want to share a little bit
about Callie sober with everybody
because I think it's such a great thing
well C sober is a term I did not coin
but it is a lifestyle that I practice
Yeah and it's we have an addiction
crisis happening in in the country we
have an opioid epidemic we have over
100,000 people dying every year from
opioids and other hard drugs and
Fentanyl and all the rest of it so C
sober is a version of sobriety that
includes cannabis and psychedelics but
does not generally does not
include alcohol and hard drugs that's a
very broad statement there some people
who will call themselves C sober that
like to drink half a glass of wine every
night or once a week or something they
it's not focused on alcohol right it's
focused on cannabis and psychedelics um
and that's how I've
managed my relationship with
psychoactive substances when you're in
the underground or in this industry or
you're a high-powered exec Silicon
Valley a lot of those folks are addicted
right and a lot of our community has
issues with this because we
self-medicate right because it's a it's
a hard life it's a stressful life and um
people self-medicate and I I I saw this
all through my career you know
and generally when when our community
gets strung out people get busted yeah
they go to prison they bring down other
people with them or their businesses
fail if if they don't get busted because
they they spend all their money on drugs
or alcohol or or they they just can't
maintain right and um whereas Callie
sober is is a lot of folks you go to AA
right the 12 step program and and if you
say that you take we to cope they they
won't allow most AA groups will not
allow you to continue in the group right
and so a lot of people feel alienated by
that you can smoke cigarettes cigarett
weird part they're always copy and you
know these These are also psychoactives
um and there are circles of of sobriety
support groups in the country now I know
of one in it's called the I think it's
called The Sober Stoner but she's out of
Texas and she she gathers people that
are in recovery and they smoke weed
together and they talk about how to stay
sober um and not indulge in the things
that cause them a lot of problems in in
their lives and and so I think it's sort
of a um it's very controversial C sober
because they why why is the word sober
in there um because it it when I talked
to David Crosby right before he died
about six months before he died he's C
sober yeah and he um said I don't like
Cali sober why don't you just call it
cie Stoner um and of course he felt that
people that are really strung out there
there a lot of them need to be sober
sober for a little while while before
they can reintroduce something like
cannabis into their routine and I
respected that Viewpoint you know I I
respect that that viewpoint but I also
know a lot of folks
who take cannabis and psychedelics and
it might be just micro doing
psychedelics sure um and it helps them
stay sober right and and so when I got
turned on to this idea um I started to
write about it in Forbes and a few other
places and I start to talk about it and
get people sort of conversing about this
because AA and 12-step programs have a
terrible not a very good track record I
think it's something like 20 to 40%
success rate yeah that's that's hard um
and if we can increase the success rate
from 40 to 80% because we create a
methodology that includes cannabis and
psychedelics while also keeping an eye
to make sure that those folks don't
start abusing cannabis and psychedelics
right yeah um people can have cannabis
use disorders people can have ketamine
use disorders I've seen it all over the
place right ketamine use disorders kind
of growing right now because people it
have access to it and ketamine is an
easier compound to navigate you know
than psilocybe and so and and and it
does it's a pain reliever and it also
you know gets your mind out of the
default mode Network and into something
that could be a little more positive and
um but people get in trouble with it you
know people get in trouble with it I
know quite a few folks that have gotten
in trouble with it and um and so C sober
is is not something for everybody and
it's and it works really great for a lot
of people my brother me this is how we
we we I we've made it work for our Liv
you know well it's a beautiful thing and
I think my takeaway is that cannabis and
psychedelics they tune you in whereas a
lot of these other drugs tune you out so
yep that's the beauty of it is you get
tuned into the world and so when I think
of sober I think of being tuned into the
world I feel like uh you might have to
face some hard reality and some hard
truths on psychedelics you know about
yourself about other things and they'll
bring things to light that can be scary
and can be these other things but they
tune you in whereas alcohol definitely
numbs you you know and these other
things they numb you from reality
whereas cannabis in in my experience
brings you back into reality well I I
couldn't agree with you more you know
and um and so you know for people that
might want to try Callie sober check it
out read my articles and you know learn
a little bit more about it yeah yeah you
I'd seen some stuff on social media and
I've read a bunch of stuff on it I had
no idea you weren't the one but you've
been a big advocate for it yeah I'm an
advocate the term has been around for a
little while now um uh and there's like
all of these terminologies that we have
and share with each other there's more
than one origin story absolutely who
coined the term but um but you've seen
like Demi Levato and you've seen Willie
Nelson and Billy strings wrote a song
called C sober recently right so it's
starting to sort of be talked about in
pop culture and various different ways
and you know just getting the message
out yeah Billy strings is amazing so
he's played a lot this year 20 2023 has
been a big year for he is a talented
yeah he's just been on the road like you
talented young man a what how old is he
like 28 30 something maybe or 28 yeah
he's super young he's super
young man he can play yeah and I guess
he played guitar with his father growing
up and oh yeah yeah you can tell he's
been with that instrument a long time
yeah for sure and yeah no it's great to
see the young some of the people coming
up these days I he reminds me of Jerry
Garcia in a way because Garcia was very
into Bluegrass and the banjo and stuff
like that and fast picking all that
stuff yeah that's right and Billy's good
at that um so it it it it you know it's
wonderful how the music just keeps going
even when um from generation to
generation
and there's so many talented people in
our country right now it's it's it's
really remarkable so my prediction for
dead and Company is that I I hope Bobby
never retires but if he does I would
love Billy strings to jump in there uh
Billy strings and John Mayer you know
John Mayer has grown on me quite a bit
because I was very anti very anti- John
Mayer in 20 18 yeah and I was like
you've got to be kidding me this is
there 2015 I guess originally yeah but
uh he's grown on me quite a bit and you
know I saw them in San Francisco you
were there at the show too oh yeah in
fact I gave Steve a join at that show
and that's how I connected with Steve to
get him on the podcast with firston yeah
yeah with firston yeah that's great yeah
that was a great show yeah that Saturday
night oh man and Saturday I was a little
Rowdy so I was 20 feet from the stage
and it was a little bit Rowdy and the
band kind of got everyone calm which is
great but yeah good experiences I mean
these life experiences we're just so
blessed to be alive right now and it's
just you know I smile every day getting
up I get to smile every day and I'm
happy and but we just get to experience
these amazing things you know and
there's so many different things that we
all get to experience yeah I haven't
seen the Wolf brothers yet but I think
that's the next thing I want to see
they're amazing yeah I went I went all
uh all the nights when they played in
San Francisco and took different friends
every night and so yeah yeah and and and
Billy I haven't seen Billy and the kids
yet either Billy strings at Red Rocks I
didn't get to go see it but I've seen
the videos and you know they played so
many roads which is one of my favorite
songs yeah uh about Jerry and about
addiction and you know I I totally
relate to that song and you know hearing
Billy strings it wasn't perfect but
Jerry's playing wasn't perfect either it
was just a beautiful thing but look man
the mistakes are part of the sound you
know when you are an
improviser and that's almost the best
part where it's not perfect and Flawless
where it almost falls apart but right
before you think it's going to fall
apart Jerry would pull it back together
somebody would pull it back together
somebody would pull it back together or
it would get yeah I've seen mayor do
that too you know um and yeah I I agree
with you at first I was like oh man um
with John Mayor um but he's really
vibing with the band though and him and
Bobby back and forth and you know and
and everybody yeah and and well and I
think he approached the community and
the opportunity with a lot of respect
and reverence I thought that was really
smart of him he knew it was going to his
participation was he was going to get
hated on for sure he was going to get
hated on for sure but he still does he
just he just kept being respectful and
reverent of you know the Grateful Dead
Legacy and um you know I was sad to hear
that they're going to stop touring but
I'm sure they'll play some special
events well you heard about the the
sphere in Vegas they're going to be
playing the sphere and that's that's
your prediction well I'm pretty sure
that was an an announcement I'm not sure
if they sold tickets for it yet but yeah
oh that's that' be cool that'd be super
cool yeah I mean yeah I just I love
everything I love good music just in
general so at the sphere would work
pretty darn good yeah yeah I saw the
$5,000 tickets but you know I don't know
but I know I know I know the U2 shows
looked pretty spectacular though yeah um
so totally so I they spent like two
billion dollars on that venue it's so
wild yeah looks it's so futuristic I
guess you'll get your money back
eventually eventually but that's a lot
of concerts man yeah to get your money
back next 20 years something like that I
know something something something maybe
maybe sooner I mean selling $5,000
tickets you probably get them back a lot
quicker yes indeed yes indeed with your
career and all the things that you've
done if you were to look back and talk
to yourself yeah the the younger version
of yourself uh that had just been in the
industry for two years what is the one
piece of advice that you would give
yourself keep more of the money I made
that seems to be reoccurring with with
people that I asked but yeah we took
pretty much all of our profits and we
put it back into legalization and
activism and you know we had a
Industrial Hemp company in the N9 I mean
all these different Ventures Ark viiew
canaline all came from basically our own
pocketbooks and um so yes I I I I not
because I'm greedy but because money is
a tool and when you don't have much of
it it's hard to build amazing things
right and it's hard to do amazing things
it's hard to do epic things so um and
you know me and my brother really love
doing epic things and so there's been
quite a few times where we had Vision or
we had idea particularly since the prop
64 happened yeah didn't have the money
man um and couldn't really go get it um
because there's just really very little
money in the ecosystem of cannabis right
now unless
you're a big MSO or Ro it's really hard
to get any kind of investors in um so
it's just a very constrained environment
to raise money in right now um and so
you know if we had kept more of our
own um uh then you know these Peaks and
valleys would be a little easier to
navigate um and I think we we could and
would and will uh just keep building
just keep building the industry and
building you know Steve's pivoted to
psychedelics a little bit he's got RV
retreats in Jamaica and you know that's
an amazing thing that he built you know
and we want to build more stuff like
that you know but we are resource
constrained at the moment um like most
people in the industry so um that's that
that would be what I I would tell my
younger self when you've been on this
journey year 40 for me you've been on
this journey all of us been on this
journey a long time you sacrifice a lot
right there's just a lot of sacrifices
uh that one has to do um either to stay
safe or to stay free or to take care of
the people you love or take care of the
plant and or get people out of prison
these are all things that are super
risky things to do um and require the
only way you make epic things happen
really is with sacrifice you know you
built this facility here and you woke up
every day and came in here and did it
right that's a sacrifice it's G to pay
off for you but it was a sacrifice right
and you do you string enough of those
projects together um and you know you
realize you're carrying a lot of you've
got big backpack of oh yeah you know
sacrifices that you're carrying around
and the
sacrifices they don't cause me a whole
lot of regret James you know
um but when I look at the lives of
people like me and my brother have been
doing this so long or you know any of
the
Pioneers um everybody is worthy of
abundance and everybody is worthy of
respect and everybody is worthy of
participating in building this yeah so
that I try to keep my eye on that as
much as I can continue to create
abundant models so that just like you're
going to do here um so that we can take
care of more people right more of our
people more more more of our community
and more of the world I mean we're on a
mission to bring this plant medicine to
the people um the people need it the
world needs it um there's I don't know
15 Wars happening on the planet right
now or something like that um and the
planet itself is sort of dying under our
feet under our watch under our watch
yeah so you know a lot of healing needs
to occur and everybody on this planet is
going to have to make sacrifices like we
had to make for many many years they
might be different they may be in
different spheres of society or or
different areas of
business or different areas of nonprofit
work or whatever it is everybody's going
to have to make some sacrifices yeah um
you know my partner Samantha she lived
on Maui for 10 years well bunch of
people she knows and loves their houses
burned down during the fires on Maui and
you know huge sacrifices right huge
sacrifices um and all those folks are
having to scatter and rebuild and and
figure it out these these plants these
medicines can you know greatly help us
with all of that and and and help us
deal with these traumas that are
probably somewhat inevitable given abut
that eightball were behind on the
climate um and not to mention you know
political divisions in
society uh um um so the plants are on
the way that's the good news right we've
been carrying the plants we've been you
know plants down have feet they don't
have hands they don't have mouths they
can't talk about themselves so that's
our job right move it around grow it
yeah um package it tell the story of it
educate folks about it then eventually
the plants do most of the work for us
right you know it's been my experience
most of the work for us yeah
yeah yeah if if you listen to plant we
show you the way if you listen right and
that's not just true with plants but you
know we kind of have a listening is
super important just being a good
listener I mean all you entrepreneurs
out there you want to really be
successful listen yeah become a good
listener um it's Richard Branson talks a
lot about that uh other folks because
it's how you get information and that's
and information is how you make good
decisions um and so being a good
listener with plants and with people and
with your teams and and with your
investors and everybody else is is a
critical skill right now yeah well you
know there's a saying that uh money's
value is in its use and not in its
possession and I feel like you have
lived that example extremely well and uh
yeah that's a great saying yeah and I
feel like there there's so many things
that are tied into that too but
everything's a tool um you know our
bodies our voices are are you know money
all these things are tools right for us
money probably is the one we're most
familiar with because when you have some
it's easy to take it and you know do
something with it um but um but all
these other things are also tools you
know and um and what we're
trying you know peace and love man it
comes down to peace and love and and
those are the two things that the world
needs the most I mean yeah you know well
they transcend language they transcend
everything peace and love at the end of
the day
yeah and all the religions and all the
Traditions um talk about this this is
not just a hippie dippy thing absolutely
this is this is you know and peace
doesn't mean a comfortable life I think
a lot of people get that wrong peace
doesn't always mean a comfortable life
no living in peace but mental you know
there is mental peace and mental Freedom
that's important oh yeah there are yogis
in India who possess nothing yeah and
they have a very peaceful mind and a
very peaceful life yeah you don't have
to possess stuff right to be peaceful
it's all within us you know um not easy
but comfort and peace are two different
things and I think struggle the
struggles that we go through are what
Define us and struggle is something that
I think a lot of people steer away from
and they're scared of when actually
struggle is something you should learn
to I do cold plunging too so now it's
like I'm embracing the cold water I love
that um and it's really the cold water
has taught me a lot uh you know I read
about Wim Hoff for years and all these
other things until you really do it you
don't understand what the cold water can
actually teach you but it teaches you to
go head on into the water and you know
not be afraid how long do you stay in
there so so the funny thing is I built
up I'm doing some of these 15 minute
plunges now which is you know you read
stuff and it's like well you only need
three to five minutes and I was doing
that for a long time and I've built it
up uh I don't always feel good when I
come out 15 minutes sometimes I do seven
minutes sometimes I do 10 yeah but now
that I these longer ones when I do seven
it feels like it's not enough but I get
the
same yeah I don't drink a lot of coffee
typically sometimes before I do a show
I'll you know drink some coffee to get
all in the mood but uh it's funny
because with the cold plunge I feel like
I get that same experience I'm awake and
I'm really present in reality and you I
feel like my brain functions better yeah
I've been doing I don't have the tub
with the ice uh but I've been doing
different types of cold plunges but I'm
it's more like 60 seconds yeah so um
I'll have to work my way up to even I
started out with a little bit longer
than that but I think I started out with
two the first time I did it was about a
minute and then I did three minutes the
next time and then what you realize is
like these things that you think are
going to kill you because right before
you get in freezing cold water you think
it's gonna kill you right your
subconscious is like you're not doing
this yeah and so over time and I I do it
daily now and there's some arguments for
how often you should do it and I feel
like you just need to listen to your
body and do what's right for you yeah
and some days I feel like only going
seven minutes and Someday I'm like I
want to do 15 minutes and I do it on an
empty stomach first thing I get out of
bed and I go into the water it's got to
be below 55 degrees is the ideal for
like the cold chock proteins yeah and
it's just it's a wonderful thing and I
think everybody should try it and force
Tony Robins method oh yeah yeah go
straight into the fire yeah no and
decision making so you decide first
thing to do something
that's naturally uncomfortable for you
totally and so all the other
uncomfortable things that happen
throughout the day become a lot easier
and you cuz our subconscious I'm dealing
with this a lot right now our
subconscious wants us to stay the same
and be comfortable right it doesn't want
us to really change a whole lot
especially if you know you figured out
how to be somewhat comfortable right
your body and your subconscious like
you're good man stay right here that's
it Oh no you're G to try a cold punch no
no don't do that you don't feel it you
all these things come in your mind right
and to and and your subconscious wants
you to not do the plunge right right but
so you have to have a lot of conscious
effort right to to make that decision
and do that I know that right before I
do mine and I usually do it after my
morning workout so um um I I stand on
the edge of the water for a good 60 90
seconds before I can make the decision
right to go in there and it's it's like
your body's it's just it's a trip what
your subconscious mind does when you're
like right there on the edge of the
water yeah um do you do it for pain
relief or you just do it for mental or
well so I have Aller of colitis and it's
in remission right now and one of the
things I that put it in remission I
believe is the cold plunges and so I was
on biologics I was on this drug called
Remicade and I got off completely off
Remicade and I was doing cold plunges
and then my doctor's like you think
about going back on Remicade and I said
well I I'm not having any problems right
now so I'm just going to wait another
month and another month turned into
another month and it turned into another
month and now I'm completely off and
that's great there you know it's like
yeah I changed my diet I don't drink
beer if I drink alcohol it's going to be
like a Gonic but I don't drink a lot
yeah right and so that's the big thing
is like noticeable changes in lifestyle
with the cold plunge I think it makes
you really aware of where you are in
that moment and I I just I see a lot of
uh guy you know Tony Robbins we've got
David gogins right yeah one of their
biggest things is they talking about
doing stuff you don't feel comfortable
with yeah and I mean those are you know
we want to be comfortable our
subconscious like you're saying really
wants us to be comfortable and I think a
lot of people try to Veer away from
anything that's outside their comfort
zone when really we should be going head
on towards it yeah and and you know I
found that getting help works with that
a lot like for for example I hired a
person trainer yeah um because now I'm
in my 50s um and now that I'm going once
a week to the trainer and he's giving me
all these exercises to do on my own yeah
you know I'm getting in pretty darn good
physical shape yeah um and it feels
really good um now I would not be as far
along had I not hired the trainer
because I learned exercises I didn't
know before um and you know before that
I would like lift a little weight I'd go
on a stationary bike I'd go on a long
hike but I
wasn't pushing myself to the edge okay
which the trainer does right um and the
trainer also gives you a homework and if
you don't do the homework you're going
to be in a world of hurt he's gonna know
it too it's real well you're going to be
in a world of hurt he's going to put you
through the workout and you're you're
going to barely be able to finish it
right um so you're incentivized to keep
going because you have to answer to
somebody right and I found and whether
that's getting a coach like Tony Robbins
or you know um other people really help
us transcend these plateaus that we may
find ourselves in life you know and and
again you know it's it's it's not to
shamelessly plug my Consulting business
but that's what people like us do right
is is is is we're here to help and um
it's hard to reach out for help the ego
and the subconscious ah you don't need
any help you got this you're fine you
know what you're doing yeah um but when
you're talking about something that's
complex act as starting a cannabis
dispensary in New York yeah you know um
I'm seeing a lot of folks in New York
just making
really page one mistakes you know
whether it be what they're calling
themselves whether it be um you know
what kind of space they rent whether it
be the deal they have with the landlord
whether it be and all kinds of things
you know I'm seeing well you're going to
save people money and that's the big I
think what people a lot of people don't
understand is with Consultants they save
you money A lot of times you can hire
someone that can navigate that knows
where you're going so you don't have to
go all over the place you can go in a
straight line from where you are now to
where you want to be that's the big and
do it efficiently fast okay because and
you have to do it fast these days you
have to do it fast these days right um
because every day that you're not
bringing Revenue in yeah is a bad day
yeah okay it is because you have to
spend money every day
to be a license holder in any framework
you have to spend money every single day
so there's thousands of dollars going
out every day every day there's new
competition coming online so that market
share gets smaller and smaller it's just
so you have to be good okay and um and
and
yes Consultants especially some of us
that have been doing this for a long
time we're
not cheap right the good ones cheap the
good ones are not cheap no but but I
like I'm not super expensive so like you
know I'm I I like to think of myself as
the best but I generally fall in the
middle of pricing in in the market you
know I'm not way out here like some of
the law firms and other people are but
I'm not I'm not way down you know where
someone who doesn't have the track
record I do might price themselves right
right um so you know and that middle
place where I'm at it it it gives people
excellence and expertise at at at a rate
that will save them money yeah I'll give
you an example in Ohio it's a medical
framework there and they just issued a
bunch of new licenses my clients got
three of them and the State Board of
Pharmacy runs the program in Ohio they
require they only give you nine months
from the time you're awarded the license
to opening your doors for a dispensary
wow that's very hard to do especially if
the buildings that are available to you
in
zoning are not very good buildings right
so we had to take two of our three
buildings down to the stud oh and then
build it out from there um and we still
because those clients hired me okay and
my team we they opened on time okay
something like 60 or 70% of the other
license holders in Ohio did not open on
time a good 20 or 30 of them are still
not open all right and and I feel bad
because like If you hired me I would
have had you open by now man and it's
like you know and a month goes by that
you're not open my God that's that could
be a million dollars right there that
you Lo that you didn't get in Revenue
would have more than paid for your
Consulting service many times over many
times over and so you know these are the
kind of things that happen um um for
folks and and and I want to avoid that I
want I want you to avoid being late I
want you to avoid having to change
something that's built with concrete
because you didn't plan it on paper
right right how many people do you know
that had to tear out stuff that they
built because it wasn't done right the
first time a lot of them a lot right and
that's where you start to get in a world
of pain um because I don't know tearing
something something out rebuilding it
that's a week yeah best case scenario a
week um and so now you've got a domino
effect because that piece of the
building or the the the the you know
isn't built and it's late and so there's
a domino effect on everybody else that
and cost is more than double because you
have to tear out what tear out and and
you feel really bad as an entrepreneur
you just feel bad right um and we don't
want to feel bad it's hard enough um so
so but there is kind of a race to the
bottom right now not just with
Consultants but with everything with
seeds with everything genetics
everything it's just a race to the
bottom um and but this too shall pass
that's I think all of this you know and
you've been around long enough with
industry so all this stuff it's like it
goes in waves and it's a struggle now
and it's going to get better and then
it's probably going to be a struggle
again and it's going to get better up
and down up and down up and down I mean
you know it's kind of like life um so
but it's more extreme than life right um
with the ups and the downs and yes this
moment to Shall Pass yeah um will there
be a race to the bottom you know for the
foreseeable future in the Cannabis
industry probably you know um because
the Frameworks are so screwed up with
regulation and taxes that consumers are
very price conscious you know and and
and all the heavy consumers are
underground because they can't afford it
yeah um and so this is the problem the
the it it so of course people want to
slash their
prices to try to bring people in right
and it can end badly right because even
if your margins are the same or get
better because your inputs are cheaper
your cash flow is really much lower
right you have lower cash flow than you
did before because you're selling
something for 20 an e instead of 40 and
e um or whatever the number is right
right and
now but you have the same amount of
employees yeah all right and so it
become the race to the bottom becomes a
cash flow issue and you can run out of
cash right okay and running out of cash
is the biggest disaster for any
entrepreneur right because now you're in
receivership or bankruptcy or whatever
it is um and talk about painful you know
and if you did a personal guarantee you
might personally be bankrupt so um it's
it and know these these horror stories
are all over all over are just all over
there's thousands of these horror
stories um so get some good advice you
know even if it's not me get get get
really good advice yeah that's great
advice yeah well man I really appreciate
you coming on the show today so if
somebody's looking for you they can find
you on uh your website and also on
social media yeah Andrew D angelo.com is
the website most of my social media is
Andrew D'Angelo except LinkedIn which is
just Andrew
D'Angelo and there's last prisoner
project.org also and yeah if anybody
wants to help prisoners check out last
prisoner project.org if anybody needs
help from me uh drop me an email or a
social message excellent well thank you
so much for coming on the show today
it's been a great show I really
appreciate it James thank you appreciate
it thanks for having me all
right
cheers Cru
[Music]
back
CR
yeah