[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James loud
podcast today I have two special guests
that have already been on the show
before we have Steve D'Angelo we have
Uncle Rick Mr Richard delisi how you
doing oh fine thank you for having me
today yeah thank you guys for coming on
the show so Steve is you guys probably
know he's uh founder of Harbor Side last
prisoner project he's been on a bunch of
documentaries in one project after the
next you've done a lot over the last 40
years for the plant and you've also done
a lot over the last 40 years for the
plant in other ways than thank you guys
for coming on the show it's a pleasure
to be here an honor to be here with
Richard and it's I think it's more like
50 years right 60 years for this guy
yeah so yeah I sold my first bag of weed
when I was 13 years old I'm 65 now wow
do you remember the the weat the
specific stream oh yeah it was just
Mexican brick we weed that was you know
basically all that was available then so
you know I bought a nickel bag and I
rolled it into six joints and sold each
joint for a buck and did that a few
times and eventually started buying eles
and yeah that that led to greater things
over time yeah to Harbor Side to Harbor
Side eventually yeah yeah pretty wild
long strange trip it's been a long
strange trip in a wonderful one too so
yeah and then uh Rick you you did 32
years plus you did another
fiveyear stint right I did I did 32
calendar straight in Maxum security
prison State of Florida yeah and you
were over a plant over a plant over a
plant nonviolent nonviolent charge over
marijuana only and the worst
part you didn't get caught for doing it
you got stitched on right I I never got
they never put their hands on me with
with products yeah it was all it it was
all a premeditated deal by the
government right yeah to go after you
yep and 32 years they gave me
98 well and then when I met your son
this this is in 200 I think 11 and your
your son he's your biggest Advocate and
said my father's going to get out of
prison soon absolutely him and my nephew
Kenneth yeah and my daughter Ashley and
that was the first time I heard of you
was in 2011 and I finally came home with
2020 yeah it took much more time I mean
my my children and my nephew which I
call my son
too they were at it for 17 plus yeah and
then when as soon as last prisoners
project got
involved it wasn't 8 weeks and I was
home right it went went pretty quickly
yeah it was fast it was it was so rapid
I was like I don't know if I was ready
you know right but I am now I bet I bet
and you've been able to enjoy cannabis
quite a bit and you have your own
cannabis brand delicioso right we we
have our own brand in Florida we work
with true Leaf yeah uh we're in 130
stores in the State of Florida it's
really impressive yeah it's so
unbelievable that I'm actually s illegal
in the state they put me away for 98
years that's what's pretty wild about it
yeah and they don't have no beef about
it or any you know they don't
even I've been trying to get clemency
since I've been home or a p or something
well because it's state you can't get a
presidential the Pres the president
can't do it it's got to be it's got to
be Ronda Santos to do
it or whoever replaces him or whoever
replaces him right and he's not big on
cannabis no he's not big on him all not
big on cannabis in a good way I think uh
we could expect the santis to uh to
probably attack cannabis yeah and then
so Steve how did you guys first meet
because you guys have known each other
for a long time I think when I met you
you were talking about Richard and well
it was through Rick right it was was it
was um uh I think uh I was late to
Instagram so I think it was like
2012 or 2013 something like that that I
actually got an Instagram account up and
it was somewhere in those first you know
a year or two after I had an Instagram
account that Rick reached out to me and
told me the story and it was uh even
before we started last prisoner project
that I think we started having that
conversation um you know for me it was
around 2017 that I really started
thinking about last prisoner project in
a serious way because we just passed
adult use cannabis in California 2016
but not a single person got released
from prison as a result of of passing
that legislation MH and so I felt like
the next step was was actually doing
something and so you know from the
beginning uh Richard was on the list of
of prisoners that I cared about um
because I remember right like I'm 10
years behind Richard okay he was like
the big glamorous airplane flying boat
captain and weed Smuggler who is
bringing in these huge loads of amazing
weed and I was like this you know young
dealer who was you know moving 50 lb
lots and 100 lb lots and if I was lucky
I you know I could catch something on
offload from you know from a big
Smuggler but that was kind of like my
role model and who I wanted to be and I
remembered so well when the federal
government started going after all the
big Smugglers and laying down these Rico
charges and these you know 20 30 40 50
98e sentences yeah and uh and it was
then that we really knew that like the
the war was on it was on and what year
was that roughly the time I remember
that beginning is when Ronald Reagan was
elected in 1980 he appointed George HW
Bush the uh drugs are of the South
Florida task force and uh they were the
first people to put US military awax up
in the air to start patrolling the
Caribbean yeah and and so what they did
is they in that time there was a bunch
of really great Colombian weed that was
coming in just phenomenal weed it was
coming in in these great big boat loads
of it um you could like go 12 miles
outside of the the coastal waterway in
Florida and like a little cabin cruiser
and there would just be like six or
seven ships there that you could buy
weed off of it was it was really quite
incredible uh for a while um Bush went
in and targeted the big slow moving
wheat chips and then allow all of his
Cuban buddies who had you know operated
with them in the Bay of Pigs and other
you know fascist kind of undercover
operations to bring in as much coke as
they wanted and that was the beginning
of the crack epidemic and that was when
they started putting away people like
Richard for decades yeah so Richard you
got a lot of good stories I've been able
to hang out with you for the last couple
days and I've I've heard some amazing
stories that I wasn't able to get on the
show the first time but yeah
um stories about hanging out with the
Grateful Dead stories about partying in
New York you know I think we got some of
those on but let's talk a little bit
about some of the smuggling that you've
done and some of the good times it was
always a good time smuggling as long as
you got home and everybody was safe and
no one got in trouble yeah that made it
a good time you know MH as far as the
the business part of it it would that
was a great time yeah cuz CU I met so
many
people I met so many people and so many
characters through through my through my
years of doing it so what was the
closest call of a load that actually did
make it you mean you mean like a close
call yeah like one that almost didn't
make it but it made it the first deal I
ever
did I went to Jamaica on a diving deal
it was supposed to be that's what I told
my dad only you know because I couldn't
tell my father what I was doing so I
said you know this guy's got a boat and
my father knew who the guy was and he
wants me to go and take care of the
engine on the
boat and
uh I wound up you know going and down
and doing it that was the first deal
that was in like
1970 yeah so you know in 1970 you could
drive a boat right up to the back of the
house and un loaded no one even
suspected anything right you know I mean
on the Three Bridges you know Three
Bridges around the corners you know and
we unloaded it right at my friend's
backyard yeah like in the canals and
land yeah like regular in full udale and
poo actually yeah wow yeah so I I
remember like you know going to those
houses right and and and and like
picking up hundred Lots from these
houses that would be right on the canals
and then in those days just bring the
boats right right into the backyard the
of the houses and the canals wow yeah
wild I mean we had we had a rope going
one rope going down tied the
bells inside of inside of sail bags we
had the the weed tucked in you know we
didn't want to really make it look crazy
so if anybody did see it and we just
keep on pulling them up and they put
them in the garage and then a truck
would back in a van fill a van up and
the van would drive away and then
another van would come in fill a van up
another van would drive away and one
would go you know they would all go to a
certain spot yeah and everything would
get weighed at the spot and then it
would go into into cars and then it
would go on the Auto Train or what go to
New York or wherever yeah mostly New
York yeah New York and Chicago yeah well
then you started out in Jamaica you
ended up in Colombia you had a
plantation in Columbia for a little bit
of coffee house or coffee Plantation yes
what happened was me and my brother were
driving around one day this how we got
involved actually and we stopped in the
7-Eleven on Sample Road and they I seen
the car trader and on the front page of
the car trader had a house for S uh
coffee plantation for selling Columbia
with
beautiful two-story house yeah so I
asked I bought the magazine and I asked
the girl behind the counter if she could
please s s me a roll of quarters and I
went outside my brother said what are
you doing I said we're going to buy this
house in
Columbia they [ __ ] thought I was
crazy yeah six days later we head the
house wow and we didn't even have
passports when I took the paper off the
thing H so we what we did
was we went and bought tickets to go to
Columbia without our passports because
you could do it back then yeah we bought
two tickets for Columbia and we went to
the passport office we left the airport
went to the passport office and said to
the passport office Hey listen one of
one of our family members died in
Columbia we need to get down there right
away we had our passports in 2 hours and
20 minutes wow doesn't happen like that
anymore no I got out when I came out
from prison yeah took me 26 days to get
my passport
wow yeah I know people it's taken a year
year and a half two years to get
passports now even people without
criminal issues but you guys remember a
time and this is before my time where
you used to walk through and there was
no airport security well I'll tell you
interesting story about uh one of my
earliest arrests uh yes there was a time
when you could just get on an airplane
with weed or or cash and you know go
from point A to point B and I was uh
working out of New York um bringing
loads from New York down to DC and I was
working for one particular character who
has actually been in the news recently
but I'm not going to name his name um
who um desperately needed the $26,000
that I owed him like so desperately that
he couldn't wait for me to take the
train the next morning I had to fly
there on the last flight out from
Washington DC to New York MH and so I
stick the cash in a in a briefcase
because that's all you had to do right I
wrapped it up in like a little satin
sheet or something like that and it I
get to the airport and there's this
machine at the gate that I'd never seen
before it was a metal detector and they
had this sign up there they said this is
this new machine to protect Stu metal
detector and it's like if you you know
you uh are not any under obligation to
consent to a surge if you put your bag
in here and it and it alerts you can
either choose to take your bag and leave
the airport or we can search it and you
can board the plane so I stupidly
allowed the bag to go through the the
the detector it alerts um uh and they
did not give me the option of leaving
the airport uh with my bag uh they
arrested me and They seized all of the
cash and you know that was uh that My
First Federal conviction wow actually my
first and only Federal conviction yeah
and then we had Rick who uh was loading
H how many pounds per load would you
guys take typically at the end yeah I me
in the in the beginning and then at the
end in the beginning um I guess the the
first load I did was
um
450 on in the SE plan yeah I said
something to my brother I said Hey
listen we we should definitely get our
own
transportation because we were having
problems with the we did like two or
three deals with the with the with the
SE planes mhm
and the guy
um he stepped he stepped to my
friend when we wereing around and he
said Hey listen I don't want you know I
don't want to work with these guys and
and uh I want to do something with just
me you know me and you and the guy says
oh no we can't do nothing with
you you can't ever even you can't even
ever work for thees again for trying to
go behind their back this this is my
Colombian buddy you know this guy was
like with me yeah and that was the end
of that and there was two or three
people to triy that you know you take
them from New York you bring them down
there you show them the whole deal and
then they go down there by themselves
they think they can they think they can
C they think they can repeat it right
because they got some cash but I don't
know if you know Colombian people are
very loyal yeah very very loyal once
they hook with somebody and they see
that you're a family type of person and
you're you're about making money and
making sure that everybody's safe
there's no way that they're leaving you
yeah it's interesting over the years
I've had my experiences with that too
but at the end I was bringing you know
like
22,000 we'd load on a dc6 wow DC4 yeah
pretty amazing yeah two you know like
two half tractor trailers before we we
load the trailers with uh you know half
weed and half uh plants yeah the back
part of the trailer would be loaded with
plants front part of the trailer would
be loaded with weed about 10
tons actually like 10,000 pounds in the
front of both of them wow wild oh yeah I
mean they were just like you know these
incredible like modern-day pirate Heroes
man who were like making it through all
the radar beating the Coast Guard
beating the US Army yeah um uh and doing
these incredible incredible and the weed
was just you know it was extraordinary I
was I was buying probably some of the
weed that Richard smuggled into New York
and it was uh I paid $350 a pound for it
which was $200 a pound more than I was
paying for Mexican wheed at the time wow
um and it was this just extraordinarily
light gold and when I say gold it was
like the gold and the logo on your cap
right um with these dark dark seeds in
it and just a turpine profile this
piny joyous amazing tarpine profile it
was just some of the very best wheat
that I've ever ever smoked strong I mean
I haven't experienced true Colombian
gold ever my life I've smoked Colombian
genetics smoke Santa Marty gold I've
seen some really amazing stuff down
there um and the effect is always really
strong yeah I've smoked the the genetics
to the claim that they're the real Sant
Marta gold but I smoked the real Sant
Marta gold and um maybe those genetics
are the same right but there was a
method of harvesting and a method of
curing that has unfortunately been lost
right the way they dried it and the way
they cured it exactly that was a very
important part of the deal with the gold
too on how you dried it and prepared it
yeah so that sadly has been has been
lost uh um so it's going to take some
enterprising uh creative young people
I'm sure they're already working on it
and I've met some of them in Colombia
who are working to figure out how to
bring that that type of cannabis back
again so nice if it was done once it can
be done again um re what is it Reland
racing the world Reland racing the world
yeah geoc climatizing the world geoc
climatizing the world man I love that
concept of yours I think it's just so so
beautiful yeah I think we need to go
back to the roots you know where we came
from and add diversity back in I think
we shouldn't be afraid of diversity I
think especially with cannabis the
problem with uh what's going on now is
we're bottlenecking all these things
people like gelato it's very popular
everybody knows gelato but uh we get
these guys crossing a gelato with the
gelato and they're genetically they're
almost identical and so what you're
doing is actually taking away from the
genetics taking away from the Vigor and
uh we need to incorporate and and not be
afraid to incorporate other things that
might not be popular for a little while
and listen to the plant right so the the
plant is incredible because you can put
her anywhere in the world and within a
few Generations she will acclimatize
herself to that particular microclimate
and start producing more optimal
expressions of of of that genetic
underlying genetic material in in a way
that is much more rapid and and and
efficient than most other plants around
around the world so the the the plant
herself is calling upon us to plant her
in different places to see what happens
and to honor and respect uh each of
those varieties so you know one of the
things we always tried to do at
Harborside was to create an ongoing role
for the small grower and and
particularly for sungrown Growers and so
you know one of the things that's still
being worked on in California but I
think should be a feature of the
Cannabis industry globally is
Appalachians just like you have
Appalachians of origin for wine and for
some types of cheese and other
agricultural products we need that for
cannabis and appalachi of origin that
you know require the seeds to be
actually grown in the soil and
underneath the sun of that particular
microclimate yeah and it doesn't matter
what the genetics are you could take
something and grow it in one place you
can go sometimes as as little as 5 miles
and get a completely different
expression you can go a th000 miles and
you wouldn't even recognize it as the
same thing you that's and that's the
beauty of the plant and you know it it's
all these environmental variables add
to not only the story but the amazing
qualities you know and it's very you can
get these unique expressions and some
stuff is meant to be grown in the
highlands and some stuff is meant to be
grown Coastal and you know I I big on
explor exploring what should be grown
where and with all these different
genetic lines being able to go test out
in these places and see what does better
in what place and you know I think
that's the beauty of it too it seems
like the islands like the the Hawaiian
Islands
yep they would rather the plants would
rather grow on the
ground than
inside in other words inside grows I
didn't see one there I didn't see one
inside grow all the time I was there and
I've seen three different
grows yeah I mean let's be clear about
why we started growing weed indoors we
started growing weed indoors because the
government started sending helicopters
and found our outdoor fart was it it
wasn't because we thought we were going
to grow much better weed in first in
fact that was contrary to the hippie
ethic of doing things as naturally as as
we possibly could and the actual real
reality is that you will never no matter
what light is created be able to to get
the kind of fullness of turpine
expression that you can get under the
Sun from an artificial light it's just
not going to happen right right so I
think that uh that that that that we
were right then right and and that
moving forward this is why Appalachians
are so important right that once we
really do go through this process of
Reland racing and and and and Geo
climatizing geoc climatizing strains for
the IDE microclimates and then
protecting them with Appalachians y
that's going to be the most desirable
weed not some weed that was grown in a
grow room that you could grow that exact
same weed with that exact same
expression anywhere in the world no
optimizing those environments with you
optimizing the cannabis for those
environments and finding out what works
the best and you know and exploring
those you know those those uh those
paths with different genetics and really
see what performs best in what region
and you know there there and there's
there's a lot of mystery there there's a
lot of mystery to be found and you know
it's it's amazing because all the
genetics we're working with came from
six things you know the six six regions
so basically everything that we have
that we're smoking today the modern
cannabis pretty much came from these six
plants or six regions I I would imagine
that there are parts of this globe uh
that have um that have been very
difficult to get to because of civil
conflict and other reasons where there
are still other basic building block
varieties of cannabis yet to be found
for sure infinite fun right Mother
Nature was so wise and generous with
this plant there are so many different
possible combinations of cannaboids and
Turpin and flavonoids that it's just
this Treasure Chest that we're going to
be opening up and playing with both from
a spiritual point of view and a
pharmaceutical point of view yeah for as
long as I can imagine into the future
talking about cannabis right tell me how
cannabis benefited your life it made me
feel wonderful yeah it paid my bills M
it's going to grow my my name delicioso
on on my uh incorporation I think is
just going to grow incredibly fast now
because I think people are
realizing that people that put the work
in before it was just you know you could
come with money and do it now right you
know we we set the groundwork and we we
we made sure that when we did it that it
was going to stay around we didn't we
didn't do it just for the moment we did
it
forever yeah and I'll be doing this till
I die you know this is my thing this is
what you were meant to do you know I was
meant to do this like you know cowboys
were meant to be Gunslingers and all
that stuff I I was meant to be a
Smuggler it was it was it was it was
part of my bloodline that my grandfather
was a
bootlegger my
father worked for my grandfather so if
you look down to generation to
generation someone in my father's family
was going to
be not
legitimate and that was that happened to
be me and I was I've been doing this
since I was like I guess
14 you know it had was 14 I was 14 years
old and and I was in the business big
time by the time I was 18 four years
later I was you know driving like brand
new cars and you know beautiful
Apartments yeah and no one knew where
were I was So Undercover they were like
how is this guy got two motorcycles you
know a Holly and a Triumph you know
brand new you know it was
crazy but it was it was like a it was
like just a smooth you know it was
like I could give someone a million
dollars worth of weed and shake their
hand and say man I'll see you in two
weeks they didn't have to give me
anything just drop I drop off like
18,000 and 18,000 would be over a
million probably you know what I mean
but I would just shake the hand and that
was that today it's like you know you
can't do that no more it's not it's not
possible Right unless you're with with
people that you grew up with like you
said yesterday I'm with my friends that
I grew up with yeah the only people that
I could really trust is the people that
I grew up with and and some great people
like I met now like Steve and people
like you that I don't you know they know
they know that they know I ain't saying
anything MH if a cop grabs me and tells
me yeah you know you're going to get get
80 years but I'm going to give you two
if you just tell me about the guy down
the street I tell him hey man you go
talk to the guy down the street you
don't talk to me about him right that's
the way everybody's get in trouble now
it's they just give up people you know
they don't know what they're what
they're involved in you know I always
sat my guys down before we did a deal I
said you know I'm going to go do this
deal now you guys are going to make you
know you're going to all load the plane
you're all going to make 25 grand for
half out work or 50 grand for half hour
work but there's a consequence if you
get caught you're going to jail right
and you got to keep your Mount shut but
obviously a lot of people don't do that
especially people from South Florida
yeah well I was shocked I mean after
spending the first 30 years of my
cannabis career in the Legacy Market
where you
know routinely millions and millions of
dollars traded on a handshake and yeah
occasionally things went sideways people
went bad on you it it happened right but
usually it was rare that people went
into a deal with you like that with the
intention of ripping you off it was
usually because something happened to
them and and there was a Cascade of
consequences right so I was really
shocked when I started sitting down and
doing mainstream business and actually
having written contracts right oh those
guys are the worst well see I thought
that the contract was actually this
attempt to come to a mutual agreement
where everybody would understand what
the terms were and it would be very
clear with each other so that you would
avoid conflict right then I learned that
there's this whole Cadre of mainstream
business that writes contracts
deliberately so that they can set you up
to be screwed a little bit later down
the line and they use the most
obfuscating confusing unclear kind of
language as they possibly can and then
rely on the courts to enforce some kind
of unfair deal right and I was just like
I was shocked that people would choose
to spend their lives that way it's like
when you could do business honestly with
people and shake their hands and find
good about it why are you going to spend
your time writing up all these [ __ ]
contracts designed to cheat people right
was just well and now nowadays you want
to work with people that you could do a
handshakes deal and you need a contract
it's like CU it's just it's there's a
lot of Bad actors out there and a lot
bad people you know and it's people that
are in it for the wrong reasons I think
when it was more dangerous and there was
more consequences on the legal side
there was a different crowd of people
you had to have some balls it wasn't
about how good is your lawyer it was
like okay we're going to commit to doing
something we're going to do it a and now
if you got money you could pay to play
it's a pay to play sort of thing and
people don't realize the importance of
quality that's another issue issue with
the industry today and I think you guys
both understand quality uh and stepen
harbor side had some amazing quality for
those of you that have seen the harbor
side of today it's not the harbor side
that I grew up knowing the harbor side I
grew up knowing was the placees set the
standard for clones if you wanted good
clones Harbor Side had the best clones
they had the best quality dark heart
originally darkart had the best clones
you know and harbor side they they sold
darkart clones but you would take them
and they were Picture Perfect clones and
they had perfect roots and you guys
would reject tons of stuff but I
remember going to harbor side and it's
like if you wanted flower they had all
different tiers of flower but the top
shelf back in the day you wanted some
chem 91 some sage and sour you wanted
some good topshelf flow it was available
there and the stuff was better on
average than you could find in most
dispensaries in California today most uh
results flow out of intention right and
Our intention was was to create a temple
for cannabis and a community space for
people who loved cannabis and yeah you
know we found oursel in this very
fortunate place in California where it
was you know still a gray Market it
wasn't fully legal by law it was
nonprofit so the big corporations didn't
want to come in and we had this
breathing room and we created this
really amazing system right um there
nobody made intergenerational wealth or
not very many people right but everybody
in that system from 1996 until 2018 was
taking care of farmers could afford to
buy the land they were growing on and
send their kids to school patients could
come into dispensaries and get the very
best weed in the world at really
affordable prices yeah people who worked
in dispensaries had the best jobs that
that they'd ever had in their lives
right um everybody was well taken care
of uh in that system I mean there was
counties in the Emerald Triangle that
their whole economy was based on cannab
M you know the whole economy all of it
everything you know if you lived up
there if you didn't participate your
spouse your neighbor the kids you went
to school with their parents did I mean
it it you know was such a big deal and
now that's kind of changed
unfortunately because a lot of those
people were the ones that helped build
the industry as it is today you know
guys like Richard we got the cultivators
you know I think I've done my part you
know I've been around since the 90s and
very passionate about cannabis but you
know and it's it's a group effort from
so many people in so many directions and
you know we were we were at dinner last
night talking about how tough times are
and how you know for for me it's all
about being grateful for where we're at
and what we have and if you start
getting too caught up on the bad part
you you forget how you know we're living
in a time that weed is marijuana is
legal we can yeah it's pretty much legal
federally whatever but you can go on the
joint you smoke a joint on the street
and they're not going to give you [ __ ]
for it too too often um you're not going
to get locked up over a joint that's for
sure what's this incredible uh in my
opinion spiritual Revolution that we're
undergoing now where literally hundreds
of millions of people all around the
world have been called into
conversations with this plant yeah and
out of those conversations we have uh
learned the same lessons and out of
those lessons we've built a common value
system right so wherever we are in the
world we value creativity over
Conformity we value individual Freedom
over submission to Authority we value
nature over industry we value peace over
War we value love over hate we believe
that every living creature and and every
inanimate object made by Nature has a
place and a purpose in this world and
that's who we are whatever language we
speak whatever race we are whatever
religion we follow around the world uh
plant people follow that same path and
so uh it's this incredible time um where
we now have the opportunity to introduce
ourselves to each other yeah and think
about it it's like we've all been called
we've all been called by the same plan
what she want us to
do yeah and if you listen the plan tell
you slel put you in the right direction
if you listen this is the reason that
governments and religions are so
terribly terrified of cannabis because
when we engage with that can that
conversation with cannabis it is a
direct conduit to Mother Nature it is a
direct conduit to the Divine and the
messages that we receive from Mother
Nature from the Divine carry a greater
author Authority than any man-made
Authority will ever have and this is why
uh authoritarians have always been so
hostile towards cannbis yeah so you've
been in Hawaii lately we were talking
about Hawaiian weed a little
bit how how's it over in Hawaii do
Hawaii is like my son lives in Amsterdam
yeah so when he moved to Hawaii I said
to him
um well how'd he like it he said dad I
moved from the swamp to Paradise yeah
and you know I've been to Hawaii a few
times I spent some time there I lived
there for about six or seven
months um I never did any time in my and
Maui but this time you know he wanted to
make sure that I seen most of the the
great things that it offers the the
island you know and it was I mean I went
fishing I we caught like over 500 lb of
Yellow Tail tuna wow then we went
hunting we got a we got a Angus cow 300
lound I mean we could have got A500
pounder if we wanted to but we only had
a certain amount of time to clean it CU
I had to come to California you know we
were and I met this great guy Patrick
that's got a farm there Richie met him
like a semi acccident it was almost that
they met each other and and the people
that worked for him and the people that
took us hunting and Patrick took us
fishing you know yeah it was it was um
quite an experience aai this time it it
was a whole new deal for me when you
said you saw some Sour Diesel there that
was really
good wow purple purple Sour Diesel the
bottom of the leaves were purple when I
lifted the leaf up I said holy cow yeah
I said I want some of this right now I
said well you know won't be ready for a
little while yeah but um I wound up
getting a few things from him before I
left
nice excellent and then Jason Harris uh
he's over there you know what happened
was I'm there right and I'm talking to
my friends and they're like hey Maui W
is so I said don't worry I'll bring
something back for you guys you know
yeah so interesting enough I got Maui
wow when I was in my probably 16 years
old or something like that and we got
this Maui woi that came in and it was
velvety it was lime green and it was
velvety like spongy velvety but it was
part of the texture and this stuff was
amazing it was it definitely would lift
you up and the effect is what I remember
the most I don't really remember how it
tasted but I remember the way it looked
cuz it was like remember super sticky it
was it was super sticky yeah it was
super sticky I don't really remember the
smell though but I do remember the way
it made me feel and it was super super
super uplifting it was strong but
uplifting yeah it was it's a happy weed
yeah the very first um what we called
then cmia the very first domestically
grown weed that was good as opposed to
what we used to call groes or homegrown
which was really really badly grown weed
in the beginning um was in 1974 in New
York City when uh I bought a pound of
Mali W for
$1,200 and and again it was like this
incredible sticker shock right because
like I was used to paying 300 or 350 for
the Colombians is like $1,200 for a
pound of wheat it's like I don't care
how good this wheat is I'm not paying
$1,200 a pound for it and then the pound
was put in front of me and of course I
did end up buying it yeah yeah New York
has always been Infamous for the
expensive Town prices well and it's
playing a role in in what's happening in
New York right now and the the
difficulty of uh of getting a workable
legal system in New York right because
New York has always been the place where
if you had a load of really good weed
you take it to New York because you're
going to get top dollar and you're going
to turn it fastest oh God you always
good in New York there's no place that
you could move weed like you like you
could in in New York so consequently New
Yorkers got used to having the best weed
in the world and because it was a
competitive environment they ended up
paying you know high prices but not
ridiculous prices for it became very
particular consumers and and that whole
network that was developed to serve
those consumers um is now the Legacy
Market in New York and you've got a
bunch of um msos who really don't know
anything about cannabis who are now
trying to compete with that network with
weed that they're growing in New York
right and uh it's not going too well for
them so far well most of your weed was
moved in New York right I some in Miami
some other plac but New York was the I
didn't sell any any weed in
Florida none in Florida none all in New
York it either went to New York or
Chicago yeah wow and I used to sell the
whole load for 250 a
pound you know if you took 18,000 you
pay 250 if you if you're a kid that grew
up with me yeah which the he used to
take the big load he grew up with me but
if say like like my next door neighbor
wanted 250 I'd give him I'd give him 250
pounds for $250 a pound just because you
know right or one of my friends that
might have been a fireman or a cop in
New York I'd give them 250 a pound you
know yeah well then so your price was
what 100 and then you're you're doubling
you're
2.5x or what was your cost May 30 bucks
a pound or something oh not even for it
was like it was like yeah $8 a pound or
something when you know cuz yeah we had
to just figure we had to figure the guy
you know the planter the guy that's
watching it sure that's how we figured
it we didn't we just figured well it's
going to cost to grow this
field it's going to cost us 20 grand
yeah all right that
fields 30,000 pound
field I mean it's deep and long you know
I
mean yes so when when you break it down
if you're getting
30,000 and you're only paying 20 grand
what do you actually paying for each
pound you know what I mean if you break
it down all the way it's like it was
peanuts sure it was like Pennies on a
dollar like type of thing you know you
pay more money to to bribe the people
they need to bribe to get the load out
of the then you paid for the week
sometimes it used to cost me 30 grand
just to get out to the desert well you
I'd be driving along and there'd be
there'd be an army stop I jump out of
the truck with a shoe box for 500
pesos so when I say waka what comes to
mind what's the first thing that comes
to mind for you guys for me um the it's
the most indigenous uh state in Mexico
and uh that was that was the best best
fol to come out of Mexico go through
ever yeah well hackin was the best ever
smoke and the best part was I had the
connection when I was
wow the Wise Guys in New York had the
connection and my friend knew the Wise
Guys so I used to go over to the
Manhattan Beach Hotel and I'd buy pounds
of w hawen for 20 bucks a
piece wow in New York yeah this in the
early 60s sure but 20 bucks a piece but
I had to buy a whole suitcase you know
like 20 of them or 30 of them yeah
nice wow I wish I had that connection
back then God it was and and and you
know we would sell them for like 150
yeah yeah that's what I I was paying if
I got a pound of Mexican Washington DC
for 120 bucks I was thrilled if I was
paid 150 I was okay if I had to pay 160
or 65 I was kind of not so happy about
it well I mean the people that I would
sell it to 250 like my friend mhm he
would double his money but that was a
Colombian yeah a Columbian yeah that's
totally different yeah he would D he
would double his money he'd buy it for
250 a pound and he'd sell it for 500
wow and Dro a few ounces for three
hearing there oh all day
long and then then he he tried me on the
twigs and the seeds you know what I mean
he said oh yeah I had like 80 lbs of
seeds and
TGs I say well knock it off the bill so
how did they do the brick weed how did I
Breck it how did well how did yeah how
did do Breck I had I I had two book
presses that I bought in New York put on
an airplane and send down there book
presses yeah book presses wow I would I
would do like they were this long yep
you know there the regular Colombian
Bells were like that and about that high
right but they were that long about that
high I guess about yeah about that high
that was 20 PBS H
pressed and then I wrapped them i'
wrapped them differently you know they'd
be wrapped in brown paper with little
plastic around them and it'd be stacked
into the bur up bags yeah and it would
be like perfectly you know the Bap size
yeah in Mexico we used to we had build
boxes is right of the size that we
wanted the Bales to be and then we'd use
Auto Jacks and put the Jacks in and then
um use hydraulic jacks to press the the
weed wild into it and then and then do
the and then do the wrapping and the
price of the weed but that that or at
least you know I would take the same
weed and I would press it in three
different levels of pressing and they
would end up selling it at three
different prices so like the pillow
press was just like barely compressed
the buds were still really really nice
but took up a lot of space in the
vehicle so the price was higher and then
you could like compress it down and get
it to like half of that size right um or
you could just smash the [ __ ] out of it
and get it down that was that was the
problem with the Jamaican whenever you
got your Mak it was never pressed it was
loose in the Bell you know it was Bell
stuffed with by hand wow so a bell like
this
big was like 40 45 PBS
H ha off
yeah but the quality of the Jamaican
stuff was really good or no really so J
so if you had to rate the different
regions how would you rate the the top
Colombian being the top Tai would be the
top Tai would be the top then Colombian
okay then depending on the era Jamaican
or Mexican in the beginning there was a
time when there was good Jamaican that
was better than most of the Mexican but
over time the Mexican got much better at
at growing good weed while the Jamaicans
kind of stagnated well Jamaicans have
improved they have improved but but but
still um most people I know who go to
Jamaica bring their own weed with them
the the oriental people in Jamaica are
the ones that got the weed up in you
know they got the quality to weed up H
mostly Chinese people growing it there's
there's the thing the cool thing about
Jamaica is it's it's you know usually
thought of is just this black nation
right but it actually you know has all
different kinds of cultural strains from
all over the place and uh and and most
of them have dabbled in in cannabis here
and there in one way or or another so
yeah I mean that the all around the
world the quality of cannabis is is
increasing right because the knowledge
is more freely available now and I mean
there are you know there's lots of
Jamaican farmers who would you know love
to be visited by some good American
Growers and and and and have some
lessons and put them to to good use this
is a really interesting time globally
let me jump back to the cppy yeah let's
talk about the cppy a little bit yeah
yeah so what's your experience with the
crippy so I I and I I I don't even know
if it's the same thing we're talking
about right but in Colombia right there
is a region in Colombia where most of
where there's a huge amount of
commercial weed production that's still
still going on right uh there's a
village called Toria which is one of the
the centers of that production and and
creepy basically is Dutch uh hybrid
indicas right that were brought into a
jungle environment right where they
never would have naturally adapted right
um and they are and it's a 1212
environment right so first the the the
the in order to get the buds to flower
they're vegged under light and then you
turn off the light to get them to start
get them to start flowering but um but
they lose about half of half to 2/3 uh
to Bud rot before they're able to
harvest it and in order to cure it
because the the the conditions in the
jungle there are so humid in order to
cure it they put it in these ovens these
gas fired ovens and actually basically
cook the wheed oh man and then this weed
is shipped to Paraguay Uruguay Brazil
and other markets in in Latin America so
amongst my Colombian connoisseur
cannabis friends cppy is a is a
derogatory term not a complimentary term
wow it's interesting yeah and I think
you know they say fire now or whatever
the terms are for the hype the hype
stuff you the hype weed and crippy uh to
my knowledge from mango and from Craig
coffee from High Times that have both
been on the show was that was the good
stuff in Florida and what's your
experience with the cppy I've always
loved it yeah don't get me wrong but I
never could put a handle on it where to
get it or find it you know and I mean
there was never abundance amounts of it
you know I mean I know Chris you know
Chris is sunshine uh Sunshine canopus
he's a real big crippy guy like he like
says like he started crippy but we know
that he didn't start
crippy but he has you know his quality
in crippy with with true Leaf is is
quite amazing yeah you know um it's I
never I never could get a handle on it
you know I wanted to I wanted to um you
know try to get my hands on like 00 lb
at a time of stuff but I never seen it
like that right so you're talking back
in the day yeah back in the day it 80s I
never heard about krippy until I went to
Columbia in
2019 this is I'm talking about in the
70s 70s crypy Totally
Miss yeah and I mean light up with Jay
and you could smell it a block away I
mean like it was so strong when you
rolled it yeah in a room you had have
the windows
open well I smoke plenty of weed like
that but yeah no it's all right but this
was
so serious like burnt
tires
yeah well it's been a pleasure having
you guys really appreciate you coming on
the show today um look forward to having
you guys again so it's a pleasure to be
here with you you know that yeah so tell
the audience where they can find you uh
if you want to find me you can find me
um at steve. DeAngelo d n g l o on I G
uh stev DeAngelo
docomo ofari Village in Montego Bay
Jamaica and that one is at R Retreats on
IG and Richard how can I find you keep
in touch with me with freed deli.com uh
deloso yeah that's yeah the way
Instagram to keep with me and to follow
me you know well this has been great I
really appreciate you guys coming coming
on the show uh thank you so much thank
you for having us thanks for having us
James thanks for uh bringing this
history to light and keeping it alive
yeah look forward to doing projects with
you guys in the future yeah
[Music]
bet
yeah
[Music]