foreign
[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James Ladd
podcast today my guest is Autumn from
cultivo from
so many things you have so many you're
like the Ryan Seacrest of cannabis holy
[ __ ] that's too much responsibility I
can't I can't take that right now
we can we can take it down a couple
notches but like literally I feel like
you are well versed in so many different
things uh we've known each other for
quite a long time long time and I don't
even know how many years yeah a lot of
experience we've we've seen different
places together Columbia uh We've yeah
been to events together lots of uh lots
of shows lots of Expos cannabis science
um good stuff and we have a lot of
mutual friends Ed Rosenthal absolutely
Gotta Love Ed and Jane Love Ed so yeah
so tell us a little bit history I guess
we'll touch on History a little bit and
we'll dive into some fun stuff but your
history how you got started with
cannabis Where it All Began
um so I got started in cannabis actually
right down the street from where we are
now off of uh Fruitvale in Oakland got
my first grow house there about 20 years
ago
and set it up with eight lights and a
tray of train wreck and grew a pound and
a half per light my first run which was
really good at the time I know that's
embarrassing to say now no that's
amazing I mean about a half you were
doing it right and that's pretty rare I
mean I think women sometimes for
whatever reason have this association
with this plant and they get better
results sometimes right out the gate I
mean I think it's kind of like a chef
right like our attention to detail and
the ability to multitask a bunch of
different things at the same time yeah
and kind of keep that mental list of all
of them sure
um really helps and definitely seen some
amazing female cultivators come out
recently where it didn't used to be that
way I don't think I met another female
grower
for probably 10 years the whole time I
was doing it yeah a new one it was a
man's world and then there was the the
rare women like yourself you know my
aunt she was growing for for medicine in
back in the 90s probably even in the 80s
uh but yeah it was definitely mostly men
yeah yeah so and you're one of those
boundary pushers who kind of had to had
to be the first in a lot of regards as
far as Consulting and stuff like that
you were the only female consultant that
I knew of back in the day well I'm an
owner's rep not a consultant so sure I'd
like to explain the difference
absolutely consultants in the Cannabis
industry typically get a bad name and I
find that one of the reasons for that is
because
they double dip they'll take money from
their clients and then they'll take
money from everything that's
incentivized all the way up that they
recommend to the grow
so the way we set up our practice was to
be an owner's rep which is traditional
in construction world to kind of back
the client get them the best possible
price and not take any incentives
sideways but yes it's Consulting of
sorts because you are guiding the
process and I think it was just
everybody used consultant back in the
day and now it's really evolved into
something much bigger yeah so I didn't
even know what a consultant was when I
started Consulting there wasn't any
there was no position called consultant
and yeah or mutual friend Ed Rosenthal
kind of pulled me up to Canada and they
were working on
what was the largest grow in the world
at the time 300 000 square foot facility
in Nova Scotia and it was the first time
I've ever met Ed and you know I met him
once here in Oakland before and then we
ended up going to Canada and working on
that facility together and that kind of
snowballed into
what became cultivo which I started for
ten thousand dollars that I basically
maxed out on credit cards and then
became
what it was was built to be which was
one of the largest design build firms in
the space certainly yeah and yeah pretty
awesome and that just as far as a
reference on time that was almost 10
years ago or maybe probably about that
maybe a little longer I consulted for a
couple years other under another company
um and became their
uh director of construction under their
brand and then started my own about
three years later yeah yeah and you've
worked with some of the biggest brands
out there jungle boys uh you know mango
you're pretty tight with mango I don't
know how much you've done with them but
you're saying yeah we
um
I I can't take credit for anything that
that he's done but we definitely have
our friend group that we bounce ideas
off of each other and what's working and
what isn't working and yeah I mean
you're part of the net FM crew we did
the net FM classes that's right that was
great that was a lot of fun and I still
still talk to Aleister all the time
still buy net offend products all the
time
um but yeah that was the uh the Fresno
Cruise so it was me you Plum dog mango
mango was there Skye was there yeah and
a bunch of other people yeah and it was
a really cool class we got really high
pretty much the whole time but yeah yeah
good fun I took good notes though yeah
me too I still have my notes yeah but I
still use a lot of NFL products that I
would never have used like uh the
four-way manifolds that you can stack
yeah I learned about those in that class
and I still like those manifolds yeah
yeah so
no and I actually talked to Aleister the
other day I'm like can we put together
another one of these classes and I was
gonna send my whole team down there and
you know learn how to use all that MCS
and stuff and um you know he's like no
now we bring the class to you like if
you set it up and you buy the system
we'll come out and we'll set you all up
and we'll train your whole staff perfect
yes they just better to do it on a
working facility anyway right totally
that was in that environment like yeah
instead of showing you how to do it in
their environment they could actually do
it in your environment and kind of set
you up exactly yeah which is really cool
it's all the pressures make sure it's
working appropriately amazing people
yeah great service yeah let's talk about
Micah I love talking about Micah you
know he's my God yeah Mike he's a very
dear mutual friend of both of ours
um they're yeah really close I mean he's
like family to both of us yeah uh you
know I started breeding with Micah and
you started growing with Micah to a
degree and we're that's that's how we
know each other the same Circle
so did Micah were you growing before you
met Micah or yeah I was growing with a
couple other friends and then several
other friends through yeah and then we I
met through Micah and my I we had a
mutual friend he didn't really want to
introduce me to Micah and then we
randomly met at a restaurant and then
had became we've been friends ever since
so that was 20 plus years ago I met him
originally in 97. okay I think 98 Maybe
I've known Micah since fourth grade
and he was
um my older brother's friend and friends
with Ryan Gatica and some of these other
guys that are all kind of close in our
Circle and um
you know he was growing plants when he
was like 16 like out in the hills of
Santa Barbara or whatever it was and so
he always had this you know wonderful
relationship with the plant and then I
moved to San Francisco Bay Area when I
was like 18.
and Micah was kind of one of the only
people I knew here yeah and uh saw his
setup for the first time which was
basically him and his couple of
Roommates had octagons set up in there
basement you know with the tube lights
and the yeah so it was probably
1998 or something like that when because
he lived in Oakland in the Oakland Hills
and we had octagons I met him because he
came over and helped him build an
octagon and we both like partying back
then and yeah and good weed and he
always had like the sour and the chem
and yeah yeah OG we had OG we had the
dog the original dog yeah yeah d-awg I
talked about on my last podcast too did
you yeah so yeah yeah that's a classic
do you still have that yeah it's still
around yeah all right we're gonna have
to talk after the show oh yeah well now
everything's got to go through tissue
culture you know it's like we're putting
everything through tissue culture to
clean it most of the stuff if it doesn't
have hot plate and veroid it has other
you know systemic bacteria and other
pathogens
so we try to keep every start clean stay
clean that's Justin's motto I love it
it's just so I know you're you're a
purist and you like a lot of the same
old school gassy stuff that I do oh yeah
so are you is that a part of your
process of bringing back these kind of
older genetics through tissue culture
and yeah integrating them I I think that
gas will always come back I think that
these things for connoisseurs they like
this you know the and the thing is some
of them may change like we have you know
the chemd was the original like super
foul gas and then GMO is just like a
brighter chemd but it's they're both
amazing it's just different and I think
these things will change and people will
breed gas but I think
right now at this moment in time people
want color it's just such a weird thing
that like they put a high demand and
high price on color that you've got to
have color in your stuff and there's
gassy stuff with color I mean even like
Jokers the strange Jokers that has a
strong gas and it's purple yeah but I
will always breed with gas and go back
towards those things because those are
the things that I enjoy the most right
and they're nostalgic because they
remind me of childhood or yeah growing
up hanging out with Micah back in the
day or hanging out with certain friends
it reminds like anytime I smell sour
diesel it reminds me of Josh yeah you
know I mean absolutely Josh would have
these pounds of sour diesel and they
were outdoor and they were so sticky and
you'd open the bag and it would just hit
you in the face you know you don't you
don't really see that as often anymore
even yeah even with the best stuff it's
it's very rare to have stuff where you
open it and it's just like this bright
punch to the face with Terps Terps and
dials yeah yeah and I remember like back
in the day
you know you'd have a specific grower
and they maybe grew two or three things
like this is my two or three things
that's it you know
um purple Urkel and sour d and then they
had you know
a blue dream yeah not that there's
anything wrong with blue dream but
people really perfected the process
because they didn't have 10 11 12
strains in one room that they were
trying to acclimate to the same lighting
and different ones every cycle it's like
you're growing the same thing over and
over I feel like the best Growers are
the ones that have really perfected that
specific cultivar yeah I mean in the
future there's going to be directions
that come with your cultivars yeah you
get it from uh you know either tissue
culture or whatever the facility that
you're getting that clone from to grow
it out or seed from and you can give
people directions like you're gonna need
more nitrogen you're gonna need more of
this and you know I think these Harvest
windows they're great like 70 days but
that's also specific to the environment
as well in the lighting too absolutely
it would be nice when we can kind of
fine-tune those spectrums I know that
there are certain cultivars that just
suffer under LEDs and don't do well
right you know and then once you're able
to play with that Spectrum along with
the environment you can really fine tune
it so I think that's I mean that's the
future yeah it's all fine-tuning and I
think it's I keep on talking about data
points a lot with people and even on the
show but collecting the more data points
we have the more we can improve stuff
including our palettes right including
the way we do lighting including
nutrition it's like data points are just
so huge I'm big on data points yeah you
know that but um you're big on taking
notes you've uh I'm a good note taker
you're a good note taker
um but yeah data points specifically
like now we've got you know we're doing
outdoor this year so it's outdoor's a
little more difficult yeah you can take
all the best notes in the world and the
next year could be completely different
yeah God's just like nope we're gonna
start in early rain we're gonna have a
you know hurricane in uh August
hurricane in August and then we're gonna
have humidity of 85 for the next two
weeks which was amazing because we're on
our last bit of stretch before
everything flips and so they've loved
this weather so far so
I can't wait yeah I just drove down from
Oregon and we had like torrential
downpour coming into California I mean I
think that's good it's good for the air
quality for sure yeah
um any rain's good for California any
rain not necessarily for plants at the
end of the cycle like those early
October rains yeah especially if you
grow really big buds and you get the
yeah issues botrytis and other things
like that yeah we're
um doing more row crop style so more
plants closer together less volume or
mass I prefer that especially at scale I
mean I I know there's guys men no dope
these guys growing these you know 20
pound plants that are 25 feet wide by 20
feet tall and really cool I mean it's
it's cool everyone's got their own style
and I'm not one to knock anyone's style
but I do feel that it's partially left
over from the 99 plant count limit days
where absolutely you know you had to
grow the biggest plan as possible you
get one Harvest a year and then they
have six plants and you're like I'm
gonna do the six biggest freaking places
plants I can but when you try to process
it and take down that mass again but try
this pathogens for sure
but then even processing it like 75 of
that plant is junk yeah you know and
you're still only pulling your top Buds
and your your outliers and then you have
all this mass in the middle that's
basically worthless right what's your
take on Autoflower
um
[Music]
flower I I look forward to the future of
Autoflower I don't think it's there yet
um
but I think it's getting there and I
think for
you know it depends what you're doing
with it if you're making extract
products carts Edibles like definitely
absolutely a place in the market for it
I'm Gonna Run them next year and see see
how we like them I might give you a call
for some advice yeah I definitely have
some autoflowers for you yeah and I
think at scale when you're looking at
doing 100 acres or 200 Acres or 300
acres autoflowers definitely makes sense
because they're very predictable yeah
and I think in the right
it's in the right place in The Right Use
they're amazing they're absolutely
amazing and we're getting very distinct
profiles and we're getting stuff that's
so much more consistent where there's
less phenotypical variation and you know
but but again I think there's more work
that needs to be done I agree for sure
yeah and it's getting there because if
you look at where it is now compared to
10 years ago it's a whole different ball
game I want you asked me 10 years ago I
would have said no I'm never touching
autoflowers I don't want to breed that
stuff yeah I was in Spain looking at
plants that were This Tall that were
yielding like seven grams and why would
you grow a seven gram plant you know
unless that's all you can do yeah
but if you grow them 12 inches apart
totally all the way down and then double
stacking Rose vertical yeah you got an
outdoor sea of green
so let's talk about Chevy volts
[Laughter]
I love my Chevy the best kept secret in
the industry was not secret anymore
because it doesn't exist right so
um yeah that was funny because
what year was that like 2014 13. so 2013
14.
Micah drives up with a Chevy Volt and
I'm like
what is this no was it was a leaf it was
originally it was a Nissan Leaf first
and then
best kept secret in cannabis because
they were reducing your kilowatt hour if
you bought one of these electric cars
for a period of eight hours which is
what it took the car to charge right and
they reduced it from
I don't know what we were paying in
kilowatt hour back then but it it was
less than half and so if you went out
and got one of these cars
the car paid for itself basically you
got a free car and your power bill was
cut in half yeah
it felt like I was everyone it felt like
we were stealing power yeah but it was
legal legal loophole but literally all
our friends within the period of six
months went out and got Chevy volts
Nissan leaves all these electric cars
yeah for these rebates and like
literally everyone's driving these are
guys who can afford yeah nice cars but
we all drove electric cars and yeah
better for the environment and you
didn't want a nice car when you were a
grower back then absolutely I feel like
that's a recent thing you know the flex
was different five ten years yeah like
you want to feel a Toyota truck you're
like so in the 90s we all had Honda
Civics and then there was the occasional
guy that got the Accord and it's like
dude you got to be careful with people
check your rear view mirrors seriously
road driving Civics for a reason we you
know we want to blend in and that was
the most popular car back in the 90s so
everybody got yeah some of these guys
are making crazy money blend yeah
they're they're driving money when you
know I mean we didn't really wear
watches back then either as much no
nothing fancy it wasn't a priority yeah
so and it was more about the weed back
then too I think to a degree yeah so
people that were in it were in it yeah I
mean
remember when we used to cure in these
jars we like burped the jars
that was the way to do it you know and
then you'd get like a box of these jars
just yeah dank is sweet you've ever
smoked in your life it was always good I
recently transitioned from jar for my
personal I went to the terplock bags
after doing side-by-side tests and I
really like terplock what they do is
they control the humidity and they off
gas the CO2 whereas like you don't get
that with the glass the only thing is is
like the the only disadvantage the
turblock is the it's a bag and if you
put in your backpack you can have squish
Buds and I like the shape of my buds
yeah but you can always put them in a
glass jar so okay so I have tons of jars
if you need to borrow some okay so you
were using the jar method for your
personal up until like oh it's up until
uh less than a year ago but yeah I've
still used jars I like jars I like the
way that yeah and then putting the jars
keeping them in a cool environment it
keeps your buds from getting crushed
yeah for one thing and it looks cool
because you can look at your product too
um but yeah now we got the infinity jars
that are UV they're black they work
really good at keeping all the Terps in
yeah I like the infinity jars
so yeah there's so many options now
that's the beauty of the legal Market
uh is the options there's options for
everything and maybe it's it's sensory
overload to a degree yeah no I remember
feeling like I was set in my ways and
not learning anything for 10 years and
then when I started working in the legal
Market I learned something new every day
I learned 10 new things every day it's I
do too but I forget about five of them
if you retain the other five you're
doing really well seriously
um that's why you got to take notes
right that's why you're gonna have those
it's so important and now you can record
it and have it dictate to the notes it's
great AI is amazing yeah scary and
amazing and you know everything now oh
yeah you can record conversations
directly to notes
so it's it's pretty great some of this
stuff is really amazing
I'm still old-fashioned though I'll
still pull out my notepad and transcribe
it later like I feel like it helps yeah
my process to to think it out and have a
notepad even though I can type faster
than I write
yeah I still take notes by hand too yeah
so you'll be able to scan them in with
AI and then it'll put them in Nice Notes
for all your friends yeah no I still
digitize them afterwards it's the best
so tell us about what you're doing now
because you're doing all kinds of cool
stuff I mean you have a show yeah
um so I'm doing
um I actually so during covid I was
working
um in about three different states
and the airport shut down and for my job
with cultivo
I was the main owner's rep I was kind of
the go-to for most of the
um project management and structure of
how these buildings rolled out and I
would take on you know four to eight
buildings at a time and I'd be juggling
a few hundred thousand square feet of
building at any given time in multiple
different states so it was on a plane
pretty much every week for about eight
years
and
then when covet hit I couldn't get on
the plane anymore and I had all of these
I usually would take all the projects
around the same time so all these
buildings wrapping at once and then a
waiting list of about 600 000 square
feet of building to pick up and I just
couldn't pick up the phone to take the
call I feel like a lot of people
reassess their lives during covet and
right I was one of those people so you
know I just I I couldn't building
facilities is such an intense process
because you're not just building a
facility you're in building an entire
business model at least the way that we
do it we have to know exactly how many
plants you have in the facility will
calculate your clones off of that we'll
understand how much you know Cuts you're
comfortable taking off of a mom and then
everything is built from the inside out
we're typically an architectural design
it's built from the outside in right
um and so you know you become a part of
the staff augmentation you become a part
of every part of the process you're the
person that gets called at four in the
morning if any irrigation system goes
out in you know Florida or something
right
um so it was a lot but I I loved it and
I
um really enjoyed my my job my career
everything that I built and
but I just got kind of tired and burnt
out at the same time so
sitting at home for like two three
months going you know I really need to
take another job here take another
client on
um and uh you know one of uh a partner
that I worked with previously that was a
client kind of said you know what are
you doing and I said I think I'm
starting a farm again like I want to
come full circle and go back to growing
and um you know that kind of evolved
into looking all over California
understanding the tax structure and all
of the 400 plus jurisdictions and what
they were doing on the local tax level
um came across Lake County for the grow
the growing climate uh the tax structure
all of it picked up these properties and
we have a 67 000 square foot
manufacturing facility which is all
solventless and allocated to it's about
seven different buildings that make up
that square footage so we've got a
drying structure that's just allocated
to drying we've got a manufacturing
component that we can run solventless at
scale and big kind of Brewery equipment
nice
um we've got Automated Packaging bagging
pre-rolls I've automated everything in
the facility with the the best possible
equipment that I could
and the idea behind that model is to
um there's so many small farmers in my
area and they're you know I talk to some
people and they're still trimming last
year's product you know husband and wife
team just so I feel like if we buy all
of the big equipment that the
corporations have
these small farmers have a chance to
compete at that level if we can bring
their cogs down that's awesome
yeah and Lake county is a special area I
was up in Lake County
I guess four or five years ago now doing
some seed production and uh yeah it's
it's a beautiful place and there's still
Boutique Farmers up there doing a great
job and yeah the environment's pretty
cool I think
there's not a lot of great restaurants
up there but there's some there are not
a lot of great restaurants but there's a
couple yeah so no I moved up to Lake
County uh packed my bags in La you've
been talking about this for a while
though in the whole Consulting thing
about like getting your own grow and
growing getting your hands in the dirt
again so the idea behind cultivo was
always to get my own facility right
um so I thought that cultivo would be a
catalyst to
entering
um you know the the legal realm with my
own facility right now
it happened almost overnight remember
like back when we were putting our
garages together you know maybe you'd
spend 20 grand yeah then Colorado came
online with these bigger buildings and
these guys were spending
000 50 000 right and then all of a
sudden these buildings went from 100 to
200 000 to build out to 20 million yeah
and it was like okay that's a lot of
plans
and so
um yeah that was always kind of the the
driver behind cultivo but
you know and I really I really love
building I loved
being able to walk away from it give
someone else the keys right like okay
this is your baby now you know
and um and that was fun for a lot of
years but now it's fun going through the
whole process again
building the staff you know driving the
race car and doing it all for yourself
too and helping other people in the
process like the you know but yeah we're
definitely
um still growing
um but our our
throughput you know would be like two
weeks in that facility so when the
licensing process if there isn't easy
necessarily no no it's a little
challenging for sure it was for a little
bit they had a program called early
activation where it was designed to help
um small farmers get to the other side
so they would give them a temporary
license and then what happened with that
is
I think everyone kind of thought it was
a building permit so they started
grading and doing major work and so the
county shut down that program right and
then made everyone go through the
process which is about
and this is you know someone who
expedites plans for a living it's taken
us two and a half years per project to
get through much different than la
LA's got its own challenges La will take
you three years just to get your power
drop
um right but yeah they've all got their
different challenges so for sure yeah
nice and you guys are planted this year
we're planted yeah we're planted on two
acres
um roughly and that's kind of our
what I would call our r d farm so where
we'd probably run Autos run different
genetics cultivars see what we want to
put in rotation nice um and then we're
building kind of another Farm up the
street uh from that and um that'll be
going in probably next next year 2024.
that's awesome yeah well you want to try
one of these pre-rolls
I do but I'm gonna
I spoke
so this is actually some Skittles okay
and uh
it's mild it has a ceiling it so it
doesn't get you too high
my business partner he doesn't smoke
weed but I started so I've been working
on these pre-rolls getting the right tip
we have the bamboo Crush in here from
organotips uh the right paper I've been
I like rice paper actually better than
these but uh I do like raw I like
supporting raw I love them or hate them
I like their you like the paper I like
the product I do well I like the company
too yeah and uh but I do like the way
rice paper tastes I feel like it's not
as harsh as the papers
so we've been working on the right
temperature to where like I was doing
real fatties that were bigger we've done
them smaller and these ones actually can
I see yep you can dry hit it are these
all um
like Knox boxes no these are all hand
rolled and we're going to have them
numbered per you know one of x amount
and you know I think it's a fun product
and it's gonna be a while before we
launched anything like this but
I uh I really enjoy the flavor and it
has if they're too wide they burn too
hot you don't get the Terps they're too
narrow they don't get as many turfs
because you're just not able to draw in
as many but so I feel like it's the
perfect balance in like the 3.5 grams is
a nice round eighth you always come with
the big bad joints and then I
watch me get real quiet really quick
I like the way they smoke
feel like
um
the flavor is the best and if you have
good flour you can re-fire to any one
point you can put it back in the tube
that it came in let it sit for a day or
even two days if it's really good you
can fire back up and it still tastes
good
yeah you're probably like the best joint
roller I think in the industry is that
is there a title for that I'd be like
every time I run into you you have like
this perfectly rolled you know it's like
sure I like to smoke too yeah and so I
really put a lot of attention to detail
into what I'm smoking
and uh but yeah there's guys that do
better professional Joy roller and
Instagram
he was on the podcast and he does really
good stuff and that's he can roll 125 of
them a day I can't do that wow
that's a lot
yeah I'm I'm really bad at rolling
joints still even 20 years later it's
like a mental block for me right so I
always buddy up to Someone Like You So
that I'm like hey you roll a joint
as long as they smoke
I mean I can make it happen but it's not
pretty totally
looks like a bent toothpick like
they're all about five to six months
pregnant yeah that's okay
they say it's better to try and it
failed than never to have tried
that's
but yeah we uh we almost died in a
private jet
five years ago the PJ incident uh-huh oh
my God you're flying out of LA and it
wasn't LAX it was uh Burbank I believe
well it was the the private jet airport
in Van Nuys there next to Burbank
airport right but we had a
wealthy client it wasn't our private jet
just uh no no no no we're not there yet
right
um
so yeah we we were going somewhere uh
and that was crazy I still tell that
story when people tell me they're afraid
of airplanes I'm like well what I
remember about it was that we flipped to
1500 feet and then we fell out of the
sky
and I remember my phone I I was wearing
my seatbelt loose because I remember my
my butt completely off of the seat in my
cell phone hit the ceiling and then flew
to the back of the plane and then my
coffee cup
so your coffee I think you your coffee
went all over you and then my coffee cup
went up in the air it said a couple 360s
and landed on my head and landed on your
head yes one in my lap I don't think I
had coffee in mine luckily no there was
because I had to go take a shower at the
airport because I was covered in coffee
but we were just taking off from the
airport
and I mean we just dropped like it was
at that moment you're like we fell 500
feet out of the sky literally 500 feet
and we were only 1500 up yep so
it's not very far no it was like a
roller coaster yeah but but way crazier
but I guess what had happened in that
area in Burbank
like by the airport over there you have
to Coast because there's all the houses
and so they actually
take up to a certain in the to a certain
elevation and then have to uh coast and
when the pilot was going up to 1500 feet
she pushed the autopilot button and we
didn't go into autopilot actually like
knocked it out or something like that I
don't remember she tried to explain the
story like three times and then the real
story came out yeah as our our buddy was
kind of new planes and was prodding
about what just happened
um yeah I know that was that was really
it was that moment where you're like oh
this is what seat belts are for on
airplanes totally you don't realize like
no if you fall on this guy you're gonna
want to be in a seatbelt yeah you can
break your neck on the roof of the plane
very easily I realized that so when I
get into an airplane now every time I
sit down buckling the seat belt
tightening it like that's that's that's
definitely your best friend in this guy
yeah for sure
yeah I totally you know I was freaked
out about flying for maybe six months a
little bit after that but I kept having
I was working everywhere so I was having
to fly to Europe and I was having a
flight of Mexico and flying all over
and so I had to fly but like takeoffs
and landings I always like the shaking
you got some Trauma from it oh seriously
I had some serious trauma for like a
while yeah I don't get it anymore but
like because I I literally had to fly
back and then two days later I had to
fly again and so I was flying but I
literally would like be holding on my
seat like oh [ __ ] like mentally I wasn't
ready for it but that was my second
plane incident by the way there was one
previous to that wow I was on a
Southwest flight now I won't Fly
Southwest anymore but I'm not afraid of
flying like I really do love being in an
airplane right I don't like Southwest
either yeah so it's going from LA to
Denver
and as with Tracy Ryan from Canada kids
you know and and uh
she's always high intensity to travel
with anyway because she's got her
daughter at home that like you know
um has cancer so uh you know we're on
this plane and I just smell burning
wires like electrical fire and
the whole plane light kind of fills up
with smoke and there's electrical wires
burning and then we the pilot comes on
and he goes we're gonna have to make an
emergency landing in Las Vegas
I was like oh my God we're on our way to
Denver so luckily the Las Vegas Airport
was right there I walked back to the
little stewardess cart and I grabbed
like a bunch of mini bottles of alcohol
like having to Tracy I'm like here oh
man we're gonna die today we're drinking
some whiskey first and so threw a couple
of those back you know landed
and it was all it was all good and fine
but I won't Fly Southwest to this day
yeah I was on a flight last year and it
got hit by uh lightning and I was like I
literally saw the lightning coming in
and the whole Sky got yellow and uh so
maybe that's the problem we can't travel
together anymore
take separate flights yeah but when it
got hit by lightning I was like oh [ __ ]
because that's bad right and then the
guy like two seats over he was like no
no no these planes are designed to let
the electrical current pass through it
and so he's like it's no big deal
happens all the time and then he went on
to tell me about the supercell that he
went through when he was Landing in LAX
one time and he got hit like 40 or 50
times with lightning it's designed to go
right through it the lighting is
designed to go right through the
airplane wow so pretty it makes sense
that
technology yeah
yeah when are you filming you guys have
another season you're filming or how's
that good stuff going
it's not it's not
no
um I'm so busy I'm working like 100
hours a week right now I'm building out
our whole facility and doing all the
construction management for it
and also kind of managing the farm and
so there was just no time with all the
development we have going on yeah yeah
you guys you put a lot of production
work into it pretty it's a yeah it was a
great show thank you I appreciate that
but yeah no I'm just laser focused on
getting everything built out up and
running
um you know surviving the California
market so to speak totally it's been a
roller coaster it's been a rough time
for a lot of people and yeah a lot
rougher than we we've both had it
although you know it's still been tough
yeah there's still a lot of navigating
it's not just easy
yeah I think I just I remember now that
um
you know we didn't always do really well
at this and it was a struggle for a long
time just getting started getting going
making cultivation make sense being the
you know the buyer the distributor the
sales person every part for your brand
like when you're coming up
that I don't know if I've just gotten
tougher over the years but it hasn't you
know it could be a lot worse
you were really tough back in the day
thank you you've always been tough thank
you and you really have to be to be
to get to the point where you're at it
takes a lot of toughness mental
toughness
attitude
being able to say no yes those kind of
things I mean I think those are all
important and it's yeah good lessons to
learn for everybody
so yeah being able to say no
um when things don't serve you even when
they sound really good is is a big part
of my philosophy and just listening to
your your gut instinct and kind of
backing yourself on those plays when
they don't feel right you know totally
so if you had any advice for your
younger self that was maybe one to two
years into this what advice would you
give yourself
save the money
it doesn't last forever
um no yeah I think when back when we
were growing even small scale the the
packs were worth exponentially more so
totally running a 12 lighter was like
running a 50 lighter now or whatever the
equivalent is to to that maybe more
maybe 100 literally bigger to make the
same amount of money yeah no advice to
my younger self yeah I think
better management of money I feel like
I've really learned that in my like
later
in my career me too I think you have to
be and especially when we just had this
recent crash you know everybody did
these rapid expansions and oh my God you
know that's why we have a lot of failure
in the industry right now because people
thought that this model this price point
was going to last forever and that the
market share was infinite and it's not
whereas so many people scaled yeah so
many people scaled they got money from
the government not necessarily in
cannabis with everything even
restaurants I saw a lot of stuff that
people thought it was going to last
forever or that they weren't getting
everybody money back that they got you
know and and it's like you'd have the
the best CFOs in the world making these
calls and I don't blame them for it like
you're looking at the numbers they make
sense the expansion makes sense totally
you'll at least make your money back
like that's what everybody thought and
then everybody thought the same thing at
the same time and they all went big and
then
I saw some completed projects and then I
I saw a bunch of half finished projects
where people realized yeah because the
project took so long that this isn't a
good idea right
so yeah all over you know and I think I
get calls every week yeah like
Washington went through the second round
of consolidation like I didn't realize
there was going to be a second round I
don't think a lot of people did probably
a third yeah and there probably will be
a third and that's just the line yeah
this is how it works
no I think we saw that consolidation in
Colorado Washington Oregon anywhere you
had you know the ability to get a
license it wasn't a monopoly
um
had a saturation Point had to right
except California's over 40 million
people or 39 million people whatever it
is
Colorado is about four million people
when their program started yeah so it's
kind of like
timing a small country instead of a
state so
it's it's a difficult Market to track
even if you've worked in multiple
markets I don't think anyone expected
yeah what was going to happen
no and I think
it's interesting with these
International markets going on to see
what's going to happen with places like
Germany as they progress yeah and uh
you know even Colombia
is still I mean they've been around a
while but they're in their infancy to a
degree of the whole
legalization and how they're going to do
an import export places like Portugal
that really are banking on places like
Germany for import but if Germany
doesn't allow Portugal's got the climate
I mean that's got I would be worried
about I mean
Mexico yeah for sure that would be like
top of my list to be worried about
um and you're talking about countries
like
it it's gonna go the way of anything in
ag right where it splits off and you
have these large
commodity producers that are just
cranking this stuff out for pennies on
the dollar and then hopefully we have
our you know home breweries that are
farm to table and have that whole ethos
and Vibe behind it why people buy
organic food and why people are are
caring more about their health and what
they put in their bodies these days
right I think the same thing will happen
with cannabis at least I'm heavily
banking on it yeah me too and I mean I
think
genetic diversity is going to come back
into play things like that and then
terroir we start talking about outdoor
farms in Humboldt and Mendocino and
Sonoma and Oregon where there is like
the microbrewery model yeah they can do
them vertically integrated I'd love to
see a lot of that going on where you can
go to the shop that they grow it on site
I skunk VA from the last episode he was
talking about he's vertically integrated
and I love that and I think outdoor
Farmers Indoor Farmers but having the
small boutique model I love it I feel
like that's so much more attainable for
the average person that loves weed that
wants to be in the industry or younger
person coming in and you see that it's
much more attainable than owning this
huge mega million dollar company and so
we don't want to ever get rid of that
Boutique model because that's where the
quality lies is in the boutique and in
the you know the passionate people it's
all Boutique product and there is
product that's really good grown at
scale but there's always the boutique
stuff which I love boutique farmers and
the those are the most passionate people
too yeah
I I think it should be no different than
you know tasting rooms for wine I would
love to see tasting rooms all over our
County at different Farms where people
can come up and visit and learn about
the plant yeah and
um you know have an experience right
like at the end of the day it's all
about experiences you know and what
better way to have an experience than
smoke a good joint of someone's stuff or
be able to experience
their facility and the stuff they go
through harvesting and being able to see
big plants I think there's just
something to be said for big plants also
sure
the beauty of what a big plan actually
looks like like yeah like back when we
were uh up in Sonoma and they'd be you
know 12 feet tall by 10 feet wide and
yeah massively yeah just there is
something about it I'm I'm not gonna
yeah it depends how you scale
what things make sense at that point and
you just have to do what what works for
you I mean at cultiva we built every
model of every type of grow hydroponic
aquaponics like everything you pretty
much we're able to test out pretty much
all the differences over four years with
and you worked in almost every state too
up until recently it seemed like you had
yeah yeah we've had a footprint in most
of the legal states yep I'm sure there's
a few we've missed
yeah and you were doing licensing and
you were doing all kinds of other stuff
great stuff yeah we do the licensing I
mean by default and get in um working in
some of the more restrictive states
where licensing
you know sometimes it costs a million
dollars just to throw the paint at the
wall let's see if it sticks so you have
to have a full set of plans going in you
have to have your board and it's it's
crazy like I think New York applications
were like a thousand Pages or something
like that so crazy then they put
um word count limits after that because
people were pulling up in U-Haul trucks
just dropping their applications out and
uh you'd have to have 10 copies like one
for each reviewer and so it was just
like U-Hauls with stacked binders of of
Sops and information it is wild yeah um
that's actually my least favorite part
of the process if I had to pick anything
in cannabis that I don't like doing
anymore would be the application
component yeah I bet it's doing the
Lord's work yeah having to deal with the
people that you have to deal with too
and
people that you you know as far as what
I've seen and experienced a lot of
actually from you back in the day having
to re-educate people
about their own laws and they're they're
the government entity that should
understand it and you're actually having
to go through the educational process
yeah can you build this what is it
classified as what can we do in this
facility right and then so you can't
just flip rooms and take your commercial
kitchen and then put it into your your
grow space so yeah
um yeah I like the plan part of it I
like the construction management part of
it I like actually physically building
the facility and watching the progress
as it comes together right
um but yeah the the planning process is
always the the biggest hurdle I think at
least for me so out of all the projects
you've done which one stands out the
most favorite projects oh God there's so
many for so many reasons
um I feel like my newest project is
always my favorite yeah until I get the
next one like I don't look back there's
facilities that I'd say the majority of
the facilities that I've designed and
manage the construction
I've not been back inside once they were
operational oh wow yeah
you never get to see the actual
sometimes they do but the majority of
the time I'm I'm working on the next
thing and I'm moving on to the next
thing like I I'm I'm really passionate
about only seeing what's right in front
of me
and I don't like look back and reminisce
I'll pull things that evolve over the
years about different
parts that I like of a structure how you
walk into a gowning room how you
you know where you place certain things
it just becomes like second nature you
know right
no but so tell us a little bit about
Israel and you did some cool things over
in Israel and I think that'd be great to
share yeah I um I travel I started
traveling to Israel with my friend Tracy
Ryan that I almost died on the Southwest
flight with
um she her daughter Sophie has what's
known as an optic pathway glioma tumor
which is a tumor that wraps itself
around the optic nerve of the eye and
they have a really high survival rate so
it's not like a high risk cancer in that
respect but they also have a very high
recurrence rate it's an inoperable tumor
so as it wraps itself around the optic
nerve the child slowly loses it their
vision and so Tracy was told
um that you know by the time her
daughter was two she was going to lose
her sight completely wow she started her
on cannabis at eight months old this was
pre-charlet's web it was before anyone
was doing it there was no Sanjay Gupta
she just got all these random signs to
give her daughter cannabis and and her
story the way she tells it is much more
elegant and incredible she gathered all
these medical connections and started
doing research all over the world and we
found
um or she found this Dr Debbie Miri who
is a scientist out of the University of
technion which is Israel's basically
equivalent to MIT
um he was working within 100 million
dollar Lab at his disposal and he was
doing all this cannabis research that we
had not done here before so
we actually from her daughter's prior
brain surgery uh Tracy was able to get a
live sample and
um basically uh take it to Israel uh had
to declare it and all that stuff and
then
um we met with a doctor that was going
to take the sample put it into rats then
they pump human blood into the rats with
the same
um
mutations or same specific type of tumor
and then test that tumor against
different cannabinoid profiles that may
help fight the disease and cause cell
death around this tumor essentially so
that was my first trip to Israel and and
I met Dr daddy Mary and I I was just
blown away by him still to this day I
mean the man publishes you introduce me
to him paper after paper right so yeah
the first time I met him I'm like I will
quit my job and come and mop your floors
for the rest of my life like I just want
to learn from you
um so that you know he's kind of my
connection over there to the country and
everything else and so kind of pop over
there and see what medical science is
doing and how that's pretty amazing
works the stuff they're doing over there
as opposed to the process that we have
to go through for drug Discovery here
there's so much red tape involved that
it makes it difficult almost impossible
to do anything whereas over there most
of the studies and stuff if you want to
do a double blindfolded study is a phone
call away and yeah the government's very
supportive of everything just the
opposite
yeah here it's the polar opposite polar
opposite and the uh hopefully slowly
changing I know how I'm opening the door
for a lot of that research and and the
main reason behind it for people that
don't know is that you cannot bring a
schedule one substance onto a university
property where all of the grand labs are
without putting their Federal funding as
a school at risk even if the doctor on
the other side holds a schedule one
research license so it's been this
weird oxymoron that we cannot study
cannabis through our universities unless
it came out of the University of
Mississippi which we you know kind of
all know what happened there was a
federally funded grow that um was really
growing trash trash product and it's the
only place that scientists could legally
get cannabis from now I've heard since
then there's a few facilities that have
come online that have better product and
and actually care but you know the that
work is just starting right and we're in
a very nascent stage where
is real because it's a small country
um not a lot of people you could do
these micronized studies and at the time
I know there's more now there was only
eight license grows in Israel so you
could actually track back like I know
they did an Autism study
and they had these uh kids who were
violently autistic like to the point
where they would attack their parents
and things like that
um and Dr daddy Mary put them on you
know schedule regimen
same strain same dosage same everything
consistency grown out of the same
Greenhouse chemovar specific yeah and
then he got thank you and then he got um
a phone call one day that one of these
kids out of a year and a half of studies
had you know attacked uh one of one of
his parents
and then you got another call the same
thing so he immediately went over there
and looked at what the dosage was and
then takes it back test the product goes
to the grower did you replace the strain
he goes no no it's the same thing it's
the same thing but through a series of
conversations and tests they realized
that he actually lost that specific
cultivar and replaced it with something
very similar which caused this complete
outbreak of multiple episodes so when
you're talking about medicine that
that's that's that finite it's that
specific
and then you come back to the States and
people are just making wild
recommendations about dosing on people's
Health yeah it's crazy but luckily you
know it's it's a fairly safe plant it's
not going to hurt you well in fact we
have a lot to learn right we have a ton
to learn on that level with chemovars
it's not just the cultivar it's also the
nutrition and environment that dictates
the cannabinoid profile and so there
could be a change in their environment
like they got a new fan and it could
produce a different chemovar at that
time in Israel it was all
um Greenhouse mostly shade structures
right but throughout the year you could
if if you have lighting from the Sun you
could have a different product an end
product that had a different profile
potentially sure and we still don't even
understand some of the there's so many
cannabinoids that we don't even
understand all of them because they're
in such small amounts yeah yeah it's a
trip
yeah so I mean the future of of medical
um for the scientists that really care
and and the people that really care
um
I'm looking forward to people feeling
like they're more dialed in because it's
a different consumer experience you talk
to so many people that are like tried
that Devil's lettuce once and wasn't for
me never again almost ended up in the
hospital thought you know most of the
time it's anxiety attack from overdosing
or taking too much yeah
and and it happens quite often
the more educated the consumer the
better right like we know we can't go
buy a bottle of whiskey and drink it
um I mean you could but you wouldn't
like the end result yeah your first time
you eat it you shouldn't need 100
milligrams right although we didn't
measure that stuff back in the day now
we know and now we can eat 10 milligrams
and see how that responds or five
milligrams and see how that responds
with this yeah before you just hope you
didn't get the wrong corner of the
Brownie and seriously the wrong arm of
the gummy bear
yeah so
um continuity is important yeah so if
people want to know more about you your
brand uh where do they go
um so I'm at uh Instagram Autumn
underscore cultivo c-u-l-t-i-v-o
um we also have our Alchemy 29 Instagram
which is our manufacturing and
processing facility
um so that's Alchemy DOT number 29 on
Instagram
uh also the same as the website
alchemy29.com awesome yeah so we'll be
open in October for drawing Services
pre-roll Services we do full white
labeling we can pump out you know
thousands of bags and products per hour
so that's awesome exciting well I really
appreciate you coming on the show today
it's been awesome yeah absolutely we
have to do it again sometime I think
we're going to be doing some live shows
from farm so maybe at some point we can
come check you out absolutely yeah come
see us in Lake County
um and we've also got a lot of cool
partner farms in the area and you could
do like a whole little tour through
there would be really fun yeah totally
well yeah thanks again and I'll talk to
you soon thank you awesome
[Music]
foreign