really with ourselves on this line we
just want it to be as clean as possible
like yeah nothing touched it but ice
cubes and water
[Music]
how's it going everybody Welcome to the
James loud podcast and today my special
guest is Nate from Jetty how are you
doing today Nate I'm doing great James
how are you fantastic man I'm glad to
have you here at the facility we gave
you a nice little tour of kind of what
we're doing we're kind of really getting
ready for production here in a few weeks
bro this place was sick I'm uh yeah
kudos to you and your team for pulling
this off man and the build-out's
Beautiful the facility is awesome so
great stuff to see what you guys do here
yeah yeah so we go back a few years like
four or five years and you guys have
been doing x-ray for quite a while 10
years our 10-year anniversary is Jetty
so 10 years we've been doing extracts
and we started way back in the 215 days
and you know we started doing
CO2 and the reason we started with CO2
even though it's not like the best
extract method we just saw a lot of
people getting charges getting hemmed up
because everybody's open blasting and
you know tons of butane canisters
everywhere dumped on the side of the
road and just we thought it was a
cleaner safer method of extraction you
know fast forward we learned a lot about
terpene terpene preservation in the
extraction process so you know from
there you know evolved to ethanol and
distillate and you know live resin and
hydrocarbons and you know now it's full
circle back to rosin and solventless and
washing hash like we were you know 15
years ago so pretty amazing I think the
industry's come a long way since using
straightening irons to make the rosin
yeah yeah that was uh certainly some
rudimentary Tech but you know it got us
where we are today so totally It's
amazing And then coming back from bubble
hash you know in the 90s to seeing where
bubble houses turned you know it's
turned into rosin today and now these
rosin carts you know you know it's
pretty amazing that you can put rosin in
a carton smoke okay yeah yeah I mean
yeah like you said back in the day it
was you know before like the really the
extract craze really hit and you know
had a dispensary in San Diego in like
2009-10
and our concentrate shelf was Tiny and
the only things we had was you know it
was full melt three-quarter melt it was
all just different Bubbles and caviars
and sifts and things like that and just
right seeing the whole Evolution to
where it is today I mean we couldn't
even smoke a dabbing like we didn't know
how to even smoke oil when it first came
on the scene you know seriously we're
like putting it in joints smoking it on
coal there was all kinds of you know
yeah yeah I mean yeah all sorts of ways
and then the swing arms and the bells
and all those funky devices came in the
big huge yeah we were talking this on a
couple podcasts ago but yeah the giant
dab rigs yeah now we have small yeah you
know portable electronic ones that you
don't have to you know use a big torch
to light up yeah the whole scenes come a
long way and you know the tech has
obviously evolved immensely as well so
it's been pretty cool to to witness and
be a part of yeah it's wild it's wild
and it's even more crazy the future I
think I think it's starting to stabilize
a little bit but there's a lot of
potential for the future yeah yeah there
is I mean it's you know this
space in this industry is always full of
innovators and people thinking like how
to preserve and more terpenes how to get
a different cannabinoid ratio out so you
know we're going to see some cool stuff
in the future for sure totally so let's
go from the future to the Past we'll
talk about your uh your origin story how
you got into the industry when did you
start smoking you know teenage years 14
15 probably started smoking I grew up in
Upstate New York and buffalo and you
know this is you know before we really
got like the Beast or BC Bud kind of
that was a big thing like later on in my
years but when I first started smoking
it was like Maxi swag weed you know
seeds and stems Brown gnarly stuff brown
or green yeah not a lot of options yeah
yeah exactly exactly yeah and there was
there was options as far as green but a
lot of it didn't even have names yeah or
they called it strawberry because the
shape of it or you know whatever yeah
when we first saw like good no seed weed
I would say like that was kind button
that's what people called it yeah I was
wrong oh you got kind butter swag you
know there's no other option right yeah
the Brad mud was interesting you know it
would definitely get you really high
give you a headache too yeah yeah it was
pretty funky I mean imagine having some
of that stuff now and putting it through
some testing regimen and see what was in
it it'd be pretty pretty gnarly I'm sure
seriously well it's hard to say you know
the pesticides were different back then
that's true that's true I think they
were real limited with pesticides and
they probably used a heavy concentration
of whatever they had yeah or they just
didn't give a [ __ ] you know so I'm
pretty sure I saw some weed a few times
that was like people are like oh look at
the crystals but it's just mold Man
heavy mold yeah yeah for sure PM back in
the day before a lot of people knew what
PM was they were like oh yeah it's extra
crystals exactly exactly so when was the
first time you saw Hash Hash I would say
you know I saw it growing up like
Upstate New York it was really hard to
get but the first time I went to
Amsterdam was when I saw like good hash
and variety of it and that was nice
probably like late 90s 2000 right around
there wow um nice did a trip out there
and like
you know the the bud was impressive but
the hash at that time I think was like
really what blew me away I was never a
big fan of Amsterdam weed except for the
California stuff for American stuff over
there but like that definitely the hash
was on a whole nother level yeah I think
you guys brought a lot of game to
Amsterdam all you guys that went over
there back in the day for sure genetics
wise and everything I mean I think the
good genetics really originated here and
then you know they had their they had
their run with the seeds and with the
genetics and you know I think to a
degree they they started doing stuff at
scale long before they did in the states
as far as you know seed companies
especially yeah yeah and pushing the
envelope with stuff yeah yeah I mean I
no doubt they've had you know a lot of
influence on where we are today but yeah
I think that's kind of no offense to
anybody out there in Amsterdam but you
know I think we've always had them beat
on flower for sure yeah and Quality
quality flower I feel like we've really
had like that and just I feel like you
know in certain places of the world
there's things where you know they
originate like I feel like California is
the epicenter for Quality cannabis for
new genetics I feel like a lot of it's
you know and not that it's not coming
from other places too but I feel like
the starting point a lot of it has come
from Northern California it's the
building blocks of it oh man for sure
for sure absolutely and there's a lot of
passionate people you know I I give a
lot of credit to the Grateful Dead being
here and kind of the you know I feel
like there's some connection to the
Grateful Dead with everybody that's been
around here long enough yeah yeah I mean
I was just talking about that with my
friend the other night and exactly like
that that was a foundation and really
like touring and all that stuff really
spread a lot of the varieties all around
the country which is amazing yeah
absolutely and even bubble house in the
90s yeah you know totally totally I
really like that 90s bubble hash I mean
it was even before bubble bags I think
people were using like we did silk
screens and we were drying them on the
screen before we'd scrape it off the
screen right right hand stir for 15
minutes One Direction
they had a recipe that you'd follow yeah
it was amazing like when I you know
because I was like
fast forward a couple years from like
when I first started smoking but I was
living in Utah and we were selling
cannabis and you know a lot of the Cali
guys would bring packs over to Utah and
right you know it was great and you know
we had a very limited market we had
really good weed and they just couldn't
get rid of the bubble hash so it'd
always be like sell these couple peas
for me I'll uh give you a quarter pound
of bubble hash and to me I was like I
like totally want the hash you know what
I mean so
um yeah it was is interesting like just
how people used to do it back in the day
just from trim and just get rid of it
and it wasn't as valued as high for sure
there was a point where trim was free
like you would get trimmed for free and
a lot of us did we'd trim wet and so
trimming wet you get uh you know you get
a lot you get a lot of Sugar Leaf too
you know some of the stuff we just mix
it all in together but like we that's
how we get great fresh frozen because we
trim wet and then we just throw it right
in the freezer we make bubble hash from
that that stuff was amazing I remember
getting some amazing Hues of bubble hash
you know where you have like the orange
colored bubble hash that was just from
purple wheat or whatever yeah they're
really nice blondes too like the sour
always made that really nice blonde
bubble hash yeah yeah and long before we
had freezers the Harvest rights to you
know get blonde hash you know we were
getting some good blonde bubble you know
Keith and bubble hash that was just
pretty amazing yeah yeah I mean love
those days and just kind of the old
stories and people taking Maytag washing
machines and hooking them up and trying
to get freaking you know it automated
and not hand paddle and five gallon Buck
I mean I started with five gallon Home
Depot buckets you know totally so Five
Guys same thing with the bubble bags too
with the five gallon bucket with the
bubble bags I never I didn't like using
all seven bags or whatever yeah yeah so
it's it was a lot of work to pull all
those bags for you know not that much
reward but yeah yeah I mean there was a
point where we had a bunch of bags on it
we had a big tree in my backyard and we
had
five bags set up at one point yeah where
we are five five buckets we were pulling
yeah you could actually tie it off so
it'd drip because lift in a heavy bag
it's like just wears on your back I'm
too old for that [ __ ] now yeah it's a
lot of work dude yeah we always say it's
yeah it's a young man's job even like
with the fancy automated washers we have
now these days it's still you know
there's big bags a lot of water in those
bags and just sifting through it's just
yeah so you guys are still manually
doing some of it yeah yeah there's a lot
of yeah like kind of the sifting of the
bags and things like that get in the
water to drain all that stuff's done
manually so you know when you got you
know
five gallons of water in a bag it's it's
heavy and it's heavy you know just
cleaning out the machines you know we're
doing you know 15 pound runs and things
like that 15 pounds of wet so cannabis
with well 35 pounds doesn't seem like
that much weight but try shaking 35
pounds yeah up and down for a while and
then like doing it again and then five
minutes later ten minutes later and yeah
I'm the same man I'm an old old guy it's
hard work for me but yeah the young guys
in there are just yeah they're stoked to
do it and they're all like that they're
all feeling good too
yeah and to a degree some of this stuff
I feel like it's still considered
Innovative I feel like we're still you
know I mean especially with the
automated systems that they're doing
today where you can do it at scale
because that's a long you know that's
that's a lot further from the five
gallon bucket yeah yeah I mean that's
kind of it like I said like it's still
pretty labor intensive it's you know as
far as like our solvence department it's
our biggest team for you know minimal
throughput compared to hydrocarbon or
ethanol extraction or something like
that so you know the the Manpower it
takes to produce you know a kilo of live
rosin versus a kilo of you know live
resin is drastically different so you
guys are still doing live resin yeah
yeah we do um you know it's not a huge
category for us but you know we do it
and you know the one good thing about it
is like the strain variety you can
basically put any fresh frozen you know
in a butane extractor and you're gonna
get a good product out as long as it's
good coming in where the solventless
genetics you know the rosin genetics are
a little bit harder to find the ones
that that hit genetics play a huge role
yeah you know and yield especially yeah
yield is you know
it's hard because the consumer want you
know they don't want to pay 100 a gram
for certain things yeah and you can't
charge them more necessarily for stuff
that doesn't yield as well yeah they
don't see that you know it's hard to do
that there's a few brands that have
pulled that off but it's a it's a tough
thing to do and ultimately you're just
seeing
you know when you look at the data it's
unfortunate but you know the more price
conscious Brands and value Brands and
value products are what's kind of
pulling off the shelves these days
especially in with the recession and all
that stuff you know yeah people don't
have as much money anymore and some are
willing to sacrifice quality for
quantity yeah yeah I'd say the majority
of the consumers are like that
unfortunately so yeah we're just really
trying to you know a big Focus for us
with the solventless play is getting you
know stuff that hits at least four
percent to wash and if we can do that we
can keep our price point like
somewhat competitive with everybody else
so what's your opinion on live resin
versus live rosin I've seen coas
comparing the two where you actually get
more more terpenes obviously water
soluble terpenes get lost in the mix
when you're washing but uh what's your
opinion on the whole thing yeah man I
mean you know I'm not like religiously
you know one way or the other I want a
good product at the end of the day I
want something that tastes good there's
certain profiles and certain strains
that I think come out great with
hydrocarbon we just one Emerald cup for
first place for our Super Lemon Haze
which is classic strain well that would
never come out in the wash we would
never be able to like taste that strain
that way if we didn't run it through
hydrocarbon so right so you know just
having the optionality to do both I
think is good and just kind of doing the
plant Justice and you know again it's
like as long as you're doing it right
it's purged right it's clean it's safe
at the end of the day you know I really
have no problem with it but it tastes
amazing yeah that's my opinion it's all
about dude put a blindfold on and like
what tastes good and yeah you know it's
clean you know it's good but that said I
don't know there's just something just I
I think even in the analytics like what
we're seeing you know they're only
testing for 40 something terpenes these
days they're not testing for flavonoids
Esters any other yeah you know aromatic
compound yeah so so I think there's like
you know because there is like a
complexity to like rosin that like you
can't really put your you know the data
you can't really see it in the data but
you know it's there there's like
something really flavorful when you and
it doesn't hits hard too yeah it hits
hard you know you just have more
compounds a fuller spectrum of compounds
which is yeah I think you know does
something to your CB1 CB2 receptors
whatever up in your brain you know that
yeah that you know we're not even sure
of yet yeah there's so much new science
that's yet to be discovered so you know
yeah we got a bunch of receptors and
we're still figuring out how they all
work together it's pretty awesome yeah
and what terpene and then the terpene
Matrix with this terpene and how those
things affect it synergistically and so
yeah a lot of really amazing cool stuff
that we're just learning and still
discovering new cannabinoids like dude
with the you know now with these hemp
conversions and things like that I mean
I just feel like there's a new
cannabinoid I see out at in they're in
gas stations and wherever the Midwest
but I have a feeling the farm bill next
month which might come out around the
time this episode airs is gonna change
some of that yeah I mean I think
because I'm seeing that too it's like
you know there's all these different
versions of THC and it's like they're
all they're they're not natural yeah
they're you know yeah conversions some
of them are you know synthetically
derived and all sorts of crazy stuff so
yeah it's uh it's really interesting and
yeah I think we got to be like a little
careful on you know what we're doing and
how we're putting things out and try to
keep it what we're putting bodies yeah
Mama nature freaking you know put out in
the plant in the first place and those
ratios right and I I don't think there's
anything wrong personally my opinion on
the conversions like Delta eight I don't
think there's anything wrong with it if
you're using good starting material and
you're using the process correctly it's
if you're just taking pure [ __ ] and
you're you're basically converting that
and calling it Delta eight I don't think
you're going to get a good end product
necessarily yeah yeah in their opinion
powders and catalysts you know that are
used in some of those conversions and
just making sure it's clean and you know
you know a safe product for the consumer
at the end of the day
yeah I mean I'm a big fan of pure thca
you know to ingest pure it doesn't get
you high it doesn't get me high but it
you know as you get the medicinal
benefits I get the medicinal benefit of
it yeah I have ulcerative colitis yeah
it's just it's a game changer I think
nice
um yeah and Delta 8 I love Delta 8 it's
conversion I love Delta 8 for sleep yeah
and it's a fifth the strength of
you know Delta 9 THC yeah it's got a
yeah kind of intro you know because
CBD it's just like it does you don't
really feel anything you know but so I
feel some of my family members that are
like kind of new to the scene I'm like
kind of give them a little Delta eight
and it's like just kind of in between
you know like kind of the starter Stoner
well you know what I really like is CBG
yeah I really like CBG I like smoking
CBG even I haven't found really good
tasting CBG yet but I really like the
relaxing effect of CBG where CBD kind of
like just makes me tired I don't get a
lot out of just smoking good CBD flour
although CBD could I've tasted some
really good CBD flowering joints CBG
I've yet to taste any so if anybody out
there is watching and they have some
good CBG genetics that taste amazing
I'd love to hear about it yeah yeah I
agree that's you know one of the cool
things that you guys are doing and just
you know bringing these kind of
alternative caminoids breeding them up
having good terpene profiles because
like you said you know CBD generally was
hemp and it sucked and now there's CBD
varieties out there that taste like sour
diesel and totally beautiful and like
you're like holy [ __ ] man and there's
actually a market for the genetics I
think the CBD you know I think there's a
market for everything for the flower for
the genetics for all of that like good
high-end CBD flower that's smokable like
there's a huge Market of people that if
it tastes great and they had access to
it and they knew about it they would buy
it bro yeah I mean you know tobacco is
one thing but yeah if you can smoke more
of a medicinal herb and yeah you don't
get high or a little relaxed just like
you're smoking a square or freaking
Newport whatever but it's yeah way
healthier for you like why wouldn't you
you know so I think there's a you know
we can talk conspiracy and big tobacco
and all that stuff later but sure you
know I'm sure they're a little scared or
also trying to get in the game you know
natural Menthol CBG there you go yeah I
mean those are things that can be bred
in for sure I've seen Menthol come out a
lot in cannabis you know we used to Cull
most of this the Menthol stuff because I
feel like Menthol isn't necessarily
desirable characteristic so because it
can throw off all kinds of other stuff
interesting interesting so is that just
a terpene I don't think I I think it's
more in line with a thile okay than a
terpene but it could be terpene specific
yeah I'm not sure we'd need to identify
CEOs because we just usually you know
it's not like I'm looking at the CIA and
pulling them I'm just pulling them
because I'm like yeah yeah that's it
yeah more just more analytics more
standards because yeah like you know for
you know what are we testing 20
cannabinoids and 44 terpenes like it's
just the tip of the iceberg well and not
all terpenes are created equal so you
can have one that's in high
concentration that basically
that is that you don't taste very much
of whereas something in a small
concentration is super super potent and
pungent yeah yeah and we're seeing that
like you know in a lot of the extracts
we do and you know the more we can
preserve the monos through our process
like yeah they're minor but they make a
big difference in how everything tastes
versus like we can tell if we added a
little bit more heat to the press or
this that and the other thing you know
it's just like night and day as far as
flavor goes you want to talk about the
jar Tech a little bit basically taking I
mean
the simple rudimentary way is just
taking live rosin you want to D
basically to put anything in a vape you
need it decarboxylated so getting the
oil to the red consistency the more thca
you leave in your product in a vape you
know more poorly it's going to function
so we want to
you know decarboxylate that oil
um with while preserving the terpenes
like that's kind of the art in it right
so
um you know with jar Tech
take the rosin put it in the jar heat it
up slowly some people eat it fast you
know you have your own kind of recipe as
a chef you would know you know just sure
certain things certain heat certain
pressure yeah so you know kind of figure
that out but it's pretty amazing yeah
that's what I mean that you know it's
like the building blocks are still there
from like the old school methods we're
doing especially on the wash and things
like that but you know just little you
know and these are things that are
pretty common I think as far as you know
you talk to you know people that work
and you know the chemistry industry or
science and you know work in different
types of extraction methods we're like
oh yeah that's super simple and makes
total sense but it's still relatively
new to cannabis as we kind of bring
bring new processes on yeah I mean holy
water I don't know if you remember holy
water back in 2013 we we uh when I was
with loud seeds or we had loud seeds we
brought that to Denver we had two booths
and we entered holy water with the holy
water guys big shout out yep Mikey in
the Korea yeah yeah they they did not
know how to judge it and they appall
apologize because it was amazing and
they had given me a bunch of samples and
I was literally I had a rig with an
email and was literally pouring yeah
it's to everybody yeah you know and that
was like some of that stuff was like 30
30 Terps yeah yeah that stuff yeah that
was freaking amazing what they they came
up with back in the day and definitely
you know set the trend of the HTE and
all that good stuff but yeah when it
first came out yeah it was Game Changer
it was it was a game changer now there's
definitely other things that are amazing
as well but yeah it's it's funny all
these stages we've gone through to get
to where we're at now yeah exactly and
yeah that's what's exciting about you
know keeps us I think all charged up for
the Futures new genetics new strands new
profiles new tech I think we've figured
out a lot of the tech now it's like okay
let's get the genetics dialed in and
then they may come out with new tech in
the future that's kind of really what we
you know we would talk about that
internally like what's the new tech is
there a new thing coming out and it's
just like what we're all excited about
is like what are the new profiles like
you know like we were talking earlier
just you know what are you breeding that
you know you can finish a little quicker
as a different profile because we're all
freaking sick of GMO and you know all
kind of the normal hash strains totally
so what do you think the new flavors are
for hash the big washer is going to be I
mean I think I've seen the banana conda
banana Oreos some of some of those
banana lines yeah the banana lines are
definitely you know that one like
definitely fan favorite we've been
running different you know banana creams
banana punches and stuff for the last
couple years and yeah you know those are
the ones that always win the awards or
you know like they just have a you know
you look at the analytics too just a
different terpene profile so yeah you
know I'm seeing some more oranges I
haven't seen like citrus really come
into play so I'm curious if we can get
like I said like Super Lemon Haze not
that you know just different citruses
yeah that's a tough one doesn't really
wash that well but yeah but is it
possible yeah yeah yeah or is it the
specific
terpenes that give the resin the
structure that it has you know where
you're looking at the trichome heads and
that's a big part of it it's hard to say
we've been really kind of also geeking
out on trichomorphology and just like
the different trichome structures and
what makes a washer a washer and you
know the bulbous head and you know how
thick is the cuticle and what the
cuticle just get crushed by the ocean
water and all the resin just washes
through the bag versus you know just one
that has like the right head the right
neck stem all that structure so what is
that if you don't mind sharing or is
that I mean
you know we don't have like we're you're
still working on it yeah we're we're
we're definitely
studying it we unfortunately the market
is
slow and that costs a lot of money to do
like a really good research program and
grow out a bunch of strains and really
get good trichomorphology data right but
we have hunches of what's making washers
and we're you know keeping that in mind
with you know our farm partners and
things like that so so I get a whole
chapter in the book that's coming out
later this year on breeding cannabis
nice and uh yeah there's a whole chapter
on on and I'm trying to get as much data
as I can we're in the final stages of
the book but I feel like it's such an
important thing and it's kind of like
the future of breeding is all not not
all of it but there is a good chunk of
it that's like how do we breed for
extraction
yeah I mean you know depending on the
method I think you know because like I
said with hydrocarbon you can
pretty much put anything good in and
you're going to get a good product out
um right with you know ice water hash
certain sift certain you know you can
talk about crazy extraction methods
using sound and all that fun stuff but
you know electrostatics so electrostatic
is a new one that I don't think a lot of
people even know about but like just
it's almost like old school new school
yeah totally yeah we uh we did an entry
for that in the emerald cup it's very
hard to scale and but a really cool
process to see and do you know well so
there's the way with the the glove where
they're yeah that's what we did yeah you
brush off the glove yeah yeah it seems
like it's a lot of work yeah yeah yeah
it is but you know like I said like at
some point somebody's gonna you know
like the hair straighteners at the
beginning like somebody might figure out
how to scale it with some crazy you know
freaking scientific magnet freaking
thing or something yeah
how cool would that be yeah where you
can turn the magnet on and off yeah
totally yeah totally so yeah I mean I
you know those are a lot of things that
we've been tracking
um you know nitrogen's interesting some
people have messed around with that
haven't really cracked the code but
that's one I've you know when we were
kind of first
pitched on some nitrogen Tech it was
like we're going to bring a big giant
air gas truck full liquid nitrogen out
to the farm and we're basically just
gonna freaking blast everything with
liquid nitrogen and we're going to
harvest all the heads take all the heads
and you just leave the farm with instead
of with all the biomass that we end up
tossing at the end of the day all the
post-ran stuff all that waste material
stems and leaves Etc all we leave the
farm with was just heads and track homes
you know totally so there's some
interesting methods out there I think
that we'll figure out which one's real
and which I think that makes a lot of
sense though I think whether it's using
that that method of extraction but but
field extraction where you're extracting
on the field to a degree where you're
not having to leave and put the stuff in
a huge Warehouse super inefficient you
know we got freezer trucks and freezer
containers all over the goddamn State
it's like it's uh yeah if we could just
have the trichomes because that's the
juice that's what we're going for as
extractors um you know that would
certainly be a either way most people
don't realize how expensive it would be
to refrigerate a hundred thousand square
foot Warehouse yeah yeah it's just the
cost it's it's not cheap and yeah talk
about when you're you know the power
goes out and you know a freezer goes
down or your truck breaks down on the
side of the road and right all your
material turns to freaking mush it's uh
that's scary it's a rough one yeah
redundancies yeah life's about
redundancies I think yeah God I have a
lot of those in place but you learn from
your mistakes too and it only takes a
few of those mistakes yeah absolutely I
feel like we made everyone in the book
so yeah we'll keep making them sure but
me too me too I'm the same way I feel
like but I feel like I've learned from a
lot of mistakes that's that's kind of my
growing process have to man we wouldn't
be here if we didn't you know yeah for
sure yeah especially as you start
getting into scale it's better to make
your mistakes early on than to make your
mistakes small mistakes are much easier
to recover from the big mistakes yeah
absolutely absolutely yeah and it's yeah
there's certainly a lot more consequence
now than ever before so yeah we've
learned to you know we we've made that
mistake too and learned to start like
small batch pilot and just make sure
everything's right before we go into big
production runs totally yeah seed
reversals doing reversals making sure
you have redundancies for those those
are always important when you're making
seeds is like having some sort of
redundancy if you're making feminized
seeds because what if that reversal
doesn't happen and then you've got all
these plants that are in veg that need
pollen when they're in flour wow yeah
yeah that's true
yeah there's a lot yeah a lot of things
that can go wrong if you're not planning
for it
um you're gonna end up getting nipped
that's for sure totally so what kind of
products do you got here today to share
with us
um let's see man I you know I brought
you a couple Vapes this one is uh The
Jetty solventless it's Amarillo
um this one's in a different package
because it's ocal certified I don't know
if you know ocal but
basically we can't say anything's USDA
organic in right cannabis so the state
love them or hate them you know but they
came up with a program
um that mimics comparable to the USDA
organic program it's actually a little
more strict there's a couple pesticides
on there that aren't even on the USDA
organic list so that's good that's a
good thing yeah and um you know our farm
partner because it kind of starts with
them our farm partner Coastal Sun I mean
they've been working on regenerative
soil and organic practices for a long
time they have a blueberry farm that is
organic USDA organic certified on their
farm so they're in the practice of kind
of doing that and all that upkeep that
and just kind of you know using all
sorts of natural Pest mitigations and
all that good stuff so they're in the
habit of doing that so they got
certified and
in that program manufacturers can get
certified you know if you're using
solvents and stuff but you can't get
certified but a non-solvent process you
can so we got the ocal certification so
now we're slowly switching all the lines
to like basically us comparable to USDA
organic so that's why this one's in the
white package to kind of it's
differentiating it we're just going to
Market with it but you know it's as
organic as it can be you know or Beyond
Organic really I mean it's regenerative
it's it's it's amazing so you know I
know really with our solving this line
we just want it to be as clean as
possible like yeah nothing touched it
but ice cubes and water in the process
and um you know it's just a really
awesome
process and a really good program like
I'm just generally what I eat I try to
eat organic I try to you know same stay
on the healthier side I should be mostly
organic yeah it's gnarly the [ __ ] they
put in food dude so seriously and I mean
if you're eating bananas it might be
okay but other stuff you know it's like
lettuce yeah any sort of greens yeah you
should be eating organic yeah totally
berries berries another one that's
another one if you're eating berries you
probably should be eating organic the
wine industry or grape Industries like
the biggest consumer of microbutanol
like on the planet like brand Eagle 20
all over everything you know and then
we're eating it you know so Hamel on the
other hand they're in Sonoma and they
are biodynamic and they do not use any
of the bad stuff and I really like that
you know I I drink a little wine now and
then but Hamill is amazing I think
there's a bunch of amazing there's yeah
there's some some Hattie folks out there
doing it the right way but you know the
big box people are just yeah just
crushing pesticides everywhere mono
cropping you know it's another thing
these guys do is they're you know wrote
rotating crops and things like that so
it's just not mono cropping it's
packaged food if you're looking at you
know packaged food stuff that's pre-made
most of it is made from
I wouldn't say great quality ingredients
most of the time yeah yeah so yeah I
mean that's kind of like you know our
way and just you know I think we just
all want to live like a good healthy
life I believe food is medicine I
believe cannabis is medicine and whether
you believe it is or not yeah yeah want
to make it as clean as possible and you
know the old Cal certification just adds
a little you know we can differentiate
our product that way there's a lot of
other rosins out there you know where
it's a little more costly we've got to
pay the certification fees it's a lot
more logging and cleaning and things
like that in between the processes but
you know we're we just want to give that
to the consumer like that's the end of
the day really cool yeah yeah I'm a fan
I'm a fan of all your stuff yeah it must
give me really good stuff yeah this is
another Jetty solvingless cart and then
um here we're doing a little uh tasting
flight which is pretty cool so it's uh
live rosin we're doing like these little
half grammars
um kind of like a plate of beer you know
so you get to taste all the uh
you know some of our favorite flavors
things like that so
um just some really nice cold cure good
stuff
a lot of fun and I feel like
a half gram goes a long ways for a lot
of people like me I do cold start when I
do dabs if you cold start I use small
amounts I like tasting Terps I like
Flavor yeah so at the end of the day I
mean I like the effect too don't get me
wrong the effect is important but I also
like Flavor especially I might take five
or six well that's great to have
different flavors variety is the spice
of life right so yeah we're just trying
to offer that and that was um
you know as far as like it seems simple
but like metric and compliance and all
the [ __ ] to put four different skus
in one package right freaking nightmare
but it becomes a big issue yeah yeah
it's a tough one yeah
um but yeah at the end of the day it's
just we kind of wanted to offer
something so it's two grams total half
grams they're in these cool little like
pop back jars which actually like vacuum
seal themselves so really good for
terpene preservation so right and is
there a lot of diversity between each
product or you use similar ones or no I
mean there's you know we have all the
profiles underneath but yeah like
there's like an orange there's a papaya
there's you know something that's a
little on the sweeter side a little more
on the gassy side so we tried to be you
know as diverse as possible but that
said that's where like I'm hoping your
breeders come up with even more
diversity in the terpene absolutely I
know so what are the most popular
flavors right now that you guys are
experiencing you know it's like what do
we like and what are we smoking on and
like what is like the general consumer
and the data kind of tell you it's
vastly different
um like what the heady crew and like
really heavy users are you know on and
you know I think the traditional Market
always moves a little bit faster so
there's new strains out that
you know I'm getting but we can't even
commercialize them or get them out so it
it's crazy to me I mean not in the
solventless side but you know Fatso is
one that kind of sells really good for
us I mean GMO as much as we all like see
it everywhere
it is yeah it's similar like they're all
kind of similar profiles
um we did a cereal milk recently that's
sold like crazy
um how's that one wash though it's not
the greatest but we got it to hit
numbers nice um yeah so they're I think
there's certain phenos of it that will I
get a zeros cross that I think would
work really well but the same thing it
doesn't yield crazy the flavor profiles
and that's kind of you know we'll like
make exceptions if it hits a different
bucket on the terpene profile you know
so
um you know as long as kind of our
average yield when we're watching like a
bunch of strains in a month kind of hit
those numbers where right we're okay but
um yeah it's it's really depending on
like what the flavor of the month is but
yeah like I said I mean you know you're
talking about zyrias and you know the
new banana crosses and things like that
that are like things that we can't get
commercially yet so the consumers used
to kind of what we were I feel like
smoking a year or two years ago
sometimes right lcg yeah totally yeah
totally you know the data and you know
when you look at like bdsa and like
these big kind of like you know data
aggregate companies there it's like blue
dreams still holds strong in California
it's freaking crazy totally I made Blue
Dream crosses last year that I'm about
to release nice uh on the website I
think
people like blue dream yeah people like
blue dream and whether I like it or not
I mean as far as like
I think it holds its place I think it's
something I can enjoy every once in a
while I think the the Terps are cool the
effect is just very subjective do you
like the effect of it you know because
it's more more mild yeah it's
lightweight for sure it tastes good like
the extract tastes great
yeah and it was like always a fan
favorite for like cultivators back in
the day but I think we all just blew it
up and grew so much of it freaking 10 15
years ago just like totally so beat and
I just it it blows me Crack yeah yeah it
blows me away that you know it's still
trending and like you know when you look
at just kind of the it's a different
consumer you know where like probably
your viewers and like a lot of people we
talk to are just like so inside it and
like what's the new strain what's the
new flavor but you know you kind of look
at what selling consistently and pulling
off you know retailer shelves dispensary
shelves it's like yeah it's blue dream
and people know Blue Dream yeah totally
it's crazy you know Sour Diesel and you
know like kind of the old classics it's
funny yeah Green Crack I wonder how
that's going to go over in metric yeah
totally totally yeah we've changed the
name on that one
um a couple even when I had dispensary
freaking 10 15 years ago you know it's
like green bubble and this and that
people just were kind of offended by the
name but man that one like was another
crazy one it finished in six and a half
weeks weeks it was freaking loud it was
interesting yeah totally so I had a
green crack that you I could grow it
side by side with blue dream and it grew
almost identical like as far as like it
was a 10 plus weaker yeah so 70 to 77
days okay and but the Green Crack was
super strong you would smoke it and but
you would build a tolerance to it almost
immediately really but like if you're
smoking it all the time you give it to
your friends you're knocking your
friends out and they're like what the
[ __ ] is this but like it was like a
really short high yeah yeah that was it
too
yeah my buddy had a Fino of it in Lake
County crushed it with it it was
beautiful and that was six and a half
weeks finished so quick which was like
pretty amazing yeah yeah it was a it was
a Crusher for many many years
um you did great with that one
nice yeah I think bringing back old
flavors is another thing that's going to
happen yeah you know because I think we
still have access to either seeds or
people have preserved the genetics yeah
the cuts yeah yeah there's
you know we uh recently
got the brand into the East Coast into
New York and you know it's a slow roll
out there but like the ogs that have
been there for a while and like you know
the chem and like the the kind of old
East Coast strains
um people still are hoarding those and
have those beans have those genetics
they've been sitting on so yeah it's
exciting and you know it's like man I
kind of feel like sour got lost out here
for a while but like there's it's such
high demand right a couple guys like
with these little closets you know
little small warehouses that are like oh
just still have like that you know great
East Coast hour man it's pretty cool
before we rolled the cameras we were
talking a little bit of hop late and I
feel like sour was kind of the vector to
a degree of hop Layton or one of them
and
Sour Diesel was amazing and most people
haven't been able to ex like lately have
not been able to experience the sour
diesel like we used to get and I think a
lot of it is due to hop late and there's
viruses and also just age yeah you know
some of these genetics are sold if you
think a lot of that stuff was early 90s
like it's not like it was today like the
91 is still pretty awesome yeah yeah
yeah that's it man and that's what's
cool about what you guys are doing here
I think with that TC stuff and you know
being able to bring it back and
Revitalize those old school genetics
gonna be totally cool well and being
able to use for us using him for
breeding you know we have the nursery
model too but I think really using them
for breeding and creating new stuff and
I think we'll be able to Pivot in any
direction the market goes because it's
not always about what I like because I
like you know as a chef too I don't
always cook the food that I love but I I
love cooking for people and I love
making genetics for people and also I
want to bring the market what the market
wants and everybody has different needs
and wants and you know I think it's it's
really interesting kind of the way
the market is shaped up we're in this
place where people want new stuff every
two months well that's not going to be
like that forever I think there'll be
always a interest in that stuff but I
think a lot of the stuff will stabilize
we'll find stuff that's really amazing
and then companies will settle on that
is their own proprietary thing yeah so
and I'm looking forward to that I'm also
you know in in the sense where a company
can do that but also where a home grower
can grow his own just like how a micro
bird can grow or brew beer sure home
grower can grow his own and you know I
think the future's wide open to a degree
it's scary on some notes yeah yeah
especially if you're in metric or yeah
wreck yeah we're uh yeah we're fully
there and it is scary it's uh it's a
tough place to operate man it's you know
I think whether it's the economy whether
it's over saturation of this that and
the other thing it's
it's tough you know there's a lot of
companies laying people off and just you
know kind of hitting this other downturn
in the market and people aren't going
into retailers like they used to and
right you know part of it like we can
again like taxation things like that you
know we can kind of get into that
taxation over taxation yeah it's just
like yeah like let us be competitive
with the traditional market and you know
be able to get more product out to the
people and you know everybody wins and
then again where does the tax money go I
still see freaking tons of homeless
people out and just like it the roads
are [ __ ] and it's like it's a that's a
whole can of worms but um yeah here in
Oakland Oakland's scary yeah I thought
was scary too I mean compared to how it
used to be and I've been in Oakland my
whole life and I just don't like Oakland
anymore in the sense that it's dangerous
yeah it's freaking wild there dude yeah
it's getting Wilder and Wilder and yeah
I mean there's you know we've been
broken into and robbed plenty of times
and you know I tell people.com it's just
like yeah like you know it's not a
matter if but when your window's gonna
get smashed make sure you take your
backpack I like you know all these noobs
coming up and you know coming up from
wherever even San Diego LA or just
people visiting I'm like dude you yeah
do not leave anything in your car like
it's gonna happen you know so
um yeah it's wild I mean just stores
just broad daylight you know tons of
retailers in stores like yeah I know the
lady that was on the news that got
carjacked and they ended up catching the
guys on Skyline Boulevard yeah she had
cameras and they used the cameras to
identify the the thieves that carjacked
her yeah but I mean that's Skyline
Boulevard and that's like the nice part
of Oakland yeah yeah it doesn't matter
where you got to have your head on a
swivel out there dude for sure
absolutely but it's still a beautiful
city I mean I still love Oakland mm-hmm
yeah it is it's great you know it's home
it's been
a great Hub and like very welcoming City
with cannabis I think like
in the 215 days when we were kind of
operating then and you know I took
plenty of raids whether that be in like
Nevada County and we started the company
in San Diego and it was super
conservative there and right you know
like
they were just coming after everybody
like we had a small grow my brother had
a dispensary we converted it to a
delivery at a four lighter dude tiny
little grow five thousand scripts like a
whole Collective backing of four later
it was crazy and they still came in
raided them charged them with a felony
you know they had to get a wobble
misdemeanor all this stuff but it's just
like you know the it was night and day
so you know Oakland was always friendly
to cannabis and you know had an
ordinance for extraction it's like you
know it was I I came home and did a lot
of things right when it came to cannabis
legalization from medical transitioning
into Rec and the way they wanted to do
the green zone they looked at the PG e
bills and they basically faced the green
zone on the PG e structure they let
people come into compliance like you
could operate there you know kind of
under the medical guidelines and then
they let you come into compliance which
was cool you know it gave everybody
everybody that was old school that
wanted to give it a try a shot you know
which was nice yeah yeah I mean Oakland
yeah kind of the birth of a lot of this
stuff okay yeah yeah no it's been the
Hub and just you know everybody coming
down off the mountain like that's it was
the place to go like that's where you
went yeah Harborside going big you know
I think Harborside was like the real big
as far as also the focus that the
government had on dispensaries because
they were pushing the limit on what they
were doing they were making all kinds of
money and they were getting scrutinized
and they were the model you know and
like yeah as a grower an extractor to
get your product on that shelf back in
the day was like you know you felt like
you made it finally you know oh I have
stories they're a pain in the ass to
deal with to a degree though and they
didn't pay you right away I like places
where you go in the dispensary they'd
slap the cash down and it was like a
transaction where it wasn't like you get
a little slip of paper yeah and two
weeks later like come pick your product
back up yeah you didn't have to
everybody was back gonna get in there
but yeah saying when we I had a
dispenser in San Diego and it was very
much like that where you know would pay
somebody on the spot and we called them
vendors you guys were vendors back in
the day and come in with your duffel
bags and a bunch of different packs
bunch of different flavors and two or
three of the best peas and
anyway yeah yeah I mean Harborside would
buy some decent quantities of stuff too
though and it's amazing how much product
they move through there and how much
money they made back in the day today it
was an amazing model it was it was yeah
it was it One of a Kind first of its
kind and
um you know it's
it's interesting The Way It All Shook
out now but yeah I mean you got to give
them props for kind of breaking the mold
and you know helping you know yeah the
industry move forward well and then even
like so we can talk about Purple Heart
there was purple heart back in the day I
don't know if you went to Purple Heart
at all hours I was down south back then
but you know I knew of it for sure yeah
and so they weren't Harborside they were
doing their own thing and they were but
they were
all about helping people out they had
really knowledgeable people working
there yeah which was great they had a
good buyer
yeah I didn't like yeah I wasn't up here
that much like we were just come up and
kind of just basically were coming up
and grabbing you know this like I said
it was the meeting place everybody would
come off the mountain I'd come grab a
bunch of packs for SoCal dispensaries
and stuff like that so didn't spend too
much time in the clubs you know up here
but right
um certainly uh
a hub and an epicenter for you know a
lot of transaction and trade which was
always fun yeah when did you get into
hashmaking and all the stuff that became
Jetty you know like I said jetty's been
around for about for 10 years now in
October it'll be a 10th year anniversary
which I'm stoked on because we're still
here and a lot of people aren't so at a
dispensary 2009 10 that got shut down by
the feds sometime in 2011. civil they
gave us a letter said basically my
landlord they're like we're going to
seize this property unless you kick out
your marijuana tenant yeah so gave us a
45 day to cease and desist so we moved
all that to a delivery I kind of
mentioned a delivery model I had a
couple gross spotted up around San Diego
and right but you know when I had the
dispensary it was like talked about like
our concentrate shelf like you know
being just you know some full melts and
just bubble hash and things like that
and then towards the end like yeah 10 11
something like that you know you'd start
to see like oils you're like damn what
the hell is this like Amber oil and
sometimes it'd be poop soup like a dark
gross [ __ ] but
um we really didn't know how to smoke it
and what to do with it yet
um and then you know I saw like a really
shitty vaporizer pen like it was like
with glycol and the cotton wicks yeah it
was terrible like it was just terrible
but I still have my general yeah yeah
it's like you know this is [ __ ] cool
and it's gonna probably be something but
it's not something yet but it really
sparked my interest right and you know
really seeing like our concentrate Shelf
at the dispensary go from like
you know a little slice and a little bit
of market share a little bit of sales
and it got bigger and bigger and bigger
and more variety and more offerings and
you know it's like weird like honey Buds
and this and that and like all these
different you know uh moon rocks moon
rocks yeah all that yeah like fun stuff
like people were doing and it started
evolving and then you know a lot of like
the glass blowing homies were like yeah
we don't really blow like the [ __ ]
bong or a pipe anymore everybody wants
these rigs dude like I'm just selling
these Rigs and people are coming in the
dispensary asking for Rigs and nails and
bangers and this and that you know and
uh you know the the method of smoking
and vaporizing and dabbing really kind
of took on and we're just like wow this
is like becoming a huge category and
this is like there barely was any Brands
back then man it was just like strain
names there was a couple like Mom and
Pop cookie companies that were like
edible Brands but there wasn't really
much branding then yeah there's two big
glass companies that I remember is
Hitman Glass and silica yeah those two
Brands kind of had the most of the
market share yeah they definitely did
and like I think yeah Hitman Dougie and
like that crew definitely had a lot to
do with kind of like evolving the method
of smoking which really helped evolve
yeah
he's an amazing guy you know yeah he's
done yeah he keeps Reinventing himself
and he's back he's doing some events now
too pretty awesome yeah kudos to like
all them old school folks man they
really like helped Pioneer and pave the
way for what it is now and it's really
cool to see that Evolution like I said
but yeah really that's kind of how we
got into it is like got shut down by the
feds what are we gonna do
um let's try to find a safe way to do
extraction because everybody's either
blowing up their garages by open
blasting doing stupid [ __ ] or getting
like these crazy charges which was like
I don't know like the same charge you'd
get if you had a meth lab you would
intent to manufacture or something I
can't remember what it was but a bad
felony
um so we thought oh CO2 is safer so my
partner
um two partners back then but you know
one came in he was kind of had some real
estate money sold and you know basically
he's like yeah I'll throw down for a CO2
machine and we didn't know what the [ __ ]
we were doing so that was like kind of
the first thing was this pre-like Eden
lab CO2 or what it was right around the
same time that was the Apex CO2 so I was
like those were the two I think the
first CO2 rig I saw was an Eden thing we
had a we had to grow in a two-story
building but the tenant was like leasing
it to all cannabis people Apex had Terps
still whereas the Eden was like crude
yeah like the orange peanut butter yeah
totally yeah yeah some really weird
consistencies would come out of that
like just how waxy it was yeah the high
pressures and the heat it was mostly wax
yeah yeah totally and they're like oh I
got a huge yield and it's like freaking
30 you know what I mean so
um yeah it was certainly you know not
the best method of extraction but what
it you know once we winterized it and it
worked really well even though it didn't
have good terp profile but it got to a
good consistency or a pen and that kind
of really got us like we're kind of just
focused on extracts in general but
having that CO2 rig kind of got us you
know more into selling more Vapes and
more pens because that's the only thing
we could really make from that machine
so right it kind of evolved I guess you
know
naturally from there
awesome yeah so and that was 10 years
ago and then you started out just doing
CO2 and that evolved you did that for
five years maybe yeah probably you know
it was a couple years of CO2 and then
you know kind of went into the ethanol
distillate thing
um hydrocarbon live resin because we had
to wait for like licensing and things
like that so
um you know every couple years it seems
like we evolved to a different type of
uh
type of extraction awesome yeah yeah as
the market changed you were kind of on
The Cutting Edge of what's new and
trying it out tried to be you know like
a lot of it like I said it was just kind
of
we you know we may have pigeonholed
ourselves into a few methods that you
know looking back on it it got us where
we are today but
um
you know the good thing is we never like
over built for anything like there's
some Mega CO2 Labs or Mega ethanol Labs
that are out there that you know
basically are getting sold off for parts
right now because no one's using those
methods so we were at least pivoting
every couple years knowing there's going
to be a new trend or new tech coming out
you know yeah those are like the cool
tubes yeah totally totally yeah I mean
the quest was to really make something
that
tasted as good or better than the flower
you know so that was kind of always the
mission and why we evolved I think nice
yeah would you like to try some uh
banana Skittles yeah dude
some fun stuff so that's uh
banana OG times banana punch then back
to the Skittles and Fino hunted by uh my
good friend's house of cultivar in
Seattle okay so they're doing all kinds
of fun stuff with extraction up there
and
I'm big fan of the live resin with this
plant but it's it's very open bud
structure I don't know if you remember
Williams wonder where it was like yeah
yeah yeah totally yeah nice okay where
the Brax really stuck up in foxtail kind
of like sour have foxtails I like that
structure man I don't know sometimes you
know like the nice tight pretty nug is
cool but like
I like it when it does its own thing you
know it kind of like comes out all weird
not bad right yeah
okay I definitely get the Skittles in it
yeah
it's it's skiddly it's got banana I feel
like it's
the flower actually smells kind of
pungent but you don't get the pungency
with the extract so let me smell it
yeah it's got a little more Skittles to
it for sure
yeah and I like it Skittles structure is
always bad like
if you wanna it's a hard one like to get
to wash well right for us and hit
numbers but the bananas definitely will
work good
um
yeah there's a fine line with this yeah
there's a little banana in there I got
more of the Skittles though yeah for
sure
the plant when you squeeze some of the
Expressions it's just straight like
banana OG like that really yeah yeah
banana OG nice and then the banana punch
those plants get so big so you can you
can really see the different like if you
look at the Skittles you take the three
plants because they they definitely all
have different structure but when you're
looking at the progeny you can really
see
what uh was inherited from which parent
uh that's cool man
I don't spend nearly enough time in in
the grow room in the fields as I'd like
to yeah it's uh that's a cool thing
about the whole you know how the extract
scenes evolving and how we're
you know more in cahoots with the farmer
and the the producer and the cultivator
then
then ever before and just like you know
breeding more for
extraction and soft and less genetics
and stuff like that there's just a lot
more data sharing and like you know
we're looking at galaxies and we're
looking at trichomes together and it's
fun man
yeah and breeding for specific types of
extraction it's like gotten it's not
like you're reading for everything it's
not yeah across the board yeah
yeah so there's some fun uh fun new
stuff I think yeah that's the thing that
excites me the most is just
what new strains are on the Forefront
you know for sure you know I think Lemon
Cherry
and I think these uh gelato
derivatives
they have their place but I think I see
over in New York they're really happy
with the pith they're going hard with
like some of this the sativa varieties
these hazes yep totally I love it I
think that's great to have the diversity
I don't always want to smoke a haze I
don't want to smoke a haze on this show
necessarily done that before and it's
just like one of these joints that
doesn't have a ceiling man it could just
keep getting cheap escalated some of
them creep up you on you too so like
you'll smoke it and then it just keeps
you get getting you more High yeah I
just yeah we just don't see it out here
man I wish there was more hazes
available and there's little markets
like niche market like uh gold seal in
San Francisco they do their uh Congo
yeah Congo yeah that Congo is crazy dude
it's a good one it's a good one and I
think that that hop late in two for a
while and I'm not sure if they
remediated or not but yeah we were
you know we had uh kind of some friends
of ours operating out of our facility
Oakland extracts they were really like
Old School Oakland ogs and pick up to
Terence Tran but uh yeah they were
rocking that gear for a while always
getting the gold till Congo and it was
just man it had just such a cool profile
loved it yeah Gucci super stoned as yeah
it's it's strong it's strong in effect
but that's one where I had a I had a big
bag of it and over the period of a week
your body really starts to get used to
it and so even the strongest stuff you
can build a tolerance to yeah absolutely
absolutely so and that's one thing like
if you're used to doing dabs or you're
used to smoking I feel like the
difference between the two if you switch
to the other one dude yeah yeah I don't
smoke flour for a while I'm freaking
ripped off at you totally it's nice
smoke some Skittles and also yeah yeah
but but yeah whereas I'm the same way
whereas I've been mostly smoking flour
lately we've been going through a lot
we're doing a lot of selections and so
I'm always trying new stuff so I'm is
getting high for that for the most part
but then I go to take a dab or even just
hitting you know doing doing one of
these cold starts that I do it's like I
can get ripped off those pretty easily
okay yeah yeah totally feel that yeah
and even strain The Strain you know just
like the way you build tolerances is
another thing I think we're just like
learning more and more about and right
you know but yeah I mean I'll switch to
smoking whatever OG the whole time and
then just switch to something that's you
would think is lightweight and mellow
but it's got that different terpene
profile or whatever hits you totally
different right yeah yeah when people
ask me what was my favorite thing to
smoke is it's like I like a lot of
different things but whatever the best
is right now because it's a fresh
product that's what I like and they're
usually like always whatever I have
that's the best is the one I want to
smoke the most of and I might have a
bunch of different flavors and then all
of a sudden I get a bunch of this I
might smoke all that before I go back
into anything else yeah just because I
really enjoy it I like the taste I like
the way it makes me feel and yeah
yeah I'd say like gas man I don't know
being in San Diego and SoCal for like so
long in the early days was just OG OG so
did you see cat piss back in the day oh
yeah yeah so was the cat piss more like
OG gas or was it more like skunk like
roadkill skunk yeah yeah it's more skunk
by a little Citrus to it than it was
yeah the other way yeah it's interesting
yeah I mean there was like the SoCal
there was the NorCal yeah and
everybody's arguing over what cat piss
is and my my argument is the cat pisses
a flavor profile and I've seen it come
up as expressions and stuff A5 for
instance A5 the A5 Haze I don't know
that one is definitely like it's it's
similar profile yeah it's yeah I mean
it's cat piss
but it doesn't smoke as pissy and
ammonia it still has like but on the
nose it is ammonia yeah and that was cat
piss was like skunky ammonia without the
gas it wasn't gas like OG or Kim it was
like this foul skunky
ammonia and it would stink up a little
tenth of a gram would smell the whole
room up yeah I love those yeah there was
again a couple guys like closet guys
back in New York when I grew up that had
like that funk and it was just yeah I
don't it was like I'd walk into like a
bar or a crowded room people be like
what the [ __ ] who's smoking weed you
know and yeah like you just don't you
don't see that you don't see that
anymore now well everybody smells like
weed yeah yeah I guess so maybe we're
all used to it I don't go to the airport
and I smell weed and I'm like is that me
and then I realize it's somebody else
yeah it's so nice to be able to go to
airports and like not have to worry as
much yeah I don't know everyone at the
Oakland Airport smells like weeds yeah I
mean I've seen people yeah go in and out
of there and through TSA and they're
looking at it this that this bag of weed
and put it back and send them on their
way you know it's amazing
so what do you uh see as the future of
the industry shoot I wish I had the
crystal ball for that one dude yeah me
too
hard to say man I mean we're in like
survival mode I feel like a lot of the
you know regulated
folks like ourselves are just trying to
survive
um well you're still here that's a good
sign still here I think 10 years I mean
what's the future uh you know I see just
an actual you know it was crazy like
back in the day we were drug dealers and
then it was like a movement we're like
fighting for just cannabis to be legal
and now it's like
here and it's legal but it's still in
its infancy like federal government
might be doing some rescheduling like
that just came out which is I don't
necessarily like it they're scheduling
it to a schedule three well let's
schedule tobacco as a schedule for you
yeah that's my opinion
I don't want to be in the same category
as heroin and freaking cocaine so I'm
glad it's moving out of schedule one but
I agree with this whole scheduling
things there's it's a little silly for
cannabis I mean I think if we're gonna
do that let's go ahead and schedule
tobacco as well yeah I don't think
that's a good point you know because I
think tobacco is my opinion is way worse
for you you know and it doesn't get me
high that's what I'm saying like yeah I
mean switch the tobacco industry to like
CBD flower you know everybody's gonna be
mellow and just I don't know
not getting lung cancer it's an
expectorant you know so there's there's
a lot of benefits uh to doing something
like that yeah it's
unfortunately the tobacco industry
probably has too much money to Lobby
against going on any sort of schedule
for the DEA right yeah the last podcast
I did we talked actually the one that's
airing
when Heston we were talking about the
lobbyists yeah and you know
unfortunately there's not a lot of
lobbyists for the home Growers yeah the
small Guys small companies
exactly yeah and whether they're evil or
not I'm not going to speak to that but a
lot of them I don't think have the best
intentions no I don't know if it's like
it's it's not a
good and evil thing for them it's just
money they're looking at the money and
you know we can look at it as good and
evil or whatever and they're just
worried about the bottom line like how
can we make the most out of money that's
not always the best approaching business
people do [ __ ] up [ __ ] to make the
most amount of money so yeah when you
start focusing on money you're willing
to sacrifice things like to make your
product quality right and like you know
it can go in any extreme and consumer
safety you know what I mean like you
sacrifice that or knowingly spray
something with a pesticide you know it
was cancer-causing but you're still
going to put it on your product anyway
because it's cheaper totally yeah so
like that side of it's not great but no
it's it's not great but there's always
the thing is is I feel like the truth
comes out with that kind of stuff the
truth comes out so at the end of the day
people start recognizing the good brands
and what they're doing and the efforts
they're making towards it you get a
following and that builds up over time
that it takes years to build a brand
properly for people that think they're
just going to start cultivating and open
an extract company or a seed company and
just right off the gate it takes years
to really do it right exactly exactly
yeah a lot of these guys are just big
msos open up you know whatever
thousand square foot indoor facilities
all around the country and yeah it's
nothing good coming out of there because
no it's not easy to do man it's not easy
it's way better to start off small
and do it right yeah so yeah as far as
the future of the industry you know I
mean I think it's going to become
more normalized I think you know you're
going to be able to go to
hotels and you know on the little mini
bar menu you're gonna have your spliff
too and I think there's going to be just
more access I mean will 7-Eleven be
selling joints at some point probably In
Our Lifetime you know so I hope yeah so
you know and there'll be craft scenes in
different types of events and tastings
and stuff like that so I think I'm
excited for that side of it and like it
to normalize and people to consume more
cannabis like I think is obviously going
to be great for the world but right you
know just surviving and you know making
sure the industry stays somewhat has
some integrity at the end of the day I
think is going to be important and kind
of like uh keeps me going you know right
so if you were to give yourself one
piece of advice back when you started
looking back at yourself that you know
you've been in the industry one or two
years what what advice would you give
yourself
um
man
a lot of lessons learned I guess
I would say just
go for go bigger man like don't be
scared to
kind of step out you know especially
back in the day it was like stick and
move a little bit you know and just kind
of like we're scared to really go
forward a really brand your product and
stuff like that but seeing other people
that have come out with like
interesting branding and just kind of
like going for you know getting their
stuff out there more you know like
exactly what you guys are doing a lot of
these genetics guys and things like that
like the seeds guys have been doing it
for a long time and pushing cannabis out
into the world and I think like going
back I just push more cannabis out into
the world yeah you know yeah it's a good
thing I think it makes the world a
better place yeah I think we all do
that's why we're here yeah but um yeah I
remember getting seed packs like way
back when and it was all sketchy and you
had to you know dude send it to
somebody's house and this and that but
you know like they've been doing it
forever and just like pushing it out and
Yeah I think that's what I'd do more of
right yeah yeah it's been an interesting
process from where we were you know I
was born in 78 or 77 so from 77 even
now it's pretty wild the Cannabis
industry and still relatively new and
yeah it's young dude yeah we're talking
about I don't know who's talking about a
bit like Pro a bit comparing it to
Prohibition of alcohol back in the day
to now so different it's different dude
it's like there's way more regulation
there's you know all these govern you
know there was no OSHA and [ __ ] like
that back then four big there's four big
companies out of prohibition that were
allowed to brew beer it was the big four
yeah and they're still here yeah and
they're still here yeah exactly but it
wasn't until the 70s and yeah until we
had these microbrews coming online yeah
yeah
so that's a whole nother podcast yeah
totally yeah it's uh yeah it's a lot so
yeah I mean I think
it's come a long way it's hard to really
know what the future holds but you know
and eventually just like trying to make
good product and put it out there to the
people I think is the best thing we can
do totally
well man it was really great having you
on the podcast today if somebody has a
question on where they can find you guys
uh how can they get in touch with you
guys where can they find you dispensary
wise
um you know I couldn't say we're in a
good amount of dispensaries in
California we're in New York we're in
Colorado we're likely going to be in New
Jersey by the end of the year MSO yeah I
guess so small I mean I don't know if
like we are that but you know we're ours
well you're in multiple States so you
are technically in MSL but you're a good
Ms yeah totally yeah so yeah but yeah
we're trying to get our product so it's
very like heavy touch we're there we're
producing it in those markets you know
with partners and stuff like that so
it's a hard thing it's not like a gummy
where you just give somebody a recipe
and here you go here's my recipe sugar
this that and the other thing and a
little bit of cannabis and here's my
product so right especially with
solventless and stuff like that it's
real Hands-On so it's fun being in those
markets
so in any of those markets but you can
check our website that's got all the
good stuff Instagram got shut down last
week got back online I think the other
day so kudos to the marketing team for
getting that back on because you know
it's not the first time we've been shut
down and that's just another annoying
thing in the industry we'll think we
know will change eventually but um yes
we got Instagram back so back on back
online as well nice really cool man well
thank you for coming on the show Thanks
James appreciate it awesome stuff sure
yeah good work yeah great talking heck
yeah dude
[Music]