foreign
[Music]
how's it going everybody my name is
James loud and welcome to another
episode of the James Lab podcast today
my special guest is Caesar from NorCal
genetics how you doing good good dude so
yeah Caesar's uh
he is NorCal icy mag at Instagram he's
been posted for a long time you've been
in the Cannabis industry for how long
um I don't know like all my life really
like that's all I've ever done so Forum
days
well this is a four then but like I
would say like eight [ __ ] I must be 40
so like probably like 22 years I'd say
yeah at least something like that maybe
you've seen the evolution from I've seen
of multiple Evolutions I was like lucky
to like come up with a lot of the
Pioneers in the industry like I knew
that was a good friend of mine
um and I was just young I was like a
very like I don't know just enthusiastic
about the game there were certain people
that were like pivotable pivotal and
like within like my like it's just me
it's just weird like I just feel very
nonchalant about [ __ ] nowadays but it's
like I was very passionate about this a
lot I still am but like as far as like
when I was younger I was like [ __ ] on
fire I was like in it yeah and like I
was like hanging out with Eddie Lepp I
met him at like you know like shows and
stuff and then we went to Amsterdam
together yeah keep Ministries he's like
Soma
um Ariane um it was cool and then I just
got I also was like very observant as
far as like how the industry has played
out and whatnot I actually went had gone
out over there it was like 2000 of five
I believe we went for the Cannabis Cup
and I was just over there I was like
it's just using the states because we
have I think we were just kind of maybe
taking off or maybe I'm not sure but I
was like dude I'm paying 22 Euros for
this like a gram yeah and it's really
just a tourism thing because it's work
it was worse than like a commercial
flower it was commercialized stuff it
was probably was gonna get happen to
here and like I don't know however long
they were already doing it there because
they were just doing all sorts of stuff
they weren't even testing all day well
they don't have testing they have really
shitty growing they're not testing back
then I mean they have testing possible
now but they're also going like the
legal route too they're allowing like
legal grows
lots of weird stuff like back then the
Dutch stuff was like getting like they
could not even stay they had like a
crystalline like spray that they could
spray on it to make it like look like
more [ __ ] interesting yeah and like so
you were the tech I don't know if it was
like super shardy like
um glass I don't know I don't I can't
say I even seen it I was so foreign
the migration rights as far as like how
we were closer to um like Africa for
like durbins and like you know uh Hindu
like for like you know all those regions
and whatnot
um it was just a migration route was a
lot easier for them to get to like
towards Amsterdam area then they get all
the way over here right so it was more
typical to be able to more closer to the
source to be more closer to the source
when you're out there you know yeah so I
see mag do you still have your copies of
what I see mag the magazine oh do you
ever have copies I think I maybe got one
um I forgot I was even it was I didn't
get into because it was a magazine I
don't know
no arms right so yeah but but the
publication to set part of it though
like you know yeah so I see was
International canographic magazine and
yeah I still have copies yeah no that's
crazy yeah no I mean I was just more of
um you know just like I said just like
passionate about like showcasing what we
were doing at the time which was very
like uh minimal in a sense right you
know we were we had good weed back then
in the bay I think yeah I know I like of
course I think it was it was if you're
growing your own you were but we were
just so used to all the commercially
produced imported stuff most of stuff
was not domestically producing the laws
were not necessarily right like uh they
weren't allowing it but it wasn't like
now that it's LAX everyone's like I'll
just throw some out there like you know
50 pounds in a year like it's nothing
it's like I guess nowadays is the way
that the prices have plummeted it isn't
as much but back then you could like you
could make I remember I mean paying
close to like five I remember getting I
got I got 5 000 for for outdoor yeah for
outdoor totally Sour Diesel no I mean
this is just whatever regular stuff
it was it was literally I remember there
was times when there was it was a
drought like you couldn't people don't
there was real droughts it was like
there was no work that's the bottom line
and like so it's like yo either you have
to adjust to this this transitionary
period where like the prices are going
to adjust just like nowadays yeah um or
like no one's getting work no one's
working and then everyone kind of slowly
started going into it then
um I don't know when I was like hosting
and stuff I was on the like I basically
like first person that I knew of that
was doing like 40 rates and then but
then it was like no breaks and so I was
looking like 320 a zip you know so it
was like all right whatever like and if
people were hella mad at me like all the
like local Hustlers whatever but I was
taking all the business you know so
whatever [ __ ] yeah so let's talk a
little bit about Dosey though I didn't
know that dosey doe was your genetics I
always thought it was from archive for
the longest time
but you did you did some funeral hunting
with it like that's yeah um I mean
basically it was just an agreement where
he we were just supposed to like split
the seeds and so he gave me the seeds
yeah I did my Mark I didn't do marketing
or anything at all it was just we were
documenting already the form and the
animal
um on the the forums right and so like
when I got in the OG KB I was just told
it was cookies and I was like this plant
doesn't even look listen because the
form an animal were similar yeah the
form was probably a bad seat I don't
know this is all just speculation but
um so you know you can't quote
I think it was because the animal was
always more tightly held and like it was
known as the animal cookies from Sirius
no I mean well I I can't I don't know
what happened with that I don't all I
know is it's animal cookies but I don't
know like but serious my homie like
recipes you name but I'm just saying um
like you know he he you know he he was
definitely known for it you know but um
yeah as far as I know they were you know
when they first hit the scene everyone
was like tripping because it was like
kind of the the new coming uh from OG
Kush like as far as like the next thing
that like supposedly like the next holy
grail right and it actually still is
like you know to be honest with you like
but uh who's growing it these days
that's ironically everyone's asking for
it still totally people like not still
but yeah because everything's cyclical
you know it's like it's fashion it's
trendy you know and so now everyone
wants the original it's like the
original Girl Scout cookies was a back
seat anyways they don't even know how it
is that's why everyone's into this
Durban Poison and [ __ ] like most people
you ain't never smoke Durban dog well so
I smoke real deal yeah yeah so we smoked
real Durbin and it had Anis the German
like I have some Durban here today
actually we were gonna smell I haven't
he's at home yeah
um that um
yeah that shit's expensive yeah I mean
so this is German that I remember was
like straight anise and musk and it was
a little hazy but it wasn't like
this kind of haze where this is more
like the people the the haze flavors
that they know there's yeah maybe a
little bit of fruit in there but like
and it's softer yeah so you know because
I couldn't tell you what I remembered as
like some certain things are very
nostalgic to me but that one I remember
smoking on it yeah it really wasn't a
big deal back then though it was just
because we were there and it happened to
be something that was an offering from
Africa so check this out and tell me
what you think of that so we're gonna do
a little bit of comparative tasting
today or comparative smelling it's kind
of how I do palette training I'll do
like and Haze is a great example because
there's a terpenoline limonene that's so
dominant with the haze varieties yeah
this makes sense yeah and so that's a
softer you know that's that's got a nice
soft smell to it we got some super
silver you have super silver yeah I got
so nice
um yeah and so the next one we got is
some jack Pereira
and then this Jack is real interesting
but but different than the Durban
and then oh you got some Sour Durbin
yeah that's what I was that's what I say
this is not the actual Durban and I
couldn't even tell you this is like the
real dirt this is just fire in general
but I could see it definitely being as
far as Durban because you tell me
because I just smelt this and I told you
to make sense see so this is much more
Durbin smelling than that yeah from what
I remember but they still both have a
Jackie
yeah Jackie that Haze that Columbia
undertone right so
it's I like it I like it it's fun
and then so now the funny thing is is
like with comparative uh
tasting or comparative smelling like
what we're doing
so super silver haze now this one is by
far this is from yeah from Chris Yeah
Yeah from Christmas this episode I was
buying so I was like a lot of people
think these smell are exactly the same
but when you have them all side by side
differences yeah so you smell them and
then you go back and smell them and then
you really notice the differences
between them because the tropinoline and
limonene and some of those other
terpenes really cancel each other out so
then you start yeah totally but if you
go from that to smell that right away
without smelling the coffee you'll
notice that smells different because the
the strong Haze nose cancels it out so
now all of a sudden you get these like
it's it's like a little bit of fruit I
get on there and maybe some Earth
so it's it's interesting when you
compare because people think hazes all
smell the same it's not true there's
some stronger than I have to you have to
have seen enough to actually know the
subtle variance is Right other than that
it's just kind of like like for me I
mean runs like I don't know I'm not into
all the hype stuff so I really haven't I
see it when people come to my crib or
something that usually yeah but they go
to the club and spend money on it and
then like I see it without homies
that'll be like this is this right this
is this runs and like yeah and they all
are very simple to run so I don't even
remember whiter there's so many renames
right so the the yeah fishing and the
Renee [ __ ] is just it's gone I mean
that's prevalent prevalent a lot with
the um the East Coast Vans and [ __ ] you
know I mean like it's like you all know
where the muscle strains came from you
know for sure there's very few that are
actually gonna be able to tell you that
they're gonna tell you where to buy it
and like how it's the best that you've
ever seen and uh you know whatever you
never you've never seen anything better
and they're doing something special yeah
but they're you know they can't tell you
about the weed totally no yeah for a
while they were renaming blue dream I
remember that back in the day I was like
it was all
on the East Coast was getting like it
was just typical it was like I knew
Bubba's like I was like I could see
because there was so much was going out
there that like they were gonna start
calling it cookies and eventually I'm
surprised that they were able to do it
because I had heard of people doing that
and I was like no that's just Bubba
because I had seen some of it yeah and
um and yeah like I don't know what the
like yeah I don't even know how the [ __ ]
people are still messing with Bubba
really but you know I like the 398 Bubba
because it's good the real Bubble Kush
that you smoke it down to the roach and
it still has that gassy soapy taste I
like it yeah those are the stuff that we
had back in the day yeah you don't see
people producing that anymore
who kept the plan alive that long yeah I
think it's that that one's probably I
mean I can't say nobody did but and it
got replaced with the other Bubble Kush
that everybody knows today as Bubble
Kush that's not as good that finishes in
like 50 days yeah no because it is back
then it was 42 days pretty much like
everything was six weeks yeah we were on
it was like you know money making
schedule like those flower rooms are 24
hours 24 hours 12 hours a day on 12
hours off all the time yeah that's it
365 days a year
um excuse me um but uh and then you just
keep the bedroom stock then just keep
the flower room stock that's it and then
like mono we went through mono cropping
I mean see you green like audio thinks
like sag is screen and green when it's
sea of green which is like yeah
completely different screen or green a
lot of people refer to it as like the
trellis netting and whatnot sure is like
no we used to take uh four by four
everything was envelope back then yeah
and it was easy because it was like you
didn't have to be there all the time
because we were just there's too much
going on see you green but the real sea
agreed I mean people
oh
I guess see if
you see him flow and that was a whole
different world we used to do the four
by fours like I think it's 64 per 4x4 or
something like that and it's the 4x4
Rockets small plants yeah just like a
lot of people don't know they're like oh
like and it's it's just like you could
flip it whenever you want before you
like while you're trying to clone it you
grow in rockwool or did you grow lava
rock what what did you do back in the
day with that
did everything yeah I kind of like the
one right now
hand watering soil you know I could I'm
gonna probably set up irrigation system
like later but I don't mind you know I
always thought soil tasted the best yeah
as long as soils you know yeah I mean
it's like the beginning of personal
stuff you know so it's like I mean why
not you know like it's like [ __ ] like
it's the Rockwell for me is just more of
a it's more easier to dial in on a
commercial scale like I'm very like
familiar with it on that scale sure but
like the home tip is definitely always
like I don't know this is for myself
anyways you know for my homies so you've
been breeding for a long time I mean or
working with pollen working with you
yeah like I mean that's the same like I
mean I always looking for something
better and like all that like um you
know there's I'm never complacent with
like mediocrity
um but um but like I'm always looking
for something better and so it just kind
of came along as a natural progression
between like at some point you hit a
point where you're not really getting
you might be getting like I remember I
was even getting really good weed though
spending money at the club you know yeah
and then one time like I said there's
certain people within your life that
like are kind of pivotal and like
um in motivating you into like going in
a certain direction and I was just a
young kid around here in the city and I
remember there was like planet Earth was
on Castro and they had then they know
had the warehouse on Dorman I believe
yeah um but there was West Coast Growers
this guy from like Mendocino who came
down and I walked in that room and it
was like it was all automated like
everything like he was had like lights
on like the Turners and like they would
go like [ __ ] I was like what the and
everything was on drip I was like what
the hell is this fully automated yeah
and he had like it was the first time
that and he was selling these um the
trace stands with like this is like 20
years ago yeah like just [ __ ] that like
to this day is still actually like I
don't know not really that uh just kind
of catching on maybe I don't know yeah
it's not that far off I mean we just
used to use the little Asian
um that likes
um
like I guess stools or whatever but like
just flip them upside down or whatever
and there's still the tray on top oh you
just like yeah yeah we used to make wood
benches like we did wood for a while it
was not the most sterile but also I mean
it was just a lot of work and it was
just like when you're shutting down in
spots and moving you don't want to
happen taking I just had to do a spot
where we had to take apart the wood
tables and it was cool but destroy like
it was like a demo team that had to come
through to take that [ __ ] out right and
then I have to throw away all that wood
which supposedly wood at the time was
actually really expensive yeah now we
have rolling tables and all this crazy
stuff so so OG KB was that your first
big uh that was your first big cultivar
um I mean I I guess mainly that's the
one I remember attached just because of
the notoriety with it I totally no but I
mean it's it's cool it's a good strain
it's definitely it's a good smoker it
looks crazy it's one of those ones that
has like really mutated kind of look to
it yeah uh but it smokes amazing it's a
good breeder too so he's like yeah
that's so like basically it was back to
that um we were just documenting the
form of the animal and then it was like
oh gkv and OG KV a lot of people are
like they don't know what it even means
it's actually um OG Kush break this like
um uh like an Ode to like the to his his
handle
um because he's my homie and um so I
can't I got the cuts from him and he had
told me they were cookies and I was like
how was his cookies dude like what like
do we have cookies right here yeah he's
like no and he's he actually OG KB like
knows like cookie fam and all that me
you know they used to we used to run
like the hemp Center and all that [ __ ]
they all know each other but anyways
came into my possession
um those guys at cookie fan were all
like I don't know they raised some sort
of like flag to them or some [ __ ]
because they were bugging me about it
initially and then uh just kind of
turned into like this whole [ __ ] show
that was like really well like I just
had nothing to do with
um but that was really it it was or joji
kushbread like a lot of people don't
even know that you know and it was just
my it was just like literally just a way
to differentiate the cuts yeah it was
nothing like cool about it like oh we're
gonna make something next cool strain it
was just names just like I had a plate
that had an animal for him and OG gave
me when I finished it you know yeah and
uh that's that's it it was a way and you
can also tell the plant because of the
fact that you know the plant grew crazy
yeah you know and um Justin he got that
plan
um and it was pretty pretty battered oh
yeah yeah but he got lots of pathogens
when I I you can ask him about it I
haven't really talked to him about it
but like yeah I mean it was definitely
it was still doing all right in my
possession but I definitely wanted to
have it backed up as soon as I could
like it was just getting it was getting
older and when I had gotten it
originally yeah it was probably to this
day like one of the worst plants I've
ever seen like wow it was screwed and I
was like I floured some of it out
because I had to like bring some
flowering plants over my place and all
this stuff and um yeah it was you know
just I just it doesn't vary it doesn't
throw many like um it doesn't take
pollen very well there's a lot of like
non-viable seeds I feel like there's a
learning curve too I've never could be
my factors I'm gonna look that far into
it like I mean there's I've seen shitty
versions of it where people grow it out
and you could tell it's the right
genetic but it just doesn't look good it
looks like kind of shreds in a bag like
yeah yeah I mean like I said at the end
of the day it's all a grower dude you
know like like uh you know Powers says
uh back in the days you say you never
know the flower the power until you
flower yeah so
um yeah
um you know and then we I harvested it
we figured out that it was like all
other guys that were running the cookies
too they were like oh [ __ ] like this is
cookies like for sure this is like
something else but it's cookies yeah and
like unmistakably and then it just kind
of took off from there I never really
gave it to nobody just because not cause
like I was trying to hoard nothing I
actually gave it to homies that helped
me out like even just like moving things
or something like that you know I was
like whatever I'm just like that you
know and I don't give a [ __ ]
um people and give stuff out as much
back in the day no they were definitely
I was just never I'm never stuff close
I'm just yeah I know and that's
rightfully so you do whatever you want
to do but once you let something out
it's gonna be out like that's the bomb
on yeah it's out yeah yeah I'm not gonna
get mad you know if someone gives me a
clown and they're like oh well you
weren't supposed to do this it's like
then don't give it to me like I don't
want to [ __ ] have to keep talking
it's always been I got workers at my
crib or something you know like that old
you know whatever like my mommy's like
they know whatever they you know just
grab take some Cuts whatever yeah oh
[ __ ]
yeah I mean we try to hold stuff close
still so there's stuff that and you know
and now
it's a little different now because
everything's yeah like uh there's things
are worth a lot more money and there's a
lot you start writing contracts back
then it was like a ways I mean even the
contracts are not really I mean it's not
100 but but at least there's contraction
for all that [ __ ] I mean like you gotta
have the money for that and if you're
really going against a big dog like a
big company it's a little harder yeah
but um but yeah so um
but now there's a lot more value within
like the intellectual property that you
possess you know so plants are just like
a very
like grayish area you know so sure
things get out you know everyone always
someone's helping somebody and then
something gets out and then everyone
starts hoarding it or like you know
whatever or someone finds a seat in it
and then that's out you know I think
that's happened quite a bit over the
years sometimes the seeds are better
than the original yeah and it honestly
like it's like like you know I give
people all the time too like about like
OG KB or whatever and um they're you
know like they'll send me pictures I'm
like I can't tell you like this is mine
you didn't get it from me and I'm not
saying you had to have gotten it from me
yeah but I can't tell you out of a
picture validate things yeah yeah
because they just wanted to be like oh
like so and so said it's like it's it's
his cut and I was like whoa dude I
didn't say all that you know like it's
uh yeah but I always tell people saying
[ __ ] like Instagram doesn't tell the
whole story yeah for sure people want to
show you what they wanted yeah and a lot
of stuff looks good on Instagram but
then you get to smoke it and sometimes
the first hit tastes good or sometimes
it doesn't taste good at all tons of
stuff looks good like like I said like
all this stuff like um like you know all
this new stuff I call it like dryer Lynn
smelling weird because it's like when I
was like back in the days hustling and
stuff coming up um we'd get the pad
that's the shipment's coming in and
whatnot and um to be the gas and they'd
be the [ __ ] Bland [ __ ] right and
there would be uh some [ __ ] was just
full of powdery mildew we had no idea
what the hell that was it that was
crystals yeah you know you didn't like
that's you know and then [ __ ] people
that didn't know they weren't really
telling you they were trying to get rid
of their work yeah Jerry kuzeki was
saying he's been smoking powdery mildew
since he was four years
older than now bro like you're eating
[ __ ] vegetables of DDT least like in
the 90s and [ __ ] you know like they like
you you don't people don't understand
what what how Innovative the plant is
and how how you actually can manipulate
it and how far it can actually go yeah
and how far it has yet to go really like
once the other rules factors come into
play for sure so yeah
so you got some flower to show us today
yeah so I mean there's a bunch of stuff
um
we have
let's see this is a Dosey dose
foreign playing
I feel like moonbow
is one of my favorites like when done
I've seen it like a couple times and I I
don't I never actually got it from
Fletcher himself
um but uh but like whatever I did see
was good like it ain't and it comes from
reputable people so I I you know I trust
their judgment you know that's really
that goes a long ways to me too yeah
where it has the frost of the doci and
then you get like it's not just it's not
like Diet Skittles it's like a
complexity you smoke it it tastes
amazing you smoke it down the roaches
still tastes good I like yeah and
there's a bunch of different females
that are all pretty good yeah I mean I
think a lot of it like I said uh from
like like modern day like whatever we
know
um nutrients have a lot to do with all
that stuff for sure you know what I mean
so and like Growers you know so like you
can see the genetic potential within a
plan if you grow really well once but if
you you know you might have a if it's
really good you know I think that's the
cookies actually kind of revolutionize
stuff in a sense because it was able to
like bring along that brand name like it
was came at a time where weed wasn't
getting that much money it was on the
way down and it actually everyone was
starting to pay for seated packs again
yeah like what the [ __ ]
um but um yeah yeah no it's crazy but
like it carried on that thing is it
definitely had that that bag appeal like
and it was um it did have a different
taste uh interesting turbine profile you
know
[Music]
um
so yeah and then there's this books on
this yeah sure
yeah so floor flame I feel like it just
keeps getting better and better and
better I mean living soil he was on the
show well it's supposed to get better as
the more easy yeah right I mean yeah my
best friend is eight like back in the
days we used to toss everything so we
would never dream of some [ __ ] like that
yeah but it's really it's like farming
that's how you [ __ ] Farm yeah you
know it's like it's it's uh it's a
little more you know labor intense for
sure the Cure on this stuff is so nice
though yeah well you got a refrigerated
[ __ ] fully yeah he's keeping it below
six yeah he's doing everything right
yeah there's no like yeah
yeah
what else you got over there the poison
gushers some Chef fuel gelato dude I'm a
big fan of that poison gushers oh yeah I
like it too like I honestly like I get a
um I've had a lot of that in the sherbet
room and honestly like
I like them either way but poison
gushers usually my go-to yeah it gets
you high it gets you really high too
it's it's nice I I think it checks the
boxes for me it checks all the boxes I
feel like it's got the flavor
here's some fritter
these two right here let's see
sorry
so these are interesting because these
are my homie Nas yeah he does uh
he's does [ __ ] good work though I've
been here on that [ __ ] for like two
weeks I don't remember the gelato 25. it
was uh he he was probably he got in on
it kind of right early I remember the
23.
there was a 33 which is probably 33 and
the 40 were my favorites but the 45 was
pretty cool that was like super purple
they were all like not bad it's just
nothing like for me it's gotta be
something like like there's certain
things that did like Game Changer [ __ ]
like I see it and I'm like wow like I
like that a lot better like I would
almost make this a staple on a menu
um that stuff too that uh so apple
fritter is like one of my least favorite
genetics and the thing is is like it
smells so good and it smells like apples
you get this apple pie smelt it but the
problem is is when I go to smoke it you
don't get that Apple taste and that's
the one thing I don't like about it I
think it's great it looks good but it's
not my choice I feel like a lot of the
apples and bananas um I mean this stuff
was growing [ __ ] immaculately though
um but uh I feel like um
yeah I mean a lot of this stuff is just
like you it's like it all comes down to
basically who whoever grew up best you
know I mean like it's I'm a huge fan of
apples and bananas though yeah I know
it's got that that's what I was gonna
get at it's like um but it's not super
Appley either it's more like GDP kind of
knows it reminds me let's see Africa
yeah it runs somewhere between
GDP that's kind of I just like avgu was
probably closer down like that was one
of the I used to grow that stuff and it
was like kind of big super sweet bad
aota
all the above that [ __ ] was yeah so you
were going back that that's a way back
that that's like early to mid 2000s I'm
old man yeah I feel you so the aota yeah
I mean I think so that afghoo was sweet
and it yielded it and it was super super
Frosty but other than Apples and Bananas
I feel like that terpene profile came
through like I said it's it's uh I've
been looking to get that real ask you
back but the after that we have is
different here than it is over overseas
originally it was a big humble staple
like totally that's where I got it from
originally help me up I'm uh he's uh he
has Shepherd's Meadow he does super
great work because this is a farmer what
not he's dope
um so yeah he that's kind of how I got
into a lot of this stuff too you know
you use one of the first people that was
growing dude it won a cup in like 2006
another High Times one but one up in uh
Sonoma yeah all of the above yeah all
the above that was a good one
I mean there's this is a glitter bomb so
this is from Sans yeah so tell us a
little bit about the glitter bomb I like
that it was basically I mean it's I I
just approach everything the way I do
man it's like
um
like I I had done some outdoor runs with
OG KV and then I pollinated them and I
still have a bunch of those seats too
that I still gotta sort through those
ones though I got down to like there
wasn't that many of those gkvs in
general yeah because like there was a
lot of non-viable seeds you know
um
so I did that to a Blu-ray headband that
I did and then I grew those out and I
gave Chris the female that I selected
um Chris from compound yeah and
um and then yeah I just went over there
and then just uh I was like yeah dude
let's [ __ ] make some happen let's see
you know cross someone your males and
nice you know I didn't know if they were
you know I didn't I didn't foresee like
them taking it like uh you know as far
as marketing it the way they wanted to
Market it which is great you know yeah
they did a really a hell of a job
um but it is good weed it's like it's
eye candy it's got It's got that it's
it's definitely photogenic yeah no
that's what I'm saying it's like if it
wasn't I'd be like uh I mean I'll be the
first one to tell you you know yeah it's
got unique troops too for sure it stands
out in the back yeah you know but my
only complaint is you take one the first
hits taste amazing but down at the roach
on the refire it doesn't taste quite as
good as some stuff but initially the
flavor is amazing again that's so and
that could be grower yeah
I always default that because that's
kind of what we've always been told you
know and everyone else wants a spout
that so right but the reality is like
I've seen a lot of good stuff through
Athena like I'm not gonna lie like
there's nothing there's no reason to lie
like you know I've obviously yeah I've
tasted good weed from pretty much
probably every nutrient company never
had a complaint there's very little
I can't really I remember like good we
better than I remember bad reader that
way that's a good thing memorable when
stuff is just like you know when it's
bad it's like oh [ __ ] like uh I'm not
gonna know names but I gotta like
um I met these dudes they had a really
flashy booth and all this [ __ ] talked to
him they had like a touch screen and all
this stuff and yeah and all that I was
like damn dude and then he's like yeah
we got these pre-rolls I was like okay
cool they got like you know he's like
yeah you take some there's a couple in
there I was like all right no dude and I
was you know smoking on the way home and
then like yeah it was pretty bad I
pretty much couldn't smoke it it
wouldn't say lit so wow yeah I know I
wouldn't complain much I'm not really
excited I think if you got a good if
you're gonna do a pre-roll you gotta do
it right it's got I mean anymore it's so
competitive you want a amazing pre-roll
I mean whether it's to show your brand
off that you're just giving away or
whether you're selling them it doesn't
tell me you have to do like the whole
giveaway [ __ ] it's like I don't just
give you my [ __ ] if I really want you to
have it like yeah it ain't I don't want
no cheap [ __ ] with my name on it no
that's silly whatever you're gonna get
it's gonna look nice I mean that that
may have worked in the beginning or or
medical in 2012 where you could give
stuff away and people were happy but
people they're not gonna come back and
then I feel bad because I like as a
person that's pays for this sort of
stuff I mean it's just not cheap you
know I don't ask for prices I just want
it done the way I want it yeah and like
unfortunately that if people want to buy
it that's on them but it's going to be
quality you know and it's not going to
be you're going to get like you know
you're gonna you should be happy with
what you get
you know
I think with clothing it's easier to
it's kind of easier to convince somebody
that's good then it's more subjective
with clothing yeah no than actually then
then weed too though we can be we can be
subjective it can be everything yeah we
all have different palettes yeah and
what one person likes you know I would
say everybody's gonna like cat piss if
you give them some cat because I like
happiness but and I'm sure I'll still
try it here and there you know like I'm
not I wouldn't be going by like a pound
of smoking to the face silver haze like
I probably would you know and then I'd
have homies that come I smoked a bunch
of that super stuff I've probably gone
through a good amount yeah a lot like
right when I saw was like boom this is
like Cannabis Cup like yeah wow it's old
school yeah it's old school it's
everything I like about Amsterdam yeah
wow it's right there yeah I know we and
then um like someone like we he had like
a lot of people get like they had a um
um nycd he did Selma dude a lot of
people yeah yeah she was fire but people
still think that's like a diesel type of
like it's not diesel though that's so
far from diesel yeah it totally
frustrates me too it's like you don't
know then you know like like when you
start growing like what
yeah I bred that into the uh
sage and sour and oh yeah see that's
like that was from DNA or who was that
was from uh th seeds right they were
like one of the first shops in Amsterdam
right yeah yeah for sure absolutely they
were the first for this yeah they were
then yeah because I remember that's
exactly right around the time they had
moved out today Amsterdam yeah yeah uh
like right when I had gone out there 7
10 Adam and I are doing a drop uh Sage
more Sage Against the Machine crosses so
we wow I did the work out of promoting
it he's doing the packaging he's putting
his beautiful touches on it but yeah
it's nice yeah the same like sage and
sour is definitely very
um it's it's yeah I had my my homie had
I have another homie that when I was
young
um he had brought some weed down here
from college he I was like oh damn this
is [ __ ] I was like this is fire oh my
God I was like girl I didn't get rid of
like 10 pounds right now back then that
was a little bit like a lot that was the
best dispensary weed that I've ever
smoked like I've ever bought and I used
to go back and buy these guys in Santa
Cruz I believe used to sell it to
Harborside and it's not like sour
doesn't have the sour structure has this
very like the the way the calyx stack is
kind of like sour but it's more like
Williams Wonder one of those ones that's
yeah really pojally uh like Galaxy
almost yeah the cow is just the way they
stack is very unique yeah that stuff
smokes so good though but it's smoked
like sour like the Fino I like smoked a
lot like sour it was like a sweet sour
diesel yeah no that's what I'm saying
it's it's it's very blend blend between
both
um I feel like a sage like
I like it but when it's burning it's a
little too offensive but I like kind of
getting the whiff of it when I pass by
it's just sitting there because I'll be
at my house my homie left some of the
house and I'm like why'd I keep smelling
this [ __ ] like what the hell and then I
was like oh and I was like it's not lit
that I could smell it and it was right
there in my kitchen like
um yeah so but the sour I love sours I
I'm I'm uh like sours I would do like I
would do it for myself all day 10 11
weeks I would just do it I'm just like
really I'm just gonna put out whatever I
like and like you guys choose what you
like and if you don't then [ __ ] I just
need to find a new career I used to grow
a bunch of sour 11 12 weeks yeah every
time I never let it just go 10 I feel
like 10 is cool but like you really
gotta let it go at least 11. and I felt
like the best was 12 but back in the
days yes because you could actually let
your [ __ ] go for three months and to get
good money for it regardless well a lot
of times I'd only go one strand so I'd
want it to all finish and yeah it's not
like I'd have half oh yeah no we were
mono cropping for sure there was like
there was certain like uh Legends
ultimate Indica Lui like that was like a
super mono crop like straight yielding
we were like I said we were throwing um
Road Cuts straight into four by four
rock walls throw them in like into the
the like get them all ready for flour
throw them for like two days in there
and then uh flip well
and then by you know you'll start seeing
Roots like they'll you know you'll end
up with short stocky plants but you're
you're gonna end up with no larf it's
all like [ __ ] toilet butts right
champion dogs champion dogs yeah that's
totally that's pretty much like yeah
that's my uh like everything with my
cultivation is like tops are all
Champion nugs if you want to pay for
something in a jar you know yeah which I
do like I like it you know and it's like
this is like Champion nugget [ __ ] right
here yeah
um and uh yeah everything else just gets
like yeah processed within the best
means possible you know
and then at the end of the day I'm
learning like yeah it's it's uh it's
it's pretty competitive out there you
know but at the end of the day I'm not
really attractive nobody else you know
and I'm not trying to say I'm better
than anybody else no but it's better
just compete with yourself yeah I'm my
biggest critician you know and I don't
take offense to nobody like people keep
me up all like you know and it's like
whatever man like it ain't yeah it's all
good yeah it's like you don't like it
cool like I respect that like
yeah you know I don't like [ __ ]
avocados people like you're crazy I'm
like I like guacamole but I like
avocados no you know like yeah everyone
loves avocados apparently they got
avocado toast and [ __ ] everywhere now
dude avocados
it's one of the most popular fruits in
the world no no I mean but that's like
more new dude like I don't know I like
avocados though that's great avocados
are good on every I mean I'm a big fan
of eating avocados in the morning I feel
like yeah I just yeah you know but I
also I mean your tastes changed like I
didn't used to like onions when I was
younger avocado ice cream
um and that's that seems weird but it's
really good actually yeah yeah I just
mine to the green tea that's why I think
if you like green tea or ice cream or
not yeah yeah yeah yeah green tea ice
cream is great yeah
some Mochi so yeah no we have like um
um uh it was like we got the clothing
and stuff going on here this is like how
it comes it's a black compostable bag
yes you get a lot of your merch stuff
that you're launching I'm gonna bring it
by show it off awesome so we got our
little baller or these uh these uh clone
boxes when you buy clones from us it'll
be coming with a individually tested uh
certificate of authenticity or not um
you know basically it's popping pathogen
pathogens
Pest and pathogen free sorry
um and then you will also be getting
this for like Snips we can bring them in
these Rose vials it's cool you know ship
Snips and all you people you guys can go
ahead and buy it away
um it's the first time I've seen a snip
shipper but I mean a lot of people use
the Clone shippers and wrap them up or
in paper towels oh no the the best way
to is in a gallon baggie but that's if
you're sending multiples like for
singles that's perfect yeah a gallon
baggie no paper towel yeah really you
know yeah yeah you could just throw a
bunch of these together and send it off
like that yeah polyethylene bags I like
polyethylene bags with almost no air in
them and you can even put them in the
fridge a lot of people don't understand
those slips are pretty durable oh yeah
that was like on the cusp of like
everything kind of going a little bit
more and yeah me getting involved and
whatnot I guess and whatever I was doing
we we had some stuff called the juicy
fruit that came down I'm not sure where
it came from actually now at this point
but
it came to the bay and we like we got it
and it tasted it was like Skittles on
the level of the sweetness of the
Skittles but it was like Juicy Fruit
bubble gum like the gum yeah yeah it
tasted just like it was Juicy Fruit and
it tasted and then I started noticing
everything started getting called the
Juicy Fruit yeah dude there's a bunch of
fake juicy Foods that's gone around yeah
and I didn't I didn't know at the time
like you know like it was renamed golden
ghost I didn't realize weed was a plant
like it ain't like my mom caught me
growing weiner in her closet and she was
like she's wondering what the hell that
light was and then
um and um and she's like what is I was
like oh it's just plants and then she's
like and then like she's like oh is that
weed or whatever and I was like well
yeah and she's like but that's not weed
that's a plant and I was like yeah it's
a plant and that's and that was probably
a little bit after I figured out that it
was a plant and I was like she was like
oh wow it smells good and you know but
she never smoked we in your life or
anything she really didn't like it at
all she didn't she does not want this
for me so she started with one light or
two lights I started going into that
store West Coast Guards and I was like
oh [ __ ] like yeah whoa like damn so I
get home and my eyes was my chick at the
time
um and I tore everything out of the out
of my closet I had like a cool like
right like three by five I would say and
I was doing soil so I did two sixes in
there and I like drilled the holes in
the and I don't even know how to operate
tools I was so young you know yeah I was
like banging away it was like the one in
the morning or I'm almost trying to go
to sleep my girl was like all the
clothes was everywhere and then I had a
portable air conditioner in there
um that didn't last too long like you
know obviously my cable bill jumped up
crazy they they you know you don't think
about these things
yeah and it's creating heat as a
byproducts so the room was a lot and
then I was you know like it's yeah it's
I like I said I've tried everything it's
it's uh I've wasted a lot of money doing
it too I used to buy like I used to be
that person buying 30 bottles of
different like now things are I feel
like are more simplified so much more
simplified we used to we didn't want
recipes that we were like you know like
do certain things for us we had to like
figure out how to do it I always got my
best results from where it was the least
amount of stuff though I didn't need it
yeah yeah and then you could but you
don't want to be turning your lights on
and off every day you know like so a lot
of timers back then they wouldn't even
handle the amperage of like a 1 000 watt
light right so you know like it's yeah
they made them better but like there's
other things like you know controlling
your CO2 I was running that closet with
CO2 and then I realized I had to do a
closed loop so I was running the the air
through the lights the two 600s and then
going back up in the roof so I would be
popping it full of CO2 and then
um yeah I was running by all this
nutrients I mean I I love that stuff um
it just doesn't really doesn't hold well
in in reservoirs at all so I think the
newer by how long has it been since used
by oh that was my first thing yeah so
they've changed their stuff oh yeah of
course they were really introducing the
bio Heaven I believe when I kind of
started veering away from it wow and
then I went on The Cutting Edge and then
I like Cutting Edge still yeah I like
Cutting Edge because they're local and I
like you know and they're cool people
I've talked to them yeah and uh I just
don't like I can't I I mean needing
moving barrels of nutrients is not you
know you need a forklift for that you
know so it's like I'd rather have a lot
of powder and you know it's a little
easier it's better for the Earth for one
thing but yeah I guess it yeah I mean I
think it's better it's better for your
back better for the Earth it's better
for a lot of things yeah
um you know and and there's interesting
you know products that aren't made with
salts necessary but I like salt I think
it's a yeah you're gonna go that right
if you're not going living soil you're
going and then I try I try everything
and like there's like I couldn't say I
was disappointed in anything really if
it was it was because it didn't but I'm
doing seed production I'm using cocoa
and I'm using salts typically yeah and I
experiment with a lot of different
things but I did that's pretty much yeah
I like cocoa a lot you know like um but
like I I just don't like using
um
like the dirt that I got was from bio
365 they do a pretty good job about like
what they're doing I'm really happy with
their dirt I would use that here but I
can't do it because it's not sterile
that's the only thing oh is it well I
mean you can get bucks potentially I
mean
they have sterile cocoa sterile cocoa
and Rockwell we do rockets mostly yeah
it's sterilized yeah see back then like
I mean we didn't even we were just doing
Royal gold defaulting and we were
putting our bags in like black contract
bags and loading them and that's why I
like when powder came into play I was
like you could just do this instead of
curious
six gallon you know like three part
nutrients you know like it's like 50
pounds a piece yeah like yeah it's a lot
a lot easier you know yeah so yeah I
mean it's like I said I've tried to like
House and Garden
um
I I all sorts of stuff and three-part
um the house and garden no no three-part
oh then another the original was always
Lucas yeah yeah it was like I mean it
was the original three-part but yeah
like most people if you knew that you
know that you didn't have to buy that
that should that the grill yeah totally
so yeah like it's like you just get by
on the mic around the bloom and um yeah
and I mean I still know people I mean it
worked it's like it's not gonna go
anywhere like it's gonna work like so we
used to use Jacks like you know out of
Home Depot and [ __ ] yeah you know it
worked
Josh was good that was the blue stuff
right
I don't even remember man it was like
that's like a long time ago I don't know
if they still make it I think it's the
one part they have it in agriculture
houses you can get it in like a lot yeah
yeah and it worked I could like that's
why I kind of really want to do these
blind taste tests where I would
purposely use that sort of stuff and
then you know for sure and it's like
there's no names attached it's a
completely blind like and it's just a
hangout like I'll we'll have an event
we'll have a hangout everyone will be
chilling smugging whatever comparing
notes you know maybe have a
questionnaire with each one like checks
and boxes you know and then they all get
thrown in and then the results get
calculated by a computer yeah you know
about the numbers and then we go by that
that's what people chose and so if you
don't like it minority yeah I mean
that's the thing is I never get got like
there was there's always some sort of uh
clandestine like
um
like sort of uh like what I don't know
like it was just it was always like very
like hell there was always events that I
feel like were held out of uh like out
of the public you know yeah like and I
just want to keep everything like
everyone shows up with their Harvest
like freshly cured you know growing all
my strains we see how it's grown we can
compare notes on who's growing what
right and all kind of help each other
grow better you know you know so I'm
just looking for like a venue at the
moment and um get started on that have
like a lounge you know really like
ultimately like uh you know I don't I
don't really go out much
um and I smoke a lot of weed now like a
lot more yeah you know I just I'm not
drink less smoke more I don't drink at
all but yeah that's great once you stop
drinking you realize how much it costs
and you're like damn like how much money
you can save money yeah I know man all
my meals are like less than half off I'm
like what and then you know that's right
that's one thing but before it was like
oh I'm waiting at the airport all right
I have a drink everything was a drink oh
it's like soda now to have a drink you
know but like it just adds up and like
really it's not a good look yeah I'm
still trying not to drink I don't drink
a lot I drink now and then but like even
flying everything in my first class and
they offer you a free drink it's like I
was free drink but yeah that was a
problem too it's like I was on a plane
so much I was yeah I would be in you
know yeah yeah so it was and you can be
smoking so but either way I'm looking at
venues currently and whatnot and like
you know uh we're going for things to
like take a little I'm gonna find the
right place do you think you'll get a
lounge in San Francisco or Bay Area I
would like to I mean that's where I'm at
you know yeah so yeah it's not cheap
though but it's not cheap I don't know I
feel like it's getting cheaper I mean I
don't plan on making money I mean a lot
of people ask me like like about like oh
how are you gonna make money dude I'm
like I don't think about throwing
anything to make money I mean I might
bring stuff and like if you know it's a
cool place to like showcase things but
I'm not really a Salesman like that's
like if I see things that I want them
I'll I'll get them if yeah you know if
they catch mine so that's why you know
people like what they're what they're
grabbing you know yeah so it's like you
know I appreciate the support always but
um like yeah like I mean it's it's like
if I could break even at the end of the
month you know and like if I throw in
the like having a Friday Saturday going
chilling there at nights bring my dogs
maybe you know like freaking even is
tough because if you end up losing a bad
month and it's like you I don't know I
lose all the [ __ ] goddamn time yeah I
probably lost more money than I mean you
know it's just like I just disappointed
I just do whatever I want to do and I
mean things kind of you do good work and
you do work you know you're still here
you're still here you're still
passionate a lot of people threw in the
towel I mean I've seen them as a reality
like I don't I I don't I don't even if I
didn't make any money off of wheat I
don't I mean
I mean I I like I I like it you know
yeah you're passionate about it yeah
like it's like it's one of those things
part of you I don't see me taking on
another career where I would literally
go into like reading every I never read
a book in my life probably before it's
ever I stuck by school never reading a
book I mean he's doing like Goosebumps
or something but
um you know I read every publication out
on this uh you know Jorge Cervantes all
the weed books but everybody never even
knew it was Robert Connell Clark you
know yeah uh because her horse cervante
was Robert right no no Robert Connell
Clark is Rob there's a there's
Cervantes yeah it's a gym it's Mel Mel
Frank
yes yeah okay yeah yeah yeah because
yeah
yeah okay yeah so I got it mixed up yeah
but those guys and Ed you know they put
out the girl books back in the day yeah
those were those were all great they
were all good they were all interesting
I mean I think some of the stuff is
outdated of course but you know I mean
that's of course it was the beginning of
an industry you know yeah emergency
stages you know what I mean like yeah
but some of the stuff still holds true a
lot of it is really nostalgic for me you
know I'm still working on my breeding
book I think we're hoping that it's done
yeah the last thing came out the Greg
Green's breeders Bible I think yeah I
read I got a breeding book that's that's
full-on reading everything about
breeding it's you know we got a lot of
uh pictures that are going in that our
photographers Julie dialed in so it's
building the facility at the same time
is really helpful when you're writing a
book because you can do step by step and
actually show the the parts the cutting
clones you can show that you can show
germinating seeds and all this stuff so
yeah no I'm very big on like taking
pictures of things that are progressing
and then you can kind of go back and
pick whether you even want to put it up
or we you know what you want totally and
showing your work isn't a bad thing I
feel like showing your work showing that
you're actually doing the breeding
you're doing the work you're doing the
phenotes all that stuff is great you
know people can talk about it all day
but show your work yeah no I mean it's
like and honestly like I I like I'm not
like you said about the whole breeder
question like I wouldn't consider myself
a reader I breed strains I don't I look
for better and I do what a typical
breeder would
um you know but I'm I don't really spend
too much time like making lines and all
that I just kind of visit things and if
they work and I like it then you know
whatever I'd actually rather spread it
out and get it to people you know yeah
like I said like with my weed like I
have you know my homies come through I
want to see what they got to say about
it you know like it's like I don't want
to smoke it all in my face but you're
looking for winners and you're popping
seeds yeah well that's why I buy this
too so it's like I want to know what you
think about about these winners some
people are like oh this kind of smells
black and I'm like but it's good weed
and it's like the hardest part about
breeding is actually finding the winners
you know I mean at the end of the day
that's the real yeah
like you know you know more losers than
I see winners like that's the one thing
like I'll post about regret room
failures like you know or like pests
whatever final product like you know
like it's like it's um
yeah it's it's it's you it's it's very
subjective as far as like um which what
you're gonna get well there's Keepers
and winners and then there's complete
like that aren't gonna work you know
just like yeah it depends on what you're
looking for too sometimes in a 10-pack
but the thing that's so subjective
because there's a lot of times I pop a
10 pack and not find anything oh yeah
and you can call it a keeper but is it
it's not gonna be something that I've
been lucky to run a lot of good stuff
like Fletcher's old stuff I I don't know
I haven't read any of his new stuff
really because I haven't uh there's
definitely something I want it's just
more of like yeah you know I have to get
it so
um and I've been busy doing other stuff
but Adam up in Portland archive grows
amazing yeah they sent me a couple some
seeds too but like it's also like I'm
dealing with some stuff right now like
yeah you know where I need it like
pretty much I'm not gonna crack those
until I got a clean space to do it at
and like usually my place I I like do a
lot of my projects experiencing I
[ __ ] a lot like you know just to see
how things work out and I really will
probably kind of know how it works out
but you know still like experimenting
yeah I do I like I love doing things I
like I remember we used to grow in like
uh laptop cases you know like like you
know like yeah like you know like I like
the micro aspect of it I I've done the
big and done really dope rooms yeah you
know it's cool but it's a lot of work
and like honestly like I don't it's just
it's hella complicated you do a lot of
people it's you know yeah
well man I really appreciate you coming
on today man it's been yeah no of course
you're talking thank you for having me I
appreciate it we'll have to do this
again sometime oh yeah anytime dude let
me know where can people get a hold of
you if they're looking to get some seeds
genetics clones oh so norcalgenics.com
www.norcalgenics.com which uh obviously
gave me that um that domain name nice
and then on Instagram you're uh NorCal
underscore I see mag yeah so I mean I
try to keep everything the same I'm not
gonna be changing names and all that
[ __ ] yeah totally if I go if you don't
see my brand no more then uh I still see
my weed it's gonna be somewhere you know
like cool and then you you got clones
out there in the rest yeah we're doing
everything you know I got I got a good
at like I'm waiting to on
I mean yeah we're the website's not up
yet but we're gonna have everything you
know once everything's ready and good to
go then it'll go up and it'll be ready
to roll yeah so people can DM you at
Instagram or do you like yeah sure like
I'm always you know welcome to talk
about strains whatever like I mean yeah
I love talking about this [ __ ] like
that's one thing you can put in a room
and I'll talk your ear off all day you
know like yeah it's like and I'm always
willing to learn more you know or like
see what other people think you know
what I mean yeah it's uh one of those
things that I really am not that like so
many opinions out there yeah really
there are so many opinions yeah no and
it's like really if something like I
don't like it and like I like people do
like it I want to know why you know and
like at the end of the day it's not like
really I just like what I like that's it
you know but sure you know like the
Skittles like you know take a look at it
afterwards yeah we'll smoke some
Skittles for sure man right on well
thank you again very much dude
appreciate it definitely for sure bro
cheers see you guys next time
[Music]
cruising