foreign
[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James Ladd
podcast today my special guest is BJ
Hughes from SOG Army how you doing BJ
good how are you I'm
fasting really good weather's been nice
it hasn't been too crazy of a summer so
far we'll see what happens right so
you're here local in California yes so
yeah and you have a cultivation facility
in Santa Rosa and you're also at MSO
you're working in other states as well
correct yes so tell us a little bit
about it so
we started out well I started out on the
East Coast came here in 2007 already
cultivating for 10 or 15 years
wow got into Medical
so like a second gen farmer right
um I was medical came here started doing
uh things with my internet friends and
selling the shops getting into licensing
so I got licensed and did that whole
thing here and then
how were those struggles going from
medical and direct I think everyone has
their stories
it was hard I mean but uh I don't know
if I would have it any other way it's
the only way I think to continue forward
in this industry totally I agree 100 you
know the trials and tribulations in the
the guys that did it first out of the
toughest because it was totally like
what do we do and then oh then there
sometimes there was no answers for Stuff
there's a lot of waiting going on
between for licensing you know getting
your license and doing it properly uh
laws and rules changing right so yeah
and then it was kind of free-for-all in
the back in the day and then you know
once they started tightening the reins
on it it got a little crazy totally I
mean it was loose at first though I mean
like even going into the transition for
medical and to rec when you were in
Sonoma County so yeah they're pretty
chill there I mean I wouldn't say it's
the easiest counting but it's definitely
not the worst they offered us a great
thing it was called penalty relief yeah
so if you're a medical grower
that was in a zoning that they approved
and you wanted to go legal if you got
architect drawn plans they would let you
transition and with temporary occupancy
so we are able to save our asses by that
as Farmers because at that point I had
two licensed things going
um one zoning didn't work that one
worked and yeah well you're up in
reading too right how's that plan going
dude
it's a it's a great area for doing
business if you want to pay to do it
yeah it's always hot and right it's hot
as hell yeah not always it's cold during
the winter yeah but you're right
bro we got a lot of snow this year more
than I had in years crazy rain we had we
had the most rain I've ever experienced
in my life in the bay here uh and you
guys also you had a lot of rain and snow
and all kinds of crazy weather up there
it looks like yeah definitely we got
feet this year yeah how'd that affect
your cultivation facility I'm not up and
going yet well I wasn't at that point
right I am now it didn't affect us at
all we were doing construction we could
still make it there to the warehouse so
nice I was shocked that the locals were
you know still working with snow you
know but yeah people want to make money
people people work yeah so it was more
like electricians yeah yeah yeah
nice
so uh what kind of genetics are you into
these days
man I'm really trying
to just going more towards gas these
days or old school ogs yeah um I feel
like that's what I personally like I've
been kind of boring myself with Skittles
lately a little bit for the past six
months or year like just seeing how much
I could smoke because it wasn't
previously available but right you know
uh I'm really kind of just looking for
crazy stuff I've been working with a guy
named crane City and working with mosca
Negra a lot
trying to hunt through their gear kind
of collaboratively
yeah Rick's a great guy he was on our
previous show oh cool yeah awesome yeah
Rick's the best yeah dude Rick is the
best but yeah working with him so you're
doing Fino hunting you're doing
selections helping with selections you
like popping seeds you like trying to
find Winners right Keepers and winners
and yeah so in all the legal girls we
have final hunt areas that's awesome so
how big
let's see it would be 164 square feet or
64 feet long by two so 128 square feet
that we hunt and we do one plant per
square foot cool so that currently
that's the deal and reading and we do
that every round every 30 days which
turns into
hunting 80 to 100 seed yeah at a time so
we're gonna find some cool stuff but in
production in Reading we set it up
around Fino hunting yeah so or the
ability to final hunt bring it to Market
under a nursery license with uh
distribution cultivation all under one
house
yeah people don't understand typically
how long it takes to get stuff to Market
from seed like from one seed doing the
process of the selection and then
actually growing that out and
replicating it big enough to where you
can produce flour of it it takes a while
right so you want to walk us through
your process our process is uh I don't
know if it's different but I feel like
it's the old school way so we grow seed
we pop seed we usually try to go 50 to
100 seed whatever comes up comes up at
that point the strong plants any even
the weak plants will let them go we'll
grow those plants for three to four
months
which is dedicating a pretty good bit of
area for a small retro you know because
we're only 100 lights right yeah well
and it's a loss leader for the most part
it's not like people want to buy a mixed
bag of stuff no and so you're giving up
a a large area of your growth that could
be used for flower production for other
things right so we're gonna run all
those seed the first time keeping all
the Clones or the seed plant in veg so I
will take a top off the Clone or top off
the seed
have a clone labeled to the plant that's
in veg right take that clone flower it
in our test area
[Music]
one time right it's kind of like a rough
sort at that point and you're just like
okay
whatever 10 that you guys we all agree
is a group is good we'll keep those down
Nice kill all the other plants
kill the males or give them out if
people want them right move on to the
next step okay now you have those two
all right that's six months at that
point probably so grow it again so see
what happens yeah yeah and in that
period you're seeing significant change
from the seed run to the second
generation of Clone maybe even the third
generation of Clone there's changes that
go on with sexual maturity in the plant
um yeah and really that second or third
time is special right on the third run
we a lot of the stuff that I showed you
earlier before we came on live was third
run yeah
and it's weird because a lot of the
things I'll say on the first run
definitely don't strike my interest at
all that over time you know on the
second or third run
change yeah so some of the ones that are
really hot in the beginning might not be
as great as some of the ones that just
didn't catch up quite as fast and then
all of a sudden wow you look at this a
different genetic than you saw the first
time and that's where you find the
special stuff I agree so well yeah and
if you skip that step you you have the
possibility of losing a lot of good
stuff I've lost so many things that way
yep I'll just do in a rough sort
killing and then being like Oh my God
but number whatever yeah you smoke it
later like it's been curing or it's been
like and you forgot about it yeah go
back to smoking you're like oh my God
what is that right it's lost yeah yeah
so that that's kind of our method and
now we keep everything for quite a while
and so and you're working in what other
states are you in your mission
Mississippi now Mississippi wow Mrs how
is Mississippi it's exactly like you'd
imagine but it's pretty Progressive when
it comes to weed believe it like the
locals as a whole the state yeah as a
whole is more accepting cannabis than
what I've seen in California really wow
in some like the rural areas yeah that
are super conservative have been
pro-weed huh so that's cool yeah that's
really cool and you guys are doing
cultivation you have multiple licenses
out there or yeah multiple license
transporter which is the same as
distribution in Cali yeah cultivation
and Manufacturing nice you can do
extraction you guys are doing volatile
no just Mark Brazen oh nice yeah cool or
being a solvent list we'll probably do
some cards but no nothing like with
alcohol or anything probably well yeah
you're a big Rising guy too I saw the
little collection you got before the
show that was really cool so with rosin
and dabs what are what are your favorite
like what are your favorite temps man
I'm going in at like four
490 these days for 480 depending on the
nail yeah yeah kind of lower I'm like a
420 guy myself oh nice I go like cold
start that's cool yeah I like dabs I
just don't like doing dabs on the show
so there's there's like a couple no-nos
that we've gone through like my previous
show that I did before the podcast I
smoked some Durban Poison with Marlin
that's a big No-No definitely him and I
we
couldn't remember what we wanted to talk
about half the time and you know so I
try to keep it Chill on the shows
so yeah uh you have any flower to show
today I definitely do let me grab them
so what we got here is basically
um a lot of sisters to our strain pink
Zaza that is uh we Fino hunted two or
three years ago now yeah from exotic Gen
X crane City oh yeah okay cool crane
City yeah so
um it was pink Zaza e actually oh yeah
and it was never released because he
disappeared for some reason but I was
testing nice so he sends them to me in a
vial with like blue tape over them right
never met the guy in person so when I
get the seeds
it's just a piece of blue tape like
written and I didn't see the eye so he
disappeared for two years we found a
keeper
I thought it was Zaza it was already
sold as Zaza but it's actually pink
which is supposedly his take on acai
interesting yeah so a little backstory
so that's was our Keeper at that point
so then he sent me more from the pink
line yeah and so this is pink Duos and
pink Godzilla nice which are the same
father different mother
interesting yeah so yeah so what kind of
so this one right here is the the pink
Duos number two which is not the one
that we're dropping yet this was the one
that needed three rounds but I almost
killed nice color good structure
interesting nose yeah almost a little
cotton candy-ish
a little gas to back I like that we're
gonna let it go yeah literally this was
around three or four they were like
we're gonna you know and then you're
like no no this might be the one right
so this was our keeper before this is
pink Duo's number four
foreign
this has a little bit of orange rind in
it it's more like the Zaza there's zazai
I feel this is more like candy gas or
something yeah that's more like candy
gas this is definitely more it's not
Tangy at all or like Tropicana even it's
like right but it isn't everyone it does
have a little bit of that Citrus rind in
it for sure my partner initially was
like it's Tangy we cannot sell it on all
that whole line because he is so like I
hate Tangy I hate Jack totally you know
that's it doesn't even matter like if
it's a hint of that so but this has
really nice structure yeah it looks like
it yields really well too I like the way
the calyx stack it is that's like 52
days and you finish in 52 days that's
like maybe 55 yeah but somewhere between
52 and 55 anything like that that's
great it was shockingly early yeah
compared to the Zaza which was like 70
65 70 to really like it doesn't even the
nose the look of the flower nothing it
doesn't come out and all the last 10
days for sure yeah a lot of stuff same
thing color a lot of times color doesn't
come out until the end I mean sometimes
some stuff is color all the way through
but a lot of the good stuff where it's
color it comes out at the end
definitely color is so subjective people
love it hate it I think
uh taste is more important taste is
definitely more important but it I feel
like the market is just like the market
demands purple it's got to have so now
it's not fully purple we just want a
little purple I don't know I guess I'm
learning I I'm behind I was looking for
all purple so that's pink Godzilla which
is a sister and it's so funny because
this nose is almost in the middle of
these two it has the candy gas but it
also and they're also like a little hint
of the Rind too right it's super small
hint of it
but this checks all the boxes this is
like marketweed this is the stuff that
the hype weed that everybody wants
purple candy gas it's got the look
it definitely has the Optics and you
know that the bag appeal of this stuff
is great and so as far as nutrients what
nutrients do you run man we're on Athena
right now yeah we use compost teas and
like humic fulvic Bud swells uh probably
30 of the time cool in cocoa cocoa is
good what what cocoa brand is your
favorite we're using floor Flex or uh
Cloud Core yeah right now yeah I like
those guys cool but um I've been looking
for different fertilizer companies we've
we're trialing cutting edge ladder
powder I'm a huge fan louder powder
shout out to Uncle John and Sean cutting
edges the [ __ ] definitely those guys
hooked me up and um we're giving it a
shot right now actually yeah if you have
any tips I'm down you know off camera or
whatever yeah yeah absolutely it's good
stuff I think it's it's simple and easy
to use if that I feel like
it's a it's a good all-around product
and you know and
I'm not stuck on just one nutrient line
out there saying one that's better than
the other but there are a few good ones
and Cutting Edge is definitely one of
the few good ones you know I like front
row as well I think front row they do a
good job and gotcha a front row is
always good for for me United nobody
even really knows about United United is
amazing and that's made by the owners of
Athena uh really good stuff good to know
yeah that's a fun one so if you yeah if
you're used to running uh Athena
transitioning United is not very
difficult interesting so I prepared for
like Jr crop Tech or anything at our new
spot where we had like I haven't ran it
but I heard that's good I'm sure it's
good Josh and Ramsey you can't go wrong
right they seem really awesome and you
know we're really knowledgeable about
the product and it made sense to me for
how they're trying to apply it yeah but
at the new place we have 16 heads on our
he Anderson so the thought was that
we'll always be trialing a new nutrient
line and kind of trying to get a hold on
the science of it of like what we're
seeing versus what we're putting for
inputs and you know and also
manufacturing the products right so yeah
they help put this facility together at
one point oh awesome of course yeah so
let's dive into your history a little
bit you know uh when did you start
smoking you're about my age we're about
this 1994. 94 94 I was 91 94 yeah it's
all about the same time it was when you
know it was the Wild Wild West you know
different times yeah so you know there
was some purple weed but like it was
green weed and brown weed yeah
definitely so yeah and then there was
there was some Exotics too you know we
got some stuff and like uh Maui Wowie
what about you guys so my dad Greer I
was in like a weed desert I was in
Georgia oh wow in Alabama when I was
growing up so there was no weed but my
dad luckily gerd so he grew like big bud
Friesland Indica he had like uh really
cool so he grew from seed started from
seed from Dutch seed mostly yeah yeah
from Dutch seed nice yeah so that's I
stole his weed you know growing up
totally legitimately stole his plants
you know his plants yeah actual plants
yeah I stole plant like the first time I
smoked I stole a plant like so how many
plants did he grow a lot like probably
40 or 50 in the backyard but he had an
indoor garden and we have property in
the country so uh assuming now he was
just flipping clones at the end of the
season because it was like late October
and I'm cutting through the backyard to
go to my friend's house and just right
there's like 45 six gallon pots like
spread out through the backyard with
plants like three feet tall flowered out
I'm like sweet well they weren't done if
you took them
yeah they weren't enough they weren't
done but uh my neighbor convinced me to
steal one so we still tried it out nice
good stuff yeah and then yeah so yeah so
your BJ the third yes so yeah you should
be called Trey that's supposed to be
your name the trays I know they're very
proud of it yeah totally and your uh
business partner is also a tray yep he's
a third which is really cool yeah and my
other one in Mississippi is the tray
really yeah dude a lot of Traders some
things were meant to be yeah he's not a
BJ as well he's a PJ PJ BJ the yeah all
the third yeah that's great he started
smoking back in the day your father grew
yeah uh and then ice what high school
job growing weed yeah for my dad's
friends dad's friends grew weed dad quit
I started being a Young Stoner I knew I
didn't want a regular job I've started
begging his friends which turned out to
be
motorcycle riders yeah and um
they put me on
you know after putting me through the
ringer a little bit Yeah I'd worked in a
grow house from like 15 until I
graduated high school at 18. oh wow yeah
in Georgia yeah really cool so how did
you get from Georgia Georgia's out here
ah the internet man like the internet
yeah do the forums the forums yeah
really yes that is a great story yeah so
yeah through the forums you met guys I
mean we were a lot of us were on the
forums right so like the bikers showed
me Mark Emery oh well and then so we
were buying seeds from Arkansas luckily
you didn't end up in Canada and then we
started going to Like Heaven Stairway
and then that kind of went away and then
I found Gypsy Nirvana totally the forums
and I see mag and over or overgrow first
yeah I made friends on overgrown then by
I see mag I was like doing my own thing
and yeah had more adult friends and like
made a buddy out here uh hillbilly on
PCP hillbilly on PCP yeah he was uh
bubble man's original administrator okay
cool on full Mount bubble yep and so he
brought out like a bunch of people from
all over the world and rented out a a
floor of the Metropolis in San Francisco
and uh showed us the medical days like
showed us the whole ropes of San
Francisco go nice so were you in the bay
when you first moved out here no I'm
here to Chico you moved to Chico that's
all I could afford you like the heat no
Georgia the chico we haven't afford
anything else man it was like insane
going from Georgia to San Francisco so
Chico's got a cool college scene though
for sure like that partied in Chico and
woke up on the lawn a couple times yeah
it was cool I lived in the country some
random people's lawn you know I lived in
Paradise actually nice so before the
fires okay and then uh yeah I had some
friends in uh Cherokee or they were off
uh red Cherokee Road yeah houses burned
down and really rough but man there's a
lot of good weed up there it was amazing
cut my teeth on big plant grows and you
know greenhouses or just yeah we did
outdoor like big like you know 100
plants and 400 gallon or bigger pots on
irrigation yeah that was big back in the
day that was like real big yeah then and
then you know still rocked houses but it
was like 20 lighters to kind of pay the
bills
seasons and stuff selling the shops
right and then um we got raided in Chico
so my guy I went to jail
Brandon B Money I come down to Sonoma
it's like 2011.
and uh get linked up with a local dude
take over helping him revise his Farms
he had like two or three houses yeah
started doing that still a medical scene
still selling to like organicannon green
Angel and Malibu and just kind of
rolling around up and down the coast
selling to the major cities you know
with our little bit of weed right
then legalization happened and it's like
dude my whole life changed so did we go
legal or do we not yeah and so when
legal because I didn't want to stop it
was almost like you know like on dead
two or something you're like I don't
want to get off the train like I'm not
ready yet like so legal was the only
option did you go on tour back in the
day yeah nice but you missed San
Francisco I mean like dude I saw Jerry I
had 91 like twice you didn't miss
getting sick though the three days in
San Francisco I got the worst flu I've
ever had in my life I just didn't do it
this time I was too busy building the
new thing yeah
great shows I heard I wanted to see the
Drone show really bad the Drone show was
nuts the whole thing was nuts and I am
used to getting seats usually you know
for shows concerts for the most part but
uh standing with my buddy Ben we were
like 20 feet from the stage all three
nights didn't miss a single song it was
it was nuts it was amazing it was like
one of the better performances for dead
and Company they finally got their [ __ ]
together
which
to be 100 honest I was against dead and
Company when it first started and I was
like John Mayer this there's you've got
to be kidding me you know and I couldn't
believe that John Mayer was going to be
stepping in for Jerry and I think a
little hurt over the whole Jerry thing
and them trying to revise it or whatever
but like he really grows on you his
guitar playing has gotten better I feel
like when he first came out he had this
commercial sound to his voice which
didn't really fit into the band and now
you listen to his voice and they've
they've filtered it differently and
they've changed it a little bit to where
I feel like it just really kind of
integrates well with the band where he's
it's part of the band and his solos he
just rips on guitar the guy is just he's
a killer
so yeah a lot of fun you know it's not
Jerry it's not supposed to be Jerry but
it was definitely an amazing experience
that's awesome I heard they're on Tempo
a lot more than they had in a long time
yeah yeah I know teal singing I mean no
teal singing is great I'm a big teal fan
too
so I'm here at Jerry's hand painted on
his face with the missing finger that's
dope yeah it was really it was cool a
lot of fun and a lot of good people that
I see it's just like I got a span abyss
and I see a certain group of people I go
to dead and Company parking lots and I
see the same friends that I see at those
shows you know that
that sometimes it's the only time I get
to see those guys right
so yeah so do you do events as well yes
I do nice yeah definitely seshes and
other stuff like that yeah definitely up
and down the state pretty much anything
legally we can and you know push the
boundaries where we can if we can work
something out like now that everyone's
kind of figured out
like a delivery service to help fulfill
to a patient yeah or whatever
so if you were to go back and talk to
your younger self
uh you know in the first couple years of
getting involved with all the knowledge
you have now from the stuff you've done
what advice would you give yourself
go harder than you want to yeah don't
stop grind like grind hard as [ __ ] like
if you think you want to do the show but
you don't know if you have like 10 grand
yeah do the show Even if you know you're
going to spend the 10 grand to do the
show yeah you know if you break even
even if you break even do it every time
because eventually you'll quit breaking
even that's my goal too it shows is to
break even yeah and I still sometimes
don't break even doing shows and it just
is what it is it's part of the business
and it's about grinding I agree
so keep grinding yeah and push harder
than you ever pushed before and you know
I think
mentally were were uh not as tough as we
most people aren't as mentally tough as
they actually are yeah like we think we
can only go here but we can go here oh
definitely so sometimes you want to give
up but sometimes it's just perseverance
and the ones that are left are the ones
that didn't give up oh definitely indeed
100 that's the biggest fear or the
biggest thing I regret was
I I was a brand and just didn't do
shares and we were concerned with
building our infrastructure and I think
on looking back at it I should have been
going to shows like crazy hard like we
are now but you know yeah I'm in one of
those giving modes too so if you see are
you giving moods at the shows I've been
going to we give out a lot of products
for people to try we do too seeds I like
giving out seeds yeah I think that's
important getting your name out you know
like I stand behind my product you stand
behind your product you have a great
product by the way thank you so yeah I
think it's great and where can people
find your products if they're looking
for what dispensaries are you guys at in
California oh man so we're in all the
harbor sides and all their Affiliates
we're in all the March and Ashes we're
in Catalyst we're in all the Sparks
we're in Mercy Wellness we're in doobie
nights we're in the cookies up in the
north state we're in the Sundial area
and all the sundials and reading we're
in
we're in uh I can't remember our
Sacramento people I'm sorry but in
Lompoc we're in Royal healing and we're
in um
reached wellness and yeah pretty much
and pretty much all over the whole state
if there's a major store in the area or
if you'd like to see us let me know but
that's where we are they can hit you up
on Instagram for any of that yeah but so
I got a question for you SOG Army is
this SM for sea of green yeah okay good
that's cool yeah I think it's that's a
great name
so and was that just an epiphany that
came on or how did how did the name come
about it was my Forum name that was your
Forum name really you see that's pretty
cool that it never was supposed to be a
business it was my Forum name yes sir
but when I came and I started meeting
Forum friends and they were all sharing
information
about clubs it was all song Army weed
I totally I I remember seeing some of
your posts so it was like that's wild so
the threads yeah so it's like it's funny
now it's uh
yeah it's come full circle yeah I'm
gonna revive I mean we're gonna do a new
brand called sea of green for the bigger
space in Reading yeah and drop the Army
because I don't think I ever wanted Army
to be in my company name to be honest
like if my younger self I would have
never said Pixar Army is legal one brand
but you know I I want to try to soften
it up a bit uh as we start producing the
soccer mom it out a little yeah a little
bit because I mean I I'm not in the Army
like you know no one in our company went
to the Army it was a military mentality
that's what it's all about you know it
was like we had an army of plants and an
army of workers because it what it took
you know an army of houses actually at
that point yeah things were a lot
different back in the day like if you
wanted to scale you didn't scale to a
warehouse typically I mean some of you
guys did there were people that did it
out there but a lot of times it was
scale like in Monopoly in Monopoly you
get another house you get another house
you can get another house and you get
another house and I have friends that
had 12 houses my business partner he had
15 houses I believe yeah you know it's I
was happy with my a lighter for the most
part and at one point I got a 50 lighter
but like there was a basement in the
house but it was houses right you know
that was that was how it was before
2012. yeah you worked within 200 amps
yeah if you're you figured out how to
make it work you know maybe you can't
turn on the the microwave and you're
definitely flip-flopping probably yeah
space if you're doing it yeah if you're
doing it if you're maximizing it
correctly
wild yeah so yeah today we have a
special guest coming on for our special
guest
um I'd like to welcome Rick mosca how
you doing Rick hey doing well James yeah
so Rick was our guest from last week
just happened to be here and uh he's
gonna be on the episode you guys are
friends actually part of the reason
you're in town was to see BJ yes exactly
I was spent a few days together touring
some uh some outstanding Farms tell us
about it do you guys got to see Flora
flame which they were our second guest
on the the podcast yes
um interesting now multi-tiered so two
level uh indoor living soil grows yeah
just perfection spectacular yeah he does
a pretty good job especially at scale
you're not seeing anybody else trying to
do that at scale and not only anybody
else trying to scale but two-tier scale
you know and those beds move like butter
right they really do pretty crazy right
he's so much space he had more space
than Hydro Growers I see between the
tears I thought it was awesome yeah
yeah yeah yeah I think he's doing a
really good job I think he's on to
something with the living soil organic I
definitely think you are going to be
able to charge more for a product like
that I like the way his stuff smokes you
know it's it's really good the genetics
yes he has good genetics
she'd grown well Smoke's great where
else did you guys go
we went to my farm oh nice yep on Santa
Rosa she got to check out the mids just
kidding yeah yeah we saw the big Factory
right the booth Factory
yeah so how was it oh uh excellent yeah
just really uh great uh segmentation of
every process along the grow so yeah
from a clone room with moms too uh
juvenile plants and then flowering rooms
growing some of those raspberry Boogie
crosses
um if you had what was it the we had the
second hunt with the second go around on
Ice pie raspberry Boogie and what was
the Hulk side I know it's blue mosa and
I the tag just ended up saying Hulk but
what was the other side of that
um
so that had the
um Planet Hulk in it so that has Bruce
Banner with our pink animal crackers
awesome yeah so that's a good one
actually yeah I forgot about that one
yes yes I there's some Growers uh
phenotype Hunters out of Michigan that's
pulling three pounds of light on here
so three pounds of light is good okay
yeah that's awesome I think if you can
get three pounds of light of good flour
you're doing good I mean there's guys
that get five pounds of light but is it
good I mean I'm not really into that I
want quality at the end of the day
exactly
you guys are working on collaborations
let's talk about those yeah so I found
the pink Zaza Rick and I have been
friends for years yeah
um like since the Forum set up I see mag
days you guys met on the forums yeah on
icy mag or on overgrown or which um I
didn't know them on overgrow but I
wasn't overgrow
um HDTV 420 was my moniker that's
awesome but uh yeah and so yeah I mean
we really became friends at uh I see mag
yeah yeah our friend Bacchus
um who ran a library back in the day
introduced us oh cool and uh he had like
a pretty substantial clone Library I
don't know amazing yeah I don't know if
people know but like back in the day
there's people in the forums that add
libraries of really sick genetics that
were clone onlys and if you you know we
kind of would develop friend trading
circles that right you know trade
genetics and he had the biggest library
I'd ever seen yeah at that point it was
crazy like 50 strains at least back then
at least yeah at least they were quality
so he had a lot of friends out here that
he would Source some from and he he
brought a lot of fire to the
old school new school just a mix of
everything it was what kind of stuff
we're going back what
um man in 15 years yeah so yeah this is
more old school so yeah more old school
but still like I guess I guess old
school now but I mean you know it's like
purple urkles and stuff like that or
like the ogs and stuff were purple
Oracle fire though like I like purple
it's you know it's not the biggest yield
or I don't think it's a really good
commercial strain or anything like that
but it's cool yeah you know I like GDP
too yeah I just don't like growing it
I'd rather you grow GDP and all buyers
right I just yeah exactly it's one of
those ones like because I used to grow I
grew a lot of GDP 31 days of [ __ ] every
time back in the daily well it's just
such a short squatty plant and the thing
is if you don't veg it long enough you
don't get big enough buds right so
yeah GDP was cool yeah it was like the
the Fino I had was dark purple you know
it was dark purple and it was like
[ __ ] candy yes
but floral gas you know I was like
that's straight up like lavendery
flowery floral character with that with
the gas and I had a nice gas to it too
so yeah so we met back on the forums in
the days and then uh we eventually met
at one of the shows here in California
one of the events and uh like High Times
I think Emerald is
yeah one of the real events yeah awesome
yes the true events
um and so yeah and so we've stayed in
touch ever since and you know
um he's got great respect for his
growing skills his flower uh he sells
out all the time so
um he puts his weed where his mouth is
yeah gotta respect that so he's all
about
quality and top shelf you know and I
think you know that's what I've been
learning from both of you is that it's
all about the quality and anything
that's not there doesn't hit on all
cylinders and you know it's not worth
growing yeah so and we want to
differentiate ourselves uh with that
fine quality and I I think people notice
yes you guys get to see a sold out show
at the fox of Larry June the other night
huh oh yeah how was that old school like
vibes okay like it was a great Vibe yeah
Larry Jean's not the best performer oh
wow but like it was great it was really
great show like the crowd was cool I
don't think he expected to see all those
shares sold out from how he acted
because it seemed like it was like one
show sold out and then he did another
one and another one so he's super hyped
on it that's so funny in uh 20 years ago
I almost now I went and toured the Fox
Theater when they were they went
bankrupt and they basically it was for
sale and uh we didn't have the 10
million dollars that they wanted for
that place but it's worth every penny
that place for 10 million dollars would
have killed it so I'm not sure exactly
how they got it back but it's beautiful
it's beautiful there's so much history
there so in in that one building and
good Acoustics good Acoustics yeah we
were feeling that baby just don't leave
anything in your car
Uber Uber is a good idea
yeah that that area is just a rough area
for parking and for theft you know
people breaking windows and uh I've had
Windows broken and there was nothing in
the car I've had uh stuff where there
was stuff in the car with Jason from
House of cultivar he was in town and we
had our luggage
and he had put his luggage in the back
seat uh and they [ __ ] broke the
window took everything it was really
rough so oh man but that's Oakland for
you you know you just gotta be smart
Keep Your Head on a swivel same thing
floor flame is not the safest area those
guys have been getting hit over and over
and over what a nightmare I think I hit
more than once oh yeah the guys have
come back multiple times and then they
had it on the news I don't know if you
saw the news commercial forklift lifting
up their gate and the big thing is is
like even if they don't get flour a lot
of times they do damage to your property
right so the property damage costs money
it's not like Insurance just covers
everything and or if it is Insurance
there's deductibles you know so people
are like well it's no big deal they
didn't get any flower they did damage
sure true still expensive still
expensive everything costs money
especially with the facility you look
you look you look at your equipment the
wrong way and it's another five thousand
dollars so yeah easily you go try to
Tinker on your ACS bad idea they're
definitely gonna do that right don't do
that yeah get a certified AC Tech
absolutely
so so we final hunt uh I got I end up
with the pink Zaza two years ago or
something and Rick and I trade clones
yeah so
um and have always traded clones freely
like back and forth and I sent it to
Rick I was like you gotta check it out
yeah and so I sent him the pink ZaZa and
we think that's probably gonna be some
of the better collaborations we've done
together we did a blue mosa collab too
that worked out really really well nice
awesome blue s once and then some blue
Mouse hybrids with the blue Hulk and or
the Incredible Hulk and you're then
selling the flower and you're selling
the seat yeah your guys are selling them
together basically
that basically is seeds yeah
um in the flower yeah he does eat I do
flour yeah and then I select and um yeah
sometimes he selects yeah part of part
of our process here is to actually have
the flower of all the seeds that we make
so we'll have samples we don't have a
lot of it but I can give you an example
of anything that we have on our menu
there'll be a flower sample to back
whether it's clone you know we're doing
some interesting CBD stuff cbv
um you know thcv so yeah it's it's wild
but we want to have samples of
everything available especially like
when we go to shows in California we
will have flower samples we have
cultivation Partners too
so that's great because I that's what I
think an educated consumer is looking
for yeah and I think it's the future I
think everyone it's it's just a standard
that should be the norm
you know correct yeah and that requires
planning planning and patience and all
those good things for sure
but but anything good takes time and
requires a lot of planning yeah right
more than you would ever think and it's
execution
execution and organization I think
organization is huge we both kind of
talked about you know note taking we
talked about grinding uh yeah so if you
were to talk to your younger self with
all the vast experience you've acquired
over these years and you talk to
yourself there is one or two years in
the industry what advice would you give
yourself
boy
um
probably to
uh double check
to make sure that uh
we understand
where the plants are and trying to keep
them
happier than we already do yeah because
it's a challenge it was a balance so you
have so many different things in the
works that you know one thing is off
kilter and it affects everything so you
know just be able to
um take that extra time to do
um some double checking because I think
it's really worthwhile yeah BJ said
grinding tell yourself crying harder
than you ever thought you could yeah
yeah that's part of it absolutely it's
like going to a strip club
yeah yeah right
stripper mentality and definitely super
mentality if your money's working yeah
work hard though no it's about hard work
for sure yeah yeah hard work and working
smart yeah yeah I mean for sure I think
you need to work smart too that's
definitely a great key point you know
when we were younger I believe a lot of
people said work smart not hard and my
father was one of those people that said
work smart but work your ass off work
hard work smart you know and I think
those two things things super important
you know because there's other people
doing it it's competitive you know
that's why quality is so important it
wasn't so important 20 years ago you
could still sell your weed if you sucked
at growing you suck at growing you don't
sell your weed anymore you know even the
homegirl guys it's done it's not
expensive so it's so competitive so
things like genetics play a huge key
role in everything and also quality yeah
absolutely yeah without you know that
quality it's all for not I mean it's not
what are you doing it for but I feel
like a lot of guys in the guys I've
interviewed lately and the people that
are still here smiling uh are really
passionate about what they do they love
weed you know most of them smoke we all
smoke you know so we and we're all
roughly the same age and so we all went
through the same trials and tribulations
to a degree within the industry and we
saw these changes from the 90s on up
and it's a whole different world
so yeah yeah it really is and I think
with us uh individually working
um with that passion but running at you
know near capacity or a hundred percent
um that just UPS the level of flower uh
engine acts we create and that's what's
going to set our work apart because
we've taken the time to put in
um all those steps and making sure that
they flow correctly yeah so and that's
what makes these kind of meetings fun
because we get to look at each other's
flower yeah I like seeing new stuff
especially and I feel like
especially with you we get to experience
some new crosses together and it's like
some new stuff I've never seen before
and that raspberry Boogie has this real
sourness that's really it's almost musky
but not musky it's definitely insincy
tiny little bit but like in a good way
yeah like nag champa-ish yeah with a
nice bouquet yeah with a few nice
beautiful bouquet that's loud I mean
that stuff is loud and it smokes loud
and
yeah you get fruit you get a lot of
character it's like eating a whole meal
dessert organic dessert fresh berries
speaking of which we have a little
flower if you want to take a look at her
sure
this is the Zero's raspberry Boogie bomb
oh yeah
it's all familiar I wouldn't kick her
out of bed for eating crackers
it's a good one that's really nice so
this one also has that funkiness yeah so
where it's like
it's funny because like it's from the
series yeah it's serious seriously
interesting um but it smells like it's
not like pine needles but it smells like
a forest like I get this Forest smell to
it I get like this creamy
sweetness to it it's got this Razz sour
raspberry like sour cherry and raspberry
maybe yeah
but really really exciting
and if it translates in the Smoke which
I'm sure it will it's going to be like
really really enjoyable but it's like I
like these complex smokes I really like
complex flavor profiles yeah it's like
my problem with the Asian Orange from
subcool back in the day
was that it was straight orange like
actually House of cultivar had a Fino of
Agent Orange that wasn't straight orange
but like all the other ones I saw and
all the flower I saw coming out of
humble
that was agent orange because that was
easy when people were busting those out
back in the day you know and this is
like 15 years ago maybe
that agent orange was straight orange it
was there was no complexity to it it
wasn't even as complex as Tangy and you
know tangie's pretty pretty orange but
there's a little rind yeah it was like
straight limousine yeah yeah and it was
just like orange cleaner yeah it was
like orange cleaner that's what I
thought of it and it wasn't cleaner like
the burning your nose kind of cleaner it
was like missing that part of it so Mr
Clean like
yeah yeah you have a very linear you
know mono turpish where you know it's
like but but like something like this
this is the complete opposite end of the
spectrum this is where you got
complexity where you smell it and
there's so many different recognizable
smells but you got to kind of pick them
apart yeah yeah very much so and this
one is our collaboration uh with uh BJ
SOG Army that is the zope to the pink
Zaza so this stuff looks freaking nuts
dude this is I mean you got Sugar Leaf
on here and the Sugar Leaf is just sugar
so we leave it on because it's so
crusted with
and so this one has that orange rind it
has a little bit of that rind in there
I'm a huge fan of that rind uh when it's
subtle like that you know and it's
complex it's another complex one
and this is The Offspring of our seeds
you know that yeah there's a little bit
close to this too I like that that's
something this is nice
like it reminds it's a funny thing is
like I took bubble baths as a kid and
some of us like my parents you know when
we were little kids I remember taking a
I mean this is like
40 years ago like Mr Bubble Mr Mr
Bubbles
that's what this is it has a Mr Bubble
smell to it underneath well we have
Bubba smells like name so yeah I mean
Bubba smells like Irish Springs a little
bit you know like Bubba Kush it has more
of the Irish Springs kind of bubble
smell and this is more like bubble bath
this to Bubble yeah like straight up
nostalgic from when I was a
five-year-old kid you know yeah yeah
that's what I love about flower though
like being able to bring back memories
of being a kid yes you know I can't even
though the last time I thought about
like bubble baths or like kids bubble
baths I don't have kids unfortunately
more fortunately I guess depending on
how you're looking at it yeah so it's
one of those mixed things it's like it'd
be great to have kids in some ways but
in other ways it's great to be able to
travel and to see the world and
you know absolutely yeah for sure I'll
be like SoMo I'll have kids when I'm
like 60. that's what I'm hoping for too
bro yeah
he's the man he's the Manny 30 year old
uh girlfriend at the time Jesse
yes yes I remember her crushed yeah
little Jake Jake is adorable turn he's a
great kid
so so I'm not so long ago a year ago
uh in Amsterdam yep okay yeah that's my
number one stop is over Summers is
typically my first or Greenhouse I have
I have a bunch of friends there but yeah
I love Greenhouse stopping by there and
stopping by the gray area yes gray area
it's been a little while since I've seen
John over at the gray area big shout out
that's the first time I ever smoked
bubble gum that was real Bubba gummy
yeah it was from the gray area yeah they
had the bus it was during one of the
High Times cups back in there they
always had good flour they're like that
their their flower selection was some of
the best voyagers was pretty good
greenhouse Hot Stuff good good stuff
from time to time hash
a lot of good hash and Amsterdam yes
Bluebird is my favorite for hash yeah
they had the Milana cream they had
Temple balls I mean they had it all you
know they were really known so you were
supposed to go to Spanish but you flaked
on us half flaked I started this new
facility right yeah we had a great time
without you don't worry I'm sorry yeah
next year we do it next year next year
yeah put it on the list we're definitely
gonna be there you know rock it out get
some good meals
so yeah speaking of which we got some
good meals to go to later tonight I
haven't figured out where yet but we're
going somewhere again I'm sure it'll be
good top shelf
so yeah well thank you guys for coming
on the show I really appreciate both
your times and uh I look forward to
seeing you again partying with you guys
later great thanks for having us thank
you for having us awesome Cheers Cheers
let's do this again
hey everybody don't forget to like And
subscribe
[Music]