[Music]
how's it going everybody my name is
James Lou and today my special guest is
Luke scarmazzo he spent 14 years in
federal prison for owning a legal
dispensary in California how you doing
today Luke I'm exceptional man really
happy to be here thanks for having me
James man really really glad to have you
on the show thanks for coming out so
you've been out of prison for almost a
year now almost about 11 months wow
really impressive yeah you know it's
it's pretty amazing your journey going
from legal you know and I can't even
imagine to be honest that's it's wild
that it it went through what it went
through especially because you had a
legal dispensary it's not like you were
breaking the law and you had some spot
in New York where you were selling
everything out of your you know your
BEDA yeah big tra you you were trying to
do it by the books and you're trying to
do it the right way and uh it's a little
ridiculous yeah it was one of the the
reasons why we didn't think we were
going to get that much time even when
after it all happened right is we were
like okay it's it's a cannabis case we
like we're following state law we are
paying our taxes we uh you know
everything was above board completely
legal in the state so we're like you
know what what are we going to get
probation a few years right no the
federal government doesn't give out
probation or a few years yeah they
decided to throw the book at you oh yeah
oh yeah 22 years is what you originally
were sentenced for too yeah yeah it was
21 years 10 months is how the the FED
sentenced you in months right so when
you get when you get in you walk into
sentencing and the judge sentenced you
he goes you know scarm Masa we're
sentencing you to 262 months so now you
got to like sit there and do math right
you're like I'm like 262 month 26 and
I'm like whoa wait that's like 20
something years yeah so I didn't really
even get the exact number it was when he
when he initially said it because it was
I just was like well it's 20s something
years that's already already way more
than anyone any one of us could have
fathomed and then the the real fight
began after that the 14-year fight the
14-year fight that was a whole different
battle Yeah so we uh we met thanks to
our mutual editor for I have my book
coming out you have your book that's out
which we have right here the high price
um yeah Angela Baka big shout out to
Angela yes thank
you big shout out big shout out so let's
dive back into where you got your start
with cannabis cuz Okay that was a while
back yeah I kind of I did like a Quinton
Tarantino to you right I started at the
end of the movie
right um so my star in cannabis was
really when I was born I guess if I
really back it all the way up my dad
grew cannabis um since I can remember it
I've been around cannabis in my
neighborhood our neighbors grew cannabis
like I grew up in California in the 90s
me Modesto in Modesto yeah so you know
every it was all around us you know so
we were immersed in the culture um I
grew my first cycle at 15 I think yeah
so I was like a sophomore in high school
and uh the the F the very it was an nl5
yeah and I didn't even get to I got it
to flower but right when I was about to
pull it my mom found it yanked it said
she said said she threw it away I think
my dad ended up burning it down but
whatever but that was my first that was
my first grow and I was in love with it
ever since then and um and then just
continued to kind of like you know back
then it was you were growing on the
Outlaw you know we were growing in
houses and you know renting houses out
and kind of Staggering them and doing
and then just kind of doing whatever we
could to keep certain genetics that we
wanted and uh then it all changed when
we started getting the medical cannabis
laws in California and then we kind of
saw like a different side of things and
you know in 96 it passed early but there
wasn't a whole lot going on early on no
it was it was very gray area at best it
was very gray area and there wasn't like
there was no real real like legal legal
shops that you could go to the Bay had
like Dennis prone had some of the you
know the early you know a patients um
clubs that they had and collectives
really really early on but some of your
legal shops really didn't start coming
around until like the early 2000s right
and in around
2003 um I'm going to get legal on you
real quick but the the r decision comes
down on the ninth circuit and it
basically barred the DEA from raiding
anybody in California that was following
medical cannabis laws so now we we kind
of the the medical cannabis laws were
always there while we were growing
Outlaw and doing our thing right but we
were always everybody was always kind of
leery of them because the feds could
always come in and Trump state law right
and they did and they did many times
yeah many times so when that decision
came barring them or is an injunction I
think back then um with Angel re um
going against the federal government for
or the de EA and they got the injunction
and then so we we sat down and we were
like wow now this opens an opportunity
for us now if we can open it's like an
easy transition it's like in a field I
already have a degree in now they're now
they're offering a a position to in an
emerging market right right so we sat
down uh my partner Ricardo Montes um
shout out Ricardo he's a big fan too man
um and you know we sat down and we
initially were like okay like let's
let's explore opening a store so I
talked to one of my friends he's he's
kind of working at a doctor's office in
the Bay Area and it was in a building
where they they had to they had the
doctor's office on the second floor and
then the third floor was the dispensary
and that was the name of the dis third
floor Flor in Oakland man that was
classic classic it was classic right and
so he says look if this is what you want
to do come over here and check this spot
out he's like there's not a lot of them
around but I got like an inn over here I
work at the doctor's office we we'll
we'll get you all squared away and you
can go up and check it out so we I go
over there I meet him in there I walk in
and I look you know we walk upstairs
it's like all dimly lit you know what
I'm saying big bouncer on the like the
front door you know and you're walking
in you're like first experience on a
dispensary like you don't know what to
expect right so you're like walking in
there I walk up the stairs and when I
get to the top of the stairs it looked
like like a mom and pop spot like a like
a like a old coffee shop but on the
board behind them it's not beans it's
cannabis all behind them and there and I
sat there and like they had like a
little like seating area where you could
consume and smoke and everything it was
dope it was like the setup was was cool
and then on the left they had all these
like clones and and all the genetics
that they were selling and all the
cultivars that they had going on so I
sat down at the table and just kind of
sat back and just wanted to watch it and
so I sat there for like an hour and
watched this spot just go through people
and and people walk out happy and and
the atmosphere was like really eclectic
there was like people from all walks of
life yeah everybody everybody it was
crazy it was a mix of everybody like
anyone you could think of from the
skater to the rock guy to the football
player to the whatever you know what I'm
saying it was everything um so I got
back I talked to my partner and I said
hey we got to do this man like this is
our dream like this this is it right
here like this we we we we can really do
this
so he's like all right where do you want
to do it at so I'm like the Central
Valley those of you that don't know the
Central Valley the Central Valley is
like the California is a blue state
right the Central Valley is like the
pocket of really high conservatism very
red very red yeah like it's like the
only counties that voted for Trump like
consistently and they do it's always
been like that it's it's changing a
little bit now it's changing a little
bit now and I and I will give give them
credit there are a lot of people that
are working hard to to to to make the
policies there that um uh more inclusive
and make it to where it's Justice for
everybody right that's what we want so
shout out to the people that are working
in Modesto to to to make the pendulum
swing the other way but at that time it
was really conservative yeah so we we
sit down and we say hey where are we
going to open this up at so we decide on
Stockton because Stockton is in the
Central Valley but Stockton's a little
bit more liberal it's like we're like
okay
it's a little rougher it's a little
looser right we might can go into
Stockton and maybe like they'll want
some business there right we're going to
give them tax dollars like maybe they'll
be open to it we go into the city
council meeting to meet with the mayor
and the city council and within like I
don't think we got four words out before
they were like no not in our
city and now we're like well that didn't
go exactly how we thought it was going
to go like we were kind of expecting
some negotiation Maybe and like hey you
this is where we want you at it was like
a dead
no so we go back to the drawing board we
go back to our attorney at the time and
we say hey this is what they said and
he's he he he was very knowledgeable
about the cannabis laws back then and he
says you don't have to ask the city to
open he said it's a state law he said as
long as they don't have like any banss
or anything in place already you don't
have to get the city's permission to
open a dispensary you just have to make
sure that you go through all the correct
processes and get the correct licenses
and everything so we're like all right
cool why don't we just open it in
Modesto then that's our home city right
and that's where we have the most love
the biggest support the biggest network
of Growers everything so we decided to
open Modesto
and man it was it was a hard decision
right
because it almost felt like the people
who were signing their names to the
Declaration of Independence right it was
like here we
are we're openly
defying what you got defying your your
federal laws we openly defying the
community Norms
right and we're on the main strip in the
city yeah right out there right out
there yeah big Target big Target yeah I
mean what people don't understand is if
you didn't do it and people like you did
do it it wouldn't be that way this day
today you know I
think you know there's sacrifices that
people had to make for us to have
legalization and people tend to forget
the past or they they they remember what
they want yeah but not necessarily the
important parts well the memory is short
right yeah so it's like especially like
my daughter's generation I always use
her as example Jasmine I love you I know
you're probably tuning in so it my bad
for putting on the spot here but it's
the other like the her generation she's
21 right they grew up knowing nothing
but legalization really right right they
grew up knowing all the stores on the
corners and everything so they don't
really even understand like she does of
course because she went through it but
you know that generation doesn't
understand like what it took to get here
right like even the bud tender your bud
tender that you walk into a dispensary
right now is what like 21 through 30 you
know what I'm saying that main age
bracket and and don't know so it's it's
interesting when I go in there and I get
to like talk to to some of the bud
tenders or some of that generation and
and just kind of talk to them like yo
like to get to where we're at today like
we had to do like we had we showed up to
work every day not
knowing if we were going to go to jail
or not yeah or get murdered or get shot
or robbed or anything yeah it was crazy
man it was a totally different time yeah
and the people and the Pioneers at that
time that really put it out there my hat
goes off to them because they took the
risks their families took the risks and
you know what the crazy thing is James
is a lot of them are still in there yeah
a lot of them are still in there a lot
of them
yeah yeah it's pretty
wild pretty wild that we can operate to
the extent we can operate legally and
there's still people locked up for it
it's just yeah there's a lot of things
that are counterintuitive and that's
definitely one of them it just doesn't
make sense on any level it was one of
the frustrating things to me as I was
sitting in prison during that 14 years
right and
watching the industry grow because like
I love the plant I'm a huge fan I'm
passionate about the plant so I'm like
watching this progress like as a
cheerleader like yeah let's go you know
what I'm saying but at the same time I'm
watching corporations and governments
Bank millions of dollars yeah on the
same thing I'm sitting in a sale for
right and the same thing a few 2,000
other people are sitting in a Cell for
so it was really it was like I had mixed
emotions on it right because I'm like
sitting there like really champion and
on the industry and the growth because I
know that as it grows it becomes more
accepted be we we see the more people
see the benefits of the
plant so you know it was it was a tough
one but yeah yeah and then so you went
through the appeal process yeah and that
was that was a fight as well yeah yeah
so we open the dispensary for like we
run it for two years MH
great and then the city begins to do
like a litigation against us they don't
want us there right and they
go all right look what we need you to do
is tell us what it would take to recoup
your costs and then some and the amount
of time and we'll give you that amount
of time unharassed to be able to you
know continue to do business but after
that we have to agree on a date and it
wasn't I was like that's not that
doesn't even sound agreeable to me like
what do you mean like just recoup our
money and like tuck our tails and and
get on our way like the communities out
here like supporting us tremendously
we're going to these City Council
meetings and you know like a city
council meeting has like 20 people at it
these City Council meetings have like
400 people at them so much that there's
people in like the Overflow outside like
watching on the monitors when we're
having like anything cannabis a lot of
supporters yeah there like tremendous it
was huge
so the city wants us out of there and
then what they end up
doing is they realize that they're going
to lose in the litigation they realized
that we have really solid case law
behind us we were we were doing business
before any of their banss or
moratoriums and they basically decided
hey if we can't get these guys out of
here we're going to call the fans wow
yep so on my daughter's birthday in 2006
on Jasmine's
birthday uh the feds raid us in the
morning at like 6:00 a.m. with machine
guns coming in kicking in doors it was
like if you watch like a documentary
raid in like um fua or Iraq or something
that's how that's how it was done they
all black tactic and the crazy thing is
they knew I was there by
myself it was it was it was it was total
Overkill
overreach but it it it was typical of
the time right that's how dispensary
owners and operators were treated like
they were families would would they
would kick your door in they take your
family out into the front lawn and stuff
like that and it was it was crazy it was
a crazy time and then yeah we we went
through and we found guilty in trial
because we couldn't prevent present a
defense really you can't say the words
medical marijuana you can't say state
law we couldn't bring any of our tax
documents in so the government on one
hand gets to or the prosecution on one
hand gets to paint us as these huge like
drug kingpins that are flooding the
community with weed and we have to like
try to sneak in like language here and
there of oh no we were paying taxes and
we had a license and you know and they
would object and strike the record it
was it was it was a kangaroo court yeah
so not surprisingly we were found guilty
sentenced to 22 years and or 21 years 10
months and 20 years for my my brother
Ricardo and then like I said the fight
began then our first appeal was dead in
2011 that was our direct appeal that one
was really like the shot through the
heart because that's when you really
like you think okay there's a chance I
had this one judge and maybe he didn't
see it the way I wanted him to but this
is going to a three-judge panel in the
ninth circuit which is one of the most
liberal circuits in the country so we're
like oh we're going to get a good Shake
nobody gives any a a 20e sentence to a
dispensary operator like that's unheard
of yeah
denied right they gave it to me and they
said you're going to keep it and you're
going to do it
wow so then like for for for the
listeners that are familiar with the
legal process forgive me but for those
that aren't it's a Byzantine Maze of
like motions and stuff once you lose
your direct appeal and you go off on
your own now now there's no legal help
anymore now you're just in prison and
you either learn the law or you
hopefully you got your parents or people
got money to be able to get a lawyer
that knows the law for you because
there's there's no court obligation for
you anymore like when you go through
trial they got to provide an attorney
for you once you're convicted it's game
over
so I had to spend like the first like
five years in prison in the law library
wow just learning the law because I was
like man like I was still like dumb
enough to be like this isn't right like
they can't do this to me mhm you know
the
irrational convictions of Youth right it
made me sit down and learn law and I had
to do it the oldfashioned way like not
with computers it was books like you got
you got to a book and then you got to
one part of the case and then it said go
see this other case and you had to set
that book down and then you had to go
back into the library and find that book
and then that might have only been like
a couple sentences you needed yeah right
so it was it was crazy but I learned
like I really learned it like that you
know I learned it the hard way so I
learned how to file my habus Corpus
motion
2255 I learned to file 22 41s and these
unique motions to try to just challenge
anything right none of it worked yeah
like I got man I got shot down so many
times like it was crazy at first at the
beginning I was like real hopeful I
would call home and be like yo I got
this in there man I'm hopeful maybe you
know something might shake and it would
get denied or it would get you know shot
back and then I'd have to call back home
and be
like didn't
work
and after a few times doing
that I stopped telling them about
[ __ ]
because you you have so many letdowns
right
you have so many letdowns
and like I can take them
yeah
but I didn't want to keep giving them to
my
family thank
you I didn't want to keep giving them to
my family so it got to a point
where I I would just like kind of do my
thing you know what I mean I'd file
these
motions study the law and hopefully find
something man that where I could
something to where a judge would
recognize the Injustice of my
sentence and that was it right it was
like I'm sitting there like in this
situation and I'm like I have to find a
way like to argue this in a compelling
way that a judge will say cuz you can't
just go in and say oh weed's legal in
the state let me out the feds don't care
about that they don't it doesn't matter
how many states legalize if you're in
federal prison it doesn't matter so I
had to find a way to make a judge
realize that the case my case was an
injustice on the on its surface just
because I was following state law and
because of the changing legal landscape
of all of cannabis even in the federal
government the federal government has
evolved tremendously from 2008 where
they were initially
right so in 2014 Obama launches What's
called the clemency Project 2014 and
it's seeking out people who have
outdated sentences from non-violent drug
offenses that if they came before the
court today would get a lesser sentence
right we were like perfect me and
Ricardo were like C perfect candidates
poster children for this right so we
were like okay cool I wrote The Motions
up I studied how to do it I got with my
boy Wen Angelo we had linked up a little
bit before won had 55e sentence for
cannabis um really knowledgeable about
the law shout out to wen Angelos and
reform brand he he launched reform brand
which is a dope brand check it out
support him so I got with Welden we
wrote These petitions they're identical
they B they basically had the name
changed on them you know because our
case we were tried together our case
conduct was the same right we file these
petitions and we wait and we wait and
we're like man we got a really good
chance in January of 17 the the
beginning like the 6th or the 7th I get
I get called into the office and they
sayhe sit down I'm like oh man this is
crazy like I think I might have got it
like I might have I might have got
clemency because we were just we were
we're great candidates we had
non-violent cannabis offense following
state law had a license paid or like you
know the list just keeps going so I'm
like we perfect for this legalization
was going on everything was going on at
this time Obama was was was doing
interviews and throwing language out
there that sounded like real supportive
of cannabis and things like that so we
were really hopeful I get called into
the office I sit down and they say hey
uh this just came in from the pardon
attorney I'm like yeah what is it and
they slide it over to me is a
denial and I'm
like so it don't they don't tell you why
you're denied it just says executive
privilege they don't need to tell
anybody you just denied you could
reapply in a year I call call home and
tell him I got denied I tell him to let
Ricardo know just so that he would you
know kind of not not I was still hopeful
for him so it wasn't like brace for
something bad but just know hey mine
already came through you know this it
didn't work out and then on the 19th of
January the day before Trump took
office uh Ricardo gets granted clemency
wow yeah it was it was one of Obama's
last acts and he called Ricardo sentence
uh unfair and
outdated but not yours but not
mine I wrote I wrote the petitions they
were yeah they literally just had the
name changed on the top of
them so I don't know whatever like it
goes through a crazy process that
hopefully the justice department and
everybody over there can get streamlined
but it's kind of a mess right now it's
like a seven layer process it's super
bureaucratic MH it can end up on any
kind of career Prosecutor's desk and get
denied at any one of those stages wow so
yeah it it that was like oh so in
2018 bear with me in 2018 um Trump
passes a prison reform bill called the
first step act I say Trump passed it but
it was a bipartisan thing and and the
Dems have been working on it for a long
time as well but it was it was passed
with everybody coming together and
buried like in this legislation is this
like unknown statute called
3582 right and this and this guy sends
it to me is he's an attorney on the
street he says Luke I think there might
be like a back door in this like piece
of legislation that they passed that
allows prisoners to directly petition
the court
because otherwise you don't have a way
to get in once you go through your
direct appeal and your habius Corpus the
court doesn't hear you anymore you can't
send them anything you can't just keep
saying hey let me out like once you've
exhausted your appeals it's done you
know what I mean there's the court you
have no what they say is you have no
vehicle to come in back into court with
right so this was that vehicle and now
in 2018 after California has their recck
laws going and we have you know multiple
years of the Roar Barker bar
Appropriations Amendment that's barring
the DEA and and the or the Department of
Justice from using their funds in states
where cannabis is legal so we we have a
series of things that have happened in
over the course of the last few years
that's making it to where I think now if
I present it before a judge and I do it
in the right way like I said in a
compelling way where I don't necessarily
only argue cannabis but argue it in a
way where the Cannabis is the main
Foundation of this Injustice because of
what's going on in the whole us today
right I had a I had multiple people help
me Ed lman over at Emerald Law Group
helped um filed excellent motion on my
behalf I filed the initial motion um Ed
filed Ed filed a motion um and then
we're kind of waiting and a huge law
firm called King and spaling contacts me
and they asked to come on to to to help
out and it was like a godsend and they
send this lady to come on and help me
named Carrie Dent shout out to Carrie
Dent the sweetest looking lady you would
ever meet right but when it comes to the
law she is vicious I mean she went in
and demolished the government like I've
never seen like such a one-sided like
battle in motions before seeing how
Carrie like just went in just like kind
of just dismantled like every like point
that the government was using to keep me
in there lo and behold after she came on
um to make a long story short brother it
in February 3rd of this year I was
released from prison because of Carrie
Dent because of king of Spalding because
of Ed lman because of Freedom grow
because of lpp because of mission green
because of uh glass house because of uh
beard Bros because of everybody because
the the entire
community and and iies for anybody I
miss I know I miss a tremendous amount
of people I could probably do your whole
show thinking people I'm serious like no
no lie but because of the community that
came came behind me I was able to get
out it wasn't just because I found that
motion somebody shot that to me right
and then I I filed it and then the
community got behind me and attorneys
got behind me and they were able to get
me out and it was the greatest feeling
in the world man like when I got to hug
my daughter like on that night like I
flew they I was in I was in a prison in
Mississippi a place called yazu
Mississippi yazu City
Mississippi it's like it sounds like
what it is I'll just say that it's like
50 years in a Time Warp wow you know
what I mean and it's like small
Southern
um like the way they incarcerate people
is different in the South it's just a
different culture and a different
mentality right so I say that to say
this I was ready to leave when they said
it was time to go so they put me on a
plane I fly back to California I fly
into Sacramento Airport I meet my
daughter at a Denny's that was my first
my first time seeing her in so long man
I mean I had she she came she was one of
my biggest
supporters I love her to death she came
up and visited me you know throughout
all those years but then covid happened
and then I got shipped out of state and
then I got shipped to Louisiana and then
to Mississippi
so by the time I actually ended up
seeing
her it was like 5 years since last time
I had saw her wow so it was a really
emotional moment but like I said the
best feeling in the world man I bet
yeah wow so let's let's talk about uh Co
because I think Co was pival in a lot of
ways in the book I mean yeah I read some
really interesting things in your book
yeah you know how you wrote the book you
know I think that that's pretty
impressive if you want to go into that
how you got the
paper it's like that that's actually a
really interesting story um so I end up
in solitary a lot during my 14-year
period and you can end up in solitary
for anything like solit they'll put you
in solitary confinement for anything a
few times was for a dirty dirty weed
test and I did like my my first dirty
weed test in prison was in long pooke
and I think I did like 75 days they call
it the shoe it stands it's an acronym
Shu and secure housing unit is what they
call it but it's solitary confinement
they throw you back in a sale you don't
see anybody your food comes in a slot uh
if you want to go out of your cell you
get one hour of recreation but
Recreation is in like a dog kennel it's
like a really small like cage like down
the hall from your cell so you don't
really ever get to go out wow and
there's no like sunlight or anything I
mean they have a window but it's painted
over um it's artificial light so it's a
rough existence torture and I don't
think I think in 50 years from now like
they will deem it Torture right but
so I had always wanted to write the
story high price like it was always in
the Forefront of my mind but I got
frustrated when I would have to try to
write like a 10-page essay like I'd be
like dude I don't want to write this so
I'm like how am I going to sit down and
write like this book like this story
like cuz to sit down and write this
story I knew it was going to take a
lot
so I you know try to sit try to force
myself to sit down a few times and I got
like 10 pages done I think and then I
end up going back into
solitary and this time it was for like
seven months so I'm sitting in my my
cell in
solitary and you like books are your
Lifeline in there like if you have books
you're pretty cool like you can sit
there and read maybe like work out for a
couple hours write a letter read some
more like it kind of makes it to where
you can break your day up a little bit
right but I run out of I run out of
books
and if you don't catch the guard coming
through with the book cart which they
come whenever they want to really then
there's no way to get it other than the
mail and sometimes they play with the
mail back there too so you're not
getting mail for like a week or two
weeks or three weeks at a time W so I
run out of books and now I'm like all
right I got to figure something out like
something to occupy my
time so I said man I wanted to write
this book this whole time let's do it
I'm sitting down in here I I just like I
felt this like it might sound crazy but
I felt like this presence that just
saying like yo this is for this like
this is why you are in here like to sit
here and do
this so I'm like all right this is what
I'm GNA I'm going to make the agreement
with myself I'm going make a deal with
myself I'm going to I'm I'm going to say
I'm going to write for Pages a day and
that's it I'm not gonna get I don't care
even how they come out I'm just going to
sit down I'm gonna force myself to sit
down I'm gonna write four pages a day
and just see what happen so I do it and
then like after
like you know two weeks I got like 40 or
50 pages sitting on the side of me and
I'm like looking over there I'm like I
have something now it's like something
real now so now I'm kind of getting like
a little excited now at my my writing
time it was like 1 to like
4:00 I'm getting excited now I'm like
okay hold on so I saw I just keep
writing I keep writing and after
like few months back there I I finished
and I was like okay like well hold on
let me back up though you're right hold
on I I skipped one of the most important
parts so that first day I figure okay
I'm gonna write this right so I write my
four pages well there's a reason that I
say I'm going to write four
pages it's cuz that's all they give you
you only get four pages of paper back
there so I didn't think it all the way
through at that time I'm like yeah I'm
going to get these I'm going to start
writing my book and get these four pages
out a day well you only get four pages a
week and you get two envelopes and you
get one little Flex pen like a little
half like clear pen that you know bends
so that you can't kill anybody with it
or something I guess I run into the
immediate problem that I'm gonna be a
out of paper really fast and then B out
of ink like shortly after
that so the way you get paper back there
is like the orderly comes behind the
officer that's giving trays out and he
like pushes a cart like once a week and
gives you like some supplies soap pens
you know writing paper things like
that so like I slide a note to the
orderly and the note says basically like
hey I need more pens and paper in this
sale and I'll pay you for it like just
let me know whatever you want so he's
like everything is everything is for
sale in prison everything like if you
have money doesn't matter what it is
somebody's going to try to make it
happen
right so he says he sends me back in a
cut what we call him kites right so he
sends me back a kite and it says on it
yeah for two lunch trays and one dinner
tray I will give
you however many however much paper and
pens you
want so I'm
like bet I mean I don't really have a
choice right it's going to hurt to not
have two two lunches and one one dinner
in a week right because that's all the
food you get like you're and it's not a
lot like they're giving you really the
food is crap so everything you heard
about prison is true it sucks right but
it's not a lot either so you're like I
was I was hungry on those days but I now
I had the plug on the paper so he would
come by like on the times when he was
supposed to give like me only four pages
he'd slide like a whole notebook under
there wow and then like a whole handful
of pens so then I would just like keep
stacking them up so that's how I got the
the material to even write the P I had
to trade my food for
[Laughter]
it but yeah I mean so high price like
trust me like I want to give it to you
as I want to give it to you free but it
cost a lot to to write that thing
seriously 420 Pages yeah amazing yeah so
yeah man and then but the end my my last
problem was once I finished writing I
had to figure a way how to get the pages
out yeah because you you you're not
supposed to have like an excess amount
of material in solitary like they come
through and they'll do cell inspections
and they're they're supposed to take it
so I was real worried about like somehow
losing this manuscript now that I had so
I wouldn't even go out to like the
little Recreation cage like when it was
time to go out because that was usually
the time they would come in and shake
your cell down oh wow so I wasn't going
out to wreck and now I'm like Folding It
Up in like you know bundles of 20 and
I'm like sending them out to my good
friend georan arson shout out to
Georgine too um who was so intricate in
making this book happen she sends it to
her friend Jenny Jenny mcmindes and
Jenny like was going to transcribe my
chicken scratch handwriting on this Flex
pen and you know solitary confinement
paper into like something on a computer
for me and she initially said hey look
I'm going to give you like you know I'll
give you a quote it'll be somewhere
around you know like you know a thousand
dollars or something I'll give you a
good deal da d da
so I don't hear back from her for like a
month he hits me back and says hey it's
done I'm like cool like you know what do
I owe you and I'm thinking like oh man
I'm gonna have to like figure out a way
how to get this lady some money and she
says you don't owe me anything he said
after I finished typing that story she
said that it affected me so much she
goes I just want you to win and I want
you to get out and I want you to get
home to your daughter wow yeah so shout
out to Jenny too man that was she helped
to make it happen and you know Angela
had like stepped me through it all the
way through Angela B is a saint she's
the bro listen I can't say I cannot say
enough about her enough positive things
about her she is like such a selfless
person yeah
like what she did to make this book come
out it's it's it was it was a heavy lift
man and she did it and she was there
every step of the way and she's helped
me and it wouldn't if it wasn't for her
uh you wouldn't that book wouldn't be
sitting there on that desk right now so
shout out to Angela Bona I'm in the same
place yeah like she made my book a lot
better than it could have ever been yes
uh and she's also the single most
organized person I've ever worked with
in my life man I'm glad you noticed that
too cuz I was like but see somebody like
me like I need that because I'm probably
the single most unorganized person that
you know yeah yeah her and I are a real
good Workforce because I uh I don't stop
I just keep working I don't care if I
have to stay up all night to do stuff
and she's very organized so she's able
to rain me in a little bit U cuz I just
want to keep working I want to keep
doing it she's like okay but we got to
do this organized and you know it's it's
great having somebody like that on your
team oh yeah it's it it was a godsend
man if
it man she's I can't like again I could
I could praise her for the rest of your
show bro yeah like she's that she's that
good and she will be family for Life
yeah or L yeah
yeah it's amazing yeah so uh your
book uh you just recently released it's
now on Amazon so if people want to get
it they can go on Amazon they can
purchase the digital copy or they can
get the print and it's very reasonable
it's a little over $20 yeah I mean I
think yeah it's a good read yeah it's um
listen we're really excited about it I
got up to like number 26 on the social
activist bestseller list I know that's
kind of like subcategory of a
subcategory but listen I'm climbing up
there right you're doing it I'm doing it
when you're doing all I mean this is
just one of the things yeah yeah it's
just it's it's one of the it's one of
the things that we're doing and it's an
important story yeah like
honestly and this might this may sound
ingenuine to people or crazy or whatever
right but if I could if if I could make
10 million people read this story and
not make a dollar from it I would yeah
like because it's it's that important of
a story to me and it's not because I'm
in it or because it's part like I'm the
character or anything like that it's
because it's it's from an era that we
need to make sure that we don't forget
for sure and it's reality I A lot of
times these days people are afraid of
reality for one thing but but it's
really important to look at reality and
to understand what reality is because
there's a lot of different perspectives
out there on these other things and it's
like the is what can happen to you even
in a legal system where it can on a
state level it can be legal they can go
in and the FEDS can take everything away
from you yeah this is this is America
right like we don't grow up in our like
Elementary School saying hey look if you
follow state law and you pay your taxes
you're going to go to prison for 20
years yeah like it just it doesn't jive
right and so like even when I'm sitting
in there in prison and um they we have
the Britney grinder situation
and she's finally freed thank God and
then but the whole time the
administration is sitting there calling
her um unjustly detained right and I'm
like you got like 2700 people unjustly
obtained here in the
US like my my actual sentence or my my
the length of my sentence was dictated
by the 1988 crime abuse or drug abuse
act who guess who like the chief sponsor
was
Biden oh
wow so it's like yeah that's why I was
so hopeful with Biden because I was like
he wasn't my first pick of course I
don't think he was anybody's first pick
right I don't even know if I would have
picked any of them but my point was like
when when Biden took office I was
hopeful in the sense that because he was
a part of that wave of mass
incarceration and the the you know crime
bills and all those things that were
passed you know during that time that he
was uniquely positioned to be able to
say hey look we got it wrong here I was
one of the chief sponsors of it let's
let's fix it
yeah it just hasn't happened yet well I
mean I think Obama had a chance to
change it on a federal level Trump had a
chance to change it and now Biden has a
chance to change it and nobody's
changing it no they all as far as
president you know I think there's
people pushing for it
but there's a lot of people pushing
against it which is is really you know
and it doesn't make sense either if you
look at it nobody should be in prisoned
for cannabis yeah nobody it it's
just it's both sides of the aisle agree
about that right like you could take the
most conservative like take a a very
conservative Republican like Mike Lee
Senator Mike Lee tea party conservative
out of Utah yeah and then take Corey
Booker a a liberal Democrat out of New
Jersey both of them agree that people
shouldn't be in prison for cannabis yeah
like so when you have Synergy on that on
both sides of the aisle like that it
becomes like a no-brainer right but
think but for some reason yeah like it
just keeps getting kicked down the down
the road and the whole time it's getting
kicked down the road there's kids that
are going to visiting rooms on Christmas
and the whole time it's getting kicked
down the road there's other people's
doors that are getting kicked in and
there's other people that are being
pulled over and sent to jail that day
and losing their jobs and just
like when are we going to stop that
suffering when when is that madness part
going to stop because we we can figure
out all the other stuff the regulations
the taxes the you know interstate
commerce and federal you know all that
we can figure out all the rest of the
stuff right but the we already all agree
on this part well and it's for something
that is a lot healthier than tobacco and
alcohol which are totally legal they're
you know they're they're not scheduled
they're controll they're controlled
substances and they're a lot more
dangerous they're a lot more
unhealthy than cannbis yeah I mean like
night and day like yeah like night and
day you know and nobody ever like goes
out smokes a joint and comes home and
beats their wife like that's not the
scenario right but the scenario is they
go drink a bottle of whis a bottle of
whiskey right and and happens right or
or somebody drives and kills somebody or
whatever the plethora of things and then
don't let's not even get into the health
issues of tobacco and empa and all they
might beat up some cheeseburgers you
might beat up some cheeseburgers for
sure you be or a taco truck totally but
yeah you know whatever we're fighting to
get it right right we're fighting to get
it right and I mean I feel like if you
look 100 years in the future 100 years
in the past they'd say we're pretty
crazy right now and we're doing things
the wrong way yeah so but you know every
day is a new opportunity to make a
difference that's right and to change
that's right and that's what it's about
right it's about like being that change
like for example back then it's it it
was easy to like say I'm an activist and
like post a picture on my my Facebook
and say oh look look at my plants or
this and that and then that's it right
right it's harder to go out there and
grow the whole field off the highway 20
like Eddie LEP did yeah you know what
I'm saying it's harder to go open a
dispensary down in Bakersfield like
Ramirez brothers did you know it's
harder to go down in in some of these
other spots where you have to go out on
Front Street right you have to put
yourself out there put yourself out
there the risk to in order to move the
needle forward yeah so that we can be
where we're at to where everybody isn't
in fear of that prosecution anymore and
it's like it's disobeying unjust laws
yeah straight up well the younger people
are getting older and the laws hopefully
will change yeah that's what I I'm
really hopeful about that actually
because you see that stigma that like
when we were young right that dare
program and turn your parents in if
they're smoking weed exactly that that
stigma isn't around for this generation
that's coming in to be legislators and
city council people and things like that
right so we're starting to see a whole
new generation and a new way of thinking
and a new way of like how how how do we
handle cannabis like how do we how how
does this work in society yeah I mean we
have professional athletes that are very
much in support and then there's ones
that don't talk about it but a lot of
professional athletes use cannabis Nick
Diaz got a twoyear sentence 209 shout
out Nick Diaz yeah big up to Nick Diaz
uh you know he he basically lost two
years of his career for Canabis and now
it's legal in the UFC yeah and then on
420 they put his you know that's pretty
it's crazy right like that you know he
couldn't fight for two years yeah but
like shout out to Nick too yeah because
of that because because of what he put
it on the line and and and went out
there right and said hey yeah yeah this
is what it is yeah uh now he's on 420
doing that and now he and he deserves
everything he gets going forward from
that because because he came out and
said hey look as an athlete cannabis use
is something that's part of my regimen
yeah and that's okay it's not Taboo it's
not crazy
yeah you know I mean and so the more
athletes do that you know the more we
can get LeBron James or somebody like
that you know I mean one of the bigger
athletes to come out here you know I
think we're further down the road on
that of course but yeah they need to
stop talking about cold plunging and
start talking about how they smoke weed
yeah exactly exactly especially for at
least the recovery part right for sure I
feel like almost everybody can agree
like loading up your an athletes body
with Pharmaceuticals versus using a
natural plant medicine I mean just on
the surface sounds better
anti-inflammatory I mean the properties
are so much better yeah Y and that's the
part that's the exciting part of like
wreck now right is that if I take you
back to 2008 and I go in and I pull my
dispensary crew together for like a team
meeting and I tell them hey guys we're
getting in a flower today that has thcv
in it and and we got one that has CBN in
it and they would all look at me like I
was speaking Chinese right because we
didn't know about isolating any of those
M like we didn't have any idea what we
knew like of course we knew the
Entourage effect we knew certain strands
worked well for us and certain ones were
better in certain situations some of
them made your heart R exactly some of
them made you tired and behind yeah
exactly so you knew kind of how to how
to balance it right just on because you
were you know using cannabis that often
and you were a connoisseur you said okay
like that's my nighttime that's my
nighttime joint right there that one
right there I can function on all day
well testing screwed up a whole bunch of
stuff oh manc percentage do not get me
bro it's
wild stop buying weed from THC
percentages please it's like the biggest
heartbreak to me as I got out like I
started seeing like none of the old
cultivars around that I used to like you
know what I'm saying so I know listen I
know they take 12 weeks to grow I know I
know that but they're special and they
were different you know what I mean so I
know the market is what it is right we
have to like people like what they like
and so you have to kind of feed the
machine and do your do your thing but
some of those old covars that have
gotten like bred out of existence
because either you know they didn't
yield the greatest or they weren't uh
you know eight week poppers or seven we
poppers they were too strong they smell
too strong exactly yeah and you had them
to where now we have this like set of
strands that are really like similar
right we don't get a re real lot of that
variation that we used to get no there's
a lot of gelato and gelato mixes yeah
runs and gelato I mean all these you it
kind of happened with cookies yeah you
know around 2010 ises when it started
and it just kind of snowballed into what
it is now and yeah uh purple candy gas
that's what people want these days I
mean but I think the old ways are coming
back Sour Diesel is coming back Cuban
black Haze which is an nl5 Haze yeah
that is coming back Northern Lights
people talking about Northern Light I
like Northern Lights I like Fort colins
cough y um and maybe we won't find it in
just pure Northern Lights On The Shelf
but we're going to find a cross with
Northern I got some Northern Lights
crosses and I think that's how it lives
right I think that's how we get some of
those cultivars that have been bred out
for whatever reason to be able to live
on is okay we'll we'll we'll meet you in
the middle now right well children live
on through their ancestors that's right
let's just try to make them uh the best
children possible I think doing the
selection process that's true that's a
very good point man and so yeah like
even with what we have with with profit
Brands man profit Brands is a brand that
I'm launching with Ricardo awesome and
that's what we're that's what we we seek
out when we do our like feno hunts and
looking for what what cultivars we want
to put like we are looking for really
specific things that we liked back in
the day cultivars that are buried like
in the Central Valley somewhere that you
know somebody one of their Prof or one
of their teachers gave him a old school
Santa Cruz blueberry or something you
know what I mean and it's just it's
Unique and it it might like we may have
to come meet the market halfway but
we'll still keep some of that Integrity
of that and that uniqueness and I think
that's what can set people apart and
that's what as you know as well as I do
as a breeder that's what sets you apart
is because of the uniqueness that you
bring and and your individualism brings
to your breeding program right we don't
need another runs no but but runs times
something else exactly you know like a
G13 or something might be G13 some
Romulan some romul in there runs Romulan
might be kind of cool Romulan genetics
they got some run romulans I'm sure but
yeah it's it's a you know and that's the
beauty of it adding adding to the the
diversity back into the plant yeah is
what it's you're G to get Vigor back
you're GNA get yeah you're going to get
a lot of amazing things so what was the
first first thing you saw cannabis wise
when you came back out of
prison the first strand or yeah Lemon
Cherry gelano of course
purple GDP so you got interesting story
with GDP too oh man the GDP man I love
her it's like it's like a tragic love
story like but it's
nostalgic shout out to Ken Estes man and
what he's doing he's a character I hung
out with him in at spannabis last year
in Barcelona oh yeah okay so he's a good
guy yeah Ken's crazy man shout out Ken
but anyway I I actually told him um when
I was in prison I actually we had burner
phones in there I mean or somebody did
and um text we text him back or hit him
on messenger and we're talking back and
forth about the story and about like the
role that GDP played in it but yeah man
it one like it was one of my it still is
it still is like in its pure form man
that GDP is special just something
special about real GDP real GDP and
that's the thing is like a lot of people
got exposed to granddaddy purple and it
wasn't Granddaddy Purple it was just
something that had color in it you know
I mean that or it was a seed made from
Granddaddy Purple but it was there was
that one cut the real deal nice chunky
buds didn't get it was a short plant yes
yeah it was a short plant and so when I
eventually was able to find the plug on
it up in mesino it was a guy named Jerry
Jerry Scarboro right and we go up to his
my buddy Addison brings us up there we
drive up to like this the cuts up in
mesino a little town called Willets yeah
and we go drive backck into like the
logging roads back there we come up on
on on Jerry's house we go up we meet him
we talk all day we don't even talk about
business at all and then at the end of
the day he says all right you know like
what do you guys what do you guys want
he ends up having like an endless supply
of this granddaddy it was like falling
into a pot of gold like we were the
dispensary that needed a supply so bad
you know I mean like I'm running around
literally James like this is not an
exaggeration at all the store would
close at 7 I would run around and try to
find the next day's inventory to like
one or two in the morning wow almost
like nightly because we were tapping
every grower in the Central Valley and
draining everything they
had yeah and you were the only on we
were the only game in town yeah so it
was like in a 100 mile radius we're the
only we're the only game in town because
the one of the things I didn't touch on
either is once we establish Modesto
passes a ban right but it didn't affect
us because we were grandfather did and
then all the surrounding cities pass a
band too yeah Stockton Merced you know
everywhere basically the Bay Area was
your next closest spot to get to go to a
dispensary right so yeah it was crazy
man it was it
was it it was wild let's just say that I
bet yeah but yeah that GDP is something
special it like the effect was good too
yeah the taste like I could I could have
like a car tray full of roaches and like
I would pull out one nope nope boom GDP
yeah I would know it instantly yeah
floral it's floral gas super floral
floral gas and there it was so unique at
the time there was nothing like it it
was so potent on your lungs when you
would inh it and listen the pounds back
then were
$4,000 yeah all day that's if you knew
like that was our plug yeah he's like yo
this is 4,000 how many do you want if
you're taking 50 of them it was $44,000
a pound for 50 of them right so it
didn't matter but it also didn't matter
when we got it back down on our end
either
because I think to give you a kind of an
idea a little snapshot of like how it
would H what The Feeding Frenzy that
would happen when purple would hit like
the dispensary back in the day was we
had run out of purple for like of of
granddaddy for like a day or two and we
were just waiting we couldn't get some
rich it was always rich or Ricardo or I
had to go up to mesino to get the pack
right so we were waiting for Ricardo to
get back or something it was just that
we had a delay so people would just come
in they look at our board they turn
around and walk right out we had other
good we had Romulan we had uh train
wreck you know we had a bunch of top top
grade strands but they wanted the
Granddaddy and that was it yeah so
finally I I I remember oh shoot I have
one stashed in like the safe in the back
like on like a reserve pound right so
I'm like boom I tell our processing guy
go to the back I tell them where it's at
I said it's the last one grab it bust it
down in all e put a 1/8 limit on it so
that you can stretch it out like to as
many patients as possible until we can
kind of buy some time like I'm thinking
I could buy at least the rest of the day
it's in the morning I could buy the rest
of the day with this pound like on the
1/8 limit 35 minutes wow 35 minutes it
was gone so now I'm doing the math on
that I'm like damn I paid 4,000 for that
pound in 35 minutes we sold $50 Ace we
ate the we ate the sales tax we didn't
charge we didn't charge the patient the
sales tax that was the top price for eth
Back in the Day Bucks 50 bucks was top
heck yeah like our top top maybe 60
60 if you're in the Bay Area 60 in the
bay you could get all day but like our
top like if it wasn't granddaddy it was
45 we wouldn't go over it but for
granddaddy we were pay we were paying a
little bit more for it yeah I paid 60
for cat piss back in the day oh man
that's another one you bring me back
with that yeah my boy had my boy Thunder
had a really unique cut of that wow like
you would he would be able to smoke that
in like a room and you could walk into
the room like 3 hours later and know he
smoked one of those joints in there it
still smells like catpiss it was the
only strand that was like that yeah it
was crazy but I love that strand yeah
yeah me too that's that's like uh if I
had to guess you if I had to say my
all-time favorite would be catpiss of
all the stuff the desert island I like
yeah it is the desert islands stain but
I want the ciss from back then not the
ciss now because I've yet to see I
haven't seen it I've yet to see anything
equivalent to what we got back in the
day but there's a several things that we
had that were really amazing yeah have
kind of been lost along the way way do
you ever think
like like it's like a kid going into
like his old house right where you
thought your room was way bigger than it
used to be you know what I mean there
there's definit truth to that yeah like
we remember things a certain way but I
think your memory can be a little fickle
yeah you know like you you want to
remember it this way but maybe it was
slightly different but you know who's to
say we're actually here right now right
yeah it's well I think therefore I am I
got tattooed on my chest nice that's the
only reason I know you guys might not
all be real but I know I'm real at least
totally yeah yeah I mean there's guys
theor the the theory we're all in a
simulation all this stuff you know I I
think that there's definitely truth to
we we remember things differently than
how they really are sometimes especially
with flavor but I'll tell you the one
thing I still remember rhubarb from when
I was a kid I still when I taste rhubarb
or smell rhubarb I'm like man cooking
especially when you're cooking rhubarb
on the stove you know because I was a
chef for a while and a lot of these
things are like from childhood
especially baking with my mother and
yeah gingerbread houses making
gingerbread you know stuff like good
memories the warm fuzzy memories yeah
yep totally yeah that's true and then it
it works in the opposite direction too
right like strawberry Boons like wine I
can't I can't get anywhere if I smell it
I'll throw up because I my first time
getting drunk was on like a strawberry
Boon Hill yeah and it was like I was
throwing up like red liquid the whole
night it was the worst thing so now even
if I smell that smell it's over with
yeah yes Cisco Cisco Cisco yeah I can't
do the Cisco it's the same kind of thing
it's almost idal I can smell it right
now that we're talking about it you know
you get those things and I think also
experience plays into like we can relate
an experience to certain tastes and
flavors in those things but yeah
especially cannabis it's like especially
when you're young we got really good
weed back then people don't understand
the weed was really good yeah so what
what was your first like what was your
first grow so my first grow was a
Phototron in a closet I had two
roommates in a one bedroom apartment and
we had a photoon with the top yeah the
one that opens up with the with the
lights on the side yeah and that was all
hobby stuff yeah you know it was fun and
one of my buddies actually took and I
went to go snowboarding for a couple
days I'm like can you water the plants
and I told him one tablespoon of fish
emotion he thought it was one gallon of
fish emotion oh no and so the weed I I
Tred to flush it all these things and
it's actually back when we thought we
could flush oh yeah well you couldn't
flush the salmon smell out of the weed
the salmon taste and so I actually ended
up selling it to somebody but uh it
wasn't stuff I would even smoke myself
oh yeah uh but yeah and then I was lucky
enough to be in the Bay Area so we had a
mix of all the best genetics oh yeah I
mean the stuff was coming down from
mesino coming up from La yeah we were
getting a lot of stuff and this is you
know 90s we were getting amazing uh when
the gas first started and I saw waves of
the purple where the purple was hot and
then the purple was not hot and you
couldn't sell purple to save your life
people wouldn't want it that's crazy
right but we also had droughts people
don't understand there was droughts
where you couldn't get weed there would
there would be like a time where you
couldn't even get brown weed you
couldn't even get the brick weed yeah
and that would that that used to hurt
like and it seemed like it always hit
like in Modesto anyway like around the
holidays man and it would be like on
Thanksgiving I'd be out looking for weed
instead of like being at house with my
family and stuff I'd be like I'd be like
anything just give me an ounce of in
Modesto we call the brick weed red butt
yeah so give me an ounce of red butt or
stress for 40 bucks I don't care like
give me something to smoke like that
yeah the drought man was real man the
drought was real and if you had if you
had saxs in the drought oh you could
kill it yeah then you can charge
whatever you can charge whatever 60 all
the way up what you want half $20 no $20
straight up it doesn't matter y wild
times but yeah so my brother grew a
plant or plants when we were younger and
we would move him into the neighbor's
backyard at night when my parents had
come home and because we had a fence
between our the neighbor's house yeah
and put them in the backyard so my dad
when he go in the backyard he never
found the plants okay and so that's that
was I guess first first Growing
Experience right on from some seeds some
High Times Cannabis Cup seeds that I got
from somebody back in the day okay I was
a big huge High Times fan I loved High
Times
magazines listen back then
that was the magazine that was that was
well it was like you like Playboy
magazine you like High Times magazine
and I was a High Times guy I love that
was way better yeah way better porn than
the porn porn way better porn yeah I
mean that stuff was a you know the high
times it was it got it inspired me to do
a lot yeah you know yeah me too it it
inspired me to see just like how PE how
far people could take it right and like
how really exceptionally grown cannabis
looks yeah right and be cuz before it
was kind of like always like you know
most of my exposure was like either
outdoor very limited indoor growth
experience early you know I'm talking
about 90s era yeah so what you saw in
High Times was like that was it that was
the Grail yeah we used to make beds out
of wood you know we'd have our 8x4 beds
out of wood you know we had air cooled
lights saw hes saw horses yeah that
we've done that too and you know and
then even uh the adjusta wing the big
huge Wing lights you know and air cooled
lights I grew with octagons for a while
uh okay me and my buddy used to use the
vertical growing cuz we thought there
was less of a vertical footprint so the
helicopters couldn't get us yeah it's
like the hel listen the helicopter fear
was real though it was real even I was
like the helicopters are going to get us
with their infrared technology and our
house is going to Glow purple yeah it
probably did you know it probably did
yeah yeah a lot of good times man it's
it's uh it's it's interesting and how
it's evolved into where it's at now
where you know we're like one step away
from a far pharmaceutical level yeah but
also one step away from real egg you
know we're talking about like tomato
farming I talk about it a lot you know I
have a lot of credit to the Tomato
Farmers out there you know I don't think
they get enough credit sometimes but
tomato farming is no joke like those
guys no any farming is real is real work
real agriculture yeah listen hands off
to hats off to all the farmers yeah um I
think Thomas Jefferson has a quote that
says something similar to don't direct
quote me I'll paraphrases like the
people that work the labor in the Earth
are like the chosen of God or something
like that and because it's true like you
really feel a connection when you're
doing things like that when your hands
are in the Earth and you're planting
stuff and you're growing stuff and
creating like that you feel it it's real
well it's so gratifying I feel like it's
a great you're connecting to something
else too and you're watching you're
taking care of something it's your
responsibility yeah and you know we're
all stewards of this plant uh trying to
make a difference and trying to make the
world a better place yeah and if you're
if you're working with cannabis whether
you know it or not you're making the
world a better place yeah so yeah either
directly or indirectly I I'll definitely
agree with that statement yeah for sure
yeah so if people are looking to get a
hold of you where can they find you I
know you got an Instagram page and you
got a website now yeah profit
brands.com so um check us out we launch
in all stores in January 19th so check
us out you can go on profit brands.com
and and find what what stores we launch
in you can get high price on
amazon.com um high price the Luke
scarmazzo story check it out review it
like it tell me what you think tell me
that you should have been in it tell me
that this person shouldn't have tell me
I shouldn't have I don't know um yeah
just any kind of feedback this is this
is my first book um I got to like gloat
over the over the holidays that my mom
had a published a son who was a
published author for the first time so
she thought that was pretty cool you
know I mean she got to kind of brag to
all the ants and stuff really cool yeah
so yeah we're we're re we're really
excited about it James we're really
excited to make sure that everybody
hears the story and just learns about
that time man like we we sat here for a
long time and we talked about that the
era of when of when you could go to work
and you could end up in jail of when you
could go to work and you could end up
robbed of when you could go to work and
you could change somebody's life life
because you gave him cannabis yeah and
we still keep we we still keep that uh
ethos alive and we still keep it alive
with our company profit Brands it's our
tagline is wisdom of the past vision for
the future and we really want to take
like a lot of that Legacy knowledge
right a lot of that Legacy knowledge
about growing and cultivars and things
that are special to us and what what's
special about the plant and and meet the
future with it you know sometimes we
need to use technology uh to to Propel
our vision but technology is a great
tool it's a great tool but let's let's
like stay grounded in what our values
are with this plant and I think that
that is where we we can find some really
great Synergy yeah so tell me a little
bit about your podcast I heard you got a
really good podcast yeah like I I did an
intro to the podcast it's called Joint
Forces with Luke scarmazzo you subscribe
to it on YouTube We filmed the first
episode we had a ton of fun and some of
the cut-ups of it you know the to the
thing I said somebody effed up and gave
me a
show and I really mean that like they
effed up and gave me a show but you know
it's it's we're going to talk about
cannabis we're going to talk about
culture we're going to talk about
current events music um and just what's
like what's going on in the industry
what's going on in California what's
going on in the world what's going on in
the United States those things like and
and how it pertains to us right so it's
it's really interesting we got awesome
guests coming up we got a lineup of
Magic's from uh cartel crew VH1 show
that was super dope magic is been all
love to me and super supportive we got
burner coming on the second episode he's
been super supportive with the brand
profit and with the uh Joint Forces
podcast uh we have the original crew
from CHC to get together I'm really
excited about that we're all just going
to sit around and tell stories and and
about the time and what we felt and how
it looked to us and all that that's
going to be one a really exciting
episode U Mary Jane a comedian a
hilarious comedian that's going to be
coming on one of our shows like we our
lineup is tremendous so I'm I can't wait
and it's it's it's exciting right
because now I get behind a mic and I
just get to say whatever I want to yeah
it's awesome yeah I mean these podcasts
are so important I feel like getting to
be part of documenting the history is
amazing it's a privilege but also it's a
responsibility because these stories are
getting get lost otherwise right so like
the fact that we can talk here today and
I can share your story I mean yeah for
me that's really
special but you know and there's so many
stories out there there's so many
stories that never get told so at least
we can capture some of the reality of
what happened of the past you know and
so hopefully we can learn from our
mistakes and right move forward so we're
not destined to repeat them right
exactly and thanks for having me man I
appreciate it yeah thank you so much for
coming on man I look forward to you
coming back yeah I look forward to it
man thank you so much yeah thanks man
[Music]
cheers