foreign
[Music]
how's it going everyone my name is James
loud and this is the James loud show
Welcome to my first episode I got my
good friend and special guest Mr Marlon
Asher how are you doing today I'm very
well thank you and it's my pleasure to
be here on this show today thank you for
having me today yo people it's been so
long that my friend Mr James loud has
been working on this and I'm so glad to
be here today actually here with you
today talking about stuff that we love
man it's great to have you here thanks
for having me man so it's been an
adventure getting this podcast set up
and getting this dialed in and you've
been a big part of this helping me out
helping the crew out you know I really
appreciate everything you've done man
it's been a journey and I you know it's
motivated me a lot you know and the way
I do things because I saw your drive and
what you wanted to achieve and today I
can finally say in my mind that yo James
is at his place of Peace you know so
this is a nice spot to be thank you so
much James as Mercedes thanks for having
me today for sure so Marlon and I go way
back we we've been friends for a long
time we met at a high times Cannabis Cup
in Amsterdam when I won the first cup
you were my first cup yeah in the hybrid
category in 2012 so 13 years ago yeah I
was partaken as a
I was actually a celebrity judge at the
at the cup at that time in performing
yeah and I was performing I actually had
the best time of my life after I met
James because James had that good good
smoke that I was looking searching the
place for we were all about it
man yeah it was all about OG Sour Diesel
the gas this is all kind of you know
cookies was coming on the scene and I
like cookies cookies was great but those
classic gas strains yeah man the OG
spliff that was the that was it for us
you know and we we bonded because we
were about you know actually levels of
the same strain that OG Kush from way
back that strain that I don't think we
can get it right now oh we can get it we
can get it nobody wants to grow it it
doesn't exactly you know farmers in in
California everywhere Farmers everywhere
they don't like growing it because it
doesn't yield as much as some of the
other varieties but LG can yield I love
OG I love gas you know I used to grow
some Moji back in the days you know and
I had a few rooms and I got a few pounds
out of it me and my good friend Judah
back in the days and you know we had a
good run from that that was one of the
most you know requested strain back then
so that was kind of a
what made me kind of fall in love with
this train oh geek that was the Exotic
of its day
exotic that was the one like if you had
the OG back in the day you had the the
one you know yeah it was it was the
strain it was the variety everybody
wanted you know like that nobody could
get because there was only a handful of
people with it and nobody wanted to
share it and it was expensive and that's
the reason why
we bonded so much in Amsterdam because
you know we it was kind of a
Awakening of Aroma when we smell that oh
she coming through the crowd bro for
sure and I must say thanks for you know
having it back then because
yeah it was great over in Amsterdam over
in Europe to have OG Kush was a rare
thing bro I would have been on a panic
streak because I had there was so much
sativity how much you guys smoked that
was the crazy part the amount of weed
you guys smoked I mean there yeah you
guys
smoked hard you know I grew up I would
say
go in and buy weed for the elderly yeah
they would call me I would go run into
the
so I had to sit and smoke the weed
before I take it back to him make sure
it's good so right you have a fair
understanding of what you know the good
stuff is yeah and you've experienced
cannabis for a long time yeah a long
time so you've seen the evolution of it
and how it's changed into the wreck
market today
uh so a little bit about my show what
we're doing is a blind tasting on each
episode so we have three different uh
products that are from the California
rec market and we're gonna sample each
one in a blind fashion and we have one
that's a five dollar gram uh one that's
around 10 and then one that's more than
15.
uh that's the premium exotic and so
we're doing a blind tasting we're gonna
see how these different products are you
know I'm gonna get some feedback from
Marlon and we're gonna see how his
palette works but let me say
before we go forward that sometime the
five dollar gram
can't have that taste that people you
know really hold on to other than the
the 80 grams you know sometimes oh man
you said the words it can go both ways I
mean it's really expensive it's trash
and I've seen stuff really cheap that's
amazing I mean
so this should this should be excited
because you know
sometimes you know the herbs that we
test
you know brings out something special
and we hold fast to it so I'll see where
it goes from here and what I'm smoking
after today so what are your thoughts on
outdoor versus indoor do you have a
preference on outdoor versus indoor well
I like indoor but outdoor to me carries
the flavor that I like you know it's
kind of how about the effect the effect
is different from the indoor indoor is
more uh if it's a if it's Indica it's
more down a Vibe but the outdoor Indica
gives you an upliftment that you you
know you appreciate yeah so sometimes
outdoor Is Not a Bad Thing OG outdoor is
amazing especially especially though
yeah it's a trip it's a trip you know
all these different varieties living
soil the living soil indoors yeah I like
it exactly that's hands down that's why
I say sometimes indoor I'm okay with
smoking cocoa I smoke cocoa yeah indoor
all the time uh I don't mind salt but I
do really enjoy living soil living soil
is is I think it's literally I think
it's actually what's leading in the
market right now so
a living side spliff is always nice to
compliment today you know what I'm
saying totally I feel like yeah you
can't go wrong typically definitely so
this is the first one all right let's
Light It Up
are you scared I'm I'm probably
sometimes you know how it is we get some
weed and we can I gotta drive home you
know so I gotta be careful of what I
smoke it's a nice gesture but come on
I'm scared a little
foreign
[Music]
from first days what do you think
there's flavor hmm
there's flavor in that one
it's got some breadiness to it
a little creaminess little breadiness
I could taste that creaminess that's
good that's a good thing that flavor is
there
flavor's there yes it's good
got that notice but all right so if you
had to guess
oh you get another couple hits in yeah
or one more and then you can tell me do
you think that is the five dollar or
less the ten dollar or less or the 15.
that's definitely the ten dollars a left
ten dollars or less yeah has definitely
the ten dollars are left
I mean it tastes good oil
we're not getting too much of an oil
rings it's kind of starting but it's not
burning clean look that's not
it's not white ash no not white ash by
any means definitely ten dollars
so 10 and under yeah
okay
well we give it that
I hope I'm right because it's got nice
flavor you know what I'm saying it goes
it it goes good
it's not ten and under 10 enough I did
it yep yeah that's it I I knew it it's
it's just that it's got the flavor but
it doesn't do anything otherwise than
that you know yeah
it's a good smoke though I would like to
smoke that like late evening you know
that's uh so the effects let's talk
about the effect I mean I feel like it's
mellow it says it's over 30 THC I don't
think so I I don't think so I think it's
a I I don't know man I don't know I mean
if it is I don't know I'm gonna take one
more hit just all right just to confirm
let me take another hit just to comfort
over 30
I don't know you must feel the effect
from uh you take a draw of the weed and
you say it gives you a feeling it could
creep on you too you know sometimes we
get some creeper weed yeah we know about
creeper
all right
not bad it could be could be a monster
so we got some Burr's crate well first
place grape and Chris see now maybe it
is 30 yeah I'm feeling it now it's
creeping up on me a little bit burst
place and it's grape and cream
and it says it's above 30 this probably
is I can feel it I don't think it's
above 30 30 should rock your world I
think it's just about 30 percent yep
well if it was above 30 percent I would
be flavor is good though
yeah I would be happy as a consumer
buying this for that price point yeah
it's just where it's at it's just where
it's at I mean in California that is a
good deal that's value bargain weed you
know a lot of people shop
and buy weed around that average area 10
and under you know we're gonna dive into
number two yeah
and let's see what you think
so tell me about Trinidad and the
legalization over there I think they've
been pushing forward with it yeah man
I'm about to get a
cultivation license and distribution
probably
or Transportation at least lies in over
there they've been working on
performing uh cannabis committee so
I'm kind of waiting around for them to
issue the license which they are about
to issue
the first 10 lives now on the island so
I think imma be part of that first
tenant
they've come a long way I must say you
know because they've been working really
hard
to meet standards and not
be overboard so yeah they're actually
taking their appropriate time to do the
right things how's our good friend Dr
Green Mr Marcus this is the Marcus Green
Mike the king of the hot sauce yeah you
know he tried politics just the other
day and you know he's he's doing well I
must say you know for himself yeah of
course it's Mr Green we all know yeah
he's a very educated man you know he's a
very educated yeah definitely and he'll
kill you with his hot sauce oh
definitely he eats a lot that was my
first experience with Trinidad hot sauce
oh yeah like literally uh well I must
apologize for it being Mr Green cause he
do yeah go heavy on the he goes heavy
yeah on the hot sauce hot sauce and weed
he gets high as [ __ ] he loves getting
high
um so we went to Trinidad and we went to
uh Saint Vincent together in 2019. yeah
we had an adventure over there working
with the Cannabis Authority
uh over there you know we gave we gave a
lecture That was supposed to be a
30-minute election I think it ended up
being like a three-hour lecture uh
what are your thoughts on uh Saint
Vincent in their future
well Saint Vincent for me I think you
know Saint Vincent is very promising as
far as the herbs go they trying to be
Pioneers in everything they're doing so
definitely in the future they're going
to be a top runner for the Caribbean
they already stare ahead in their
programs and yes you see we've been
there it's a special place yeah it's
definitely a special place especially
the soil they got they got lava molten
lava yeah that you know covers the land
from time to time so they
they always got fresh soil and they have
some of the poorest people that I've
ever seen yeah yeah definitely some of
the happiest people too and some of the
most uh enlightened people for sure at
the same time it's a it's a nice place
to be we probably be going back there
soon yeah you grew up going there right
yeah vacations and stuff like yeah well
vacation no but I always I got friends
that I always go visit and it's always
you know when you leave your home and go
to yeah exactly when you leave your home
and go to a different Island it's always
party time and then
you leave in your country to go there
and Sample the weed that's in that
island so
back then
the Vinci the Saint Vincent weed was
like top number one on my Island so
describe the Vinci weed for us well like
the weed now or the wheat the weed back
in the back in the day what you guys
loved about the Vinci wheat was it the
effect or was it the flavor I mean you
guys did a lot of roll-ons too right
yeah but I think it's a combination of a
lot of things that made that weed
special all right
all right for instance this weed was
fluorescent yellow
fluorescent yellow like spongy or like
dry and hard not spongy not spongy so
completely dry not it's dry but it's not
spongy huh and it's not hard either but
there was a lot of trichomes
there was a lot of trichomes it was
properly grown and properly well trimmed
wow so you could actually see was there
seeds in it it was seeds there was lots
of seeds and there were seeds man I wish
you would have saved those seeds for me
back then I had no idea that we would
have been doing what we're doing what
we're doing today totally and that's the
thing about life you know It prepares
you for a lot of things that you don't
understand because as soon
this video as soon as you finally see it
you go and put it in the Earth for sure
because you want to grow something like
this right so back then we'll be
collecting the seeds and growing them
out and
you know having
not being able to grow it right and get
a bunch from it but we would get a smoke
right a couple buds on a branch and yeah
it used to be
because
control the seeds were not controlled so
they couldn't heal the same thing every
time right so man so how do you can a
quick question how do you compare it to
Orange Hill man Orange Hill is different
in what ways well Orange Hill The Strain
in Orange Hill is a land race train that
yeah
that is stands out you know I I can't
even knocks you on your ass
the thing about that Orange Hill weed is
you get it today you smoke it tomorrow
it's the same effect every time yeah
you can get a different smoke of it so
well let's jump into this what do you
think this is do you think this is the
five dollar or less do you think this is
the
15 or more it's probably
it's pretty good pretty good I I'm
actually really surprised I surprised I
mean we got an oil ring on this thing
yeah but it's five dollars though yep
but I know it's like that is because
here what that's a bargain right there
yeah and I feel like it gets you high
like I feel high from this yeah more
High than from the other one but but the
thing about this fight another spliff
that
with me I feel high while I'm smoking it
but as we stop now
I feel yeah I believe
this is a 13 eighth
this is Republic Riverview Farms
gushments gushments yeah
gushments we got Smalls of gushments it
was it was it was good bargain weed dude
check out the buds though so it's all
smalls yeah you're getting small I mean
they're good Smalls though like
I think it smells delicious but while
I'm smoking and I'm feeling the high but
as we stop now it went away so that's
why I think it was five dollars
yeah it's interesting yeah it's it's
hard to I mean but if you compare these
I think that's pretty accurate yeah yeah
like as far as quality goes
oh man I might have tricked you by
putting a another five dollar one here
you just never know oh let's see yeah
let's see what let's see what goes
so tell us a little bit about Jamaica
you just got back from Jamaica you've
been working with Don Corleone yeah man
that's an amazing man you know uh Kelly
B you know Kelly Keys you know amazing
writer Don Corleone amazing producer you
know I think my album this year is gonna
be
something that the Grammy is going to be
looking at so yes really that's the
level of music that I think it's so tell
us a little bit about your new album
it's a little different style I got to
hear it in Atlanta when I was there and
I'm freaking blown away because it's a
different style than that I always put
out you know how I sing I sing deep and
I like to go into the music that uplift
and really resonate with your heart yeah
but this this stuff just just
it's like um like blood to your body
it's a new style for me it's more uppity
beat it but you know at the same time
it's still the message that I would like
to carry right and portray myself as so
man I can't wait for people to
see what we've been cooking up you know
and you just filmed a bunch of videos
for it too right yeah Jamaica was nice
man I had I went to uh
Kingston Metro Sizzler my good friend
says La kalanji yeah we did a video for
a song that we did together it was so
much fun man had a big cookout you know
Sizzle is amazing I got it you
introduced him to me yeah that dude is
just amazing I mean uh
super nice guy
oh my spiritual
what do you think of that it's pretty
good it's strong bro this stuff here
is what I would go to this that is
Pantry for how much would you pay for an
eighth of that
75 bucks oh I think so yeah that's 75
bucks right yeah
this is a this is a this is the one yeah
this is the flavor
SF Kenna oh my God these guys are
killing it by the way this is their
zerbert so it's a
sunset Sherbert times Skittles and uh
dude it's a fire breeder too like it
just it's it's a little bit skiddly but
it's super gas like I like the candy in
it because it's not too candy if you're
gonna do I don't like Diet Skittles
right so like if it's gonna have
Skittles it's got to be real Candy I
don't like the half candy this has a
little tiny hint of it but it's super
strong in the gas yeah it's my taste of
the Skittles but
the gas comes at you like whoa gas and
there's cream there that's it's it's
nice it's really nice I would pay for
that I must say
yeah look how it burns clean I mean I
think it's a winner
this would be nice in a pre-roller too
I don't I don't know if they do
pre-rolls I think I saw this in a while
back but I haven't tried any of their
pre-rolls I'm sure they're probably good
yeah
they're producing good work I mean they
got a bunch of different varieties there
they have a skittles that's friggin
Ultra delicious
and then it has one of those uplifting
highs that's the one thing Skittles is
on what's that back flavor you get in
from there
The Bachelor I get cream almost cookies
from Girl Scout cookies yeah it has that
like creamy breadiness to it maybe again
we
oh it's interesting that's nice James
but yeah so we're talking about Skittles
and Skittles is on this upward Trend
it's become really popular again and
I've always loved Skittles you know it's
like yeah yeah the first time I smoked
Skittles was in 2014 at the High Times
Cannabis Cup in San Francisco I believe
Brandon
from third gen walked up to me and I was
with Kenny from tricome Technologies and
we hit it and I was like holy [ __ ] still
to this day I have that kind of holy
[ __ ] every time I smoke I'm like oh man
this is this is what weed should taste
like and I think if all the [ __ ] tasted
on the level that Skittles does
more people would smoke weed for one
thing yeah yeah because the first time I
I got Skittles I was like how did they
do this what did they what how did they
Infuse it with something and then they
were like man this genetic is going to
be the next thing yeah and so sad so
done Skittles is uh one of the you know
the most sorted after strain right now
yeah
let's talk about our collaboration so we
got Ganja Farmer Seed Company yeah yeah
uh we sell seeds together I make seeds
and Marlin helps with the selection
process
he's the face of the company yeah he's a
good partner too yeah
yeah we make good music together you
know uh ganja Pharmacy has come a long
way for me it's a dream you know I met
James and he fascinated me with you know
the the works of the seed and how it
actually you know is actually the engine
of marijuana and
I just wanted to be a part of that and
we've been doing a lot of good things
with the marijuana breeding a lot of
good strains and you know the process of
you know selecting for me has been
wonderful you know I've learned so much
about marijuana and James you know
I I was kind of a one strain-minded guy
but then I you know learned to
appreciate yeah you went to GMO you went
from OG to like GMO and then you were
you were puffing hard so you were
[ __ ] GMO yeah crazy bro yeah that
stuff gets you super high bro you quit
doing dabs in your smoking GM no
remember no actually the GMO reminded me
of dab so I could I could smoke and dab
at the same time that was my feeling but
at the same time
I made a lot of good music off of that
gmodo yeah that meditation and that
state of mind that I needed to be in
yeah was necessary and also
you got into like Lemon Cherry gelato
Pluto we like Pluto Pluto for a minute
Pluto was killing it yeah but you know
for me
get into appreciate the different
strains and the way we'd evolve yeah you
know it's been a process for me but I
learned to you know navigate and
understand that
the weed is a industry that grows and if
it's growing a lot of different things
will happen a lot of different changes
so it makes the world a better place
yeah it's good it's good I feel like
we're having positive impact we're
having positive impacts here talking
about cannabis definitely for so long
you know it wasn't a mainstream thing
and people looked at it negatively you
know good people even looked at it
negatively because they didn't fully
understand it that's all [ __ ]
changing
we we live in a world where you know my
parents weren't heavy smokers I I was
just about to say I would I never
thought I would see that day that my mom
would be using a CBD product exactly me
too so you see what I'm saying so yeah
my parents have a CBD company yeah
that's like uh sweet Wellness is the
name of their CBD company out of Texas
but they were against marijuana when I
was younger exactly dude Sanjay Gupta is
the one that changed a lot of it when he
had a 60-minute special and he had kids
that were being cured of their disease
with cancer
uh well with cancer with the Cannabis
see I'm high yeah it's a good thing
though but yeah it's not about James I
must say that yeah man but my parents
back then if they ever knew
that I'm involved in cannabis that would
have been bad for me because I would
have got a whooping my parents would
have been Invincible I mean they were
disappointed I mean because I was pretty
honest with them uh all the way about
what I've done you know I was a chef
I've done other stuff but one thing I
think we both have in common that very
few people have in common is that if you
looked at our 18 year old selves and you
told them what the [ __ ] we're doing now
they were like right amazing yeah
amazing you know what I mean to be able
to kill that story is that your 18 year
old something this is the kind of life
you get to live in these years it's been
a blessing man traveling around the
world's been a blessing man it's been
such a blessing you know God
has really shown us a way to you know
love what we do and get to you know do
it on a constant basis it's a good thing
that our work is our lives you know
totally yeah definitely yeah I mean
we're gonna be in Spain together like oh
how pain is going to be we get to go to
Spain span of this is going to be
amazing this year man uh I can't wait
let's go a trip you know the last time
we were there we were like oh let's do
this let's do this you know and this
time we're going back there with a plan
that we're doing this and doing that
yeah we kind of got yeah I'm not gonna
say we got screwed but covet screwed
everybody but definitely like right when
we were about to launch Ganja Farmer
Seed Company in Europe all of a sudden
covet hit we had this booth set up
a good chunk on all this stuff and doing
it right and we had a booth set up it
was a beautiful Booth they had like the
banners up and everything we didn't even
get to use the booth and so that kind of
put us back a little bit but it's like
all this stuff happens for a reason I
believe that I believe so we're on the
right pathway we're doing the things the
right way and you know a guy's a farmer
Seed Company uh is gonna take off yeah
we have so much more to offer now and
and then as far as you know genetics you
know it's the best that we can offer to
the world I think there's some good
stuff I think there's a good variety of
stuff so and the gods of farmer seeds
will be available on James lab genetics
definitely it'll be online soon and
everyone will get to enjoy what we enjoy
you know which is growing good strains
and getting good results when you grow
your strain and smoking good weed oh
yeah definitely does it yeah it's funny
we I don't think either one of us smoked
nearly as much as we used to but we
still smoke a good amount I can still
put it down especially joints I love on
my days off really unfortunate but I
don't smoke as much during the days as I
used to say that I sit down and remember
what I would smoke non-stop all day bro
it's like you don't dab anymore I I do a
little bit I do like the cold start you
know the baby dabs yeah you know if I
take a dab now I would fall asleep
immediately yeah I mean I got a pen I
love my pens I still use that that's
like I do have a pen at home but I don't
travel with it as much because I don't
really go to the pen how was the
farmer's cup so you did the judging for
the farmer's cup what do you think of
the the entries do you have you have a
good time there's a lot of products I
saw the video that was a lot of products
let me tell you this James people are
sure being Innovative yeah you know and
trying to be the best is what at what
they do yeah but you know sometimes you
got to really fine tune what you're
given to the world and make sure that
it's absolutely the best product cause
what I like for myself is what I want to
present to people in any aspect of sale
you know so that's just something for
people to think about yeah as far as the
family so did you judge just the flower
or did they you just extract in I I went
through the chocolate
there was chocolate entries yep I went
through pure rolls I did flowers and
then I did some like
like drinks you know what do you think
of the new beverages man
I don't think I'm all that too fancy of
the flavors they're choosing though
interesting I I really I'm a fan I know
that's like the next big thing you know
but
I don't know if it's a Pacific you know
cup yeah you know and that's limited to
what those people presented but
sometimes a thought is not really good
in taste yeah you see what I'm saying
well I think so many products
conceptually sound good like in your
mind it sounds like this is going to be
amazing but you have to do a lot of r d
and you can't just stop at a certain
point until it's right and I mean over
time that's like what we do with
breeding and everything else we don't
stop and I mean at least I try not to
just stop and go that's good enough yeah
you want to get we wanted the best
product yeah especially with something
that's going to be so competitive you
better have something that's amazing and
it's just like everything with cannabis
you better have a competitive product
these days to be successful it's not
like you join in a market where there is
nobody there to compete with and you're
just giving people something that
they're gonna get accustomed to yeah you
know people already know what they want
yeah as far as cannabis culture goes
right so you got to really come with
something that Wows the taste buds or
even their smoke so what's your new
favorite
oh man I just
can't even say right now my new I like
the Mochi right now
there's good Mochi and bad Mochi but I
agree mochi's good when you're in good
when you get a good Mochi you get a good
that flavor tasty
yeah I mean it's all about tasty weed
these days that flavor is to die foreign
especially like if you roll joints of it
I want it to taste good I was really
surprised with the samples today you
know not the sfk I'm used to smoking sfk
and I really like their product yeah but
the other two were for their price it
was not bad
if I didn't have a lot of money I would
probably yeah either one of those
products and to be honest with you I
figured the five dollar left in my mind
was gonna be garbage right like I've
seen garbage weed in wreck too that but
it wasn't garbage no that wasn't garbage
no you know it's like all three of those
definitely have their place in the
morning yep yep and I know in the market
there's a buyer for every
for all three of those there are buyers
yeah because people smoke differently
I know people that
thinks that you know oh I can't smoke
that Mochi it's too much and I know
people that
they can't get enough of that moochie so
definitely these three strain here right
here
that we tested today have a place in the
market and I would definitely buy any
one of them and smoke
I mean
yeah ish ish yes because you know what I
would lean to well no and it's always
like we want to smoke the best stuff
that we can afford right like there's a
price point for anything I mean I heard
about 1800 ounces the other day 18 100
ounces living soil weed
that's a nice that shit's crazy it
should be nice I I wonder that would
probably be something that we would like
it is I got a sample of it I was like
[ __ ] not the 1800 I got the thousand
dollar oh my god
um
sure yeah shout out to NorCal Nemo oh
yeah crazy big respect to them
uh yeah mind blown like the concept I
mean I'm okay with people live inside is
a real good concept bro I like it yeah
silence I always wanted deck on IG grows
so [ __ ] crazy crazy crazy living soil
weed that I really appreciated over the
last three or four years since I've
known him but man he uh he presses it
all I would love to see more Growers
Laura flame you know exactly what
they're doing uh
Lauren flame in Oakland are doing living
soil and they're doing it at scale I
would love to see some more of that I
actually like uh or even home girls home
Growers living soil yeah the cleanness
of the smoke is really nice and I like
the high from yeah it keeps you high
for a longer period too and it's it's a
different kind of high yeah you know I
feel like it's a different kind of high
this the soil
you know it's like uh
it's one of those things it's just one
of those things man yeah back in my
country in Trinidad there was this
string called Mother Earth
and you could smoke any weed in Trinidad
that grown in Trinidad but this weed
when you get it you know in this [ __ ]
especially you know yeah and that's the
thing about some good weed
you could
smoke whatever but when you get a good
weed
it often you know brings you back to
that place of
comfort and happy place and so
I definitely will lean more towards the
more expensive yeah really appreciate
you coming on the show dude oh man thank
you so much for having me James it's
been a pleasure you know just what I say
to all the fans out there look out for
my new album it's coming
soon you know are you gonna launch the
videos at the same time well actually
gonna be launching a few singles before
it yeah just leading up to the album but
it's about Productions fast production
is definitely looking we got Sizzler on
your own who else is on the house
Luciano Taurus Riley Massacre I got
Capleton you know it's a good
the next album's gonna have Rihanna
slightly stupid oh yeah
that's why we really into the you know
music like right yo I hope you know
people recognize us for the works that
we're doing you know definitely
well you're putting out amazing stuff
man I really appreciate you coming on
the show today
thank you very much if Thanks James for
having me bro much love tune in next
week for the next episode of the James
Loud Show
Keep It Low
[Music]
foreign