Yeah,
How's it going, everybody?
Welcome to the James Loud Podcast.
And today my special guest is Craig Coffey.
How you doing, Craig?
So Craig and I go back at least ten years from high Times events.
That's getting close to 20 years.
Yeah, it's interesting.
It's been a while. I mean, time just flies.
But you, you've worked for high times.
I feel like
you were
the perfect person for the podcast because you were a connoisseur of cannabis.
All I've ever care about my whole life.
I keep the main thing as the main thing.
Totally. No, that's amazing. And you love weed.
You know a lot about weed.
You know a lot about flavor profiles and getting high.
Well, when you asked me to come on the podcast,
I asked you what we were going to talk about,
and I was afraid you were going to say like work or industry or something.
But you said we
absolutely,
you know, talk about we're yeah, we're going to talk about weed.
And that's what I like and genetics and how genetics have changed.
I think that's a great topic for today, at least to start off with, is how
the genetics have changed over the last since you started smoking.
But before we talk about that, let's dive into your history.
let's start at the beginning.
The very first time I smoked a joint was probably in 1991, and within
a month of that I would say I was a regular daily
smoker every day awake and make it actually turn my life around.
I was kind of a bad high school student and the weekend got me really interested
in my first period chemistry class and out of nowhere, because of weed,
I became a really good student.
I graduated with a great GPA and got a good job.
That's awesome. Great.
We tell your mom I credit we entirely her graduating high school.
Nice.
And so you're probably around 1413 first time.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Me too.
So I was born in 77, 76, 76. Yeah.
So yeah, same years that was doesn't good year for weed chem dog.
That was a good year for him dog. Good year for a lot of things.
91 was a good year to this day I think that it's the pinnacle of weed
this can anyone I don't think has gone further than that personally.
No. And it's so influential to so many things,
just like the Grateful Dead. I mean,
and Kim Dog is a part of the Grateful Dead, the person and the genetics.
I think, you know, we talk about the Grateful Dead a lot on my show,
but I think there's a lot of ties to the cannabis industry for sure.
Even if you're not a Deadhead. Yeah, you like weed.
You should respect and love the Grateful Dead.
Yeah. Integral part of what we do right now.
And if that scene didn't exist, I don't think we'd be even close
to where we are today as far as strains and variety and.
Oh yeah, everything. Everything. Well, yeah.
I mean, I think Dennis Prone said it said it
best that it's medical whether you believe it is or not.
Every single time
you smoke a joint, it's a medical, there's medical benefits for sure.
You know, and I think
now that we're
older, you look at it, you know, we've been smoking since we were kids.
And I think it's only had positive influence on my life.
I can't think of a negative one.
Me either. Not not my health.
I wish I was I wish I spent a little less money in my lifetime.
The munchies for me, it's the munchies.
You know, It's giving me the munchies when,
you know I don't always need to eat so much.
Totally. For your life. Absolutely.
Yeah. And so you in the last
you've been in California for a while now, but you moved out from New York.
We first met in the High Times events, but hung out in New York
at the office, smoked weed in New York when it was totally illegal.
Now you can smoke it on the streets and it's pretty amazing right now.
I haven't lived there since 2015.
I went back recently for the first time in legalization. Wow.
Just blaze enjoy
right out in the public and all the places I've ever been arrested or harassed.
I just when I went to ah, I'm in.
That's amazing. Smoking in every spot.
And Times Square. Coney Island. Yeah. Yeah.
So genetics wise, what were you smoking out there
in California or my brother with me,
I went into a few shops and honestly, like,
there's got to be great we in New York, there always is great with New York,
but there's so many storefronts right now that I feel like it's kind of
hit and miss.
It's pretty hard to find great weed just up the street.
Yeah, there's a lot of mediocre weed.
New York right now, a lot of media just everywhere.
There's a lot I mean, there's a lot of stuff that looks good, too.
Or it's like, Oh, that's good.
Then you get to smoke it and it's the pretend ticker
you used to call it pretend to go back in the day.
So yeah.
So how's weed changed over the past since you started smoking?
What were the evolutions that you see and where it is today?
Well, when I first got into weed in Florida,
you read about strains in high times, and if you were lucky,
maybe your boy had something he said was some strain that he named water.
But in Florida, at least at the time, there was two types of weed.
There was Kirby, which was basically didn't have seeds.
And then there was everything else, you know. Right.
So anything that was like a proper strain growing out, right, without seeds
in the nineties in Florida was created and that was it.
Wow. I'd say in my life until about the year 2000,
I only knew I was like,
I didn't know exactly what strain I was smoking this, right?
Yeah. The next step in the evolution for me
was when I got into the high crime scene and started working cannabis Cops
as being guys like you and the people who were actually
doing it, like doing breeds and seeing a hundred different strains of the cop and
the variety.
Oh, so much variety and and then over in Europe, it was like this
big melting pot of people
that had all kinds of different genetics that they were bringing in.
Every year you see the span of business.
Cannabis is still very much like that, you know, where you have
all these people coming in from all over and everybody.
So some people,
they wouldn't even talk to each other except for the fact that
their passion about weed.
And that's the beauty of weed too.
It's like food.
It's just another one of those things that really brings us together as people.
I mean, one of the interesting things going on
and we now that all these laws are starting to peel back is, um,
we used to have little islands of people
developing great strains and we were completely disconnected
from each other because of the law or whatever.
Yeah, occasionally you go to a festival
and meet somebody else like you or whatever,
but now it's like you can develop a strain in L.A.
that within a year is a nationwide strain worldwide.
Like, yeah, it's crazy.
It's all global now. It's so wild. Yeah.
And I think there's good and bad to that.
Like it's kind of made the gene pool a little homogenous, in my opinion.
More modest. And I would like to see it not completely homogenous, right?
I mean, like, I agree and I think
we fall into these
traps because that's, that's how I describe it as a trap.
Because of hype, because of popularity.
We get excited about something.
They did it in Europe with Hayes, I always talk about how, you know,
in the nineties, like they homogenize the genetics over there with Hayes.
People got excited about Hayes and the diversity went away
and then gelato came along, you know, I mean, cookies,
sherbet, gelato, you know, lemon cherry gelato.
Then we have runts and all these things and it's like they're very much
similar and people, you know, and then that's all people demand.
And then the other stuff is like,
No, I don't want any Jack Herrera or I don't want any survivors, you know?
And but that's changing now to look at look at the scene overnight in New York.
So I feel like because there's so many people, we also have this
these groups of people that are like, no, I want some survivors.
I want shit that doesn't have a ceiling where I can keep smoking and keep
getting more. Hi.
Scarcity breeds popularity.
Like, yeah, like if you have a flow like people are Tiger runs right now,
take runs away for three or four years and that's going to be
the only thing anybody wants you totally.
Yeah GDP Nobody wants to grow GDP though so yeah.
Why didn't anybody want to do well in my opinion the reason people on
I love GDP but nobody wants to grow it because it takes about 31 days
to veg it properly to get big enough buds so that when you harvest
you got chunky bud and says small buds so it doesn't get big.
It's not a big plant, it's a small short plant.
I knew a lot of sour diesel growers in New Yorker in New York
that unless they can get $500 an ounce, it wasn't worth growing.
Yeah, look at that price at that time, you know.
Right. Oh, yeah.
The reason is just not a chopper, you know, I still love salads.
So everybody knows You don't.
You don't See, It's so funny, though,
but I think a lot of people don't even know what sour diesel is.
So there's some confusion in that strain that started
with the European diesel, which is not sour diesel at all.
The right thing
altogether like well, like Silver's New York City diesel completely.
It's it's great and it's grapefruit it's it's loud but it's not gas.
It's not gas by any means.
It's it's you know,
I was actually just talking to Soma yesterday about that
because we're we're working on some tissue culture stuff
with with the New York City
diesel is very different than diesel chem dog any of these, you know
and then we're talking about burnt rubber, the smell of burnt rubber
as opposed to fresh grapefruit Further complicate that strain with
the popularity of the name.
It became like rappers were putting it in their lyrics and stuff like that.
So anybody who is trying to hustle some, we wanted to call
whatever they had and sour diesel in the in New York would be so yeah
we went through a summer where everything in New York
that didn't have seeds was called the Summer Crazy, you know, Blue Dream.
No one wants Blue Dream. We're calling it.
So it is like, somebody told me once, if you love Blue Dream
that you don't know anything about weed,
But if you hate Blue Dream, then you really don't know anything about
that. Is 100% the truth.
I couldn't agree more,
you know, and I'm not the biggest fan, but I'm also I appreciate
the fact that it probably has the single best out of all the stuff
out there as far as structure, as far as vigor,
consistency.
I mean, you grow nice, huge monster buds and if you do it right, they're loud.
It's just maybe not the personal preference for a lot of people.
It's not what people want to smoke every day.
But Good Blue Dream is still good. Blue dream.
I like it because it reminds me of
in New York, The only access to reliable clones
that I had in the early 2000 was a guy that in Strawberry Coffee.
Yeah. And the actual Carl Cushman Strawberry
coffee is very similar to Blue Dream, I think in flavor profile.
Mm hmm.
Maybe not in tax policy or whatever, but totally when I smoke
Blue Dream and it's a blue dream, it takes me back to smoking.
And of course, from strawberry coffee in my head, you know, that's awesome.
And that's the beauty of it also is all these flavor profiles are nostalgic.
I'm seeing stuff coming out now that people are seeing as original.
I'm like, Hmm, well,
I was smoking that same flavor profile, you know, 25 years ago.
We had some similar stuff, like the Juicy Fruit, like from back in the day,
you know, And that wasn't even 25 years ago
that maybe that was a little less. But around that time,
we're seeing stuff that's
very juicy fruit, like juicy fruit, bubble gum, you know what I mean?
Like where you taste like you're chewing on the gum.
Well, those that's not an original profile. And
the lemons?
I haven't even heard the slimming.
Yeah, that's that name is great.
When you say that's what comes on. Totally.
Yeah. And I love those unique flavor profiles,
but they remind you of something very distinct.
You know, like Bubba Kush has this soapy ness to it, right?
And every time I smell that slurping is,
I think of barbeques, but I also think of Irish Springs.
So, you know, heavily.
And I love that.
I love that about it.
And the really, you know, Bubba, I think some of the mass producers
in large scale cultivators kind of fucked the Bubba market up, but real good.
Bubba Kush is real good.
Bubba Kitchen is amazing, amazing flavor profile and it burns to the roots.
Amazing. You've fire, it gets really high.
I wouldn't say gets you super high, but the flavor so good it gets you lit.
Yeah. So, yeah.
And back in the day, we had like, the Master Kush, the Bubba Kush.
The OG goes to a trend of more flavor profiles.
And that's another thing that, like,
I'm kind of disappointed with the legal cannabis
industry is everybody is just racing towards potency.
Now. And yeah, above 24 or 25% who even can tell the difference?
Honestly, it's like, I mean, I have some stuff that's 14%
my sour diesel, for example, I grew sour back in the day
and we had our sour crosses that were testing like 14 to 16%
and those will smoke any of the 30% stuff that most people have today
dragging the THC here.
Oh yeah, It'll get you some serious couch log.
So it's really interesting the recent debate on the word psychoactive
versus psychotropic and technically
CBD is psychoactive because it passes the blood brain barrier.
Is that the definition? The difference between.
Uh huh, yes.
So psychotropic is the one that gives you the effect, right?
Like the high in psychotropic.
And I've always used psychoactive psychoactive.
And just recently I was corrected
that.
And I think that's an interesting thing to share.
Yeah, it's it's all about those little details in life.
And, you know,
I also pronounce the incorrect a lot of times until somebody corrects me.
So I was saying GTP instead of tea for a little bit.
Yeah, that's yeah, seriously, what's wrong with you?
You know
so. Yeah.
So let's, let's talk about high times for a little bit, you know,
how did that start?
so I was working for a, I came up through college
with a network engineering
focus, you know, in the mid-nineties.
So like pre Google, you know, like the Internet
was still an infant, but I knew it.
QML Yeah, Excel and things like that.
So I was making a lot of really good money doing temp jobs
in, in Manhattan, in New York and I was also
like, I
would take a temp job, find the two or three
people in this office and smoke weed like I do in the week that I was there.
And now I have a new client, so I like it all.
Duct tape killed in my life.
Really Well at the time, right,
I one of these temp jobs finally turning to a job with a
a company that was building Ford Motor Companies internal website
and I was I was managing a pool of programmers
and then 911 happened and we were in Lower Manhattan, our office building.
So we closed.
The company never reopened
and we all kind of scattered, but we remained friends
and one of the guys that I used to manage got the job at High times.
This guy, Jeff Westin.
I don't know if you're out there, Jeff. I love him very much.
When he got
the job, everybody at the company we worked for looked at me.
Nobody congratulated him.
They all looked at me to figure out how I
that was my job because I was God's only stoner in that place.
I was selling everybody from the owner down to the receptionist.
We ran the place, you know.
Right.
And Jeff lived in high times for about two years,
got a job as the lead programmer for The Onion,
and he dropped my reference and that was it.
I got my dream job. The job I always bought for. Totally.
I couldn't believe it, man.
It was like a life changing experience. I bet.
I bet you're
just so stoked to go to work every day just to go and take the interview.
I'm going to go walk into High Times office
and talk to Michael Kennedy over high times?
Yeah, that's a trip job. I was almost enough for me, man.
I was like, I was pretty psyched. Yeah.
I went into the interview and Michael Kennedy, you know, rest in peace.
Michael's kind of an intimidating guy, like a serious, serious,
very serious player in counterculture history.
Like, Yeah, broke business, too, you know, it's.
Yeah, gangster at every level, like from the professional to the street
level, right?
And I go and I was nervous as hell, man.
I went in there and he didn't even read my resume.
He looks at it, he's like, coffee. That's my last name.
Yeah, we have a house in Ireland.
Our neighbors are coffee and they're good people.
I think you're going to do fine here.
Oh, that's great.
Amazing.
And that was that.
12 years later, man. Yeah.
So what did you do there?
You did the same thing the whole time you were there. Or
in 2005 as the
Director of Technology and Director of technology at High Times
means that anything that plugs into an electrical outlet is my responsibility.
From the toaster.
Yeah. Website to the fax machine. You like that? Yeah.
We were 15 person company, so. Right.
Well, yeah, you did a lot of coordinating too like
for events then as it I'm a paperwork and organization nerd that's really like
I mean I have this work style that I call Alpha.
I'm going to write a book about this one day.
I call Alpha Lazy.
I cannot accept low level output like I want to do big things.
It also deeply lazy, you know?
So there's a conflict inside of me all the time,
and the way I make it work for me is I go into a place
I find the hardest thing that this business is dealing with.
I take it on and I do it for five or six months to figure out ways to make it easy.
And then in six months my alpha leasing techniques have got me
doing the hardest thing in this company without really putting any effort.
Everybody thinks I'm a dynamo and I'm just maximum efficiency, you know?
Maximum efficiency, Yep.
So I was able to employ alpha lazy
in a really good way in high times because they were in chaos.
Like organizational chaos.
Yeah, they were just starting us cards and things like that.
We were going from the minor leagues to the big leagues right when I got hired.
Right. And they needed major organizational help.
And that's what I do. That's my forte.
So it's awesome.
Match Made in Heaven. It was perfect.
Yeah, I love them and they love me.
And it worked out great for 12 years.
Yeah, Yeah. The perfect storm.
I was great.
We did big things together, was high times, did big things.
You know, I think some of the younger people might not know exactly
like what went down in high times, but like we started doing cannabis crops
when changing the game, they would say to Europe to do a cannabis cup,
and there was no guarantee that we were all going to end up in a European prison.
Yeah, like there was no God like.
And we knew this going in.
Like that was part of what made us a special crew, I think.
Yeah. And people did get arrested.
Mila got arrested one time.
You know, it's like you make an omelet, you break some eggs.
Yeah, Yeah, totally.
I remember when they arrested
Mila that one year, and it's in Oregon, bailed her out of jail.
But, like, they arrested Mila out of all people.
Yeah, she. She was.
Yeah. She's tough as nails, though.
Yeah, she was. She was ready for it, you know? Well, she was asking.
We are when that happened we, we had just picked,
we used to do the Cannabis Cup at the Powers of Amsterdam,
which was like a nightclub right. In the power zone, its doors.
And we found a new venue which was much fancier, much nicer. And
outside of the city limits, right
to be a problem because the local police didn't know how to deal with this.
The radius, you know, totally with an army full of jackboots
and straight like patios all down our way.
And oh, I remember.
I remember it was pretty great. Honestly.
Turn out to be one of the best cops. Like that was a lot of good memories.
Yeah. Yeah.
Mila is marching around going from cop to cop asking,
How much were you in my order?
I think 300 grams was what the answer was.
Maybe 600 grams.
And she's like, look, 31 grams.
Take her to jail, right? Yeah.
Classic Vila.
I want to go to jail.
Yeah, and she did.
And she did.
Yeah. Good times.
The jail old man.
It's a different experience over there for sure.
I stayed in hotel her worse than that.
She also like.
Yeah. so has been in the hospital.
I don't know if you heard.
Yeah, I just talked to him today so some will know
which episode got, you know, he.
But he's out of jail.
I'm in the hospital
which is similar for so because he's like smoking
and they don't like smoking in hospitals I'm sure he doesn't like being
institutionalized in in any way, shape or form.
So That was when we were going to Amsterdam,
I would be
they would send three of us early, like a week early,
just to start getting things together, collect money
for a couple of years, who wants money and things like that.
And someone was always our first out because he would pay.
First of all, he would buy a giant ass was right to pay for all of it in cash.
So we go there, go to someone's house.
I'd have to take the next day off because if you ever go to someone's
house, it's not like you can do anything tomorrow.
And it's true.
Like a sack for money.
Just to get everything going right?
Yeah. And someone loves smoking.
Oh, yeah. So, yeah.
Love smoking hash, loves smoking, everything.
So you like hash as well.
I used to be a huge diver. Yeah.
In fact, for maybe two years or so, I barely smoke flowers.
All I did was that.
But since I moved to California, I've kind of gone back to flowers.
There's such good flower out here.
There is so much variety.
And like, we were indoor growers in New York forever.
You know, we had grown in closets, basements,
attics, you name it, like and I, but I never was able to grow a full sun.
And we moved out here and I'm in Vallejo and climate is beautiful, man.
I don't know if you guys know much about it,
but it's like sunny and 75 degrees, about 300 days a year, you know?
Yeah.
So we're full time growers now and I'm loving every minute that I'm the cover.
Like I used to think Express was the answer.
And that's not right, guys.
Full Sun is the fucking answer.
Yeah.
Vallejo has changed so much since the Romper Room gang.
You know, like, like back in the day, Mac, Dre and, you know, E-40, you know,
rapping about that stuff in Vallejo,
for better or worse, a lot of the bears changed,
but I think Vallejo especially is cleaned up quite a bit.
It's a wild place now.
It's still a little crazy, but I thought I knew what a bad neighborhood was
and yet but I personally, like I thrive in a bad neighborhood,
so I kind of love it there.
Yeah, I know how to operate in a in a bad spot.
Yeah. You got to keep your head on swivel.
You don't jump out of a car in a parking lot.
I grew up in Brooklyn, like, I know.
I know how to do it. So, yeah, awareness.
But that's just about life too.
Being aware of your situation.
On the bright side,
you know all that we're done talking about negative shooting.
Vallejo. Vallejo is a wonderful place.
It's a beautiful city with culture and heritage
and a very that goes to San Francisco and like it's.
Yeah, and there's access, there's restaurants, there's you know
Benesch is right there The San Francisco's close Yeah for sure.
Yeah I mean I think there's so many people move in there too.
It's like the property values went up like crazy.
I didn't think I could ever buy a house like I was a an apartment dweller.
I thought I was a rental guy for the rest of my life.
And we moved to play on water for something nice.
Could have never happened if it wasn't for
you got in at the right time too, because now it's crazy.
It's almost doubled in value since since we bought it.
The pandemic.
Crazy. Yeah.
And there's no houses available. Really. Like the.
Yeah, the
the amount of properties available in California in general is just
really difficult. So we got
a nice sized backyard and I was a little bit afraid that
I would have trouble getting robberies or maybe I'd piss off the neighbors.
I'm a New Yorker, man, you know, I don't know
what California people are like growing weed next to, right?
Apparently nobody gives a shit in Vallejo.
I mean, most most places they don't give a shit.
My my neighbors, like every fence that we share, a fence with.
Yeah, yeah.
And I noticed, like, some of them were just throwing
seeds in the dirty living to do whatever.
And they were like 12 foot tall males out in my backyard.
Oh, God.
So I bought a horse about this grove.
I was swear to God, this is the tree.
And I gave it to all of my neighbors
with a butterball who was I know they're growing weed.
And I was like,
you know, read this book
and let me tell you, these guys were so like,
you should have given them Danny Daniels book,
But there are a bunch of Chicano guys.
Yeah, yeah.
Or, Hey, everybody loves Hauge.
Yeah, Tell him he's Canadian.
That's great.
Classic.
in the Bay Area, everyone goes everywhere. There's lots of people.
I mean, most neighborhoods, you smell it. Yeah.
And it's also legal.
It's legal to grow in most cities, I think in most areas in the Bay Area.
Yeah.
Well, they cannot stop you in California from going indoors Some counties, right?
Outdoor.
Yeah. Yeah, I think Concord is like that.
They don't want you growing outdoors.
So long right there.
Yeah, I can't be outdoors but everybody totally.
Yeah.
They don't even want to mess with that in Oakland
because they know nobody's going to come in.
Right? Seriously?
Not unless they're going to buy some weed from you.
But yeah.
So high times and then the cups and I mean, I think that was like a big
like a big thing that happened 12 years ago
when you started doing American Cups. Yeah.
Like you went from doing one cup a year for four to not 20 years, but for like 15.
It was like, yeah, have a fun party,
right type stuff, attitude towards cups to a full on business.
Yeah. Six a year. 100,000 people per cup.
Oh yeah.
Multimillion dollar operation and Yeah crazy
and like and it was radio up here.
It was still a hurricane.
It was and it was still like herding cats for you guys
and dealing with stoners and people that think they want to
do business and I mean, it was just crazy from the outside looking in.
I think a lot of people thought High Times
was like 100 person corporations and totally like 20 people in a room.
Yeah, yeah. No, but it did feel like that.
I mean, to organize an event where you have that many people going,
it takes a lot of organization and you're going to make mistakes,
you know, a ton of mistakes.
But I was the thing I was proud of is like we never took a step backwards.
Every couple is better than the last one the whole time I was there. Right.
I'm very proud of that record.
We made a ton of mistakes. We fucked up all the time.
Yeah, but that's part of life.
That's part of life.
That's part of growing to making mistakes,
learning from your mistakes, correcting them.
So the next crop or the next event can be better.
This is how progress happens. We make mistakes.
We learn from our mistakes. I talk about that a lot on my show.
I think it's a it's a great thing that mistakes are a valuable teacher.
Yeah. And having
a small enough ego to recognize that like to get better at something.
Like you don't just learn how to play the guitar bad ass just right.
It takes a lot of time and repetition, you know what I mean?
You learn how you make mistakes and you have to have a small enough ego
to just keep practicing and practicing. Even if you suck.
Everybody sucks in the beginning, it whatever it is with not growing
because I think some people just get it right out the gate and crush,
you know, especially women, women cultivators.
For whatever reason.
I feel like they just tend to do better right out of the gate than men do.
Not a sexist remark or anything like that, but I think there's
a level of attention to detail on the female gender
that I don't think that we are.
Yeah, yeah.
And it's something it's so individual. I mean, that's just generalizing.
I know some people, some of my friends just right out of the gate.
I mean, I don't think right out the gate I was the best at growing
or even making seeds like I learned in the book.
I yeah, my plans to make I did every stupidity thing as a young girl.
Yeah, well, I mean, I remember I was excited to get a couple thousand
seeds per light and now I can get 45 to 50000 seeds for 4x4.
And yeah, I mean it's like, but that's the whole thing.
But you're excited that you got some but not realizing what the potential was.
And now that I see the potential of 45 that I'm like 50,000, no problem.
quality too.
Like if you've,
if you've never
experienced quality at the level, there's always levels to this stuff.
And so most people are exposed to this level, they get something a little better.
They think that's, that's amazing.
But if you show them this, then it's like, Oh, wow, amazing.
That's kind of how I felt.
Like, I'll go back to what I said earlier.
The pinnacle of cannabis branding to me.
Yeah. Can you one.
Yeah, Like there's been things that are almost as good as anything better.
And the funny thing is, is it was a bad seed.
It was a mistake. Yeah, well, I don't know.
I mean, it was God's.
Yeah. No, no, no, no.
Greg and his cut of very lucky.
Yeah. Here we are.
Popped a bunch of them and,
you know, shout out to the whole Kim dog crew, you know, all those guys.
Yeah.
We had skunked VA on a while back and he's, he's amazing guy.
But you know Mike P but all these guys.
GS Amazing.
You know, I think.
JJ Yeah, he's got a seed thing coming out now too wild.
Some sour diesel seeds have can meet him and give him cash to get him You can't buy
one hilarious face and Mike
right He's going to pick and choose who he sells to.
Yes our
diesel sees that's an interesting one because
I think JJ from Top Dog has actually done a really good job with his back crossing.
have you popped any of those?
I have smoked some that other people have grown to show me how good they are
because I struggled making, you know, I mean, we did a lot of back
crossings with sour diesel to try and that was a what he's doing
is what I was trying to do 15 years ago, and he's actually done it a lot better.
I think he started from a better place than we did.
We started with the spicy jack
times, sour diesel or spice, but we tried to recreate it.
I wanted to create seeds of sour diesel and so we like its base
base elements or through we have we have sour diesel.
Basically we had the real sour diesel.
The our crew had the real sour diesel.
The Cam's all the kinks come since all that stuff.
But I wanted sour diesel seeds but I wanted to sell
sour diesel seeds so everybody in the world could enjoy it.
And it was really difficult because we crossed
it was a spicy jack cross that my partners had made.
And then basically we took that and basically put it back on the sour
and then put it back on the sour again to find sour diesel.
And the spicy jack wasn't like Jack career that everybody knows.
This was a funky like pungent Jack didn't have that
you're okay change to it or not
so so some of them did but most of them weren't like that hazy Tropeano clean.
This was more like funky
and it went really well with it, but it was its own unique thing.
It wasn't sour diesel even through the back crosses.
And I think my buddy Micah that I've talked about on the show
took that four times back.
And then so we had four back crosses
and at that point we, we didn't work on it anymore.
It was, it was cool. It was its own thing.
There was a 70 sour.
And if people remember the 70 sour that we did
that Mike and I did together.
But it was it was unique.
It was its own thing, but it wasn't sour diesel.
And then we went over to Europe and mess with some Europeans
that were like crossing it with White Widow.
And so we had to cut over there doing some White Widow crosses.
And that's definitely not the right direction the way JJ did.
It was good.
I think there's a couple other people that have done it as well,
but JJ is really going through going for that nose and it's very difficult,
more difficult than what most people think because it's not always
a straight, straight and forward as it looks like on paper.
On paper it looks like, Oh, you do this, this and this, and you get this.
But there's a lot of things that can happen in that time period
where you get different things, quantum mechanics and play and you get so much.
Yeah, I feel like we have this real interesting
tie to cannabis that, you know, it makes it makes us feel whole.
Some of us, not maybe not everybody, but I feel whole from cannabis.
I get that I feel like it completes me to a degree.
Like I wouldn't be doing anything.
I feel like this is where I belong in life.
You know, I agree.
And I like
cannabis, like I have a serious A.D.D.
issue, I think.
Yeah, A.D.D.
issue from when I was a child and cannabis fixes.
And that's the reason it's undiagnosed
because I never had to go further than cannabis, right?
Totally.
Well, until the balance is. Yeah, right.
Like it does the same thing for me.
I mean, I grew up in a weed house to my parents are basically just like
I am like they my dad was singing in the seventies and stuff.
Yeah, they smoked weed in front of us.
Like a lot of parents drink water
in front of their kids, you know, like it was not even a thing.
Like, it wasn't even, like, hide it.
Yeah, right.
So for me, it's like you're on cannabis and dealing with
cannabis is as normal as talking to my mom or something.
Yeah. Yeah.
I would feel weird if it wasn't in my life.
Yeah, you. It's. It's one of those interesting things.
Psychedelics, too.
Like, I, you know, I struggle,
I love psychedelics, but struggle to embrace it
as easily as I can embrace cannabis. Yeah.
For me, it's on the same level. It just depends on what it is.
But like mushrooms and people doing all these microdosing When I was younger,
we didn't do micro doses when we were kids.
No, nobody did even weed though.
Like we didn't we were you smoke weed the high.
We didn't smoke weed. A couple of puffs and that was it.
It was like, we're finishing the joint.
We're not going to put the joint away and then pull it out later.
You know what I mean? Like, that never happened.
When we were young, my brother and I had a thing where we.
We were always smoking in the car in Florida.
Yeah. In the nineties.
So you didn't even want to have a broken ashtray.
So whatever had the last of the roach had the ether roach, I was.
Oh that's so disgusting. It's disgusting.
You better smoke it all the way down so there's not a big roach, you know,
But you guys weren't using crutches either.
So it was like you're smoking.
Smoking it down to the little bits.
Yeah, well, let's fire some of this stuff up.
Yeah. What are we talking out here?
this is Skittles season,
so I've been working on the perfect joint
for a while now with the tips we got Professional general on Instagram.
Big shout out.
He rolled these actual.
These are the last few I have but I run professional joint over.
That's a job.
That's his name.
Yeah, that's his Instagram name.
Yeah. I mean, if you want that job, we're looking, we're hiring.
So I think part of what we do
as James led genetics, we want to show the finished product.
So like if you're going to buy seeds or clones from us, you'll be able
to have access to the flower
to see the finished flower so you don't have to wait 90 days.
That's one of the beauties of kind of what we're doing.
But also I smoke joints like this.
And so what I wanted is to be able to share that experience with people.
And this is still probably a year out before we have these to market
in California.
But I want people to experience the same thing I experience when I get to smoke.
And so then they get to really get the full flavor of it.
And we've been, you know, so like, for example,
you know, with the R&amp;D process, we were doing some of these monsters
where these these are great, these are cool.
This is a five grammar, you know what I mean?
But and it's got a big tip, but it burns hot.
Yeah. So it burns too hot.
You're like, okay, yeah.
Like you lose the turnips like you still taste them
and it's still good, but it's just not as good as this shape and this size.
I feel like these are 3.5 grams
and you get the real full flavor and get clowned on all the time.
But I prefer skinny joint.
Like to me it's equivalent of like a low temp that you're not.
Absolutely.
Well, it goes through and it's not hot and so you're not killing those Terps.
I mean, this is fun. It looks cool.
It's like,
you know, all these things are like they've been researching for cigars
for a long time.
And if you look at the best, smoking cigars, some people like the big hot ones
that burn.
But the flavor profile is not nearly
as delicate on a cigar as it is on a joint.
you're looking for those subtleties and you want to be able to get those, like
extreme subtleties, not even just subtleties,
but like extreme subtleties with some of this stuff.
Can you legal and this I don't know if this is even legal or not
can you legally sell seeded find it like Sure.
So like you were just saying you would like people to be able
to smoke that we see the weed before they grow it out.
Yeah nobody packages seeds just like grow out of seed and put it in
and let me buy you.
You could, but you wouldn't want to smoke that bird
because it's less potent for one thing.
So. But you could, you could.
Yeah.
But then, so I mean that basically goes on to our model where you'll be able
to get our flower and see flower samples so you don't have to wait the 90 days.
And also we're going to have joints of stuff
that'll be in metric too where you can check it out.
We have, you know, tissue culture, all the stuff.
So if you're getting seeds from us, you'll be able to see the finished product.
You go to an event
and I guarantee you we're not the only ones that we didn't start this.
We're the last ones to do it.
I think everybody's probably going to do this eventually.
It just makes sense as a business model to be able to show
proof is in the pudding.
You know, we do QR codes with stuff too,
and lot of SEO is lots of testing involved with everything that we do
convince shady businessmen.
There's a lot of work to do.
There's so much, there's so much shadiness you don't even know what you got for
12 weeks, like, you know, or a year or something.
But the thing is, is I read a statistic somewhere
and so maybe somebody knows that's in the chat, but
75% of all seeds that are bought,
retail are collected and not germinated, which I totally believe,
but you may not ever know, like I believe it's a lot,
but if you look at how many seeds I have in my seed collection, I get it.
You know, I mean, like if you look at percentage wise of stuff,
you consider a seed to be viable for it.
Like if you store them correctly, you can store them for 20 years,
maybe longer.
I mean, I don't know about longer, but I know that they stay good.
If you control the environment and you keep the humidity really low and
basically take care
of them, you don't want fluctuations in humidity like that to happen.
To note the freezers to cold.
Yeah, you want to keep your so so everyone has a different opinion on this
but like that 55 to 60 degrees with really low humidity
that's ideal.
And the thing is is you don't want a big fluctuation in temperature.
You don't want you don't want the extremes
and the the you have it in a good environment
like that, the longer it will be good for and there's embryo risk, you know,
if you were to keep it in that environment and you were struggling
30 years from now, the embryo rescue 30 years from
now is going to be a lot better than it is today.
But it works very much embryo rescue.
Oh, did it embryo or embryo rescue is an amazing thing.
Big shout out to Justin, apical biotech, my partner, good friend.
He does embryo rescue.
I got to witness the non-viable seed somehow.
Make it something that just doesn't pop.
They do it in culture right and basically in a petri dish
using hormones and use it.
The thing is, is with embryo rescue, it's like a, you know, the game operation.
It kind of feels like that.
So they got a pair of tweezers where they actually
crack the seed and then pop the coat off of the top
and then remove the embryo like surgeons did.
They do they they absolutely
go extremely sterile.
You know, I'll give you a tour of artsy lab.
And that's also just this past season,
you know, Rest in peace, my little Big Buddha.
Yeah.
I had actually was a Lisa McDonagh
on former coworker from High Times had a
blister pack that he gave
us the year he won his first cup of the cheese.
I still have one, I still have one.
It didn't work out, but man, I really wanted that to work.
Yeah, I mean, the cheese cuts around them.
The real cheese cut is around rest in peace, Milo.
We lost a lot of friends in the last couple of years, but.
But, yeah, Milo's good, dude.
I always had a smile on his face. Nice guy.
Great weed.
Yeah, I think.
Had that good boy in England until I get my life
totally in.
That cheese is something special.
Something special.
Its own unique flavor profile.
He when we had the cup we were talking about earlier on when we got busted.
Yeah, they stashed a suitcase behind, like,
some art that had like $200,000 worth of seeds in it. And
me and my wife, Melissa and Jen Bernstein
from High Times smuggled out of there while the cops were put in a car.
He didn't know any of this.
And later that night, we found him at where was it?
Maybe it was Barneys uptown or something like that. Go right.
We were like, Oh, wait, hang on.
Got it. And brought it out to him.
And he started crying now, like the tears shed and they just could make out.
It was gone. Like, I bet.
I bet, you know, that would suck, you know?
But it's happened.
It's happened, you know?
So cool.
Lost all his seeds in the fire years ago.
Yeah, I always I always my piece of advice to people
when I was in high times is like, if you want to win the Cannabis Cup
and you don't have any connections to a breeder or court or something like that,
the best place to start from ground
Zero is just buy a package of cool online and pop around.
And the first San Francisco Cannabis Cup, somebody actually did that
and it was Vortex.
You called it God's pussy.
Yeah.
And Valerie Corral had go up on stage and give this guy an award for God's pussy.
All that's so amazing.
And then we had to issue a formal apology and correction.
It's actually more taxes and more hypocrisy.
So going do.
That's hilarious.
The first San Francisco Cup was pretty exceptional.
We were expecting eight or 900 people and it was more like five or 6000 people.
Like, yeah, yeah, yeah.
The police helped us manage the crowd.
We thought the cops were coming to shut us down.
We didn't know we were coming from New York to Yeah, we you hear stories
about how liberal San Francisco is, as in New York, but we had no first experience.
I mean, I still have friends that I met at that event.
I'm still friend industry people.
Mike from Gus House, Big Mike, you know, he's Russian,
I'm Finnish, so are Finnish ancestors.
And yeah, so him and I hang out still.
But we met at that event and yeah, cool dude.
Like a lot of good people, we were doing like crazy dabs back then
to like the rigs were completely different than they are now.
Working the front desk at that event, it was like
me and my wife and Mary McEvoy, who was a publisher in High
Times, was sitting at the front desk scanning every ticket of people coming in.
Yeah,
and we were all expecting like 800 people, so we didn't think it was going to be
the crush it was.
And now we got a line of like 4000 people right in front of us.
Right?
Basically at that time, if you came up to the desk,
look me in the eyes and said, I'm on the list,
I pretended to find your name and said, All right,
you know that for
future events, guys like that, I'm sure they don't do that, you know?
No, but when it's crazy, that's what people do, you know?
Yeah.
Oh. Oh, man.
But yeah, so that was interesting what I remember about that event.
And it was it the is it the Segway?
It's in San Francisco in the furniture district.
Yeah.
Right.
It, it was like a lot of cool couple of super cool
gay couple who ran a high end wedding space.
It was just a wedding. Yeah. Furniture district.
It was chill to give us our space to do our crazy shit and every little thing.
Yeah, they were super cool, man. They helped us in every way.
Yeah, I remember, though, there was, like, the poacher,
the guy who didn't pay for a booth that was selling
medical recommendations because they wanted you
to get the medical recommendations to smoke at the event.
And so there was a dude that was in a bus in
my buddy had a medical booth and he was so pissed
because this dude was making all the money because of the one there provider.
So they were just pumping out medical cards as a high times employee,
we had to act like we hated it, but we really loved that shit, man.
Like, yeah, to me, if the High Times Cannabis Cup
felt like the parking lot of a Grateful Dead shows and, you know, yeah.
For you know, Yeah, some shakedown street action
the whole day man.
Yeah and it's interesting the flower back thing because that was like buffet.
I mean Girl Scout cookies was a little it was there around, but it was like
just but GSC didn't win
until I won with the Cross in 2012.
That cup was also the very first time I wasn't competition
coordinator and that, yeah, they finally gave me opportunity to judge.
It was the first time I ever judged which emotional immigrant in San Francisco.
Yeah, Francisco.
Like I was responsible for ticketing.
Yeah, but I wasn't responsible for running that contest.
It was like one of the only ones in the whole time I worked at that.
That wasn't responsible for running to. Yeah.
So I could judge and kind of get some in.
This is my pitch to the corporate.
Let me judge so I can see from the inside how judging works.
I'll make competition better. Nice.
That's awesome.
Those old school judge's kids were awesome, too.
It was great. Yeah, great.
But it was the first time I ever doubted my
Phillips.
Our ex entered.
I want to say it was Ingrid.
I think I remember that.
Yeah. Oh, my God.
I had to take it afternoon off. I took it down.
It was the first time I ever did. Yeah, we didn't.
We had hookah calls.
Oh, yeah, for sure.
Next that
most people don't even know about us.
We should probably talk about the ways we used to dab before dabbing.
There was an atom smasher, which was one of the ways
that we was a glass pipe that had holes on the side.
And then you heat up the element and push it down on your hash.
Right from British Columbia sent us
a swing.
It was basically like a down stem with a titanium plate.
Yeah. Yeah.
And you didn't get the titanium red hot and put your dabs on it.
You suck it up. I think they call those bells.
They had the bell's the one, the bell that you would put the smoke.
I know you put it in there and yeah, that those were cool.
One of those.
And we started bringing some down back to New York from these
because that you couldn't find.
Well the first way we did DABS was definitely on coal like you'd
heat up a piece of coal and it'd be like an ashtray or a cool little dish, right?
And then you drop a little bit on and you either have a pen cap or
I even saw BHO like we were doing that with like bubble hash
or so it was even called.
So, yeah, know, people were making alcohol extraction stuff.
Yeah, we were doing that back in the day for sure too.
So but, but even like the old school bubble house, that's how we smoked it
before there was rigs and stuff like that on the, on the stove.
Yeah, but I did the hot knives on the stove,
so those were great for old school house, but not real high quality bubble hash.
It would like completely ruin it. You wouldn't get the experience.
You got a fair, you remember that?
Oh, it's like a little black box with a ceramic stick.
Yeah.
Got red hot instantly when you plugged it in and there were no on off switch.
There was no deadman's switch.
So yeah, you plug it in and you do a dab that makes you call so hard,
you drop it, you're basically going to burn your house down.
You're like, Oh yeah, totally.
That's really cool. They were great.
They were great.
I think it burned like 550, 600 degrees something.
And then the rigs just got out of control.
So they had rigs and they kept getting big.
In the beginning. They were big monsters rigs.
And there still are cool, big monstrous rigs, but most of us small
got a small rigs or now, you know, these these e like rigs we get the perf
co we've the car to it was always 90%
or more of go and then we recently got the 3D Excel chamber.
Uh huh
it's like a whole different product that's really mad.
It's like
not, it's not as good as a high quality quartz banger.
I think it's better really.
I'm a huge fan so I haven't tried it, but I like the Carter two from Focus Focus V.
I think I got it here.
We can try it out right now, but yeah, dude.
Yeah.
I mean, I'm a huge fan and you know, you're not having to get a torch like this
in for. Yeah, you out in public.
You know, it's a little weird when you see people trying to fire up.
I always thought the the copycat
give a double plus for convenience and innovation innovation
they skipped a generation of product entry like
like people were starting to make these e rigs
and then they skipped a whole generation of them and came out with their product.
It's like a level beyond what anybody else was doing.
I believe personally, yeah, this.
But I still would prefer a perfect temperature finger to it.
Me too. Me too.
So for sure I like, but I do slow starts, right?
So I do the cold start where it's like
I put the extract in and I just heat it up as much as necessary to get it to smoke.
And then you get the most chirps.
That's my style.
I mean, everyone has their own way, but so this new 3D Excel, you can not only
control the temperature very accurately, you can control the airflow.
So you can kind of like tweak how hot or folded up is and how dense
like how much resistance you get when you put on the nice pretty nice hands.
Pretty nice. Yeah.
We're going to have to do it side by side on one of these shows like
Perfect versus car to
so that's hilarious.
I feel like
as we've gotten older and as I've gotten older, but like looking at the industry
now with what the industry has become, we really need to be united
and not like, Fuck this person, fuck that person, the ones that are here.
Let's, let's fucking give
props to everybody for even being here for, for even being around this long.
If you're a legal brand, big ups.
Glad you're still doing it. Deal like that's what it's all about.
I mean, people talk about wanting to go back to the black market.
It's like that doesn't make any sense.
We just need to figure out how to do it right with what we're doing now.
And I mean, I love seeing these seed companies thrive.
I love seeing new genetics.
I love seeing innovation, all the stuff.
But we need to like unite as a group seven people to jail for.
Absolutely. You don't know.
No one belongs in jail for weed.
And if you can and if you could.
Yeah, if you could fill a room full of cartons of cigarets
and another room for alcohol, you should be able to fill your house full
of as much fucking weed as you want and preserve it,
because weed can be preserved for a good amount of time.
I think it's silly to worry about anything, that kind of stuff.
There's so many other things like homeless that we should be worried about.
You know, the homeless situation is all fucked, but that's all.
I tried to talk about Too many depressing things, you know, but being in the bear.
Oh, yeah.
Especially when there's so many good things like the cannabis cups to discuss.
I don't
sense since I left, I can't really see
you haven't experienced the Emerald Cups or anything like that that I go to.
Yeah, I live and I go to
I like to buy there people running it or super cool Timberlake Those guys.
Yeah, they do a great job with everything they do, but
they really care about the weed.
I think that's, that's part of it for sure.
The passion and about the meeting the focus on the product
and not about our money.
Yeah.
As a former high Times employee, I want to put this on the record.
I know a lot of people claim that our contest may have been corrupt.
There's absolutely not.
Never, not once ever.
We made a system
to allow a group of people to pick out what the best weed was.
It was a system. Perfect note.
It got better every year for sure. Occasionally.
Are there things that one that I wouldn't have picked personally?
Absolutely.
But we never put our personalities into that decision.
The system decided. Right.
Well,
but there was some incidents back in the day
with like where you could buy cups as a as a coffee shop every time.
Right.
Well, they're not even talking about another ball game.
The sure thing.
Right.
We allowed the somebody to buy a ticket.
Sure. And give an award. Yeah. Yeah.
This was it on you guys. I'm just saying that this is
just it became so corrupted by the manipulated, right?
It became a lesser reward. And that's how we treated it, Right?
The real award in that forum was a secret.
Just right, judged by our prizes.
Hey, I wouldn't be here today without it. Probably.
It's funny how impactful
I think that was for me in my career and being featured in High Times.
I love that man. I'm glad. Yeah, great guy.
So good times.
Good times.
And, you know, it's like we didn't go in thinking we were going to win the cup.
We went in there trying to put the best we could.
And the the thing is, is
I think the first time I entered, we, I lost a bunch of times to guys.
So it's not like I won the first time out there we had lost.
And so I had this amazing extract that we had in it and they didn't
even know how to really judge it.
And I thought for sure we're going to win.
Drove out to Seattle, entered it in there with my buddy and fucking I was wrong
and we lost and I think I saw the other stuff.
The other entries were better.
One thing we used to do also, like a guy like you.
Maybe Anthony would enter in the California market?
Yeah, I would go out of my way to try to get you to judge.
Maybe in Seattle or something like that.
Right. So you can see the sausage.
I want you to see the inside of the sausage as a competitor,
a guy who's putting in for sure.
Yeah. It's so funny.
I could have probably won two cups in Amsterdam, but I didn't enter my O.G.
in the same year.
But if I would have entered my O.G.
and I wouldn't have been able to share it with Marlin Asher
and me and him are good friends now, so everything kind of happens here.
Yeah. The guy's a farmer. He's doing great.
He's doing great.
Get a new album coming out and he's just a solid person.
But like I met him at that 2012 cup at the milk bag.
Actually, I think we met before, but I've got him some O.G.
and then they kept wanting all of my O.G.
Kush and I, if I were to enter that I probably could have won.
But I was happy with just winning one One thing, you know, it's like it was
pretty amazing the fact that we won it all because we had the smallest booth.
So the I can I can attest to the fact that you guys did a good job,
especially there because we weren't the Kelley connection was across from us.
And they had like this 50 or 60 foot long booth by 20 feet tall,
and we were a little ten by ten.
none of that, none of that matter.
And the thing is, is like my sales guys didn't even know what numbers
your entries were. Yeah, we kept it separate.
Two separate worlds and, like, untouchable.
Yeah.
one of the things we started figuring out so, like, you would come to the desk
with your entry and some people would see us
write our number on the bag, the code number, right?
And they started to it.
And then they try to figure out who the judges were and dropped.
Our number we call went to that early.
So when we started doing it,
you would come and I would tell you, All right, here's a table.
One is your entry right now would be the number I put in the system.
But then when we broke it down for the judges, that all got scrambled
with a second set of numbers. Right.
The team, along with becomes a team of 32 or whatever.
Sure.
Nobody knew that
how to scramble except for the three of us running the competition.
all kinds of things like that because you have to you have to do the job.
It was the best job I ever had, man.
And that to me,
the only way I can maintain job security, I thought was to run a clean competition.
That's all. That's all I care about.
You know, there were some years where Hype won the cup to do the hype.
So hype is a powerful thing.
So tanduay, which is so recognizable, that's the big thing.
Like it was so recognizable to the judges.
It was it was the most popular thing at the time
to put something in a box that nobody's ever seen before,
even if it's not the best thing in the box of judges.
I think there was one time in L.A.
where there was like ten tanduay entries to sometimes
you get that or it's such a popular cross.
Everybody's loving it.
The ten people in it. I mean, OG Cruz was kind of like that.
There was, you know, over the years, things hazes probably
five years were especially the indigo in the hybrid category.
If it if it wasn't like OG gas, you had no chance.
Yeah.
Over in Europe, the amnesia people were like, Everybody's got the amnesia.
Super lemon, one of those, you know, all of us.
Cannabis.
I've never been I cannot believe, my dad was.
He died in 2019.
Yeah, he was a world traveler.
It was really it was his main thing.
He was so mad at me.
He died mad at me because I've been to Europe eight times.
I never left the city walls of insurance.
Really?
Well, you get to come to Spain this year.
2024. Let's do it.
I got you know, I did my booth with Greenhouse,
and we're probably going to do a booth with greenhouse again.
But it's amazing experience. And you know, everybody.
It's all the same.
Yeah, literally, it's the same people.
And we, we all go out to dinner and hang out and
a lot of them, it's kind of like how Amsterdam was.
It's the one time of year I get to see a lot of people that.
Maybe I only get to see that one time a year or less.
And as we're getting older, it's just great seeing
some of these people still doing their thing and, you know, all over
South Africa, we got friends
all over South America, South Africa, and it's just some of the stuff,
some of the magic of high times got carried on over in the span of us.
I love that. I love it.
And when we didn't answer, it was really special.
I think like, yeah, it was absolutely.
I mean, it was a game changing thing
and it was really special, especially the people.
I mean, we all have great memories.
It's kind of like how I can imagine how disco was like once it was gone,
it was gone and I'll never be the same.
That's the the real high times experience.
Like after it was a perfect venue. Yeah.
We for whatever reason in an alternate universe, did the same progression.
But it was New York and not Amsterdam.
Like you would walk around New York for a week and never bump into another time
right after.
I was like, such a like a perfect tiny little capsule.
Like, Oh, yeah, every time I left the hotel room. All
right, when it's a small enough group that everybody kind of knows
everybody to like, I mean, everywhere you go, you see somebody with a.
Sure, yeah, I love it.
Yeah.
Good experiences and then celebrating afterwards,
celebrating Thanksgiving together with people.
And I would say the the high times because we're very tribal to a degree.
Like we were a tribe we had our own tribe of.
I give Steve Hager a lot of credit for that.
Yeah it's like ceded the idea that was his
he wanted this to be exactly what you were saying.
Yeah, that was what he wanted.
We were the tribe. Yeah.
And it's like this wasn't very rich.
It wasn't like an event. No.
And if you ever won the cup in Amsterdam, you would get to experience
the real, like, the ceremonial side of it, which was one of the most experience.
Amazing, profound experiences that I've ever had in my life
was winning the Cup and then the Cup party afterwards
for the people that had won previously and then the Cup winners
and nobody else does anything really like that.
And but very ceremonial.
Good people, you know, Amsterdam, old Dutch cannabis cups, too.
Like the sweet prayer.
Oh, yeah.
It's like a piece of art
by a pretty famous artist that you can only obtain by winning it.
Kind of. It's. It's a pretty unique thing.
Totally. I still have mine.
We got a bunch of other really cool
new ones, the US ones that were, like, real thick.
Yeah, they didn't bend like that.
You got to be careful with the European ones.
Like, yeah, they're soft, but really amazing art.
So yeah. So tell me what you're up to now.
Oh, well, when the world fell apart
in 2019, I kind of pulled back from the working world.
I've been doing consultations and stuff, but yeah, I've been going fishing.
Fishing? I see you're fishing.
That's great. I love fishing as well. I just don't have time for it.
There's all kinds of stuff.
I love that.
I just don't have time for because I have 5 minutes from the carpenter straight.
So like I roll a joint in my living room, I put my pull in the car.
Yeah, one of the car, like the joint.
I'm still smoking when I'm standing in the water, throwing it.
Yeah. It's awesome.
Yes. Yeah.
I mean, there's all kinds of stuff out there
too, but yeah, the stripers servers are awesome.
I mean, as far as work stuff goes,
when I moved here, we started, what am I, a brand?
Yeah.
And we decided to go the manufacturer rather than the IP licensing route.
You know, we're going to make it ourselves, right?
So I got thrown into managing a commercial kitchen for the first time in my life.
Would be fun.
Yeah. Oh, man. Yeah. Serious experience. Yeah.
There's a big learning curve, though, too.
I sure know more about it than I ever thought I would know in my.
Yeah.
And what I've gotten really good at is that, you know, back to the amazing
thing is how to take a home cooks recipe and turn it into an soapy
recipe calculator and something you can hand to a contract manufacturer
to start turning on product. That's awesome.
This is what I offer to people now.
You know, I yeah, I work with people. I know and stuff.
I'm not really fishing for clients, but like,
I help people bring products to market basically.
but yeah, the whole efficiency side of your past ties
in really well to restaurants because at the end of the day
it's all about efficiency
because the more efficient you are, the more money you make.
But that goes all over like that goes with grow rooms too, and cultivation,
even seed production.
It's like the more efficient you are, the more money you can make.
And it's not about money, but at the same time
you get to keep your lights on.
You got to pay your bills
and if you're going to do it, you might as well do it right.
And that's the same mentality that you've had is like
you've also got to develop processes, don't burn people out,
and then you want somebody to work with you long term.
You can't, you know, and some people can work really hard for a short term. Yep.
But it destroys the man.
And then what do you end up with there, seriously?
I mean, it's a struggle.
You got guys working 12 hour days or something like that.
No, it's sustainable.
It's totally sustainable.
But also as a business owner, as opposed to an employee,
I mean, there's no work life balance for what I do, really.
But it's okay.
I enjoy what I'm doing every day.
You know, I'm friggin blessed to have a job
and my blessing and probably in life
is whenever I get a job with somebody, I work for somebody.
Yeah. Take it on as the culture of my life.
It's not just my job, right?
That's it.
You embody, the whole experience.
Yeah, well, it is an experience.
And I feel like each time, as you go through life,
you can gain some more knowledge and some more experience.
And yeah, it makes you a better person to, you know, it's like better
learning who you are.
I think that's the big thing in learning where you belong in the world.
And the more experiences you have that you can put it into perspective.
I don't know.
I think we were talking about data points earlier
and I believe that even data points with that, the more experiences you have,
the more data points you can collect on who you really are
and who you want to be and where do you want to be?
Do you want to be working 12 to 16 hour days or do you want to work
for hour days and hang out on the beach?
You know what I mean? Because all those things are possible.
That's the beauty of it.
All those whatever you want to dream of, it's possible in this day and age.
It's possible if you make the right moves
in your efficient
efficiency is the key.
Yeah. cannabis, you're mostly smoke in your home grow.
Do you go to the dispensaries?
I try not to go to dispensaries.
When I do go to dispensaries, Um, I'm really into CBCs right now.
Antibiotics are great.
Nice.
Also high times down on there.
That's a nice good stuff.
with the smoke personally.
Like, even though it's not like I can a really good weed.
I know what I'm doing.
Yeah.
It's not always the best way I that's.
Well, let's dive into that
another level in the weeds.
So do you grow soil? Do you grow coca?
What are your preference for as far as substrate.
All right In a perfect scenario for me, what if I have a dream?
Growing room.
It's in the Northeast in December,
drawing in winter air to cool the room, growing in Morocco
with salts and and hydrogen peroxide.
Are you serious? God.
Oh, man.
I know you're going to be. Yeah. No. Nope.
No comment.
I grew up as a poor guy.
Sure, Me too.
I think most of us at least use it through a Lucas formula guy
with that same three part I learned about Lucas formula,
which is just like basically cutting out the
the grow portion of the two
part and balancing with just the micro and the flora.
Mm hmm.
Lower panels and more often feeding, you know, and the end goal
is, is something that's not going to play a role in the expression of the turkey.
And in this plant, like it's a neutral element.
Sure.
It's not always my theory and starting out in this and then I did this for a while.
I got the job in high times.
I got to try all kinds of products that I did, you know, Sure.
Of the kind of care pro line.
I had a good experience about and a couple other things.
A lot of these guys I don't really like anymore,
they all got sold to
Monsanto's or whatever, but at the time, things I really like sure,
I went to see Greg Can Dogs Grow,
which to me still to this day was the best we ever smoked in my life.
Really? That's awesome.
Fucking, you know
Cam Dog I
think does really well and it's very cultivar specific.
And also if I saw that.
Yeah, that's it.
That's it. That's what you're doing.
And I do an indoor outdoor right now.
you do it outdoor as well.
Salts. Yes.
So it's
often more often much lower
GPM feeding so I feed them like so outside you prefer that over soil.
I grew up Oh you grow soil with three part in
luger's formula of GM
and you're adding any microbes with
no earthworm castings in there with your stuff or teas?
No tea?
Not that I disrespect any of it. Yeah.
No, definitely.
Whatever works for you.
And I feel like you don't grow with all that stuff.
Yeah, I appreciate it.
And I love the guys that do that when you're a real smoker too.
So I know that you're not bullshitting because that's just amazing gift
for for you philosophy in that pursuit of what I'm going to grow my with.
Yeah, I just want something to let the plant do the work.
I don't want any I don't want molasses.
I don't want anything that's going to flavor the weed like, yeah,
I don't know.
I feel like that's lower ownership, you know?
Yeah, yeah.
Great genetics.
That's where you start. I like it. Yeah.
James Legendary sitcom.
Yeah.
It's for some strange others, too.
Like, I agree 100%.
Things are big eaters, man.
Like strawberry cough.
You can dump nitrogen afterwards.
So what are you going right now?
What flavor? So in 2019.
Former coworker I like a lot of guys by Norman Cusick.
Yeah.
Was going through some serious health problems and
we had just started an outdoor crop.
I had bought some clones, I had pumpkin seeds.
We let the males go intentionally to out the just left the females a little bit.
Yeah.
The next season we call those Q6 beer
Donovan Brook, who is recovering from some pretty bad stuff and
but still around zero so actually we grow
30 of them 19 females first the F1 round
we kept
all the males stored the pollen together.
Maybe we should have kept them separate.
We kept you homogenized.
All the pollen. Yeah.
So for the next four seasons
after that, we would lightly pollinate everything and only save
the seeds from the female that we're trying to isolate the one that we like.
Yeah, and maybe, just maybe, I'm work a free consultation of you right here.
Is that even make sense?
Sure. Sure. I mean, it's not the worst thing.
I was hoping that eventually I would get more and more seeds.
That expresses vino, but that's not really what happened.
I tend to get well using that same pollen.
Yeah, you're going to get you're basically using that same pollen.
And it's almost like a back process is what you're doing to a degree.
So I would
suggest, you know, like these are regulars and it's not feminized.
So it's yeah, so I would select a new male and a new female and
each each time through each generation, instead of putting that pollen
that has all this diversity, because each year you're
incorporating all that diversity back into the genetics, right?
Half of Yeah.
So and not knowing and it's like it's almost it's very much an experiment.
You don't really know what what you're going to get. Yeah.
No, no, no, no. And there's but there's nothing wrong with that.
I think a lot of people frown on it and they talk about pollen checking.
There's nothing wrong.
Everyone should be experimenting with pollen and making seeds.
I don't think there's anything wrong with pollen checking like that at all.
I think this product, this project is a pursuit of pure joy.
This isn't a commercial thing we're just doing.
Yeah, I've never done it before.
We never had the access to, a space that we could do something like this.
So yeah.
So my friend Gordon, what he does, he's in Grass Valley
and he
takes seeds every year and homogenize everything.
So it's like the true open pollination
and he's getting new stuff to throw in there every year and he's mixing
all the seeds together and he's, he's got his own reasons for it.
He'll be on the show one of these days to talk about it.
Really cool, really, you know, but nature
the most diversity possible, you know
so and everyone's got their own style and their own things and
but I would be selecting I would get rid of that pollen or or,
you know, save the pollen.
But like, it's probably not going to be viable for that much longer.
What are you freezing it or
Yeah.
Stored in the high forties, maybe 45 degrees.
Yeah. It's still viable after three years
and they keep You should just keep using the pollen
every year to see how long that pollen lasts. That's what I would do.
I think that's a good experiment because I don't have an endgame.
Right.
We've just been doing whatever comes naturally
when the feminized pollen doesn't last nearly as long, for whatever reason.
That's interesting.
So, I mean, we're working on some pollen preservation
techniques and using things cryo.
Question to I have for you in this free consultation, I'm sure
I've had more than one female that I wished I had kept a clone of.
What could I have done like once you're already like a week, three or four
or five of flowering and you start to get a sense
of what you're okay, You're okay, You can revisit the plant.
Well, I tried that and it never worked out.
Then someone has to show you how to revenge correctly. That's it.
You ravaging.
So they.
They say revenge and you lose potency and all these other things.
But a lot of
well.
So here's the thing.
You have a plant and you pop seeds and you grow those seeds.
Well, there's this thing called sexual maturity
that happens over a couple of generations.
So that's why when you are doing your selection process, your final hunting,
you should probably grow it out multiple times, right?
Because it changes from that initial seed run through the first
generation of clones to the second generation and the third.
And then they stabilize pretty good to where they express the same.
And so that difference that you saw that could have just been from
the maturity of the plant,
not that it was that different and maybe growing it out, but
but either way you would have probably got a different plant,
something slightly different.
And so that's why you want to grow them out multiple times.
And yeah, it's a trip like that.
And so we when we're doing our selection process, we're doing the final hunting.
We, we're going now from the first clonal generation
rather than from seed indoors, especially.
So it saves time for the long run and you start getting a better picture
of what that expression is actually going to be over time.
And that's what's important.
So When I was much younger, we just used to grow that once and that's the winner.
Or this is the winner or that's the winner. Now.
It's like grow it up
multiple times to really see what the best one is and how they change.
And a lot of times you have one out of 20 or 100
and you're like, This is the one, this is the best.
There's no way anything could be better than this.
And then you go to again, you're like, no, this is this is different.
This is the one this is better than that one
or the one you grew out that you thought was the best isn't quite as good.
So you'll get stuff popping up that's good and stuff that's not as good.
And they change. And
it's all about taking detailed notes and
also smoking.
Your product helps the cross that we have
that I've been talking about what we call it.
Q6 Nice things like, Oh yeah, the mother was a Royal Highness
female clone that I bought from Dark Heart Nursery on the legal market.
And the father I bought a ten pack of lemons
from Source genetics, Breast cancer school.
Yeah. And intentionally let them die.
Yeah.
And how is it? Smoke.
It's delicious.
I love it. It's super citrusy. It's hybrid.
I mean, the Royal Highnesses of Green Cross.
It's. Yeah, big.
Nothing special, but big resonating glands.
You know, a good person.
Well, you just mentioned Gigi.
I think it gives us a great time to talk about the High Times cup in L.A..
When they released the Clones, they did a really smart thing that I'm not envious.
I maybe a little bit. I think they did it right.
And I think it's worth sharing with people, too.
You know, I
really held genetics tight and close, and I we didn't let genetics out.
We didn't like letting our stuff out.
We didn't like sharing it.
We want to keep it in house because we didn't
want it to blow up like pale blue Dream did.
Yeah.
Jesse Weil's recipes.
He went to the cup,
him and his crew went to the cup that they won in LA,
and they were giving out clones of gorilla glue, like literally giving it.
I think I got five or six clones.
I don't remember how many, but I brought them to Sonoma.
My buddy Josh and other people, we all we were all growing gorilla glue
and it was the Sour Diesel people, especially because it grew so similar.
It had an awesome gas profile, but instantly within a season
it changed the game, especially 90% of the guys growing sour quicker on sour.
So yeah, and it was good.
And like they shared it and they shared they wanted to get it out there.
It was a really
business model that I think
people should be aware of and it's like sometimes sharing is the way to do it.
Sometimes it's not about how long you hold it to your
and that that strategy might really saved them in the long run too.
Did they get nailed by Gorilla Glue Company for copyright?
They they did. And then they had to beg for it.
But then was everywhere.
So it wasn't even, you know, was like, yeah, they spread the risk.
Oh, yeah.
That's a whole nother conversation about using names that,
you know, are copyrighted that are owned by other Disney.
Be careful. I wouldn't use any Disney.
You did.
Seriously, you guys get some Star Wars names?
I don't know like and I think a lot of stuff.
When it was the black market it was fine.
But then moving into recreational where you have businesses
in a business address to send a cease and desist
like a badge of honor, you contact George Lucas and get the paperwork.
Yeah, he's not going to get.
Yeah, no and I think a lot of guys were that you know
in business they wear like badge of honor where they get a cease and desist.
And I think it's cool, but it can also be bad and slow you down,
especially if you have something super popular and then you want to call it
whatever beer, name, Disney name, something that's already taken.
It could slow you down. So.
So it's a balance. Yeah, it could be expensive.
I mean, I don't think like even like Skittles.
Those guys would change the Z.
But I think Wrigley, who's also in cannabis,
they basically went after them and then I don't think they had to pay anything.
I just think that they had to change it to Z.
So you might get lucky, you might not.
And Starbucks got some of that money there.
I think. So.
Comedy,
it's it's a hard loss, man. I get you, man.
You don't want to be in the courtroom across from corporate lawyer.
No. And the thing is, is what I think a lot of people
don't understand is lawsuits cost a lot of money.
So even even if you win,
it costs time and even, you know, losing whatever, even if you're right,
you can totally spend an arm and a leg and it bankrupts companies.
Right. So lots of fun. Lawsuits are no fun.
And you know who wins and losses?
Lawyers. The lawyers. Every time.
Every time the lawyers win, they're the winners.
I should have been away.
My mom was right. Yeah. Great job. They do.
There's. There's a need for stoner laws in the Bay Area.
Sure.
Yeah. I still, even though I lived here
getting close to ten years, I still feel like a New Yorker visiting.
Really? Yeah.
You don't feel part of the community yet?
I am part of the community. Yeah. Yeah.
But you still feel that you get the New Yorker vibe to it.
And like, Yeah, In New York.
You don't even want to change. That's.
That's what makes you who you are.
I think especially now, like New York is.
I don't know if you've been there recently. It's crazy.
I haven't been.
There's like three dispensaries unlicensed on every block.
I got arrested in Europe multiple times for smoking cannabis in the late nineties.
Yeah.
And now it's like you can literally smoke weed anywhere.
You can smoke a cigaret, which to me is it's a beautiful another really nice one.
All they need is 12 plants per person.
If you have three people living in the apartments, 36 plants, it's amazing.
There's nothing that your landlord can do about it.
It's like,
Oh man, it's going to be a home grown capital of the world.
It's amazing.
There's a company and
I wish I can remember names of companies I would love to give a shout out to.
You know, Raekwon, the chef from the Wu-Tang
Clan, is an investor in a company that is trying to put
grow boxes in people's houses in mass that basically do everything.
So you pay this company to let you grow
your plant, count in your house for each year.
That's amazing.
It's like a service, like having
maybe a home, like a maid or something like that, you know?
So do you remember speaking of Wu-Tang Clan High Times Cup?
I think it was 2012. It might have been 13.
Wu-Tang was on stage and they called Rico up.
Yeah.
And he he had been drinking and yeah,
he basically he replaced old Dirty Bastard in Lincoln.
It's on you, dude.
We should definitely put the link on the show.
But it was it was an amazing performance.
He threw up Mid-performance and kept going.
And it was it was Ghostface Killah was the headliner.
Yeah.
And he called five, four or five people from the audience.
Each do verses of the other Wu-Tang Clan members in the song.
Rico is one of them.
Yeah.
And like he was possessed by old Dirty Bastard for about 3 minutes.
It was amazing.
Yeah.
Oh, bastard him through the mouth, was he?
Literally if you go on stage
at night, man, like we went to the whiskey bar
and everyone was like kind of a popular late night spot.
Yeah We didn't even know he was in there.
The whole High Times crew was in there and we're reminiscing about all that.
That was so awesome.
It was like one of the greatest high times moments ever.
And he kind of sheepishly came over to us and was like,
So glad you said that, because he was embarrassing.
Like an asshole in my ear.
Yeah, totally.
He was an amazing guy, man. Rest in peace.
One of the finest guys.
Totally best personality. Happy.
Some people, some comedians, some comedians in your joint.
And certainly these are right.
Totally. He was definitely one of those.
Yeah. Sad.
All the people were losing.
were losing.
what do you see happening with High Times?
What's your opinion?
High times now? What do you see happening with high times in the next five years?
I mean it's they have a great name still.
I mean, they tried the dispensary model
and it didn't seem like it worked out so well, at least here in California.
Let me say this.
I don't know. I don't know anybody who works for them right now.
Yeah.
Have no connection to any of them.
I don't it's I'm a I'm an observer.
And like, where I started when I was 15.
Right.
Well, every now and again, whatever, whoever did
the design on the storefronts for the High Times dispensaries now.
But I think you did a great job.
I don't know who you are managing a really good
totally a cover of a magazine
I drive past and I'm like, Holy shit, that's a fucking.
Yeah. Yeah.
I think they just closed in Oakland, right?
I don't know.
Yeah. Yeah, me either. I'm not really following along.
I went in there once too, and it was kind of like going into a high times museum.
I was really.
I had a really proud former employee moment.
Nice.
I have mixed emotions about where I am in the world right now.
Yeah. Out of that, when I went to those shops.
Good job, man.
Heard Totally, yeah.
Michael Cerrone I haven't heard his name in a while.
He's, he's got sweet leaf grinders,
sweet leaves, the original that was there.
That's the problem with that grinder.
Unless you lose it, you never buy another one.
Like I still have one I bought like 30 years ago.
Totally.
Yeah, I like both. So there's two grinders.
I like there's only two grinders elegance.
Sweet Leaf is my classic.
And then I like the flour mill.
I think that's pretty cool.
Is that the one where the teeth kind of whirl around? Yeah.
And they have different plates that you can use
on their more expensive model, and so you can get different grinds.
I kind of like that is a fun little feature and kind of Yeah,
yeah they're, they're super cool but of a sweet leaf, you know.
I mean that's classic like, that's the original original grinder.
Before that, we were using scissors or we were using our hands.
We, I was breaking up stuff with my hands.
I went through a scissors, the shot glass. Totally.
That was where I graduated.
Who like the whiskers?
The whiskers, The fiscal scissors.
Yeah.
And you go as fast as you can with this spring, chopping it up.
And but, you know, back then we were smoking like point 75 gram joint still.
Yeah.
It would suck to do in a whole life to get it perfect.
Oh God.
Where you smoke in the joint in the seed pops and shoots out like you can see
if it's dark. You could see him shoot across the room.
Yeah. Good times.
So if people are looking to get in touch with you,
they're interested in consulting you.
So you're not taking on really clients,
but how can they find you on Instagram or social media?
I mean, I'm on Facebook and stuff, but honestly, I find my clients, I'm not,
so don't go looking for them because he's not there and that's it.
You know, that's how you, me, I tell you, you make them and you become exclusive.
Yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah.
That's the false limited figure.
False limited marketing.
Yeah, that's totally.
I'm like, I'm a vibe worker.
Like, if I'm not into your project, I don't.
It's not that I don't care about your project
if I'm not into it personally, at some personal level, just
I don't see how I fit in and I don't do it totally, really cool, you know?
And that's great, great way to to be able to do that.
I don't think everybody is fortunate that they can
in a project that I didn't personally feel different.
That's nice.
Yeah. I mean I hope that
some I mean, I think Cup is doing a great job
Spano is is doing good and I think to do some cool stuff too know
Yeah a few guys from my era were like, Oh yeah, doing some of that so
I think you can call it.
Yeah.
And then there's Doug, Big shout out to Doug.
He hit me in Glass Chalice Masters like he threw the chalice.
That was, you know, all those events.
And I never got to judge a challenge by as a guy to run competitions.
I was super impressed with what he did, especially the presentation
in his judges kits that, yeah, he kind of set the bar for that.
Just yeah, just hit it out of the park with that.
I don't know. He's got an eye for detail too.
Like on a different level.
On a different level than I have an eye for detail.
Like when it comes to genetics,
I love my genetics and stuff, but with logos and stuff.
Doug, Doug is all over that, so he's always had that eye.
So my business partner also that came up with the James Lab logo,
he's got that same eye for, Oh dude.
And just to know what's going to be what's going to look good and very stylish.
Not that I'm not that stylish.
I'm just I'm a genetics guy, so.
But yeah, lots of fun.
Well, dude, I really appreciate you coming on the show.
It's been great. Yeah, like you do. That's awesome.
Yeah. We'll have to do this again.
We'll get you in the wife next. So awesome.
Thank you very much.
but they