[Music]
how's it going welcome to another
episode of the James Lab podcast today
my special guest is Shiloh massive how
you doing today Shiloh I'm great bro
thanks for having me dude thanks for
coming on the show I've been looking
forward to having you on since we
started the show yeah great to be here
it's a a super nice place you got thank
you very much really appreciate it so
you have a long history in the industry
you know you worked with Eddie LEP among
other people you want to go into
starting out around Eddie LEP I think
that'd be a great place Leapster yeah so
uh back in the day you know I lived in
Wyoming and uh was the late 90s I was on
a a a a student loan repayment program
for rural areas so they you would go
serve the community for two years and
they would pay your all your student
loans it's amazing crazy right
so Wyoming's a different kind of level
you know you got Jackson Hole then you
got Wyoming so um I was like oh yo can I
transfer out of this thing you know can
I get another spot and there was some
spots in
California and this is right at the time
that major G was passing in mindo and I
was following that as like because I I
I'm from I lived in California a long
time before I moved to Wyoming so oh
Major G minino County grow 25 plants I'm
looking at the map of the of the
programs and ones in this place nice
California and it's right by Mendo and
I'm like wow that sounds nice little I
know um that it was the meth capital of
the [ __ ] world so
uh uh
relocated and uh this is the time that
215 is going on you could get your
doctor's note right boom I see in the
local paper oh D call this number come
up on uh come to one of our clinics and
meet the doctor and d d du so I'm like
okay this sounds great I'm going to I'm
going to go to this so I put my nice
shirt on you know and I'm like
go to this place and I'm like driving up
and it's rural community Lake
County uh Upper Lake lern Road you take
the turn and then you get to the
driveway and there's a big gate and uh
this time it was open dirt road go up
around the bin and you my first scene I
Come Around the bin and I look over and
it's just a field full of weed plants
you know like it's maybe under 200 but
in this that's a lot of weed plants to
have open in your in your yard right and
I'm like [ __ ] I remember
thinking am I supposed to be here is
this the right place because if it's not
the right place this isn't the time you
want to roll up on a on a guy so sure I
got up there and there's some other
people in there and you know the doctor
the doctor uh old Milan Hopkins was a
Vietnam medic and uh he uh you know EDD
he like pulled him out and was like Hey
this and that he started writing he made
a a lot of money off off that Arrow but
people would go up there and uh get
their things and there's a group of
people and then you know there's [ __ ]
Eddie goddamn and this is Eddie before
he was Eddie so he was just like he's a
Gruff dude black Levis you know he's not
he's not the rock star that he became
later in life swears like I mean he
always swore like he hit his thumb with
hammer but
um I'm like enthusiastic because my
whole life up to this point is about
weed right and I got to convince this
dude that like hey this is what I want
to do where do I get in you know what I
mean and I don't think he like me too
much because Eddie wasn't a nice shirt
type of guy and uh so anyway I I
convinced him that I was worthy or
something and he he he he's like I'll
start you off at a yellow leaf Merchant
little did he know that I had a resume
that well succeeded that already at this
time so I started going there all the
time I didn't have many friends so I had
a kinship with Eddie we became great
friends friends nice and uh we grew weed
together for many years and was this
like late 90s or this is the late 90s
before it all happened and like I said
so the more momentum it got and the more
people and then the High Times started
coming in it became this Juggernaut and
you know Eddie wanted to take him on and
win so uh that was the game so he wanted
to go big and how he's going to go
bigger and the the real thing what he
was trying to do was okay you get your
grip we'll grow your weed up here you
get the weed at the end of the year it's
like $10 a gram it's revolutionary and
the type of people that are going in
there at this time are people that
really need you you know some help so it
w it was a plan with with with multi-g
goals to help the people and to take on
the big guy right and beat the big guy
so we ended up uh I forget the year
because uh you know my son was born
somewhere in there and I I kind of left
towards the end but it was uh we grew
40,000 plants right there on the side of
the road on the 20 it's pretty County
and uh the pictures are still around to
Pro the pictures are there and and and
uh a guy Jason Dunlap was there for
years with a camera wow so he's got a
freaking 5,000 hours of Eddie Le Farm
footage through this whole period and uh
all all all the craziness that went on
and led up to the point where uh
Eddie became the Hugh Hefner of weed
totally with his Smoky jackets and his
parties and his right multiple wives and
um yeah it was a it was it was it was
something else I'll tell you what it was
something else I bet it was an adventure
yeah every day you know and then uh then
uh you know I uh moved up to Oregon for
a while and I moved back and and and I I
didn't have my house anymore so I
actually lived there you know and Jack
lived there and then uh wow yeah it was
pretty crazy wake up every day and smoke
just roll joints so this is Jack post
stroke yeah and he still had a lot to
teach you know you just had to pay
attention to the lessons right but uh
yeah it was an epic time epic time to uh
thought we were going to change the
world and uh maybe you did you know leg
legalize maybe you didn't yeah I mean on
some level you guys definitely had some
impact for sure yeah we did
so uh tell me how you got started with
smoking you've been smoking since you
were a kid I take it gez so
uh yeah just where I grew up in the
Northwest it was
like I was a skateboard kid and my homie
uh maybe I shouldn't even say the name
bleep that out but he had a halfpipe and
you know there was other kids and his
sister had like a wicked collection of
bongs remember ceramic bongs and they're
like saying Wizards and just stuff like
that and you know we kind of started
smoking around the skateboard scene and
then uh there were some older kids that
were in our neighborhood and they were
uh they were foster kids but they were
far Advanced and I'm telling you this is
in the 80s these kids had Briefcase full
of the Kryptonite lime green
crystally insane weed when we were
little kids you know so we're just
running around the woods smoking weed
that's
awesome so the genetics back then what
kind of stuff were you smoking for me it
was green and brown we had green and
brown and there was like outdoor yeah so
where we were we didn't have that
outdoor I didn't see that that that
stuff till later we didn't we didn't
really have we didn't have brick weed we
just had KGB yeah killer greenbud you
got greenbud greenbud indoor Washington
northwest right uh Northern Lights um
the G13 the Pez these strs but before
the names started coming later those
names but really we called
it The Killers or the cripplers yeah and
then uh you know they started coming
names like Pez and then You' start know
the northern lights and stuff but right
it was greenbud
KGB crippes it I don't know if it was
related to The cppy Strain but it's like
we just called it the
crippes yeah it's interesting we I mean
I think we saw names in high times
before we saw names on the streets when
you know growing up
yeah I was this was I was smoking way
before I seen a high time so it was like
and then
uh my my mom used to send me down to my
grandpa when I was growing up and I was
like 13 and stuff and uh maybe maybe a
little older 14 and and uh I'd go hang
out with my cousins and and and their
dad was a Vietnam vet and my my Grandpa
would take us on these big trips we'd go
to like the air show in Wisconsin d d d
and then I I remember one time before we
left my cousin shelle she's like come
here and into the into her dad's bedroom
and in the closet bro there was a stack
of High Times it was like High Times and
Easy Rider magazines yeah and then there
was a garbage bag black trash bag and
she reached in it and she's
like she like grab some of that and so I
grabbed some and I grabbed High Times
too so she took two handfuls I took one
and that just pretty much fueled our
summer as kids just and that was like
that was like that lime green
skunk bud yeah and ever since then I was
a smoker really I just uh and it was
skunky skunk bud right like sweet skunk
like this the Brotherhood skunk yeah
that's awesome skunk the stuff we don't
see anymore I feel like you don't see
skunk that [ __ ] would got busted so much
in that time that it it couldn't exist
anymore because it would get you busted
and and whether whether you're buying it
you could smell it right cat piss too
cat piss is another
one um yeah some of those old flavors I
feel like a lot of the flavors back then
I mean it's not the weed was back better
back then but I feel like in general
there was a lot of good stuff in the 90s
when we first started getting names and
stuff like that I feel like the quality
there were more passionate people
involved and so there was it was also
more dangerous and a lot of other things
there was a lot of other factors but I
feel like there was a lot of good stuff
and a lot of unique flavors there was
more diversity I mean there was all kind
of sativas especially there were
tertiary tertiary turps that have been
bred into non-existence yeah like thcp
thch they're they're finding this again
in small amounts in roadside hemp in
Italy wow and it gets you extremely high
because as a kid like you got so high
you couldn't get the get the lighter to
the Bowl you know what I mean so there
was some other chemistry going on in the
plant that exist existed in such small
levels that it was obviously the first
thing to go with uh not poor breeding
practices but a bunch of people that are
trying to breed plant that don't know
much about the stuff behind it and don't
even know that that stuff exists to
begin with so it's like no nobody's
fault but it was just in its natural
state it had some things that were just
more powerful totally yeah it's
interesting and with the gelato hype now
and the direction of the market has gone
it's completely changed right there's
guys like Kevin JRE I don't know if
you've been following Kevin in the stuff
he's been doing but like he's been on
this adventure he was in Columbia for a
while I see see yeah Pakistan I saw that
that's what it's all about yeah you know
that looks like a legendary uh crew I
know some of the dudes you seen over
there and yeah you know big up that's
that's really that's really cool and
that's that's the stuff that got me
excited about it in the beginning the
ability to maybe go on trips like that
and you see him he's like looking
undercover with his hat his beard shaved
like a certain way and that's cool man
um
yeah I feel like we need to get back
into that kind of stuff yeah get some
more diversity in the gene pool I think
so much of the stuff has gotten
homogenized we saw it happen in Europe
in the late 90s early 2000s with the
hazes right you know everything Haze
getting bred into everything and I think
we've gone into the gelados now we need
to take a step back the second everybody
started using purple as a qualifier BR
we used to throw the purple strains away
yeah we used to throw the purple strains
away because they didn't get you high
right they don't get you well and that's
normal right know and then that comes to
the thing is there's a fatal flaw on the
testing is like you must have got
something wrong that that that if these
purple strains testing in the 35 36 and
they're not getting you as high as a a
20 something OG Kush something's wrong
in the science you need to go back and
refigure it out and like we were
touching on before the the other turps
that you know still exist but need to be
found preserved not turps but cannaboids
is what I meant to say yeah like the
thcp well and there's so many other
molecules at play right so like we've
been just looking at cannaboids and tpin
we're just getting into THS which create
like the skunky smells and uh yeah I
just saw another article came out the
other day about a whole new class of uh
smells and cannabis I didn't really have
the I didn't read it so I I assumed it
was probably about THS but it it might
even be about something else but I
didn't yeah yeah I just I just read it
it was a abstract Tech yeah yeah it was
abstract Tech he tell them call them up
James say that's old news we knew about
these we knew about these Styles but no
they really did an in-depth look at THS
and also started doing studies with
people and and tpin I don't ever want to
downplay tpin we know that tpin are
valuable but there's other things that
play for sure in the effect especially
when you're talking about skunky things
where or like nose burning things those
those tiles that burn your nose they're
so small too right so yeah small small
amounts and then now everyone's
searching for these large amounts of
things when it's really it's really like
the small things that count it's the
magic it's it's the small pieces don't
forget to you know admir those moments
those small moments in life as well as
in the cannabis plant well there's like
40,000 tpes right I mean we're we're
only testing 40 of the 40,000 that are
out there you know it's like we don't
even really know what's out there to the
degree and there's such small particles
of so many different things that's that
kosher grape soda that right there
that's the
P5
that was grown in
uh go ahead that's got a good good
flavor it does right it's creamy right
off the git it's like creamy and a
little grapey
sungrown Nevada County The Ridge North
San
Juan it's a little fresh still but uh
you know I got a bunch of other stuff
too but that one yeah that one stands
out for sure oh it also makes hash nice
it's got a really distinct
flavor it's not super bright with flavor
it's more subtle which I like yeah it's
got a lot of subtlety to
it it's not like everything else
everybody's smoking right now which is
like I feel like this P5 is what all the
new uh hybrid what is a P5 though the P5
is a gelato 33 TK well which is what
Pluto is it's a backseat of the Pluto oh
it's back seat of the Pluto Pluto's good
it's a little bit different than the
Pluto I feel like Pluto's amazing this
is a little uh it's it's well-rounded
like the Pluto but even more so I feel
like all the gelato hybrids are trying
to be what this stuff
is so that was a in fact I didn't even
come up with that quote somebody said
that last night when I was in an event
so we were smoking on
it yeah it doesn't it has something
that's a little different than than the
gelat it's like a liveliness yeah like a
like a opener at the end yeah it's
floral and it has a really long finish
which I
like but yeah this stuff's
great and I like that that burns down to
the ash like literally you could put the
joint out fire it up five more times and
smoke the roach and it would still taste
good right so and I think it tests above
five% turps That's The Telltale yeah
when you smoke it down to burn your
lips so for feno hunting when I'm
sharing bags now instead of giving
people
flour instead of giving people flour uh
to do whatever they want with I'm giving
them joints right and everybody gets on
they're on the same even playing field I
feel like it just kind of evens out the
playing field a little more yeah totally
bro um yeah sometimes it doesn't look
the best but if you smoked it it would
beat these other things that are just
like oh just a gleaming picture yeah
I've seen it happen more more than once
but then at the same time and all over
goals it's got to click the others too
so right A lot of the time in the fenal
hunt we don't give it as much time and
like and like we were going to grow a a
crop for flowers totally so they get a
little beaten down and right I'm a firm
believer of growing it out at least
three times too like one time doesn't
really tell you the whole story right
this the genetics change over the period
of three generations typically it'll
stabilize somewhere in there and yeah
but it's a lot of work a lot of smoking
yeah I like the idea of coming up with
some go some guidelines like that like
you just said grow it three times or
like a lot of strains like people are
like oh my strain and and this and that
and they it's just like a single cross
with one somebody else's seeds like it
should have four parents right or four
generations before you can claim it you
know you breeded it four times or it had
four distinct different parents which is
like four generations of breeding also
so we got to get into that so what is a
lot of the breeding out there is just
participation Awards yeah yo you get
this and you get that let me tell you a
story about the birds and the bees okay
you're going to make some seeds guys but
then the real work is in taking that to
something else so right making it your
own yeah
absolutely yeah it's funny because
everyone's doing these F1 complex poly
hybrids that are just like it's it's
beyond the bottleneck yeah well and
they're like I have access to good
genetics so now I make good seeds and
it's like well you made a new cross and
that's that's great I mean I think I'll
commend anybody that makes some good
genetics I think that's great no nobody
owns seed breeding no no one owns seed
making yeah well and it's a group effort
and I think uh we're all working on the
shoulders of the Giants that came before
us at the end of the day we're we're uh
in the infancy of this industry to a
degree but like we're working on
thousands of years worth of work
technically speak we're we're just we
work for the plant yeah we work for the
we're working on cre
stewards to a deg this is like you know
we work for the bees we was like we take
our role way too seriously that ego gets
in the way you know like let's talk
about that for a second like we come
from the 215 and then it got buried by
by the the proposition 6 what was it 64
69 and and and the first thing that went
out out of out the window was compassion
right the whole thing about 215 was
compassion you found your way because
you believed in the medicine in the
plant and through that you found some
people that really needed your help and
and needed that and as soon as it
changed there was no more compassion
yeah when slowly butet greed and ego
took its place yeah but there's still
Balan I mean there's people like us that
are out there still trying to do bro
it's there there's a lot of Warriors
it's a big war and there's a I'm not
going to discredit the world that
there's no but like you know and the
main thing it's just like we didn't get
any cheaper
you know what I mean it actually got
more expensive and it got maybe you
could get it get get it easier but you
didn't have to wait for the guy to call
you back and drive around town but uh
but you know I was like yeah to the
retail guy it didn't get any cheaper but
on the wholeale just they broke
everyone's backs killed the farmer
chopped them off the knees and right
that's pretty crazy the the
consolidation that's happened over the
last and the people failing and giving
up but then you see who the real
passionate people are cuz it's like they
won't do anything else and I feel like
there's a lot of people that watch the
show and there's a lot of people out
there yeah there's a lot of people that
love weed their whole life is weed
plants medicine uh all all all that cool
natural stuff I feel
like this is where I meant to be at this
time in this place in my whole life if
you look back I talk about my
18-year-old self being really happy with
who I am now um we've gone through all
these phases and it's like the people
that love weed you you can't you know
you can't bypass those weed those those
people
or necessarily like that that's what's
happening with these big corporations
too some of them are like forgetting
about the passion side of it they're
just focusing on profits right and you
know it's one thing to focus on profits
and care about quality and care about
the plant you know I mean I think
profits are part of the model too like
you have to we're all trying to feed our
our families there's nobody out there
that doesn't love a little bit of money
absolutely you know there's a lot of
battles to pick people yeah they open it
up for the corporations come in and and
you know Corporation is just a way to
form yourself to protect assets and
stuff but I know you say that that
mentality of that whole thing but yeah
there is a worldwide worldwide uh
militia of true ganja people from coast
to coast and everywhere in between yeah
and there's young ones coming up too
they're super passionate I see these
young I mean I'm 46 and so I'm seeing
these guys in their 20s that are super
passionate that have been smoking weed
for 10 years and they get it they get
the pass they get the quality some of
them maybe not all of them but I guess
it's like that with everything in life
right so let's uh let's dive into
talking about uh one of my favorite
strains of all time you know I love I
love Skittles I love everything about it
Skittles I love the TPS on it the Z
train the Z train it's funny because
Skittles does have a ceiling right so
like I feel like I can smoke Skittles
all day and it gets me here where some
other stuff definitely either gets me
here or takes me a little higher but
Skittles is very social yeah totally it
doesn't like yeah uh incapacitate you
it's very social it's fun it makes me
feel good great for the golf course yeah
women love it yeah everyone loves it
everybody loves it Atlanta yeah it's the
I don't I don't see what they're all
fighting about everyone loves it what
are you fighting about seriously come on
you guys are fighting over plants and
alphabet
letters yeah it's Ser get over that [ __ ]
that TPS belong to the streets by now
yeah get over that [ __ ] Skittles is a
game changer though on so many levels um
as far as when I saw it for the first
time in
2014 there was I mean TGA was breeding
turpy stuff there was a a lot of other
people breeding turpy stuff up to that
point but nothing when Skittles it kind
of changed the game I remember the first
time I smoked it to this day me too at
Sierra Nevada Reggae Fest I wasn't
feeling the best yeah feels he had that
[ __ ] it was like damn homie that's a
whole that's a whole new thing because
we're all smoking cush and sours and
[ __ ] it's like and it energized me like
I said I was I was like kind of laying
down I was having some back pain came
through what up Shy boom smoked that
[ __ ] boom and I was like energized and
that flavor was like cotton candy game
changer Chang the [ __ ] world it yeah
so I smoked it in June 2014 at the High
Times Cannabis Cup right Brandon came I
was with Kenny Morrow from tyum
Technologies and N from yeah n nectar
nectar nectar n yeah and so I was yeah
shout out to no I Tri Tech the legend
the the legend the legend great author
great dude he's done all kinds of
amazing stuff when I was young I was
reading that dude [ __ ] yeah he was the
dude on 60 Minutes that you know that
was all blacked out back in 96 or
whatever yeah legend for sure but yeah I
was with him and null at freaking the
High Times Cannabis Cup in June of 2014
and Brandon came up and was that in Sack
or it was in San yeah it was in Rosa I
believe and Brandon came up to us and
[ __ ] was like you got to try this
it's
Skittles and back then there was a lot
of stuff going around with names where
it didn't taste like it you know it was
described right there was so much stuff
and I'm used to you know I was used to
this world where it was like catpiss
tasted like catpiss you know and skunk
smelled like skunk but then somewhere
around the 2010s it seems like we got
the names all [ __ ] up uh cookies was
okay though cuz at least there was
something related to you when that [ __ ]
first came out was it next level fire
yeah um that [ __ ] existed before it came
out too though so that was just it was
just that [ __ ] was a mythical strain
definitely yeah it was good you know
people loved it and it was another one
that had smoked down to to the roach
it'd be delicious if you grew it
correctly and then Sunset sherbet it's
an interesting one because I feel like
it never got its day like cookies did
and gelato did because gelato came to
it was like you ever been to the races
and [ __ ] and it was like sherbet was
everything was people talking about then
dis just came out of [ __ ] nowhere
yeah took over the [ __ ] planet dude
there's not a there's not a country in
the world where they don't know what the
Skittles is seriously so shout out
Changers probably Antarctica game
changers I don't think you're allowed to
go to Antarctica but let's not get into
that yeah that's no I don't know my dad
went to Antarctica when I was a kid so I
don't know yeah they're like oh that's
the end of the end of the Earth they got
some crazy you a flat earther I'm not
but s my good friend I love s my OG Soma
yeah big shout out to S
yeah I've had some of the most amazing
experiences with s I'm not convinced
we're even here so how is the earth flat
around so I don't you know what I mean
I'm not here to argue theories about
that I'm here to uh uh cultivate Bliss
Within Myself totally yeah yeah it's
interesting it gets to the point it's
like people want to divide and conquer
so much or even separate us by Democrats
and Republicans and people with long
hair and short hair and all this stuff
and really we're all just people at the
end of the day 100 that's a trip well
yeah people that like weed so yeah and
it's amazing that we get to work with
this plant so like I just I'm still I
still
smile saying that I'm smiling at you
brother get to work we're together in
this you know and it's wild because you
know I see a lot of people that had this
vision of who they were going to be when
they were older and this is exactly what
I wanted to do me too bro and I'm like
my homie came through from high school
he's passing he's like dog you're one of
the only people that I knew in my whole
life that did what you wanted to do as a
kid
yeah totally and it's like and the weed
it's always been good but like it's
pretty amazing now I mean I think
there's some interesting stuff still
coming oh man these kids are changing
the game every day bro blowing it up bro
but even the even the stuff like this
right this old like we look at some of
the old school the piff is very popular
now again and Hazel are starting to come
back but this isn't like appealing to a
lot of people but it's appealing to me y
I got a a piff Cross or the Cuban black
cross in there because they're just
different FAS of the same but it's a w
hawen pineapple thae Master Kush Cuban
black K pineapple tie Master cush Cub
black ha was the male that's awesome on
the W Haw let me dig that out yeah it's
real interesting so with that piff and
the Cuban black because I've seen the
piff S1 and the Cuban black there's
definitely some diversity in there and
some real interesting
combinations we can't tell the story
without saying Neville's Hayes yeah
they're just different fenos of
Neville's hay oh yeah different people
Neville's ha is amazing it's Neville's
hay yeah A5 Neville's hay is actually
smells like cat piss that's the closest
thing outside of catpiss that I've ever
smelled that was piss this one's the
wakan uh pineapple toe Master Kush Cuban
black Haze
cross dude it even
looks very we were talking about
terpinolene earlier and and getting high
of terpinolene and it's like terpinolene
should cause a panic attack because it's
but like yeah you can see so you got to
smell these side by side it's real
interesting smell this one first cuz
yours has a little bit more uh loning I
I pick I pick up the lme
and the pining heavy on yours uh where
it's brighter you know what I mean it's
[ __ ] good we do a mix seriously
should we mix this think you want to
roll it yeah I'm down that's we got
we're gonna smoke some Sour Diesel too I
got some Sour grown by Josh Freeman good
friend he's like best Sour Girl i' know
I love the sour so like and then there's
we were talking about Mis mislabeling
things and stuff and uh I think this
sour that when
came uh associated with the sour was
actually the Virginia skunk and they
were just calling it Sour Diesel but it
was actually Virginia
skunk and uh interesting I don't know
like there's so many people telling the
same story it's hard to keep it right A
lot of people don't want to tell the c
fishing going on but uh yeah this I'm
pretty sure that it was uh Virginia scog
well so my understanding you know
there's all kinds of opinions on Sour
Diesel but Sour Diesel originally I
believe was just a bag seat of the chem
91 there wasn't breeding work that went
into it uh the stories of my book
actually right you know I think it's the
same story that Mojave and I talked
about on a podcast a while back but and
uh my buddy at rotown genetics he has
you know Gabby Gabby got to get that
dude on the sour story those are some of
the kids that brought it out those dudes
original dudes we don't mentioned all
those names but [ __ ] like there's
there's some stories and there's some
different things but yeah continue yeah
yeah yeah the weasel story about the
weasel and all that good stuff um but
yeah I don't even know where I was going
with that but uh um the bag seed Sour
Diesel oh yeah Sour Diesel and the bag
seed in Root Down genetics so Root Down
genetics my good friend Allan U who I've
known for a long time he actually has
fingerprint work done for my flora DNA
and he has some genomic stuff done on
sour and his genomics show six different
Oakland Allen yeah yeah yeah yeah he's
good dude yeah for sure OG yeah we we
would definitely have some of his stuff
for sure yeah I think he's he's doing
some real breeding work yeah you know
there's there's a handful of people
there's more than we know you know it's
just such a weird small circle that
people are like oh this is it this is it
and it's just like bro I'm a complex
human entity the only thing I don't only
just breed plants and I love plants I
collect corn seeds and sunflowers and I
love that stuff but like to Define
someone just by the of oh bro you put
plants in the and then you make
selections and then that defines your
essence no bro it's like I just I just
love that you could grow something in
the ground and like get a melon or or a
tree or this weed you know it's it's an
amazing thing
totally yeah it's amazing to be able to
grow stuff out of a
seed you know we were we were seeds at
one point
right so this is going to be a tasty one
I could tell already
yeah that one's going to be
crazy yeah there's studies about can
tpin that cancel them each other out too
right there's some new stuff coming
out yeah you know that's the thing is
now there can be a lot more studies yeah
there's so many like things you could
study about the weed plant it uh
anti-aging you know you smoke enough
weed you don't get wrinkles right you
know what I mean totally there's some
truth to all that stuff especially the
anti-aging stuff and then it's just like
people overdoing it with high power [ __ ]
all the time I like Dabs at night I
don't roll with like a dab rig or
anything like that but I I like hash and
rosin but most I like the puffco and I
like the rosin Tech the uh the focus V
CA 2 that is cool they're both cool I'm
not I'm not a hater on either one I like
the technology on both of
them yeah dab they're all kind of the
same that dabx rips what other what
other one the do
Dabber yeah it's a shredder yeah I mean
we used to have the volcano electric
dabs bro it's like I back in the day
maybe it was 2 216 I don't know but I
was sitting there with lot comedy and uh
he had turned me on to [ __ ] H cold
starts and I was like yo in the future
everyone will cold start their dad yeah
totally and look at us now just cold
starting you ever smoke it on coal back
in the day like
yeah yeah back in the 90s that was like
one of the ways early 2000s did you ever
vaporize with eagle Bill no no no that
sounds amazing yeah he was one of those
Amsterdam uh dudes back in the day he
had that huge Globe vaporizer yeah yeah
yeah what about do you remember that cat
the uh now the the pope of dope from New
York pope of dope I remember that name a
lot of people don't know this and they
need to check it out before uh there was
a dude and it was like in the 80s and he
ran this delivery service in New York
you could call him and or and he wore
the pope thing and stuff Pope and dope
he had 800 number in the and he ran it
forever bro yeah that's awesome and like
that's like I was like this dude is on
another level bro he just ran this whole
uh Enterprise from a 800 number and and
my bicycle Messengers dude it's so crazy
yeah back in the
day people taking
risks yeah that that dude is a legend
they need
to they need to do a documentary about
that guy yeah so what are you doing now
for work right now so uh I got a lot of
[ __ ] going on um you know my dudes at
Pacific Reserve um we were working
together and then you know they they got
acquired by uh collaboration Ventures
and um we've been working together for a
while so you know they reached out to me
and we we worked some things out so on
uh the head breeder over there we got
over 200,000 Square ft uh mixed light
indoor and the new Farm in uh North San
Juan massive Farms so we have like 12
dispensaries maybe a little more in the
state and uh we're vertically integrated
where all the weed we go just goes into
our stores and Our Brands and what that
allows us to do is keep the price down
right last month we were number one
number three and number five in the top
uh
top [ __ ] uh the top 10 eights sold in
California so we were three in the top
five wow so it's pretty exciting you
know it gives me a huge platform to to
do more things and you know definitely
grow more seeds and be active and uh got
a lot a big machine behind us we can
really do anything right any product on
our shelves 85% of the products are ours
whether it's uh pre-roll a tinure
gummies drinks yeah you guys so you guys
do everything everything fully
vertically integrated pretty much fully
vertically integrated you know and uh yo
my guys they bootstrapped this off off
10 Millie and uh they built this machine
and it's just uh it's a great Evolution
yeah for the massive for sure so we got
a lot of massive stuff coming out and uh
you know working on some stuff um all
kinds of stuff so we just uh got a new
hash lab so we're going to be working
more on water hash and rosin bringing
that to the table because that's one of
the things we have been Outsourcing but
so you guys have been feno hunting too
it looks
like did we've done a couple pretty big
feno hunts the first one was uh in
Selenas in our uh we're still in Selenas
so these guys were some of the first in
Selenas when that whole green Rush uh
blew off and now we're like one of I
think there's only eight Farms still in
Selenas but we're still there we did a I
think it was a 36 strain feno hun out
there wow and how many seeds of each did
you typically Pop I think we tried to do
at least uh 10 of each maybe maybe there
was more of certain strains yeah there
was 50 of a few strains but uh yeah it
wasn't huge numbers it was just more
crack cracked the surface and then uh
see what you got see what you're working
it was overwhelming working through the
turps in there and uh it was really hard
to pick things that that that weren't
like really hitting and some of the
things just you know how you had to pick
because they didn't really fit the
commercial uh paradigms or or
all the markers but some of the most
phenomenal weed you ever seen so we'll
be able to get back into that later but
we did another feno hunt up there in uh
um North San Juan as well and that was
uh I think like 12 different strains we
were just up there last week testing uh
just different hashers and just exciting
stuff like that yeah that's awesome yeah
yeah so when you're doing
selections uh at scale
what are the selections you're looking
for what are the the main traits that
you're kind of going for you guys going
for nose well so like we're vertically
integrated so like what do we want we
want to have stuff that nobody has
number one so as slowly massive takes
over uh uh we still have some of the
Hitters from other people but it'll be
you know a big portion of that and you
know we want to cover all the tping
profiles orange you know you want
primary colors like yeah exactly 100%
and then uh yeah that's the that's the
whole thing and through that process
find Elites that are are really exciting
and once we click that just move on to
the to the to the next thing and uh
digging deeper and uh you know we've
been testing some of the males just to
see there cannaboids and uh you guys
reverse them at all or you just yeah
we're we're we're reversing we're doing
a lot of that stuff that's awesome um we
we were doing uh a lot of cleaning of
the genetics outsourced with these guys
and uh do a lot of redundancy testing
and then uh there's protocols for
cleaning the plants and then restarting
from tissue culture so they they go you
guys are going through they go through
testing like uh eight months and you
know redundancy over and over for like T
TMV and the The Hop and then the curly
nightm whatever the next thing is so um
and and then by testing them multiple
times you can see that's clear from the
system and then we can release them back
out you know they're going to they're
they're doomed to get infected again but
through this you know you saw that
research they found some immune plants
yeah plants and me into the hob vroid so
whether it's the hob vroid something
else will show up next week you know not
next week but like there'll be another
thing so you got to stay on your toes
and be current with all this yep science
and and surround yourself with smart
people and uh yeah continue to
learn yeah and realize that you can't
just do it all yourself it takes a team
it's great you can't you can't do it all
yourself no and it's amazing working
with a good group of people too because
it's motivating you know my guy
shred I'm beyond blessed bro these guys
are just like they shred dude and it's
it's kind of amazing when you go to
these different uh parts of the of the
system and just see how big it is and
and
like you know it's crazy we have over uh
300 employees I think maybe
amazing yeah and from vital you guys use
his soil down there too yeah we we've
had a long relationship with Brian and
uh vital um yeah Brian he's part of you
guys too yeah yeah Brian yeah he's he's
amazing he's he's an amazing human I
like him for sure yeah 100% And His soil
is really good I just got some delivery
the other day you know all my seeds have
been made using vital I've always used
vital and and then I became friends with
Brian and then at one time I even worked
with uh for vital
on the night shift on the forklift nice
and uh yeah that that was uh that was a
good time so we continue to be friends
and great products vital Garden Supply
um yeah he was on the podcast not too
long ago it was a good podcast so uh
what kind of stuff are you working on
specifically this year anything you want
to talk about or you guys keep it all in
the dark what are we working on so you
know we also wanted to bring some
sativas like you're talking about well
there's a debate is it sativa it's not
sativa well there's obviously TPS that
exist in this
other side of the world weed that you
don't want to call sativa anymore that
aren't existed in this so we wanted to
look for some of those profiles that
we're actually smoking right now and uh
offer some stuff like that some
preservation stuff also for this growing
uh uh consumer Market of people 60 and
over you know the Boomers they the some
of the weed's too strong for them they
want a nostalgic effect of like oh yeah
remember I smoked the aapco gold or the
you know d d and they didn't get so high
they couldn't function cuz they're old
now and it's just like it's hard so um
you know appealing to just different
demographics when they want to smoke a
whole joint and not be high right you
know like I had a chef that I used to
the biggest demographic of emerging
consumers of cannabis that
taste that's the one though that's like
that combination right there that's the
combo we
should yeah do the [ __ ] massive loud
yeah down we we should definitely super
this is one of the best ways to actually
figure out what crosses you know you
smoke stuff together this [ __ ] right
here though it's got good flavor it's
complex and it's a it's a hitter too it
hits hard yeah it's one of those ones
that I feel like it expands your chest
though some stuff that's one of those
missing things is that expando yeah
where' the expando go yeah it got lost
somewhere along the it's very rare now
like bro bong hits yeah just bong rips
like of the Kryptonite weed back in the
day that's strong as dabs bro that was
like that was like some Next Level [ __ ]
there's there not a lot of snappable
weed anymore bring snappable weed back
because bongs are cool yeah when they
bubble and they're C huge collection of
Bon fing love that [ __ ] bring snappable
weed back that's one of the you ask me
that's another thing I want to do yeah
lime green crystally cripplers for your
bong custom tailored for bong heads
yeah I mean I bet some of that stuff was
like 18% that just rocked our world
because of the chirpin because of the
flavor molecules y cannaboids Cano serp
just different combinations of stuff
yeah pull it up uh again THC H thcp or
do the research on your own uh be
surprised what you find out they're
learning new stuff about cannabis every
day but thcv thcv is awesome about that
one for sure I got some dabbable thtv
that's been sitting for a couple years
and I just found it and took some dabs
of it it was could have thcv in it yeah
it feels like it's a likely candidate
for thcv right thcv and cbdv I mean all
these things are amazing and there it's
actually considered hemp by itself it's
hemp until it's not hemp right but
that's the flavor flavor Chasers are
gonna love this stuff come on dog that's
like you L yeah I mean it's good good at
Sol that [ __ ] that would have you
hallucinating at a Burning Spear concert
yeah I could see this giving you a
little paranoia too that's what I was
saying when I was out there waiting and
I was like [ __ ] am I going to park on
the street excuse me and I smoked the WW
and I was like wow I got a little racy
and was like a little overwhelmed I'm
like maybe that wasn't the best
choice yeah but now we're safe in the
compound well you know and I don't
really dab this kind of stuff either
because it's so strong because the dabs
will [ __ ] wreck your life um at least
in my opinion some of that stuff so high
yeah definitely
but the flavor on that so good and we're
just getting into it and I feel like
with those kind of things The Joint
changes in flavor got me high as [ __ ]
just those couple hits well it kind of
really elevated from the stuff we were
smoking earlier we were smoking good
stuff but it's like it's just another
level another level of good and then you
show people those buds and they might be
like oh bro get that and yeah they look
at like oh nobody wants that but it's
like smoke it come on fire the ugliest
weed I ever smoked was also the best
weed so that's yeah that's so I always
St the homie I was like uh what's it
what [ __ ] uh healing of the Nations
I'm like you got your ugly weed cuz he's
a Oh's got the fire but then he's got
those Ethiopian crosses I'm like what's
up you know I want that ugly weed yeah
the uglier the better sometimes
especially the ones that like you have
the bracks that are stacked at fox tail
out it's like some of that stuff that
looks very undesirable is absolutely
amazing I mean Sour's kind of like that
yeah Sour's like on the nice end of that
but some of this stuff looks really bad
where like the buds are just s like that
the one that's tolerated but yeah right
just [ __ ] that will never get
trimmed yeah seriously what else did I
grow that this year uh just in the
backyard I had
some
zal Mala Panama nice so zamal like the
reunion Islands it was from a seeds and
they they were they turned out pretty
phenomenal dude they're they're in my
book too they love those they just focus
so much on that stuff and I just wanted
to check it out actually finished and uh
it was pretty amazing that's awesome
yeah I think they're doing good work I
think there's yeah I mean there's a
handful of people doing really good work
and there's you know I like I like the
guys that are using stuff that's outside
the box it's like yeah we can all breed
this stuff that's around but going back
and you know you're doing the Lord's
work going back and working with land
races people don't understand like land
races are nothing like if you think I'm
G to work with the land race man there's
a lot of work some people be like the
they'll be like oh yeah I got the the
Hindu Kush land and then you bring it
back and grow it and it's like bro
that's some scraggle yeah I didn't do
what you wanted to do and like you said
it got to take one two three times to
master some stuff and like tweak it out
and and and have a large amount of seeds
in that case yeah well Mojave Richmond
said once the seed leaves the land the
race is over right so because it grows
specific to that environment so the
second you move to a different
environment whether it's indoors or
whatever you're changing the environment
you know the plant naturally adapts to
its environment too it's like we do too
as humans you know it's it's pretty
amazing but the land R stuff it's like
try to grow some Colombian and see what
happens you know and some of these
really long flowering 18 weeks 20 weeks
yeah wild and then Big Ups to the people
that do grow those out those 20 weeks
yeah for us to see and just you're a
real badass if you a 20 we plan I got a
lot dude yeah 100% because I mean I
think a lot of people that have 20 we
plants probably cut them at 10 weeks too
right you know and I think that happens
a lot or they weren't ready for the ride
and then there's a whole like few more
extra [ __ ] a month or two of uh of
problems that could happen occur yeah I
mean when you're flowering for that long
there's so many things that could happen
it's one thing when you're flowering and
you have stuff that flowers for eight
weeks or 10
weeks how's the flavor still oh
that's what that's a that's like a top
joint that's a top 10 joint right there
yep it's got Nice Ash too it's got a oil
ringing Nice
Ash and it's a day wrecker for sure a
turp ring on the sativa
Banger yeah you know it's a banger yeah
and a lot of people haven't even seen
this to make a decision themselves and
it's like you know
yeah people make their mind up by
looking at something rather than trying
it and I
think there's people that have that uh
interest in experimenting trying
different things especially with
cannabis and those are the ones that get
surprised the most like if you're
looking for an experience instead of
just trying to do what everybody else is
doing you're going for a new experience
right you're gonna find some magic out
there yeah my homie uh uh uh lives in
Willets um wo was weed he he he's been
messing around for a few years and then
he loves land races a lot too and then
he showed me this strain that he made uh
is the Robert Creek Congo nice crossed
with the Cong congales land race Congo
is amazing and bro it was like nuggets
of the Ste it was a stickiest land race
I ever seen in my life shout out to
homie bro and uh I was like man you're
on to something with that yeah it was
like cuz you you think of it like one of
those ones horrible to trim or whatever
it was just it was like some 98 yeah 98
chronic wow crazy did you do you know
the story about the Robert Creek cono no
no that's I want tell the best that I
know but I'll probably mess it up but so
there there's these guy the congan
Pirates running running weed and uh and
and then they were like H north of Spain
uh what was that Island I forget but the
it Shipwrecked on this island and there
was this dude Monro dude the black hand
that was a boat mechanic and he fixed
these dude's boat they were they were
running bales of the Congo weed and so
he he like you know wanted to get paid
and stuff but he wanted like a bail so
he he like handpicked the bail or
whatever and from that he selected the
seeds and he grew it [ __ ] I can't
remember the island name right now off
the top of my head but uh he grew it
there forever and some Canadian dude
went there got the strain I think that's
where JRE and a lot of people got her
from but they called it Robert Creek
Congo nice I think Robert's Creek's a
place in Canada where they were growing
it but uh that one by itself is one of
those nightmares to trim but his cross
is fire bro so big UPS to him for
looking outside the box and doing
something yeah and the genetics are
amazing it tastes really good it's got a
unique kind of musky muskiness to it
along with it has the African kind of
taste a little bit but the effect it's
funny cuz Durban is also a region in
Africa right right and Congo you know
we're talking about two different places
and they have two completely different
effects I feel like Durban kicks your
your head's another one that they got to
find that bring that one back the real
Durban that's like an e we were just
talking about theor t yeah it's all that
licorice it's that's what it's all about
it's that real licoricey like that stuff
will get you but then red Congo gets you
super high too but the thing with the
Congo is it makes me happy and laugh and
like Durban I think Durban is like an as
a little bit Congo's like almost the
north by uh by Morocco right or is it
more in the mid I believe it's in the
middle somewhere it's a great time to be
alive I think it's a scary time to be
alive and a great time to be alive
there's so many things and like with
weed it's just we're we're still in the
infancy of it we're still figuring it
all out it's not stabilized yet and I
think that's those are the beautiful
times there's there's enough for
everybody yeah to figure some things out
yeah we're we're we're in the best time
yeah and struggle is real and I think
but struggle is okay too I you know I
think people shy away from struggles
sometimes you know you just got to
accept it and then suck it up and then
we're going to evolve into better times
I mean I think that's just the way of
life
yeah there's there's not too many people
you know there's that have just had a
pure plush upbringing there's there's a
few but you know I think yeah but you
need that in my opinion you need that
like the sour and the sweet right so
like you don't appreciate the sweet
unless you experience the sour and
that's that's one of the things Buddha
and you go on your own path right I feel
like the the tough times have made me
appreciate the good times even more but
it's all fleeting anyway yeah nothing's
promised we're we're just here you know
occupa occupying space and time yeah
what we're left with what we're left
with is our last breath and it could be
a breath of anger could be a breath of
of Joy so you you choose how to live
your life when it at any minute could
and Which choice do you want
totally yeah man you're B in cold
plunging too I saw some videos I love
cold plunging that's my thing I co
plunge every day and I just love it I
feel like it gives I I don't I used to
smoke before I did now I do it first
thing in the morning i' get out of bed
and I just go plunge and I do long
plunges I don't do the short ones it's
crazy to think that it's one of those
things that like right now just us
thinking about coal plunging yeah is
having positive impacts on our body
because we've cold plunged it's that
powerful that you could just think of a
time when you did it get some of the
benefits yeah I I agree 100% so I have I
listen to meditation music right so I
listen to this music that I've listened
to every day since I started doing it
and now like if I have it going on my
head I all of a sudden get super relaxed
right so pretty amazing yeah I like I
like those ones when it's snowing out
that's the best ones when it's really
like it's hard to keep it going like in
in the summer fully like the cold plunge
unless you got the electric plug in or
something yeah but uh those best ones
are just like in the snow just like it
really makes time stop for for and
really SL just I'm feeling it right now
brother yeah yeah it's it's y I went so
when I did go to Amsterdam this last
time because I hadn't seen Soma for like
20 some years and then uh we we linked
up and we we uh spent some time together
and and SP bro took us to the the sauna
ritual oh yeah I've done that many times
that's and it was like that first one
and then it's like the super hot one and
then they got all the things that
they're putting on on the hot rocks and
then they finish it up with the
opning and then the Opium drops on you
and you're just
like and then cold plunge and then the
second one's like like pretty mellow in
comparison but the hot air and then they
ended with the uh that elang Lang flower
that made Chanel number five yeah one of
the best scents in the world it's like I
never knew that there was such a ritual
around sauna and then and then of course
some's like yeah you got to this this
one security guard you got to watch out
for this guy but we could go over here
and smoke the Hash Pipe and we're just
like it's
always put he's like okay give me your
coffee and just Scoops the butter in
there it's the best just to put the
butter in your coffee before you go in
so he makes the most amazing brittle too
that that brittle is something special
blessed to have s
oh yeah bro blessed to have them yeah
the spa experiences those are the best
I'm finished and I love sauna like
that's that's a thing from my child I
want that in my life all the time bro
it's like you know that's one of the
things I look forward doing to doing
every time I go to Instagram is going to
the spa yeah and it's just it's always a
different experience too you know so
always an
adventure uh yeah I've been too high at
this the spa before bro it's kind of
like it gets crazy dude it's just like
yeah that Spa
totally that good still still delicious
it's fire that's a good combo I feel
like those would be good together I
think they would breed pretty pretty
good too it is pretty fire Str
especially because it's similar
structure so people wouldn't be upset
because they know what they were getting
into from before you
started so some of this stuff if you
were to cross it with the gelato and
sell seeds of it people would be like
wait a second what's going on here the
plants look crazy but it's like like
yeah you you know I think there's
potential for this stuff too you just
have to be able to appreciate a
different
structure yeah like like but like you
said if it was in a joint and people
didn't see it and one another that one
might be too strong for people it might
be so it's really
racy it's really racy it's got a good
freaking uh profile but then it I feel
like it kind of Mellows out too a little
bit like I think I was more high like a
little bit ago and now I'm more like
Smooth right well it's it's funny how
extracts have evolved into Rosen carts
like where we were in the 90s right you
know that's when I first started seeing
hash was in the 90s to uh you know
extract Tricom Technologies he was doing
the original BHO before anybody else
right and then uh Rosen carts we got
into rosin and now they're putting in
carts capture inter and these are really
good this is Jetty and uh they do a
great job with their cards they taste
amazing this is a TAA one too like it's
my warning
pen yeah I was lucky enough to move to
Amsterdam well I wish it wouldn't been
the end of an era but the end of a Great
era of hashish when that there was some
just amazing land race hashish before it
became dominant on these other cultivars
and stuff uh real like Steve Hayes
Moroccan morocca stany lebanes all just
just distinctly different yeah bro um
he's actually the guy that brought me to
to Neville and then uh that's another OG
Steve Hayes shout out to that guy Steve
ha is a character great guy like bro I
was just young when I moved to Amsterdam
and they were like go to this place and
meet this guy and he's just a Gruff old
[ __ ] and he was just like he became my
brother bro that guy [ __ ] taught me a
lot of [ __ ] and and he showed me so much
about hash before it vanished off the
Earth there's still hash and there's
good hash but it's it's different there
was so much more variety of stuff for
sure but yeah so tell us a little bit
more am about Amsterdam did you live
there for a while Amsterdam so it was
like around 2,000 years old I was like
so I was always in the seeds and all
that and that's what I was doing with
Eddie too was like I convinced him about
the seeds and then that's when the
Eddie's medicinal seeds started and then
uh we were doing some stuff on the side
like the beaster side so we we had some
funds available and uh just we had met
some people and we're like yo that's the
that's what we wanted to do is move to
Amsterdam and start start a seed company
grow weed because that's that was the
Apex of it right right so we funded it
we we had a couple spots and we we moved
over there and we were growing and uh
that's where I met Don and Aaron and
they they were like hiding out and this
and that and like you know they were
like okay come down here this is where
you buy a buy a bike for a 10 10 uh 10
euro maybe was was even Gilder back then
I think it was right at the end of the
Gilder and then yeah we just got to go
down here and spray paint and silver
like everyone El and then like we just
we just raged for a while while we were
there but that was a great time um like
that's when I first met s and stuff yeah
went to meet Neville and
stuff yeah some was a good dude but yeah
and then then I went back recently and
Amsterdam's way different than it than
it was yeah it was so much it was like
and now it's like uh it's like Las Vegas
of Europe kind of and it's like well the
greenhouse guys are now in Thailand so
like they're
chilling for sure Y Thailand being you
know I never thought Thailand would be
legal that's pretty they used to kill
people for weed not even too long ago um
like Singapore but like uh I hear that
they they changing it again or they're
not it's all propaganda who knows it
doesn't look like they're changing they
got a new president that doesn't like it
but they can't not going to be able to
stop it making too much money for every
everything's cheap in Thailand except
the CI weed right or the greenhouse weed
too yeah but you know I got friends
growing out down there my my buddy from
NorCal genetics Al they're actually
growing fire there too yeah for sure
shout out yeah there's GNA be some guys
dude Al Al's there he's rocking it he
moves so many people are there Ed Borg
is there dude rocking it out Del I
haven't seen ited in a minute but yeah
he was there in the original days and oh
Adam D I met him he used to have a drum
and Basse I think it was on Mondays or
cheeky Mondays yeah yeah that was Chris
Bliss was a legend back in the day You'
cook everyone dinner yeah once a month
or something good times for sure
Amsterdam was so wild dude back then
compared to now and I mean I guess we're
older too well when I first well I went
to college in London for a while and
then I would take the bus and the ferry
over to amster Dam it took like 11 hours
9 hours or something and it was the
cheapest way you could get there cuz I
was a college student and then i' just
go there for the week and stay in a
hostel and I just smoke Ash and weed and
[ __ ] it's amazing and that was that was
way back in the early that was
like cheapers that was like 91 or
something wow long before I went there
it it was it was a different era yeah
for sure 91's when I first started
smoking same year chem dog 91 was a
special year yeah for sure for so many
things so Grateful Dead that bag seed
the 90s was a great era for cannabis it
was it was like the Age of Enlightenment
to a degree I mean I think it was really
special with all the different genetics
that were being created and the people
were growing quality I think the quality
improved you know I we understood
technology a little bit more we also
thought three-part was an amazing input
for for I've always been organic I was I
always thought that was the way to go
guos and stuff and just natural yeah not
that I haven't thrown some cammies on it
here and there but like that was just my
my right I prefer organic for for the
effect I think Coco's great
now but yeah back in the day soil was
three part though there was people bro
back in the day that Miracle Grow that
doesn't exist anymore I see some
oldtimers grow some weed that look like
grow Krypton
and like just smell crazy smoke that
[ __ ] it would knock you out probably not
so much that the weed was so powerful
but the kimys and the heavy metals just
dusted you no flush no these guys were
flush I think one of the first dudes
that I learned that [ __ ] from back in
the day one one garbage can one cup of
of Miracle Grow every watering wow and
then you switch it to the other one at
the end and then at certain time but
it's just like so that's that would be
be a super low dose of it this guy was
this guy was crazy he had the he had the
laskan Thunder [ __ ] back in the day in
in the 80s late 80s 90s in Tacoma he was
he was these it was good weed in
Washington if you were doing it back
then you had to be a little bit crazy
yeah or a mad genius and those dudes
like hit out a little better it was
usually a balance of both yeah but there
was some that dude was a lunatic bro my
family Washington they were the yeah
they've been growing a long time yeah
Washington Got The Chronic forever the
only problem they never [ __ ] it it
would be so the humidity was so high
it's really hard to maintain we're so
blessed in California for the humidity
especially in the temperature but uh our
weed stays perfect most of the times
like Colorado gets too dry Washington
would Colorado will ruin your sack
Hawaii you got to keep that [ __ ] in the
freezer just take nugs out or it'll be
dusted it just Brown out and uh I took
stuff out of my my freezer that was in
there for 5 years it was almost like it
was frozen in the block of ice at the
bottom and it had been there for 5 years
and finally we defrosted and it was some
loud Berry from back in the day and this
stuff five years old still had turps so
freezers were good freezers a great way
to preserve your stuff yeah for sure
yeah a lot of people don't utilize the
cold chain for turp storage yeah I think
that's going to be a game changer in the
future for the entire industry though
you look at loganitus you were talking
about lanus earlier but I think
but what what was I saying about Lanas
you were saying that Bill Gates now owns
Lanas well Bill Gates I he own heekin a
big chunk of it so hinin owns Lanas y
technically if I'm wrong drop a comment
and uh let me know but I shout out to uh
Tony McGee and Jeremy Tony McGee Legend
changed the beer game uh that iy was
just believed in what he believed in and
just kept doing it him and Jeremy
Marshall yeah I mean dude like the
Jeremy kind of is taking the Reigns now
and he's amazing too you know still
there different different side how many
but how many times did did he fail
before he became lanus a love times
blowing the the whole the city's uh
septic sewer systems up and just like
you know but he did he started that all
from just a craft brew set what a
freaking Legend what a legend yeah a
legend I mean his book too Del book is
amazing yeah yeah delicious beer and he
was also very um early on with the craft
brew and a Pioneer to Bringing like
craft brew culture and C like that craft
beer Culture Beer Circus and just like
Yeah The Beer Circus was amazing I mean
that was they were like kind of freaks
like so I was part of the whole Beer
Circus crew circus is one of the coolest
things I ever went to I did the food for
the backstage at the Beer Circus for all
of them uh so dope and it was amazing
you know they took me on tour to Chicago
and la and we we went all over we were
in Seattle we were in New York we did
these circuses and just that group is
just they're a different breed really
good people all fun they understand hard
the funny thing about the guys who did
the B the Beer Circus like vair society
and all the people that were involved
you know that I was friends with this
guy Travis who was one of the managers
but everybody really knew how to work
hard and also have a good time right
that's one of the beauty beauties of
life if you learn how to work your ass
off when you need to and then also party
when you you need to or want to you know
I think that's what life's all
about the balance the
balance but that stuff still tastes
great that's pretty amazing hit that
[ __ ] up I can't remember this was the
sour one or was that the sour one was PT
I guess sour yeah the the Sour's pretty
good this one's good too
though yeah a lot of good flavors today
so where do you think the industry is
going you think we're going back to
green weed again you think
uh people are going to get in where they
fit in yeah you know
uh so whatever they like personal tastes
and just experimenting with that and
just uh you know a lot a lot of people
follow Trends it's green weed a trend
yeah probably I think you know I would
hope so because love green weed I love
it all I I mean I really like
just that lime green almost just like
ooh there's something special with that
I think lime green has its place yeah
yeah like the TK green like the green
bud has Shades like that's that silver
green sour Diesel's got that silver
Super Silver Haze silver yeah that lime
green pine just [ __ ] nuclear dog dude
like the old OG kushes all of them and
that TK was even more lime with bigger
buds but like that stuff yeah was always
good yeah for sure well man I really
appreciate you coming on the podcast
today if people are looking to find out
more about you where can they go um
check my Instagram massive corc
creations1 you know and then you could
go to enjoy the
farm.com you could check out Coco Farms
Antioch conquered vtown uh valo uh
Pacific Reserve farms uh Santa Cruz but
you know just get tap in awesome dude
thank you so much yeah thanks bro had a
great time for sure dog face yeah I
think we're going to go on location one
of these days so it'd be great to come
check you out let's do oh yeah we got
lots of locations so uh that's awesome
yeah let's do it cheers okay
[Music]
thanks yeah
he