the Bea dragged away the crops and seeds
were scattered everywhere so there was
so there's feral hemp growing all over
the reservation now courtesy of the
DEA how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James loud
podcast today my guest is Malcolm
McKinnon previously from High Times
magazine amazing photographer good
friend we haven't uh talked that much in
the last maybe 5 years but he's a great
guy and I'm glad to have you on the show
today oh thanks so much Jam it's a real
pleasure I mean it's been a while I mean
I I toured your Grow rooms in San
Francisco we spent a few days together
you know and
uh 10 years ago oh yeah man you were you
know you you you you brought in all
those great artists at the Cannabis Cup
too man so you know you were part of
High Times there you were in deep there
during the Cannabis Cup during the
Golden Age of cannabis cups I should say
those were amazing times man really good
times uh yeah it's it's changed a lot
the whole the whole world's changed a
lot since back then well you know for
you know especially for High Times I
mean this I been talk about this just
you know former colleagues and I think
you know one of the real problems is for
High Times is that you know the outlaw
Edge is gone you know it's you know
cannabis is becoming more and more
mainstream so what is High Times now you
know protesting against it used to be a
very very uh definite opposition to
government control and and way that's
what High Times was High Times motto was
you know like do what the hell you want
as long you don't hurt anybody and the
hell with anybody else you know [ __ ] him
you know it's that was High Times so you
know the whole cannabis thing uh has
kind of changed High Times a bit I think
theyve made some real poor decisions in
the last few years and the publishing
industry has certainly been a problem
because do you see magazines anywhere
anywhere any anymore except the dentist
office possibly so um yeah it's uh
Everything's changed in the industry as
far as media is concerned there are a
lot of pot magazines out there and uh I
can't really say a lot of good things
about them they seem to be covering
their advertisers for the most part um
and they're kind of boring they're
they're great for rolling on um but uh
you know I can't really get real excited
about canabus media these days certainly
um you know there are a lot of corporate
entities now in the business and uh you
know you want to cover these people fine
but right well you used to have to have
some balls to be involved in cannabis I
mean even on the the media side to do an
event you had to have some balls to go
out there and try to do an event because
they wouldn't always allow you to do it
even if you'd planned and paid for
permits sometimes you we got raid you
know I remember Cannabis Cup I guess it
was I can't remember maybe 2011 2012 in
Amsterdam we had 150 cops come in raid
and raid the Cannabis Cup oh yeah um
seriously it was it was Unreal it was
you know they thought a drug Park was
going on which a drug Park in in Europe
is you know where people are doing meth
and they're doing shooting up and stuff
like that but you know then we listen
the one thing that people don't realize
a lot of people who are newcomers to
cannabis the Johnny come lately that
cannabis was very very dangerous to deal
with and a lot of people went to jail a
lot of people had their families broken
up had their property taken via the
these Draconian uh Rico laws does
forfeit laws I should say um you know
terrible stuff happened so I think when
people you know these days don't
understand that the industry stands on
the shoulders of these people the
entrepreneurs The Growers the dealers
who kept this plant alive and believe me
it was dangerous during the Reagan Bush
administrations it was downright
dangerous and Clinton was no better by
the way and Obama wasn't even better I
mean we there was a lot of persecution
for pot the War on Drugs has been a war
on pot why because meth is dangerous and
heroin is dangerous and cocaine is
dangerous I should say the people who
are dealing with that stuff they're
dangerous people but pop people are
pretty peaceful and so you got a grow
room you you know the the cops come in
they seize everything seize your
property break up your family it's a
hell of a lot easier the dealing with me
with meth dealers the War on Drugs has
been a war on cannabis
period yeah from from the beginning from
the beginning from the beginning that's
what it's all about you know when
Richard Nixon declared the War on Drugs
he was holding up a pound of pot okay he
wasn't holding up needles or anything
like that right so you know it's it it
was also war on hippies you know I mean
it was a war on counterculture it was it
was more than just drugs you know sure
was it sure was you know people have
pointed out to me that you realize
around
7879 you know disco got real popular and
you know these you know polyester shirts
and you know looking like a disco guy
really became the popular thing it was
like you it seemed to be this Insidious
war on hippie culture because suddenly
you have this manufactured music it's
not rock and roll and you have John
trola dancing around in tight pants
suddenly I what the hell happened to the
culture you know seriously because the
60s and 70s man it was all about you
know hippie and you know the great rock
groups of those times things changed man
they really
did yeah I believe it um so let's go
back into your history a little bit and
start talking about uh your experiences
with cannabis from the beginning where
did it all start you know my my
experience from the beginning I mean I
went to University of Michigan um uh
1975 and Ann Arbor Michigan is was the
most liberal place for pot in the
country period it was a $5 desk
appearance ticket if you were walking
down the street smoking a joint if you
had an outs it was only a $25 F and
those these laws predated the
legalization by decades so that's where
I went to school and I experienced some
of the greatest pot ever I mean I had
some wak I remember one time it just
blew my mind I thought I was having an
anxiety attack this stuff Mr been just
off the hook yeah I mean I thought I was
going nuts the only anxiety attack I've
ever had so that was you know going to
University of Michigan and uh you know I
I I went to New York to become an actor
I was a I was a theater major got a MERS
in in in theater and I went to New York
to became an actor I had some success
you know uh did did a few different
things and then I moved into the fitness
industry I became a top of robic
instruct taught in Japan I was part of
the pro rebok team I I led New York
Sports Club during the aerobic boom and
I got sick of that ran into Peter Gorman
who was an editor of high times at the
time and uh he recommended me to
photograph some of his stories I was you
know working on as a photographer for a
long time it was my hobby and I got
better and better at it so this was a
real real break for me to go to High
Times and uh start a career there I did
my first full feature
1991 but I did have a feat you know had
had had work uh published in 1989 so
that's where it started
1991 and I became a photo editor then
features editor then a senior editor and
I became an editor at high at hemp times
I would you know really and it was a
wonderful place to really hone my
photography find out you know how good a
photographer I could be but also
learning about cannabis simultaneously
because this was a real uh education for
me there the people who were involved
with high times and were inv involed in
legalizing drugs were very very driven
people intelligent people very very
creative so it was uh it was a great
great break for me out of the fitness
industry in the High Times magazine um I
mean High Times opened up the doors for
me in so many ways so many things I was
able to do so many celebrities I've
interviewed so many experiences I've had
are all because of high times so I have
a great affection for High Times I spent
25 years there 25 years my God that's a
quarter Century you know that's a over
third of my life when you get down to it
so yeah I mean it was a tremendous
experience that's where it all started
1991 and uh you know seriously uh you
know High Times was my uh my entrance
into the world of cannabis and meeting
all all these people people like you you
know you know very righteous people
people who were really brilliant seed
breeders uh you know you know plenty of
you know big-time dealers and
celebrities and people in the Cannabis
industry who are really leaders who were
doing their thing you know on The Sly
and Loud seeds was one of them you know
when I've visiting you in San Francisco
things were still you had to keep things
undercover you know it was still a very
very dicey Arrangement so when I visited
you and you know toured your Grow rooms
with you we drove down to La together
there was pot being delivered down there
to a dispensary you know it was
different times that's only 10 years ago
man so when people say that they're
Pioneers or that they've you know forged
a path on their own I I ain't buying it
I know what people went through I know
what the work had to be done by the
activists the entrepreneurs the dealers
and The Growers the people kept this
plant alive while it was being you know
vilified by the government right
Generations before me I mean I'm
standing on the the shoulders of giants
in the in the breeding world the
cultivation cannabis people like you
that you know believed in the industry
that you know tried to make a difference
yeah well I think I think we all did I
mean I think we realized we were
involved in I think that was the
exciting thing about being with High
Times truly was just the fact that we
felt like we were we were on a mission
of some sort we weren't doing People
magazine or you know a food magazine we
were doing cannabis and it was dangerous
and believe me the Government tried to
stop uh shut down my times a couple
times first with green Merchant in the
early 90s when they actually subed UPS's
records to find out who was buying
hydroponic equipment that was a you know
a war on you on on Growers they were
going after them you see if you you know
ordered hydroponic equipment you might
have the DEA showing up your door and
say can we see what you're doing with
that stuff that's how bad it was and
then of course in 2003 2004 operation uh
Head Hunter and operation pipe dreams
when they went after the the bong
industry they tried to go after our
advertising we had very very heavy
advertising High Times at that point in
the glass industry we were getting tons
of glass ads bongs were huge and uh so
they went after it and they arrested 57
people for shipping bongs and
paraphernalia over state lines they they
so they busted 57 people including Tommy
Chong Tommy Chong was the only one of
that group that went to prison he went
to prison for 10 months for selling for
for manufacturing a bong that was not
that long ago folks that was like 2005
so it's dangerous it was dangerous and a
lot of the country it remains very
dangerous yeah it's a strange thing in
the stigma is slowly changing I mean I
see it with the older generations and
also the the younger Generations like
myself that are getting older um you
know the there's a lot of people in the
United States that have tried cannabis
on some level whether it's an edible or
a joint or whatever whether it's high
school but I think the the stigma is
changing I think especially in places
like
California uh New York you know we have
this area in the the center of the
country where slowly but but even look
at look at Oklahoma I mean Oklahoma's
changing Texas is changing so I know but
there are a lot of you know the the deep
deep south States Alabama Mississippi
yeah are that are they not uh friendly
to marijuana at all I mean you you're
still taking your life in your hands
Nebraska ain't so cool either that's
always the weird thing when you're in
Colorado you have a choice of Nebraska
or Kansas those both border Colorado and
they're very very tough States on
marijuana you know I've heard of often
of people crossing state lines in
Colorado of going into Kansas and the
cops are just waiting you know you got
stickers you look like a hippie car
they're going to pull you over find out
if you got pot in the car yeah they
don't care yeah that they're yeah
they're and it's a money thing too oh
God yes I mean you know listen the War
on Drugs is all about money you know it
put a lot of people you know a lot of
people made money off the war on of
drugs you know prosecutors uh States you
know all the revenue people had to pay
court costs all that kind of stuff you
know and of course you know we
incarcerated Millions the United States
has the most people in prison in the
world we imprison people for everything
now I know granted there are a lot of
bad people you know who should be in
prison and I don't know if there's an
alternative I mean I've heard people
talk about you know are there
alternatives to prison and that's a
really really difficult question I
remember interviewing this woman named
Maya shenir an attorney in Chicago in
the in high times and she said you know
listen it uh prison evolves I mean you
know people used to put people in Chains
we don't do that anymore you know so I
don't know in many ways I think we're
still a very primitive society as far as
how we treat people who uh disobey the
law you know especially when it comes to
drugs and uh our our treatment of people
who have addiction compared to places
like Norway compared to countries like
Norway and and Portugal and people
addiction especially 100% agreed yeah I
mean this is the thing these people I
remember kind I remember were
discussions like this on and talk shows
back in the 70s honest to God talking
about why are we treating people with
addictions like this why are we putting
them in jail why are we treating them
isn't it cheaper to do this you know
maybe someday I don't know we we are
like I say the United States I mean we
always talk about how great a country we
are and stuff but I tell you it just
drives me crazy the
stupidity of of of our politicians and
it's all policy driven you know you know
cow Towing to their Pary uh leaders and
so forth I mean everybody's on the same
page as far as nobody nothing changes to
get people to actually come out and you
know use their backbone to support
something that makes sense you know all
suddenly they're a Maverick or a rebel I
mean we're talking common sense is
completely bizarre in this country these
days common sense is not so common but
you know it's
just it's so Money Motivated and and a
lot of it's motivated by greed as well
unfortunately and you know I don't I
don't even know what the answers are
we're in a difficult time right now I I
have to agree with with with our
political landscape and so forth I think
if people you smoked a little more pot I
think everybody would calm down a bit I
mean if you know you see what happened
at Woodstock 1969 everybody's smoking
pot nobody's doing you know hard drugs
except for a fool a few fools um and
were there any fights were there any you
know any you know riots or anything like
that no I you ask
cops they go to an event and it's a POS
smoking event they know that nothing's
going to happen you know right if you go
I remember cannabis cups you bump into
somebody you oh sorry it's Sor K man
it's okay no problem don't worry you
bump into somebody where at a at at an
event where beer is being sold you bump
into somebody man you can lose your life
seriously how many times have we seen
fights in the stands of uh sporting
events and me it's all it's all
motivated by drinking I mean people get
beer muscles I mean but people don't get
cannabis muscles they don't want to
start fighting you you know after they
smoke me joy you know for sure deaden
company that was the people causing all
the problems were the people drinking
alcohol you weren't seeing the Stoners
the people eating psychedelics pushing
and shoving there was a little pushing
and shoving going on at the second the
last night at dead company in San
Francisco but let's talk about some High
Times photography one of my favorite
covers of all time I have a bunch of
them but I and I still have I still have
my magazines believe it or not but uh
one of them was the chocolate box they
had the different hash it CH the box
that was my I I I had a very short rate
as cultivation editor not knowing
anything about cultivation I they
actually made me editor for a year but
uh yeah that was my first cover uh that
was BC bud and I was covering BC butt up
in Canada and it was a Valentine's Day
cover and I remember I showed that cover
to some people um down in Arizona and
they had a daughter who was uh who was
somewhat autistic and she saw the
magazine and came over and tried to grab
some of the chocolate off the cover
which were
buds pretty realistic looking covers
that was like February 95 I'm going to
guess yeah February 95 that sounds about
right I remember seeing there was some
green hash and I I was so excited to try
green hash until I tried it for the
first time yeah excited for years I
don't think I it was probably two or
three years before I found some green
hash paid a bunch of money for it and it
was the worst tasting hash I'd ever
tasted
so you can't believe everything that was
in High Times believe me
totally so as far as other photog
photography that you've done for High
Times magazine covers Centerfolds this
you know the centerfolds it was like uh
Playboy magazine for weed is kind of
what High Times was back in the day well
I think that's the way it was conceived
James yeah um it was to be a kind of
like a a parody of High Times magazine
of Playboy Magazine with with a
centerfold yeah I was really thrilled to
be able to shoot as many centerfols as I
did I think I shot 35 covers uh in all
that includes hemp times and high times
so I I you know I get to shooting
incredible stuff um you know I got you
know shot buds shot people shot models
you know it was it was great having
control of the cover um was was
wonderful I when you get a cover that's
like that's you know you've hit the you
know you've hit hit a grand slam in
photography so you know I was always
shooting for the covers always always
always because you know it's it's it's a
huge rush to see your your image on the
cover I remember you know there are
sometimes that you know you things go
great I mean I remember we we shot Kevin
Smith on the cover and the art director
Frank Max put Jason Muse on his shoulder
so it looked like he you know a devil on
the shoulder like that and so it hit
news stands right as 911 happened and so
it died on the news stands nobody was
buying magazines then maybe some news
magazines and stuff so that was very
very disappointing and then I remember
one year we were have we were limping
along toward the end of the year and uh
you know not not really the our covers
were not selling you like two or three
you know bombs in a row and I shot Jenna
Jameson for the cover the uh the porn
queen and I went to her house in Arizona
and shot this this cover of her and we
ended the year on a bang no no no no pun
intended um but it was amazing I mean
the thing sold off the hook and not not
necessarily saved the year I mean High
Times always did well but certainly made
the owners extremely happy that they
ended the the year with a huge huge
paycheck so you know we we we turned in
some cover that were selling in the
hundreds of thousands um back then um
there were some bad bad decisions made
in 2003 they decided to take the pot out
of the magazine this honestly happened
they brought in John Buffalo maor who
was the son of the author Norman mailer
and another man named Richard Stratton
who was a Hollywood writer who had spent
some time in jail for hash smuggling and
they brought them in and they decided to
make it an outlaw Vanity Fair if you
will and the readers roundly rejected
within a few months High Times was on
his deathbed that is not an exaggeration
so the owners decided that they admitted
a mistake we rushed back to cannabis and
save the magazine and you know the best
part of that you know because the
publishing industry has been you know
dwindling for years the best part of all
that was that we decided to finally
bring a Cannabis Cup to uh America in
2010 the San Francisco cup that was our
first one and we realized we had
something so we entered a absolutely
golden era of High Times from 2010 to
2015 our cups were just tremendous you
know in Denver I think our the fifth cup
we had there we had 40,000 people show
up over a three-day weekend I mean we
had you know just so it was while the
publish industry was dwindling and you
know was really struggling and magazines
were closing High Times was still
holding firm you know so uh yeah so I
was with High Times till
2017 and you know I think they've made
some very very questionable decisions in
the last few years um you they they uh
you know they have massive debt they've
had five CEOs since I left five
different CEOs which doesn't really bold
well for a company and uh and apparently
they have massive debt which is uh
coming due in September so you know I I
don't know um I would hate to see High
Times go you know Wonderful magazine you
know certainly a huge part of my life
but uh who knows you know cannabis media
is a very very dicey things these days
yeah and I don't know if I'd be here in
the same place that I'm in without High
Times magazine winning the Cup in 2012
was a big big deal for me and my brand
and yeah my my friends and you know all
all the people around us that were
growing our genetics and I think we held
our genetics a little close we didn't
want them to get out as much so you know
I've made mistakes along the way but
High Times was definitely pivotal for us
when we first won in 2012 we had no idea
that we were going to win cuz I'd lost a
couple I lost in Seattle entering some
extract we we' done some stuff and we
went to Amsterdam thinking we were just
going to have a good time and then you
know we had uh Cali Connection right
across from us with swerve in his 40 or
50 foot long booth that was like 20 feet
in the air and we're like oh man these
guys know how to do it we had a little
10 by 10 and we ended up winning the cup
it was pretty wild I love that with we
always love that when that happened
because you know the greenhouse and
Barney always had these huge booths you
know and C connection too but you know
it did happen a few times when DNA first
showed up they had a tiny little booth
at the Sugar Shack in amstr a tiny
little booth and they took you know I I
I forget what it was I think it was for
CH Chou chalou you know and they they
you know just it was great it it just
absolutely uh put them on the map you
know Arian from the greenhouse wanted
their strain immediately and I'm sure
you've had dealings with these guys too
when you're a winner they want their
strain your strain in their coffee shop
for you know so so yeah winning the cup
of the strain is a is a huge huge thing
you know it's a shame we haven't had a
cup there in years though I mean good
Lord like seven eight nine years since
we've had an Amsterdam cup um and they
were I'll tell you that was the most fun
I think I've ever had in the Cannabis
industry on a regular you know yearly
basis because you know it really gave
Americans a feeling of what real freedom
is I mean I remember the first time I
was at the C 1995 and I was there in the
greenhouse and I'm smoking a joint in
the window of the coffee shop having a
cup of coffee I said what is you know
what is why is this so forbidden this is
the most natural thing in the world you
know just enjoying you know an evening
you know I it's wonderful now that of
course Amsterdam has got you know he's
getting a little bit more uh uh they're
getting a little bit more strict oh yeah
about no smoking on the streets they
still have the coffee shops but even the
amount of coffee shops compared to back
10 years ago there's a less than a
quarter of the amount of coffee shops
there been real Crackdown you know
they're trying to you know like they
don't want Amsterdam any longer to have
this image of like an any anything goes
town with a red light district and you
know buying psychedelics over the uh
over the counter and you know buying
seeds and stuff they want to soften they
want to they want to make their their
their image a little bit more
respectable it seems that's seems to
seems to be what's happening there well
and it's really unfortunate CU that's
one of the most beautiful things about
Amsterdam is you can go there and be
yourself and get whatever you want and
you know you you want to smoke whatever
you want to you want to take some
psychedelics you want to go visit s s
s's I I just talked to him the other day
he was he's sick in the hospital and now
he's out of the hospital and I think
he's doing he's he's in a good mood
that's for sure yeah so s's a a real
character I mean i' I've known him for
years uh I've photographed him and
interviewed him for High Times uh you
know he's very interesting guy very very
strange you know odd background he's had
some heart problems I remember he pulled
up his shirt in one of the gam gups to
show his uh you know bypass scar down
the middle of his chest oh yeah that's
that's s for you yeah but he's a you
know he was a cohort of Jack hair I
remember you know before they went over
to the cup in 1995 I remember s and Jack
were just smoking up the the entire
office I mean just all day long so it
was wonderful I mean every time we'd go
back we'd uh go back and uh you know
talk to him and stuff like that uh and
jack it was it was a great great couple
days before the Cannabis c yeah good
time so yeah and then Steve hagger he
started the Cannabis Cup and then his
last year was I think
2012 the the year I won and that kind of
changed the vibe yeah Steve uh did did a
wonderful job inventing the Cannabis Cup
and I think I think uh I think the
people who started working the cup after
that probably did a better job of just
making it a more uh marketable
experience for everybody um you know I'm
not taking anything away from Steve
Steve didn't have much to do with the
Cannabis cups after 2008 or so I mean he
wasn't in the organizing of things right
so high times is and the Cannabis cups
are are synonymous and I and everybody's
taking their queue from High Times uh
and and our events uh throughout the
country we had tremendous success with
our cups and I I don't see that same
success happening at this point I mean
now now there's all these there's all
these other events too you know what I
mean and emerald cup has kind of been
around but now Emerald cup is this big
production and it was never like that it
was very underground and and you know
very it wasn't private but it was yeah
there's there's money to be made James I
think that's why sure and spannabis is
still amazing I mean I like spannabis
it's a great event that's kind of turned
into for a lot of us that's like how
fish is to the Grateful Dead you know we
we end up at spannabis every year seeing
the same people that we saw at cups and
we've seen at cups for a long time you
know you're I think Europe sensibility
Geor gab is is very very unlike Americas
so uh you know just more cultured you
know we have a little bit too much uh
you you know how America is this
capitalism you know cannabis capitalism
right and you know it's really caused
problems California hasn't brought in
the revenue that they thought they would
New York doesn't seem to be doing too
well either I mean legal Canabis has
been uh not a you know a great success
so far um as far as what the states
thought they were going to bring in and
the black market is a l well so my
favorite issue when I was a kid not my
favorite photograph but my favorite
issue was the million-dollar growroom
and I think there was something about
ecstasy in it but that was like my
favorite when I read a million dooll gr
room and then I was actually featured in
the the next million dollar grow room in
10 years later now I'm trying to get
somebody to do the billion dollar grow
room I think that's the next
thing I've seen some big big Grow rooms
I mean in Colorado I they they they
started using all these indust pars for
for cannabis out near the airport those
were the biggest Grow rooms I have ever
seen it was like an acre of pot I mean
just unbelievable stuff and I'm sure
that there are bigger Grow rooms like
that right now I mean if you think about
Holland and all the flowers they grow
and all the green houses that are just
lined up for Acres I mean this can be
done very very easily in the US and
Canada you know I think we're going you
know I would love to see a billion
dollar grow room I I I those are the
kind of things that you know that we
brought to High Times you know after a
while it became a you know like okay
we've seen it we've seen it before but
when it first started happening it was
great it really was when we started
seeing the the big giant grou was people
like seeing that but then there was also
that underlying feeling like is this the
where we wanted the pot thing to go I
mean I still would you know I'm still
very much like Jack her I I I'd like to
see just like growing everywhere and you
know have v stands you know sell right
along with tomatoes I mean I hate all
the regulations and that's what I made
High Times great was because we always
encourage people you know grow your own
grow your own grow your own right
totally yeah and I mean I I like I like
the boutique cannabis and I like the the
micro Brewery model for cannabis I think
there's definitely that's got a future
it's not going to be like how alcohol
was where there was just four big
companies it's going to be a lot
different I I at least that's what I I
hope and I expect for the industry but I
also see these uh smaller businesses if
you're a kid coming in the industry when
I was 14 I started smoking but if you
look at you want something for those
kids to look up to it's not going to be
like they're going to you know the
average kid is going to be able to
afford a multi-million dollar business
but that's who's to say that he can't
grow really good cannabis and eventually
build himself into a nice Boutique
cannabis brand well you know I think you
know like anything there's room for
everybody in this business if you do
your job well if you if you're a good
grower if you handle your business
responsibly and you know I deal with you
know similarly honest people I think you
can do very very well it's just you know
it's you know regardless of the
corporate in the influx of corporate
people I think you can still you know
create your own uh entity as you did
James I mean you obviously you know you
had a head start because uh you know you
were laying the ground work in it's very
very underground fashion but you know
now when you're able to come out of the
closet you've already you know you
you've laid the foundation you're ready
to go so laying the foundation you know
what you did you know it takes years it
takes years but if you want to get
involved in the Cannabis industry this
is that's what it takes it takes years
and for the most part with everything it
takes years I mean it's just it's you
want to you know some people have a
natural gift but sure that's not
everything you know what I mean like
just because you can grow really good I
think it's perfecting it it's at scale
as you're growing up and you know and
even if you're not good it's like uh you
just do it over and over till you get
better and just as far as my photography
the same thing when I mean I started out
I was I was a good photographer when I
started out with high times but you know
I learned over the years how to get
better and I you know I I you know I
observed everything you know all other
photographers other you know I looked at
you know thousands of photos you know
try to figure out what works and you
know I over the years you know it took
me a long long time to really say I
think I'm I think I'm pretty good
photographer it took me a long time to
actually say that you know it really did
but at least 20 years and and I didn't
you know when I started like I say in
working with High Times
1991 so yeah I think when I can say
20111 I can say like he's my my
photography is fairly consistent at this
point so yeah look like anything and
that's why I'm so so pleased to you know
issue this book this book is coming out
um pot shots the Journey of a High Times
photographer that's the title and it's
really going to be a historical
documentation through photographs of the
of the movement some of the uh incident
that people don't really know about and
uh you know lots of uh Still Life
photography lots of gardens lots of buds
you know models uh celebrities the
leaders who have gotten us gotten us
here the icons of cannibis Jack Herod
Dennis Peron Lester grinspoon Tommy
Chong all these people I photographed
and you know got to know so it's really
uh it's it's you know people have been
asking for for the book and you know
it's been a SLO getting there but I
think it's I think it's going to be a
real representation of of at least my
career and which kind of coincides with
the legalization
movement totally that's great I
mean these things take time and and you
have years and years and years of
Photography oh yeah I mean I I you know
I was taking snapshot pictures for a
long time and my wife bought me a Canon
A1 camera for my birthday this was uh
for for Christmas it was 1984 so I this
is you know so I started my photography
career regular you know relatively late
in life at 29 years old I just got
totally into it and so I shot in an
amateur way for years and years and
years before I did something for High
Times that was you know I did some some
uh photography for for money prior to
working for High Times yeah but in 1989
I did my first uh feature uh you know
shot some some rocket munaka which is a
an editable from India that Peter Gorman
had brought back from his travels and so
I photographed that that was my first
first photograph in High Times 1989 so
I've been published now James in five
different decades five different the 80s
90s the zeros the tens and 20s I shot
two I shot the Dennis Peron cover um and
uh I I have wrote an article uh January
of this year about the the New York
state of kind the first legal Harvest so
that's five decades so if I were Gordy
how I if it who were hockey I'd be Gordy
how that's what I always say wow really
cool so let's talk about you're uh
working with the people in South Dakota
on the resz yeah in 2000 Alex White Plum
and uh some other people decided to grow
hemp they had pushed an ordinance
through through the tribal government
which had okayed the IND Industrial Hemp
cultivation so in 20002 crops were swn
on the Pine Ridge reservation they were
both plowed under and raided by the DEA
by the uh FBI and by uh local Tribal
Police they came in with guns drawn to
um to uh seized the crops and dragged
them away this was
2000 and they did it again in 2001 they
tried to grow again and in 2002 they did
it again and finally a court injunction
was slapped on them a federal injunction
telling them not that they couldn't grow
anymore that was lifted in 2015 but the
funny thing about this in 2000 when they
first raided the crop in 2000 the F the
the the DEA dragged away the crops
dragged them away and seeds were
scattered everywhere so there was so
there's feral hemp growing all over the
reservation now courtesy of the DEA I
mean just an amazing thing because you
know this this this operation had to
cost a half million dollars and it was a
completely for what to to seize a you
know a couple acres of of hemp you know
seriously that's how that's how crazy
things were that is crazy I was I was
there and and you know and got to know
the Alex white plume very very well been
friends with him for 20 years now um and
uh yeah so I mean there something I've
been involved with a long time is with
is with the Pine Ridge reservation and
uh their attempts to grow hemp now
they're growing uh cannabis legally and
James loud seeds are in the ground there
from what I understand U Vic Camp who's
a very very prominent guy the
reservation uh is growing James loud
Seas right now um he were kind enough to
donate them and uh yeah so that's it's
something else there's legal growing now
they have a couple dispensaries on the
reservation and uh you know it's
becoming mainstream there like everybody
everywhere else they have tremendous
drug problems on the reservation you
know meth is a real Scourge so you know
not that cannabis can can can change
that in any way but certainly it's an
alternative doing meth which is the most
destructive drug out there right now I
believe well that and Fentanyl fentanyl
is killing people meth is just [ __ ]
people up yeah y
unfortunately so yeah I've you know been
working with I I go to the Lakota War
pony races every year I I play kuster
I've played kuster in a number number of
them where uh you know I kind of ride
through all the Indians they come and
try to grab the flag from me it's kind
of a symbolic uh thing in the middle of
the race and whoever grabs the flag you
know gets like about $500 or something
like that it's a little bit dangerous
but I been doing that for' been doing
that for years um so yeah I've got to
got to know the Lakota people extremely
well over the years we have a lot of
friends there so it's one of the things
I'm most happy about but also in my book
there are a few other things I mean uh
you know the for example in 1996 Woody
harelson in Kentucky uh planted four
hemp seeds in order to draw attention to
these ridiculous laws that were
outlawing hemp cultivation in Kentucky
which was the biggest hemp producer in
the world I mean in in the country back
in the 1800s the early 1900s yeah so he
so he orchestrated his own arrest I
covered that I was there at the planting
and I covered his four years through the
legal system and he was finally
acquitted and uh ironically and not
coincidentally the lotas plants were
raided on the same day that Woody was
acquitted now I don't think that was
coincidence I think it was purposeful it
was the Federal Government showing we
don't care we're going to continue to
Outlaw hemp but we're going to continue
to this mad mad war on on cannabis in
any way we can so yeah i' mean I've had
a lot of experiences um that you know
were afforded through High Times
magazine yeah really cool yeah so I mean
Lakota like so that went all the way to
the federal went to Federal Federal
Court they went to the federal court
Miss
um didn't go you know the uh the judge
uh said although he understood and
probably agreed with the fact that they
should be allowed to uh grow hemp it was
still up to Congress to change the laws
and he couldn't do anything about that
so it's kind of where it stopped right
there it's kind of where it stopped and
where it started I mean I think without
that who knows if hemp would have been
legalized and we would have passed the
farm bill in 2018
yeah well you know you know there were
there were experimental crops going I
mean they were allowing you know head
crops to grow you know there listen
there were experimental head crops uh
growing in U Hawaii far back as 1996
1997 um the the Hawaiian legislature
allowed a a hemp quarter AC to be grown
in experimental CRS if it needed to be
experimented with um it crazy
experimental hemp crop I mean what what
did they expect um yeah so uh it's there
were a lot of experimental crops up
until the the the point where the farm
bill was passed but here's the funny
thing back in the early 90s we always
thought it would be a domino effect like
hemp would start things off then medical
marijuana then recreational marijuana
and what happened Rec it became medical
first then recreational and then hemp
came last I mean seriously it doesn't
make any sense I mean not the PO legal
on the on the federal level but
certainly you know when you have
California and and other huge States you
know allowing recreational pot the
gloves are off you know we still have a
long way to go we still have a long way
I mean we've come a long way but we
still have a long way to go and I think
a lot of this stuff is just so
counterintuitive it doesn't make sense
necessarily like oh I know it's the
hardest thing I think for activists back
in the 90s and and the 2000s was talking
to politicians and trying to explain to
them the idiocy of the laws and the
sanity of you know using cannabis in a
way that can really help people and to
just get NOS or to get outright
hostility or to get people who you know
say well this is not an issue that I
want to get involved with because I
won't get reelected it must have been
extremely frustrating you know I was
involved on the political level by any
means I certainly testified it uh uh uh
before a few legislatures I testified in
Vermont and in North Dakota and I
testified at the olala tribal council
about
he didn't change anything you know
people they kind of listen MH MH you
know then they go home you know yeah
that's what's so refreshing about going
to some other countries um St Vincent
for example I I was down there and we
lectured to the Cannabis Authority down
there but they were sincere in the fact
that they wanted to help people with
cannabis we the the government the
actual government was very focused on
allowing people to to use cannabis for
medical purposes especially and and I
didn't feel like we were a a thorn th in
their side like in in the United States
I still feel like to a degree we're like
a thorn in the side of the government
they're they're just they're going to
let us do it but they're it's it just
pisses them off a little bit still oh
yeah yeah I don't think things have
changed like that I mean you know Biden
is you know he's an old guy and he he's
no marijuana supporter um he's allowed
it because I think he realizes that you
know that most Democrats most liberals
are you know think that you know should
be legal it should be people should be
allowed to use it but he's no fan of
cannabis he's made that very very clear
over the years you know so certainly
when he was uh running for office you
know he never spoke out in favor of
cannabis but still had you know so but
he a lot better than the
alternative but uh yeah it's it's it's I
you know I I don't follow the industry
as much as I used to I'm you know
marketing my photographs for the most
part um and you know trying to you know
Market my photography stuff but I'm
still I'm I I I certainly know a lot of
people they tell me about the problems
in the industry and it's overregulation
for the most part that has caused uh the
industry to kind of like St be stifled
right yeah things are slowly changing
but not fast
enough I don't know what we can do but
uh yeah but this you know this High
Times Like I said James was uh my ticket
you know there are so things that uh I
was able to to accomplish all the
different celebrities good Lord I mean
you know when I was with hemp times I
you know I've met I met Merl Haggard you
know I got this gu I went to his house
really cool you you hang out with these
people I got to meet you know I
interviewed Oliver Stone um you know the
Lewis Black uh Jesse Ventura you know I
remember when I interviewed Jesse ventur
was he was still just doing his Radio
Show in Minneapolis in 1998 and I just
called up his radio station you know and
said hey this is High Times we'd like to
interview H you know he'll get back you
just a few minutes and he did he called
me back so this was before he was a
national uh a national figure so he was
you know we just knew him as a wrestler
so what do you think the the future of
High Times is where where do you think
that Magazine's going I mean from your
inside perspective I know it's hard to
say
but it's hard to say because I've read a
recent article it's recent this last
week says that they have massive debt
and the debt is coming due that they
have not and that uh
their lender is also having problems and
it could go into receivership which
means that High Times could be owned by
somebody else you know so I thought the
dis the dispensary model like we have a
dispensary off Highway 880 and in
Oakland I thought that was a great kind
of I thought it was a great thing
because everybody knows High Times
magazine that smokes from back in the
day at least now we have a lot of new
people and I don't think they've done
really well like they thought they would
or like I hoped they would well apply
they owe an awful lot of rent on some of
these places um they've made some bad
deals um I think that you know the
dispensory business is not the Gold Line
that everybody thinks it is it takes a
lot of work it is a 247 job stocking the
place Staffing the place you know it is
it's and and believe me you inventory
goes fast so you know sure that you know
High times has had their problems as far
as the dispensary business in California
as well I mean it's an over-regulate
industry so all I could read James um I
mean I don't have an opinion about where
it's going because I don't I don't
understand High Finance at the least
they seem to keep going even though
they're carrying massive debt that's all
I can can tell you from what I read and
you know people can look this up easily
enough you just uh you know Google High
Times debt you can see where the
magazine is going so even though I have
you know you know fondness for the
magazine and uh you
know I I'm very very thankful for my
experiences you know I watched the last
five six years and you know kind of
wonder where it's going you know is if
is it going to survive right you know
simple as that like all magazines you
know so many magazines have died over
the years I mean so many believe me it's
you know the only magazine that seem to
do any are celebrity magazines you know
right
tabloids yeah very very Niche magazine
but like I say you don't see magazines
anymore you don't people don't go to the
news stands anymore I got to pick up the
latest issue Esquire or something like
that people don't do that anymore so
it's I I even think to a degree books
will be going away I mean I think
there's there well like books like yours
that's a different kind of book so
that's a book that you're you know
coffee table book those are great but I
mean even even books regarding
technology or breeding or growing I
think the access to information on the
Internet is just so vast but the problem
is is dialing the information in because
now it's almost sensory overload you go
on the internet and there's 20 different
ways to do the same thing well which one
do you pick and you know there's ratings
on stuff so I'm going to pick the top
rated one but maybe that's not
necessarily the best maybe it's not the
easiest so it's it's difficult and the
future is uh going to be interesting
well you know I that's one of the the
the reasons I think High Times is also
struggling because we used to be the
go-to source for marijuana cultivation
tips and techniques and so forth and all
the new
Innovations um now all as you said all
of that stuff is on the internet you
know you can dial this up there are so
many experts there's so many videos that
you know that you don't need to buy High
Times any longer um so that that is also
U you know it's made it difficult I mean
grow articles are not all that
interesting anymore I mean you can write
a thousand words you know in High Times
or you can you know read the read it
online and you can read other sources
you can it you know that's that's
becomes a difficult uh difficult for a
magazine to survive with all the
information they used to publish is
online yeah yeah it was a whole
different world I mean photron if you
wanted a Phototron in
1995 you had to get it from you know you
go in High Times magazine you read about
it they didn't have a website you you
could call them you could give them a
credit card number maybe but or you
could send a checkin that was like a big
thing back then you'd send the check in
do people know what the photo tron was
no you know what we've talked about on
my show before but I that was my first
uh attempted growing was in a Phototron
and then I cut the top off and put a you
know 400 watt light that was taken from
the Sun Valley Mall I always loved
reading about the people who did
Innovative things to grow very very
small the people would take an ordinary
closet make a vegetation room on the uh
and a flowering room on on top and have
you know Perpetual harvest in this tiny
little area I was always thought that
was fantastic I really did all the
different ways people grow um I remember
going into Las Vegas and you know guy
took me into his garage you said you see
the grow I said No No 7 and he had a he
had a wall that actually you know came
out of the that actually came out like
you know like a horror movie like it's a
secret room it was he all these shelves
came out and you could walk behind it
and he said cops had actually come over
he could not you know you know and
looked at it for something looked at the
house for something else could not see
it you would never know it was there so
I always you know I know I saw a guy in
Santa Cruz once who under the foundation
of his house and he was reading the
house he did a sea of green grow room he
only had three feet of space down there
but it was amazing he had cut his
floorboards in his closet in order to
climb down underneath the house in order
to make a sea of green grow room so you
know that that was that kind of
innovation back then just blew me away
it really did yeah so one last question
before we go what was the best thing you
ever
smoked oh
jeez in all these years you got to have
one standout that I'm you know I I
haven't had it in a while but I really
like Sour Diesel nice I really didn't
like sour diesel and but I as I said the
the most intense experience I've ever
had was on Waka that was back in
1976 and that just blew me away I felt
like I was spiraling up it couldn't come
down you know how New York of you for
sour diesel yeah that's that is the the
most
popular as far as you know I think
there's some other stuff coming for the
longest time that was the one diesel
kushman always had a had a uh steady uh
steady supply of Sour Diesel in the
office nice yeah yeah I remember the
first time I came to high times's office
I think I scared you
guys we welcomed you we welcomed you
anybody with the kind of strengths you
have hey you're our best friend the
backpack and and you know I'm from
California so I didn't realize you
didn't want to smell like weed in New
York on that
level well it was it was the office we
were more more concerned about than
anything else because right always
getting complaints from up and down uh
you know in our highrise I remember
people below us called us 70s
floor that's
great well if people are interested in
finding out uh more about your book or
they're interested in following you
online how would they go about it well
my book I I once it's uh out I will be
publ publicizing it heavily but you can
I'm on Facebook Malcolm McKinnon and I'm
also at M McKinnon photos on instagrram
at M McKinnon photos that's on Instagram
so you can follow me there I have a
website malcol McKinnon dcom
at Native American photography.com which
will take you to the same place so
people can see my work and I hope they
do um as I said James I'm really really
happy you had me on the uh happy I'm on
the show and uh you know you're part of
the book um you're in my
acknowledgements and the photo of you
undercover there with your San Francisco
49ers hat pulled down you know that shot
oh yeah you know you took some good ones
you say I still have the one of me uh
shooting pool into the glass jars that's
like one of my favorites of all time
they said Alice in a few shots so you
should have them awesome well thank you
very much and uh yeah I look forward to
talking to you soon hopefully we can get
the guys on the res to uh tune in one of
these episodes well I'll try to get them
try to get them other the line was bi's
a great guy I'll I'll do that for you
well thank you very much all right Jam
take care
[Music]
cheers
yeah back
CR
yeah