[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James La podcast
and today my special guest is Miami
mango how you doing what's going on
James thanks for having me uh having me
here appreciate it oh man I'm glad to
have you on um you know you're another
one I'm super excited to get you on here
when I started doing the podcast uh
planning I'm like who do I want on here
your name was one of the people you know
we've we've been friends for a while we
went to uh the the class at nfm together
I think that was the first time we met
that was like was like five years ago
four five years yeah five years ago five
years ago almost five years ago we had a
good group we had we had autumn autumn C
he had her hat she's the one around me
Scott yeah so we got we got a bunch of
Skies now with you know he's doing his
own thing with smoking Mir yeah smoking
mirrors grow in we have Plum Dog
Millionaire and and Plum dog's the man a
couple other people in there I think we
had uh the Keith from Spectre LED in
there too in that group it was pretty
cool that was fun times it was a good
group we went out to dinner that's where
I met uh James from Liberty Liberty
chemical too he was there too he was at
the class but he was at the the
restaurant yeah nice that's pretty cool
it's definitely been a while about five
years since we known each other yeah so
for our guest tell us a a little bit
about your history uh in the industry
how you got started back in the day ah
let me see um uh started back in the day
because um all my friends or well I
moved from Columbia to uh thefield Beach
or pompo Beach
Florida and uh I became a surfer and all
my friends were Surfers and most of them
were rich and they all smoked weed and I
was anti-weed and then um they were just
they were even rich and they were still
sell weed I'm like [ __ ] man I need to do
that because I was busting my ass being
a bus boy salad boy you know prep cook
cook construction and eventually I just
said you know know I want to sell some
weed you know I need to buy a car or
something because I beat up car and yeah
um you know from there I got into
construction and then they wanted me to
um they want me to build stuff for them
so then I would I would build it and
then I would get all the rights to to
whatever came out of that place that I
would build and that's how kind I got my
my starting in the Cannabis thing nice
and that was Miami back in the '90s 20
was actually it was actually Palm Beach
uh I kind of skipped when when we came
from from Columbia we skipped the the
whole Miami thing was straight straight
to brow County North brow County wow
South Palm Beach and uh and yeah it was
around that that area that that all
started nice we had some we had some uh
I mean it's just luck of the drop but we
had some Surfers that were that were
pretty connected and they they you know
they they had access to indoor back in
[ __ ] 80 886 87 I had friends in high
school that would go by this week called
crypto yeah from this this dude with
long hair Surfer Dude the name was Taco
Joe M that was his nickname cuz he had
he had like a like a like a Mexican
little restaurant
but he had the best weed around and then
that weed to this day is still some of
the baddest weed yeah that that I
remember uh there's some interesting
things that came out of Florida for like
example OG Kush did you see OG Kush back
in the day was that something that went
around as like the crippy or you know
what crippy is crippy to anybody that
remers seedless you know uh you know
that that crypto was the original thing
that we remember as as you know as
chronic seedless stuff that that was
pretty damn good and then um people
started growing more and more and more
weed in in Florida um the Cubans the
Cubans they're beasts they were growing
all all kinds of weed down in in in in
Homestead in Miami lots of sativas lots
of sativas yes lots of hazes you know
lots of stuff and anything that was
seedless became synonymous were creepy
yeah and um you know little accents the
creepy the creepy the creepy you got
that creepy yeah so everything was
seedless it was it was crippy to anybody
so crippy could be whatever it was at
that time that you first started smoking
that was seedless that's the Exotics of
its day yes sir yes sir then the the
Cuban black Haze and there was I really
like the Cuban black Haze I got some in
the other room uh and some piff really
good stuff pretty much almost the same
thing is you got that you know like that
cat piss kind of leathery you know burnt
rubber kind of like smell you know it's
definitely different you know yeah well
it's it's got Pine and limine and so
it's like got any it's got a lot of it's
robust it's got a lot of different
flavors super super musky stinky yes
like dank I guess you could say yeah MH
yeah I like the effect of them too but
they're long flowering plants yes
they're definitely not a commercial
viable plant uh anything that takes
longer than than 10 weeks is really hard
to justify because no nobody's going to
pay for for for for what it cost to grow
right so uh they kind of they're faded
out on the commercial commercial side
there are some people that have um you
know bred the piff and and other hazes
into uh into nine week strains you know
I don't know how they did it back cross
to something and there are some 9 10s
yeah exactly the haze that I grow is the
the the mango Haze and that's an 63 65
day strain haste yeah and that's kind of
where we grew and and it threw down too
I mean back in the day it was so yours
finishes the one you showed me yesterday
yes finishes in 63 days 63 65 days that
thing's done it's a late bloomer starts
slow yeah and then it just puts its
weight on and uh in in the last you know
couple of weeks it definitely you know
throw some weight yeah yeah 63 there
it's got an interesting structure it's
funny because we were just talking on
the last podcast I did about structure
and you know appealing structure people
like those nested tight buds whereas
like that stuff is very open bud with uh
BRS that stack on top of each other and
yes very foxy you know some of us looser
than others uh the D mango haste happens
to be like T tight fox tails super
bright uh orange hairs and like I call
it wet TPS uh it retains its weight you
know when it dries out um when you have
dry you know wet flower with no leaf on
it and it dries it usually dries
anywhere between 19 to 22% average uh
the mango is one of those that kind of
retains his weight because it's it's
like heavy oils yeah so it's like in the
20 22% resist rate yeah greasy doesn't
wash for [ __ ] yeah it's a loser in in
the in the wash but still in the it's a
loser but uh for BHO it's a winner it
definitely throws down on that for sure
yeah and I'm sure smoking joints of it I
can just imagine from smelling it
yesterday how it tastes yes it's
definitely got a I mean there's some
people I like it I like the taste chicks
love the taste too there's some people
that uh love the taste some people
actually you know don't like the taste
they I think it's strong I could just
tell by the smell of it that it's
probably pretty strong it's full flavor
but it's probably also strong in effect
super pungent and uh you know what
actually T tests pretty low for THC like
in in the mid 25s nice I've had it
anywhere from 23 to 26 roughly yeah but
uh it definitely gets you high and we
all know that just because you know
something's lower or in the High Teens
or low 20s doesn't mean that it's not
good as you know it's it's got a
different effect totally people just
starting to figure that out that like I
don't think they'll ever figure it out
James yeah if that's not the truth you
know what anybody that's that's that's
in the Cannabis game may know it but you
know most people they just go straight
to their store and they just look at
that percentage des and that's just it's
like tunnel vision like a horse with
blinders and that's all they're going to
buy if it's I I think that's going to
change though I see it changing in
Colorado I see it changing in Washington
more that people are relying on Brands
rather than just THC and so if you have
a good brand and you have something they
they trusted enough to try it and it's
just going to take time and it's going
to take better products with low THC on
the market where people are like holy
[ __ ] it's only 22% me to me it's about
Flavor you know flavors like I I don't
see anybody that's going to a liquor
store and goes like what let me see on
the Shelf Bo got the highest alcohol
level I 151 I want I just want great oh
that's just so alol that's so soothing
to you yeah it doesn't work I mean
that's you know and like even even
alcohol I like you know I like the P
colad like the strawberry D crease you
know I do like a good P colada that's
one of the better drinks out there
especially for tropical it it feels like
vacation so even if I was at home I feel
like I'm on vacation on vacation you
know it get it gets the mood going you
know like I like Moscow Mules you're
some kind of you know with some little
extra mint you know just a little you
know kick of some you know herbs in
there but uh people are just're stuck in
this high THC thing which I just I can
say yeah give me 151 r or give me some
some uh what's it called some um the
back yeah ever the backwards uh uh uh
the stuff that they make in the woods
what's it called the your moonshine
moonshine yeah give me some moonshine
that just tastes great no that's just
like fir water literally you well see
that that's a that's a the the Moonshine
that comes right out of the still yeah
that's the fir water but you got good
guys to make moonshine and they they
dilute it properly they put some fruit
in it what're talking about we're going
back to tast yeah and craft exactly
tasting yeah some guys that you know
Infuse it with you know apples or
oranges citrus or something whatever is
to making it their own exactly but
that's what we need to do with genetics
too I feel like we're um we're in this
really interesting place where
everything is like purple candy gas
gelato and that's going to change
everything changes that's what it is if
it a if it ain't candy gas just but how
do you make it your own you know what I
mean that's going to like the my your
your mango strand your mango Haze right
yep I'm getting ready to those things
are gonna over time will develop into
popular things I mean I I can just
assume that will like everything else
but like we need those things because we
need the diversity because taste is so
subjective um you know it's it's
interesting yeah like everybody says you
know um you know I hate fruit or I hate
gas or you know I hate earthy whatever
it is I tell people is uh Basin Robins
got 31 Flavors for a reason you know
what's what's the best vanilla or
chocolate you know strawberry or you
know some chunky monkey you know
different palletes Vanilla some people
just love that FL on vanilla you can eat
an edible if you don't want like I got
to say I like haand vanilla where it's
got It's not infused with with air like
all those briers and all the stuff but
oh yeah I'm a vanilla guy Roman Risin
though actually actually better so
there's some fruit yeah I love gelato I
love Italian big on the Italian style
where they don't have the air the
overrun no exactly yeah when it's
fluffed out it kind of you know D it
ruins it it Ru but it's also different
where it's like it's healthier I think
gelato is healthier than ice cream it's
probably real milk cre yeah or real milk
or whatever ever it is yeah but yeah and
you eat it fresh so where's ice cream
you pull it out of the freezer I think
gelato if you make it that day it's
freaking amazing you know this texture
right special texture and especially
when they start mixing like pistachos or
this caramel or stuff like that there
was a place in Oregon that was
insane that made the most insane ice
cream or gelato and I forget what it was
U fins and feathers or something
something some weird name but they made
the weirdest ice cream and one day they
were making out of duck fat or something
like that it was just
the best the best ice cream I ever
tasted duck Fett ice cream sounds crazy
yeah super creamy yeah I bet it's a
heart stoer yeah exactly yeah I made
gelato when I was uh in my 20s my early
20s I worked at a gelato shop for like
six months gelato Milano in Berkeley
Avenue and I really wanted to learn how
to make gelato because I was so D and
it's just amazing the process and I I
have so much appreciation for you can't
get away from gelato can you no gelato
then gelato now they're forcing the
gelato on me and I do like some of the
gelato you know like the 33 is super
diverse I feel like there's a lot of
amazing stuff but like everything's
gelato these days back seat gelato came
out of something some kind of bag and
everything's just from there and then
another back seat came out it was just
you know yeah back seed after back seed
but and and that's okay I think all
these Evolutions that we're going
through these different stages they're
all okay they're all part of the process
of wherever we're going yep can you call
can you call what the next what the next
fad thing's going to be it's so hard to
call it what do you
think I think gas is coming back
honestly I think gas gas and lime green
we're I've been talking about lime green
a little bit with people and I think
lime green has the potential but gas
like old school ogs and also old school
favorites that we were nostalgic about
those are going to come back the a lot
of people are saying like the hazes are
coming back you know I think I I read
somewhere might have been an Instagram
post from Mr Nice Seedbank that he says
that in the last year he sold more mango
hay seeds than than than like since he
ever started selling them so well also
so what we have is we have the increase
in popularity and so more people are
trying cannabis we have like a larger
pool of people there's more people
breeding there's more people agreed
buying seeds to a degree although it's
been a little slow this year with seed
sales retail but I think that has to do
with the economy I would probably say so
too I would probably say so too and uh
seeds aren't cheap you know and then I
can I can see where that that would
probably hurt you know that the the seed
breeders a little bit because people are
not buying them yeah mhm I can see that
totally well there's so many there's
just so many breeders everybody's a
breeder every Everybody Wants to be a
breeder there is there is and anybody
can make seeds seeds aren't hard to make
I think breeders nowadays I mean they're
not like they used to back back back in
the day when I remember breeders I mean
they didn't have seeds all the time and
they would work the line to it wasn't
like what do you call it f1s or s1's you
know when you when you you you cross
them you sell everything but now now
they cross it and they sell everything
it's like a pot it's more like a lottery
ticket yeah stuff was held a lot tighter
and you didn't want to necessar sell
stuff when you were breeding or you
didn't necessarily it wasn't it wasn't
the same and like your the sour diesel
cut we didn't want the sour diesel cut
to get out we didn't want to share the
sour diesel cut want any good cut to get
out no you didn't want cuts to get out
especially in Florida let me tell you I
PID 60 Grand yeah for the mango cut back
in 2001 crazy 60 grand for for for nine
little clones and a recipe on how to
grow it and uh but you know paid itself
back then I mean you grew weed and you
sell a pound of weed anywhere from 4,000
to 4,800 whether it was one or 10 it
didn't matter so uh you made your money
back on on one run and then from there
on you know you it was all all profit
and the thing back then is um you didn't
really have you know it was federally
legal in Florida to this day 25 plants
or more was threeyear minimum mandatory
yeah so you didn't want to mess with
with seeds in Florida because you know
it was a potluck you know we're going to
hit I'm not going to hit you know and
then you needed to hit I mean you you
have this house you spend all this money
on on a grow you need to hit from day
one yeah now the good thing is back then
if you hit from day one you got all your
money back and you made some even if you
grew into y or weed back then you got
your money back and made some yeah it's
pretty wild times were so different in
so many ways and you know I just I can
appreciate the past it was wild it was a
wild west 100% and uh yeah I mean you
were you were doing you you were
building out multiple grows and you were
growing gr and doing all kinds of stuff
so since 1996 yeah since 199 96 95 I
started building one thing we we grew up
first grop in 96 amazing and uh it was
um it was a house four lighter six
lighter and then the bathroom was the
the the mom room and clone room and then
from there it was all history then we
started you know just gutting houses
gares you gut houses you put in you
lights in every room you guys film out
to like 30 lighters or were you doing
like smaller like 10 lighters uh 10
lighters 10
lighters and then and then we would do
them they would they would flip you know
you know 10 lights dur the day 10 lights
at night you know what I'm saying so
they they would flip um so they will be
working 24 hours like you know you had
to make that money so you definitely did
that 2 lighter and my friends wanted to
jump in or my buddy wanted to jump into
a 50 lighter with me and I was like
that's too big you know that's now it's
like 50 lighter nothing 50 lighter you
in doing in a house you got to go to a
warehouse and we were scared of
warehouses in Florida it just didn't
happen Florida is a little different
because
uh you got to jump the power you can't I
mean here in California you guys yeah
you guys are spoiled you Sacramento they
turn you into too I heard in SMUD SMUD
area they do SMUD they'll they'll they
they'll point the finger at you yeah
well so in Oakland how they determin the
green zone was by the power so they went
and looked at PG the highest used power
areas where everyone was already growing
that's where they put the green zone for
cannabis in Oakland interesting so very
supportive of the movement yeah nowadays
just like uh nowadays with these LEDs
that we have now and uh you can slam
them on the canopy you can turn that
that power way down and slam on the
canopy you still have the same ppfd
that's a winner because you don't have
to tap anymore so yeah that's a pretty
good way to go about it now you got into
the lighting game kind of early or I
guess not so long ago but you got in
with a good product and yes and it was
kind of by accident in a way uh I got
I've told this story several times I got
raid in 2017 6 months before
legalization in California yeah I was
planning on going out west I mean uh
well East from here West from Florida to
Colorado I was invested into a into a
grow over there that was kind of failing
I was buying some Partners out and I
thought I was going to you know make it
there and then I got raided in in 2017
in in orille California and that threw a
wrench of my spoke and I had to reinvent
myself I had to figure out how to how to
survive and you know feed the family so
I started doing more Consulting because
I had started doing it and I met this
this Asian dude in in Oregon at at a
trap that I was re building and uh he
liked me he seen something in me and um
we started you know selling these
controllers and I started giving them
feedback as a grower you know because
they had a great product as it was
anyway but he just needed to be refined
this is the original troll Master
correct before it was troll Master no it
was troll it was troll Master already uh
it was troll Master already it wasn't in
any stores yeah um back then it wasn't
haon it was a Sunlight Supply yeah
turned them down hydrarm turned them
down and uh any other store turn them
down so the owner went up up and down
the coast from door to door with
pamphlets he moved from Hong Kong to LA
and went up and down the coast just
pamphlet after pamphlet you know and now
he had some sales and the guy that I was
doing a trap for you know picked up the
pamphlet and told me we were going to
use his controllers I was kind of
against it but it wasn't it wasn't my
dog and pony show so I had to do were
you hand watering at the time no no no
no he actually hired me he was hand
watering he was handw he was handing
watering posit with this big you know
Coco on a on a on a on a pallet with
caster
on this makeshift stuff you know and he
wanted to get
automated since my first grow in 1996
James I was automated Intermatic baby
Intermatic with you know automatic
drippers there's no [ __ ] I was going to
hold I think it's important to learn how
to hand water in the beginning like you
got to get away from it there's no way
to do it I was a contractor I was a
contractor
we [ __ ] see here counting at 10 you know
multiple times a day it's just not going
to happen so we automated everything me
from back then I you know I you know
somebody showed me a grow and I said I
can do that I can do it better in my
mind obviously I didn't see I didn't
voice that right but uh you know you
walk into this girls and but you know in
their defense they're not contractors
they they're not they're not
construction savvy so they do the best
that they can what they got but as soon
as I walk into this place okay I'll
change that I'll change that I'm just
looking around in my mind going I'm not
going to do this don't do that that can
be the B better yeah and eventually you
you have an automated system you know it
was in armatic but it's it still work
turn on and off turn on and off yeah and
that's why I was so against trow Master
because I had this little controller
that was smaller than Intermatic time
clock and it did everything I'm like you
[ __ ] kidding me I'm I'm not the most
um you know um technology Savvy guy and
I'm like I was scared of it did you use
50 gallon drums to build your stock tank
back in the day you just have a we uh we
used um it wasn't there weren't drums
because I I recirculated feed back then
so so to do it the easiest way so things
wouldn't break is um we had a pump in
these low shallow like you know 16inch
60 gallon um res Wars that sat sat
underneath a long table and we top top
drip feed to a gutter and then the
gutter back gravity back into into the
reservoir and we were circulated yeah so
you really only have to um you know uh
rely on one pump and one timer you know
to uh to to activate that it was
actually you know it was it was
technologically you know at that for
that time you know high tech for that
time but it was it was simple to the
point that you know it wasn't going to
break I mean intermatic timer on off
like a sprinkler outside on off on off
pretty simple yeah those ball valves
were pretty simple and I remember my
buddy at his
grow uh we we showed up but he had the
the float valve to fill up the 50
gallons big problem and the the the
float valve didn't work and the whole
room is flooded oh yes it's not when
it's going to flood you know not if it's
going to flood but when it's going to
flood it's uh we also had when we built
grow rooms in Florida when you know the
guy that taught me we used to build sub
FL so uh we we did a sub Flor we pitched
it and then we used back then we used to
use um shower pan liners when they put
underneath a shower in a in in a second
story home you know and then they put
concrete and then they put the tile on
it so we used to glue the shower pan
liners that would uh go on the on the on
the on the pitch floor up the wall and
then we was some hearty Hardy Board that
was painted you know the first one
wasn't painted and they got mold e and
said okay we got to paint them we
painted you know the outside of them and
then the inside of them were moldy so we
painted all the way around when you know
the the shower pain liner went up the
wall hardy hardy plank on the side and
then we foam the whole rooms and then we
the first ones was just the the closo
foam aluminum and then we started
painting them and stuff like that so we
got better it was a progression yeah we
graduated with uh using TPO which is a a
roofing roofing membrane that needs 500
Degrees to to to seal it together wow
and then from there we went to just
through Straight you know you know the
the rolling benches and stuff like that
but so back to that is uh if something
ever bursted it wouldn't flood the house
because there was a drain at the corner
that would send it to the outside of the
of the Garden or whatever right of the
house do you guys use wood rolling
benches back in the day or did you even
from the beginning no no from the
beginning like I said from the beginning
we had a s floor and we started with um
I think it were like one one gallon pots
that were
um call do the hydrogen hydrogen and
then a 3-inch Cube inside the the that
that the one gallon pot with hydrogen
and with top feed and feed to waste feed
to waste so we go on the on on the
shower pan liner work its way down to
the the drain and and go outside yeah
then when uh when when I met the guy uh
the qan guy that um that I bought the
mango from he show me these benches that
they they had a little bit of benches
he's the one that showed me the benches
with the gutter and uh they had 2x4s on
cinder blocks yeah with a gutter and
then they had soft hose that would go
like this in between leech trays you
know Dutch Le trays you know pitched at
an angle uh and they had the little
little L's that you put into the Le tray
so yeah so I'm looking at this thing I'm
trying to absorb as much as possible
because I don't you don't get to take
pictures you only get to be there once
you know or they tell you whatever it is
and then um I said well I'm not going to
use bricks I'm going to use legs and
then uh I'm not going to use this hose
that's going to go like this cuz you
lose pressure put a pipe down the back
of it and then offshoots and then uh
spaghetti spaghetti drippers so while
you're evaluating this this girl as as
you're as they're telling you about it
or you're or you're looking at it and
then uh before you know when they look
at your stuff it's like [ __ ] I should
have never told this guy I should have
never told him you know and you know you
show me once and it's over and then from
then on I just I just you know I just
kind of do it on my own
right nice and so going into the troll
Masters that so that was in California
or Florida no the troll master was
actually Oregon oh in Oregon in Oregon
yeah in Oregon I went up to Oregon to um
to work for six months I thought I was
going to jail oh [ __ ] after I got raided
you know I was fighting this Cas and I
was in my mind I was going to jail so I
was figur I'd go to work and try to save
as much money right to save whatever The
Shoe Box had at that time cuz they got
my ass kicked in uh in that time so I
know all about that yeah it sucks shitty
feeling it sucks bro you know you got
you know you're on your own people treat
you like you're leopard uh everybody
from from theet good you know just
you're a rat I mean they don't you know
people said I got out the next day bull
[ __ ] I said they kept us unweeded
unweeded they kept us in jail for 30
[ __ ] days wow 30 days on weed yeah I
had a [ __ ] lab but they still I mean
people get out they wouldn't let us
because we're from Florida they thought
they were going get out and then skip so
um yeah the wife say said you want going
to baild you out I'm said I said no
don't baild me out
it would have been 50k either too and I
don't want to lose that 50k yeah a 2
million million $2 million Bond I didn't
want to I don't want to lose 50k so I
said no I mean I know how the law works
you know what I'm saying the longer you
sit in there yeah the the lower the bond
gets you know what I'm saying I listen I
didn't I didn't kill anybody it wasn't
an aggravated all nonviolent nonviolent
offense you know I didn't you know I
wasn't a pedopile none of that I just
knew in time the bond was going to go
down they weren't you know they it just
has to yeah so I just didn't think it
was going to be 30 days but it was it
was 30 days and then they finally uh
they finally um let us out you know on
on a on a lower Bond and then uh I got
out with with with another guy and then
I went to the bank because they released
my bank accounts yeah and uh and I got
the other guys out you know I got the
other guys out and then uh then they
wouldn't let us leave to go to Cal uh to
go to Florida for four months which was
kind of cool you know why because I had
free labor from those guys that were
staying at the farm and they helped me
oh sh de construct de construct the
3,000 ft building and put it back to
normal because I had to sell that
property oh wow I had to sell that
property so I did constructed everything
I sold everything that was that was not
strapped down M and then I kept a 16 uh
16 lighter as a as a as a comeback hit
cuz like I said I thought I was going to
jail so right I kept a 16 lighter that I
put in a in a in a warehouse for like
three years or four years waiting for
back then it was a good time to do it 16
lighter yes yeah that was the comeback
hit you I can come back with 16 lights
and and build a future from there
totally now maybe
not don't know it be tough itd be tough
I can probably just you know probably
just pay the bills you know I don't know
about a comeback but you can probably
survive you could probably survive if
you goow good in enough flour if you do
it yourself you know you [ __ ] with the
new technology you can get three pounds
of light of good flour I mean we were
looking at those undercarriage lights uh
yesterday and uh what's his brand it's a
fa it was F really really cool Bobby
bags shout out to Bobby bags out Bobby
bags uh you know my buddy Justin he'd
been talking about that for a long time
with his own version of it but like
these lights 200 bucks and they you
retail 200 and you got one per 4x4 and
you're G to he talks 25% yield I don't
even care if it's 10% yield you know I
think it pay for itself it's going to
make the quality better I've been doing
since the place that I got rated at I've
been I've been doing the Sid lighting MH
uh
the Pacific light Concepts gave me some
uh some cobs and so did next light gave
me some some some panels nice and I ran
them up top and I wasn't I don't think
that I think the LEDs were almost there
they really weren't quite what they are
today yeah and I had a [ __ ] on LEDs and
I'm thinking you know it's like I mean
these things are cool what am I going to
do with them and then um they had the
cops or three cobs I forget the wattage
and it just says you know what I'm going
to put him on the side of the [ __ ]
walls nice so I lined up all these rooms
with with lights like every so often and
I did a run and I'm like holy [ __ ]
bigger yields holy [ __ ] is they like you
know some strains are are better than
other some strains I mean you with all
of it it's some some strains are better
in CMH than they are in HPS or LED but
I'm saying like there's some strains
that have butt sights all the way down
to the rock wall I mean like back then
purple punch was hot and I I would have
buds of purple punch almost this size
right here yeah I I don't like purple
punch that's a bad example you know what
back then hot I don't anybody says you
know what say if if they pay for it it's
great you might not like to smoke it but
people paid for it it looked amazing
purple punch it was the biggest let down
we ever it amaz beautiful and I was one
of the first ones to have it I got
blessed some dude goes somebody stole
the cut from somebody I don't I didn't
this is the story those hot women in La
that look amazing and then they have no
soul there's a lot of Miami
yeah more in Florida probably more in
Florida yeah but this guy calls me about
about a couple points I found obviously
found this story about later I didn't
know and it's like you know I took a you
know took a whim on a whim I said yeah
whatever a th bucks no problem I go and
he goes well where you at when can you
come get I go I'm I'm on my way to
Sacramento Airport he goes [ __ ] I
thought you were in Miami obviously he
reached out to me because he thought I
was in Miami like most people do I go no
I'm in Sacramento I'm going to the
airport so he met me I got the purple
punch and and and I grew it but anyway
back to the LEDs the LEDs I mean I
remember I but a purple punch almost as
big as this coming out of the rock like
this and it's like are you kidding me
but then I called Pacific FL concerts
and I order more I paid for these next
time and then I just lined up the whole
two sides wow and then I dropped
HPS bulbs in the center of the aisles
and I caged them because people you know
guys or or girls were were burning
themselves in the shoulders because they
were touching were hot oh I bet and then
the heels just went through the roof it
was just crazy uh because I had I had
upgraded from um standard HPS to these
and then I added this side lighting um
that was on the outside walls yeah and
then the drop walls on the S and it was
just it was just massive massive
everything's getting an even amount of
ppfd it was just tons of light I don't
know what the [ __ ] ppfd back was back
then you mean but it was just tons of
light and it just and I just knew that
it worked and then uh later on after I
think it was
2018 or Beginnings to 2019 2019 I think
it was after I came back from Oregon
yeah I built there amazing two-car
garage for the guys these guys in Santa
Rosa
California and uh I called the guy um
cord which is uh he was part owner of
Pacific light Concepts and I said hey
man I'm looking to remember those those
those those slice that you gave me I'm
building a garage and I want to make
these these custom panels you know that
I can erase up and down in the aisles
because right the other place was just
long and it was just two rows so I could
put them on the outside but this one was
several rows and you got to work in the
aisle so how am I going to do this so um
he goes yeah don't problem I I'll help
you out you know so we we'll do some
strips so I kind of did some drawings
and I still have those drawings that
says uh king wooks um sidelights or
something or hilarious yeah guess he was
kind of you know he's like he like a
hash guy and that was his nickname you
know wook you know King wook so we
called him King wook um so anyway u i I
designed these panels and then I went to
a fabricator in town he got this piece
of aluminum metal you know I gave him
the dimensions he made and then uh you
know I glued these these the I think
were 100 100 watt sticks with Samsung
LEDs um and I put them on there with
this with this tape that would allow the
heat to to go into the metal and I built
these things and he sent me the whole
kit to be able to hook them up and then
we had sidelights that would go up and
down wow and that place Crush too for a
two-car garage [ __ ] I parked the range
on the outside of the other the house so
the light just goes up and down nice and
slow no no no you you put it in in place
you know in in the in the walls it was
only one-sided it was fixed to the wall
but in the aisles yeah you would drop it
you you know you you leave it there but
then if you had to go service dial then
you got a pulley You' pull them out of
the way you spray the you spread the
rolling benches and then you go service
you go defoliate water you know whatever
you whatever you want to do you know
yeah um pick and then when you're done
with the aisle you uh you drop the
lights and then close the benches and
then go to the next one and do the same
thing yeah and uh that that garage is
actually operating to this day really
and when I built it back in 20 see we're
2023 now 2018 people uh
well they didn't call well they called
him through my Instagram what an idiot I
can't believe he's spending that money
he's going to get busted it's going to
do this he gonna do that they thought I
was still a rat at that time yeah you
know you hear it all and then guess what
silly [ __ ] 2023 and they're still
operating
yeah I feel you I feel you they're
number
funny yeah man but yeah that's great and
so with the lights what makes your light
so special because I feel like you have
a special light that's different than
other people's light lights um at first
our lights were special because they had
the right spectrum and they had the the
the best diodes in the market yeah uh
and the controllability is second to
none um the cats out of the bag
everybody knows you know what what what
good diodes are what bad diodes are
everybody knows that lm301 BS were the
were were the best di at that time
they're not anymore they are uh there's
an H there's evos but they're so
expensive nowadays that it's just not
commercially viable to go to those to
those um di because the difference is
not that much you know maybe for a small
manufacturer lights it is but not for
for a bigger company uh the osram Reds
is what we use but uh controllability is
King and uh people started to catch on
that you know you want to be able to
control the the the deep red and or
control the far red uh so they started
adding that but um to this day there's
not a combination of controller and
light that work as good as the
trollmaster Hydrox Pro with the th gr
LED lights yeah um now our lights have
four spectrums and they're all can be
individually adjusted to your liking and
strain dependent uh as you saw yesterday
when I brought you through uh when when
you stopped by uh our plays I show you
the the test that we're doing um a lot
of times people read Google or read
books or whatever it is and they get
information and then you go to the next
story it contradicts what you just read
right uh and that was the issue with me
for this last four years that I took a
Hiatus from from growing um I was
selling LEDs and I knew there were
really good good LEDs you know um but I
didn't really play with them myself
because I didn't have a personal grow so
I'm just starting to actually put all
this stuff into into into uh I'm
implementing all these tests myself
because I'm I'm a kind of person I I
want to do it right I want to prove it
to myself and um all these things that
I've been you know they've been telling
me that you know the the far red you
know was stretch was short short and
will uh will take off time so I'll find
and dandy but I need to do it so I can
see it for myself believe it and then I
can teach people about it and tell them
how to do it so the first test that
we're we doing yesterday is we we you
seen it pretty dark on I wanted I want
you to stay there when the lights went
off so you could say wow okay yeah yeah
there's far red here and it's not really
light polluting any anything in the
center no um so it was important for me
to show you that so you know five
minutes of of far red after dark and
then the opposite side at 30 minutes
after after Darkness you know that that
the red stay on mhm and um it seems like
it it shaved two weeks of a nine weeks
train well it looks like something's
going on there for sure for sure for
sure so uh what we started doing I you
know we're going to do this the right
way what we're going to do is we're
going to cut tops of somewhat the same
size same height away from the light in
in the five minute after dark the the
control subject and then the 30 minutes
after dark and then we're going to label
them okay this one was it you know uh 50
days and three days later do it again
and then another three days later do it
again and then we're going to send all
that stuff to testing we also look at
them through the loop and the loops are
are showing that that that it's pretty
much done but uh at the end of the day
you know um the test is going to tell
you the the the truth I think it's it's
a
cbga that's going to tell you if if if
that plant if you left meat on the bone
per se or not you know when it's fully
mature so at the end of the day roughly
um we have to take that room to 63
because the majority of the room was set
for that so even if if if these two rows
get twoo dark as that get two Amber or
whatever what's going to have to happen
um and the environmentals in that room
were set to finish in nine weeks yeah uh
so then we'll send those for testing the
next round we're going to do it to where
we expand our our test subjects to five
racks from one side five racks in
another there's 13 racks in that room
and then three racks are going to be in
the that are going to be the control
control and then we're going to run that
room to finish the environmentals we're
going to run it to finish in seven weeks
so it should actually what you seen
yesterday it actually should be farther
along because now we're we're we're
making the room colder faster we're
going to we're going to drop the EC uh
you know um earlier yeah and then we're
going to uh you know lower the ppfd and
the light you know earlier so actually
what we saw yesterday should be actually
probably even farther along and even
more Amber than than what we we sawest
yesterday because the environmentals
followed the the the timeline right yeah
it's really impressive and it's really
it's it's very obvious it's not yeah
that's the thing is it's very obvious
it's you can't argue the fact and the
funny thing is like when you you know
like uh the the other day uh you know
the director cultivation was in there
and then you know the the the ppfd is
down on the on on the on the LEDs and
you can't really dim an LED by the way
you can't dim an LED the way that you
Dim an LED is by um
it's flashes LED flashes okay so when
it's on 100% it's just on and when you
start doing let's say 90 90% it flashes
off for super quick time and it comes
back on the lower the dim the off cycle
is is longer yeah then the on cycle so
that's how you Dim an LED believe it or
not so it's not really dimming it is
you're talking to it a morse code per se
so then when you're videoing you see all
these little lines yeah in in in the
phone but then so I told the director
ofation turn these up to 100 cuz I want
to do a video because the lines were
messing up with the video the color and
know you're doing this video and then
their representation on the phone is not
the same as your eyesight when you're
seeing this these things are [ __ ]
done they're purple and then you look
over here these are these are white you
know still got white hairs and stuff
like that it's more of a visual thing
when you're there and you know it tells
you wow these things really working
right so um so it's going to be
interesting to uh to do it the next time
you know and uh and and really be able
to have the science behind it and give
people the feedback
uh and on on this totally well you've
been doing a bunch of data collection
sounds like from talking to you guys you
guys collecting data on phenotypes and
you're also doing some pheno hunting yes
we're doing some pheno hunting uh you
know something that I'm not used to
doing this is something new for me uh
you're the expert on this on this on
this field for sure very challenging
this is the first like I said I've never
I think I in my life I probably count
one hand how many how many seeds I
popped until this last run I went from
like five seeds in my life to like you
know 520 seats wow so it was it was
definitely it's an adventure it's
definitely cool and then seeing these
these these different fenos like oh my
God this one's tall and it's busting out
this one over here looks like a bonsai
tree yeah uh it's like H holy crap well
then you're doing the initial growing
from seed the first run so your next run
is going to be completely different so
some of the stuff that looks a certain
way when you grow up from the first
clonal generation it could be a
completely different expression you
could lose chps you could gain chps you
could you just get different things as
the plant matures and uh well sometimes
they get better which is I ask a lot of
questions to to to to breeders like I
said this is not my field so yeah um by
no means am I nowhere near a [ __ ]
expert or anything like that so I ask
questions and what everybody says just
best just clone everything in there yeah
you know put it to the side you know
flip those see which ones are your males
then go back to your clone room and kill
those or if you want to keep them
whatever you know but you know get rid
of them and then once you're left you
know what everything is that you think
is females then plant those that way
they all run at the same time right you
know it's like you know you have you
know 400 plants this one's small there
take less less water this one St is
going to take a lot less water when
you're an automated system it doesn't
work that way yeah so it's best if they
all grow at the same speed and then uh
obvious going have to keep an eye just
in case something throws a banana um but
um they say that it gives you a better
representation of what that that plant
or that feno is going to be once you're
start cloning it so I don't know you
tell me me I like getting rid of that
first generation because I don't want to
see something that I can't have okay so
I like getting rid of the SE me
personally that's just I think that
growing from seed is great outdoors and
I think there's obviously growing from
seed is great you'll get bigger plants
you get a tap rot but if you're looking
for what's the long-term expression
because you're going to keep this alive
in a clone form getting rid of that
first generation is okay perfect you
gota and it saves you time so you don't
have to grow that out to see it again
now you get the first generation the
second generation CU you really got to
grow them out and you'll fall in love
with some and then the next Generation
you might fall in love with some others
and then third generation it's like the
ones that are still amazing those are
usually the ones you go for sick Okay
cool so I guess I'm I'm I'm in the right
direction somebody you're going the
right direction somebody Point me the
right way it's yeah and it's all fun
it's all like this it's a very like very
fun the exploration side of it like
where you're exploring different plants
and you have a chance of winning the
lottery cuz technically it's a big
lottery we're all playing the lottery
trying to hit that one here the lottery
for
sure as expensive as a lottery too yeah
yeah but back to the L you have an
expensive facility you have the the most
expensive the most built out facility
I've ever been it's like yeah it's the
Lamborghini of facilities but there's a
reason for that you know I know that I
went over and Beyond yeah uh in in in
building this thing but the reason why
this facility is so nice is because we
use it for tours when I was selling
controllers and selling lights oh yeah
it's the best the best sales pitch you
don't have to tell anybody you just show
them come on by yeah come on by you're
looking to build something you want to
see how it's done you know come on come
on check it out the funny thing is that
um like you were saying about the LEDs
you know um you know I started and I got
sidetracked um the controllability on on
these LEDs is like no other and then
while I was building that facility a lot
of a lot of ideas that the owner of
trollmaster had and combined with my
ideas we developed a lot of products
while we were building that that space
right Co did throw a wrench on our on on
our spoke and slowed us down but uh
there was a lot of products that were
developed while the facility was being
built like you know the lifters or
something that he had in his in his mind
for a long time we actually built
prototypes and I tested them tested them
and then gave them feedback and um even
like the the there was a room that I
actually changed lights without even
growing in there because there was a new
model that came out and I wanted it and
I wanted to show it because you know
that the facility is there is to sell
product and me sell products for for for
troll Master showing the troll Master's
potential so I Ed the troll Master too
in some of my I've used it in the past
and it's beautiful in the sense that you
can control the lights too you can dim
your lights with the trollmaster on your
phone correct I want to dim the lights
and down to 1% you can dim our lights
down to 1% and 1% increments which a lot
of lights you can only dim down to 40%
well I never thought of the troll Master
as scalable back in the day and now you
go to your place and it's like okay hey
you're doing it and that's another
reason why we uh we decid to do a
facility and we we decided to do it big
enough to where we can show people hey
because trust me a lot of people tell me
yeah Q controller you know it's like
Legos okay nice cute for the garage and
they used to make fun of me and tell me
yeah you keep building your little
garages and stuff like that
and I can look at him and says yeah I
got a I got a I got like a you know I
don't know like a 600 car garage now
that I grow eting seriously haters are
going to hate every day all day they
don't stop and you know most of these
haters you know where they're at they're
they're in Mon's basement somewhere cuz
they don't have a life seriously I never
had anybody come rag on me that was
doing better than me you know why James
because they're too [ __ ] busy they
don't have the time for they don't have
the [ __ ] time for it so anybody that
that goes on my page or your [ __ ]
page and and and K you know what they
got time in their hands they ain't got
nothing going in their lives yeah
seriously it's just it's a it's a hard
reality for some people but you know it
is what it is you know what they say if
they hate on you you ain't you ain't got
nothing going on yeah if you haven't
made any enemies along the way you
probably haven't gotten there yet no no
you ain't doing [ __ ] so that's the way
it is for sure your whole uh place is a
family affair you got your son working
for you and yeah my son my son works for
me and uh he was he was super sad to to
leave Florida uh obviously you know
Florida's a beautiful place I love to be
able to go back there uh sometime um
we're uh uh we're we're a red State
Republican you know California is very
liberal it's very um very blue very it
isn't it isn't like you're here but but
you know what like there there's a lot
of red areas in uh in the in the rural
areas but like you know mostly
Sacramento you know
lailan people and s in Sacramento San
Francisco you go Bak field and it's
pretty red pretty red exactly you know
all the rural areas are pretty pretty
red everything else so it's definitely
uh some adjusting but you know the kid's
young you know he uh you know he's in
his early 20s yeah you know chasing
girls the beach you know playing
volleyball in the sun you know hot hot
water ocean and you take them to a
landlock place you know he's he's
depressed yeah uh but you know what you
know he's depressed but then he um he
came to the facility uh you know just
like any any Father and Son there's
arguments you know there's fights
there's yelling at screaming you know
and uh but the kid the kid uh the kid
came into his own you know he stepped up
and um he he is the go-to guy if you
want any [ __ ] questions answer about
troll Master go to my kid yeah because
he way surpassed me on the on the troll
Master knowledge on all the controllers
and there's a couple reasons for that
they're young they're very Tech savy
super tech savy information [ __ ]
buttons like dude slow the [ __ ] down
dude you know well let me figure it out
and I'll tell you after I'm like no talk
to me through it he's just like you know
pushing fingers it was aggravating and
then he laugh he thinks it's funny but
but whatever and then and then the other
thing is also I I feel like I tell
people all the time I walk around the
building go I don't even grow eat
anymore I grow a business I grow emails
that's what I do I'm you know I do make
sure that I get out of my office and I
walk the rooms all the time I'm I'm at
the facility every day I get involved
but at the end of the day you know I run
a business I you know if there's if if
there's an issue that they can't take
care of her dress then then I go and and
try to figure out but they for the most
part take care of that stuff and then
that kid came into his own with uh with
trollmaster actually him and the owner
him and the owner of trollmaster not
talk probably me more than I do because
he's the one that's doing all the data
and all the testing you know that um is
passed on to him so he he takes care of
that yeah that's great that's great and
it's something that you can pass on to
him that you guys share and you guys are
both passionate about because I I see it
I talked to him a lot yesterday and it's
really impressive what you guys are
doing yeah he's definitely came into his
own uh I think he likes I think he likes
it you know he he likes he likes being
there he he sees I think he's I mean he
kids have their own personalities I got
one that's in colge that that graduated
college he graduated from law school
he's an attorney now he wants nothing to
do with cannabis he doesn't drink he
doesn't party doesn't go to strip gloves
nothing there's other one is more like
me you know the mango doesn't fall far
fall far from the tree when he lives in
level ground you know and uh but now the
gentics lean heavy on your side yeah for
sure and now that he sees there you know
he's never and I sheltered my kids for
for a reason because I knew what you
know what weed kind of the taboo you
know um that that I carried with it and
and the time that I would carry and I
didn't want him to follow my footsteps
never did I realized that this stuff was
going to become legal and I moved to a
legal state but but now he he
understands and he seen a transition
from okay that's a mom that's a teen
that's a clone and if he goes to Florida
for five days comes but you know he's
eager to come back into the room and
like what we did if we ever stepped away
from our grow room we you know first
thing you come back from a trip whatever
trip or vacation or what it is the first
place that you go to is you go to the
grow room and then check it out you go
holy crap they [ __ ] exploded oh my
God I can't believe how big they got how
fast they grow so he's starting to see
that and he's starting to get the love
for the plant which is kind of kind of
cool he you know he's he's uh he talks
to I hear him talk to his friends and
show you know show pictures on videos so
he's definitely de developing a love for
the plant that that we all develop well
when we were young and then and then
growing up right yeah and it's great cuz
he's going to evolve into some I'm sure
in the industry and it's like as far as
his passion it's going to take in places
that we wouldn't never even thought
correct and I and I hope so I hope one
day you know he's you know he's
hopefully say I'm getting old IA want to
you know yeah take take a take a step
back here in a few years once
everything's running properly and then
uh you know the the I got I got I got an
awesome crew at the at the facility you
know I got a great director cultivation
he um he puts his heart and soul into
the space uh I don't think I could have
hired to say a better guy for that role
um he's like me he's he's there early
he's there last sometimes you know I
feel I feel guilty if I don't go to work
and sometimes I feel guilty if I leave
leave him there it's like yeah I feel
like [ __ ] I'm I should be the one that's
closing the door uh but he's he's I'm
I'm very very satisfied with with the
guy that I got there and then same thing
with the director of operations they
they were all they were both hired to to
do their roles and uh I think they both
do them well and then I think we got an
awesome team you know everybody all the
other managers that uh that are there
it's a happy environment right uh it's a
happy environment everybody does does
their job and there's really no no
issues there and it's pretty it's pretty
cool I mean I'm I'm pretty happy with
with everything you know nice can't
complain that's nobody going listen
anyway yeah well you're like you're
pretty much a workaholic when you're not
on your phone you're trying to build
stuff you got you got other projects
going on too right yes um we uh we're
we're just getting ready to open up the
mangot tech store nice happens to be
about a mile and a half from from the
facil
uh another 20,000 foot building roughly
uh 6,000 of that towards the front of
the the space is uh it's a showroom it's
like 4,000 square foot showroom and then
2,000t of offices where we're going to
be uh have sales people there we're
going to be able to do light Maps nice
you know we're going to be able to do
electrical drop maps for our uh daisy
chain cords on uh on Cad and then we're
going to do wind Maps because we got a
new fan line coming wind maps to figure
out you know um we got a new whole new
fan line that was developed while this
place was being built right uh cuz some
other companies didn't want to play ball
with me and pay me commission so I
became their
competitor and U that happens it happens
you know you're gonna pay me or I'm gon
I'm gonna compete against you just you
know I was I was lucky enough to be able
to find a partner that uh you know um
that can build stuff for me and uh then
we can you know I can sell it so that's
what happens and uh and the showrooms
pretty cool the showrooms is is is is
one-of a kind first of its kind is like
an Apple Store uh Hydra store uh we
don't sell everything under the sun
there we we we're we're branded we're
focus on selling uh troll Master stuff
nice think R stuff and all our affiliate
companies that that that are with us
we're going to carry their products
there um we're going to we're going to
Showcase them and sell it too but uh but
the place is also buil there's also a 16
light custom grow room in that space DPS
panels and everything uh grow Glide
racks double tiered single tiered and
I'm going to put every single call it do
hickey that troll master has in those
racks and then uh the thought process
was and obviously this evolves as it
went we're going to put a tag with a QR
code and everything from the daisy
chains to to the the the flood detectors
everything so people just they're going
to go I didn't know they made that I
didn't know they made that what is that
they can go scan it with their phone
yeah it can take pictures you know
because they the only place the only way
you're going to get a tour my fail if
you can prove to me that you're going to
spend about 100 Grand in my store you
know what I'm saying because yeah at the
end of the day you know I can't do a
tour for everybody a tours take two
three four five hours and if I did a
tour for everybody I wouldn't do
anything so people that come to the
facility are either friends that I've
had for a long time you know they get a
tour or they've opened somebody's opened
the doors for me to go to their space or
you're going to buy if you're going to
buy come on in let's go yeah how many
lights you want to buy you know how many
controllers you need come on in I'll
show you and we get people from from
around the city the state the country
and around the world they can come on in
but this Bas anybody can come in you can
you you don't smoke weed you can still
come there and chill out we're going to
have a little Lounge area um and uh and
then you can see how this place is you
know like that place is built like a
commercial facility and you're going to
be able to copy and do it whether is you
have a a one light in a in a room and
you can do whatever the best you can
with with with the funds that you got
the capital or or if you have a
commercial facility that or a trap
whatever I don't care I don't judge come
by check it out you know and um and it's
perfectly located you know eth mile off
the 50 between Lake Tahoe and San
Francisco and between you know reading
and like Selenas roughly you know yeah
middle middle of the road so I'm sure
there'll be I'm sure there'll be many
drug deals being done in that parking
lot yeah I want 10% yeah right
especially if you come inside and sit on
the couch
right how do you see the future of the
industry as far as lighting has made so
much progress since 20 like 12 13 when
it was the purple LEDs and the it was
the worst butt ever the blurp yeah the
blurp from that to where it is now as
being the the main focus for most
companies they're like okay we're doing
LEDs they're cost effective all this
where do you see the industry going in
you know five years 10 years the I think
I we went over to that
um to that uh I call it a seminar where
where Bobby bags was talking about the
yeah connect event exactly that surger
throw um and I went there just you know
just check it out hear out what they
have to say um one thing that we've been
trying to work on for the last four
years is is some kind of side lighting
interner canopy lighting they call it
inter canopy lighting yeah is something
that's very hot uh I went to MJB last
year and seen a bunch of it there the
side lighting or the inner canopy
lighting back then it was side lighting
was something that would work on yeah
nowadays is uh is inner canopy lighting
um so it's not uh it's not um under
canip Li on canopy lightning sits at the
bottom of your tray yeah um pretty much
level with the top of your medium and
and the light shine shines up M so uh
the way that the light goes up into the
bottom of the canopy and then the top of
the leaves well the light shines up to
the bottom of the canopy it reflects and
then it hits the top of your leaf and
that's called aaal U because it's
reflecting it's hitting the bottom of
your by bottom of leaves but the plants
are absorbing the light that's
reflecting from the bottom of the leaves
in the canopy yeah um we wanted to go a
step better above and beyond so we we
put our
lights up in the canopy m a diode has
180 degree I mean sorry 120 degree
spread yeah um and we went both sides so
then that's called um Ada axio because
the light shining on top of the leaf so
it's more direct it's more
efficient um we've had a couple of
prototypes and I thought the last
prototype was the one that we were going
to go with which I showed you and uh at
the last last second you know sometimes
I I leak Intel and
purpose to uh to see what the peanut
gallery has to say you know you got
something to say there's always op
there's always P you know and then and
you you evaluate that information that
comes in you know everybody's always got
a has got an idea how they're going to
do it better and stuff like that but at
the end of the day it's it's Intel that
you take you evaluate and then you you
you work from there so uh this was going
to be the last prototype and I ended up
kicking like a little girl and saying no
we need to change it and you know by the
time this thing this thing's been
through projects you know there's a mold
there's this there there there's
thousands and thousands of dollars in
time and hours right that's been put
into this
project so they don't really want to
scrap it but um you know finally at the
end of the day you know I take
temperatures you know and you know with
you know Leaf temperatures are touching
these sinks and then you know some some
Leaf might be having a little burnt I
said we're going to you know I take
pictures and I send they go we're going
to get picked for that we're going to
get Nick picked for that so um so then
we uh we decided to call the ICL 300s
because it has a 300 degre spread of
light nice not just 180 but you know
they're going to go actually down and
then all the way around right and you
can stack our our lights so kind of
touching based on what you think the
future is because that's what the
original question was is I think Bobby
bags was correct that in in a couple of
years yeah people will have some kind of
inner or under canopy inter canopy
lighting
because to build another space cost a
lot of money yeah um and you know the
buildout the rent the time that you know
say if you have this space how can we
squeeze more juice out of this fruit
yeah you know what inner canopy lighting
that is the [ __ ] Next Level so Justin
our our mutual friend Justin apical
biotech uh he when I first met him he
was talking about this stuff and he was
like you need to attach it to the
trellis like it'll go up with the
trellis you know the lighting that goes
and I thought he was a little crazy
right I've heard every freaking
suggestion oh totally no this is but
this was 2018 and I was like this guy's
crazy a little bit you know cuz he has
crazy ideas yes he does he's very
knowledgeable yeah he's super
knowledgeable he thinks outside the box
he has some ideas where I'm like oh no
and then now now like it's pretty you
know I think it's going to be a
standardized thing is eventually we'll
have 100% And especially for green
houses I see the benefit even more than
for indoor indoor it's great you'll get
more yield and stuff but if you can
harden up those buds that are in the
greenhouse where you have supplemental
lighting now you've got an indoor
product right it looks like an indoor
product it'll help it'll help it'll help
increase it'll help to increase the
quality of like you know I I love
sungrown too so I think it's like the
perfect mix if we can do mix light a a
little bit of mix light Little Mix
Little Mix light yeah for for sure and I
I just think that's like I said Bobby I
think hit it hit it on the nose in in
the future people are going to evaluate
wow I can get another 20 you know he's
he's right on numbers you know 15 to 25%
yeah increase uh and he was right on a
lot of things that he said you know now
you you know you have a a a buds that
are that are purple you have a buds that
are not you know they say purple or
whatever color that's that's you know
color of the day or you know color of
the Year whatever and then you have your
bees and stuff like that and then when
you have under canopy lighting or inner
canopy lighting everything becomes
unified uniform you know you got bigger
Buds and then the problem is going to be
is what it not a problem but everybody's
going to is going to brag we have the
best pre-rolls because it's all bud you
know they don't know they're not going
to use the the micros yeah for pre-rolls
everybody right now everyone's using
Smalls although some people like the
guys over SF Canada their Smalls are
just as good as the big nugs you know I
mean they burn clean all that [ __ ] y so
but but yeah it won't be like you won't
get Smalls Smalls is going to be a thing
of the past I he was talking about 5%
and I get it like when when it's all
graded you know if you did it right and
you had the right genetics because
that's very dependent on the genetics
too yep yep the good thing about our
inner canopy lights is that um single
tier you you run a little bit taller
plant than you do in your double tier
yeah uh our our inner canopy lights
you'll be able to stack you know one on
top of each other so you're going to
have and they're going to shine up right
so you're really going to have light
from the tray yeah and you don't need a
ton of light so we're not talking about
wat 12 watt 60 60 watts per side it's
really it's really not not not that much
yeah but think about it if you have a
five foot tall plant um you have light
from the top coming down yeah and
then and then you have a light bar
inside the canopy that's shining and
then you have another one up here you
have light from the bottom to the top so
there is no maximum efficiency maximum
efficiency it also is going to require
more uh more parts per million higher EC
potentially correct Y and he had a bunch
of good information in there too
additional you're going to have to feed
it more have to feed it more a little
bit more feed you know for sure
transpiration more transpiration a
little more humidity but that's because
you can handle that you know you can add
a dehumidifier you can add you know a
these serious dehumidifiers now that to
handle that kind of stuff yes and then
obviously uh there's there's there's
reheat also if people want wanted to go
that way they can do use the reheat in
in a in an AC unit if they wanted to do
that too yeah so there's definitely
options but I think I think the easiest
way to
increase your money in a current space
is going to be the inner canopy lighting
hands down instead of building another
SP besides having good genetics besides
having good genetics you know good
genetics goes we all know good gentics
everybody's genetics but but but having
good gentics got to have good genetics
it's everything 100% 100% you got to
have good it all starts from that seed
at some point in life but it starts from
having good genetics I mean if if you
don't have good
genetics it's hard to get I you can't
get good weed out of shitty genetics it
just doesn't you either got to have good
genetics start good seeds or you got to
have friends that give you good genetics
yeah there's somewhere along line
sometimes you cheat and you say hey man
what do you got and they go I got this
for you don't give it to anybody okay no
F yeah yeah you know totally and that
works and that works for yeah genetics
is everything you know at the end of the
day I feel like genetics is what it
boils down too like we're in the
genetics race right now everybody's
trying to get their own new thing
there's so many noway just kind of crazy
you know everybody like I said even if
you're not a breeder you're you're an
in-house guy and then you know you have
a little of pollen you have a reversal
plan and you go start touching I mean
you might not be getting a jar of seeds
like this but you know you get you get
you know you get you know 10 20 30 40 50
seeds out of a branch you know if you
want to put pollen on a branch
and then you're you're an in-house guy
you can get genetics there's just so
much of it well I was talking to one of
my friends I was talking to Mojave
Richmond we were talking about cultivars
and how many cultivars there are in the
United States right now in in wck and
there's somewhere between 35 and
5,000 different C different named
cultivars it could be a lot of the same
[ __ ] but and then worldwide 20,000
different cultivars that's way more than
any other plant species that's been uh
domesticated available for you know
commercial and and Retail you know what
I I don't I don't know if there correct
me if I'm wrong but I don't think that
there is there I don't know if any of
you guys have sat down and made a a
forum page whatever internet page that
shows every single name of strain
because I mean there's so many strains
nowaday that it's hard to come up with a
name and I suck coming up with name it's
tough It's I suck coming up with names
the director of cultivation that work
for yeah chat gbt hey call it this but
uh the director cation that that works
for me he's great at coming up with
names like [ __ ] just just spat that
out I've been thinking for three days
what to call something he just just spit
it out but um what happens seedfinder EU
is the place where you go for all the
genetics it's the closest thing we
really have now that I think is an
organized list of lineage interesting so
I got a question for you let's say you
cross two strains and you come up with a
name for something right and then XYZ
person over there crosses same strings
or two different strains uhhuh well
let's go one one problem at a time they
say crosses the same strains and then
causes the same thing by accident or
whatever it is so what takes president
what takes president I mean this is this
is the question of the of the year uh
you know because it happens all the time
people have the same come up with the
same name you know because there's so
many names Black Betty for instance like
I named something Black Betty this other
[ __ ] guy named something Black Betty
too and it was probably someone else
that named it before that it's like you
can kind of take credit for anything
until you get it trademarked you ain't
got [ __ ] yeah until you have a trademark
on you can't trademark strain either
anyway you the name the name kind of
like I get yeah but you can trademark
the name in California you on a state
level you can trademark stuff okay right
but but there still I mean and that's
like if we're looking at it from a legal
standpoint if we're talking about uh if
we're talking about clout and all these
other things that's a whole different
thing because I can the perfect example
is rain rbow runs uh can Organics came
out with rainbow runs I was working with
Tim and Kyle and there's rainbow runs it
was originally rainbow runs and then
literally Mike from exotic comes out
with rainbow runs and sells it
commercially he's obviously way bigger
big dude so he get he gets everybody's
like rainbow runs and they think of his
so Tim and Kyle renamed rainbow runs
rain shadow runs which is the Skittles
times gelato 41 and it's [ __ ] amazing
and it's different completely different
but like this happens all the time and
so it's like um I think it's just one of
those things like we're going to have
you know it's going to be rainbow runs
by exotic as opposed to Rainbow runs by
that in the future and that this kind of
stuff happens unless we have trademarks
that's the only way to really like if
you have it trademarked and it's your
[ __ ] then you know you've paid the the
money and you can enforce it too if
other people try to do it on the
commercial now if we're talking outside
a wreck that's a different story correct
yeah I gotta yeah and and it's tough to
to to enforce things nowadays on
something that's kind
of regulated but not regulated you know
there's no banking stuff like that so if
if these guys that are trap and they
they they breed and they call something
you know how a lot of this stuff becomes
big on the black yeah on the black
market how you supposed to find those
people send them cease assist right hey
you can't call that that that's you know
that's this Trin that I that I created
and I've been working years and I paid
all this money to get go getting
trademarks and putting them implementing
them in every state it's not cheap no
it's not cheap B no enforcement's the
the most part of getting a tradar if you
have to enforce something had some guys
in California they were um they're
selling Vapes with Miami mango and then
somebody sent me a thing and I'm like a
[ __ ] dude okay got to send it to the
attorney right and the attorney's going
to you know five six s you love
lawsuits no I don't they sue me you know
but you know the little little [ __ ]
and they uh they you they started on
Instagram listen I talkot I talk a lot
of [ __ ] on Instagram but but it's my
page right and I don't call anybody out
in particular I just say you know a
group group of people you know um uh uh
hand watering yeah I don't say James La
hand Waters he's this this hell yeah
hand water no I'm kidding I I I I make
fun of a group of people you know what
because I sell automation equipment if I
sold a [ __ ] host I would say
automation sucks mean hello and then I
sell salts you know I sell liquid
fertilizer that is synthetic so J for
you know synthetic fertilizer I make fun
let's say of you know organic stuff even
though I got friends that grow great
organic weed and and then vice versa but
I sell salt so I'm going to make a meme
yeah people get so hung up on it they
they get they get so CAU up on it so
they get they get angry so I talk [ __ ]
on my page but I sell the products and
then people get hung up on it and then
they hate on me they never met me a day
in my life I could probably go out and
have a beer and hang out whatever but
they get so caught up on this because
they do it then there's those people
that say you know what thank you mango
for you know you your memes just got to
me and finally and then I I made the
change I never go back you know those
are cool but uh I talk a lot of crap but
like I said it's generalized to sell and
then these guys come on my page and then
they they they attack me attack my
products I never go on your page they
take it real personal and Instagram
isn't the real world guys it's just
[ __ ] bit it is a piece of the world
but it is not the world and some people
live in it as if it is the world and
it's like there's a whole world outside
that man that's the real world but when
they come at me and then they attack me
on my page then then uh then I start you
know going back at them and then they
they push back and then I started making
memes at him because you know then I got
time you know I sit in my truck and just
[ __ ] play you know I I am the boss of
the company so I can sit in the truck
and make a meme if I feel like it I
don't clock in so I got time um and then
they uh they start feeling in and people
start you know they call them the mango
minions they start you know you know
joining in and then they they start
feeling threatened they don't like it
you know they get poked and then uh give
me your legals bro because I'm going to
sue you you know you're going to feel me
I go okay well we went to [ __ ] court
and then Lu yeah I you know I got smart
and then I I attack jurisdiction I'm not
going to entertain your your case your
seven counts that you try to to me on
they were [ __ ] and frivolous um I
attacked jurisdiction and um and that
was that but it cost me a [ __ ] bunch
of money right to to to go fight that
thing it cost me a ton of money to go to
court and they know it you know what
they [ __ ] know it yeah um they call
themselves that they have in-house
attorneys and that's [ __ ] they their
Partners is a is is a law firm because I
know that the attorney that sued me that
filed the paperwork my attorney is not
dumb he goes and sees the guy runs the
name you know see if he's you know a
legal attorney who he works for if he's
you know got a you know um what firm he
works for they do all the due diligence
you know they they assess the the
problem you know you assess your the
people you're going to go battle with
and the the same um attorney that was
suing me that was an in-house attorney
was in the same attorney that was suing
Lux or ET yeah they're all different so
what does that tell you he's partners
with a law firm and they uh it's cheap
to them to drag you into their state
yeah not cheap for you it's not cheap
for me lawyers always win it's not
correct 100% And it's not cheap for me
but we we we did it a smart way we
fought jurisdiction they had a chance to
appeal and they um they decided not to
and then they realized that coming to
California the what they were suing me
for was a lot tougher to enforce enforce
in California a lot tougher to enforce
that they knew it and their attorney
probably told them it's just best if you
probably don't yeah and it's it going to
cost the money because now they're going
to have to hire an attorney in
California that's that's you know CU not
an in-house attorney right um so they
they they just decided to go away but
I'm sure they I don't know at some point
I'm sure he's find he's going to try to
find something else who
knows I know whatever wild times yeah
just reminds me like California or uh
reminds me of Florida Sue State you know
seem like everybody wants to sue
everybody yeah we would it's it's the
day and age unfortunately when I grew up
we didn't sue people you know no no you
didn't you freaking kind of dealt with
it it is what it is I don't remember my
dad talking about suing people ever you
know no no but but people would fight
back back then too like with fists that
too yeah instead of like this yeah I I
think people fight nowadays to with
megaphones yeah oh dude it's wild that
was pretty funny yeah those uh those got
flagged on Instagram for bullying oh
yeah are you kidding me yeah you're the
biggest bully yeah so so big oh my God
it's crazy so if people are interested
in finding more about what you do where
would they go you got a bunch of places
the easiest way to find me is the
through the through the store uh-huh um
you know ww. mangot tech. store um you
can go go direct yeah go direct yeah you
can buy direct we ship worldwide yeah we
ship worldwide um in uh they they can
they can they can find us or um you know
we we're working on a website should be
a release for the for the facility we
got to have it up before we can we can
sell to the to the wck market and we've
been working on that and you got some
good genetics too you got uh Flamingo
runs Flamingo runs is a great cut of
runs is definitely flavorful and then uh
and that fui is another is another uh
good good strain that you know it's it's
got the right color it's got the right
nose yeah smokes good smokes good tastes
good and then uh people telling me that
that we smoking great so nice shout out
to the director cultivation he's doing a
[ __ ] great job you know yeah he loves
working there he likes working there and
then you seen the improvement from the
from the first time that you you from
the first time it's like night and day
yes I'm be honest it was it was a little
rough in the beginning and it is some of
the rooms were rough uh some of the
rooms were rough um like I said I took a
Hiatus from from growing yeah um well
also you're at a big scale too you're at
a whole another scale it's a new place
with all kinds of new technology uh new
technology technology that you know that
a lot of people have't even uh you know
played with you know thean bubbler you
know LEDs that are badass they're
intense and I took a Hiatus from growing
you know personally even though I so
sold uh sold LEDs this new uh way of
irrigation came about that was you know
crop steering that I no [ __ ] clue
about you know I cycled feed back in the
day um and then you um I actually paid a
couple people to come and consult for me
MH and tell me about crop steering a
couple different people because you know
you you want to get a couple different
you know aspects of their views you know
yeah and then you kind of you know start
playing with this stuff and then I tell
you every [ __ ] room is different
because some rooms are just super
charged they're super efficient yeah the
way that the air flows the way that the
AC is working too much AC less AC a lot
of wind whatever it is so you get all
this information from from people that
been doing it but everything is going to
work out slightly different yeah in your
space and you got to learn that you know
there's there's you can't buy experience
from [ __ ] anybody and that's why I
tell my kid all the time so you got to
figure stuff out you got to put the time
in do the work you got to put the time
in um and so yeah so I'm glad that you
came you got you got to come back
yesterday and we got um it was a great
tour I I redeemed myself a little bit
and for sure you James come here come
here James come into this room what do
you think remember last time so
different so different and very even
canopies now I'd say your canopies are
super even especially compared to before
it's like but these are all learning
curbs and everybody goes through them if
you have it grow and you want to get
better it just it it happens over time
yeah and then the differ size canopies
also like when we started this thing we
started with 63 strings and and against
that's pretty wild that's pretty
aggressive well you had to throw
everything in there and then the
director cultivation is going oh my God
I can't believe I can't believe but I go
we got to figure out what they like what
they don't like and let's just figure
out now so [ __ ] we can put stuff to
the side well it's great doing a handful
at a time but you get a 63 it's like so
hard there was one room that had 17
cultivars you know 2 221 2200 plants and
we had 17 cultiv ours the good thing is
that we kind of uh figured out we kind
of knew the ones that were going to hit
and we we we bulked those in the room so
so the room did okay but overall the the
yields and the ratios from atbs to to
Smalls and micros was was a little
whacked right and uh since then we we we
we we've turned the corner by far and
and we see the light at the end of the
tunnel it's definitely going to get
better from this point on can't wait to
get the inner canopy lighting though in
there yeah it's going to be awesome I
look forward to getting a tour again so
if anybody's looking for you they can go
to your four Instagram accounts mostly
it's the mango 2.0 now um it's Miami
mango Miami period mango 1.0 yeah uh
that's the main account that's the one
that everybody follows because you've
been getting deleted a lot over the
years but now it's been a while yeah I
got I got I got a guy that I paid to
bring my account back but eventually
they they disappear yeah so that that's
the one that everybody follows that
everybody complains about but they love
to follow because it's the most
controversial yeah uh that's the uh the
Miami period mango 1.0 yeah the other
one is Miami period mango period Cali uh
that's the other that's the backup to
the to the fuckera account yeah now
professional accounts where you don't
see no memes no personal [ __ ] no cursing
yeah is Miami period mango uh period ca
for either California or cannabis uh
that's the actual official um Instagram
page for for the facility and then
there's Miami uh I mean there's
mango
tech. store that's the the store's um
right Instagram page and uh we put post
controllers and and there's that's
another professional page and there's
some people that say that there's not
professional you're looking at my blog
page you know it's um it's supposed to
be me what what I'm about you know I I
say it like it is yeah you have fun with
it too and yeah I mean I think that's
part of the beauty of it is you have a
lot you could tell if if you actually
follow it you could tell that you have
fun with it you know what I mean it's
part of you it's it's a very big
expression of yourself I'm addicted I
need to go to to Instagram Anonymous
well dude thank you so much for coming
on the show today it's been a blast
awesome thank you for having me yeah
I'll I'll come do another tour in three
months and see where you're at I'm
excited com by in three months hopefully
we have some inner canopy Lighting in
there and then you can see the the whole
can here from top to bottom you know
being big buds awesome sick well have a
good one thank you very much sure that's
a pressure good
[Music]
stuff