foreign
[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James loud
podcast today my special guest is Heston
Alcorn from Oregon how you doing Heston
very well thank you for having me so he
actually invited himself on my show it
works try it out yeah it's great because
uh you are a home grower you you're very
passionate about cannabis so you said
you wanted to be on my show yeah and I
was like well let me look at this guy
and I looked at you're super passionate
I haven't had really any home Growers
and I feel like the majority of people
that watch my show
are home Growers or yeah very passionate
people about cannabis and you know I
feel like you're super passionate just
from looking at your page and talking to
you you know it's I'm glad to have you
here yeah no I appreciate it I've been
uh been around it for a while and trying
to you know find my place in the
Cannabis scene these days and that's
kind of leaning towards the educational
realm and home Growers uh very a big
population of Home Growers I mean every
year there's new States coming online so
the amount of Home growers in the
country grows every day every week and
people have you know much more access to
information than I did you we did when
we first started growing you know in the
90s uh I was afraid to go to the local
library to look you know botany books
because you're afraid the sheriff's
department are coming and check the card
catalog or something silly so now with
the amount of information out there and
people have access to it all it's kind
of unfiltered uh Avalanche and people
make these big purchases and uneducated
decisions and I feel like I uh took a
shot to uh we moved our family out to
Oregon to try to do the OLCC commercial
production and got our license in just
before the moratorium got caught up in
that whole nonsense for a year and a
half or so we ended up having to sell
our farm and uh kind of gave up back and
forth Oklahoma legalized I'm from
Oklahoma originally so we took a couple
of trips back and uh toward this idea of
moving back and and partnering in on a
couple of grows and it was Oregon is way
better for cultivation than Oklahoma man
that was talking about wild west that's
uh finally starting to settle down a bit
out there but it was kind of chaos and
uh and yeah you know um got family wife
and kids and kind of happy in my
situation and finding that people are
hungry for information and want to want
to grow their own and I think there's a
big crowd of people that are uh you know
really passionate as well about it and
that's uh like I said I appreciate that
and I feel very strongly and I have very
opinionated sometimes about certain
aspects of the of the process but at the
end of the day I think I just want to
share my my passion and and be able to
let someone that's never grown a plant
before
have that experience of taking a seed
harvesting it and then having a really
nice product that they did themselves
it's a very satisfying experience very
rewarding so yeah and it's an experience
I think those are those are great life
experiences to see something that starts
as a seed and then finishes as a usable
product that you can smoke or there's
other uses as well you know you can put
it in an edible you can do so many
different things with it definitely very
versatile yeah you can juice it you can
make ropes with it you know it's like
the sky is the limit and I think it's
just a really amazing thing that slowly
but surely as
we get more technology we start losing
these things like Butchery as a dying
art too you don't see real butchers very
often like you used to every town used
to have a butcher every place had a had
actual butchers that would break down
cattle but a lot of you know I mean I
would say that all grocery stores for
the most part are just yeah not all but
the majority of them have have actual
just packaged meat yeah and it's cows go
on one end of a building and packages
come out the other and into a truck and
shipped out yeah The Butchers cut out of
that process now well yeah and even
vegetables so many people used to grow
their own vegetables or grow some of
their own vegetables and now most people
I would say more than 90 just by produce
from the grocery definitely so and I
think there's some real enjoyment that
you can get and you can learn a lot
about nature and you can learn a lot
about failing and and learning from your
mistakes I think those are important
valuable life lessons and you can get so
many different things about cultivation
yeah spot on you said it right there
it's just like the the physical the
reward of being in the garden moving
your body interacting with plants
learning from your mistakes and people
you know in the age of social media
pretend like they're perfect and only
put their best face online and you you
know assume that they don't make the
mistakes and it's like they've made
those mistakes for years and years and
learned from them to be able to get to
the point to show you these you know
pretty pictures right but I think it's
also it's very important to acknowledge
your mistakes and you know be humble and
learn from your mistakes and be honest
about uh be honest to yourself oh yeah
be honest be honest to yourself and you
know that's the best way and I think you
don't get good at something without
making mistakes
you don't it's just not how life works
you know and I think you can be
naturally gifted and have a natural
green thumb and get good results right
from the beginning but you can also be
someone who's passionate but stubborn
and they don't give up and learn how to
be a really good grower you know if
you're passionate about it just because
you don't get it right the first time
that doesn't mean you shouldn't try and
try and try again until you get it
perfect if you love it yeah and I see
you see you see that a lot unfortunately
people you know spend a couple Grand on
a tent and it's for sale in six months
because they bombed their first run it's
like you put put that in your notebook
what did you do wrong learn from that
like where how do you build on that
don't just one and done and quit and
give up you know well yeah and I see
what happens a lot of times is you know
people they get into it and they're like
they want to build a six lighter right
out the gate and then spend all this
money and invest all this energy into
something they don't really know about
and the best thing they could have done
is probably just got one light and put
it in a room or in a closet and
experimented with one or two or five
plants instead of putting the room with
36 plants because it's so much different
and these scale yeah as far as people
don't think of 36 plants is a big scale
but compared to one plant or two plant
it's significant yeah it's yeah
exponentially and it takes all you know
for each one of those plants to properly
care for it you know and there's
automated watering and there's some cool
stuff but like I think people should
learn how to water by hand I think I
would never do large scale by hand and
I've been a big proponent a proponent of
automatic watering at scale
but I don't think that there's anything
wrong with waking up in the morning and
going Watering your plants in your
backyard I've really got enjoyment over
over the period of my life from the
plants where I've watered you know right
when the sun's coming up I'll go hit my
plants with water or whatever and I feel
like you're there's a lot to be learned
from that too definitely 100 and not
only that it's like the more you're
interacting with your plants on a daily
basis you're going to catch issues
before they become problems right you
know if you've got a your automatic
watering and you pop into the tent once
a week to check the reservoir we could
have spider mites that were in there you
know the last time and now they're well
established in a problem instead of
being in there every day and seeing some
pest damage or pest pressure and being
able to react immediately totally
yeah you know I think being able to
recognize problems early is great and
also one of the beauties of automated
watering that a lot of people don't
realize is that it allows you to spend
more time with your plants so you can
find those problems before they become
issues definitely yeah I've been become
a huge fan of of the automated watering
at least in partial replacement of hand
watering because uh just you know in my
my my four by eight I was having issues
with uh pH fluctuations because I was
getting dry pockets and just the volume
of soil uh you know going from 20 or 30
gallon bags to 430 gallons of soil uh
just that that change was enough to
throw a wrench in the system and then
adding the automated water to keep the
soil moisture to more consistent level
changed changed overnight you know
improved things overnight so let's talk
a little bit about how you grow because
I feel like that's important part of the
story too you do no-till living soil I
do yeah I and that's taken me a long
time to get to this point you know I
might we started uh just kind of shotgun
planting seeds back in the river bottoms
and late 90s in Oklahoma and it was you
know gorilla style go out and plant them
come back in October maybe one of 20
plants would survive and like going from
that hands off to now every day Hands-On
and being involved as you want and kind
of ran through the the nutrients I did
you know you know start off in Miracle
Grow and Botanicare and emerald Harvest
and you know ran through the Gambit and
then that kind of started uh getting
into the organic side I smoked some
organic flour you know years ago and and
kind of did a side by side and was
really intrigued by just the process and
then kind of started down that road and
it's led me to the no-till and trying to
be uh close the loop as much as possible
in in my personal growth so that led to
some Modern natural farming uh methods
and composting is huge I've been by
little bug friends or do a bunch of the
work and really trying to dive into the
soil biology and just the the life that
exists under that multi-layer and that's
where all the magic happens so I really
really enjoy the process
um you know get that kind of the mad
scientist in the lab with all the
ferments and you're doing a lot of those
inputs making that stuff yourself
another another something that's very
rewarding is that your you know you're
hand crafting a lot of your inputs
yourself so that's another level of
satisfaction that you coming back to
yourself right and uh any I I enjoy the
process it does you know takes a little
longer that's always the thing that
people come at me with you know the
organic soil and yeah hydro's faster I'm
not going to argue against that it is
but it's it's you know apples and
oranges situation it is it's very apples
and oranges that's a great way to put it
so you know it has it's a tool I think
there's a lot of people that want to
have you know this black and white
you know definitive this is the best
this is the best you got to do it this
way or you're you know doing it wrong
it's like you know there's a thousand
different ways to grow and none of them
are wrong or incorrect or bad you know
there are tools that can be applied in
certain situations that they work best
in the situation right you know and if
you're uh depending on what your goals
your personal experience and preference
are is going to kind of lead you and
draw you more towards one style of
growing or another you know we've got a
buddy that's a plumber and he's not ever
going to quit growing hydroponically
because he's a plumber and he loves it
you know he gets going tinker and build
manifolds and do the pumps and uh sure
it's just like that's his that's his
deal it's so individual it is the whole
thing and there's so many different
things on every level whether it's
lighting or genetics and it's all
subjective to personal preference yeah
and I think that's what people don't
understand is and and it's it's all
subjective you know best is just like
what what the best is it's like saying a
Picasso is better than a Monet yeah and
really the sky's the limit but then you
start talking about organic
living soil like no-till living soil or
even just soil as opposed to Cocoa as
opposed to you know rock wool or
different substrates I think when you
start diving into that then you start
looking at things like effect right
that's the one big thing that stands out
the most for no-till living soil I think
you can get pretty good flavor out of
cocoa really good flavor uh yeah Ash
white good flavor Oil ring all that good
stuff and it's a great product it's a
great commercial product but then as you
start getting into some of the boutique
stuff the the thing that stands out the
most is
the effect of living soil smoke where I
feel like it has the best effect for me
and if you go side by side comparisons
which I've done many times I feel like
the effect on the living soil it has a
better effect and if you like smoking a
lot and you like the effect of it that's
important yeah and even without the
higher THC numbers a lot of the times I
I don't hit the I don't hit the high
numbers in in my living soil that I do
but I feel like all of the other
all the other cannabinoids that are
coming into play are are balancing that
out and making it that full that full
spectrum effect the Entourage effect
what kind of numbers are you hitting
roughly mid-20s you know low to mid 20s
with with the with just water and you
know not pushing anything not doing too
much supplemental feeding at all um you
know I I had a
so nitrogen deficiency not because there
was a lack of nitrogen in the soil but
you know when the Woody mulch starts to
break down the bacteria tie up the
nitrogen so I had to feed some fish
amino acids and fish hydrosylate off and
on to bump the nitrogen up to acceptable
levels but once the mulch breaks down
and starts cycling properly it's
basically water water only it really is
and you can you can add the beneficials
and do compost teas worm teas and add
stuff to it but and then that's another
conversation about diminishing returns
it's like well you have this living soil
this you know 430 gallons of soil that's
like a self-contained ecosystem and
really all the work that you've done for
the last few months six months a year
jump starting that to life is so you can
step back and really let it do its own
thing and only have to add water and
make sure that soil moisture stays in an
appropriate range so the nutrient cycle
and then it's all up to the plant you
know and that's the that's going to be
kind of the the heart of the class I'm
putting together here on uh I hate to
say it we call call it a master class
no-till master class and it's basically
geared towards people who want to
transition away from uh synthetic bottle
feeding even bottle feeding Organics but
transition from that to a more no-till
hands-off just don't give Master ger
certificates out at your master class I
was not I was not a fan of the name
Master Class I'm okay with but I feel
like the master girl it's just such a
generic thing you know I've seen it on
resumes when
I was going through those processes it's
like you know it just it tells a lot who
told you you were mad who gave you that
certificate it's just it's one of those
interesting things so
let's walk through your process for so
what do you do you do tests you send
your soil out for testing do you have a
microscope how are you doing tests and
then as far as identifying issues like
nitrogen deficiency how are you doing
that yep so uh by build you know mix my
own soil and uh send in for soil tests
after every Harvest so see if I need to
catch up on anything at dry amendments
and
um I don't I don't have a scope yet I'm
kind of playing with that the
microbiology scope there's a couple of
companies that offer testing kits as far
as uh you know what bacterial fungal
levels your soil is at and so do you
test in one zone multiple zones how do
you yeah multiple so in my four by eight
bed I'll take six samples basically six
different samples uh at all about the
same depth so uh well you know a six
inch core sample taking the entire core
and and two pounds of soil tested out so
it's pretty good average right you know
it gets a pretty good uh cross-section
of everything in the soil nice yeah and
it's you know since I mixed it myself I
know it's pretty pretty even mix it's
not going to have too many hot spots and
when I had amendments it's very
consistent and evenly spread so there
shouldn't be you know hot spots so you
build your soil from scratch yes some
people use build a soil some people use
vital as a starting point so you know
and then build on top of those soils but
those are those are great that's where I
started Coots mix you know that was my
kind of 101 and I don't think that you
should just dive right into it and make
your own recipe there's tried and true
recipes that are great for your first
bed build a small bed use someone else's
recipe don't try to reinvent the wheel
right off and then in your situation you
can decide after a harvester two like
okay well I'm going to bump this add
this change this more aeration more
compost and then start making those
decisions but yeah people come in and be
like well I'm going to add six extra
cups of blood meals a bump the nitrogen
it's like well you got horrible pH
issues you haven't you know nitrogen you
know clawed plants in the first two runs
because you just the soil is too hot and
there are definitely lots of there's
lots of room to play and adjust and make
your own recipe but just like with
anything else you you don't just assume
that you're going to understand soil
biology better than the people that have
been doing it for 30 years and come in
and totally do it differently you know
they're not set in stone and you know
the Coots mix has got a lot of of
controversy last few years but it was a
good starting point you know that it was
kind of the first
soil recipe that people could just grab
off the internet and then kind of start
on their own doing it and uh and before
it was a lot of trial and error a lot of
people
mixing their own batches and doing like
eight or ten batches next to each other
and trying to decide what what worked
better in their in their environment and
situation right so I do and that's like
uh yeah mixing the soil Source I try to
Source local inputs as much as possible
that's awesome I had when you have good
inputs you're up in Lincoln City I got I
got a nice pick in there yeah I got the
the coast is right there so I can
Harvest you know seaweed and do the kelp
Bowl kelp oyster shells and seawater for
minerals and you know the forest is
Bountiful uh harvesting as well for lots
of ferments and inputs uh horsetail and
I just filled up a barrel of horsetail
for silica for uh you know Nettles
blackberries I got a nice spread to
forage through so the blackberries are
popping this time of year they're out of
control and it's they're an invasive
species so as many as you can cut back
the better and that's what I've heard
yeah this time of year especially it's
great for uh for ferments or
putrification for jdam because you have
all different aspects of the plant you
got fresh growth immature flowers and
ripe fruit so you get a nice broad
spectrum fertilizer right there growing
Wildfire yeah yeah but this year now you
guys got to worry about fire danger so
I've heard like starting like you
probably don't on the coast it's not as
bad but it is not as bad and we we moved
to Lincoln City seven coming out eight
years ago now and the Wildfire was not
you know we're in the temperate
rainforest on the coast we don't have to
worry about wildfires and we almost lost
our home two years ago uh a fire we
burned the well house and uh had some
smoke damage but our neighbors up the
hill you know a few hundred yards away
was the fire line basically and some of
our neighbors were not so lucky still
recovering and it's definitely something
that everyone's having to have a
conversation about unfortunately now so
we have our fire plan and uh well you
were there recently it's uh one Road in
one road out it's right it's not a great
place to have to evacuate from yeah for
sure
yeah it's a trip you know and then even
Hawaii there we had one of the worst in
history yeah In Our Lifetime yeah that's
that's rough yeah and then I was
wondering about my trip down here this
was uh when the shower air but it was
tropical storm threats and oh yeah
hurricane possibilities yeah so driving
from Oregon the other day yesterday
there was Smoke in Oregon I was driving
through Eugene it looked apocalyptic
where you keep the bright red Sun and
you can't see more than like 200 300
feet like clear and it's all just worse
than La yeah surprisingly yeah we call
that the the PTSD orange now that Smoky
orange tent and you're just in in that
well and even with the recycling air on
your car where it's recirculating oh
yeah I could still smell it so let's
keep it up it's no good but then we get
into California and it's torrential
downpour and you know the roads are
greasy because we haven't had any rain
so you know you don't want to drive too
fast on those
and uh yeah there was flooding in La
they had an earthquake
pretty wild pretty wild times man so
let's talk about autoflowers because you
want an Autoflower cup a while back uh
2021 yeah yeah which is great and you
know I love having people on the show
talking about autoflowers because I
think autoflowers are amazing and uh so
did you grow in soil or tell us the
story yeah no so it was uh kind of
serendipitous actually I had got and
ordered a pack of photo period seeds and
got a couple packs of autoflowers as
freebies and the last time I had grown
an Autoflower was back in the like the
low rider era so I wasn't like super
impressed with the low rider and I hated
Autoflower too much annoyed but but yeah
so times have changed yeah for sure so
that was a great great experience you
know I had a you know nice big plan
beautiful flower uh smoked great chunky
butts big chunky buds it was really nice
but it was like I said it was kind of an
offhanded uh freebie and it turned out
beautifully and then it's like I just
had joined uh Instagram at that point in
my life and so there was a come across
the Autoflower cup up in Washington
state I was like man I was into
autoflowers I was kind of you know
trying to find my entry back into the
world of cannabis and thought you know
same autoflowers are great they've got a
very uh a big application I think here
in the near future they're they're up
and coming yeah and I could kind of see
that then and wanted to be involved in
the community and meet some people so I
was like I'll enter this cup uh and and
you know no expectations really of
winning it so it was the first
Autoflower I had grown since a low rider
so you know eight years or so
um and it entered a couple two or three
weeks before the cup and was excited to
go and meet people and it just kind of
worked out and I I won the for the
flower and got to meet some just amazing
people and had a great experience and
been like uh it was kind of my my
welcome back into the world of cannabis
I love Washington I love Washington
State I was born in Oregon I was born in
Portland oh nice but uh I love
Washington State I love Seattle I have
good friends people I consider family up
there a lot of them yeah I love watches
gorgeous it was out on the the canal uh
and just picturesque gorgeous setting
yeah yeah I found some interesting
flower at some of the dispensaries up
there too and nice you know I I was
looking for the Jaeger oh yeah so Jaeger
flower just to smoke so yeah I'm it's a
good train it is yeah
good variety and very popular in Oregon
it's popular more popular in Oregon the
other thing I was looking
still looking for the Trinity my buddy
Bob from Eugene I used to call him
Eugene Bobby did the he went to Canvas
cups and brought some Trinity one time
we had it back in the day
and that's a good one the the four-way
the Trinity the snow and the corn I
think there was one other one but we got
all those the dog we got we got those
from Eugene nice yeah all good stuff
about yeah Oregon's always had good bud
yeah that's yeah it was uh you know
Northern California Emerald Triangle
Oregon Southern Oregon there's best
growing conditions in the world yeah so
that was one of the we were we were
living out in Rhode Island at the time
and uh talking about where we were going
to move when my wife finished her
residency and I talked her into Oregon
and that was you know the the weather
the climate she found a job that she
liked and kind of all the stars aligned
and the the wreck Market was open at
that point so that was I was gonna go
and grow for OLCC yeah and uh I love the
place yeah I love Lincoln City it's
definitely become our home for sure it's
chill it's chill for sure it's got a
nice vibe to it yeah it's a little Beach
town it's a little Beach town There's
the like the hippie side which I like
tie-dye they have good they have a good
tie-dye yeah shout out to the people
with
you know so but but yeah a lot of fun
and I think there's really good food
there there's diversity yeah it's a nice
it's a nice mix there was uh you know 20
years ago because of the mild climate it
was a big draw for retirees and then
that kind of a
whole Market kind of came up around that
but now it's kind of the people moving
from Portland and Salem out of the
Cities down there brought some uh some
nice amenities to to town where it's
usually closed down at seven o'clock I
don't know if it was okay it was like
seven o'clock lights out so there's only
Town well when we took the Uber because
I didn't want you know if we have some
wine or whatever I like wine we went we
went to the Bay house at South Shan
we're going there for dinner and I was
gonna have some wine so I don't drink
and drive that's my one big thing and I
don't drink very much anyway so I
definitely don't drink and drive so I
was like well they got Uber so we got an
Uber it took like 10 minutes for them to
get there that's not a big deal but we
get in the Uber and the guy's like we
you know there's only two Uber drivers
in the whole Lincoln City yeah
turns out there's actually three because
we got picked up by the third one but it
was only his second pickup and drop off
we just got Uber yeah just brand new to
Lincoln City yeah it's like a year old
or something like that yeah despite the
taxi love you taxi 101 if you need a
ride sometime but yeah the taxi it would
be like an hour after you called they'd
show up with four other people in the
car and be like we got to make five
stops before we drop you off right
that's great it's like come on over when
are you gonna get here yeah well so as
far as Autoflower advice if somebody's
gonna grow Autoflower for the first time
because I feel like there's a lot of
skeptical people that are like oh
Autoflower sucks
I you know I think the autofire are
special and it's Unique and I think it
maybe not for everybody but like for the
people that are interested in growing on
a flower it finishes from seed 70 days
80 Days 90 days depending on the the
variety yeah uh so there is that beauty
where it's predictable and when you're
gonna Harvest uh what advice or tips do
you have for people that are interested
in getting into autoflowers man I think
the biggest thing for autoflowers is
less is more like people want to like
drown them and feed them and burn them
up in that first two weeks and the the
first you know three weeks of an
autoflowers
super critical it's the most important
part I think for the first three weeks
because if you [__] up in the first
three weeks you're not going to get a
big plan that's the one you know and I
think that is the biggest issue that
people have is in that first three weeks
they just they're what they're doing too
much yeah you know they don't understand
Autoflower is very light feeder light
Drinker it's easy and they have a small
root Zone compared to a photo period
plant of the same size definitely yeah
so I think right less is more and I also
think everyone should grow an Autoflower
yeah it's an awesome if you've only
grown photos if you like myself and you
know had a bad experience years ago with
an Autoflower they've come so far you
know I think everyone should try it out
because like you say you plant a seed in
you know 80 to 90 days later it's
harvest and I've just vegged for 90 days
you know what I mean in my photo period
so it's a nice turnaround and I think
that once people start to see the
versatility and the utility and it's
like I have primarily grown from seed
the last few years so I'll start my
photo period seeds and I'll start Auto
flower seeds along with them and you
know two and a half months later when my
photos are ready to go into flower the
our the autoflowers are ready to harvest
yeah so you get that you know the little
bumper crop in between for a transition
where you would otherwise yeah the
bumper crop is cool yeah for sure so
even if you're not like you said if
you're not getting pound plants yeah
it's like it's it's taking up extra
space in the bedroom and you're getting
a harvest that you wouldn't have had
flour you can still get four ounce
plants oh it's not like you're getting
minimal efforts yeah I mean a lot of
people don't get four I had friends that
I got better yield from my Autoflower
plants than they do from their photo
period oh yeah you know what I mean so
yeah I mean four ounces is on a plant
indoor is pretty good and four ounces
outside that's fantastic and I mean I
think that's the higher end but uh you
know I've seen some some plants on the
internet where I'm like that's got to be
at least 200 grams yeah like close to
those yeah the auto pots I think is the
one the biggest ones I've seen the
self-watering the bottom uh sub
irrigated planner set up right against
the big Auto flowers and those things
for sure bigger isn't always better it
doesn't mean it's gonna you know smoke
the same as a smaller plant but you know
each to their own it's still a fun plant
to grow definitely definitely do you so
side note do you think that plant size
affects the The Taste and flavor and
quality because I've kind of been on
that I do yeah I do I think having
smaller buds as opposed to having
monster colas
uh is beneficial you know but but I also
love looking at big huge colas and
arm-sized colas but as far as like
concentration of cannabinoids and
terpenes I think you're going to get
from smaller colas but it's also so
specific to the cultivar and and you
know the genetics a lot of that has to
do with genetics is some plants are
meant to be big and some plants are
forced to be big you know people force
them to try to get them big and you
don't get the same benefit Blue Dream
Sour Diesel those are naturally just big
plants but like sour diesel for instance
it's more Airy so you're not gonna get
you know Blue Dream the bigger it gets
it's it gets pretty dense and you can
get some serious botrytus in there too
um whereas Sour Diesel I feel like it's
more Airy so it lets water in and water
out some of those equatorials the reason
they're like that is so that they can
allow humidity in and humidity to escape
from the plant yeah it's 98 98 humidity
and rains for two hours every day you
gotta have some sort of moisture we're
there for a reason you know yes sir yeah
I just having a conversation a couple
weeks ago about
like you said a 10 pound plant yeah
gorgeous it's a thing of beauty but I
feel like too like a pound plant tastes
better than that 10 pound plant if
they're yeah or whatever side by side I
feel like
the plant struggles to produce 10 pounds
worth of cannabinoids where it can focus
some more of its energy on a smaller
plant and and be more efficient in that
production and it's not but I think even
within the zones of a plant you can take
a Bud from the top of the plant under
strong concentrated lights and then you
can take a side branch and you could
smoke I mean you'll have even if you
smell them the one on the side is going
to smell stronger typically than the one
on the top that's exposed to all the
light it's not always the case but I
think a lot of times like you'll get
that difference and it translates into
the smoke too yeah no it's 100 of the
last the the best smelling bot I had in
my last run was like Up Under The Canopy
and shade like a little Airy little golf
ball smelt fan just fantastic yeah so
when you see guys smelling the colas on
Instagram a lot of I mean if you get the
experience guys they're going to be
selling the side but this side colas so
it's just and that's just you know
that's a personal preference thing but I
notice you get way more Terps smelling
the sides yeah for sure exactly like the
proximity to the light and the intensity
and the heat up there a little bit so
what kind of genetics are you working
with up there
um man I've been uh I've been all over
the place uh I'm kind of going back to
play with some land race stuff right now
um like uh talking about just trying to
get ahead a little bit and I think you
know in Oregon especially man we've
there's a few strains that just got so
hyped and played out so fast and
everybody's tired of the same thing
no I'm not Jaeger yeah that's like a lot
of the cookies crosses and stuff and
then yeah sure I mean that's all we
talked about the funneling kind of how
everything kind of goes towards one
thing because people get so excited and
that's all the hype yeah and they call
it exotic but yet that's all everybody
has yeah and everyone demands yeah it's
not rare and then that's the same things
like that when I think exotic I think of
that like 16 to 18 week flowering uh
plant that nobody has but
that's exotic you know so trying to
capture some of the qualities from those
super long flowering plants cross it
back to something that's been worked
better shorter flowering period and kind
of having the Best of Both Worlds or at
least when you're doing some breeding
too uh a little bit see production so
breeding may be a stretch I'm trying to
educate myself enough to to start down
that way we're making seeds I am making
seeds yeah so you're making seeds yeah
so you're a seed producer a seed
producer baby yeah yeah whatever making
seeds I think that's great and I think
everybody should do it you know being a
Sega I just
I think everybody should have that
experience so they understand the
difficulties of it you know it's like we
talk about
how to select for these certain things
and then how do you find out
what traits get passed on and really
from experience from growing out the
progeny you really see what gets passed
on by mother and father you know donor
or receiver however you want to put that
but like that's that's the interesting
fun stuff for me is because you get
these recessive traits that sometimes
they don't pass on to the progeny you
get some gas and you breed it and none
of them have the kind of gas that you're
looking for yeah
I'm fascinated by the process and and
love seeing like you said the
what are you going to get like what's
the seed gonna do if there's not much
better than popping new seeds I love
that that just the anticipation you know
a couple months and you start to see
flower set and get some Aroma coming off
of it and right you're disappointed
because it doesn't have that gas or it's
like oh man this is exactly what I was
hoping or it looks amazing in the plant
then you go to smoke it and you're like
oh man it doesn't translate into the
smoke yeah so it's just such a myriad of
possibilities in that little tiny seed
so right and I I want to
we're talking about I was like I have a
plan maybe one day in three years I'll
be comfortable to like to sell a seed
but I have I have I have you know a goal
I have a plan to get to where I want to
be and then it's like you go online and
everybody's a breeder you know you can
throw a rock and hit 100 breeders on on
social media anybody can make seeds you
can call yourself a breeder online
whatever you want but like anybody can
make seeds it's the Fino hunting that is
the hard part selecting new you know
funeral hunting is only used in cannabis
like yeah we're doing selections for
phenotypical expressions or you're
selecting for genotypes but
the thing is is like that's where the
magic comes in and you have to be able
to grow the plant good enough for it to
express to be able discern between the
different plant expressions so you're
looking at different phenotypical
expressions and if you grow shitty
they're all going to look very much the
same and even when you smoke them
they're all probably going to taste the
same and not that great but the second
you start becoming good at cultivating
enough to that's how you you're good at
cultivating too when you're popping
seeds and this one's like this and this
one's like that and this one it's
completely different or all these are
the same and these are all pretty good
but this one smokes way better yeah you
know it's it's really so cultivation is
always the starting point for being a
good breeder for being a breeder that's
making good seeds even and I think
that's another benefit for the the
living soil is you're not
you're not feeding the plant you're not
steering it with your you know your
nutrient selection it's you put it in
this this healthy environment and it's
going to do its own thing and it's going
to communicate to the soil what it needs
when it needs it and it's going to
express itself kind of differently I
think that it would in uh synthetic
nutrients it's allowed to to show what
it would do you know in the wild and
right that's when you see like you see
the really different expressions in the
plant in the organic in the organic
environment where they're allowed to to
do their own thing yeah what do you see
of the future for Oregon I think they've
gone all around with allowing everybody
to get a license and then people
struggling yeah so Oregon
um we we
it was two and a half years ago put in
we got our license right before the
moratorium they stopped taking
applications for a new license yeah uh
we had a 33 Acre Farm up in Tillamook
County and we're planning on you know my
sister moved up from Texas my brother
moved up from Arkansas we're gonna do
bootstrap it up and and kind of slow
build out yeah
and the OLCC made the rules such that uh
previously it was like your caseworker
basically for the OLCC calls you was
like hey you ready for a facility
inspection come by make a list of things
you need to fix call me when it's done
come back in two months when you get get
all the problems resolved the shifted
from that to your caseworker calls you
okay 30 days from now we're coming for a
site inspection it's pass or fail so for
us to have been able to do that we would
have had to build out a facility not
knowing if or when we would get
inspected for a license so you know
talking a half a million dollars
invested in a facility out there
not knowing if it would be eligible for
a license ever and we got we ended up
having to sell the place and uh it was a
year and a half after we put our license
application in that they contacted us to
see if we were ready for our uh
inspection and by that point we'd moved
on
so I think that they early on uh with
the big canopies and stuff they made it
very easy for whoever wanted one to have
a license and the overproduction kind of
changed the direction of that and now
it's uh it's a struggle and with the
testing laws and regulation changes it
seems like they're putting pressure on
the smaller farms and the organic
Growers uh I don't know if you saw the
the aspergillus testing that they just
implemented no in a couple within the
last couple of months so you know no no
studies no data no cases to you know to
imp to no reason to implement this
testing law other than these companies
coming into the state and lobbying for
the laws to be changed because you know
this remediation company comes in and
has a solution but no problem so they
changed the law where now everybody's
failing for aspergillus and now what
pretty much everywhere it's everywhere
it's on everything it's a it's on
everything and it's everywhere and it's
never caused an issue uh like I said
there's seven minutes right here yeah
exactly 100 and it's not causing any
health issues and has never been
documented you know right smoking
cannabis causing any health issues but
because this company came in and lobbied
for the rule to change that because they
had the solution to the problem that
they created basically so
I don't know yeah
no it's just like and that's kind of the
what I've you know up and down and when
Oklahoma went online we're from
originally from Oklahoma so I had uh
friends and family building out and I
flew back and forth a couple of times
early on in Oklahoma
and uh
you know that kind of burnt me out again
and I just kind of stepped back away
from it and it's just such a a rat race
and like it's a Cutthroat deal in the
commercial I mean I I can't speak on it
as well as you probably know person
personally firsthand but whenever I
first started growing it was like this
super close-knit group of people it was
like a community right yeah it was it
was very uh hush-hush it was a very
close-knit group of friends and family
that did this illegal thing together
because you couldn't talk about it and
post pictures on it and now it's like
the industry right it shifted from the
community to the industry and now
understandably so because it's a
multi-billion Dollar business yeah
people aren't friendly to each other on
the commercial side of things and you
know yeah I agree to a degree and I
think that we need some more of that the
passionate people and you just stick
together and quit trying to bash each
other and troll each other online it's
silly because we're in this together and
the more of us that are still here doing
it the better as far as like you want to
see quality cannabis don't get rid of
the little guys and
you know we should all be joining forces
and not
separating we should we should get
together I think that's the big thing
100 and I I'm starting uh trying to
start a non-profit up to hire a lobbyist
on the national level to promote and go
to bat for home Growers because we we
have nobody and like you said and you go
online and it's it's horrible uh social
media go on and everybody just talks
constantly talking bad about other
people's grow right and honestly like
the last three four years I haven't seen
a picture of a bad looking Bud online
now the cameras are so good you see
every little Mite every little bit of
powdery mildew all those things if you
look at pictures you know so like people
are really aware of it but then you know
we've got filters for all the cameras
too it seems like yeah yeah but you have
that you have that everybody's bashing
each other and it's like especially like
it's it's especially absurd in the home
grower like we're not competing against
each other like we should be banding
together to ensure that we have the
rights to continue growing at home in
the future yeah absolutely I think that
is kind of where my energy and focus is
going in like now moving forward is to
provide a community instead of an
industry provide that Community for home
Growers to come together and and all
band together to fight for our rights as
home Growers and ensure that we're able
to continue doing that in the future
right ten years ago everybody's like oh
man that's so awesome you're doing such
great like kind of see to you know
sharing information about each other
back and yeah it's just that social
media toxicity where you gotta be better
than everyone or you know right whatever
uh ego you need a stroke to yeah
ego is just yeah the ego needs to go
with a lot of people and they don't even
know it now that I'm older I recognize
it even more you know in my 20s I had
way bigger of an ego and I thought it
was way cooler than I was realize I'm
not that cool I'm just a dude
but uh I think as you get older as you
start losing friends as you start
experiencing life more I mean I think
that years go by faster for one thing so
as you're alive longer you it's more
relative I talked about data points all
the time living life is the best way to
collect data points because you're going
through life and the more data points
you have the more you understand things
in living life and going through life
you really start picking up those
experiences and seeing what's real and
what's not real what really matters and
what really doesn't matter
you know are you really passionate about
quality are you really best passionate
about quantity yeah those kind of things
and without home Growers though there's
not going to be the same level of
quality because I feel like those guys
are the passionate ones the you know
they're the majority of the people that
watch my show too I think and uh you
know super passionate people we get
people that are in the industry too but
the home Growers like that's something
special it is and it is so just uh
rejuvenating like uh seeing somebody
grow for the first time legally like
there's there's so like so much joy and
passion coming out and I like said I've
been doing it for a while and I lose
some of that childlike wonder and I
gotta like it's nice to to see somebody
so excited about it and it kind of
rekindles that fire in me uh that
there's still people out there that are
doing it for the first time and it's
like this is all new and they want to
they want to soak up all the knowledge
they can and do it as to the best of
their ability and I think that's just
fantastic because you get so cynical and
I've been I've been cut uh backstabbed a
couple times on deals and you get you
lose faith in humanity and you just It's
a Grind and you're growing is becomes a
chore and you got to remember this is
like
this is still new for some people and
they're still they're still got that the
passion and fire to get out and oh
that's the best yeah in the beginning
that passion in that drive and it's like
that's one of the reasons you're on the
show because I saw the passion you're
like you got the real [__] passion
for the the plant
and and I appreciate that and I feel
like and it gets uh overlooked a lot of
times but people that have been around
it a while can can appreciate it I I
thank you for having me again it's
awesome yeah I know it's a lot of fun
and it's like it's all about the
diversity on the show and being able to
see different perspectives and to be
able to capture all this stuff on film
great stories and you know it's like
you're in the industry at this point but
five or ten years it's going to be great
to look back and see these conversations
that we had and see where the industry
ended up because it's definitely not
going to be in the same place the one
thing for sure is
it's not going to be in the same spot
you know it's like we evolve and we
change and no matter what the only thing
constant really is change definitely
well yeah it's scary 10 years uh Federal
legalization and it's scary beautiful at
the same time I don't want to see people
going to prison for cannabis I don't
think that people belong in prison for
for a plant no you know and I think that
we've come a long ways but we still got
a long ways to go I saw this coming over
20 years ago I saw legalization
happening in my lifetime I had no idea
it was going to look like this I had no
idea I'd be sitting here talking to you
but I knew that it was gonna happen in
my lifetime and it's still not fully
happen though we're still not all the
way there we're not at the Finish Line
no no and that's the thing is he's like
gotta remember this is like an industry
that's in infancy this is just starting
up and there's there's a lot of
directions that could go at this point
totally we could go back to no
legalization and totally Black Market we
could you know and then
everything in between yeah my I just I
tell people I might I'd like to be able
to sell 15 pounds a year farmers markets
a couple Zips online here legally
illegally you know that's where I would
like to see it Go and and be able to
have the farmer's market I agree I would
love the vertical integration model and
the terroir for the guys we I talked
about this on my last podcast too but
like terroir with the outdoor farmers
and it's vertically integrated so you go
to the farm you can smoke the weed that
they grew there if you go to the right
part of the year you can watch them
harvesting the plants definitely a set
of bed and breakfast everywhere whatever
they want to do but I feel like going
back to that Boutique model is is great
too I feel like that's another great
direction that the industry should be
going in I mean commercial cultivation
it's great there's nothing wrong with it
genetics on a scale or on a commercial
scale there's nothing wrong with that
but I also like the boutique aspect of
it I'm a big fan of uh micro Brews I
don't really drink beer anymore as much
but I do like the micro Brewery model
where there's all these micro breweries
all over Oregon you have for example
like there was more uh microbreweries
there than anywhere else per capita in
the world and I think I like that
analogy I think that's something that
people can really relate to wrap their
heads around you know it's like there's
always going to be the the market for
you know the cheap beer you get a big
case for 10 bucks and then there's going
to be the 500 bottle of scotch and
there's going to be the the market for
those well and I also look at it from
the perspective of someone that's young
that becomes very passionate about
smoking weed when they're 14 like I was
being able to acquire a billion dollar
company or 100 million dollar or even a
10 million dollar company that's a lot
further away than being able to open up
my own custom you know my own dispensary
or my own shop that's vertically
integrated where we grow the weed on
site and it's just you know a
mom-and-pop type business I think those
are going to keep the passion alive in
the industry and and it's great to be
able to see that you know because I
think it that's when the passion for a
lot of us it started was when we were
young you know for me it was 14 16
myself yeah yeah High Times magazines
back then I love I still have my High
Times magazines we couldn't find so
Tahlequah Oklahoma was the town I grew
up in there was one record shop in town
they didn't have any explicit lyric
albums there you had to have an 18 year
old come into the store and order it for
you yeah so super conservative religious
small rural Town Oklahoma we didn't have
high times at the gas station that was
not it was not an option right yeah so
it was like you go visit your cousin in
Tulsa and they have High Times magazine
it was like
yeah just seeing it and then uh kind of
joking around too so uh we had a lot of
you know brick like literal brick weed
in high school so uh somebody knew
somebody or had an older brother or
cousin uh they had something that wasn't
brick weed it was called Dro just
because we Associated hydroponic with
Hydro it was like that was good weed you
know so find some Dro and I was like 30
bucks a gram or something you know for a
nug of dro which was fine it was it was
worth it at that time and then that this
that that mentality seeing that bleed
over into the Oklahoma Medical Market I
talked to a couple of people and tried
to they they wanted me to come out and
help build out a hydroponic facility and
I was like well I think you should
really consider like soil organic soil
and they it was because of that Dro you
know that mentality from 20 years ago
the dro was good that's what they wanted
to grow yeah so they built their
Hydroponics system out and then six
months later two harvests later they
were tear it all out and go on organic
living soil just because the the demand
for it but kind of the holdovers from
the the before times when it was you
know illegal and the mentality of people
crossing over into the legal Market it's
like oh it's changed a lot and the thing
is is I think at one point anybody could
grow and make money and now like you
have to have the best quality if you
want to be successful in this industry
now you better strive for Perfection
because all the big companies they can
grow middle grade they can grow B plus a
minus maybe even a grade but if you
grow that a plus if you're that one
percent or better and that applies to
everything in life but I think
especially with flour and if you want to
be a cultivator you better be a badass
cultivator it just doesn't it doesn't
you know it doesn't make sense to grow
middle of the road stuff even in some of
these Emerging Markets you might get
away with it for a little bit but like
Montana you got skunk VA over in Montana
and that dude's crushing some badass
flower yeah
so and you know all over there's people
all over that are really good
cultivators and before where it used to
be you know and the part of the reason
it was illegal
but now with legalization and popularity
and awareness and also we have all these
tools yeah I know like I said you know
15 years ago you could nasty looking
flower was still going for a few grand a
unit and then no more it better be
pristine gorgeous check all the boxes
there was outdoor pounds going for a
hundred bucks last year it's 300 bucks
you know it's like and how do you make
money as an outdoor farmer when you used
to get a thousand bucks and now you get
a hundred bucks at best sometimes for
some of these people it's like
times have changed
yeah sometimes for the better sometimes
for the worse yeah like I said they're
changing not anything we can do to stop
it just try to anticipate what direction
it's going and find a find a way to
being able to Pivot you know have enough
sense in to make the right business
decisions to Pivot when necessary and
know when and which way to go and
sticking to your roots I think is good
too though being able to stick to the
roots like what you believe in not not
straying away from your beliefs yeah I
think and that's that's been huge for me
as well just like the not trying to to
jump to the next
trendy thing I understand people need to
play that game and have to and they do
their own thing and no judgment but I
felt like it was you know even even
though I had like you know a few hundred
people follow me on the social media and
it was like it didn't matter I was like
able to communicate with these people
and talk passionately about uh organic
soil and living soil and how to how to
kind of close the loop on your own
personal Garden right and then you know
uh very fortunate last couple years I've
kind of met some met the right people
made the right connections
um invited myself on awesome shows and
you know trying to trying to like I said
find my find my niche in the emerging
market and got my uh fluoropharm.com and
we're doing the the living soil class
and I think that's kind of I'm just
gonna embrace it and lean into that the
home home grower education and try to
fight for the home Growers place in the
world yeah that's great
I think that's awesome and I think you
know passion is going to take you a lot
of places it's just the way it goes and
everything I mean more passionate people
are about the better products the chefs
that they love food and everything about
food the best chefs definitely so but
yeah it's really interesting the whole
evolution of cannabis and where it's
going to go and the home Growers and the
home Growers aren't going to go away
I think uh you know maybe the the guys
doing it for money are going to go away
to a degree yeah but the people
passionate about growing stuff in their
house just like people making beer in
their house that that's people still do
that yeah definitely no and it's like uh
there's a lot of conversation about you
know hunger is getting pushed out
because the you know the the bigger
production facilities don't want that
competition they want to have the market
it's like well there are a huge amount
of people that aren't able to grow their
own don't want to grow their own they
just why they want to go to the
dispensary and pick up it's the vast
majority of them so like if everyone
that wanted to grow at their home did
it's not going to take money off the
plate in the long run for these
companies you know so I don't think
there's a need to there's not to
demonize the home Growers for any reason
it's not going to make any kind of
Denton anyone's portfolio
um and I think that it's it's important
like you said just for the the culture
the the quality and and sharing those
genetics and
uh the passion yeah is that it's people
are still passionate in the home growth
situation and they're
new and exciting and
trying to learn all the new stuff that
they haven't been able to do it's cool
too it's like I talked to a gentleman
last week who the last plant he grew was
you know in the early 90s uh in like
outdoor in the Ozark Mountains like way
gorilla so he's like this is
night and day difference like LED lights
indoors with oh LED control your LED
change the game and I hated LEDs in the
beginning but then once they dialed the
LEDs in their big time Game Changer I
think so I was I was always hid lamps
I'm two years into the LEDs now working
with uh Grand Master Level Up in Canada
and yeah I have no complaints there
uh my only issue with them is I keep
underestimating how intense and Powerful
the LEDs actually are yeah and yeah so I
had to kind of dial it back a bit
parameters yeah just just the learning
curve with something a new technology is
what it was but yields are definitely
bigger
VPD and led are the two big game
changers I think in the last
12 years that have increased yields
significantly yeah and going back to you
know people that have a bad experience
right off the bat because they treat it
like something else like I'm saying with
autoflowers it's like you come from HPS
and you run your room the exact same way
you did with LEDs the HBS it's like of
course your results are going to suffer
you're not getting the same weight you
were with your HPS it doesn't mean that
the lights are bad or that the
technology is bad it doesn't mean you're
a bad grower it means
you need to learn something new and you
just need to say I don't know I need
help I need to learn somebody there's a
learning curve to stuff that's all there
is to it and people are so proud and and
I appreciate that especially from a
grower that someone growing on scale
it's like you have to be very
confident in your ability right you
gotta you gotta feel like you're doing
the right thing and the the best thing
but it's also like with that knowledge
and experience comes the knowledge and
experience to know that you need help
and there's well you can't have to be
afraid to lose or make mistakes because
that's the best way you can't let your
ego tell you that you're gonna do it
right perfectly every time ego you just
you said it you mentioned it earlier I
think that's that's a huge thing and if
you can take the ego out of most
equations you're going to do a lot
better solve so many problems yeah and
not being afraid to fail in business in
life in general like take risks and
believe in yourself and believe that the
next time you do it even though you
[__] up you might you might even
completely fail and it's a learning
experience and you know
it's not a failure if you learn
something from it yeah right in life you
just really never know what's what and
what what things mean and if they're
good or bad until
you know until the future until
everything kind of unfolds yeah
hindsight it's always uh
always easier to see how it is from a
distance
no cheers thank you cheers so we've been
working on these for about six months
using different papers
different tips different flower grinds
like the flour mill got me on the
different flower gardens like so you
grind it thick you you know real real uh
small or you go of course it makes a
difference and somewhere in the middle
is what I like and then these organic
tips these are bamboo
um they're they're disposable but I feel
like they're natural they're pretty good
and then professional general or the
Instagram big shout out to him he helped
me with some of these and then I've been
working on them on my own different
papers I like the raw but I also like
rice papers uh you know we're not
releasing these on the market anytime
soon but it is something that's going to
be for sampling when we do our selection
process every time we get bags of these
and I prefer
I know what the plant looks like I know
what the plant smells like but what does
it taste like to you is this something
you want to taste or is this something
you don't like and it's really
interesting doing the blind selection
process or the Fino hunting blind where
it's like smoke this smoke this smoke
this give me some feedback yeah it's so
it's so subjective like you're saying
it's like you probably every person that
samples it has a different opinion or a
different experience they do and some
people like the effect really and I
don't think a lot of people realize like
they like the effect or the taste or
whatever they most people are just like
I like this or I don't like that but
what I like about this size is it
doesn't burn too hot is 3.5 grams in
here by the way so it's a big joint but
it doesn't burn too hot when it's rolled
this thick I tried
The Wider ones and those just burn a
little bit too hot you don't get the
full Terps but if you can provide
somebody with this then they get the
best experience possible
and really at the end of the day I want
people to have the same experience that
I have so being able to share my flower
or stuff I'm working on with them I want
them to have the same experience so they
can judge it kind of the same way I
would and then people that are
connoisseurs out there that already roll
joints when they roll it they're like oh
[__] that's a good one nice so yeah
yeah well done it's a fine looking
specimen there yeah they burn pretty
even uh you know you get some good stuff
with white ash and the oil ring around
it
you're looking good but what what
flowers this do you know yeah so this is
the zerio's
Skittles uh zerbert it's nice I like it
yeah yeah candy Terps and we got some
skittles-s ones and so I did a lot of
stuff with Skittles because I really
like the candy Terps yeah and it's
interesting seeing what it gets passed
on to like in other things structure
wise and the structures heavily tied to
the flavor profile
so if you want the stuff that's real
skiddly and you cross it to something
that's very different
the ones that are going to taste real
skiddly are the ones that are going to
be the most similar to the structure
nice so that do you start making calls
early on based on that structure then if
you're if you're just looking for that
candy no because I every once in a while
you get like some crazy like I don't I
don't pull I'm not pulling stuff that
smells amazing like if it smells like
Skittles and it grows like [__] I'm
still gonna grow it out because Skittles
looks like [__] pretty much when you
harvest it small like it's not the
nicest looking it's the most finicky
plant it looks good in the bag or
whatever but like
I think that it's also very difficult to
grow and so like it might take you a
couple rounds to actually grow it
properly so even if you're popping seeds
you should probably grow it out multiple
times if not for the sexual maturity
Factor just for the fact that you might
have to learn how to grow
those specific plants definitely you
know better so and then same thing with
pheno hunts when we're going through the
first time we might have a different one
the second time that we think is the
best and the third time typically by the
third time we we understand it and we we
have our selection and we're like that's
the one nice or those are the three that
we really like the best and we keep
those around you know out of
however many seeds were popping
and that's that's one thing it's like I
have very rarely run something
consecutively or multiple times or
enough to become intimately familiar
with it uh like I said he likes the
difference of the gross back in the day
we all used to grow the same thing over
and over and over and over 10 10 runs 20
runs and might only grow two cultivars
yeah but like what you do is you'll grow
the same thing for just a couple runs
and switch it up yeah yeah and like I
said I'd like to uh been primarily
growing from seed the last few years and
I just you know new seeds every round
you know starting something new every
two months or so and then
that's kind of I forgot I was talking to
you it's like do you call the early ones
and that's like something that kind of
uh we're forced to do as home Growers is
like I can't run a thousand plants and
keep a hundred keep a thousand cuttings
back to you know hold on to to make make
those selections after the flower has
been processed and smoked uh so I gotta
like start making some decisions early
on and and you know am I throwing away
some potential Keepers sure
do I have the option no I'm you know I
got a small small little basement grow
and a lot of people are confined
confined to the you know plant count you
know you get four or six plant count and
uh first and foremost I select for the
nose typically when I'm going through
the rooms no even the shitty structure
you know my partner Jason Hutto up in
Seattle we've done a lot of funeral
hunting or selections together he he
definitely has an eye for the way the
plant grows as opposed to yeah the nose
first and then but me I'm all about the
nose first and sometimes I'll get and I
can be off I could be wrong I've been
wrong before and and that's another
thing like translating into
from the smell on the plant to the smoke
in the joint so one thing smells amazing
and the other thing might the the other
plant might not smell as strong but then
when you go to smoke it it's like whoo
that's the one it tastes totally
different than it's totally different
than or it just tastes louder where
sometimes they smell really good and
then it just doesn't translate into the
smoke
so yeah that's always disappointing I
hate that I think you got the one the
winner and it just smells like I would
say that the majority of stuff in the
dispensaries does that for me I go to
look at it or you see the samples like
even in Oregon some of the stuff that I
checked out it's like
[__] it looks pretty [__] good and
you smell it it's like it smells pretty
good but then you smoke it and it's like
oh like
not necessarily cardboard chips all the
time but like lack of yeah lack of
flavor or the initial it tastes good and
then as you're burning it down you kind
of lose that yeah no I I agree and I
think that's kind of like a you know
byproduct of the commercialization
people are selecting for bag appeal or
high numbers and that's unfortunately
like so many people the nose is like the
last thing selected for when it's a lot
harder to select for the flavor than it
is for the look right oh look it's very
obvious and then the flavor and all
those things are still somewhat
subjective right where the look it's
like if it's frosted that's the one
that's it I want the Oreos yeah no it's
the Oreos looks freaking amazing it's
absolutely amazing but as far as the
smoke it's my least favorite thing
pretty much to smoke
um I'd rather have the worst Autoflower
typically yeah but but no honestly the
Oreos is like all these things you know
because I I don't I'm not a huge fan of
apple fritter Oreos purple punch but
they're all one step away from being
good yeah in one generation or one cross
you know it's like you could find
something good in there there's
definitely good genetics in there
there's definitely
things that desirable traits that can be
passed on so when's the next cup that
you're going to do
uh I missed the a bunch of stuff going
on this summer as far but the the class
together with Dr zymes I've got a couple
of other projects going and kind of
dropped the ball on the uh the Oregon
Growers Cup this year so uh next year
like probably a few months off but
they're probably hit a couple of next
year nice yeah yeah got some interesting
genetics for you to check out it might
be a little super excited a little care
package of stuff to try out and
so I think there'll be some winners in
there I got some unique yeah I try to
breed for Unique stuff with auto flowers
yet you want the least amount of
phenotypical variation for what I'm
doing if you're trying to grow a row
crop
you definitely want something that comes
out pretty even across the board
definitely
so yeah that's kind of like that's what
I was saying earlier I think that's kind
of one of the the applications I see in
the near future for autoflowers it's
like you see so you still see them you
see it popping up now and again but you
know 100 acres of row crop oh yeah it's
almost hands down it's the obvious
choice if you're going 100 200 300 acres
for extract it's just because they're so
consistent they're so predictable as
opposed to photo period and you got you
know Greenhouse is okay but Autoflower
you know is very easy
and it's grown like a row crop you grow
like a tomato
and you can pull a couple of harvests
without any infrastructure some places
like three harvesting you're maybe maybe
even four in some places but typically
like to be able to you know and the
yields are really incredible too so at
scale if you're talking about 1500
pounds is normal but some people just
crush it yeah it's not bad and like no
infrastructure for pulling tarp to light
depth too you know but even three
thousand pounds let's say you got three
thousand pounds you can do three pulls
up to 9 000 pounds out of an acre
that's pretty good you can't do that
with photo period
not really no no I've never seen it not
three yeah especially not not because
you're getting three three bumps a year
like that
yeah [__] baked
yeah so these Doogie lit but I feel like
this has a ceiling so as far as like we
talk about the effect
um I like effective this because it's
not like overly powerful in the sense
that I can smoke a big [__] joint of
it feel pretty good and it has a ceiling
whereas like you smoke some of these
equatorial land races or equatorial
crosses even
you know any of the sativa stuff these
hazes where they don't have a ceiling
you just keep smoking you get more high
and more high and sometimes you get more
height and then it creeps up when you
get even more high after that yeah yeah
I just uh had a bad experience with some
some hash last week the too much too
panicky kept going then didn't stop like
he said there was no ceiling it just
kept getting more and more like a dab
yeah just uh just hash I I did dab there
for a little while and I just man I
don't know I don't it just doesn't do it
for me you know I I like flour I like
good rosin dabs some good living
like the live live resin oh for sure I
just love the I like Flavor I chase
flavor I'm constantly looking for
something new flavor-wise no I do that's
my favorite thing is I guess it's got a
little two inch uh plate press uh but to
do to press flour and then do the rosin
and then just like drizzle it on a bowl
you know the same flour on it same idea
rest on a bowl yeah so that's my that's
my go-to for sure right yeah there's
something special about rosin
I like rosin I like the effects from it
too oh one more thing what about soil
outdoor versus living soil and or
what's what's your opinion there that's
a loaded question so it is
the sun is special right you know uh
indoor lighting has come a long way it's
great that you get I think I'm hooked up
with best company out there uh personal
experience anyway they it's the sun's
the sun you know and then you could take
plant you know cuttings from the same
plant plant them on opposite sides of
your property and have two different
expressions in those plants just because
of the soil chemistry in those two
different locations yeah so I think that
outside in the earth in Under the Sun is
is very special right yeah if if you're
able to do that I think you should take
advantage of it and I I I pretty much
committed to indoors uh uh because I
can't get stuff to finish if I pull tarp
or an Autoflower finish outside but full
term photos on the coast oh you saw how
cool it gets at night there in Lincoln
City it's like this time of year it's
down into the 40s and like 80 humidity
already so it's tough to get something
to finish Outdoors uh but I do I have a
few plants outside because it they're
special it's it's nice I love outdoor
plants in the Earth for sure they just
grow different and if you if you have
some place that you can really uh put
some some energy into the soil you can
do some some awesome stuff yeah in the
Earth yeah totally yeah I mean huge fan
of mixed light too yeah yep yeah
supplemental Lighting in a greenhouse I
think you get a little bit of sun Best
of Both Worlds Best of Both Worlds the
future cannabis I think a lot of the
stuff is top shelf you can go really top
shelf amazing sticky Bud yep you can do
that on every level though in all
reality I mean I think they're sticky
Bud that can be grown in
with every substrate for sure yeah yeah
like I said though it's uh Law changes
and emissions and the energy stuff
coming down to the pipeline like uh
mixed mixed lighting may be a realistic
thing in the near future as far as like
indoor commercial production especially
in the cities and pushing the CO2
emissions and I just read some
ridiculous uh that was one of the
arguments against home Growers is the
the CO2 the extra CO2 emissions you know
of course and it was like oh like
138 pounds of CO2 to grow a pound of
flour dried flour produced like 138
pounds of CO2 for well I don't know what
average they used or anything but then
like on the same the opposite side of
that same coin it's like an hour of a
private jet creates two tons of CO2
right and nobody's trying to stop those
but it's the home grower with the little
you know 200 watt light that we is like
the criminal and destroying the
environment which is you know yeah I
mean there's so many people that try to
manipulate data it's just ridiculous all
over and everything everything yeah yeah
so have you experienced cannabis any in
any other parts of the world or pretty
much just the U.S Mexico I've been able
to go to Europe that's definitely on the
on the list I'd love to go to Europe and
and have some traditional hash and go to
the you gotta go for Spanish yeah now
that you're talking about you're gonna
go for span of his March yeah and that's
the bring them bring the family
definitely yeah I mean I think Spain is
an amazing place the culture there is
really great and it's a big uh event
where everybody from around the world we
kind of get together I have my same
friends I've been friends with going to
dinner for the last you know on and off
the last 10 years more than that yeah
more more than 10 years and it's like in
just great people from oh yeah people
from Australia people from South America
people from South Africa we got the
Dutch guys over there the Spanish guys
but but my friends from all over some of
them I only see at that event that's
cool so yeah it's and it's great seeing
them and hanging out and seeing you know
what they're up to and talking about the
genetics and because genetics are kind
of popping different all over I mean I
think gelato is pretty much everywhere
it's a lot of crosses Thailand Thailand
crazy Thailand's like fully emerged now
and that's wild I that's that's wild
yeah I'm looking forward to going to
Thailand one of these days yeah
so I haven't been there yet well I think
Spain that's an easy sell my wife's been
uh trying to get us over there for years
now so I think that's it's so great to
even mentioned span of us but what a
coincidence we're here in March for
spanibus we might have to check it out
doggy a free pass so check it out yeah I
mean it's a lot of fun and the food is
great food in Spain is amazing the food
in Europe in general is really good but
especially Spain yeah it's definitely a
start a start there somewhere and train
around for a few weeks
on the internet you have a website you
have an Instagram tell us a little bit
about it yeah so fluorofarm.com is
coming up that's where my uh online my
living soil master class is all going to
be funneled through there on my
Instagram florofarm same same handle all
across all the socials and my YouTube
channel as well so trying to spend a
little more energy
um on the YouTube producing some media
content for this for the for the class
and YouTube as well so
I'll be more involved there than
Instagram I think it's just so
frustrating like censored constantly and
post removed and playing that social
media nonsense so I'm kind of kind of
burnt out on that end and try to focus
more on my my website and the YouTube
side of things yeah yeah we've really
been focused on the YouTube I mean
Instagram is still Instagram but we've
you know I really like YouTube doing the
videos and I think that's been a lot of
fun and I got a great team we got a
great team of people here so definitely
yeah you guys are awesome thanks for
having me during work unfortunately
but yeah it was great having you today
man I really look forward to seeing you
back here and uh doing this again
sometime and maybe hopefully seeing you
in Spain for span of this that'd be
great man count on it thank you I know
all your wife's friends that are
watching are going to tell your wife
about it oh yeah for sure definitely
well your wife's probably gonna watch
you better be watching it yeah she's
gonna watch this show and be like hey I
see what you did there yeah
it'll be too late I'll buy the tickets
before the show comes out thank you
again and have a great day I appreciate
it thanks for having me cheers
[Music]