[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James loud
podcast and today my special guests are
Dave and Brian from Crockett Family
Farms how you guys doing today great hey
thanks for having us on the show yeah
awesome man thank you James glad to be
here really appreciate you guys coming
on um so let's get into it you guys have
been uh making seeds together for a long
time and you've been making seeds for a
long time and you've been with your
father for quite some time as well yeah
about 11 years now when I turned 18
legally I started you know working but
as a kid I was always involved you know
holes and whatnot so fantastic all the
the young back breaking work yeah that's
what that's what you start out at
yeah totally yeah and that's the best
way is to I mean if you're in a kitchen
the best way to learn how to cook and
everything else is start at the bottom
as a dishwasher and learn your way up
and I think same thing with growing
being a water boy at some point in your
life is pretty important you know like
learning how to hand water I don't care
how much automation you have I think
there's something to be said for
learning how to hand water properly yeah
there's there's stuff that automation
yeah you can work with dryb backs and
all these other things but there's
something special about hand watering
definitely definitely and just
understanding you know um all the
positions all the way through the best
uh way to learn is to learn everything
yeah and have a real well-rounded
understanding of everything and like
especially when you get a scale like you
guys have a farm you need to know when
people don't show up or whatever you
need to know how to fill in the gaps
yeah how to fill in the gaps how to
train new people and you know just to to
to be able to walk around and kind of at
a glance see what people are doing and
see you know if it's correct or not
totally trim jail is an important place
to go for part of your life I swear
right right no windows movies totally I
mean there was a point where I used to
sleep next to my plants when I was
trimming them you know or whatever you
know I'd have stuff in the bed and I I
have allergies now that I can't do that
but I think it's important to learn how
to trim um and learn how to trim
efficiently and learning that like if
you can trim one gram in one minute
that's a pound of flour in a day yeah
that was always my example but and and
you know when I started trimming you
know it wasn't even really a job it was
an a uh an honor totally you know like
it like if you got invited because I'm
going to harvest or somebody's going to
harvest some weed right you know and
this is way before we used to call them
trim parties
right I mean you're lucky if I feed you
yeah like you you're you're GNA go home
with some really good green you know
some really good bud that's not
available to anybody else and maybe some
scissor hash if you're lucky yeah then
it turned into a you know a whole circus
at some points you know with some of
these bigger harvests and outdoor
Harvest you see you know and it's you
have to have 20 30 people there camping
out doing all kind you know it's it
sometimes sleeping out for months into
February March you know I've seen that
before at some places you know it's
pretty it's done till it's done you just
you know and I've seen some workers that
just are pretty wild they'll get up in
the morning and trim till they go to bed
and they'll do that for seven days in a
row for months straight yeah yeah I we
we had a few people that that you know
good people that would come up and take
it real serious and and make some pretty
good money and that was their only form
of you know money for the year and they
would make enough to survive on the Year
by trimming you know totally I've seen
people come from other countries and
rock it out and that's all they did for
years they come trim and then they
travel the rest of the year yep and you
could do that yeah so but I think
trimming prices were more expensive back
then I think they were
yeah so yeah so tell tell me how you got
started in the industry I I think it's a
long complex story I'm sure uh well you
know a 30,000 foot view you know I I was
kind of born into it my family were
Growers before me growing up you know it
was a it was a different type of um
situation back then you know you can get
in really serious trouble a lot of my
family members did go to jail and prison
for different things at different points
this was the mid 80s uh yeah this is the
mid 80s and um I mean all the way up
into the you know 94 in even some after
you know when even after 215 passed
there was some people still going to
jail without cards and doing things a
little too big and you know this and
that but um yeah so I mean I I kind of
grew up in the culture in in in more of
a a more coveted culture back then you
know um saying that you were a grower
wasn't just like showing up and clocking
in and going into a $5 million facility
and doing the job that they had trained
you to do you know being a grower was
was everything it was being able to to
successfully pull off a crop after the
year and trim it and store it and sell
it and everything and Survive by this
and it was just a it was almost um it
was just a different type of time then
it was like there were there was there
was not as many Growers right there
wasn't it was harder to find and it was
a more special thing if you knew
somebody if you knew some Growers up on
the mountain and you you know you could
make a living off that you could go up
and get you know bud and take it back
and sell it for 50 bucks an eth or
whatever this is you know in the 90s and
stuff but that' be like 400 bucks
today you know and uh but it it was you
know and that was when you know 50 bucks
an eth then you know minimum wage is
probably three or four dollars an hour
totally you know as a whole it was a lot
you know to to spend that much money for
that small amount when everybody's
smoking you know pressed or brick weed
or or whatever that's so much more
inexpensive and people held genetics so
close too t they didn't let it out yeah
it wasn't there wasn't the circulation
of genetics like there is now totally
totally and and even regions like even
like in Jamaica like like orange Hill
and these different places it was kind
of like that here too right there would
there were certain F like oh families or
Crews or people and areas that were more
famous for specific strains yeah you
know like uh you know I heard on your
other podcast you were talking about
blueberry like the Oregon blueberry uhuh
that was a specific place you know what
I mean and and uh you know over time the
cut gets out and it gets wherever but
that cut I haven't seen it around very
much no me neither I I actually lived in
Oregon for a while and the the late 90s
and I know what you're talking about
yeah the snowbud the dog the blueberry
all the Trinity you know that's a
trinity is more well known but the other
ones you know and there was a corn there
was the corn and it had the looked like
corn on the cob yeah yeah so yeah but um
yeah so so I mean different places have
different like we in in our area you
know it was more of a citrus we had we
were always dealing with the Calo and we
had like these Citrus skunks and like
you know different hazes a lot uh back
then when I was younger younger and I
was in charge of any of that you know I
was just kind of there what area was
that um we're above Fresno in the in the
right below the king's cany National
Park oh wow yeah nice yeah that's where
it's kind of Southern sieras but uh see
Foothills is we we have a really great
micro climate where we're at we we don't
get any rain
from basically the end of April till
Thanksgiving it's super super dry it's
super dry and we can escape the heat
from the elevation so we have a very
very specific microclimate that does
really well for outdoor nice um and
Greenhouse anything you know that
depends on the on the weather right nice
so what kind of genetics were you guys
working with back in the 80s and a lot a
lot of skunk yeah a lot of like like I
say like Helio skunk um
hazes um and and and honestly there
there was a few um varieties that they
would get just from good brick we right
you know because back then there were
like I'm talking about when I was a kid
there were we didn't have indoors right
we didn't have a greenhouse everything
was outside everything was off your
property yeah you're you're literally
crawling through the mountains and
running water lines off of creeks and
and growing growing very very different
than you would today or even the last 20
years you know right um it was it was a
different thing and so every year they
would just start everything with seed MH
um and um cloning didn't go on very much
cloning didn't really go on this one I
mean I'm talking late 80s I mean there
there was indoor don't get me wrong sure
of course but it was when you were going
to grow outside it was always from seed
and you would start a and you would make
your own seed and in fact that was one
of my very first jobs that I ever had um
was making the seed cuz I couldn't I
couldn't go to the out to the crops
because I was too young and they would
think I was going to get in trouble or
something like that so around our house
we had different areas that well one
specific area that we would plant and
leave a mail in and make seeds for the
next year but it would literally be like
one mail yeah and we would make enough
seeds for our you know all we needed was
a few thousand so you had to do some
good selections on that mail hopefully
yeah yeah and I I always had help with
all that stuff but I was in charge of
like watering it keeping it you know
getting it going and all that but um
yeah so we would grow from seed and a
lot of the seed would just be like I say
made so one year if if you didn't make a
good selection and it did or it just
didn't take well that was the next
year's whole deal almost you know we we
had a few different spots that had a few
different varieties but it was mostly
very vanilla like it was very like this
spot has this this spot has this it
wasn't like hey there's a bunch of
different things in here and a bunch of
different things in here right and names
weren't as important they were not they
were not as important you you'd kind of
have a name and most of the time when
you'd get a name it was from somebody
else or a whole bunch of people calling
it something else like we we had the
Calo for a long time and people call it
uh the Cheeto Bud CU it was very orange
haired and like this orange hair and
like people would just name these things
these things and then that's it just
stuck you know it wasn't like hey I I
put these things together and I call it
this yeah it didn't really happen like
that the lineages weren't as well
understood or or I mean maybe they were
better understood because there was less
lineage to work with yeah but uh but
yeah everyone's got to have all these
names and they're related not yet yeah
but but really at the end of the day the
focus should be on quality definitely
definitely you know the the the quality
is is what's going to make or break you
you know you can't survive by just
putting out subpar flow especially back
then you know I guess it might have even
been easier back then because the only
real competition you had was brick weed
yeah so it was I
guess I mean I think you could grow
shitty weed up until about five years
years ago and you were probably doing
okay I think a lot of people got by on
mediocre flower yeah mids Dusty mids
uhhuh you know so but those guys have
most of them have went away yeah so
luckily yeah well you know with the the
the laws and the regulations kind of
clamping down and making it a little bit
more you know risky to to do and um and
then if you're not very good and the the
the competition is so stiff it's just
even with genetics all these things you
know yeah yeah for sure for sure um you
know there's
more especially with genetics there's
more seed companies now than I'd ever
seen every year there's so much more
because I think a lot of people see the
value in it but anybody can make seeds
it's making great genetics is a whole
different story yes yes yeah I mean
there's a big difference between seed
production and breeding for quality and
and I mean you always want to breed for
Quality if you're doing seed production
but there's a whole different thing when
you're actually making packs of seeds to
put out to people for me anyway yeah I
agreed you know uh with seed production
I focus on on different types of things
um you know structure uh flowering time
and not only flowering time but when it
will come in outside you know you have a
a 60-day flowering plant versus a 50-day
flowering plant well you're like well
this one's going to I'm going to harvest
this one 10 days before I harvest this
yeah and it's not true outside no it's
when that initiates flowering that's why
you can have a a haze that takes a 100
days inside and it could be done October
10th because it initiated in July yeah
and you can have something that that is
uh you know 60 days and it's not done
till Halloween like the strawberry
banana right like the strawberry banana
is a great example so uh when did you
start getting into selling seeds I know
you worked with DNA but were you doing
stuff with seeds before you guys kind of
started working together um actually
selling
seeds I sold them kind of in bulk not in
packaging MH to different people back in
the day but with DNA that's when I
actually started selling seeds nice yeah
like to the public yeah you guys had a
long run together yeah yeah I mean some
great great genetics came about your
collaborations with DNA you guys won a
ton of
Cups uh you know and it was like it was
pretty impressive yeah I always I mean
those guys like share a really warm spot
in my heart I those they're my brothers
right there but um and I'll never forget
you know all of the things that they
helped me get through especially in
Amsterdam and getting the seed company
going and and introducing me to people
now I've I've uh been fortunate enough
to get full control of my company back
and Beyond you know just crock it and go
do like my own directions yeah and uh I
I'm really uh like stoked I we're we're
really uh having some fun you know
because it only happened about a year
ago yeah you know so we' had been I've
been with DNA for so long that we were
doing projects together and I was
working more towards all of that stuff
and really not focusing on Crockett very
much yeah so now the focus is all on on
uh on our farm and and what we can do
and and doing things that we really
enjoy doing and and bringing back things
that that maybe people would enjoy that
had forgotten about that we still have
and and just getting together with
people that I normally wouldn't work
with right um because you know of
whatever I was doing I was too busy or
this or that you know so it's been a
it's been a good ride yeah yeah there
was some great genetics that came out of
all that and strawberry banana being
like the first washer I mean there's
been washers throughout history but like
as far as that was one that really
changed the game I think to a degree
yeah strawberry banana you know I I
think I we made that in 2006 and that
was me and a friend of mine Craig in one
of our our first Endeavors together and
uh we went to Amsterdam together and uh
bought a bunch of seeds and uh ended up
getting
uh um some of Simon's bubble gum was one
of them oh yeah right and uh we came
home and we started making some seeds
and we crossed it with the banana OG and
lo and behold this beautiful plant came
out of it but we only made a few seeds
there was only a few seeds to be made
like out of that that little project you
know and so they never really got
released um and uh the original cut you
know I I I coveted for a probably half a
decade almost until I gave it to Da and
Aaron and then they started producing it
in Amsterdam and made a few runs with it
um you know in fim form um and uh it's
just never really been released since
then it's always been something I just
bred with yeah you know and uh yeah it
dumps it's it's one of the the first
real hash plants that I I had created
that really really dumped like everybody
like the size of the heads the the the
easily collectible as in the yeah it has
that gritty feel to it yeah you can
almost pick up a head with your fingers
I mean it's it's a it's an incredible
plant it really is and um in fact I got
two joints of it right here so whenever
that's
awesome yeah we should probably fire one
of those up but let's talk about you for
a minute so you got raised in the
industry yeah so I mean it was never
really a secret you know growing up I
wasn't necessarily involved too much on
it because I was you know underage and
whatnot but yeah I was digging holes and
and carrying soil in and bamboo steaks
and and that kind of aspect for a long
time and then uh yeah let me like he
said I earned my spot in the trim room
and uh learned how to trim and whatnot
through a season and uh yeah that was
like a whole experience like dealing
with you know all of his friends that
were like cultured and everybody knew
what they were doing and I was kind of
new to the whole thing and and uh it was
a cool cool experience but uh eventually
I started growing on my own and and uh
obviously he was like right there beside
me teaching me like hey do this do this
you know get your spot ready now it's
time now's the time to plant you know
like um setting me up for just you know
success so and uh as soon as I was of a
of age I started working right under his
wing you know um working on designing um
you know grows and we built out loud
pack and bunch of cool and I was
involved in all of it so I started
getting like this more Broad View on the
Cannabis industry instead of just like
my high school experience yeah um I was
you know growing it and cultivating it
and I was included on like breeding
projects and stuff so and at the same
time I'm still going to school college
and stuff so like I'm also applying the
stuff I'm learning in my Horticultural
class and my business classes and and um
working with like the legal stuff and
you know the stuff that like my friends
had no idea they knew about the hype
strains and all the stuff but they're
like yeah I grew a plant in my backyard
and you know whatnot and I'm like yeah
yeah you know how much it cost to trim
it and to get it process and then you
know all the stuff behind it and they're
like no I just grow a SM it like yeah
once it becomes a business you start
analyzing all those little details and
time and energy and everything else yeah
totally especially if you're trying to
make money off it you're like okay this
is my life you know every summer and
spring this is what I do like and each
year we get closer and closer to being
tomato Farmers you at the end of the day
you know it's like but it's a passion
driven thing yeah so I see you know the
last 20 years there's been a lot of
people that are you know financially
motivated and everything else but like
now there's a lot of the people that are
sticking with it are people that love it
and I think that you know I love talking
about it you guys love talking about it
it's just it's a great thing when you
can do what you love and you know be
passionate about it and and be able to
take home a paycheck definitely and he's
super passionate and I like totally
carried it on I was you know as a kid
growing up you're like the ideal job
would to be somehow make money doing
this for the rest of my life you know
and he like started this company and all
the stuff and I was included on it and
it was like pretty freaking cool and you
know still grateful to be a part of it
and running with with him right like he
said we have the full control of the
company again yeah and it's like not
we're not answering any corporate
anything it's just what do we want to do
who do we want to work with you know
like you know
so definitely interesting so were you
able to go to any of the cups back in
the day how long have you been kind of
in the industry like I guess the first
cups in the US were 2010 but did you go
to any of the European ones yeah so the
first um the first cup that I went to
was in Denver and 2013 nice that was a
good cup yeah that was a really good cup
had great experience Milo with his big
Booth rest in peace Milo but man there
was that yeah that was a good experience
and that was like the transition phase
yeah from where it was before to kind of
where it is now like those years were
those years were special yeah they were
they were there's that those are some of
the most fun and special times I'd ever
had and those were when you guys were
crushing the cups too you guys were
every every event DNA and crocketts
getting called up for like literally
every event there was a handful and
sometimes it was like they got called up
over and over we won a lot of awards we
we did we we won a lot T just yeah and
the Tangi had its peak like when the
Tangi was peing and you know it it was
tough to compete with Tangi at that time
because Tangi was such a specific thing
so we talk about hype weed like gelados
and stuff like that Tangi was that at
its time and if you were a judge and you
like DNA and you like Tangi everybody
knows what Tangi is all the other stuff
there's subtleties but Tangi is like oh
yeah it's like there's nothing and like
someone else couldn't enter it and call
it something else because it would get
disqualified too and in the early days
you know it was uh the early days of BHO
right um when it started really hitting
with with with everyone and everybody
wanted shatter right and and all these
these hash makers and these guys were
all making um shatter
and um and most of the time with the
shatter there was no flavor right they
Bland it's all land and it was just this
or that it wasn't very tppy yeah and so
like Tangi was one of those varieties
that the turps came through on it so it
was an easy way when judges were picking
out the the like nothing nothing got he
wins you know totally so um but yeah
that was a great run in a great time I
mean uh those those were great days and
and uh yeah Brian helped me through
almost all of the you the shows in the
US like almost every single one did you
guys go to the first one 2010 in s
Francisco yeah yeah that's where I met
where we met I think that yeah that's I
think that is where we met it was either
that or in Amsterdam I'm not sure the
the one in 2010 is where I
showed um Aaron and uh and our other
buddy Sergio uh the Tangi for the first
time oh wow yeah that's that's the one
in San
Francisco I showed it to him for the
first time and uh yeah that's when they
they loved it and uh and I actually came
and brought them a cut of it and uh it
took off from there and those were like
OG gas guys too that's the funny thing
is like these OG gas guys are like Tangy
and then then that became a big thing so
yeah I like gas too but so let's go into
the Tangi a little bit how did that come
about I love hear the backstory on the
Tangi because well you know we had been
messing with the Calio for the longest
time M and 14 week Calo or 14 to 16 the
yeah I mean it it was more of like
October 10th Calo okay you know um it
was it was the the shorter variety nice
you know um the GU indoor in the bay it
was like 14 to 16 weeks I had a friend
Sean Alberts that that grew it at one
point but yeah um and then you know W
with that it yeah ours isn't that long
it's it's more of
like 10 to 12 weeks yeah you know um
that's doable 14 to 16 that's that's
pretty crazy yeah um but uh you know
that and I was I was messing around with
a lot of skunks like Island sweet skunk
and citrus skunk and all these different
skunks back then and I found this really
great skunk that was was was just
beautiful and uh and uh we had bread
with it with our Calo because the Calo
that we have is from seed we've been
making seeds from it for a long time and
it's not pure Calo it's not the Calo
it's it's what we had up on the mountain
like it's it's our kind of it's your
calo calo it was just called that like I
said back in the day there W the name
names weren't there they weren't
important there wasn't the importance
played on names as much yeah and uh so
this other Citrus skunk and we the cross
just made this
beautiful um Aroma of like pure oranges
and it ranges too like if you planted
20 female
tangies you'll get an array of the the
the structure and the potency and all of
that will be right there it it'll be
pretty stable but the tpping profile
itself will differ from like an an
orange peel to an orange juicey peel
with the the fresh squeeze yeah that
fresh squeeze kind of almost orange
blossom like I've I've smoked I've
smoked a bunch of different tangies over
the years purple Tangi too and you have
a blood blood orange Tang BL orange and
the purple Tangi was uh off of the
original Tangi stock that I had got to
uh o OG Steve yeah yeah well so I have
this thing about like with phen hunting
now I'm sharing weed with my friends
like typically I prefer the if I'm
asking for feedback I prefer giving a
joint a big joint and they don't get to
look at the weed because we know what
good weed looks like right we know what
good color looks like we know all about
the structure but like I'm more
concerned about the flavor and the
effect and if you give everybody joints
you get the same kind of response and I
feel like more than likely people are
going to smoke those joints because
they're easy to smoke yeah Light It Up
flavor on this is amazing the flour it's
not super eye appealing like as far as
like bag appeel typically compared to
some of the you know I guess depending
on what you're looking for but like you
put it in a joint it smokes amazing you
put it in hash it smokes some of the
best yeah and it dumps I mean and the
the there's a few different varieties of
strawberry banana out there because they
come from the different seeds you know
and and so the the one that was from the
original clone there is is pretty eye
appealing the like it the Aesthetics on
it is very very nice it's just frosted
where you can just hit it and just it
just rains and the buds get a little bit
bigger but it is a little leafier and I
think that's that's what helps it like
get such a big yield right on you know
hash so on on a wash nice but um yeah
it's it's beautiful it's a it's a
beautiful plant so you guys also have a
farm too for vegetables you guys selling
vegetables uh or promoting them online
at least I I've seen something about
that um no
Texas that is not me that is not you
guys um I'd like to um no we should
collab with them you guys should totally
collaborate with them so there's a farm
in Texas that is called Crockett Family
Farms and it's from Crockett Texas right
that makes sense and um yeah and they
they uh they sell vegetables people
should check it out totally shout out to
crock Family Farm
Texas so yeah so uh breeding Focus you
guys what is your focus right now on
breeding do you guys what you you guys
doing large scale production you doing a
lot of outcrosses we have like three
basic
focuses um you know seed production
for uh you know THC seed production for
hemp and then you know seed production
for for or just breeding for um THC for
our packs and for the brand so we we run
three that's kind of our three resources
right there so like depending on what
you're looking for if you're looking to
to get something outside and you want to
plant 10 acres or 20 acres of something
and you need it to be done by a certain
day you know we can help with that um
obviously with autos and different
things like that on the larger scale
stuff
um but uh the fun stuff is the stuff
that goes on just in our on our farm
yeah yeah that in the Andor and all the
hunting and popping your 30y old seeds
and yeah hoping for one to pop you're
like they have they have a embryo rescue
now yeah we yeah just it's pretty wild
yeah that is pretty cool it's like
surgery it's like the game of operation
almost on this you got to pop it off
with a pair of tweezers like you pop the
the uh shell the coat of the seed off
you pop that yeah and then you actually
take the embryo out and yeah put it in
something that's more um suitable for it
to to be able to to recover yeah and
sometimes you can actually just take it
out and put it in agar and grow it and
like with hormones it's
crazy but yeah 30 40 50 year old seeds
but I think they've popped seeds that
are thousands years old so if that's
possible anything's possible right yeah
but but uh you know our Focus like right
now is is making new varieties testing
the varieties that we've already made
yeah um getting uh into the other spaces
of of other states for our our products
to be able to be available you know
trying to expand a little bit are you
still doing the European thing are you
guys just focused on the US now or no we
do we're worldwide we do uh you know we
have full distribution almost everywhere
that's fantastic um here we're focusing
more on just you know testing out the
stuff that we've already made yeah we've
got so much so many things we we have a
we've got a test you mentioned Milo
earlier yeah and uh yeah he he came and
he came to the states I think it was
like
2018 and came to my house and stayed at
my house for like a week and um he
brought a bunch of seeds from cheese and
blue cheese and and all all these
different things that he had uh uh some
of his original stuff right yeah yeah
and so we when after he passed I was
like man I'm going to plant i' never
planted them I just always just had them
right and I was like I'm going to plant
these seeds so we planted all those
seeds and we just uh you know uh we're
we're actually like kind of going
through them right now we we picked a
cheese winner we picked a blue cheese
mail I yeah and I've never really had
like a true experience with cheese like
like offensive cheese where it's almost
borderline offensive I didn't even know
like I was like growing up me and my
friends we thought we knew what cheese
was we bought weed chees or cheese you
know what I mean and then we started
growing some of these out and I'm like
yeah I had no idea what cheese was super
loud it's very loud there's like some
are sweeter and all the stuff I'm like I
thought it was supposed to smell like
cheese or something you know like that's
what I was expecting and it's hasn't
been that so far so I'm we haven't
smoked any of these varieties yet so I
haven't like got to they're almost done
yeah that sounds exciting that's the
beauty of popping seeds and then having
to wait so long before you actually get
to try to smoke it you think about it a
lot sometimes it's a big let down and
other times stuff that like looks a
certain way it changes so much it
changes from the time you harvest it
even where you're like it looks all
right and then you go to smoke it and
it's like the most amazing smoke yeah
but the one that looks so good that
yielded so much is just kind of a big
let down yeah yeah yeah the whole the
whole process is a lot of fun definitely
you guys uh go to any events right now
I'm
kind of just planning on spannabis yeah
I think that's going to be the next big
one but yeah I don't have uh any big
plans except for spannabis you going to
spannabis this absolutely I'm going to
spannabis we'll be at spannabis we'll be
at the uh Greenhouse Booth again like
that was usually for the last few years
I'd been doing the big Booth but with
other seed companies and then Arian was
like come down and you could get get in
our space and hang out and I was like
cool let's do that so that was a lot of
fun and we were over right by Don and
Aon you didn't you did go last year yeah
yeah I seen over there yeah I seen you
over there good times we were like right
next to DNA too yeah so yeah I remember
uh you had a booth at spannabis yeah and
you were kind of in the center and right
across from you was another booth and
Mark um Bubble Man oh yeah was in there
and he had about 100 curling
irons that's so funny smashing
everybody's Bud giving everybody rosin
totally It's funny yeah character it's
funny how the curling iron is evolved
into uh I think I even have one in my
pocket rosing carts we have today yeah
yeah it's like we got these Rosen carts
yeah and uh that started with the
curling
iron so Jason midnight ryer Jason yeah
uh he was the curling iron guy he was
doing a lot of curling iron action him
and Ashley were yeah he's a he's a
gadget guy man he's like cool stuff he
can always figure [__] out he he took
this old maale Jeep I know this is off
topic and turned it into a it where it
burned hydrogen and all the stuff and he
was getting like 90 miles to the gallon
on this like old maale Jeep he just like
does stuff he's a guy who can like
figure stuff out yeah he's a good dude
grow some killer weed too definitely
definitely he introduced us to the loud
Berry I remember I was like this yeah
this is amazing what is this it was like
the
fruitiest i' ever SM Hunted that out of
so many seeds the laberry was pheno
hunted out of we we had done so much and
then he got a 10pack popped them and
then found the loud Berry wow and I mean
literally there was so many there was
probably 1500 seeds that had gone
through different people's hands yeah
for him to get that one out of a 10 pack
pretty amazing that is wow an amazing
but it's it's also uh proof that you
have to be able to grow really good weed
to be able to feno hunt because the
thing is I think a lot of then there was
a lot of good fenos too but like really
the best Expressions they stand out but
you have to be able to grow to a certain
level and if you can't then a lot of
your stuff just looks the same and
you're going to miss a lot of the good
stuff that's super special yeah you got
to bring it to its fullest potential if
you could you know well then there's
like the drying and the curing and all
those things are super good and if you
can't do those right yeah that's half of
it that's where usually people ruin it
ruin it at the end you know right at the
end after all this they ruin it in a
week's period or two weeks by drawing it
too fast or drawing it too slow or you
know having the environmental usually
it's just an environmental thing they're
scaring it up but yeah there is a lot of
well and it's also there's an art to it
I think a lot of people can follow
recipes anybody can follow recipe but
it's like it's when there's an art to it
that that separates people for sure yeah
so because there's a lot of stuff you
can't read about it's like uh when
because the Bud's different sizes so
like do I pull it out of the room today
or do I wait another day like if you
just follow the recipe it doesn't always
work no it does not being able to just
kind of eyeball things and touch and
feel and you know just kind of you know
always bend to the snap you know what I
mean there's just little things that
totally you know so but yeah the canle
brush have you guys seen that now it's
been around for a while that little
nylon looks like a baster for like yeah
it's like a meat exactly and those I
thought I thought it was kind of a joke
like I was like you got to be kidding me
like people use this and then one of my
buddies he crushes it with it and they
do like four to five pounds a day uh
metric but still it's like four to five
pounds of trimming but he also grows
really big buds and he keeps the
environmentals perfect and just because
you know just because it doesn't work
for somebody doesn't mean it won't work
for somebody else so I was totally blown
away and the thing is is like a lot of
the top shelf guys because if you do it
right you're actually touching the bud
less and then you have your temperature
and humidity set to where the tricomes
are pliable but they're not going to
snap and so then when you brush you're
not [__] up the tricomes and you're
getting all the butt off but you have to
have chunky buds you can't do it with
lar it strin specific for sure yeah I've
used one a few times like they've had
them at facilities and yeah like oh well
this kind of work uh yeah I totally
wasn't sold on in the beginning I was
like you got to be kidding me that
people are coming out with different
stuff all the time it's cool though I
like seeing it I saw some cool you guys
would like the under canopy lights oh
soen for green hous and for indoor
whatever like I feel like it's just
another thing but they're talking about
25% yield increases and stuff and I
think that's cool but I really get like
where you either have mixed light or
greenhouse and you could put under
canopy light and get all the stuff that
doesn't really fill out to to harden up
a little bit yeah yeah there is that
light too uh it goes around a pot like
so it's like um beta product I think or
whatever but it's supposed to go around
on a specific size pot and your plant
like is growing up through it and it
shines up but it's like some uh UV
that's supposed to like sterilize
everything interesting you run it like
60 seconds or something a night or
something like that and supposed to work
I have one I'm starting to use it so see
if it works but I've heard like good
things about it but everyone's like I
don't know how far you're supposed to be
away from it when it turns on CU like
I'm using it in a tint so I'm like okay
is the tint really blocking these like
Rays right here going through I'm like I
think I'm gonna leave the building and
like then I'll let it turn on right but
better than microwaves I guess maybe I
don't know yeah it says it kills DNA on
it so I'm like oh [__] that's not good
send him to Don and
Aaron oh man let's go back into some
breeding talk about like uh separating
males like you guys do you do a lot of
male breeding also feminized yeah but uh
regular breeding
with true
males oh yes you keep them alive in
Clone form for a long time or how how do
you guys do that we do we do we do keep
specific clones Al or specific males
alive in Clone form yeah um there are
some that we have that are very
difficult do that because they turn to
like flower a lot more even in even if
as soon as they like touch the pot and
like their Roots start bounding they
like even if you have them on 24 they
exactly 24 and they'll flip but you just
got to keep cloning them after yeah they
Autoflower yeah so so we have a few of
those and and and uh that makes it kind
of a pain but um we we do check um quite
often just to make sure nothing's going
on but um we keep our males in Clone
form we um we we're constantly looking
and constantly checking and using
different males and growing side by side
males and and and you can turn a male as
well yeah back right and so we'll
sometimes we'll do that and just see how
much resin we can kind of produce on
these males and get a smell from them
and kind of pick out our males in
different ways like that not just and
obviously with structure and just you
know a stem rub and looking at it right
but I mean you got to have some sort of
after 40 years you you figure You' you
pick up a couple tips along the way
tricks yeah but yeah and observations
and I think the real one is growing the
next gener a out and seeing how well you
did but there are definitely identifiers
I mean stemra but also triome production
on the mail yeah yeah the definitely how
they they're structured too like if
they're long and short compared to their
uh female counterparts siblings yeah
yeah so yeah I mean we we do a lot of
different things with with you know just
the selection that we were we've been
doing even lately I mean just using it
in in different ways too you taking our
taking our males like you know a
specific variety male and female and
going both directions you know
reciprocal yeah um you know reciprocal
doing reciprocal breeding yeah totally
um that's that's what I like to do
that's where I find my most success when
I'm looking for to to find something
that I want to happen yeah that's when I
can kind of make that happen because
it's more predictable totally well you
could be missing out a lot of stuff and
then it's like depending on if the
traits from the father or the mother you
know you totally could miss out on some
of the best stuff yeah so and until you
know your lines really well those are
the kind of things you have to do and
even still it's always interesting
seeing the results but also space and
time so time is the one thing we don't
have enough of yeah yeah and space is a
close second yeah
seriously well yeah so where do you see
the future the the industry going you
know I think you have your your foot in
the genetics and are you guys going to
go into other products to try to predict
it it's it's definitely difficult I mean
there's there's no I I couldn't have
predicted it 10 years ago to where it's
at right now you know it's it was it's
definitely going in a in a in a bigger
more commercial Direction yeah you know
but at the same time a lot of these
people that kind of jumped into it and
had all this this big money kind of
dropped out or are dropping out and the
the smaller the smaller more you know
Boutique the more the more heavy weed
the the better
weed absolutely quen weed's coming back
it's not all about purple even though
purple has its place or whatever but
like it all has its place yeah you know
and it's all so subjective I think good
flower is not always I mean it's pretty
obvious you know like good and bad but
it's making a comeback and I think the
commercial stuff Boutique would be great
I would love to see farm to table or
like these uh these micro Brewery type
models pop up all over California to
where you can go to the farm and you can
buy flour at the farm of the stuff that
you see growing where you can talk to
the farmer and he can tells you all the
things he's put into that plant over
Generations or how he bred it to get it
to that point yeah I think that's part
of like a bigger experience that like
we're missing a little bit that would be
pretty amazing yeah definitely
definitely I mean you can do it with
wine you can do it with almost anything
you know so Wine's not schedule three
that's pretty wild the whole scheduling
when they could just deschedule it but
yeah but yeah and I think we we've been
taking steps we're still going in the
right direction as far as I'm concerned
yeah yeah and and and I'm seeing you
know a lot of the weeding out of of of a
lot of the boof and a lot of the the the
meds even like the stuff that's coming
around on you know the traditional
market and this and that there I mean
the quality is rising in a lot of things
and the prices are going up in different
states so you know um those are good
signs good signs you know yeah yeah I
mean I think the last couple years have
been rough and then there's more seed
companies now than ever before it seems
like there's new ones coming out all the
time well and those seeds St Fresh So if
you make one round of seeds your seed
company's good for 10 years
right yeah yeah it's it's you know it is
what it is you I mean there's a new seed
company every day yeah and and just
people not even seed companies just
people that are have uh online presence
in some sort of social media or
something that that are doing something
that people find interesting I mean
there's people that aren't even seed
companies that are just growing in a
tent and were really successful and
they're like they they put their whole
story on there of how they're going to
make some seeds and they make seeds and
then people want to buy them yeah you
know I don't know like I it's not the
well it's the hype around I mean it's
like just because you have access to
good genetics now you can be a breeder
and it's it is what it is I mean I'm not
gonna I'm happy people are working with
the plant if they're producing good
quality genetics that's even better
they're smoking good flour that's even
better yeah know right the end of the
day I mean content is I mean it's
interesting you know I mean it is yeah I
feel like we're also going to see a big
uh comeback with a lot of the genetics
we liked when we were younger and I
think even getting land race obviously
the land race stuff has kind of been a
Hot Topic lately but I feel like we're
just going to keep going in that
direction because the we need more
diversity and and it's like the top 40s
list so like what's popular today isn't
going to be popular tomorrow well I mean
when we were uh younger you we're
probably the same we're the same age
maybe I'm older than you I don't know
yeah I'm 46 so I'm a little older than
you but yeah back in the day you know
when we were younger you know we were
looking at these these varieties that
were that were out of our reach right
they were our parent stuff or whatever
things that you you know the yester year
stuff alap Poco gold or or this or that
this you know
uh now you know people are looking back
on the stuff that we were doing oh yeah
you know so they're curious about these
things you know I mean I I've seen like
Northern Lights 5 Haze and all this
Shish Berry and all these Norther lights
the the nl5 hazes there's a ton of
different Fort colins cough is one of
them too you know it's like there's so
many all of these things you know that I
was taking
like like a bus up to like Vancouver in
1996 to like buy these on like Hasting
Street from like uh Mark Emery and like
a respectable joint I have a funny story
about Mark Henry but that's love to hear
it well it's uh we we were traveling up
we we took for I think it was back then
it was 49 bucks for a round trip ticket
anywhere that great Hound went yeah so
we got on this bus and we went all the
way up to Vancouver BC and uh and we
found this place called the respectable
joint where it's cool to smoke weed in
there and um but they didn't sell weed
in there but you could smoke it and so
we were in there and uh we were like
smoking weed and talking and stuff and
me and my buddy turned around and there
was like nobody in the store like even
the counter person and people selling
coffee everybody was out of the store
and we were like the only ones in there
and uh we seen out the front door you
know somebody like like giving a speech
in front of a bunch of cameras and all
the stuff and like the the local
media and uh we walked out the door and
it's Mark Emery and me and my buddy just
flanked him with our Grateful Dead
freaking tie-dye shirts on like standing
on each side of him and just we were
like in front of all the cameras and we
were on the news that night nice yeah
and uh
we ended up meeting people over there
and we'd always buy seeds over there and
bring them back like I think there was
what like it was Northern Lights number
five Hawaiian indicia Northern Lights
number five blueberry Northern Lights
number five hay it was Northern Lights
number five times everything and then
there was the Northern Lights to like
the
Oasis I don't know if you heard you
remember that the Oasis it remember it
was that's what they would call it up
there I don't know if I ever saw that I
remember the name
and uh you know just all the stuff that
we would get up there all these
grapefruits and yeah and uh Island sweet
skunk and Romulan and the Romulan was
pretty amazing so actually Jake from
Romulan genetics is coming on the show
and yeah Romulan is a good one it was
popular in the baraya for quite a while
yeah definitely I grew my share of that
that's for sure it would get you really
high yeah yeah yeah there's still some
of your buddies growing that and the
that Romulan and that is sweet skunk cut
they still got like sweet skunk that's a
good one it was one of my favorites back
in the day we grew we grew a lot of that
too um but that was a that was a huge
plan if you want to gr if you giant grow
like 15y and had a lot of lmon in and
yeah and big yield and the effect was
just amazing super cerebral I mean head
sweats paranoia I mean they brought the
whole if you think if somebody says oh
here sativas don't really hit you very
hard like have I'm smoke a joint to that
one drive around Tot drive they've never
been to Europe I don't
think some of those hazes in Europe are
just so strong you know it's yeah I I
really like I I like Haze also and I
like European Haze but sometimes I don't
like where it's like I don't do dabs of
those either because they're so strong
yeah it's some of those European ones
are just it's good they'll get you there
too only a couple hits yep yeah that
original
hay and I guess Hayes Brothers Hayes
those are guys they made Blue Dream as
well
maybe um yeah Haze Brothers right yeah
yeah yeah that's the I mean there's been
so many like even that the we were
talking about Jason earlier that Ranger
that's that's like a Mexican Haze that's
like a a just a a Maj pod of that thing
is legendary yeah is the cut around
still no I don't believe so so the the
only thing we have is seed form of
hybrids of it yeah um and uh but that is
a a really really unique variety that is
is it doesn't really look like much yeah
like it's very leafy but it's super
Frosty it it almost has that Oregon
blueberry look to where it has that it's
like really like frost like bluish
purple like you know and uh but it's
long flowering it's it's like a pain in
the ass plant to grow but it is really
good the effects on that are probably
some of the my favorite that I found in
my life yeah that Ranger well it's funny
because Haze can go in a lot of
different directions with effect because
and and even within African if you go
Durban versus Congo the Durban kicks
your ass and then you got the Congo and
it makes you super happy and laugh like
crazy and it's like those are Regions
they're not that far apart in sense you
know yeah um that they're on the same
continent but but yeah completely
different effects and flavor and then
you got that anise licorice with the
with the deran which I really like
that's one of my favorites as well yeah
the anything black licorice or Anise is
like a totally yeah especially if it's
like coating like that Menthol almost
like a menthol coat with it or yeah so
yeah are you guys working with land R
stuff bringing them back yeah definitely
we have like uh pakist Pakistan and that
black African Haze oh yeah
Vietnam black African Haze fire what
else was there there's a few other ones
but yeah there there's a tie um Tai yeah
very interesting thing the pakis the
Pakistan and
the the uh the African Haze those are
the two that really stood out like
honestly like different than everything
like if you had some pounds of that and
you went around and tried to like you
showed some people they'd be like what
is this like I've never even seen this
you does even look like weed yeah it's
very leaky and and and well well the
Pakistan had had a all decent structure
but it was still kind of Airy and but it
has like that food smell it was just
like this crazy resin on it too it was
just like turning it was small but it
would like turn to sand like real quick
but it was was pretty interesting and
then the African Haze was Giant and uh
the resin on that was was a like like
extraordinary but it takes a lot of seed
the butts were very thin and it was a
lot of leaf around them too yeah if
you're looking to grow something
different those are great options
especially because we're growing stuff
that's so similar a lot and then you get
something I think that's why the freak
Show becames and also like freak Show
doesn't put out a ton of leaf it's like
a low Leaf to to flower ratio but it's
different yeah completely different now
they got a purple freak Show too they
got yeah two different expressions
adding things into some of those land
race stuff I mean some some some of that
stuff's one step away you know like one
two steps away yeah yeah yeah like Oreos
that's I feel that's a it's once yeah
purple punch and Oreos are like you know
I don't bag on strange usually on my
show at all but like I feel like they're
good and they're one step away from
being great I think Mike from exotic did
a lot with the purple punch that made it
great made it better the red runs was
like the best expression well you know
when you're when you're looking for
stuff you know you want to look at you
know the purple punch it's not what you
want to smoke but growing the groin wise
I mean it's it looks pretty good and it
puts off a lot of resin and and
everything else but it's not what you
want but if you if you have something
else that's dominating with flavor and
smell and you put that to it you know
hopefully that it'll retain its flavor
and smell and not Tain too much and you
can you take advantage of that structure
problem with the Oreos is it has like
these chocolatey weird the turps are
really weird yeah and so like it doesn't
smoke like you you like it to smoke and
the effects are okay the effects are
fine but like as far as like Flavor it's
it has something that's going to compete
with stuff too but I think it's so
Frosty you know I feel like more of
those crosses you get a couple
Generations away where it has a turps of
something else yeah it'll do it has
potential yeah I mean we we've done that
a lot of times in the past with
different things but you know like there
was a Blackberry that never oh my God
the Blackberry from nor it was tested
like 8% THC it was the darkest Bud too
it was super black and it looked amazing
but it didn't get you high but you had
to T it was so covered though and hash
you're were like oh my God sometimes it
would like flower in the bedroom out too
you'd be like you'd have to thin it out
cuz they just start flowering a few
steps away though like you're talking
you know and like it's like these
different things that that have like it
was a cool plant for breeding purposes
I'm sure yeah especially lock in that
that color pretty easily I think yeah
something like that but yeah I remember
it did not get you high and and it's
funny CU Green Crack was one where it
would like get you high but then after
you had a tolerance your tolerance would
kill it and then you would you could
smoke a whole joint of it you could
smoke a pound a day it wouldn't you
wouldn't be high at all that's what I I
think I told you that before I was like
I love green crack I want to get like
one ounce a year yeah that's all you
need like the first couple days the
first day with it is great cuz it gets
you super lit but then if you have a
high tolerance to your friends come over
and you're like dude you got to try this
and you don't really prep them for it
man they're they're going to be on the
couch yeah so we still have a good Green
Crack cut we do nice I need to get that
yeah we have an excellent one yeah it
actually washes a little bit too yeah so
it's pretty wild because I feel like
there are genetics in Pocket certain
things like green crack I I've been
looking for a green crack for a long
time and I'm like and then I just bumped
into the cat piss guy my my cat cat piss
buddy well he's somebody who actually
grew the cat piss back in the day so I
can get his feedback on the cat piss
that I
know you know it's like because there's
cat pisses in Aroma and so there's this
huge war going on of everybody like I
created the cat piss yeah or I was given
the cat piss and I'm valo and you didn't
create the cat piss and then there's the
SoCal ciss and the NorCal ciss and
they're different they should have named
it something else but you know it's like
it's a description of an aroma and and
it's a it's it's a funny thing because
capus was the best thing growing up and
it looked the worst I was going to say
it's very very old you know cuz people
were calling a ciss a long time ago yeah
well 90s is when I saw it yeah the first
time but then I heard some hippie at a
Grateful Dead show or not Grateful Dead
it was dead in company he was saying no
no I'm pretty sure they had cat piss
back in the 70s they had stuff they
called cat piss he said it probably
wasn't the same thing but like C it
makes sense because catpiss is the
description of a smell yeah it's like
blue dream where it's a very specific
name name yeah yeah I need to uh to uh
bring you up that green crack and a few
other ones I'll give you a list of some
stuff that I have man yeah I'd love to
trade some genetics so we got some cool
stuff too for sure U yeah and I got some
really cool Autos I'm working with right
now that are got full color expression
gelato taste you know it's been and it's
been a while coming but yeah and then
using some genetics to get reinforce the
color because I thought I could do it on
my own and never could and then got some
amazing stuff Mandalorian full full
duplex gnome gnome yeah gnome yeah gnome
they're doing really interesting stuff
color-wise
yeah so yeah that that black strap
actually breeds pretty true to the color
so incorporating that in through a
couple Generations you can get good
color that's cool but yeah so you guys
do auto breeding too yeah yeah I
actually brought you some stuff dude
that's awesome um
yeah I got some black Cuban Haze and
some piff we were smoking some piff out
there in New York a few months ago it's
like everybody's got piff and S right
now especially with how you know what I
mean there's like everybody's growing
and every it's around every corner and
everybody's got P everyone's got sour
but nobody has the real Sour my buddy's
coming a little bit later day he's got
real Sour and I love Sour Diesel I've
always loved Sour Diesel it's one of
those things like I hadn't realized how
much I'd even though I missed it a lot I
hadn't realized how much i' missed it
until I actually saw saw it again for
the first time in like I don't know five
or six years where it was like the real
deal where it's like that you open the
bag and you get hit with like that um
like the burn of it smells like burnt
tires burnt rubber like yeah it smells
like might burn your eyes you're like oh
[__] it's offensive a little bit and
then you squeeze the buzzes and it's got
like the lime and the pine yeah and it's
funny cuz like over the years you like
as you've moved further away from stuff
you don't completely forget what it
smells like cuz you smell it again and
like I know that's it yeah but like you
forget how amazing stuff is definitely
and I've always loved sour and the funny
thing is like this stuff tests probably
like 14 or 15% and it [__] gets you
ripped yeah well I mean we all know that
that story I mean I I had an LA con that
would test it like
18% La con was fire and it would just it
would just floor me every time and and
it was right right when everybody
started really testing a lot of stuff
and and I'm like man this is low you you
know and and some of this other stuff is
higher but I it it the effect on me it
it wasn't uh as strong you know big nugs
La con oh yeah it was a good yielder and
they had orange hairs too they had nice
orange hairs short and stout yeah long
veg but uh definitely worth it yeah and
smoked really good definitely joint yeah
it was joint weed it would wreck your
day if you weren't ready for it too yeah
yeah so but yeah good I miss a lot of
those OG's I feel like that's going to
make a comeback too like the gas and all
these things are going to make comebacks
in their own way with crosses but I feel
like the nostalgic stuff that we grew up
with and where if people can find it
either in seed form or a clone getting
bred back into this stuff yeah because a
lot of people have a lot of OG crosses
OG is one of those other things that
it's like when you cross it you don't
necessarily get an OG almost no you
don't because it's because of recessive
traits so like and and so having an OG
that actually shows an OG traits you
know the the shape the buds the the
smells the you know everything that's
not just you know a hybrid of it I mean
those are kind of hard to find right now
yeah and you did some good OG seeds a
while back and I feel like it's so funny
because I think you did the koshers yeah
I did I did kosher um what we said we
called kosher OG yeah um and I did uh
the version of the Holy Grail yeah and I
did uh Sauer kosher mhm um and uh hell's
fire but there wasn't a lot of straight
OG seeds forever and then they tried to
do them over in Europe and they put it
with White Widow and then you know or or
critical or whatever they were using to
breed it with for their donors uh and
they completely ruined it because like
those recessive traits are difficult to
breed back defin you have something so
dominant so definitely and something
that so like it o OG takes on you know
flavor right uh from just how white
widow does it does yeah exactly the same
thing so it's hard to keep that OG like
funk you know like it's I don't but um
it always turns into more gas because
and to me it's like there's a difference
between like the gas and the funk yeah
OG is gassy don't get me wrong it's it's
gas but it's like it's got that it's got
that P piny earthy bement fun that's the
best yeah like yeah I love that earthy
like Pine where you get the it almost
smells like fresh pine needles and and
that I mean that's one when you grow It
Outdoors it comes out amazing like it's
it's one thing the guys growing in
indoors I love it but like the outdoor
like those are the outdoor those are the
years I remember you know with the sour
that was outdoor the ogs that were
outdoor yeah there's a bunch of outdoor
and it's just those were better for
smoke like if you're a smoker for flavor
I felt like those back in the day were
amazing oh yeah especially the sour
stuff yeah and you smoke those to the
roach like it tasted good like there was
only a handful of stuff that I was able
to get when I was younger that would
you'd smoke it to the roach and it would
be absolutely amazing but the outdoor a
lot of that stuff it no yeah yeah sour
I've always been I love sour even in the
garden right now we have a bunch of
headbands and sour and Kims and i95s and
I love headband too that's another one
like we have a headband that we've had
for a long time and OG's we've got all
the old still yeah the it's funny cuz
the gassie from like n the chem dog
and the gassy from the OG are two
different kind of gases you got that
burnt rubber
latexy like super pungent and then OG is
super pungent as well and super loud but
it's like gassy like Rocket Fuel kind of
gas yeah like gasoline rather than burnt
Tire yeah but yeah I love both of them
and this has that nice Earth to it yeah
yeah is that the ghost or that was the
ghost yeah it's really good yeah that
one's a good
one it has the effect I mean OG is OG
like what I like about OG the most is
just how how the effect on it it's like
that it's hard to find weed that that
will hit you like that totally you know
um make your eyes all low this is this
one though this one smells you tell me
what
it this is
good it's
not smells like Tropicana orange
juice what is
this that's blood orange this is the
blood orange yeah yeah it's got that
Tropicana orange juice smell yeah it's
Tangy for sure yeah but it's funny
because this is really on the blossom
side like the the fresh squeeze juice
and not the Ry side and I do like the
Rind too I think the Rind is especially
extract like that rind is pretty amazing
I like the sweet I was I like the bar
like the orange sickle yeah yeah orange
sickle
like well so you guys seen Agent Orange
you remember that from sub yeah another
guy rest in peace like yeah yeah I mean
I grew so much of his stuff too like had
a lot of TPS in his stuff yeah Jack the
Ripper
and D I can't Chernobyl Chernobyl yeah
we had the there's like the Chernobyl
and then there was the golden ticket cut
of the chern
I remember that yeah there was it wasn't
a it wasn't the Slimer yeah sler or the
golden ticket both I drew both of those
itun yeah there was but he had like all
kinds of great stuff the agent orange
was really so I didn't like the agent
orange until I saw it grown at House of
coltivar in 2018 I thought it was bunk
because I in the you know early 2000s
there was Calo that I was exposed to and
then Tangi and then agent orange I saw
agent orange and I'm like W this stuff
that I saw was very linear it was like
just an orange it was almost like a
orange color and no complexity at all
right so not color but orange uh smell
that was very linear there was no
complexity at all and then uh I went to
House of cultivar in 2018 and he had
stuff labeled agent orange and I didn't
want to smell it and he's like no dude
this is good and I'm like okay so I
smelled it and I was like this is an
anent orange there's no way this is it
wasn't Tangi but it was just another
anent orange and at first I was like
well maybe Tangi because it smelled more
like Tangi than agent orange but it was
different than Tangi and he it was from
seed and so you just never know when you
get seeds you ever someone might get
that one winner loud Berry yeah and then
the the you know the turps on on the
agan orange I've grown it you know it's
it's uh for for the ones that I had they
were they were more orange peel and
orange rind but they there was orange
turps to them yeah um what I I thought
had a amazing TPS from sub subcool was
uh Jil Bean the Jil Bean Jill Bean was
good too oh Jill's taking credit for
that
oh I don't know bought it a long time
ago I didn't totally yeah I mean that
had great turs yeah that had great turps
but I think with all their stuff it
almost all had flavor and they had so
like the green Avengers yeah they had
like literally they had some of the best
guys working for them you know I'm good
friends with a bunch of them and it's
like uh you know between Pat here is
from the farm they had Shane uh Sunny
Chiba Odie was there all you know that
that was quite a and there's a bunch
more the good old days the good old days
those were fun events though like the
old old events it was like a you know
it's hard to describe and even put it
into words but it's kind of how disco
and once disco was done it was done they
still try to do disco now but it's not
what it was back then yeah and cups were
kind of like that way to put it it was
like a big family it's like we had the
most most amazing times but it was like
the same people would go to all the
events and so we were like a big family
and it was like going and seeing your
friends again because you know you're
going to a cup you know kind of who to
expect and there was probably like 250
of us that all kind of went and we all
intermingled maybe it wasn't that much
maybe it was like a hundred that were
pretty constant but still that's a lot
you know that's a lot everybody kind of
knew everybody and yeah and we were all
there for for weed because we like we
like flour like we like the Cannabis
which I think it's an amazing thing that
it can bring all of us together
yeah definitely especially when it was
like in Amsterdam and stuff and
everybody would jam there yeah oh yeah
from all over the world around
Thanksgiving and it's cold and we' all
have Thanksgiving at that uh one uh
hotel that that served in American
Thanksgiving and it was like a 100 200
of us every time going in there pretty
cool yeah yeah adventures and then
spannabis spannabis is another one like
spab it's it's my favorite event that
goes on now yeah and I see my friends
there every year and it's great seeing
people that I've been friends with long
time and so yeah and there's such good
food and you know it's it's very social
and I don't do social stuff like I used
to we used to do it like once or twice a
month right and now it's like oh maybe
like twice a year three times a year we
get to really break loose as we're
getting older but I think that's how it
goes yeah yeah well I mean there I
couldn't do it twice a month now no
there was a lot of work back then you
know and uh you know showing up to all
these different places and getting
everything all like ready to go and you
know we we had that was a whole thing
whole crew I would fly people in and
just like it was it was a whole thing to
do all that yeah and then like if you
did booths it's like setting up the
booth and oh yeah getting there early
early and and then while the events
going you show up before everybody gets
there you stay till most of the time I
mean I saw people closing down early
quite a bit too but yeah but uh but yeah
I mean it was we were hustling we
everybody was working really hard and
you you had long lines definitely we
long yeah where it was like the whole
day yeah we were just at one point we we
did like I don't know Well we'd have
like five employees like just lined up
everybody selling seeds the whole time
like all day like I added up how many uh
packs of seeds that we had
sold and um how many minutes they were
and the and the time that we were open
right selling seeds and it was more than
like two or three packs a minute wow
yeah it was crazy that that was the our
the heat of our our was that at Colorado
yeah but we ran out that's why it didn't
we didn't last the whole time like we
ran out in like 4 or five hours it was
just like those are the best though when
you can sell out at shows that's only
you know yeah yeah I prefer well and
especially if you're going anywhere
destination if you sell out you don't
have to go home with seeds that's 10
times better aome yeah yeah definitely
definitely but um yeah um we've been
we're looking forward to am or Amsterdam
to Spain and and uh G to go up there and
see everybody and yeah had a great time
last year a lot of fun yeah postco that
was it was unexpected because the first
year that they did it after Co it was
pretty dead and then last year was
amazing I felt like it was like people I
hadn't seen in some of them I hadn't
seen in 10 years or you know it would
seem like everybody came out yeah good
show a lot of people yeah there was more
people than ever at any spannabis on
that last one yeah it was pretty packed
I came home healthy I didn't have Co
like the first time I brought the ba3
back like Co ba3 I was one of the the
carriers of it and I tested before I got
on the airplane came back started
feeling funky took a test I was sick my
wife was sick within a day oh man yeah
and it was It was kind of rough but
interesting experience we almost went
out there that year too we actually
cancelled
our everything because we were headed
out there but uh that's crazy so if
people want to find out more about
Crockett Family Farms and you guys where
would they go to the website Crocket
family farms.com yeah um Instagram uh
the real Crockett
420 um the Crockett Farms
official crito o Cito yeah you got your
own Instagram following it you can
follow my wife at M Crockett she's like
the backbone of this whole whole thing I
know that feeling without her I would
just I wouldn't be here right now I'll
tell you what yeah it it takes a team
yeah so and then running a company as
you get bigger you just can't do it all
so it's great you have someone that can
help manage and pass it on
to it has been a a lot of fun yeah and
the whole family too our whole family
helps out I have twin girls that that
have helped out on big giant farms and
done all kinds of stuff I have my
daughter that done she's helped out and
grown she did her thesis for for Santa
Cruz on phto remediation with hemp and
all this stuff and she did that I'd be I
mean the whole family is in in it and I
I just
uh she's got a hemp Farm yeah R mommy on
Instagram cool so she's farming right
now finishing up Harvest over there
so awesome well thank you guys so much
for coming on the show today man really
appreciate it it's been fun for having
us yeah yeah we'll have to do this again
thanks for having us James yeah really
appreciate it have a good one all
[Music]
right