[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James La podcast
and today my uh guest is Reggie Gino how
are you doing Reggie I'm doing well
thanks for having me James you're very
welcome man I'm glad you're able to join
us where are you joining us from uh I
live in San Diego so I'm and it's not
Sunny so it's been really
cloudy wow the first time I met you was
probably around 2012 or 2013 at Steep
Hill when you're over there in uh
emmeryville we we started out in open
though actually right by the airport so
well and then it was Halen originally
before steep hill and right well there
was steep hill and then there was Halen
Right so Halen was run by Don land and
camona Cesar uh they came from UC Davis
and and um David lampack had started
along with Addison Deora right and and
Steve D'Angelo right um they had started
uh Steve pill so and then right they
were they were like the the two big
competing factions and they combined and
that was the history was made so yeah
interesting times it was that was the
very infancy of uh genetics and test as
far as testing genetics and coas and all
that stuff kind of came out of that that
era exactly right and the first sex test
on the market was from Depo um at one
point there was a I think it made it a
weekend we had a billboard up up on the
101 and made it a weekend before they
made us tear it down um but you know um
sex you know sex your genetics right so
um and then uh we followed that up a
year later with the the first CBD test
right so but but all of that was built
on the fact that we had built that
chemical database well not not the sex
so much as the the sex was we had some
some buddies who who are willing to give
up some males they didn't want so we
sequenced those when everybody else was
sequencing females right because
everybody wanted you know the THC genes
whatever and and we were like well okay
but but about like things like sex
determination doesn't anybody care about
that yeah so now it's an interesting
thing I think once the price gets a
little lower I think it's gonna you know
it's it's already pretty accessible for
most people but you know once it gets
even lower everybody's going to use it
it just makes sense
you know um talking about that right so
you know and I think the coid you know
pandemic helped right a lot of you know
a lot of stuff that was not mass
produced in such quantities because it
wasn't didn't have you know like a
day-to-day use in in everyday life right
you know that whole idea of genetic
testing and you know the the RNA testing
they use for the co is pretty much a lot
of the same kind of work that we do you
know for for like hplvd testing it's
it's an RNA virus as well right so so um
you know so now these things are being
cranked out and the prices have gone
down right so so the the cost of goods
that it used to do you know used to to
cost us to run those tests has gone down
because people are now you know DNA
primers you know for PCR or Diamond
dozen now right so some of that the
prices have really come down yeah um you
still you you you still need the people
who know how to interpret the results
though right so that's the right
absolutely before Co people didn't even
know what PCR was I mean the average
person now everybody knows the the what
PCR stands for exactly right so and and
that's sign of times and it's also a
sign of why the prices are coming down
and you know so back in the day um when
we first started we we we were at you
know with our with our cost of goods we
had to charge like 15 to 20 bucks for
for the the sex test right people are
offering it for seven eight bucks now so
so tell me how you got started in the
industry it was a mistake really or at
the time my day job was um was the uh
senior patent adviser or the senior
patent agent for um a biotech company
called squin so squin was the company
that had invented prenatal diagnostic
testing so they could do a complete
fetal carot type from the blood draw of
a mother so as a side gig I I did um IP
evaluation for other companies and David
lampac happened to be friends with my
cousin um back when they went to high
school in New York and suffer New York I
was like one town over in Muny New York
but I never knew I never knew David
right so um so David was talking to my
cousin said wow I wish I I had an IP guy
I could trust and my cousin said well my
cousin's an IP guy why to talk to my
cousin right so that's how I met David
lampac and then um that was back in the
time I don't know if you guys remember
quanan right so quanan was the first
near IR like you know instant
non-destructive accurate measure of you
know everybody's doing it these days but
but Steve had the first
near potency detector or or evaluator so
right um so I came in I did the
evaluation for their IP and
um unfortunately because they were
already selling quanan they could no
longer patent it right so
um and and what I found was is they had
this Treasure Trove of data they had
been collecting for already the years
they had been operating you know all of
this database of chemotypic information
from different varieties well once you
have a database right that's immediately
how you start building markers right you
look for the differences in the
populations right because that's a
segregating that that gives you
segregation of of genes right so so um
so I said to them well you can't patent
this but have you guys thought about
doing anything with the data you're
accumulating because you guys have a
huge amount of data here that could be
used for all sorts of stuff and and they
were like well like for what I said like
for building breeding markers they were
like oh and so they were like well what
if we were hire you to do that for us
and so um that's how kind of it started
so um my background is in you know
molecular genetics and biochemistry um I
did a you know that
Jean jock the home line yard so you know
I I was at the very Forefront of
qpcr so when I started qpcr it was a
stopwatch and three different water
water baths at different temperatures
right you just lift your thing in you
know instead of having the thing cycle
you cycled it so wow um so you know a
lot of the stuff that we do in terms of
our Market design like that is stuff
that you know um we have a very strong
foundation for because of either my
background or the data that we had
already accumulated and and so you know
um that's kind of how it started it was
kind of an accident right I went for one
thing and then when they realized that I
actually had a vision for what they had
already accumulated they were like well
here let's just hire you to do it and
nice so what what kind of markers back
then were you guys able to uh identify
so the we had the first CBD test in the
market so
um you know and and not only that but
RCB test was the first and for a while
was the only one that actually
pinpointed the ultra high kind of ratio
at the time it was greater than 20 to1
like the ACDC class right right so so
our marker was actually specific for
that class right so it was significant
because you know it allowed you to start
going down that farm bill hemp path
right so right um
we started uh looking for like varen
markers um it was a long uh row to hoe
um and ultimately phos did a better job
than us but we we F faced all sorts of
turmoil you know at steep hill and
that's how we ended up at Front Range
and a whole bunch of stagnation kind of
thing so um but ironically we found the
bkr
marker either around the same time or a
little before anybody else we just
couldn't finish validating it because
literally we we were in a spot where we
were doing very little work because of
very little money and because we were
also at the time kind of transitioning
between hemp and going back to the THC
markets and now you know the company
that I worked for while it was a big
hemp company is no longer hemp focused
right so there's there's always always
that well now you got to stop and then
pivot right so um there was a lot of
that throughout our our history so how
did the transition work from Steep Hill
to Front Range I guess you guys were
acquired by Front Range at at some point
yeah yeah so in
2019 right so this is and and this kind
of this was forced by you know the a
change in the industry right when when
when the BCC well the then BCC now DCC
rules came out and you know um you know
the nature of the game changed right it
was very hard for a a Testing Lab making
slim margins to support a full-on R&amp;D
program like we were right and at that
time I probably had probably eight or
nine people in in just my R&amp;D program
right so um so uh Front Range had made
an an inquiry because they were looking
for that kind of being able to build
markers and and and you know having a
science team to to to drive a
science-driven seed development company
right so so they uh talked to to steep
hill and and there was a deal made for
you know some money and some stock and
you know they got the IP uh along with
us right um we got the Front Range and
it was you know like we hit the ground
running right because you know we
already had CBD marker we already had a
bunch of stuff we had already had
turpine markers and some of and some
other pathway markers that were already
you know in development and or either in
development or already validated right
and so um you know they
were um at the time Front Range was you
know going down the same road everybody
else was which was more CBD is more
better right so we want that that higher
CBD to THC ratio and everything else be
down well um so you know we were able to
get in start screening their entire J
plas population and then within the six
first six months of being there we had
screened everything and already um had
our
first cross we got there it was just so
happened they were in the process of of
getting to do seed um you know seed
increases so they could to sell for the
following year right so so we walked in
and they already had plants ready pollen
plants and and well we did was apply the
the screening that we had done with with
our markers and then
better designed the crosses that they
were going to do to be able to hit the
mark they wanted to do and and and
within the first seed stock that came
out we already had hemp that was
performing way better um in terms of a
number of parameters right so um and
then and then that year we took all of
that stuff and we did the largest field
trial of him probably to this day right
I don't think anybody's done it larger
um we had 27 27 location around the
United States um including five
University Partners Cornell was one of
them and a few others and then we also
went outside the United the the United
States we had five locations in in
Canada we had Jamaica we had Hawaii we
had Colombia in South America so so we
we we literally went hhog right and I
had aerial flyovers he collects multipal
data we did you know Fant testing we did
you know we had field agronomist go out
to all the sites and collect data so
like literally we went Whole Hog because
if you're gonna were you guys using
drone technology for uh yeah we had FL
drones in two locations in one of our
locations in Virginia and one of ourc in
Colorado we used higher perspect Imaging
to to look at Fields yeah pretty amazing
the Drone stuff is just kind of
mind-blowing for me still so so so you
know we put together you know I mean um
you know we we designed a big a type of
model right so so to go out there and
and and the only way you're going to you
know you
talk how often have you heard well yeah
I got shitty hemp seed from I I I called
this guy up and you know and he he told
me how great his stuff was in his State
and but I'm in a different state and
right so and it's the truth right so you
know a lot of people can make decent
hemp seed for their one state their one
microclimate right but in order to have
seed that is successful in multiple
locations right you have to do the work
you have to put it there and grow it and
observe it right and and you have to
take good notes right because the other
thing that you need to do is to figure
out because of the huge amount of of
hybridization and and just mishmash that
you know some cannabis represents right
there there is you know photo period
sensitivity right like so some stuff
when you put it in a short day is not
going to do as good as some other stuff
and vice versa for for short night right
so um you know so we learned a lot you
know it was a huge undertaking costed a
lot of money and I was immediately
immediately taken to test by the company
for spending so much I
bet right but at the but the next year
right when we sold our hemp seed right
nobody complained we had have any any
complaints so and it's unfortunately at
that point that was kind of
2021 when they have industry went right
so yeah and it's so competitive you have
to have really better seeds I mean
marketing just doesn't work anymore
either it's you know it's like there's
there's a handful of people producing
really good seeds and there's a billion
seeds out there so yeah and and for a
while people were just giving the [ __ ]
away 10 cents a seed five cents a seed a
penny a seed right
well when I spent the year before you
know couple hundred grand running field
trials right that's not gonna fly I
can't you know there's no way to do that
so no but at the same time you can
justify why your seeds are more
expensive sure I feel like that makes a
big difference and moving forward that's
what people are gonna have to do yeah
that only that only matters to some
right because some people are oh free
seed yeah I'll take that right so yeah
yeah and that's good for like the first
year and then you really you know that
that's what happened too A lot of people
bought cheap seeds and then they
realized why they don't want to buy
cheap seeds yeah you know or they failed
there's a lot of failure over the last
couple years a lot of businesses going
under and uh you know and it's it's wild
Oregon in California and Colorado you
know the the production the amount of
production is wild it's very targeted
right so if if you look at the USDA um
numbers right so we we're still going
down right so they predicted that the
hemp industry would rebound by 2023 and
you'd see an increase well we had
another two-fold decrease in the number
of hemp Acres from 2022 to 2021 to 2022
right so went from 54,000 acres to
28,000 Acres right so it's still going
down that's that's that's the actual
number of hemp Acres planted in the
United States
total right wow so yeah know so I mean
you look around there not a lot lot a
lot of those hemp companies don't exist
anymore so yeah I mean even some of the
biggest ones that you never thought
would fail are gone you know I can I can
think of a few and it's
like it's it's just amazing but I think
everyone was thinking it was just going
to grow grow grow and that's just not
how it works yeah and then genetic lines
become the tragedy here right because
right as when people are looking to make
the most money spend the least amount
because because they're not sure where
they're going to put their product
anyway so on and so forth nobody's
buying $5 seed that that even though if
it's 5% CBC or makes you know 5% cbdv or
whatever these things right which
actually ends up being the secret to
making compant hint right is the more
minor Canales you have the less THC you
make right so right yeah there's been
some interesting Cult of arts created
over the last five to 10 years you know
I think Jen can had a zero THC they were
working on or
had a couple companies um yeah um there
was panaka which was a which was a zero
there was a pure CBG which
was that organ CBD
with know both of those companies so one
was from hemp trading I think they're in
Spain or somewhere in the Europe and the
other one was from from either Sweden or
Switzerland some so uh the Varon you are
you guys still working on that at all I
mean I think that's still a Hot Topic a
little bit but it it was you know it
started about five years ago people were
really excited about it the cbdv and
thcv and so yeah we have I mean I've
we've made cultivars I got a whole bunch
of stuff I'm trying to integrate it back
into um you know everyday Bud because I
think people got a little carried away
so yeah I have an 8 to 10% producer as
well but nobody wanted to buy it right
and and I think what we're seeing is
that nobody has really adopted the Varn
in any edible products or anything like
it just hasn't grabbed on right but in
the old days right you know yeah geran
poison right
had super high one to one to two% right
THV and everybody loved it right so I
think there's a place for a good quality
high THC bud with a couple to 3% thcv
that I think is going to be like a good
daytime buzz you know kind of kicking in
the pants kind of thing right so so we
we've been working on a couple of
varieties right now one of them is
purple actually so um I had done some
work with some red Congo a while back
and I had um which is phenomenal variety
if you've never tried it red cono I love
it yeah my my friends grow it in San
Francisco it's amazing it's super it's
super strong yeah so super strong same
thing with the Durban um so but but we
used a red Congo base with our thcv
producer and now we have a few lines
that are you know between 1 to 3% thcv
putting out you know 20 22% THC and I'm
gonna see if I can bring back Durban
Poison dude because you know I would
love it if the real one came back I
think there's a lot of people that the
problem is is a lot of people what they
think is Durban Poison is actually a
hybrid of Durban Poison that's been
crossed with super silver haze y you
know and so everybody thinks it's this
hazy plant and really it's this
musky you know it's it's powerful and
but it's not hazy and it's extremely
like licorice you know I we we grew up
with Alice yeah so so I actually had a
cut so I read with that last year and I
I found a cut that had that an Anna
smell that lior smell and so so yeah so
I'm I'm stoked I can't wait to you know
to to start you know going through that
that seed population but um but yeah no
so I'm right with you man everybody
keeps telling you I'm like dude that
swell sweet that swells sweet that's
terpinolene that's that's not it's got
theine L that's no that's not the real
Durban Poison I think it's Greenhouse
that actually we we can blame Aran and
those guys over at Greenhouse for that
you know with the super silver haze but
I think yeah it's it's really
interesting what most people think of
Durban Poison you know and same thing
with red Congo I've seen a lot of red
Congo that's not the real stuff I mean
Redbeard and there's there's a handful
of people in Northern California that
actually sell the real red Congo you
know and I I got to be careful with how
much I smoke of the red Congo cuz it's
like one of those uh cultivars that
doesn't really have a ceiling so you can
keep getting more high and more high and
more high from it the more you smoke
whereas a lot of the modern you know the
the modern varieties that we're smoking
has a like Skittles has a ceiling you
smoke Skittles you can only get so high
but some of these you know and some of
these land race varieties some of these
African varieties especially they just
have no ceiling and you smoke more you
can just you know they're almost
psychedelic too so right so ironic that
you said that I got my red Congo germ
plasm because I was in the Berkeley area
with the guys who were growing the real
red Congo back in the day and and and I
saved every seed I ever got from every
ounce I ever bought from
them that's awesome so that's how I
started and um and I actually had one of
one of the seeds that I popped from that
red Congo line like I I uh gave some
cuts to a buddy of mine uh who's but
used to be a black market grower back in
the day and and he said he was he had
people tell him that it was like they
were tripping on the weed like they like
dude what this this a place dude like I
I was getting all sort of like no dude
that's just good weed yeah right yeah
but some of that gives people like heart
pulpits you know it's like it almost
gives you an edible edible type effect
it's not for the fan of heart right it's
the real red cono some of those African
varieties are are really not for the fan
of heart right because they they they
they they will push the blood pressure
up they will get the heart going they
will they're they're more edgy right so
so but I like that feeling I like I like
to feel like I'm jumping out of my skin
so yeah and for me it's like I like
smoking this stuff sometimes not all the
time not when I'm doing podcasts I did
that once where we were like uh laughing
too much during the podcast I was with
Marlon Asher he's a r singer good friend
of mine and we uh we laughed pretty much
for an hour and we had a good time but I
think it it wasn't well Reed ceed
so cool but yeah so uh are you you guys
are working on some modern style
genetics I mean gelato is kind of hot
and all these gelato derivatives is
that's mostly what we see in the Bay
Area it's got to be purple candy gas
yeah and so so the whole chasing THC is
really in my opinion destroying cannabis
right so that that whole thing kind of
annoys me and and so I thought that I
was going to Buck the trend and make
something really awesome uh so we have a
few things that came out of some of my
righto crosses one of them is called
Watusi and I swear to God it's the best
weed anybody's ever smoked right so but
really but it won't hit above 22 or 23%
so nobody will buy it right but like all
these guys who have who are cultivators
for other companies have dude I love
this I just can't sell it I'm like okay
well you're not doing me any good right
so but no but but I I learned the hard
way dude you can't Buck the trend the
industry is the industry and unless
you're playing the game right so so yeah
so now we're doing the gases and doing
some of the candy and I got a bunch of
purple [ __ ] and so um but it's you know
it's a little disheartening right that
that you can't bring forth something
that is a superior product because it
doesn't test right you know well and I
think Market awareness is part of it but
I also think that uh education like the
the we have an uneducated market and so
they're really focused on hype
unfortunately uh but that these things
change I feel like everything goes in
waves I think the gas is coming back I I
BR I did some breeding with the
shoreline and with the Fort Collins
cough and some blue dream stuff and and
you know some older genetics with the
hype stuff we did some selections and
found stuff that has the look of what
people want but with unique flavor
profiles that that's that's exactly it
that's what we he right now so we're
gonna have green flour again people are
going to be okay with it you know I you
see it more so in like Washington than
you do in California I feel like that
Market's a little more educated same
thing with Colorado to a degree well you
know what's interesting is that
everybody wants purple right but so
purple an anthocyanins are a less
efficient form of chlorophyll right so a
plant that's heavily purple will always
test less lower than a plant that is
equivalent pathway and green right so so
yeah you got to take into account well
you have different versions of the
optimized pathway and so you have
natural variation in cannaboid content
anyway right so but all things being
equal if you had the same exact genetics
in a purple plant the green plant the
green plant would always test higher
because it makes more energy because
it's a better chlorophyll that's it
right so we as an industry are confused
right we want high THC and we want High
turps well can't do that right you can't
have the floral the candy those are gpp
based Tarpin gpp makes THC right so you
have a competition there right so this
is why the high THC varieties tend to be
more CES turpy heavy because that's a
different precursor fpp right that is
not in competition to make
THC so it's it's as an industry we're
confused we want things that you can't
necessarily have because the plant
doesn't work that way the American dream
it's like I always want stuff we can't
have
yeah and I think with education I think
these things will change but also like
when we're doing feno hunting and we're
going through the selection process I
try to give people joints now because I
want to know what their I know what the
it looks like and I'm great at doing the
selections but let's talk about the
taste and the effect right and I think
it just kind of puts everybody on the
same page instead of giving people bags
of flour my friends bags of flour or
guys were working with bags of flour to
look at and they can try it however they
want if you give them a joint it's
pre-rolled everybody's getting the same
thing yeah no yeah and then they don't
they don't get to look at the color I
can I can identify if the color is the
the right color or not or well you know
what's interesting though
so God I I I wish I wish I could sit you
in front of all of the people that were
naying me before right so I'm like why
do you guys need to see see a COA right
like why can't you
guys take it smoke it and then make it a
termination without seeing a number did
you like it did
do you right did it did you have the
right
experience and if if it passes that all
those tests what the [ __ ] do we care
what percent T was back in the day I
when I was 12 and 13 years old you know
even 15 and 16 years old smoking Panama
Red akaba Gold because that was the [ __ ]
back in the day right like dude none of
that stuff ever tested more than
12% maybe
14% right well yeah but even even Sour
Diesel when I had it tested at Halen in
2012 I had the highest testing outdoor
sour d so I still have the COA but it
was only like
24% was the top that was like the top
that
year so yeah people you know and it was
amazing stuff and then Sour Diesel only
tests it
14% the stuff we were growing back in
the day right right so so clearly we
didn't need astronomical THC numbers to
get a good experience out of cannabis
right we didn't right and and and the
nature of cannabis is changed right so
you know you had you if you you know
it's been a long time and I'm sure you
know some of this is rose-colored memory
right so um but you know you open up a
bag and and there of good weed and there
was a deep complex fragrance right you
don't get that anymore you get like a
couple of notes because literally you've
only got a a handful of tping
of which one or two of significant
content right like you know what when
when when when the majority of weed is
only one and a half 1.2 to
1.8% tpine content and we consider top
shelf two and a half% tpin well dude
right 2019 what was it the gree monkey
had 5% tpin right I I had I had stuff
from Outdoors this year that hit three
and a half%
tpes like you know so what what are we
doing to ourselves right but whatever so
yeah I don't need to derail the
conversation oh that's okay yeah it's a
it's a real interesting world we live in
you know and I think yeah like I was
saying about the education and and I
think market demand changes over time
but yeah I remember stuff back the the
best stuff we had in the 90s was the
ugliest it was the cat piss we had this
cat piss and the cat piss looked like it
was basically br a in a bag and there
there might be some stems in there but
it was sticky and it the one little gram
of it would smell your whole house up
right you don't get that anymore and you
know it was $60 an e back then straight
up there was no discounts on it it it
was hard to get it would sell out and
you wouldn't be able to get it for a few
months
yep well you know whatting about that is
that that brings up another point right
so we talk about nose we talk about bag
appeal right
yeah you know things like cat
baby [ __ ] right like so those are
the as far as we go in terms of the
almost but not quite borderline
unacceptable fragrance in our weed right
totally dude body odor you know all
these things they're foul to a lot of
people but then if as a connoisseur you
like that kind of stuff well there are
40,000 [ __ ] tpes dude and some of
them smell really bad some of them smell
like vomit some I mean like right so so
and and and so I'm just left thinking
about through all of the you know
because we we found you know high THC
cannabis Going Back 2 200 years in some
ancient Chinese Emperor's tomb right
okay great so um so when did the
selection against really bad smelling
cannabis start that's what I want to
know right because
there's nothing that smells really bad
in cannabis but there are all sorts of
genes for Turpin that you would expect
to find right in potentially in cannabis
that you know we have some borderline
smells right there's like the cheese
which kind of you know depending on what
it's combined with smells like dirty
feet right which is you know border and
we still see these Expressions I me we C
them out you know but we're still seeing
some funky stuff in there I mean even
these Menthol ones I don't I don't
particular like Menthol you know
expressions in my flower but you know I
think there's an interesting side to
that too so that's funny a couple years
back I so I I I had a cut of meno breath
that
um oh no no it was called tach Tre turp
was it was a stram from orgon but it was
from the it was from the meno breath
line right um dude it was straight up
[ __ ] benay like literally like the
like you broke open the buds and it was
like you were benay right and it was the
weirdest smoke because it gave you kind
of like this almost like Menthol flavor
in your lungs right it was the weirdest
yeah know but but but it it's cool
because you know the important thing
about tpin right is that is that they
they kind of set the body up for the
experience right so right right so so
the the tpping profiles are really
important much more important than I
think people really understand sometimes
right so like certain tpin like certain
tpin are actually having physiological
effect in your biochemistry right like
Alpha pining is an a inhibitor right
which is which leads to increased Focus
increased energy right so so literally
there are these there is a biological
reason why the turpins do affect you the
way they do and if we understood that
better right like we'd be so much more
in tune with what turpins do we have
then how much THC do we have right
because you can have high THC we with
very low tur
and feel the same as lower THC weed with
higher tpes right so
right yeah it's pretty wild and then
jumping into that it's like the
conversation with indica and sativa and
I feel like stimulant versus sedative is
a much better description these days
because everything's so hybridized yep y
y you know at one point it made a
difference right at one point you
generally found sativas tall and lanky
always had a kind of more uplifting
cognitive thing and then the short stop
hocky ones generally where made you
couch lock and kind of right you know
Stone right so not the case anymore as
soon as as soon people started putting
the tall and the short ones together and
making babies all went out the window
there dude so so yeah we got one that
looks like Bubba cush but it smells like
uh Jack herrer oh nice so that's that's
a turpine dominant then so that's pretty
cool totally yeah tpine it's got a lot
of loning and terpinolene Beauty so but
but it looks like a it looks like a
indicia like if you were to take a
picture of it and put it in a book
people would think it was some afghanica
Inda yeah variety so so you know what's
interesting about this is that you know
and there are there are kind of like
vestigial organs you know like the ones
you don't use anymore there are actually
a few vestigial tpine families right
that uh we found through some of our
work which are very interesting that are
are like the sativa Gene right like so
literally it's a
terpinolene gene that has this set of
minor Turpin that are made out of the
same gene that are all strictly sativa
three carine Alpha fandr all these
things that are hard sativa kind of
Turpin right and like we found this one
terpinolene gene that made all of them
so it's literally like well yeah so we
actually can select for a
sativa you know kind of phenotype if we
if we have this Gene we know it's going
to be that type of phen right so it's
it's that level of of understanding that
allows us to do really really
hardcore predictive breed for effect
kind of cannabis now think about that
right so now we're not just pheno
hunting right we're setting up crosses
with a purpose because we have we we
have known genes that are doing known
functions and we want to carry that
through to be able to achieve an effect
right that's that changes the nature of
what we do right if you think about it
yeah well I mean you can select for it
or you can not select for it because
you've identified it right exactly so so
it allows people to actually start to
have more confidence when they pick up
that pre-roll that says chill or energy
you know with that depth of information
the people who can now offer those
things that will be 100% spoton And and
people the majority of people who you
know with the right ECS conditions right
so because there are there I I have I
have a few friends that can convince me
that they are wired backwards like stuff
that makes everybody else jump up and
down puts them to sleep stuff that
because everybody else asleep makes them
jump up and down right so I'm not sure
how that happens you know what what got
what got messed up in those people's you
know endoc can aboid system but but for
the most part right you can you can say
85% or better of the population will
respond this way and if you were to
question those people you'd be able to
get responses that indicated that so and
we're close to that right and that's
where we start to cross over from just
cannabis as a
potential you know healing agent to a
yeah I can treat myself for various
things conditions whatever because I
understand how this thing plays in my
biochemistry right you know antios
reception pain relief there are certain
chemicals in cannabis that that do that
job right we know what they are
so it's cool I can't wait to see where
we are in five years so yeah I mean
we're getting closer Israel is so you
know they're they're further ahead with
us in a lot of ways but I think we're
definitely catching up well they're
definitely ahead on the medical side
right so I think in terms of variety
creation and and and just the the newno
you know like the new hot [ __ ] I think
we still have an edge there absolutely
yeah there's nothing that compares to
what we're doing here and there's just
so many people you know breeding and
making I don't know if you could even
call it breeding but they're doing seed
production breeding whatever they're
making new genetics all over the place
you know on so many levels from the guy
who's doing it at home and it's not like
that over in Israel but as far as like
drug discovery on the medical side you
know ddy muy the stuff he's doing over
there it's it's it's pretty impressive
yeah I I've have yet to have a
conversation literally where daddy's
name has not come
up yeah I mean I love the guy right so
he's an awesome guy so um it does great
work and but but but literally that he
is the epitome of making something like
you know applied academic research work
dude I met
ddy at this first canite right and
that's when you know he and I became
friends since then right so and took me
through his lab dude this is 2013 2014
maybe right like he already had cell
lines immortalized cell lines then he
was already using you know extracts from
different varieties and dude I mean like
it you
know it's it's well planned wellth
thought out science in a regime where
yes let's consider this as a medicine
and see what we can do right that's as
opposed to there's just so much red tape
less less red tape over in Israel than
there is here it's just you know and you
know we're still having politicians
argue whether it could be medical or not
which is
[Laughter]
yeah so let's talk about autoflowers a
little bit you've done some work with
autoflowers over the years and are you
guys working on autoflowers now and tell
us a little bit about it so we we we did
um um it it was our main focus um it it
served two purposes it served for us to
be able to um develop a mapping
population and so that we could start to
map that Autoflower Gene right so our
flowering time genes in general right so
we we've had a marker for a couple years
right you know and it was actually I
ironically we never published on it
because we drug dragged our feet we were
out to do more work and now that we got
scooped on it and we're gonna have to do
more work to be able to publish what we
had in the first place so uh but but
yeah so the the Ft Gene that that people
are talking about now you know we had a
marker for it probably about two years
ago where doing more more work with that
marker to kind of see what what Al
variants there are you know and and and
to kind you know I think we what where
we didn't see far enough was we didn't
anticipate that there might be a tandm
duplication like these guys found so so
so now we know that there's you know
there's potentially a a gene copy number
component to flowering time strains that
only have one copy are longer flowering
strains that have two copy are fast flow
potentially
autoflow so we tried to a while back
use uh combined Autoflower and Vons and
um I made a bad choice in one of the
parents so us ho Jo is in fact
Autoflower however it's a shitty plant
to work with it set me back over a year
like literally it set us back like a
year so um we went back and we were
trying we were trying to make Autoflower
cbdv basically right so um and yeah
there's a couple people working on that
I think Nick strongberg was doing some
stuff and yeah yeah yeah yeah so Nick
goes back to Steve Hill so so Nick we
helped Nick way back
um um because at the time the only way
to detect tcv was was Through Chemistry
and we were the first lab to be able to
detect thcv actually Steve pill so so we
wored with ni ni Nick and I go back a
long way Nick goes back a long way with
Steve Hill so he you know in fact in
fact at one point I think he may have
worked with either halent or us I'm not
sure but he had free Rand you know he
used to come in and run samples on our
machines so yeah yeah yeah he wor I mean
he got his degree from Davis so yeah so
makes sense yeah there were a lot of
people interested in it back then right
so so we we all had a connection to Doug
Janks who who was the guy who developed
um you know Doug zon right so which was
that that the the real first I
think talked about high fairly high tcv
and even back then it wasn't that high
it was making like four to 7% but you
know it was a one to one so it was
making about four to 7% THC as well
right so
um um it it was it was a blast of smoke
tasted like crap but dude would hit you
hard man yeah I got some uh some extract
that was pure thcv that was pretty
interesting oh really it's you hard yeah
yeah yeah from from Nick actually oh
really so yeah it's interesting where
all these uh cannaboids are going to go
in the future
there's there's dude there's so many so
CBC has no you know
uses uh the varens you know with the
with because it's not only like the
thepress right but but they've already
got um I think it's in mice models or
rat models where they showed like
diabetes type two like in a in a mouse
model that that t administration of thcv
helps you know regulate blood sugar and
some other stuff so so dude there's a
lot of work that can be done with canabo
right we just need as a country to get
off our [ __ ] asses and and and accept
the fact that this is not the demon that
was made out to be it has a lot of good
uses uh and and and free the plant and
let us do some research right so um
totally yeah so where do you see the
industry going in the future you know
over the next five years I mean you have
a pretty great perspective from from the
stuff you're working on as far as
genetics you know I I I thought I did
but I but I I I don't dude dude I don't
I James let me tell you like I had a
conversation with the CEO of my company
yesterday and not saying what the hell
do we need to do to get people to buy
our weed right so
um so you know the industry is a Fickle
Beast um but I I think where everybody
everybody has to go right because at the
end of the day this is farming I you
know I know nobody likes when I say that
right but this is agriculture right so
so an agriculture becomes commoditized
right so so at the end of the day down
the line people are going to be
concerned about their cost to produce
right because they're going to be
squeezed on margins clones are not the
way that happens dude clones are the
most expensive way to cultivate cannabis
that you can do and this is why no big
cash crop well I take that back roses
and some other ornamentals right but for
the most part most things that are grown
Outdoors or most things that are
grown in large green houses right are
not with the exception of things like
coffee
because every single coffee tree has a
very different flavor profile right so
but but for the most part your your
you're growing stuff from seeds you may
not plant the seed yourself you may buy
your germinated seeds and little things
right that right but but the cost the
cost to produce seed is far cheaper than
the cost to produce clones right so
where everybody will have to go is to
stabilize seed because nobody's going to
want to throw out a thousand seed and
get you know 50 different varieties
right yeah nobody wants that so so so
further inbred stabilization right so
gentically stable seats yep right which
can which with the the use of snip chips
that are being offered by my company and
other companies with you know Mark
assisted breeding you can make do some
real damage and you can get some very
directed kind of Corral germ plasm
populations to work with right and and
and have a much better chance of
achieving things that you want and and
so now the work begins you either are
going into an inbreeding program so that
you can now create F1 hybrids that are
have the full you know hybrid Viger that
we see now when we throw things together
and say oh my God that thing's [ __ ] a
huge producer well yeah you just did the
hybrid Viger thing right so
um um and so I I think that's one of the
things but I think the other thing we're
gonna have to see is is you know dark
heart was doing it Oregon CBD was doing
it manipulation inace Floy right so yeah
um where you're starting to make
triploids so that people can't steal
your [ __ ] but more importantly right and
then I'll get to triploids in in a
minute and why I think some companies
who ran into it early did it wrong right
so um agreed but then also the whole
double haid reading thing right because
you we we are not in a spot where we can
take eight to 12 years to stabilize you
know to to get to an f8
F9 you know right so that we have you
know greater than 90% of the seed
looking the same when you when you throw
them out in the field right so so double
haid reading gets us you know cuts that
down to a year and a half two years
right you know and that includes
actually trud type testing the fact make
you have the right things right yeah um
I think that's where everybody has to go
otherwi otherwise right you know more
and more people will fail because
they're paying cutting fees on their
Clon on their moms or they're having
huge mother rooms so that they can have
get enough cuts to be able to run that
1,400 you know plants in that bay that
time right so uh or they're paying you
know uh a lot of money to companies like
node and conception and you know for for
clones you know eight1 clone whatever
yeah I mean right so you know so double
haid you want to talk about double haid
a little bit sure yeah for for the
viewers that aren't familiar sure so
double haid breeding is where you take
it's called anther culture right so you
take so you take whatever variety and
then if it's not a male already you you
make it you make it produce anwers right
so you take that answer and you those
anwers and you culture them you know on
Aug or like tissue culture and you get
callus and then from there um you know
so now you got to remember that anthers
the sex parts are hloy they're not
diploid in the cell right so um so you
you you then take that callus and you do
somatic embryogenesis and so you get a
regenerate from that just like you would
from regular tissue culture callus right
um except that because it came from
anther and not from a diploid tissue
it's a haid tissue so you get a haid
plant right so you can then take that
haid plant right and cross it back to
itself right that you know or or or
cross to some other haploid plant right
if you don't if you don't cross it back
to yourself then you're not really
making the double haid right so you're
you're just out Crossing in a different
way but um but you cross it back to
itself and then what you end up with is
a plant that is 100 100% homozygous at
every low side right so what happens to
that plant well that plant looks nothing
like the plant you took it from right so
because it's now 100% homozygous at
every at every low side the plant that
you were
using to you know was not 100%
homozygous at every low size so now what
you got to do is you got to go through
and you got to find the
combinations because you're not just
doing it with one plant right and then
now that you've got these 100%
homozygous lines that You' created from
this culture and remember every
anther is the rule of independent
assignment right so it's not like you
get one genotype out of an anther right
so because the so so there's still a lot
of phenotyping the the markers justed
you know kind of you know selection to
make sure you have the right things but
once you then breed those two 100%
homozygous things together you end up
with the best version of an F1 hybrid
right so because it's it and and you see
the kind of hybrid bigger that people
refer to when they say F1 hybrids right
so what we typically do in cannabis is
not really a true F1 hybrid a true F1
hybrid is is is from inbred lines right
right so totally stable stable lines
right right so so so that's what what
Double H breeding allows you to do it
allows you to cut that inbred line
development which takes a long time into
a very short period of time right but
there's still a lot of evaluation that
has to happen right because part of the
in red line process is picking the best
ones as you go down to to continue doing
the breeding with right so now that
you've created this population of hloy
genomes right that you're going to now
make diploid by mating to itself right
you now have to look at well what
combinations did I get and how do I put
those together to make good seed right
but that seed that comes out is 100 %
identical everything in that population
from that next cross is 100% identical
and so now you get you throw you throw
your thousand seat out there and
999 at the very least are looking the
same and that's where we need to get to
to be able to really drive the price
down because when you you get to that
point you know even if it's topnotch
seed right you're going to be you know
in bulk you're going to be paying a
couple three bucks a SE as opposed to
eight 10 12 bucks a cut right so yeah so
and then what are your thoughts on AI
for predictive models and stuff like
that so AI is good if you have good
input data right so so they they tried
to do a lot of AI modeling with tpin and
I think they haven't had a lot of
success they've had some success but not
a lot because garbage in equals garbage
out right so unless you have very well
curated tping data and not everybody
does the same job and all and the same
thing for all that stuff right so so AI
has potential use assuming you have good
input data right and I think the way
things have been going in the industry
with elevated numbers and so on and so
forth I don't think there's good data to
be able to really to to do any good AI
modeling right I who have in my my own
data for my own work um which is very
well curated I have a data scientist
whose job is nothing but to tell me what
is my good data and my Shady data right
and even he is not at the point where he
thinks we have data that's sufficient
for AI modeling without heavy
handholding of the model so uh so so I I
think it's I think it will get there at
some point you either need a good amount
of really outstanding data or you need
[ __ ] tons of poor data or or mediocre
data right and and and to be able to to
to work through all of the the the the
falsehoods right so so and I and I don't
think there's and there may be enough
data like if every lab in the world got
together and dumped all their [ __ ] into
a big repository and set some AI engine
on it it'd probably do a decent job
right but I but but but we're not at
that level of cooperation where
everybody's just dumping all their data
into single repository yet so yes it's
it's it's interesting I mean we're we're
just starting to scratch the surface
with some of this stuff and yeah as I
was descri describing double haid
reading before I I kind of badmouth
triploid stuff so it's funny because you
know a lot of
people went and did triploids they
thought it was the thing to do well
because now you you know you know you
won't get seen
well if your [ __ ] didn't Herm you
wouldn't need triploids to take care of
that problem right so there right so
there your neighbor sh didn't H them too
you know and and traditionally triploids
are used at the end of a breeding cycle
right so and because now you've done all
this work you have your inbred lines
right you you know what your F1 hybrid
seed's going to look like so now you
take one of those parents and you make
it a
quadrio you breed it to the diploid
equip diploid version of it and you have
a triploid seed that exhibits the exact
phenotypic stuff that you needed to
exhibit right yeah so I don't think
anybody had weed of any kind CBD or THC
dominant that was at that end of the
cycle
breeding kind of path you know what I'm
saying right makes perfect sense so so
so it was really used to solve a
problem right that could have been
solved other ways so that's that's my
opinion yeah I don't think we're quite
there with the the triploids yet but
yeah I mean like the concept is great it
works great for watermelons yeah well
and it's it's a great example right so
so when you make triploids right not so
you know either have complete triploids
or or or partial triploids right like
like for instance you know Mac one right
uh is is a partial triploid so so and
boy was that hard I tried to agree with
that and I could never figure out till I
figured out that it was a partial trip
I'm like God damn it why why are 95% of
all my seed in mature [ __ ] Duds like
I I would I would Harvest like a
thousand seed and like 50 would be good
would be mature right yeah sfv is like
that
too yeah sfv cultivar yeah yeah so
when you look at fruit that's been
tripled right y like you have to be
careful like not every triploid is going
to be increased Mass better sweetness
right like you you really have to make
sure that the triploid combination that
you have is giving you something that
you want right like you know so
otherwise you just have a triploid and
and and that's not making seed but is it
really a better plant right like I mean
the the reason you use triploid is to
get something extra right
yeah so increased Vigor increased yield
increased flavor no seed exactly right
the no seed part is important yeah but
if that's all you're using it for then
you're kind of wasting the technology
right so right
so yeah they'll be there eventually yeah
there's probably enough people working
on it well we have to right so if if we
want to survive you know I mean I hate I
would hate to see this become the future
of the Cannabis industry right but yeah
you know I'm I'm sure you've heard
people talk about how there's going to
be this split in the industry you're
gonna have like the small craft beer guy
and you're gonna have the big box beer
guy right like that already
happening you think it's happened to age
degree already I think so and I I mean I
personally think so and I I kind of like
to see it going that way with uh Terre
and stuff like that if we're talking
about humbled and Menino these guys with
their specific genetics that they grow
that are specific to that region and
make it more like wine and beer I mean I
like that
model so yes so so as long as that model
is well regulated right because just
because right you know you you can't
take some dirt from Humble go to La and
grow it in LA and say oh this is humble
grown no it's not because now
temperature is different humidity is
different you know insulation is
different right like you know so so
remember this was few years ago they
were talking about this stuff and they
wanted you know for sure that they
wanted to have the Terre map of of the
humble you know the the Emerald Triangle
up there and you know they had asked me
to to consult on that whole program you
know um when I was with
ncia and I was like H you guys don't
want me to consult because I'm I'm gonna
ruin everybody's party dude because you
guys want you you guys want to be able
to say oh yeah it's this variety you
know grown under licensed by this guy
and I'm like well that's not that's not
Terre that has nothing to do with it
dude that I mean terar means you grow it
in that spot this is your region and you
can't grow it outside that region right
because if you grow it outside that
region it changes it right so so yeah so
anyway um you know because terar is very
it's so complicated dude it's it's it's
soil microbes it's mineral content it's
it's it's so many things humidity
elevation all these things come into
play for sure so um the idea is a great
idea it's a great idea if it's done
right if they do it like they do
provinces in France for wine right like
like literally you can grow the same
grape in and two provinces that are next
to each other in fact one there is this
is actually what happens there's a wine
called make vage and another um wine
called Pui right and literally it's the
same grape the two places are next to
each other on the
map yep right but because they have a
line down the middle and there is a
slight difference in the I think it's
the acidity or some mineral content um
you know this county has more of one
thing than this County does literally
right different wies can't call them the
same so yeah and Canabis will do the
same thing if you had the same growing
techniques in two regions right next to
each other one that was up a little
higher or lower you're going to get
different expressions and so this leads
to something else right why brand
names need to go and I know nobody's
gonna like to hear that right so
absolutely right but but it's based on
what you just said the chemistry right
so you take blue dream and you grow it
up in Humble and you grow it in LA do
you expect to have the same chemical
output no right because it's phenotype
is equal to genotype plus environment
right right so literally blue dream may
not look like blue dream if it's grown
in two different places right so you
yeah you'll get a different
expression yeah well and then besides
that it's like so these guys are selling
packs of seeds right the these retailers
including myself but you're you're
selling a pack of seeds and somebody
pops one and they call it blue dream and
then someone pops another one from that
same pack they also call it Blue Dream
you're getting a different expression
blue dream's a bad example because it's
a little more stabilized but like a lot
of this gelato you know CU Blue Dream
you get basically with the s1's you're
getting for Expressions that's pretty
much it they lean towards one of these
four Expressions but with something like
gelato 33 you put it you know you self
gelato 33 you pop 10 seeds you get 10
different Expressions hell yeah dude you
pop 20 seeds you're probably gonna get
20 different
Expressions so and that's and that's the
problem right so everybody you know so
don't get wrong I don't say it's a
problem but it's a challenge right but
it's also what leads
to such amazing diversity that we see
everybody's always got every year
there's always something new coming out
right so yeah so so it it helps us in a
way right but we we we have to be
careful about whether or not we're over
hybridizing everything right and we'll
eventually lose distinctions right so
how H how many Bakery products do we
need right like you know
all ice creams do we need right and
they're and and they're all made by
banging the same plants together right
and so that's where we start to have
problems with you know genetics and and
who knows right some of these we're not
we don't study this kind of stuff
because nobody really studies anything
to any depth in gene in cannabis because
we you know to bus trying to make money
right so um but how much inbreeding
depression have we already
seen right and it's contributing to some
of these hard to grow strains and and
hard to work with strains because right
literally we have been banging the same
[ __ ] together over and over and over and
over again right so right things like
hop plate and verid you know I think
yeah hop plate and verid has been a hot
topic for the last couple years but
especially now it's like it's decimating
some people and it's you know it might
Express on a branch it might Express on
a plant or a row or a whole room yeah
but uh you know and that's a problem but
I mean I think and correct me if I'm
wrong wrong but uh you know with with
all this genetic depression that's going
on from inbreeding a lot of people don't
think they're inbreeding they're
Crossing this with that but then the
plant's more susceptible to things like
hlate and viroid and different pests and
other pathogens there's some evidence
that different cannabis lineages have
different levels of resistance to Hops
and viid right so yeah I don't think
anybody's got a real handle on it but
you know what we we've done a lot of
work with it and we've we've actually
you know point when we were a hem
company we we we were running a a
cleaning program we would you know we
had some of our varieties that we were
working with um we put them into our
tissue culture program and and actually
ran you know some thermal
cleanings and and were able to
show significant decreases in the level
of hops slate and vroid after one
cleaning like one of the pl one of the
lines was 75% reduced one was 60%
another one was like 40% and there were
some lines you could not clean at all at
all right so so clearly there are
genetic differences that if we
understood better we could in fact work
with to produce more resistant plants
now whether that resistance is due to
like a a pathogen kind of gene or
whether it's because it's producing
certain Turpin or not right and remember
Turpin are in fact kind of like the
plant's immune system right so it's
definitely an Avenue that we we should
be looking at now the way you're saying
it is is are we seeing less resistance
to hplvd because we have been doing all
this damage to the genetics through in
breeding and depression that's a great
question and I don't know if anybody's
ever thought of it that way right but
the more we've started to focus on the
gelato or the gorilla glues and the
cookie ke and breeding those lines
suddenly we're seeing this increase in
hplvd it's it's almost like it's
occurring at the same time so while I
don't know for sure that there's any
support for that it certainly fits the
available observation right so there's
definitely seems to be a correlation
between you know there's been a much
bigger Spike but you could also
potentially attribute that much bigger
Spike to the now it's legal in so many
states dude I so when when my company
licensed panaka from hemp trading in
Spain the first thing we did when we got
the cuts was run hplvd test on it they
came to us from Spain with hpbd wow yeah
and it's transmissible through clones
and even seeds I mean they're they're
proving that you know now that it's
transmissible through seed as well yeah
so so did they change that number I
haven't read up by that recently but the
last time I heard it was like 8 to 10%
transmission is is it still that low or
they people that's what I've heard is
I've heard 8 to 10% yeah yeah yeah so
yeah which is still a good percent right
like so that means what if you if you're
dealing with two infected plants that
means one out of every 10 seeds has the
potential to start bad right like that's
that's not good so yeah and I mean I
think a lot of people aren't testing for
it either and they're just assuming and
you know ignoring it and something that
needs to be identified and you know I
think that's another thing with
awareness you know people you know they
start seeing and the thing is is a lot
of these cultivators they see it on one
branch right so you see it on one you
get a dted branch no big deal then you
start seeing dted plants and you have to
co those but you know and it can it's
funny because unless you're using bleach
to sterilize your tools if you have it
in your room you're just going to spread
it everywhere yeah you know even with
with irrigation if you're if it's
passing through the water from one plant
to the next you could spread it that way
so yep so you know and then and what was
it Kevin from genomics just like two
days ago had the paper that leaf Hoppers
are carriers right so they they gra some
Leaf Hoppers and found the virus the
viroid in in the leaf Hopper right so so
and so think about this though right so
the main mode of transmission previously
was mechanical right you snip a plant
you don't wash them good you snip
another plant bang right well who's
washing the mandal parts of the insects
eat biting our plants right so now you
you you you find it on Leaf ho you find
it in leaf Hoppers right well what about
all the other plants that happily munch
on cannabis right it's not a virus right
it's not like it has to go in and infect
and then get protein coat and then lice
the cell right it's literally an RNA an
infectious RNA it gets in if it you know
through some sort of mechanical
transmission so if a bug is on a dirty
plant and hops to a clean plant and
bites that clean plant why wouldn't its
mandibles or or prascus or whatever it's
sticking in the plant to eat right why
wouldn't it potentially have the same
ability to transfer that the scissors
that we're using to cut do right like
and before there was no Bonafide insect
you know transmitter now we know that at
least there's one right so now it's time
to keep our eyes open I grow I grow I
grow at tourist dude I find I find
crickets like huge crickets like happily
muching all my cannabis right so oh yeah
you know can cricket carry it too like
if it bites a bad plant will it transmit
to a good plant so yeah well and I think
if you have a tissue culture lab if
you're if you're blessed enough to be a
cultivator that has a tissue culture lab
and you can keep clean germ plasm you
know it's it's going to make a huge
difference moving forward yeah I work
with apical biotech I'm not sure if
you're familiar with them with who
apical biotech from Justin from apical
biotch and they they do remediation and
they do a really good job with it and
you know they have they have tests that
prove that they're actually remediating
with Mir stem excision so there's so
much misinformation disinformation and
lack of information right and we need to
change that so drastically so
drastically um you know in order to you
know we we want to be legitimate right
we we want to be a self-sustaining
industry that doesn't have every year
more and more people dropping out
because they're losing their shirts
because something with regulations or
something with you know uh Finance or
whatever is is is kicking their ass dude
so yeah I'm I'm speaking from personal
experience right now
so yeah the industry is wild we the Wild
Wild West still but but it's evolving
and it's it's growing in some ways and
you know I think it's stabilizing in
other ways which I think is really
great so yeah no once again let's
celebrate that that one step closer to
Safe banking dude that that's gonna make
so much difference so much difference
yeah so we went we went back a couple
years back and we started doing a bunch
of land R stuff like pack said J
Kush so dude let me tell you the stuff
that we started to get out of that the
tpine profiles and just just amazing
stuff so um you know there's something
to be said for the old school genetics
man you know land races old school
genetics there there's some power back
there still so well now with like
Thailand opening up and Asia opening up
there's a whole
new uh group of tping that we can start
going after and and flavor profiles if
you talk about you know green tea ice
cream or Fried Chicken Fried Chicken
most people don't want to smoke stuff
that smells like fried chicken but you
you take it over there and they like
Savory more than sweet I think Y and so
you know South Korea goes online we're
gonna have some kimchi swing cannabis
it's going to be
amazing that'll be awesome dude you know
so there's been such a bottleneck in
yeah in US genetics right like like if
you know I I'm I'm geeky this way so I I
started to create a chart I was using
the the seedfinder.eu
docomo um yeah so I started to go back
and and I start to make a chart of like
all of the crosses of the stuff that
that was popular today right you know GG
and right so when these are just said
crosses I think a lot of people I think
a lot people take the data on seedfinder
as fact and I know for a fact a lot of
it is incorrect just because somebody
says it's one thing doesn't necessarily
mean and still there's a lot of
information there but but when you go
when you take a lot of the of the of the
current genetics and you start to go
back to grandparents great-grandparents
dude we're all at the same [ __ ] [ __ ]
like literally it all came from like six
or eight different varieties created
like like the thousands of varieties we
have today like you know it's it's the
um Durban was one of them you know so so
the the Durban self was was one was a
big parent the Afghan that went into the
early cookies like literally dude like
like cush yeah yeah it's it's there's a
lot there's a lot of similarity in what
we do these days then it goes back to so
so Reggie if people want to find out
more about you what you're doing where
can they find you online oh um so it's
uh it's argadin Front Range bio.com
um I I was told that our our website no
longer works so don't go to our website
um yeah but just uh yeah so just Argo r
g d i n o frontrange bio.com and I'm
happy to answer questions if anybody any
questions I mean I get back to you the
same day but I always get back to people
who ask me questions so awesome you have
an Instagram or social media or
that I try to avoid it like a plague but
I do have an Instagram it's Dr Reggie
Gino nice all all one word so and
there's not much on there um but I I do
have some pictures of of uh my last
breeding Harvest uh which where I went I
found a really amazing cut of strawberry
OG it was like this really sweet
kerosene and uh and I went nuts with
that sucker dude I read it to
everything that's awesome so I have yeah
when you find a good one that's the best
way to approach it um and so yeah so so
I have a few pictures and some stuff
some of the stuff that comes out of FB
because I'm not a big Instagram I'm not
a big social media guy so what when I am
when I am reminded by the company to put
[ __ ] on my Instagram I do so there's a
few things of some of our relatest stuff
but um yeah that's where where you can
find me awesome well thank you very much
and have a wonderful day thanks take
care guys
Che
[Music]
cruising