foreign
[Music]
how's it going everyone welcome to the
third episode of the James Lab podcast
today we got a special guest his name is
Chris professional joint roller at
Instagram how you doing today great how
are you good how are you doing I'm
fantastic man I'm glad to have you on
here thanks for having me yeah so it's
it's kind of interesting how you came to
be on the show I saw your Instagram and
I saw these badass joints and I'm like
oh man I want to get this guy on my show
and the last guest I had Chris Castle
you actually worked with him so when he
came on the show he brought some of your
joints oh awesome so oh is that poison
gushers what are we smoking on the
poison gushers and I was hand rolled
from professional joint roller does some
super super super great work
so it was just kind of meant to be that
you'd be on the show of course yeah yeah
we've been working together now for a
couple months uh he hit me up through
Instagram and uh yeah I've been working
with his material now for what now five
six weeks what do you think of his fire
he's got some good material there I I
like the jungle cake I'm sort of partial
to that strain it's super strong so that
jungle cake is super super yeah I like
the poison gushers because it's Unique
oh definitely uh you know the the Goji
the pine salt yeah the pine sauce fire
and it's like it's got the gas
characteristics if you don't mind green
weed yeah amazing that is the thing
these days right the green wheat it
scares people for some reason it's like
not not all people yeah people that know
what's up I mean people that have
smoking a long time still love green
flower but I think a lot of the market
demands purple candy gas yeah they want
Lemon Cherry gelato runs yeah uh you
know even the Skittles now has color of
course yeah yeah well everyone's just
crossing it to make it look prettier
because it's always been like that
strain that has zero bag appeal but
everyone that smokes it sort of knows
what to look for yeah but I mean
honestly I'm just happy that I'm in a
place where I can choose what I want to
smoke like like we were talking about
earlier I came from the east coast and
we didn't really have options of what
flavor of weed we wanted it was like do
you want OG or do you want whatever [ __ ]
this dude just made up like and it's all
mids like none of it's good weed when
you come out and actually see what's
available on the west coast and
specifically the Bay Area so how long
have you been smoking for I've been
smoking since what is it like right
after I graduated high school basically
and so it's kind of like a weird thing
for me I I basically grew up in a more
sort of traditional conservative
household and no one in my family had
really smoked weed so it was always
looked down upon and I remember in high
school like when I found out my friends
were making the the Sobe bottle bongs I
was super like distraught because I was
like they're throwing their lives away
like these are my friends who I've
looked up to but like now they're
smoking weed like and I didn't really
know how to deal with it and so after a
while I realized oh it's not that big of
a deal like they're just sort of happy
and hungry around me I don't really care
so I was always just sort of that kid
who was around the friends who smoked
but never really partook and then
finally like the senior summer one of my
friends we were we were a little bit
drunk and he was like hey like I'll put
a star next to your name of the people
who I've smoked with and I was like well
[ __ ] it like let's do it and so I went
up I we smoked a little bowl and then of
course as things do with weed like
literally 30 seconds after I hit his
bowl my friend's brother who was inside
was like oh Wilbur's smoking like you're
hitting my big bong so I went
immediately upstairs and hit his like
two and a half foot bong nice and so I
was just completely floored but at the
same time I was like this isn't all what
I expected like I expected to be
completely out of my mind like I was
feeling fantastic totally and I was like
this is what I want like I don't like
the feeling I get with alcohol as much
but this is what I've been looking for
and pretty much since then I was like I
gotta kind of like control myself with
this because I can feel how much I enjoy
cannabis and I know probably shouldn't
be smoking at this age so like I kind of
weaned myself into it where I was like I
won't smoke for like a couple weeks so
it only spoke like once every few weeks
and then of course like I went to
college all my friends in college smoked
because I was playing D3 lacrosse wow
and I don't know if you know what this
but like the lacrosse Community I would
say probably 90 to 9 95 percent of
lacrosse players smoke weed it's just
like basketball players exactly and so
we we all just like in football players
and baseball players and that's what
that's what we're finding out now is
that everyone's doing this stuff I was
listening to a podcast the other week in
an ex-nfl uh D lineman was micro dosing
mushrooms during games oh I believe it
and I'm like now now looking back at him
like it makes sense yeah I mean Nate
Diaz and Nick Diaz these guys they would
you know those guys have been smoking
weed publicly yeah and now it comes out
that everybody's kind of been doing it
all along yeah yeah for the most part
it's a trip and and there there really
is that sort of
I don't know not performance enhancing
maybe but it really helps you focus the
mind more like sure whether it's whether
it's weed or like micro dosing mushrooms
it's a similar experience where you're
sort of hyper focused on one specific
task and you can really get into that
groove of sort of grinding whatever that
specific thing is right and I mean for
me that was like I would wake up we had
an early morning lacrosse practices and
I would smoke before practice just to
sort of wake up and get my body going
totally I used to smoke and go to the
gym it's the same thing [ __ ] Jiu
Jitsu yeah exactly for me it takes my
mind out of it so I don't have to think
about it I just do it I think that is
the beauty of it uh you know if you're
gonna go get on a treadmill you'll start
doing cardio the best way is to actually
smoke a little bit and keep your mind
completely out of it yeah you know it's
a personal preference and maybe it's not
for everybody but man it definitely has
helped me along the way oh absolutely
and I would say it's definitely not for
everyone like I have best friends of
mine who like I'll will be out on the
golf course and I'll be two and a half
joints in and I'll say hey do you want
to hit and it'll be like nah dude if I
take one hit I'll be done for the day
yeah and like I mean maybe some people
paranoia and I think it's because of
the genetics I mean I I think that maybe
if they smoke the right type of [ __ ]
flower yeah or edible or whatever it is
you know so I think Edibles is what
ruined it for a lot of people 100 my
sister herself she was I'd always talked
to her about it like how I smoke and all
this stuff and she's like oh yeah I
tried weed with my friends one time I
was like oh tell me about it she's like
yeah we decided we're gonna make our own
Edibles and I said well there you [ __ ]
up right away
Edibles will do that I was like you had
a terrible night because you just
literally dosed yourself with an unknown
amount of weed and for your first time
ever experiencing it like that sounds
terrible for someone who's done it for
what is it now 15 years yeah I mean if
you take too much coffee you're gonna
have a bad experience 100 so it's so
funny because I think a lot of people do
relate that edible experience and
Edibles on uh you know the strong side
can be stronger than mushrooms or LSD or
other drug other psychedelic drugs it
can be just as potent or or more oh
absolutely and isn't it because of like
the way it digests in your body and it's
so so it's not really weed that you're
getting anymore it's not the same THC
high that you're getting it metabolizes
into a different drug so it is more
psychedelic than a traditional oh yeah
you can get limitations all kinds of oh
yeah I've been stuck in my bed for hours
off Edibles yeah me too I curled up and
you know yeah one time I was making
Edibles for tray cool from Green Day
yeah yeah yeah and uh I was tasting them
because he's like oh yeah we need him
really really strong and I'm going
overseas and I was making Fruity Pebble
Treats oh because I kept tasting them
and I didn't realize how strong they
were and I ended up curling up in my bed
and then I have people trimming in my
house and my wife was like uh she was at
work and I had to call her and I'm like
I think I need to go to the hospital she
[ __ ] and hung up the phone on me and I
was like oh my God I want to call her
back and she's like you need to man up
you know you just ate some weed yeah so
go figure yeah well I actually have a
similar experience my friend and I were
making like you know what firecrackers
are so it's basically the jankiest form
of edible you can possibly make you take
what we would do is we'd make s'mores
firecrackers so you'd take a graham
cracker you'd put a little piece of
chocolate down you'd put a little peanut
butter for fat for the weed to bind to
and then you put a marshmallow on top
and so we were making these Edibles and
you have no idea what the dose is on
them and people were like you never did
no no people were liking them so we were
like oh let's make a batch or two of
brownies and cookies yeah and so we're
whipping up cookies like you normally
would eating some eating some of the
batter and then my friend's like oh I've
got to go like grab more materials
because we don't have enough to make all
these cookies that we've got batter for
or we got we've got uh butter for and so
he goes to the grocery store and by the
time he gets back like 40 minutes later
I'm curled up using a Betty Crocker box
as a pillow just to sleep on his kitchen
floor and he wakes me up and we busted
out another like 200 something cookies
okay so part of the show and part of the
fun of my show is that we get to taste
some flour and so we have a blind
tasting we have three samples uh one of
them is a less than five dollar a gram
joint one of them is a less than ten
dollar gram joint and one of them is
more than fifteen dollars a gram and you
actually help me roll these today so we
have some beautiful beautiful cones uh
you do everything so you do cones you do
big fat uh you know fingers yeah yeah
the normal ones that most people know me
for are like uh two grams typically and
they have like the nozzle tips but these
are actually what I kind of prefer to
smoke if I'm just smoking like by myself
or if I'm just rolling up quickly like
either on the golf course or just at
home so you like to play golf yeah I
play golf a lot I'm not huge I'm not
really picky on the course I'm not that
good but I I mean it's my main form of
exercise these days getting out and
walking the golf course
nice yeah I like golf I just don't have
enough time for it yeah it is so busy
it's time consuming it'll eat regardless
it eats up a half a day
if you're lucky it needs of a half a day
if you're lucky I mean that's the
minimum and then you're exhausted
afterwards especially like I go out
there and I walk so it's like a six
seven mile walk on Long courses like so
a lot of the time you're exhausted
afterwards as far as when when you hit
one of your joints you don't take big
monster Hits I don't take big monster I
see sometimes people like you know I was
at a party the other day and people were
hitting it and all of a sudden it starts
running and they're complaining about
the joint I'm like dude you can't
[ __ ] hit it like that yeah expect it
not to run you know a lot of the issues
with with running typically come down to
what exactly what you're saying is
people are used to that sort of puff
puff pass mentality right that we all
grew up with where it's like everyone in
the group wants to get high so like
let's get this [ __ ] over with puff puff
and pass it along whereas
we have access to an amount of such
quality material at this point to smoke
that it's less now about that let's get
high and more about the experience it's
like a Cohiba cigar it's more like that
where you're you're in this for 20
minutes that is the mentality I like to
have is the kohibo cigar I like cigars
too I don't smoke a lot of cigars but
it's that mentality well and you'll see
like when I smoke it's not
I typically don't take like direct to
Long hits I typically will inhale into
my mouth to let that smoke cool down a
little bit more to get more of that
flavor
yep where you see a lot of people when
the joints start rolling is because
they're sucking directly into their
lungs and it causes that cherry to get
way too hot totally what do you think of
the way this is burning in the way the
ash looks what's your opinion Ash I mean
I think it really ashes
such like a batch dependent sort of
thing in my opinion like I've had I've
had good weed that smokes like this
where it's maybe not as white as it
probably could be but it's not offensive
the smoke isn't I'm not upset with how
it's smoking yeah but
the thing is it's typically a mark of
someone doing those couple extra things
right yeah that when you get that white
ash it typically does come from better
weed from the drying process yeah the
drying The Cure has a lot to do with it
for one thing well but at the end of the
day like there's good material that
smokes a little bit darker it might not
be somewhere in genetics too genetics
definitely play a role in it I think
it's something that we honestly still
are the jury's still out like we're
people still don't really know what
exactly causes it because there's so
many factors that go into growing the
plant sure
I mean maybe you can correct me if I'm
wrong but like from my limited knowledge
like there's so many different factors
that go in from the growing to the
drying process that it could be any one
of those along the way that yeah it's
not just a lot of times people want to
say it's how you flush it and yeah just
how you flush it it's how it's dried and
cured and the actual I mean I think we
we understand it a lot more but it's
definitely not just one thing that makes
sense and that makes sense
so yeah and what about oil rings what's
your opinion on an oil ring I mean if if
you're not
smoking the joint
just to look for the oil ring yeah then
I don't think there's really much to it
it obviously it shows that there might
be a little bit more THC content in
there but at the end of the day
unless you're holding that joint upside
down to consolidate that resin on the
paper yeah it really it doesn't show
that much in my opinion and definitely
how it's rolled too I think yeah
definitely the the rolling style yeah
absolutely getting a good paper can also
contribute it to contribute to it
because I I feel like papers that are a
little bit on the the Slicker side yeah
like like an element's paper they show
the ring a little bit more maybe it's
also because it's a little bit lighter
of a paper so what's your choice as far
as papers what's what's if you were to
pick one piece yeah what do you use
paper well I personally I typically
smoke the raw organic chems typically
yeah just because that's sort of the
flavor profile that I'm used to if that
makes sense yeah because every paper has
a little bit of a taste well hemp hemp
seems to have a little bit more of a
taste and a little bit more of a burn I
get a little from hemp yeah yeah
personally I do like hemp but I like
race paper yeah yeah and that's that's
what a lot of people that's what a lot
of people say is that they prefer like
elements I just prefer that because
that's what I've gotten used to yeah and
so it's kind of like when you're tasting
something you have to taste it on top of
like whatever your palette is raw's got
a lot of controversy right now I know
it's kind of crazy the weird thing about
it is
he's played it so well that you don't
really know how much of what came out of
the lawsuit is true sure because with
every lawsuit there's going to be a
kernel of Truth where yeah it might not
have been made in alcoy Spain it might
have been made in the town next to it
which seems to be the direction that
Josh from raw is sort of going with it I
I don't really care where the paper came
from obviously it seems kind of silly to
me to lie about something like that
totally in any extent like who cares if
it came from alcoy or came from the town
next to it like right I don't really
care I think it's unfortunate that it's
sort of blown up to the point but the
way that he's handled I think is great
the exposing sort of where where it's
coming from providing people an
opportunity to come and see it well the
truth is we live in a world of
snowflakes that's it is definitely so
we've got a less than five dollar gram
less than ten or more than 15.
that's got to be less than ten less than
10. yeah that's my guess okay more than
five less than 10. we'll let you know at
the end you've got to get into number
two
and actually I'm going to throw you the
lighter and we want to see how you light
it see if I can figure this is
cigar lighter that's that's pretty cool
but it's all about that Cohiba mentality
yeah I typically I mean similar to what
you were doing I it's honestly exactly
how you would light a cigar just Char
the tip it's absolutely and then once
you see that cherry coming give it a
couple blows and then inhale yeah
and also I don't know if you notice on
on that first joint it did start running
a little bit at the beginning yeah but
then it it balances when you take your
time with it yeah it balances all that
is it dead it might be dead
got my little collection
yeah you can't fly with torch lighters
by the way
you can fly can you fly with normal
lighters you can fly with normal
lighters but you cannot fly with these
torchlighters uh any sort of torch
lighter they will take it or you can you
know give it to somebody else or
whatever like but yeah but you cannot
fly it you can put in your check bag but
I think you got to take out all the gas
really so you're so you're supposed to
yeah
I have a lighter that looks like a torch
lighter but it's not and they always
[ __ ] with me they like take it off my
bag like it's not a torch lighter
they're like okay you have it so
what are the other travel tips that you
have for us because that's that's a
useful one I didn't know that
yeah same thing butane like if you smoke
Dabs you don't want to fly with that oh
no no you obviously can't even check
that you have to basically take out all
the gas and fly with an empty
explosions and stuff like that of I like
those rosin carts a lot that I've just
recently sort of getting popular carts
are awesome my only concern though is
you have no idea what they're cutting it
with yeah and that's my only concern is
like you get some that tastes like
better than others you're like well it's
not just pure rosin so what's like the
cut uh you know you gotta talk to
nicotine he's got his his way where he's
doing I mean he's got Pure Rod he's one
of those guys yeah I mean the guys that
are doing rosin carts that aren't
cutting it with anything yeah yeah that
are thinning it has to do with heat well
I'm just not an expert yeah subject at
all because I believe in doubling down
when I'm good at I'm not trying to do
everything yeah of course we're kind of
talking about it a little earlier why I
never got into mushrooms or anything
like that yeah it's just I believe that
whatever you're good at if you double
down on that that you get rid of all the
other distractions you're going to be
successful absolutely you know it's like
you're successful with joint roll your
your joints are awesome online you do
tutorials you have a subscription now on
Instagram as well I don't know I I was I
was toying around because they had some
sort of like uh a messaging platform and
I think all it really is is what
Instagram used to be where if someone
follows you they're gonna see your posts
which seems crazy right like if someone
follows you they want to see what you
have to say but I'm I'm not I don't
think I'm going down that that line
anymore so with the first one what were
the flavors that you tasted I got a
little bread yeah I I didn't get a ton
of it wasn't over no yeah it wasn't a
ton of flavor like maybe earthy but like
nothing nothing gassy maybe yeah but not
like OG you know it didn't stand out and
that's why I I sort of hedged my bet
with the the middle guess on that one
this one I'm getting a little bit more I
get more on that as well
you know without seeing the bud it's
like it's a different experience right
without looking at the bud and analyzing
the bud smelling it and trying to get
those uh and I genuinely don't remember
which is which now oh yeah yeah so it's
it's like I'm really trying to like
piece together this one I would I would
say is a little bit smoother than the
first one yeah I agree
I think it's smoother and I think
there's definitely more Terps I get a
little bit of fruit in there a little
Berry I get a little yeah definitely
some berries some some gas for sure on
the back of it but it's not super gassy
and it's not super fruity it's just kind
of balanced and I mean for what it's
worth there's a little bit more resin on
the paper for sure like I mean
but I also the aftertaste it lingers a
lot longer than the first one kind of
like you'd hit it you get a little bit
of flavor that's it but it was gone
whereas this like after I take a hit
it's still on my palate for like 30
seconds well when you before right
before you handed it back to me I still
had a little bit of the flavor on my
palette I mean I might have [ __ ] up I
think that one might be I don't know now
I think that one might be the middle one
you think this one might be the middle
one yeah and I think the first one might
be the low one that's okay you can
change it as we go all the way to the
end all right
that's what I'm thinking right now yeah
dude the effect of this one is
noticeably stronger than the first oh
absolutely it's not just because I
didn't even take as many hits of the
second one as I did of the first one
took more of the first one for sure yeah
yeah and I think we took like two or
three hits and I definitely feel the
effect like yeah uplifting and it's not
like tight around the eyes it's more
just it's almost more of like what
people would call a sativa High yes 100
100 and I don't smoke a lot of sativas
so that is no I mean but yeah it's
definitely if anything it's like a
sativa leaning hybrid it's not on that
far end of sativa it still has gas in it
it still has uh almost like a
caffeinated Buzz right but I love
caffeine with weed is always a good
combo uh one of my favorite uh combos is
uh Cuban coffee yeah with with a nice
like cigar nice uh or a nice uh blunt I
don't know if you've heard of gonzarello
uh he might be someone to look into
having on the podcast future actually
but he rolls
heirloom Cuban tobacco cigars
uh with with cannabis in them wow and he
invited me over his place a few years
ago when we were first sort of doing
business together he he was selling me a
few few of his Blunts and so I go over
there and he fights me into his home
very welcoming so we we smoked together
and then he brings out similar to this a
small cup of of coffee and I assumed it
might be like an espresso or something
like that
and he's like this is a Cuban coffee
yeah and what it is is it's basically an
espresso but it's whipped in with sugar
huh and so it's like a sweet but like
almost silky smooth espresso yeah and it
was it was so delicious I had like two
or three of them and my heart was just
racing the whole time but it was just
like that that experience of like the
the cigar along with the the tobacco and
like the do you like Vietnamese coffee I
don't know if I've ever had Vietnamese
coffee oh dude you got to get the I
don't know after this we'll go get some
Vietnamese coffee because Vietnamese
coffee is one of my favorites they do
it's sweet because they use condensed
milk oh right and so they do a slow drip
and the drip actually goes in and it's
like super strong oh wow the heart races
yeah you can't sleep at night
so we're gonna get into the third flavor
here yeah
so so far so good today I mean I really
think the California Market has improved
over the last
year since the beginning of covid until
now absolutely there's definitely
improvements in quality I think product
is moving faster too so it's not sitting
on the shelves quite as long which is a
bad thing but I feel like a lot of the
shitty cultivators that thought they
were going to come in and grow these
mid-quality yeah things and not even mid
we're talking about the low quality
stuff those dudes are gone yeah so and I
mean well I think also a lot of it comes
down to like people have now found their
path into the legal Market
yeah and I mean there's there's some
Boutique Brands there's a lot of Booth
still 100 but I would say there are some
really good Boutique Brands uh the the
struggle I find is finding finding the
quality brands
in dispensaries like I typically am not
a dispensary Shopper but the last time I
was in a dispensary
the bud tender didn't even know what he
was talking about yeah I bought one one
like an ounce of one flavor and then a
week later came back and it was the same
same packaging but a different color wow
and he had told me oh yeah it's it's the
same bat or the same strain but a
different batch of it and I go back home
and I look at the two labels and it's
completely different crosses of two
completely different strains wow and I
was like most people don't know what the
hell is the difference sure but to
someone who does that's such like an
off-putting experience compared to
knowing the person who grows it knowing
all of what went into it well that's the
difference between the the wreck world
and the black market back in the days
you were a lot closer to the cultivator
for the most part if you're in
California especially yeah maybe not so
in other states whatever but like in
California we were like blessed to I
mean growing up in the bay we always had
somebody who had weed for the most part
but we had Brown weed back in the day we
you know I mean like with [ __ ] seeds
in it before yep yeah I mean the old
Mexican weed and those seeds are [ __ ]
I wish I had more of those still because
there's some interesting stuff that came
out of those and you know but
uh you were closer to the if you get got
homegrown weed the green stuff the stuff
coming out of [ __ ] uh the
uh areas up in Humboldt and friggin
Mendo and Sonoma you know they've been
freaking producing bomb ass weed forever
and there was home Growers that did a
good job too but like you were closer
and so
I don't know well it's just different
experience well so I grew up on the East
Coast where like I was saying like you
didn't always know what strain you were
buying like you can't always even trust
what other people say the strains are
yeah and then
I was very much like a person like I
want to know like the flavors I'm
smoking I want a couple different ones
so I can like try different strains and
growing up in like a small town in
Massachusetts there's not a lot of
access to that but I was able to sort of
I know I was always making friends with
other people who had access to good weed
or were just cool people to hang out
with and happen to also smoke and one of
those people happened to be like the
sort of town Weed supplier for the kids
who didn't mind dealing with kind of the
weird guy and he would have
like sort of you have set up here he
would have 10 different strains and like
you'd be able to sort of smell sample
some of them totally and he would be
able to tell you hey here's some purple
Romulan here's like so and what year was
this like around the 2000s no well so
this was probably like
2011 2012. okay and so he he had a guy
out in Washington who he was willing to
play a little bit more but he could hand
select hey I want these 12 strains yeah
and I want the good [ __ ] I don't want
the [ __ ] you're peddling to most guys on
the East Coast right and so he had that
quality flower and then when I went to
school in Maryland it was the same sort
of thing where I was like
I want to know what I'm smoking I want
to know where it comes from and so I
made those relationships and then when I
came out to the West Coast it was always
well who grew this yeah and then I would
meet the person who grew it or I meet up
the supply chain and eventually meet the
person who grew it and not to make any
money off of them but simply for the
sake of the relationship I'm interested
like you I don't have the expertise so
I'm interested in what you're doing like
I want to know how you do that like I
want to witness this and then I can
maybe help you in something else or just
watch it right and I think I was able to
sort of build those relationships
because I wasn't worried about making
any money off of
the relationship at all yeah I think
when you're driven by Passion you're
going to be more successful yeah you
know it's like there's so many different
ways to make money but like passion
driven people are usually the happiest
yeah you know if you're just motivated
by money I I don't know that it's
definitely not the industry to be in
anymore it's just Money Motivated but
really interesting so let's talk about
your giant rolling yeah uh your
Instagram is professional joint roller
yes sir and do you have tips for people
on rolling joints I think we did some uh
joint join uh videos that we'll probably
cut in yeah yeah you spare people with
people but yeah give us some tips yeah
so I mean a lot of the time people are
dealing with either papers that are too
small or not enough weed is what I find
and a lot of really what joint rolling
is is getting the material into the
shape that into a workable shape and so
when I'm rolling specifically like cones
like this I'm not necessarily like
working the material that much I'm more
shaping the paper into the shape that I
want it to be and the material then yeah
goes goes with right and then from there
it's knowing what what it feels like to
have like a clump in the joint so that
you can work those out stickier dry weed
all right it's got to be it's got to be
if I have to choose it's got to be
sticky it's easier to roll a sticky
definitely easier to roll and also dry
weed it tends to to run more because
you'll get clumps on one side I mean I
have a guy that grows the most amazing
weed and it always comes out super
[ __ ] dry yeah I mean Super dry yeah
but it rolls fine and it burns fine it
actually breaks down super [ __ ] fine
and so then it burns real slow oh okay
that makes sense but you know I like
sticky weed too I mean I want yeah I
want it so it doesn't matter how dry it
is the the resin is the sticky part yeah
yeah I I definitely prefer a little bit
on the fresher side yeah because then I
mean typically if I'm rolling like a
pound of joints they're not being smoked
that next day as well so if you roll
them when they're slightly fresher then
they a lot they're allowed to cure up in
the paper a little bit and then you get
the joint when you'd want to smoke it
yeah you don't get it when it's too
fresh or too dry
totally yeah you just for my Amsterdam
we used to uh I I stayed in Amsterdam on
and off for a lot a lot of uh you know
the 2010 through 2012 13 and 14. okay
yeah and I'd stay for extended amounts
of time with my buddy and he basically I
learned how to roll joints good for like
with the crutch yeah do a reverse role
in Amsterdam and my buddy Abba he taught
me how to do it I was staying with him
and he like looked at my joint and he
was like sad for me yeah he was actually
sad for me he's like you need to learn
how to roll real good joints I don't
know what that is well a lot of a lot of
people are too heavy-handed with it
where they try to like
crunch the paper into the form they
think a joint should be yeah where it's
really like the less that you manipulate
the paper the better like so you're
almost using the paper to form the weed
you're not necessarily like forming the
paper itself it's almost like so the old
uh joint rolling you remember the joint
rollers from back yeah yeah yeah two
bars of course the whole concept is
doing the same thing with your hands
yeah and shaping it and then using that
top I I use the top paper to push over
yeah you know you're basically my when I
roll my left thumb stays on the crutch
yeah and so it doesn't move from there
because that's basically the most
important part is getting that crutch
tight yeah and then from there you're
just basically what you said you're
you're forming the weed but with the
paper as you're basically like your
finger yeah and then as you go you're
getting that fold from here I'll get out
of or actually you have a paper over
there yeah
so you're getting that fold
and that's the part that most people
struggle on
is getting the fold over
you're getting that fold
simply by going over that material
and then running your thumb there enough
to where the material is down and you
can get that glue strip over top of that
paper totally and that's what I think a
lot of people over complicate the the
whole thing and that's why I've sort of
simplified my joint rolling process
whereas I don't roll these on mass yeah
I roll them I roll my joints a slightly
different way more like a cigar that can
be sort of rolled out totally how many
joints can you roll in a day
if I'm putting in a 10 11 hour day I can
typically roll about 150 to like 160
joints nice so
then I guess let's dive into what you
think number three is is that that one
got me high I feel I mean they've all
got I want to think have the best flavor
I would agree that it had the best
flavor the best finish it had [ __ ]
Terps and it's halfway down we keep
smoking that one because it tastes so
[ __ ] yeah
um what kind of chirps
getting a little bit more
more of like an lcg terp yeah but it's
definitely like a good
candy chirp I would say like yeah candy
floral yeah candy floral gas
you know I feel like it got it has that
it's not it's not linear it's definitely
layers of flavors it's good yeah that
definitely Cherry yeah [ __ ] strong
Cherry note in there yeah I think I know
which one that would that one is yeah I
would assume that one's the the what is
it Cherry poppers
I don't know we are gonna go through
these that one I would I would assume is
the most expensive one the most
expensive so I would go I would go
three two one so expensive middle low
that's what I'm going okay now
this one
is Oak Fruitland still amazing this this
one's kind of special though so this Oak
Fruitland was I went to cookies Hayward
big shout out to cookies Hayward but I
went there today and picked that up it
was a thirty dollar uh thirty dollar
quarter ounce oh wow and normally it's
like 60. yeah so that was their 30
special the price for the price [ __ ]
yeah you you can't beat it but that's
the less than ten dollar again so this
was Oak fruit land and Sherbert times
piscotti yeah fortune cookies I remember
fortune cookies back in the day was just
a phenotype of
Girl Scout cookies like the Forum cut or
maybe it was one of the other random
cuts that it was but fortune cookies was
just cookies so then the next one
boom I really want to smell this one but
this one right here was the lesson five
really so which it was good lesson five
the sativa one big Dave's Bud uh gummies
which was jet fuel gelato times peach
rings yeah yeah and uh that makes sense
that peach rings that's from dying breed
[ __ ] Terps it's got good Terps I love
that one
marionberry times uh that's definitely a
sativa hybrid then yeah for sure I just
got the jet fuel gelato which is
definitely on the other side so but as
far as it was uh
hmm marionberry time something
but uh yeah so man I'm [ __ ] high off
that yeah so we we go in the the order
here and number three yeah you guessed
it yep it was definitely the more
expensive super dope Cherry poppers lcg
S1 yep or lcg it tastes just like lcg
definitely
um that's like definitely smoked well
yeah the buds are nice it's pretty dry
yeah definitely definitely on the drier
side
but I mean you got to think at least at
least five dollars out of that is going
into the artwork dude absolutely
it's impressive their packaging is
impressive it's it's like a big collab
too well I mean it's been it's been fun
thanks for coming on the show thanks for
having me yeah for sure we'll have to
get you back we'll do uh we have to do a
collaboration with some flower awesome
sounds good man thank you very much
thank you
[Music]
okay