[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James loud
podcast and today my special guest is
Dale Sky Jones Chancellor of oaksterdam
how are you doing today I am fantastic
James how are you I'm fantastic thank
you for coming on the show really
excited to have you here Angela Baka our
mutual friend uh kind of hooked this up
we've met before yes we have a a mutual
admiration for Miss Baka and her talents
yes she is absolutely amazing indeed you
know it's like it's rare to find some
for me I like waking up early I wake up
about 5:00 a and she wakes up at 4 and
so she's ready to go she she's the for
those of you who don't know she is the
editor for my book uh and and she she
produced a lot of good content for the
book as well so she wasn't just the
editor but contributing writer and she's
also working with you guys or has has
worked with you in the past on a lot of
stuff well she's also the editor of the
book we just just published the bud
tenders guide so yeah uh we also uh
recently published a second uh guide as
well for writers authors especially so
many journalists that are covering this
that's a style guide similar you know to
the AP guide that you might use to just
know proper terminology uh and she also
uh worked on another book uh I wrote the
sustainability chapter and several
oaksterdam experts worked on Ed
rosenthal's uh cannabis Growers guide so
yeah she is uh multi-talented and and uh
works with us on a lot of projects she's
super organized she's super driven she's
a rare breed you don't to keep up with
the likes of us is and you know I'm like
okay 5:00 a.m. I'm ready to work uh I do
my seriously 8 a.m. on the East Co and
she's already been rocking for an hour
seriously and you know it's like I do my
cold Plunge in the morning and I get
ready to go I I do it religiously every
day cold plunge game changer for me I
don't drink coffee first thing in the
morning now I do that and I feel like
I'm more productive so that's you know
and it's so interesting talk about
Different Strokes for different folks
because I have something called cylic
vomiting syndrome oh wow and one of my
triggers is cold really so that would
put me in the hospital if I did on cold
Plunge in the morning that would not be
a good day for me well cold plunge is so
interesting because I feel like I know
the science is is there I just
personally can't but the first time I
looked at the water I was like that is
going to kill me there's no way I'm go
in there and be okay if you stay in
there long enough it will hypothermia
but not not not what you're doing yes
and no but I do 15minute plunges
sometimes and I go a they say three to
six minutes and I've pushed it to 15
because I'm like this guy Rick rubben he
does 30 minutes Joe Rogan he does 20 I
can do 15 and I don't feel like I get
more benefit from doing 15 minutes than
I do from doing eight and so I sit
around 8 minutes and it's 45° right now
so I was doing colder and now I settle
around there I feel really good
afterwards MH you found your sweet spot
yeah and everyone's body chemistry is
different it's kind of how cannabis
works I feel like there's no one
specific cultivar that works for
everybody across the board I mean I
think cannabis in general like in
generally speaking works for pretty much
everybody but there are nuances to it
and certain people like uh stuff that's
sedative and some people like stimulants
well I would also add the method of
ingestion matters yeah uh how you can
assume it really affects your experience
and uh it's something that's really I
think under under discussed uh there's a
lot of localities and states that are
afraid of smoke they're afraid even of
vapor there they've outlawed any type of
com combustion and they they drive
everyone towards edibles but that's
there's a whole another issue with
Edibles that uh folks don't seem to
understand when your liver metabolizes
versus your bloodstream so right uh yeah
you can be more like tripping on acid uh
you hear the the the funnest or funniest
stories of people thinking they're
melting or dead I always go back to the
cop that called 911 telling them you
taken our class you'd have known better
but uh yeah uh that that it truly is uh
metabolized 11 hydroxy THC is is more
psychoactive yeah uh and and you really
it can melt you in that same way I feel
like it's stronger than LSD in a lot of
ways like for me person brownies it is
yeah well in in back in the day we
didn't really measure what we were
taking there wasn't like milligrams we
were like okay we're going to put this
much in this amount of butter high but
that's also I I dare say how we bred CBD
out of so many varietals is because
folks were passing around how high was
the measure and what was you know they
they' basically throw it away to
patients and patients are like holy [ __ ]
this is really helping me yeah and and
it wasn't until around 2007 when when we
finally started testing for it that it
was like oh oh there's this whole other
thing going on here that totally no one
understood and these are still
underground labs oh yeah well and then
Reggie Gino he's been on the show he
wrote the forward for my book so he kind
of paved the way for some of that stuff
and yeah it's really interesting testing
and and also the market in we're still
in uneducated Market in the whole of the
market I feel like it's getting there
it's getting better I see improvements
but as far as like we're still focused
on THC we're still focused on look you
know I'm excited for the day where we
can sell you the joint the pre-roll
where it's all pre-roll driven like
brands are pre-roll driven where you
don't even need to look at it it does it
make you feel good does it taste great
that those are the two important things
in my opinion because some of the best
stuff that gets overlooked it it's not
aesthetically pleasing some some of my
favorite things over the years have been
absolutely the ugliest strains oh let's
talk about Aesthetics shall we uh I
would love to jump on this bandwagon
especially uh before we turn this on you
said not not a lot of women join the
podcast and and I think uh there's
there's a few different things going on
with with looks and part of the problem
is just North American bias that what we
are accustomed to at least what we're
accustomed to saying looks good and is
worth money uh is is generally what
we're accustomed to seeing from NorCal
and those tight nugs in the jar uh but
that has to do with you know where it
was grown on the Earth where Northern
latitude and then folks go oh well I was
in the islands and it was all stringy
and ugly but wow it smoked nice I'm like
yeah that's cuz it's great quality
cannabis it just doesn't look like what
you're expecting and I think this the
same concept around like body image that
you had to be stick thin white tall
skinny to be beautiful for years and now
it's like you got booty that is
beautiful well it was always always
beautiful it's just what aesthetic are
you putting forward and what is most
familiar what are you seeing on the
magazines what are you seeing out there
as held up as beautiful and I think it's
just continuing to have the
conversations like you are about what
makes quality what makes the best
experience yeah it's all about defining
quality and and perspective and it's
like uh Instagram hasn't really been
helpful in that regard when is Instagram
ever help no it's it's it's so difficult
you know it's it's I have a LoveHate
relationship with Instagram and it's I'm
aun driver at best I yeah yeah it's
tough well and you know especially for
for cannabis and for flow you see the
stuff that looks amazing and most of the
stuff that looks really amazing and
especially the stuff that's super high
THC doesn't necessarily taste the best
or give you the best effect in my
opinion you know everybody has their
opinion some people are chasing the high
and they want to get as high as possible
and flavor doesn't really matter they
just want to be high and that's okay too
so it's all subjective to the individual
well but ironic Ally when you blind
taste test M the highest THC is not
usually the winner of what makes people
feel no it's the best and yeah and it's
not always the strongest that's you know
that's my point yeah tpin
flavonoids uh what's the new term for
abstract Tech I don't know if you saw
that the they so they just put out some
white papers I think six white papers
about basically fils and really
interesting I mean I think we've known
about THS I've known about THS since
2018 we've been reading about them and
their importance and you know that's
what gives you the gas and the skunk and
some of the offensive smells I really
like offensive smelling weed so it's
kind of like cilantro right it's either
soap or delicious exactly I feel that
way about diesel so like not so much I
don't feel like licking a gas tank thank
you yeah yeah burnt Tire latex gloves
you know no that yeah that chem smell no
it's but that yeah you you give me any
Haze and I will follow you to the ends
of the Earth so yeah it's and you know
bring that back to humans uh part of
what we've always taught your nose knows
yeah and what's remarkable is when we
break down the science and then start to
correlate that to the effects on what
are your symptoms you know not even what
what's the disease but just what are you
suffering from yeah uh and and we start
to to take a look at different things
and we the doctors that have now collect
hundreds and thousands of testimonials
are starting to also see those
correlations where their nose Nos and
it's it is what is actually helping them
and that goes back to maybe why it
became about the numbers we no longer
have Apothecary style it's nearly
obsolete you can no longer go in and
sniff before you buy right it's really
sad so it's just and and now you also
you're not even allowed to package in a
lot of places so all you can say is the
label yeah that's it and so what do you
have to look at well the one thing
you're familiar with what's the THC how
high or the brand name yeah cookies or
whatever well you're definitely paying
for the brand name in a lot of the
brands yeah and I think is it quality is
it consistency that is the question it's
hard state by state well and the thing
is is what's going to happen in a more
mature Market is we're going to start
trusting brands that we know and you go
bu you know from one company you buy
their brand three or four times and you
have a product you like you're going to
trust that company you're going to tell
their people about it and the next time
you go in as long as it maintains the
quality that you're looking for you know
and that's the future of the industry
too like that the trusted brand because
I think there's been a lot of Brands
where they're associated with the
celebrity or influencer driven and
that's still yeah and and that's still
okay but as long as it's paired with a
good product because you have one time
with a customer right if you if you have
you I'm not going to name any name
celebrity Brands but some of these guys
put out really [ __ ] in the beginning and
you know I think they learn their lesson
because you get your customer to buy it
once and maybe you have this big surch
in the beginning but they're not going
to buy the product again if it's garbage
especially not for the price you're
charging for your name no and the thing
is is after taxes people paying $65 for
an eighth and it's like if you're a real
smoker an eth doesn't go very far no so
no that doesn't fill is that an eth yeah
those are those are 3.5 Grandam joints
yeah just eyeballing in there yeah yeah
and it's like and I prefer the eighth
size joint and if you have really good
flour you smoke it down to the roach you
could put that out five or six times and
it's still going to taste good yeah so
and you that's my determining Factor
especially now when the I give flour out
to my friends because we're trying new
phenotypes they don't get the flour they
get joints so it's because it puts
everybody on the same playing field and
then when you do that you get honest
feedback from people and I feel like
it's the feedback that I'm looking for
so it it's said you know you get one guy
who has a bong and one guy who has a
joint and one guy who does this or that
and he has a glass pipe and it's dirty
you you never know what you're going to
get as far as feedback so I feel like
it's a truer way to get honest feedback
well and it's also one of the safer ways
to consume cannabis yeah yeah well
depending on how you feel about germs
you know if you're sharing well no that
for you alone absolutely yeah yeah it's
h the puff puff pass has become
questionable at best yeah I mean
probably always was we're just a lot
more conscien I mean we used to get the
cup cough we'd go to Amsterdam and come
back with the c used to I just everyone
just came back from MJ biscon and
they're all telling me how sick they are
it's like yeah the they need more cold
plunging that's that's I feel like
stressing your body out is you know it's
good for your immune system so some D3
yeah D3 is a great yeah I take a lot of
D3 so I also have Crohn's disease it's
been so Angela also has Crohn's yes but
I've cured my Crohn's through cannabis
and I believe cold plunging and I think
those two pieces are the determining
Factor um I was on biologics where I had
to give get injected with the drug every
two months I had to get an infusion in
my blood and I'm off that for it'll be a
year next week which is pretty amazing
congratulations so yeah thank you very
much it's wonderful to just find
homeostasis in your life yeah and
balance and yeah it's it's all those
things are great so let's talk about
oaksterdam what what have you guys been
up to lately oh my goodness what haven't
we been up to lately I'm so proud of my
team it is just it's phenomenal where do
I begin uh we just graduated a cohort in
the state of Connecticut so we were
hired by the state of Connecticut social
Equity Council a year ago and we uh got
to work actually a year and a half ago
uh and uh we had a cohort go through a
full-blown accelerator and this is the
first time a state has truly invested in
from beginning to end Soup To Nuts what
an operator needs to be a startup and
the fact that uh we were given the time
uh with each participant uh we got all
the way through from teaching the
business of cannabis and the supply
chain then we went into an
entrepreneurial coaching program where
we had professionals work with them to
build business plans then we worked with
arcview so it's kind of like having the
Shark Tank uh coach before you go pitch
uh and then we brought a bunch of
investors together in Connecticut uh and
had our graduates pitch to real live
investors and in fact on the way here
I just got notice that one of our
participants just got funded so like
Soul Marine I'm con you wonderful I'm
over the moon uh just the the
opportunity to see them uh grow and
Thrive and
especially you know we had both 100%
owners where they were on their own solo
making it happen and we had some that
were partnered with msos and I got the
chance to speak with one of the MSO
partners who just described the change
in that participant like you know they
were quiet in the room they had nothing
to say and by the time they were done
with this accelerator they were a true
partner in the business and not that
second class partner that so many social
Equity participants are relegated to and
true change is is happening so that's
awesome when you hear success stories
like that it's just you know and they're
there there are there's a lot of success
stories and you know it's a tough time
in the industry so people need to hear
those kind of success stories I think
let me be your head of hope James I have
yes I have many uh and and we were
recently hired by the New Jersey
Economic Development Authority to do uh
not quite as Grand a program but to uh
to definitely help launch some of the
participants that are getting a grant uh
from the state uh we've been working
with the city of Los Angeles for over
three years now um working with the the
social Equity participants down there
and the City of Oakland uh Palm Springs
uh Monterey County The Growers out there
there's a couple of really phenomenal
Growers that are managing to get
permanent licenses so helping Legacy
secure their space in in the new
industry uh is also really gratifying
important it is so important these are
the shoulders we stand on yeah and it's
it's like they the people that help
build the industry are the people that
deserve a place here indeed I just I I
can't talk about it enough I just you
know and coming from the Legacy market
and coming from the traditional side of
things you know it's like it's changed
so much in the last the the landscape
has changed so so much and the barrier
for entry has changed so much uh you
talked about New Jersey and that's a
that's a tough nut to crack as as far
as to get into that industry yeah it's
it's one of those ones if you hard than
New York yeah it's way harder than New
York they really limited the licenses
and you know and there's nothing wrong
with that I think limiting the licenses
is good to a degree but it's like
depending on how far you limit them but
uh you know I have mixed feelings about
New Jersey but I think New York is
really impressive and and we're all
learning from each other like Oregon
they they overdid it and they allowed
too many licenses and so there there's
got to be a fine balance and you know
I'm not an expert on the subject but uh
I I just I have some experts on that
subject and there's a yeah there's
there's there's really there's
fascinating arguments and I think this
is you know go- go gadget federalism
this is the 10th Amendment at at at work
uh and I'm I'm actually look up the
states act if you get the chance because
it just dropped yesterday the states act
2.0 uh to deschedule because right now
we're talking about uh rescheduling and
uh no no schedule three uh but you know
the the yeah the we could go off on so
many tangents James which way so we
definitely need I had Andrew D'Angelo
and we've had other guests on talking
about reschedule versus deschedule it I
am very anti- reschedule and I am very
Pro deschedule completely we're going to
get along just fine yeah I I can't even
imagine trying to reschedule at this
point I it's not right um there wrong if
you work with the pharmaceutical
industry maybe yeah it's like let's res
mean the ones that have been paying
millions and billions to keep it illegal
while they furiously study how to make
money off it yeah and it's well can we
walk in chum at the same time listen it
needs to be pharmaceutical IED we need
to be able to utilize this in medicine
and doctors and nurses need to be able
to call up you know 10 cc's of whatever
for folks that are suffering through
radiation chemotherapy whatever that is
uh we definitely need to find ways for
the FDA like let's legalize researching
would do that uh and and decriminalizing
and that's the other half of this is
just taking the teeth out of the
criminality uh and at this point um I
have folks argue of of like it's just a
softer gentler prohibition yeah and and
it's like but but I think a lot of
people are condition you know I we had
Brandon from inh House genetics and he
said it really best is like people are
like well schedule 3 is better than
schedule one and it's like is it really
you know and he he argued the fact and
he agrees 100% it's like it's it's not
and there's a lot of people are saying
well it's not schedule one but that's
true but is it better no I don't think
it's I don't think we understand the
ramifications of USDA and FDA and and
the the folks mucking around and not
letting who's doing it keep doing it
yeah yeah well and these are all
difficult conversations and things that
need to be talked openly and we need to
have some hard conversations about
really what are we looking for out of
this stuff you know and who are we
supporting by saying that schedule three
is okay so indeed and you know full full
disclosure I I sit on a committee with
with several folks that that have these
conversations with uh law enforcement
Action Partnership leap uh uh she's
actually on our board as well the
executive director Diane Goldstein um
and and we also Americans for Prosperity
it uh reason there are several groups
that uh have these conversations and
again we can go back to the
pharmaceuticalization of of the various
medicinal aspects and research but we
need to start from a
deschedule uh footing it needs to be
removed from the drug enforcement agency
and the controlled sub Substances Act uh
first and foremost and I don't fault the
folks that are willing to settle I'm not
right I'm not willing to take that trade
I'm not willing to trust it no it
through through actions and a stack of
evidence we have a lot of reason not to
trust it indeed and and that's why I I
keep mentioning the states act 2.0 is
because what we also need is an
alternative to point2 yeah and right now
to have the rescheduling schedule three
on the table without a what else it just
becomes a yes no and what we need is an
also and and an option and the state's
act 2.0 offers the option of
descheduling and it's not going to be
you know a a flip that a switch that
flips overnight we're talking about uh a
a slow painful process uh that also has
to happen in nearly every state or or
Commonwealth in the nation there's I
think Virginia didn't adopt the failed
federal policy schedule everybody else
has a lot of work to do uh state by
state as well um so this is it's not
going to happen overnight but nothing
good ever does no it's not
indeed so let's take a step back and
talk about Oaker Dam University and how
you got involved with Oaker Dam and
where the start came about well the the
area named oaksterdam uh Oakland and
Amsterdam was really founded by my
husband Jeff Jones and he was the first
to work with the city of Oakland he was
permitted uh and and helped dispense
medical cannabis to the necessity
patients back in the 90s he actually
started before the law was passed um and
and worked you know he sat at the feet
of Dennis Peron and and learned uh many
things and decided to go the route of a
a a medical cannabis dispensary versus a
club yeah that uh he he really wanted to
take on the mantle that would be
adoptable in South Dakota where he was
from and and where he lost his dad uh he
was frustrated by the Clinton
Administration uh wound up um winning in
the ninth circuit so it was legal I have
a picture of him uh handing a legal bag
of cannabis to a medical patient uh he
was legal for about six weeks before the
stay that took him to the Supreme Court
and the battle that that took over his
life uh his grower who he had moved out
from Texas named Richard Lee uh went
ahead and picked up the permit and
picked up the mantle and it was Richard
who founded oaksterdam University in
2007 now I was a fly on the wall uh just
starting to date Mr Jones falling in
love with both of them at the the same
time this the oaksterdam concept of a
school because I come from a corporate
training background and and just uh
vocational adult learning helping people
be the best them that they can be and
the uh the school I when I first started
I came in working with doctors so I
immediately looked for well where's the
education what do you mean there isn't
any yeah so the only Educators I found
were well it they all worked with Jeff
uh because he was the one that was
trying to teach patients
um how to be safe and responsible how to
find medicine and uh while he couldn't
dispense it himself uh and I started
volunteering um I showed up to the first
class in LA to help make coffee and um
again just the fly on the wall I was
obsessed with the concept of training
but because I worked with doctors I
would have been the bridge to ating and
a betting a felony um so crazy I
couldn't yeah I couldn't like put my
name on anything because I I was
representing them uh the doctor though
uh that was supposed to teach that day
got lost in Compton and oh man the yeah
uh he was fine but the long and short of
it was they didn't have a teacher and so
the facilitator ran up and said hey do
you think you work with patients do you
think you could cover this material and
I looked at it and it was almost
verbatim What I talked to patients and
doctors about like sure I can do that
never missed a class uh replaced myself
at the doctor's office and became uh
Chancellor of LA and then eventually uh
got involved with a campaign that I
accidentally became the spokeswoman of
um I say that because I kept thinking I
was going to go back to Corporate
America I wasn't ready to come out I was
just behind the scenes you know prodding
everybody else to do it right uh but
there was nobody else to do it and um
when Richard decided to put his money
where his mouth was and pay for the
first legalization campaign in 30 years
um the the first elected official That
was supposed to show up um was suffering
from his chemo treatments and frankly
the voter initiative would have been
Dead on Arrival and so I said well do we
have what he was gonna say can't you
know half of this is print media anyway
just read it they're like okay read it
I'm like no not me right so as they
shoved me from behind in front of a bank
of cameras for my first uh full-blown
press conference um suddenly I was the
spokeswoman for the pr 19 campaign yeah
and uh and then I became the legislative
leaz on and the community leaz on
because we were just a small rag tiag
group of rebels just trying to make a
point and then suddenly we were winning
and then then the next thing we know
everyone's you know they start taking
you seriously when you're at you know
54% in the polls you're a threat uh so
we got not one but two October surprises
um we had the Governor Schwarzenegger
signed the well it was uh vetoed four
times it was the largest
decriminalization measure in history for
California and the result of that was
87% James that's nine out of 10 people
that didn't go to jail the very next
year because we pressured him into
signing that DM measure here in
California and more effective than any
other state that just legalized because
they only legalized for 21 and up we
decriminalized for everyone and so that
was the biggest win um the second was
just sparking the conversation and the
debate internationally because we were
the only thing to talk about in 2010
yeah so while we had every living DEA uh
every living drugs are and the president
of the no on campaign was our our former
um Senator Diane Feinstein and our
current vice president KLA Harris wrote
The Ballot argument against us I mean
these are the good old days my friend oh
yeah uh that uh we we really did um our
Coalition of NAACP and unions and
doctors and environmentalists and yes
Legacy people went on to change the law
in a lot of these other states and I
cannot say enough about our students who
are it's not the secret to Our Success I
shout it from the rooftops they are um
behind the success of so much change
because we taught them advocacy and it
was them that went out to their neck of
the woods and changed the law from city
council to state to Nation whether it's
Germany we're we're seeing changes in
Thailand and and then I get emails for
my students it's like oh my that was you
like that was us holy crap pretty wild
we really have changed the world yeah
it's mindblowing well pioneering
education and then you know the
influence from all the students that
have come through it's just amazing and
you know you guys were kind of the
gateway to the industry for a lot of
people yeah and we were willing to let
the cameras in yeah and I look back just
how bananas like
so oh the stories I can tell um but
letting the cameras in I think was
really important and then also just
seeing a dude in a wheelchair and a
pregnant redhead of you know like that's
oh that's not that scary drug dealer in
the corner you knowt like wait a minute
who who's that and you know people make
fun of chich and Chong and you know I'm
certainly guilty of that uh having met
Tommy several times now I realize how
intentional he was to always portray
cannabis in positive light I knew that
he was an intelligent and Brilliant
writer and comic but I didn't understand
the intentionality of like yeah it was
dumb fun but it was never evil or scary
or dangerous it was always fun and
uplifting and funny uh but the only
folks that were willing to come out were
the ones that you know your mama didn't
want you to grow up to be like yeah and
so it wasn't that you know cannabis made
you stupid it was just stupid people
enjoy cannabis and they were the ones
willing to talk about it out loud and
get busted right uh and so I we stupid
or crazy it's hard to say but it really
took folks that just like look look like
Middle America that were not we not
scary we're just like to normalize it
yeah and destigmatize yeah and it's
funny how normalized it's become it
still has a long ways to go in some
regards but oh we're not no but but I
feel like Sanjay gupa did a lot when he
went on 60 Minutes and said that uh kids
that have seizures have now been cured
from their seizures or they've had a lot
less seizures from CBD he's an amazing
example of evolution he also by the way
came out against Pro 19 uh and and you
know little Charlotte Fiji was changed
his life and ours um across the board
because it really Illustrated you know
you can't ignore these videos of of baby
seizing and I can't even talk about her
I'm going to start crying so no yeah uh
and and it it really um and dying um
that are they are they seizing are they
learning are they growing um Sanji Gupta
and the ability to have that
conversation on CNN the ability you know
I didn't tell my friends at the time but
the ability to go talk about it on Fox
all the time yeah you know that's that's
half of America and if you've got
steuart Varney talking about the money
uh then we're also capturing you know
Wall Street not just K Street um and and
we've already convinced I think Main
Street in most
places he was our troan horse he was the
voice for all of us in some regards you
know and it's like telling my parents
all these years that cannabis isn't bad
and them kind of arguing with me and you
know I I think after seeing that they
completely changed like that one
60-minute episode like literally an hour
changed lives of so many people because
you can't argue when you have kids you
know it's like you can't argue that
people need you know they should have
the right as long as it's not hurting
them to do whatever they want to make
them better I and How brave are
Charlotte's parents and and she also
passed in 2020 a lot of people don't
realize that um her parents you know
risked losing her and this is a threat
still everywhere even here in California
people are still losing their children
over cannabis they're still splitting up
families and it's sick it's it's really
it's sick like they that you could do
that and or that you have to go to some
other state to save the life of your kid
exactly that you are a medical Refugee
we're not even going to get abortions or
anything like that that that's a whole
another shitty conversation but it's
like these laws and you know I have my
own opinion other people that watch the
show you have an opinion and there's
nothing wrong with that but
like when it comes to your kids
especially like I I don't understand how
we can do that so and for our pro-life
friends I I have the argument that if
you are pro-life then you had better be
Pro cannabis uh because because Pro
cannabis is pro-life and and for the
rest of us yes we just uh hope to to
have the freedom uh if we need medical
attention right yeah yeah at the end of
the day it's about freedom and this is
the conversation across the board it's
the freedom to be able to protect
yourself with the Second Amendment uh
which also has been stripped from
Cannabis consumers you know there's just
about every amendment in the first have
been subjugated by the War on Drugs by
prohibition and you know these are these
are largely the people we serve we've
we've always taught it's I can't even
believe some of the the titans of the
industry but the the ones that I choose
to talk about most often tend to be
those that uh were Justice involved that
did spend time in jail you know the king
of weed on hate Street uh you know he's
always been the king of weed on hate
Street for like 30 years now uh and Sean
rich Rich has has has been there doing
it uh now he's the legal king of weed on
hate Street and we get the asterisk at
oan line and now he's balling man I mean
people are paying him just to be on
their boards like it's his experience is
far beyond Legacy his experience now is
in the boardroom uh not just the
courtroom so he's he's really you know
and it's there's so many firsts that
have come through and that are yet to
come because there are states that
aren't there yet businesses yet to be
founded um and it's you know there's
this is the argument for maybe free
market is there's yals that should get
the hell out too um and the free market
pushes out often those that uh are less
than I just had a conversation with
someone from Oregon uh saying it rocks
because the you know the losers get out
yeah I you know you can having that low
barrier to entry uh is is one of the
best equalizers out there and so you
look to Oklahoma
and it's you know just organically more
Equitable because there are no barriers
to entry now are they all good operators
no absolutely not no there should be
standards there should be training there
should be more better yes MOA MOA yeah
for sure like in Oregon it's a perfect
example but it's so competitive in
Oregon and that the price is so cheap
and then nobody wants to pay the higher
price for the the product yeah and I
wouldn't say nobody because you know you
got you always got the folks that just
want to show how much they paid for a
product yeah and I'm all about the
quality so at the end of the day like I
I don't I don't really I don't shouldn't
say that I don't care what it costs
because I think cost is important for
people but for me it's about an
experience a lot of times and I I'll pay
something more for a special experience
and I I might not smoke that all the
time but I'm all about I'm chasing that
experience yeah you know there's guys
chasing the dragon they want to get as
high as they can flavor Chasers and I
chase the flavor to but I feel like I'm
I'm chasing that experience and I'm I'm
trying to find something new always
trying to find something new is and that
kind of goes along with
breeding you know so like we're looking
for that new gem something that's
slightly different or completely
different I want I would love to find
something that's completely different
show me some uh you know some green tea
flavor or some red bean ice cream yeah
soing like a trino hunter yeah I'm I was
looking for weird stuff but so what have
you seen as far as like uh as far as new
genetics and new new flavors you you
love sativas and you love that stimulant
for it for the effect but also the
flavor I see yeah it's I I'll just say I
trust my nose it's hard to say um you
know I I am awful with these
conversations because I married a grower
and so whenever folks ask me like what's
my favorite um Mr Jones
finest what whatever he's doing uh is
got right now yeah
um he did finally after years of of
looking um he found a haze and we just
have a small garden we're not you know
this which everybody should have yeah
this is you know next to the tomatoes
and the basil Abol and we've got
chickens too so we get the yeah uh but
the yeah it's uh it just takes so damn
long that you can't find it on the
market is the problem because like the
super silver haze it's if if you can
turn over this many crops in a year
versus this many crops in a year you
know it's it's you know three to five is
a huge difference on to pull the money
out of it eight and a half week super
silver so it's really good I'm sorry
yeah so I'll talk to Jeff about that one
one more time yeah it's a short
flowering super silver we and a cross
bread with with a uh go ahead it's just
a short flowering version it's good okay
it's really good but there's you know
and then there's all kinds of stuff out
there I think there's some really good
hazes that are is a cross with an
Autoflower or was it is it I don't know
no it's good it's really good it just
works yeah yeah yeah all right yeah I
mean so and then people have gone
through a lot of things to find stuff
like that I'm sure it's crossed with
something but uh yeah you guys can check
it out I would love that I might even
have some flower here for you to check
out later to take home with you oh
goodness so yeah you're G spoil girl
I've been getting into the sativas too
as far as like uh the the piff going
back to some Classics though like the
piff and the Cuban black I've been
enjoying those quite a bit lately but
yeah I I enjoy a little bit of
everything so I like some stuff to wake
me up and I like some stuff to make me
tired and I'm always looking for
something different but yeah no and we
enjoy salads I think that's also the the
bigger reason that I struggle on you
know what's my favorite because we we
like to blend it's just a better
experience uh overall over time and yeah
it's uh the the good news is is he is so
good at what he does um and he is your
horiculture faculty not me so we uh well
we have several uh Joey oretta uh has
been uh just worldwide at this point
it's it's phenomenal the folks that
started you know just coming into our
classroom and teaching people how to
grow or now Masters of the Universe it's
it's phenomenal yeah well and it's a
repetition thing too like learning how
to grow and I [ __ ] it up oh am I
allowed to curse C you can [ __ ] it up
all you want already did it's too late
for that you can totally curse on the
show we we appreciate cursing it's okay
but yeah I think and that goes for
everything in life you should [ __ ] it up
a bunch like figure it out do experiment
you got to [ __ ] it up and then get back
up you really learn who you are in the
grow room outside the grow room uh by
making mistakes and I've made plenty of
mistakes I've made mistakes my whole
life and learned from them especially
growing and making seeds you know it's
like I've made seeds where I didn't have
pollen ready and my reversals didn't
work and screwed up everything well and
what I try to share you know with my
kids with my class is just you know try
not to make the same mistake over it
make new fresh mistakes each time yeah
as as a chef I would allow people to
make mistakes one time you know you make
the mistake one time oh you can make
different mistakes that's okay that's
part of the learning process exactly and
I think with cannabis and with
cultivation it's really good to make
mistakes because if you never make
mistakes you never learn because that's
that's the best way to learn is to screw
stuff up indeed and making room for that
is is important and coming from
hospitality and working with a multitude
of chefs uh I know you now yeah all
right I see
yeah but yeah the whole Chef mentality
and it's like uh get the job plus also
you got you have to have your stuff in
place everything in its place and I
think that's super important to be
prepared whether it's scheduling
scheduling is important but also do you
have all the things on hand that you're
going to need today or do you have to go
three times to the grow shop to get what
you need you know it's all proper
planning and and if you start applying
those things to life your life's going
to be become much easier indeed it's uh
I've gotten in the habit of of like
asking each day when I'm looking at my
schedule and what I'm doing am I moving
myself closer to my goals or further
away yeah uh because it is really what
you do that cumulatively turns out as
your life yeah those little choices
really add up yeah and what you do
throughout the day is what you do all
the time you know like it it everything
is so repetition based I think for most
of us if you're lazy part of the time
you're lazy all the time in my opinion
yeah and but then how do you also break
out of your own because as much as
repetition is is vital how do you also
break out of your own habits you know I
I talk about to do this every day this
industry is hard yeah I mean at Capital
H it is so difficult it gets harder
every day uh for new and different
reasons um and even just what's going to
happen next week uh with with the FED
just every yeah it's it's so tumultuous
and being able to both enjoy change take
it as you stress versus distress and you
know be able to stay Dynamic uh but I
try to like how do you get out of bed
every day and and keep it not not just
on the days you feel inspired days you
don't well I got a little secret it's uh
put one foot in front of the other yeah
right and that's it's tenacity and you
know there's day yeah it's doing stuff
on the days that you don't want to do it
that's what'll kind of Define you you
know what I what I tell people is that I
I don't only get up that day but I get
up at 4 in the morning that day and what
is your competition doing yeah and it's
the days you don't want to do it exactly
yeah exactly and I think it's just it's
it's a lot about discipline but it's
like doing stuff that you don't want to
do that's like cold plunge is the
perfect example I don't really going to
bed at eight and going to bed at well I
wish I went to bed at 8 well I go to bed
at 8 I just get cranky after 8 cuz I get
up at for yeah right yeah and well and
we need our sleep that's something that
I I appreciate sleep a lot more than I
used to well and it's what is in your
control and that's what I finally
realized a few years ago and I think it
was actually Ariana Huffington that made
it okay to talk about but you know I
used to pride myself on how much work
and how little sleep and and I realized
like at a certain point never mind
having a family and needing to find some
trade-offs but are you putting yourself
in an early grade like for whom where
who's going to build a [ __ ] statue
like what are you do so the one thing I
can control is how I eat and if I sleep
and so yeah I try to well and we all
need different amounts of sleep I think
to a degree but sleep is super important
and quality sleep is more important than
sleep in my opinion yeah what do they
say you're only at 70% if you don't get
enough yeah yeah so you just walk around
a dumbass all day yeah yeah totally I
don't want to be an idiot or an [ __ ]
so I try to get enough sleep yeah and
yeah for sure sleep is so important so
let that
be smoke too I used to smoke right
before I go to bed and I don't do that
anymore you know what I just discovered
I'm gonna out myself right now because
you know I've been I taught the damn
science class like this methods of
ingestion is my jam and um the science
of cannabis and why this works but I
could never consume Edibles like I would
it was just
like done like it could be you know
Saturday morning ready to go and just
I'm ready for a nap if if you even like
wait edible under my nose kind of thing
uh and yet I suffer from insomnia of the
worst degree and I just finally figured
out Edibles for sleeping uh is it like
two and a half milligrams uh yeah I oh a
little itty bitty like whatever edible
whatever little Gummy it takes me like
five days if I just kind of gnaw little
it little that and that was it is I just
I was having too much and it yeah I'm
the same way I'm AB so I did well you
know how I learned it was Delta so
delta8 when I was because I I go through
insomnia bouts and I'm sleeping really
well right now but for me it's like
exercise Cal plunge all these things by
the time yeah I don't sleep as much as I
probably should but I sleep really good
like when I sleep I sleep but if I am
going to take a sleeping pill I was
taking Delta eights but really Delta
eight is just 20% strength of Delta 9
THC so you can just take less Delta 9
and you get the same effect yeah and I I
think that it's but it's you know shake
it a little try stuff you haven't tried
in a while it's well it's experimenting
and knowing your body and I don't think
I think a lot of people rely on doctors
to tell them what they need when I think
doctors should be able to guide you this
is not taught in medical school no no
they don't even teach about the
endocannabinoid system no they don't and
I think but but like knowing your body
the only one who's going to know your
body is you know you can rely on doctors
for stuff but you should know your body
better than any doctor and what you need
this is truly the difficulty I think
with cannabinoids and cannabis first off
it's not water soluble and all the easy
drugs are water soluble right so the the
fact that it's it's hydrophobic is not
helpful for really anything testing all
that you've got to like burn it to test
it in a lot of ways how hard it is to
work with you know and Equipment gets
sticky everything it's it's uh it's it's
not friendly um the way you know say the
bark of a willow tree is which you know
fun fact women used to get burned at the
steak over and now it's aspirin um so
the the fact that it's so hard to to
work with number one but uh number two
because it affects each of us
differently and I think of a pendulum
right and you know each each of us our
pendulum swings differently how much
sleep did you get how much coffee did
you drink water exercise did your spouse
or partner just piss you off what you
know all kinds of things did the
cherries just pop in your rear view you
know all of these things can affect your
state of mind and how cannabis affects
you right from day to day hour to hour
so the same dose or uh whatever it is
you're consuming can affect you
differently even from Thursday to Friday
yeah uh and so for for for you to find
homeostasis for you to find that Center
of your own swinging pendulum um it's
it's really we we've always focused on
just teaching titration um and
moderation you know you're you're also
just wasting your money if you're
smoking too much like save it for the
next guy but uh yeah just um you know
taking unless you are the type of
medical patient where cannabis you know
if you have Ms or Parkinson's where you
really can't function without it but if
if you're someone who is just you know
consuming commonly as much for adult use
as for medicine just even taking a break
every once in a while and listening to
your own body because Canabis is so
effective across different symptoms and
systems I worry for just a delay of
diagnosis that something that is wrong
with you is being treated by cannabis
but not cured and what are you ignoring
because the only doctor you go to is
your pot dock yeah yeah and that's why
good pot docks at least touch you you
know they take your pulse they look for
these things Dr Frank Leo he just
retired sir I'm so sad he is a giant he
T years ago yeah I mean I've been seen
Frank since 2000 I think maybe 99 to get
my first I'll introduce you to Dr T Rand
maybe he'll pick you up as a yeah Frank
Frank Lucio he's quite quite the
character and a really really great guy
and uh good luck in your retirement I
just I think yeah Che cheers to cheers
to luo I mean yeah he was such a game
changer and he wrote a recommendation
for cannabis for my friend's younger
brother who was 14 he was willing to do
it yeah he was willing to do it and he
was the only one willing to there was
nobody else that would do anything like
that and he was quite and this this is
back in 1999 yeah 98 maybe actually when
he wrote that um he was very brave yeah
yeah indeed and it was it was Dr Todd
marcaria who passed away in 2007 that
was uh you know help found the medical
cannabis Association who helped push for
that early testing that finally helped
us realize that I mean it's like the
Amazon rainforest in this in this one
plant and now it's just chased the
varietals and and try to say we don't
even know what we don't know we're just
unconsciously unskilled about all of
this Scrat surface and that's what's so
exciting is what next totally and we got
guys like ddy mu in Israel which he's
really you know he's paved the way for a
lot of people and and you know we got
front- range biosciences and we've got
you know medicinal genomics and guys
really going on the the genetics side
which are really impressive but what
they're doing over in Israel is really
impressive because there's way less red
tape so they can do actual testing and
this all comes back toed research yeah
which is
crazy so we can do it we can do yeah
we're getting there and we're going to
do it there's no way we're not going to
do it it just blows my mind that we're
not there yet we just have to keep
demanding it and yeah which and and you
know it's it's hard because Biden he is
not our biggest fan and I don't you know
it's uh well so silly because I mean I
know whose fan he is a fan he's a fan of
and it's not us no so
unfortunately uh but you know things
change and we evolve and the thing is is
like the younger generation is so much
more educated about can and so many more
people have tried cannabis and people
it's it's normalized to the younger
generation so over time things will
change indeed and it is uh and this is
why education is so important uh because
good Lord our children will inherit the
earth and uh you know the the fear the
stigma uh it for so long in California
we were trying to convince people that
the sky will not fall Chicken Little
like cats won't sleep with dogs and if
they do that's cute like nothing bad
happens it's it's everything going to be
okay um this is
not you know and marijuana Madness I
dare say is one of the most effective
marketing campaigns ever yeah uh and and
the most believed uh and and the most
false uh but it's it's hard to get out
um you know I was a dare kid uh I
actually went in and talked
D actually one of our graduates was one
of uh Hassan Rashad was one of the
little black kids that she grabbed to go
stand to her to just say no to drugs on
the on the national stage yeah and now
he's a oer dam graduate that's right
really wild yeah I remember the the
commercial this is your brain and this
is your brain on drugs crack Sizzle oh
yeah and just you know getting getting
over that and now you know I I
have young people walk up to me and
they're like I've wanted to do this my
whole life yeah how old are you and I do
the math I'm like oh [ __ ] first off I'm
old and then I feel I feel you you're
not
old it is their whole life yes good
genetics um but it's yeah Irish uh they
don't remember when it was more
dangerous to get
caught uh it it's and and so many you
know just don't don't understand and
don't appreciate and how lucky that they
don't have to think about it the problem
with that though is we're not there yet
no and we're still ripping babies from
their mother's breasts we're still
arresting 17-year-old Hispanic kids
because that's who's getting pulled over
is black and brown and Indigenous no
matter where you live that they're still
more likely to get shaken down for
whatever it is uh and and go to jail now
because they're underage uh you know we
we really need to take the teeth out of
the criminality so that because you know
the cops that I've met in the field by
and large you know the frothing
prohibitionists or the LOB lists they're
the ones that represent the police
officers associations most cops on the
street you want a good laugh ask them
about the last marijuana bus that they
were scared for their life yeah you know
there that is not their biggest concern
out there it is a tool in their toolbox
they're like if you take this tool out
I'll simply use another tool I just need
to know where the damn line is and tell
me what what matters to you community
and then once we change that line you
know that our cops here in California
are still being taught police officer
standard training post training is still
the training of the 90s that we're all a
bunch of just druggy drug addled idiots
and and you should go crack some skulls
and all of this is just a bunch of
[ __ ] they're still being taught the
old standard and so we also have to
demand at the same time that we're all
educating ourselves and and good Lord
come out to your mom if you haven't yet
that you are a Canabis consumer yeah uh
that you know that have the conversation
with the people that love you of why you
choose this and
and what happens uh you know show them
your success not not just your your
goofy side but you know it's it's just
continuing the conversation and
remembering that there are folks on the
right side of prohibition but there are
still folks on the wrong side of
prohibition and and that again we're
just we're not done yet there are still
people sitting in prison as we speak on
this issue more than you can possibly
imagine yeah and we're not it's just for
nonviolent drug offenses nonviolent and
in fact some of the most egregious they
were Rico cases my friend they weren't
even caught with cannabis or cash it was
just some other criminal them yeah Rich
delisi he was on the show you know he
did 32 years he spent 32 years in prison
Behind Bars it is a travesty and they're
leaving young children behind and moms
that are trying to raise those kids and
moms are giving birth in shackles still
in Texas we are not done yet right and
and you know if you've got that great
Aunt Betty in Texas give her a call
about this you know her Governor her
legislature need to hear it but you know
if if you live in in my district you
know call the ones to vote for it too
yeah because otherwise they only get
called to like get yelled at of what
they yeah people are pissed sometimes
you got to call them and say thank you
good job do that again Texas is so
strange though oh Texas is so strange
conversation about Texas now so my
parents live in Texas how many people we
going to piss off yeah yeah totally are
you from Texas I should ask that first
no we're good all right you don't want
to piss off the right totally my parents
live in Texas yeah our founder lives in
Texas yeah we had a lot of students and
Texas is like started they're okay with
CBD now yeah hemp's great hemp is great
yeah CBD is great they have stores that
sell thca could we replace the Attorney
General could we agree on that maybe oh
that's a rough one yeah I mean I'd love
to go for the governor but let's just
start with the attorney general yeah
well I mean I think the people are
starting to demand change and the people
are you know we got Austin there's a lot
of Californians going out there to Texas
I don't that's what I'm hoping we'll
just kind of change it to they're like
change changing the landscape out there
what register to vote friends but yeah
and I I like Texas for what Texas yeah
some of the stuff in Texas well and and
I'll wrap this back to the beginning of
the conversation uh cuz I'll do that for
you which is you know the the Christian
conservative right so Richard's mom and
Lee founded ramp Republicans against
marijuana prohibition and so she is
showing up to CAC over the years and
having this conversation and then all of
a sudden you know rep boner is now
repping cannabis so you know there's
there's a lot of change that uh comes
from both sides of the aisle and this is
one of the things that we can all agree
on we can sit around that campfire
probably won't sing Kumbaya uh but at
the end of the day but that's okay
depending on where you live it's the
Dems that are standing in the way so you
know this isn't a red or blue issue and
and frankly um it it it's an American
issue yeah Agreed 100% it's an American
issue and we as Americans should be
addressing it it doesn't matter what
side you're on left or right you know
it's like it just needs to be addressed
by all of us and at least thought of
Thoroughly by all of us I think if
because if you thoroughly think about it
you'll understand that it's not a bad
thing and legalization is the best thing
for all of us a lot of folks say
James it's weed like this is not my top
10 yeah I don't it's I've got so many
other things to worry about all right
well what is in your top 10 and let's
talk about how marijuana prohibition has
[ __ ] that up right you know is it your
kids is it your schools because right
now we're more interested in putting
people in jail still than in school uh
you know where are all these resources
going uh and and what are the cops
focused on you know there we have rape
kits that have sat on shelves for over a
decade because they're so focused on
testing that green [ __ ] in that little
bag finding out whether or not it's what
something that's never killed anyone
except for one recently uh that and that
I think is more of a Workforce issue
dust it's not that was asthma
related exactly I just wanted to
acknowledge her death because uh it was
attributed officially to cannabis um but
you know at the end of the day it's it's
we uh used to say it takes it takes
about a ton um to to kill you um falling
from about 10 feet know that you have to
be crushed physically by the Cannabis
yeah I mean I've tried it just didn't
well you have to they say if you smoke
um five pounds uh or 10 pounds in five
minutes I think so like smoke the
telephone pole outside in under five
minutes but it's not even the Cannabis
that kills you it's the CO2 poisoning um
lack of O exactly and you can't eat
enough you'll split your gut before the
Cannabis itself can kill you so you know
and it is a conversation to have is we
are moving so much of this into Labs
especially to to like subjugate the law
you know that we we've been contorting
CBD and hemp you may feel like you want
to die from overc consuming but it is
not gonna kill you not GNA kill you but
we but there there there are now and and
you know I'm not I'm not here to be an
alarmist but but there are these are new
constituents that are being created and
we we don't fully understand the safety
profile or how long it stays in the
system again we just have to understand
like what you are doing in the lab to
convert delta8 what what what magic are
you doing behind the scenes because you
know a lot of the stuff it's not you
know vaporizing is one of the healthiest
ways to consume Canabis but not if
they're adding vitamin E acetate to make
it more viscous and give you a bigger
puff of smoke that could kill you so
what are we adding how cheap is that
metal uh that you're heating up and
and Main Ling to your brain is Delta a
bad for you we don't know we don't know
we probably probably not if you're using
good starting material you know it's if
we're talking about an enzyme using
enzymes as a pathway to convert it I
mean it and we know as well and this is
I think a larger issue is is that
because cannabis and hemp same plant are
bioaccumulator
that a lot of folks are buying what they
can find which is Industrial Hemp which
is not fit for human consumption and
because it's a bioaccumulator where was
that grown if it was grown in China or
Russia because we were the number one
importers for from Russia up until
recently uh and China as a matter of
fact of hemp uh and and what is that
grown in what kind of heavy metals
radioactivity
Chernobyl now the good news of that is
Reclamation you know we've had students
come in from Japan after Fukushima
having whole conversations about how
hemp can help reate that soil because it
can right and so this is what I think is
like the biggest travesty of like wow
aside from prohibition this is what we
really got wrong we have we we've
whiffed on the benefits of hemp and and
there was this brief moment where there
was a gold rush towards hemp but they
forgot oh [ __ ] we got to process it and
and oh we need a market to sell it to
like oops you know we you forgot to
build out the full supply chain but so
close mhm but in the meanwhile all of
the opportunities for for fiber and Fuel
and building materials and all everybody
wants to do is go convert Delta 8 like
that's all that matters is let's go
compete with the legal cannabis market
and meanwhile the legal cannabis Market
is struggling under all these B the the
taxes and and the burdens and then is
selling the same [ __ ] at Circle K right
yeah it's it's a tough one and you know
there's so many uses for for hemp it's
unbelievable you know hemp cre bio
remediation soil remediation it's the
largest just growing in the ground it is
the largest carbon sink crop we can
plant yeah like we can do it people yeah
just we have the knowledge let's just
apply it Con Johnny apple seed James
just give me the seeds all spread across
yeah that's what I'm saying like let's
go you get the helicopter I'll see you
in South Dakota right come on chrisy
I'll see you soon yeah I mean I saw
something on a Indian Reservation that
that's got funded for uh hemp creete and
so they're going to be doing hemp creete
which I think is great it is so exciting
yeah when you start to really study with
building materials and what that can do
to to start to offset carbon which is
all we keep talking about and the longer
it sits there the more carbon it
continues to accumulate from what I
understand as well it it and it just
gets stronger over time um yeah there's
it's
we've really got to figure out how to
unstick this stuck and again I've got to
go back to
descheduling because I don't
see again I get incremental but you've
got to shoot for the flipping stars to
catch the moon or next door yeah right
and if we just keep settling for good
enough we're never going to get to good
yeah we we can do is a bad thing and you
know at at the end of the day I just I
hope people just keep showing up and and
this is something we one of the things I
try to leave uh are graduates which I
call Oaker Dam grad Gladiators uh
they're the first through the wall
sometimes get bloody make money you're
trained fighter right and uh you've got
to advocate for yourself for your
business for your choice uh for your
freedom and that means showing up to
vote and showing up for jury duty and
look I get that same like a God damn it
every time I get the jury duty and then
I remind myself you know it still goes
down California uh what what's going on
in Arkansas and the ability to get on a
a jury that is trying a marijuana case
and you know jury immunity is something
that a lot of us uh missed in Civics
that you're not just judging the
defendant you're judging the very law
that put him there and you can hang that
jury uh because marijuana isn't a crime
right yeah totally so if you had one
piece of advice for yourself going back
to the younger self that was in the
industry for one year or two years what
would that one piece of advice
be get over yourself uh I was I was in a
position to have even more
conversations than I did in rooms with
uh you know i' I've had a lot of
conversations with powerful people but
I've also been in rooms with with folks
that I just didn't want to
ask I had a hard time asking for help
and having that conversation and just
getting over the
no I I wish I had asked more yeah uh
because I I I regret those things I
don't regret most of the stuff I've done
I regret those missed opportunities
because by not asking by not talking it
wasn't no yeah I never opened my mouth
uh so yeah I think just you know tell
your story and and don't don't be afraid
you're bothering people I still feel
that way like I'm not going to bother
them they don't even talk to me and then
later on like damn it why didn't I just
go shake their hand and thank them for
their trouble so yeah I would say just
get over
yourself I feel you it's hard it's hard
to get over yourself isn't it sometimes
sometime yeah sometimes it can be hard
um so now where do you you see yourself
in five years with still with Oaker Dam
doing your thing with oaksterdam and I
bleed green and gold that's awesome yeah
this um so we were rated in 2012 and
that was by the uh the Obama
Administration yeah and that's when I
took over the school um this is Legacy
at this point for me it started with my
husband almost 30 years ago and it came
back to our family um we you know I
still see myself talking to to Congress
I've had the opportunity to talk to
several other governments of other
countries but I still um need to be on
the on the on that that floor and and
the be again we're we're not done yet
and and the good news about education
James is we're never done there's always
more to learn and whatever the
government decides to do there's more to
do and whatever state you live in uh
whatever country you live in uh whatever
it is you love about the plant you know
it's there's I know genetics and growing
cultivation I strongly recommend that
everyone like plant a seed and try it uh
you know and and the development that we
are doing with the school um you know
they they made a movie about it uh
there's documentary out now um that you
can catch in various film festivals uh
that that really captures the the
history of of the end of prohibition it
captured legalization uh in the journey
uh nearly nearly there and so also just
making sure that folks catch the that
fire see the film take a class um and
and find ways to to better themselves
whether it's just as a patient trying to
understand how this affects them or
their nephew coming out of school and
looking for a new career uh I think
Workforce Development and uh helping
people rise in their careers which
ironically is how I started in life and
now I'm doing it for the Cannabis
industry and it's just beautiful to see
and hear the governments that I now work
with spewing the same thing that I was
saying with a microphone in 2007 when
people thought we were [ __ ] crazy
yeah it is amazing uh to to see the
change and and we try to encourage
people to be lifelong Learners and uh
it's it's really just where do you want
to grow from here yeah yeah well the
second you get rid of ego you realize
that there is there's no Mastery it's
all Improvement it's a practice it is
and it's if you love it you get up and
you do it and you learn from what you're
doing every day you need learn from
other people and it's also ever evolving
and changing so it is amazing that you
just brought me back to the one thing
that I didn't finish earlier which is uh
fall in love with the problem yeah don't
fall in love with your Solution that's
how you get stagnant fall in love with
the problem you're trying to solve and
it never gets old you always stay at the
cusp of like what's new what's next
something moved how can I torque it now
you know shifted go pull it push it do
it just get up and do it yeah be
Solutions based yeah but identify the
problem indeed and and by all means be
part of the solution not the problem
absolutely indeed well thank you so much
for coming on the show today it's been a
lot of fun it has thank you for inviting
me and I hope to encourage more females
on your show you know Growers love
females so yeah we're looking for
females guys yeah and so if somebody's
looking to find you and where can they
find out more about oaksterdam and you
have Instagram or where should they go
yes I am Dale Sky Jones and so you can
find me on Instagram and well all of all
of the the whatnots and such things and
oaksterdam university.com oaksterdam
dcom is is really a hub uh that is is
growing every year and I think that's
what's most exciting is we are also
evolving and so if you've ever been to
Oaker d uh we're not who you remember
come meet the new oer dam awesome indeed
well thank you so much thank you James
have a beautiful afternoon and the rest
of
[Music]
you