foreign
[Music]
how's it going everyone welcome to the
James loud podcast today my guest is
Chris Castle from floor and Flame how
you doing Chris doing fantastic thanks
for having me James awesome so Chris was
actually
the guest of my show that never aired we
we did it we did a pilot of the James
loud podcast in San Francisco it wasn't
really what we wanted for lighting you
know the context everything was good the
stuff we talked about was amazing but uh
yeah it's never gonna air we might share
it with friends and stuff like that down
the road but how you doing I'm doing
great man I'm glad you drugged me away
from the facility from work for a little
bit so we could do this yeah awesome
so we also filmed the cultivation
episode at your facility before you guys
were live like I guess you were live you
were just in the first couple weeks
before you had finished product
definitely yeah before our first harvest
yeah and so Chris does something really
special uh Chris go you grow livingsoil
at scale
which
I haven't seen done successfully too
much in the recreational world it's just
a very difficult thing to do
um what's your take on it yeah and also
we grow vertically on a tiered system
which makes it even crazier I don't know
anyone that's growing like you said
living soil and a two-tiered uh system
it's been quite the learning experience
to put it lightly I've been working on
this project for about six years
full-time we've been in operation at the
facility since August and it was all
ground up construction awesome
you guys do a real good job I I was
questioning when I first heard about you
guys were doing double stacked uh double
stacked in a huge tall room of living
soil beds and these beds have to weigh a
sh I don't know 1200 pounds of bed yes
and that's and then you do 1200 on yeah
it's wild 40 40 foot long runs uh
10 lights on the bottom 10 lights on top
and your rollers roll effortlessly yeah
they use like uh like a bicycle gear
type system uh it's from Montel racking
they're like a French Canadian group but
fantastic stuff and so you're doing a
no-till living soil correct I call it
low till like no-till would be not
disturbing the soil or the top soil at
all I say we are disturbing the topsoil
maybe the first couple inches or a few
inches so I'd call it low till just if
you want to get technical sure yeah and
your flower's great I think I think it's
gotten better actually you've done a cut
what this is on your second run now oh
gosh finished product or third run right
we just harvested our fourth room oh wow
yes but yeah definitely each room is
getting more dialed in just better and
better quality awesome poison gushers
yeah what do you think of poison gushers
different
um definitely the definition of exotic
in terms of its terpene composition yeah
tested over like two around 2.2 percent
but just based off of the composition
um would put it in an exotic class it's
not something you would taste or smell
typically in the California market and
that's because of its parents Afghani
times gushers so that Afghani um gives
it something really unique with the
sweet uh profile from the gushers yeah
yeah yeah what checks the Box yeah as
far as like it checks all the boxes
actually in my opinion I mean it has the
has a little bit of candy it has a
little bit of color it actually has
really good color fantastic color the
structure is amazing
and it's it's loud it's really loud
I would put it up there with maybe you
know other unicorn strains because it
does check like all the boxes that
people are looking for in the market I
think the biggest thing is just getting
people to get more familiar with it
right once we kind of get it out there
and uh have more people try it I think
they'll it'll create a bigger demand no
one has that cultivar on the west coast
so it's exclusive to us yeah I haven't
seen it anywhere yeah thanks Justin
appreciate it Justin uh yeah my partner
Justin he's now your partner too yeah
tissue culture and he does amazing work
I think uh you know start clean stay
clean that's his motto and he provides
amazing
amazing genetics it makes all the the
difference in terms of cultivation I
mean more vigorous plants are going to
get a better yield
um just a healthier overall better
program totally yeah so on my show what
we're going to do is a little bit of
blind tasting sweet and so we have three
different products here we have a one
that could be under any one of these
that's a five dollar or less gram we
have one that's a ten dollar or less and
one that's a 15 or more
and we're gonna smoke them blindly
without checking out the packaging
without even checking out the bud and
you're going to give me your thought on
what you think it is and then at the end
we'll do a grand reveal sounds great
I'll do it
can I dry it at first absolutely that's
a great idea
kind of bland not very terpy I think
it's Hydro it's all California wheat
yeah
yeah I definitely think it's Hydro
definitely think it's Hydro yeah for
sure
foreign
make sure it's burning evenly
there's chirps
within the California wreck Market what
I've seen is across the board you know
it's hard to predict what's what Terps
is usually a giveaway but not always
your stuff is super terpy but it also
Burns way cleaner and I think the thing
with the living soil is the effect
definitely so and I think that's why you
can charge more for it besides the fact
that it costs more to produce and it's
more of a pain in the ass I feel like
the initially initially over time it'll
it'll definitely save money right
so what kind of cost per pound are we
looking at typically with living soil uh
just on average we'll be able to get it
under 400 eventually yeah under 400 yeah
what kind of lighting are you guys using
we're going with fluence uh right now
we're using their spider 2ps yeah I
think they're about like 635 Watts I've
tested out probably like seven or eight
different LED companies before we chose
fluence we're actually going to be doing
their trial runs for their new fixtures
too which is really exciting for their
three PS I think is what they're called
so what I've noticed with the California
Market is
three years ago it was all [ __ ] and
like not all [ __ ] I shouldn't say
that but even some of the brands that
were like in the black market crushing
they came in the white market and it
sucked yeah I'm not gonna name names or
anything like that but it's really
interesting now I feel like even some of
the cheaper stuff is good and some of
the top tier you know stuff it's just
all over the board 100
inconsistency is tough I'm gonna take
one more hit of this yeah yeah go on to
the next but
um you put it out yeah
um no I think you're totally right I
think um the lower
quality is coming up even with the
cheaper or bigger produced Brands yeah
100 I mean I took a visit to one of the
bigger farms in Santa Barbara yeah I
think that close to a million square
feet of canopy oh yeah glass house it
was not glass house really is another
group I can't say sure
um I was blown away by their quality I
was like damn they're producing this at
scale like it's catching up I mean
granted a lot of that is being used for
extracts but but still I mean at scale
but I feel like there's a certain point
at scale that you cannot control
everything no matter what you look at
the boutique guys you look at this you
know there's there's this you know I
mean it's gotten bigger that I feel like
it's scaled up but there is definitely a
you know you pass the that threshold and
you cannot control the quality the same
as the guy who has 20 lights the guy who
has 100 lights you know I'm seeing guys
that you know that have a thousand
lights that are producing pretty [ __ ]
good weed and I want to try to show
people because where Adam about 8 000
square feet of canopy maybe 8 500 but I
want to show people we can put out
consistent quality Boutique flower
round after round Harvest after harvest
right I don't think anyone's been able
to like really do that consistently yeah
it's really difficult I mean there's 70
days in the life of a plant you screw up
one day
oh game over it's like screwing up one
year of a life of you know some a person
yeah so uh what do you think about that
first smoke that we had do you think
it's five dollars or less ten dollars or
less or fifteen dollars or more
what can I try the other two first
before or do I well just let me know
what you think and then you can change
it too okay
um either a five or ten dollar gram that
would be my guess
I'll give you my final answer at the end
your final final Final
remember the old hemp Wicks oh yeah you
gotta use a lighter to light the hemp
click and then I used to be big on those
thinking I was getting more flavor but
then I uh a buddy of mine he told me he
was like we got to think about no one's
actually testing the hemp wig for like
any kind of like chemicals or anything
so it's like you might as well be
smoking some butane yeah at a whatever a
few parts per million then not knowing
what you're actually smoking with the
hemp wig what do you think about the
drama with Josh and raw right now you
heard about any of that stuff ah I
didn't know I mean I just don't even
have time to like read into that stuff
I'm so like this literally in the weeds
right now yeah you're it's going crazy
over there and then people calling in
sick oh my gosh I mean it's you're not
just growing weed like I have to worry
about like right now network issues
mechanical equipment issues managing
people people calling out sick you know
it's just it's endless but yeah it's a
great learning experience and I'm
grateful that I get to do this every day
for a living
yeah I mean I think I know times are
tough all over it's it's great to be
able to have a job be able to do what we
love
you know if you look back at your 18
year old self would your 18 year old
self be happy with your be like hell
yeah you're going to do this no I was
super into cannabis even at 18 19.
that's when I really started like
getting into cultivation yeah
um actually growing some you know maybe
like five or six lights growing some
Tangerine Dream driving it down to Santa
Monica selling it to you know some
Armenians at the dispensary for like
four or five grand a pound that's when I
like really fell in love with the plant
um I definitely didn't think I'd be
doing this but
it was definitely a dream of mine then
so I'm like it's it's crazy that life
has come back full circle
yeah so uh what year was the first year
you smoked this already went out that
tells you something maybe this is the
five dollar gram right here
or maybe it's the 50s they tricked this
it's all
it's all lies it's all lies true it's
burning a little black too
yeah so the first one we didn't get an
oil ring off it but it did burn but oil
oil ring could just be the tightness of
the joint too well there's a lot to it
yeah I do like a good Oil ring on my
joints though see how black this is
though that is black yeah but yeah and
this was white yeah that bird white yeah
that burned pretty good
it was it it wasn't smooth but it burned
pretty well yeah it definitely wasn't
smooth you got a little initially you
got a lot of Terps but then the chirps
kind of faded a little bit
um most strains don't do good in a joint
all the way through well I think most
Growers don't grow good weeding to make
it taste good all the way through
because oh did you hear that guys yeah I
mean I think that has a lot to do with
it it's definitely genetic yeah there's
definitely truth to that but I think
that a lot of guys don't grow good
enough and that's the thing with so for
instance for breeding right like you
talk about guys that are breeding
um the hardest part about breeding is
not making the seeds it's doing the
selections being able to grow the weed
good enough so you can make selections I
think a lot of people were missing out
on that part you know yeah there's some
guys doing really good
a lot of guys are just making seeds and
it's like making seeds as a breeder like
that's not really breeding breeding is
doing the selections
um
yeah I was just up north at House of
cultivar going through some selections
that they got up there man they got some
crazy stuff some news so yeah some of
the stuff I made with Jason up there and
I mean you're making some crazy stuff
like like the seeds we pop for the
flower contest yeah that's gonna be a
good one everyone's hyped off of those
twenty thousand dollar grand prize June
1st uh ten thousand dollars dollars goes
to charity and then ten thousand dollars
goes in your pocket I love the charity
aspect dude that's so great yeah I feel
like we're our industry should be more
about community and you know I feel like
doing the right thing we're already
doing the right thing by growing weed in
my opinion you know I think that
cannabis is something that should be
shared with everybody and I think making
seeds you're putting out amazing stuff
you know I think it's it's a positive
action growing cannabis is a positive
action it's something good for all of us
yeah 100 I agree man it's medicine
did go out again and what do you think
on that one you think the five the less
than 10 or the more than 15. I mean the
industry is so deceiving dude that could
be a 15 gram you know and we don't even
know it my opinion that should be the
five dollar gram I mean that tasted like
it just tasted like wheat like not even
weed like wet weed it did taste a little
wet I I just it also was a super dry
super yeah at the same time yeah right
well and there is you know like as far
as like testing and moisture content
that can be an issue with compliance and
everything else yeah definitely
so well should we get on to the last one
I guess are you ready yeah and then
we're gonna try some ears because yeah
[ __ ] yeah we gotta smoke some good weed
we gotta we gotta and it was some good
stuff but I feel like we won't be high
enough
we gotta redeem ourselves
you smoke cigars also no I don't I don't
smoke tobacco I don't smoke tobacco
either but I do like the occasional
cigar but I won't do blunts I mean even
though that's cigar but it's just not my
thing I used to do blends growing up
everyone smoked blind so it's the
easiest thing to roll
yeah one of my friends died from
esophageal cancer about three years ago
and
when he got diagnosed was like when I
quit smoking cigarettes completely I
mean I didn't smoke a lot of cigarettes
but socially I would smoke a cigarette
here there you know you have a drink
which I'm trying not to drink now that's
my new thing is like uh
it's been
10 days it'll be 10 days tomorrow dude
so are you going to Spain though so
we'll see how that holds up everyone's
saying Oh no you're gonna drink in Spain
but I really don't
I don't plan on drinking in Spain we'll
see what happens I like gin and tonics
yeah dude the food's gonna be fantastic
over there the food is epic yeah the
food is absolutely I mean it's one of my
favorite places I'm going with Justin I
got some friends over there I get a lot
of friends the people I get to only see
once a year sometimes yeah you know and
everybody from around the world that
likes good weed you know a lot of them
are there real real connoisseurs real
aficionados you went last year too right
yes I gotta go with you guys I've had
booths there several times uh I'm gonna
be in the greenhouse Booth I got a table
set up I'm not doing my own booth this
year uh Aryan from Greenhouse invited me
to be in his Booth so we'll be slaying
seeds out of his Booth I'm doing my new
drop with all the stuff we got you know
the sour diesel which is uh the Skittles
back cross times the sour diesel It's
the weasels diesel
some good stuff dude that is awesome
that's super exciting what was uh what
was the cross that you did for the
contest so that's zerio's which is
cereal milk times zerbert times the zbx
which is the Skittles back cross it's
the original Skittles I think they're
all fire I love Skittles but it's got to
be all Skittles man that diet Skittle
stuff yeah no one wants that no and I
talk a lot about the diet diet Skittle
I'm not a huge fan you got to have
something complex moonbow for example I
love moonbow Yeah from archived that's a
great Skittles cross
um I love candy we I got a juice box
from loud canogenics which I'm part of
okay the juice boxes Skittles times
gelato 41 that [ __ ] is fire okay all
right
um
we're getting a little oil
yeah actually it's the rain shadow runts
that's the [ __ ] uh
bring Shadow runs to the Skittles that's
an award-winning Shane too it's super
fire
41. that's Skittles times g41 okay
gotcha yep that sounds amazing yeah it's
fire
and you know so what's your opinion on
uh gas is it making a comeback I know
you got some fire go geog that shit's or
not Goji it's a Pine-Sol yeah it's a
Goji OG Fino and I'm glad you called it
gas because some people get gas confused
with fire or Zaza weed gas is just the
profile for OG
um but yeah we have the pine saw from
Bodhi uh very interesting doesn't smell
like your typical OG Fino uh we do have
the jungle cake yeah which is the Wi-Fi
times wedding cakes super strong by the
way I smoked that [ __ ] and it [ __ ]
yeah that was that that's some good
stuff yeah
okay so what is your take on the third
one that tastes probably the first one
might have been the terpiest that one
wasn't bad
um this one doesn't burn as much it
doesn't burn as much it wasn't harsh uh
wasn't super chirpy but it wasn't bad
I'm gonna say 15 5 and 10.
fifteen five and ten yeah fifteen five
and ten
okay so the first one
let me move this joint to the back here
delighted delighted
this
is the lesson five
or five or less really okay creepiest
one was who would have thought yeah and
uh they're Smalls but they smoke really
good yeah that wasn't bad yeah
and this was the five
that's what I said yeah that was the
harshest backpack boys oh this backpack
boys is uh chocolato
yeah that was a little harsh and burned
a little bit it was pretty harsh pretty
black uh the first one was uh
alien cookies Times cushman's by the way
so that's what the delighted was the
alien cookies times cushman's that's a
good cross yeah I feel like it was
Turkey yeah you know I mean maybe it
could be grown a little bit better but
for the price
it's not too bad yeah
so the last one you've heard of
preferred Gardens yeah preferred salad
preferred crushed it do you like that I
mean was that that was their indoor or
Greenhouse
I think this is indoor
but uh yeah it's 33 THC I don't see any
outdoor
popping numbers like that really no that
I mean that wasn't bad no no it looks
like indoor and it looks like indoor
flower yeah so it wasn't super chirpy
but yeah it wasn't bad
nice it wasn't but if it was smooth it
didn't burn like the first one no so
so who would have thought the backpack
boys you know I think uh it what Terps
did you taste did you taste any on that
one no none I didn't taste them I didn't
either yeah it wasn't terrible but it
wasn't like it had bad flavor but it
just didn't have like I mean we're
[ __ ] spoiled in California and like
we're weed snobs so
yeah it's gonna taste good you gotta
taste good if you fired the road chip
the next day that's my you know
if I can smoke it a week later and it
still tastes like good I think we have
something for you nice I think that'll
do the trick so oh is that poison
gushers what are we smoking on the
poison gushers and uh it was hand rolled
from professional joint roller does some
super super super great work
got a logo on there what's his name by
the way Chris his name is Chris Chris is
going to come on the show I've been
talking to getting him on the show I
think he does a really good job he wrote
some bigger joints as well yeah but
they're actual joints I like big
crutches it's a very California style
totally
um yeah exciting yeah fire tastes good
all the way through
we're gonna get the special letter after
this one
it doesn't die
I like my torch lighters yeah as a cigar
smoker for many years no it's a it's
appropriate if you want to light the
joint evenly
yeah I'm a member of this club called
wingtip in San Francisco is that a cigar
club
they do have a cigar lounge
but uh so they got a cigar lounge they
have like
well some of the best food in the city
and during covid they were one of the
only places that was opened it was open
for business and stuff like that but
and uh yeah so they have a wine bar and
they have you know a really good bar but
uh good food really good food really
good staff the people that are cool and
then as far as like they have a smoking
Lounge smoking jackets and all that
stuff so you smoke weed there
no no
yeah yeah I mean you're not supposed to
smoke weed there but
I mean I'm not surprised you're a member
of like a Swanky club like that with you
being a former chef and all I mean are
you friends with like the owners or like
no no it's just a social club okay so
drink covid the reason I was a member
was you couldn't go out to eat they
closed all these restaurants and I like
good food and my friends like good food
so we ended up going there several times
a week at one point wait you didn't want
to cook for everyone well no we did that
too we did I mean I I would say that uh
you know from not working in the
restaurant industry anymore I definitely
got my fixed drink covered because we
always had parties at our houses our
friends had parties picked more wagyu
with my friends and yes
Pursuit Farms so Eric from Pursuit Farms
amazing dude uh
actually uh I introduced him to one of
my friends and he's growing these
amazing pigs and they're feeding a hemp
oh awesome so among other things I think
he's brewing a beer right now he's gonna
freaking feed the beer to him too uh
Japanese style oh that's awesome
so how's that smoking so far I feel like
this is uh uh 20 and up you know I'm
guessing 20 and up perps are good
I could smoke this one all day how
smooth is it it's really smooth do you
know what kind of papers he's using no
it'd be a good question to ask for sure
I like them I like the pattern on these
papers too but you got a nice Oil ring
on yours yeah but also that's credit to
how it's rolled to 100 for sure
we didn't even use the coffee didn't
need it
I do like the smell of coffee yeah
definitely
yeah it's interesting the California
Market is pretty uh
interesting in the sense that it's
freaking in its infancy you know where
it's going to be in 10 years 20 years 30
years or more
I mean who knows who knows we try to
compare it to alcohol all the time and I
think there is some interesting
comparisons to Prohibition and the end
of prohibition and cannabis there's
there's similarities but it's a it's a
different Beast I mean we have a
completely different I think cannabis
which there's more varieties of cannabis
than any other cultivated species of
anything yeah
um
yeah that says one thing about it you
know it's pretty impressive yeah no I
mean like you said we're just in its
infancy so I mean we have a long ways to
go I think anyone that tries to predict
anything about the future of our
industry especially in California or our
country they just don't don't know no
one knows what's going on seriously
yeah so what's your uh you think they're
gonna get rid of uh
traditional HPS and make everyone go LED
I think they already did I know but do
you think that's gonna really hold up
and you know I mean I guess it'll be
what's your opinion on it uh one I think
it's a great thing I mean you're using
LED too though right yeah we're using
the fluence I mean it's hard not to use
LED just because of the cost you know of
running anything else yeah if you're
doing anything at scale the cost of
power but also I think people that
haven't made the switch they're just
a little stuck in their ways sure um
because the technology has caught up and
you're clearly able to get quality I
mean I mean I'm already not even using
adjustable Spectrum now with the
adjustable Spectrum you can maybe HPS
like you can I mean to a degree it'll
mimic the Spectrum right you can set
something almost to a degree but I think
Spectrum change we're not there yet yeah
because there's some companies like
science I think they went out of
business they were big on Spectrum
change we're just not quite there yet
with the formula I've tried those lights
out
like with fluence it's a white broad
spectrum it works from start to finish
so from propagation all the way to
flower you don't have to change anything
and that's actually better for the plan
especially with LEDs but I do find with
certain cultivars they just don't like
LED lighting that could be due to the
breeding uh just the genetics I mean who
knows well it's just like some some
cultivars perform better under HPS and
some perform better under a CMH and LEDs
same thing yeah blue dream I think does
really well under under traditional HPS
lights I didn't know that back in the
day yeah we used to go out just freaking
flourished it still does I mean it makes
sense you know because there were no
LEDs back then when blue dream was out
totally yeah
but yeah I mean I think a couple of my
friends have done like CMH versus HPS
and it's funny like especially in that
Spectrum some stuff does way better into
the CMH 100 wise yeah
so
it's real I mean it's interesting how
far we've come but still how far the
industry really has to go oh man
so far I mean in 10 15 20 years
if it's federally legal like
everything's going to be ran like a food
food facility or a medical grade
facility kind of like what you're you
know doing here with the lab you're
running like a real laboratory yeah yeah
I mean they're the government's going to
get involved of course on a federal
level and it's going to change things I
mean
once they learn more we educate them
more they learn from us yeah because
it's like people from the state you know
they don't they don't know that much
like we have to kind of educate them as
far as what what we need yeah
well it's like FDA ABC all these Federal
entities yeah you know you know it's
it's really interesting as far as
[ __ ] it could go in multiple different
directions definitely but I hopefully
the quality be going up that's that's
one thing I've seen over the last but
then it plateaus right so then it
plateaus and you got a lot of guys that
grow Rockwell and I think Rockwell's
okay I think there's some people
crushing it yeah but for the most part I
see a lot of mediocre rock wool and then
Coco I see amazing absolutely amazing
cocoa soil for the most part the guys
who have the balls to grow soil indoors
you know there's a lot of [ __ ] risk
involved here one thing there's a lot of
people are scared to do it yeah I think
especially if you're already being you
know you're successful you've been grown
in Cocoa forever why would you switch to
soil I would just I don't blame them I
don't blame anyone yeah yeah because
it's it's probably the biggest learning
curve to make that switch and it's the
hardest media to grow in consistently it
also has the most buffer though too you
can if you recognize what's going on
with the plant yeah you know what I mean
you have you have a much bigger buffer
than you do with rock wool or with cocoa
to where identifying problems you know
that could be nutrient related
especially you know you're talking about
food yeah so bigger buffer but I think
just more issues to deal with especially
indoors and it's harder to hit certain
metrics you know if you're trying to
hit yield I think also it's hard for
people to get density out of their flour
too and living soil mm-hmm
I do like living soil though I like the
way it smokes yeah I like main effect
how do you feel after smoking that I
feel good yeah I feel high yeah but I
feel good like it's it's definitely like
a clean High clean
um and that's yeah across the board for
the most part it's usually a cleaner
version of the eye you get from stuff
that was grown in
cocoa or rock wool I mean not that those
are bad I I like smoking whatever else
if it's Skittles or if it's [ __ ] OG
and it's grown oil it doesn't matter
they all smoke pretty good you know as
far as Sour Diesel back in the day oh
yeah of course but soil living soil Sour
Diesel that would be wild but I don't
know if that makes sense to grow that
commercially but we do it takes so much
longer for one thing and problems just
the length of time yeah to grow you
don't like growing 12 weeks of flour
yeah you can't afford to just need a
bigger facility yeah and money to burn
yeah but we do have this the original
Super Silver Haze so you do I saw the
plants those look nice like everything
you guys are growing that that whole
tester room this stuff looks really good
thanks man I appreciate it eye candy I
can't animal cookies the animal cookies
looks ridiculous it doesn't even look
like animal cookies and those are huge
nugs yeah yeah super excited to bring
that back
yeah animal cookies that was from Sirius
in the bay yeah he's he's since passed
yeah rest in peace dude 100 respect
seriously this is a good one I I got a
t-shirt from him it's funny because he
he gave me a t-shirt he was just in the
parking lot at a high times Cannabis Cup
and maybe 2013. well no maybe it was
even earlier than that maybe it was 2010
or 11. the first one was in 2010 in San
Francisco it sounds about right yeah
yeah that was cool the first one was
interesting it's like the those cups
changed from back in the day you know
even Amsterdam to to the US and how they
went from 2012 to uh though they had
they haven't had one in a while but the
last one that they had and the last ones
that they've had for a little while uh
it's like disco the old ones were like
the classic disco and once disco's gone
it's gone forever even though you can
try to do it it's just not quite the
same so does our animal cookies does it
do you remember what animal cookies look
like back then yeah
silly the buds the buds look bigger and
it could be the tissue culture it could
be the growing it could be alive so I've
never seen animal cookies other than in
a bag I never saw it growing on the
planet same you know and I think the
smell of it is pretty freaking amazing
it definitely has that that almost uh
doughy kind of [ __ ] cookie smell to
it sweet it's it's Unique for sure sweet
and yeah it's like cookies are such a
pain in the ass to grow back in the day
yeah
I mean coming from tissue culture it's
it's making it look easy yeah I mean
just a test to tissue culture
right on man
well I I appreciate you coming on the
show and it's been great dude thanks for
having me man this was great for sure
let's do this again sometime yeah let's
do it man good luck on the contest thank
you appreciate it brother thank you
[Music]
thank you