you know rosta far were vaporizing
cannabis 50 years ago wow 50 years ago
and almost nobody in the world of
cannabis knows
that how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James loud
podcast today we got special guests
first M from Jamaica and Steve
D'Angelo uh
activist uh you've done some amazing
things we bumped into each other at
deaden company came by and gave you a
joint and then you posted it on
Instagram and we connected that way it
was a great joint too right I can't say
that about many joints I really enjoyed
that joint thank you very much how are
you guys doing today I'm good enough I'm
solid it's a honored to continue to see
the evolution of this great plant you
know yeah awesome so you guys want to
tell me a little bit about what you guys
are doing in town you guys in town for
the Psychedelic conference I take it
yeah um rust ofar
is not normally a part of or I don't
even know if we're ever a part of
psychedelics but we are definitely a
part of the earth movement of Earth
Medicine of plant medicines you know um
being ganja is one of our Focus one you
know that's the one that got to us first
in our enslaved space you know um so
being in California that's a that's a
good thing but there was the Oakland um
psychedelic conference you know and um
it it's really a conference that uh
promotes the black African way of
thinking within the Americas you know
and
um yeah it was important you know for us
we have a space uh that is interfacing
with our African concerns as well that
is all raaf Fara is really about you
know um in terms of you know this this
this this how can we have a return to a
better way of life you know amongst the
Human family so um to see this African
movement in this kind of a space what is
now called psychedelics it's good to to
to come and to learn to touch base with
my family you know and to see what we
all are doing on different sides for our
restoration you know for our
decolonizing mission and all of these
things so yeah so I came up just to um
view this conference to check my
brethren
um Steve you know um Steve and I are uh
doing this project in Jamaica um also
where it was hard it was hard to find
someone
who really would assist us to focus on
our African retention and to you know we
needed some assistance after after coid
and um we find a way out to assist each
other by um implementing a project down
there um on R ofar and indigenous
Village this space has existed 15 years
however um after co co was frightening
you know Co we didn't know what that was
and we still don't know what it what
what the hell it was however our
standard way of functioning was to bring
in visitors and educate them in an
experiential way about our community
when Co that could you could see 50 80
people in our space after Co we decided
that there's no way we're going to do
that again and then when we looked into
it we decided that the best way we could
have smaller groups you know and um we
had some cabins and they required um you
know upgrading and so on and I spoke to
the great man here and we worked out
what we considered to be alternative
economics which is what I think where
Steve and myself connect is that there
is the system you you know has still
govern the people who are looking to
make the change you know and that's what
ganja was about how can we
change how can we be different from
these systems you know rest of I call
them [ __ ] Sims you know and this is what
our journey is for us now to start
looking at alternative ways how to share
resources how to function how to speak
to each other how do we evolve our own
Community you you know without the
lawyers or without the this or without
everything else that that seems to guide
our relationship how can we move out
outside of the box so that's what has
connected Steve and myself we move out
of the box with this particular project
you know and um and yeah it it has
brought us here it's it's still a it's
still a pilot project it's still a you
know a kind of a experiment but with
some clarity that what we're trying to
do is to make a change
amazing amazing so where is it located
so we are in Montego Bay um uh mon
Montega Bay we're just outside of montea
bay the property is called rastafara
indigenous Village so you know it's it's
popular in in that area if you Google it
ww. rasav village.com you'll find it and
um yeah it's it's it's kind of the last
piece of
green you know that that that is a
ecosystem where people live there and
insects and animals and rivers and so
everything is there as cu the the this
city is expanding you know human beings
are actually creating our own hell on
the planet we're just removing trees and
putting buildings and the place is just
getting hot hot hot and we're fulfilling
our own Bible Mission you know religion
is still leading us straight over the
the the precipice you know so
yeah so that space is a preservation
space you know for a culture that has
been
so so attacked and marginalized only
because we wanted to mitigate the lies
that were told about us about the
continent of Africa so there is a
preservation space where all the
traditions of Rastafari that are being
lost you know because of systemic um uh
discrimination over the years it has
really made our children not always
connecting to our community so we are
preserving the tradition of our food
tradition of our herbal knowledge with
plants the tradition of how we make
drums you know everything that requires
for our spirituality and our way of life
to be preserved you know that that's
what that space is sort of looking at
yeah so many things are going away
because of convenience exactly exactly
it's it's really unfortunate I mean even
if you look at some you know me having a
background as a chef you know even
vegetables yeah you know there's the
disconnect between the farmer and we we
lost that many years ago but I think
with Farmers Market some of the stuff is
coming back so this is one of the you
know amazing things about Rastafari
indigenous Village is that it's a it's a
place that preserves and lives by the
lessons the sacred plants teach us so uh
I encountered the village and met first
mon in 2019 when I was on a global tour
going around the world trying to see
whether changes we had made uh around
the world were worth the sacrifices that
we made in California to get those
changes and um I ended up in in Jamaica
and came to the village and the village
is this amazing 4 acre Oasis just 20
minutes away from the Montego Bay
airport and since the village was
founded in 2007 Montego Bay has kind of
grown up around it but the village
property is this beautiful natural spot
so there's a medicinal herb garden where
there's more than a hundred medicinal
herbs that are being grown and part of
the experience that visitors uh can have
is to go into that garden with Queen ey
or ner or one of our other healers who
understand those plants and can help
folks select the plants that that are
most beneficial for whatever issues they
may be facing and everybody's got some
kind of issue a little bit of tuneup
that they need for sure and then Queen
ey has a BAL yard where uh folks can
learn how to with very simple techniques
turn those herbs that they can go home
and grow in their own garden into
tinctures into balms into shampoos into
lotions wow uh there's a regenerator to
food and cannabis garden where
everything that's being grown is being
grown in relationships with one another
insects to plants plant to plant plant
to soil all in a beneficial cycle of of
relationship a drum studio uh where King
Toto preserves drum making techniques
that have been handed down Generation by
Generation all the way from Africa uh a
beautiful river that runs through and
one of the things that that's just an
amazing experience is you can wake up in
the morning you can walk down to the
river and on the way to the river you
pass by these Cathedral like trees 100
feet tall 50 ft tall bamboo trees but
also mango trees Aki trees avocado trees
bread fruit trees Jun plam trees and
just in what you collect from those
trees and your walk down to the river
and back is enough to feed everybody in
the village amazing and uh and then
folks can sit down and learn traditional
rosari itol ways of cooking that food on
an open fire so all about reconnection
to this natural way of life that the
sacred plants lead us to pretty amazing
pretty amazing I mean it's it's just
it's just what we have to do what we
have always been doing you know um in a
way we are living in a different world
you know where the world can can you
know you we're so far before a time this
movement R when we started to speak
about one love it was so
misconceptualized to think that it was a
one love of human beings because it came
out of our great poet Bob Marley you
know but it was really one love of the
planet what we're doing to the planet
and how how you know our behaviors and
attitudes are affecting the resources of
the of the earth and the connections
between every living thing exactly so
all of all of that was there but now the
world is kind of waking up to you know
climate change you know we are seeing
that we have been messing up a lot of
things you know and it has opened up a
different kind of conversation may not
be with governments but with ordinary
people you know people are getting much
sicker by the fact that they're not
eating real things no more you know a
lot of traditions are being lost people
are recognizing that the impositions of
system today you know some of them have
been living in the time when it was not
like that and people now want to revisit
what their yesterday was now that they
have experience tomorrow you know so um
so there's a lot of there's a lot of
movements and and it has created this
timing for a different a more sobering
conversation instead of a conversation
of ridicule right that would normally
come you know the first time when Rari I
remember not eating meat and we decided
that we were italist CU we didn't know
anything about vegan you know and your
parents out of concern they just thought
you're going to die
right they literally just think that all
that is going to happen to you is that
you'll be maln and you will die pretty
soon you know and now the entire world
is big and big and bigon everywhere you
know so
right yeah it's amazing and I think the
big problem that often time gets gets
overlooked is processed foods and
getting away from processed foods vegan
people that eat you know whatever you
eat meat you whatever type of diet
you're on I think you're better off
eating whole ingredients and you know
for for many many thousands of years we
ate whole ingredients it's only you know
recently that we had these processed
foods with all these preservatives and
these things and I mean there's
definitely something wrong so and I
think we're the time where we can
identify and we can all agree that
there's something wrong the world is so
educated yeah you know um it's very
educated now all information is at the
tip of your finger yeah it's almost
sensory overload yeah well whole grains
are part of it right whole anything is
part of it eating food as close to its
natural form is part of it right but one
of the reasons that I dedicated myself
to a plant-based diet is because I've
gone all around the world advocating for
a hemp based economy and I knew that one
day somebody was going to ask me from
the crowd well Steve if you are
advocating for a hemp based economy can
you tell me exactly how many acres of
land it's going to take to convert our
current economy to a hemp-based economy
so I sat down and started thinking about
that and doing the calculations and what
I learned was very sober in right there
is just barely enough agricultural land
on this planet to convert ourselves to a
plantbased hemp based economy and and to
head off the climate catastrophe just
bar
but it's not possible to do today
because
80% 80% of the agricultural land on this
planet is being used for animal-based
agriculture wow so if you believe in a
hemp-based
plant-based economy if you really want
to get rid of fossil fuels then adopting
the plant-based diet is a necessary
corollary to having a hemp based economy
so that's what pushed me over the edge
I'm Italian man I love my parmesan
cheese I still miss it um but um we're
living in a time now where it's very
difficult for human beings to take
individual actions that have a real
impact on preserving the planet uh where
we don't have to go to the government we
don't have to go to an investment
committee we don't have to make an
investment all we have to do is make a
decision that we're going to eat a
little bit differently and if all of us
did that if all of us who who have
relationships with plants decided to do
that we would remove a massive amount of
atmospheric carbon from the air so we
have the potential to do these really
amazing things now that we've been
United by the Consciousness that these
plants spread it's amazing has to start
somewhere as far as uh legalization in
Jamaica you guys have had legalization
for cannabis for a while how is that
chaliz decriminalized how how do that
change the lands Cape man I tell you you
know we got the same thing um we saw
different uh type of subconscious or
implicit bias type of
colonization coming from the investors
of overseas you know mainly darting in
from Canada yeah yeah yeah yeah you call
the name yes yeah mainly coming in from
Canada and so on um as I said I don't
I'm I'm not going to say to you that the
the move was let's go and and and
colonize you know it's just how it feels
to us you know I have no no thoughts
that there were bad intentions at the
beginning or anything like that it just
works out to be that when when when I'm
when I'm speaking about this
community I'm not expecting to see the
suits I'm really expecting to see The
Roots You know right Andrew gave me that
yes today and um I think that's what
happened too much suit you know the
plant does not reason like that doesn't
have the conversations in this type of a
way and you know we can I I have spent a
lot of time blaming governments but then
not in this industry in this industry
it's it's the people yeah you know we
are
misrepresenting the behaviors and
attitude of this plan
and we can't put that on government you
know we have to put that on when we got
that opportunity to move what did we do
so when they got the opportunity to come
into Jamaica you know um everybody
started to behave as if they were ganja
smokers they forgot about the Legacy
Community they were not patient enough
to allow what Jamaica had contributed to
the world to be something that is
properly um packaged and structured not
not not just in a flurry of
advertisement but in real hardcore steps
you know to just Ure that um Jamaica and
its tradition was represented in know
Rastafari and what what we did you know
I
mean we were releasing so much valves in
the 70s and the and and the 60s you know
when that's all all ganja was coming
from Jamaica and giving a lot of New
Yorkers Miami the entire us you know an
opportunity to breed from all the
systemic pressures that were coming down
on them and we know this you know and
this is why every time I speak about
these things I'm saying that we as human
being should not hide behind government
when we get the opportunity to move are
we recognizing Legacy are we looking at
the restoration and the reparation
within our own Community you know and
and and and that has been to me the
issue in Jamaica so it move off too fast
there was no Legacy conversation the
people who suffered for it was not
recognized and then it just
went up to Nowhere it was just in the
mind that it was going up I don't think
of ever reflected in sales it never
reflected in nothing that it was
profitable just this idea that Jamaica
has a branding and Taurus is going to
come and they're going to buy but
everyone was sold the dream everyone you
got it right man everyone was sold a
dream you know so that's how the that's
how decriminalization work you know at
the moment I think all dispensers are
quite
possibly um suffering because they were
trying to build an industry instead of a
relationship yeah with each other you
know we have to really find the way how
this PL that forces us to think you know
unless everybody is going to collapse
yeah you know everybody's going to
collapse so rastafar also got some kind
of a um preferential treatment it's not
a it's not connected with the philosophy
yeah rastafar philosophy is one legalize
the plan for every human being yeah you
know that's our like mango pop Choy and
it needs to be fully
decriminalized yeah we're having this uh
discussion about re scheduling and it
needs to be descheduled I think it's
it's just common sense yeah exactly
exactly you know so they gave us this
kind of a preferential treatment which
is now allowing us to sit with
governments and Lobby and where our
rights are and so on and so forth but
then again as I say sometimes you find
you start looking at the government and
wondering if they were not there how
would we as the community deal with each
other are we able to self
ulate I think that's a big question to
the Cannabis Community can we
self-regulate can we properly
appropriate you know ourselves to each
other right do we recognize
Legacy we need to so it's passed in
Jamaica in 2015 there was medical quote
unquote medical cannabis legislation
that was passed and as part of that
legislation Rastafari communities were
supposed to be given certain sacramental
rights around cannabis and it was really
a um another example of cannabis being
regulated by people who do not
understand the plant and do not respect
the plant and and thereby misregulate it
I'll give you one glaring example when
you go into any of the dispensaries in
Jamaica which are by law medical
cannabis dispensaries first of all the
only people who can afford to go in them
are tourists because the price of the
Cannabis is the same as the price of
cannabis in most legal American states
in legal tax dispensaries so quite High
far higher than any Jamaicans or most
Jamaicans would be able to afford the
second is that the only form of cannabis
that you can get at the quote unquote
medical cannabis dispensaries is inhaled
cannabis hash or Bud something you have
to smoke oh man no tinctures no capsules
no cakes nothing yeah and the reason for
that is because there's a history in
Jamaica of tourists coming to the island
eating space cakes in a tea shop eating
too many of them ending up in the
emergency room um and then the
government having to deal with the
Fallout from those kinds of incidents so
in a completely ridiculous move um the
most effective format edible AR tinure
format for medical cannabis patients was
made illegal and the most dangerous
format inhaled cannabis was made the
only one that was available so that
that's one sector that was given birth
to by the 2015
legislation that sector is not doing
very well there was a second sector
which was an export sector and the idea
behind this sector was to take advantage
of the sunshine the low labor costs uh
of Jamaica and set up basically a
neocolonial extractive model where the
plants would be grown in Jamaica maybe
you would do a basic extraction in
Jamaica but then that basic extract
would be sent to Europe Europe mostly uh
for further refinement further pro pro
processing further value added right and
then be sold into the pharmaceutical
supply chain as an API An approved
pharmaceutical input that sector seems
to be doing a little bit better some of
the companies there that had wellth
thought out business plans and had some
financing seem to be doing some sales
and Thrive and maybe not thriving but at
least surviving yeah other companies in
that sector are in crisis because the
international market that they were
relying on has developed much much more
slowly than was originally an
anticipated right I've seen it and then
there's the third part of the market
which which is the most interesting part
of the market because it's the only part
of the market that's really connected to
this incredibly Rich ganja culture that
Jamaica gave birth to and it's such an
amazing gift to the world right and
that's the culture that that grew out of
rosta fari as expressed by reggae and
now adopted in one form or another by
hundreds of millions of Reggae fans uh
all around the world so that version of
cannabis in Jamaica is now found in
Rastafari community so there's
discussion that's going on um about
formally authorizing communities um and
once that discussion is is fully
potentiated right then the hopefully
where we end up where we would like to
see it end up is a situation where
visitors to the island can go and have
access to the real genuine Jamaican
ganja experience where you can learn
about the Rastafari history you know
rosar were vaporizing cannabis 50 years
ago wow 50 years ago and almost nobody
in the world of cannabis knows that
right um and uh and then just the all of
the all of the stories uh all of the
songs that that go along with all of
that culture the way that cannabis has
influenced uh the thinking and the way
of life of of Rastafari and it's just a
an incredibly Rich experience for
anybody who really loves cannabis and
it's one that so far has been you know
pretty difficult to seek out and find so
hopefully uh with uh this conversation
going on Rastafari communities will be
fully EMP powered to represent not just
the plant right because it's not just
the plant that's important it's the
lessons that the plant teaches us and
what we do with those totally yeah it's
really interesting some of the genetics
that have come out of Jamaica Orange
Hill so when I was in Jama I got I I
basically gave $20 to a bunch of
different people and never got anything
good when I was staying at a resort and
uh finally I I brought some flow from
the States from from Hult it was some
really good good OG and I gave it to the
guy and I told him to take it to whoever
he gets stuff from and he comes back the
next day with big joints from Orange
Hill I didn't know what to expect
because I had gotten some really bad but
this it was so strong that I think it
was 10: in the morning and I woke up at
5: with my wife we woke up at 5: in the
bed going what the heck was that and
then we look over in the joint still
about that big so yeah I mean there's
some legendary Lamb's bread Lamb's
breath I think all you know it's a big
conversation you know you have to
remember that as rest of far we don't
see Jamaica as our home right Jamaica is
not necess it's a colonized space that
we have now to sort of by dwelling there
this is where we have to recreate
ourselves from to go home to Africa
that's our ultimate Mission you know and
as a result of that you know being in
spaces like those you have to you have
to to be strong and and and powerful and
everything you do has to be potent you
know because you want to do it natural
natural natural is our potency is not
necessarily about how much percent is
here or how much it's how is how natural
you you really have have engaged with
your process you know yeah and and and
and that's one of the what that's one of
the things you know in in doing that
those messages come from the process you
know what I mean it's a different it's
cultural science you know and and you
know what prohibition did it it damaged
that it damaged that spiritual
relationship of the cultural science you
know you you have to start storing your
Herb in some weird places you know um
you have to start putting fertilizer on
them because you need them to grow fast
you know and then you sort of bring in
all the Hybrids because you want weeks
instead of 6 month you want 12 weeks
instead of 6 months so you know the
entire culture started to go through a
process of adaptation and all kind of
mixup you know kind of attitudes you
know amongst ourself so it is good that
this time is here for us to revisit you
know um the way how we would want it and
want to be however the conversation is
not just so much about that the
conversation is really about the lessons
that the plan has taught us and how do
we incorporate those lessons not in
terms of just material gain but in terms
of preservation and protection of
ourselves as the Human family how do we
do this you know and um and and I think
that's that's the main conversation we
want we want Lamb's bread and we want to
play the role that we saw to play but we
also want to evolve we want to see every
aspect of this because it's only
restriction that stopped us you know
from from exploring all our cultural SS
you know so yeah pretty amazing yes I
think so too yeah it's really
interesting with all these
International uh countries that are
going legal and how we can all work
together um you know it's like and and
then as Steve was saying earlier
with these countries like Germany for
example that they've gone so slow but I
feel like there is potential and I mean
I think working with Jamaica's like
Lambs bread or Orange Hill I mean Orange
Hill is a a region more than a yes you
know I think that would be more like a
VI cultural area yeah yes so but but
being able to work with those and being
able to import into the United States I
think there's huge benefit for us to
have access to Jamaican flow and vice
versa you know I think on a world scale
I think it'd be amazing honor each other
that's the conversation that I'm really
sort of trying to get at is how do we
honor each other yeah there's so much
except when you know I I can't remember
where I went to and saw a a man changing
out all the things that he has he's now
getting in new equipment and now he's
getting rid of old ones and that
technology has not even reached Jamaica
yet yeah he has nothing really to do
with it you know what I mean but you
know he just has to get rid of them
because now there's a new technology
either it be in lights and in trays in
methods and whatever be the case that
that hasn't even reached Jamaica yet you
know and then you're having Jamaicans
coming over here planting and growing in
California here as well and they come
and they see the systems they try to
come back and Implement some of what
they think they saw and how that could
work but there's nothing unique to that
local space more than what was there
from orangel where those people have
crafted their own relationship with the
plant and has delivered from that you
know and when you speak to them about
this relationship it because most of it
like most cannabis people is is really
the time they spend with the flowers you
know everybody call it their girls or
whatever they it's it's this very
intimate intimate relationship
relationship and and I think this goes
for probably all kind of people who
touch the plant you know they all have
that type of a Vibe you know we all have
these unique intimate relationships and
they're all different and and that's the
beauty of it you know Steve has a
different relationship with the plant
than I do you know as an advocate is as
somebody who got us to this point to a
degree you know I mean I think you paved
the way for a lot of people you were a
boundary Pusher you know when there was
other people that were scared to come
out and say F you I'm gonna do this and
I don't care if you guys want to stop me
let's go to court you you were there to
do that and and I think we have all
these different people that love
cannabis and it's growing it's
exponentially growing yeah and it's so
amazing you know we get people in other
countries I think Thailand is a great
example where they they did have
cannabis but the culture the people
there are excited about the stuff that's
going on the west coast too but it's
like we have this International
communication now that because of
Technology you know it's a blessing and
a curse well you know what folks in in
in California I I hope can get a a
greater appreciation of Y is the degree
to which the change that we made in
California including the passage of prop
64 has sparked other changes all around
the world right so the king of Thailand
would not have done what he did and
allowed to happen what happened in
Thailand land if we hadn't legalized
cannabis here in California right the
legislature of New York and the
legislature of Illinois would not have
moved forward to to pass cannabis
legalization which is what they did
following the passage of legalization in
California um there's been this massive
change and it's it's going to take a
long time for that change to spread all
around the world but we're seeing it
happen now in places like Germany uh and
it it undoubtedly will spread all around
the world so we're moving towards the
day and and g i I hope I could say I
thought it was going to happen in my
lifetime but I'm not sure but the day
will come when we have a globalized and
normalized Canabis economy and when that
happens different strains of cannabis
are going to be grown in different micro
microclimates that are most well adapted
to those particular strains of cannabis
so one of the things that's missing in
the North American market right now is
long maturing exotic cea strains like
the ha right and if you can find a real
Haze you're going to pay through the
nose for it because it takes you know
forever to mature right so it's going to
cost the grower twice as much to produce
per gram maybe three times as much to
produce per gram when you're paying for
lights you're paying for stuff like that
it's not really possible to do but in
Jamaica it's 122
365 okay okay so the sweet spot for
Jamaica and they have these beautiful
beautiful super tall mountains the Blue
Mountains where some of the most
expensive coffee in the world is grown
so my prediction is that Jamaica one day
if the government of Jamaica seese the
value in doing things like creating and
granting appalachi and and supporting
Jamaicans and developing their own
consumer facing Brands is that Jamaica
becomes the world's leading source for
the most EXO
most expensive most hard to finded long
growing mature SAS and that's a really
nice position to be in yeah that's a
beautiful thing I would love to see all
the other islands in the Caribbean get
on board I know St Vincent yeah and
Trinidad you know I think they have
Ambitions they're all it's the same
thing if decriminalization never took
place in Jamaica you know these these
other countries wouldn't sort of be
opening up their doors as well you know
and um for sure they're they're really
having um the conversation they're
they're honestly having the conversation
and um some of the people feel good you
know about what is happening but it you
know it's all about regulations
everything is regulations you know with
with the Cannabis Community with the r
ofari Community you know our position
that we have taken as rest ofari in
Jamaica is a
self-regulate you know it's a
self-regulate and all of this is just
coming from the fact that we see our as
a nation and which is why another reason
why I connected to Steve because what he
was telling me was that he saw you know
a plan tribe you know around the world
and um and and that this tribe is huge
and that this tribe um in itself could
actually start to live by the teachings
of the plant and create the changes that
we would um want to see on the planet
for ourselves we have the money you know
it's possible and I think if we bring
the plant into the conversation you know
in reverence you know cuz there's a lot
of there's a lot of I'm not sure you
know in every way how these things are
happening how the plant and human beings
are evolving if there's always reverence
in that you know um sometimes it seems
it's just the end of the dollar you know
and and I I I I have seen azasa fari
where the relationship between money
and spirituality during the times of a
you know selling ganja to the world
there was synchronicity in community
development in spirituality I think
there's a template of the way how if we
give into our spirit we will receive a
lot more you know probably not in huge
houses and in excess but more in
community in Community Development
because that's what these plants are
here for they are here for Community
Development right they bring us all
together they bring us all together you
know just the nature of it you light it
you sit around a table and you're ready
to talk just as much as food I feel like
on that same level it brings so many of
us together that normally we may never
cross paths yeah but because of this
plant it's a special connection that we
all share yes yes yes so this is this is
where this Vision you know sort of came
to me in 2019 as I was traveling around
the world which I called the the One
Tribe or plant tribe Vision yeah and I
had this opportunity to go to four
different continents about 14 different
countries uh hanging out with people who
consumed cannabis and loved cannabis of
all different races religions economic
classes educational levels just about
every thing that you could imagine every
difference in the Human family that you
could imagine yeah and I came off of
that tour um really missing people like
who I just met but like my heart really
hurt you know and so I started thinking
about what had happened there and how
did I become so close in such a short
period of time and what I realized is
that no matter where we come from our
race our religion the language we speak
how much or how little we've been
educated or where we've been educated
the
plants have spoken to us in the same
language
we've learned the same lessons and out
of those lessons we've built a common
value system so wherever you go around
the world today you find people who have
had the plant
conversations valuing creativity over
Conformity valuing individual Freedom
over state or corporate Authority
valuing nature over industry valuing
peace over War valuing love over hate
radically including everybody and being
intolerant only of intolerance right and
that's who we are no matter where we are
in the world or what our background is
and you know the UN claims that there's
300 million regular cannabis consumers
in the world I think they got it wrong
by an order of about three um me you
know you talk to the US government they
say there's 30 million Americans who
have found their way to psychedelic
experiences I'm not talking about the
Retreats and everything just regular
folks sure some public opinion poll say
20% of Americans have had psychedelic
experiences extrapolate these numbers
out to the whole planet and collectively
we are as large or larger than all but
the largest nations on this planet and
everything that usually divides a group
of human beings we can
transcend and so the question that comes
to my mind now is okay we've all been
called I think we can all feel that
these discuss are calling us to a
purpose what is that purpose and what
are we going to do with it right and I
don't think any of us can figure that
out on on our own I think there needs to
be a convening there needs to be a
conversation we need to figure this out
because the future of the planet
probably depends on us getting this
right right yeah it's a collective
energy makes you have a lot of respect
for people who call themselves
government you know when you decide to
self-govern yeah you realize that [ __ ]
these people you know have a very
serious job to do you know and um you
know self-governance is not easy but is
the ultimate task it's a reason why we
are being led by by by by who is leading
us know um because we refuse right to
regulate and govern ourselves know and
you know in places like
Jamaica that those are the impact of
colonialism you know we're we're working
on a decolonized um program and every
time you say it you know
white people think they're not involved
you know what I mean only just but the
privilege is is a mental disorder it's
not real you know what I mean and it's
been used as a tool yeah for the broader
liberation of the Human family you know
and in places like Jamaica um when
abolition of slavery was really uh a
strategy for neocolonialism it was set
up that way perfectly
thought out and put together and so on
one of the main things that came out of
the abolition of slavery was how much if
you different disenfranchise people and
discriminate against them and then you
tell them to govern themsel they will
choose slavery over
Freedom that was a reality you know they
did that in Jamaica in Jamaica wages was
what they used to keep the Africans down
you know so if you go to Jamaica right
now like you take a guess what do you
think is minimum wage in
Jamaica $3 an hour so it's about
$258 okay so I'm not too far you're not
too far off you're not too far and then
and it that just increased probably like
about three or four months ago it was
less than that yeah and this is coming
from that strategy of slavery where what
happen is that you paid the people solo
they own no land you know this is the
African people the classism was set up
because the Indians got land the Chinese
got land so everybody was being used as
a tool of differentiation and divide and
Rule you know and it's a responsibility
that we have to recognize this we have
been used to play a game against each
other and we have to decide to have that
conversation amongst ourselves so you
know when people decide that they want
to and this is why spoke about the
implicit bias and the subconscious
colonization
because a friend of mine that I know
this is a good person man I love him
he's a good man you know um we have had
interactions and he's real coming from a
real place but he was having a
conversation with another person and he
was telling them you know you know why
you should come to Jamaica electricity
is high all the services are high but
labor is cheap and man that cut every
part of my system you know cuz I I I
know that he did not he didn't even have
a clue he's just a businessman looking
at the real reason why you should do
business here you know and he needs to
save his business but this is a ageold
18th century issue well I think in life
so many things are
counterintuitive you think it's one way
but until you have experience to see it
the way you know it's it's hard to gauge
stuff sometimes and I think you know
it's just like struggle you you want
your kids to you know live a comfortable
life but I think struggle is important
to Define your character and to figure
out who you are very much so very very
much so and but but you know you said
till you encounter what is real I think
we have a problem yes with defining what
real is and until we work out what that
formula is and it's a very it's a very
simple formula it's you have to do your
impact study right what has been the
impact of your behavior you know and how
does it affect others and affect
yourself you know and I think that's
that's the that's the that's the that's
the realest real that you could come to
you know that's the realest real you
know
yeah yeah it's interesting you know I'm
in my 40s and I'm a completely I
wouldn't say I'm a complet completely
different person but I think we change
so much and as we get more experience we
understand how fragile life can be all
these other things and how important
knowledge is I think that's one of the
biggest things for me and and to really
understand things thoroughly you know
whether it's cannabis or psychedelics or
whatever it is you know to get a real
firm understanding of it and you you you
understand things through experience I
think that's another thing so with your
retreat uh H how does that work so
people can can schedule online they call
you guys up yeah so the retreat is um
you know there are the you can contact
us we promote people contacting us
through our website yeah ww. village.com
and once you you know you will you will
get an opportunity to sign up um you
know uh we do have them weekly we may be
making some adjustments to sort of give
them a set date right so we can have
more people connecting to them at a
different time you have individuals and
groups yeah um but not deliberately we
rather to because our container is
community we rather groups you know um
our philosophy is that there's no
problem that is yours all problem
belongs to the environment you know be
cancer this that it is something that is
happening in our environment as human
beings so it's it's a one love bringing
everything into one yeah and yeah so
once you book um uh a email will will
then be sent to you you'll be contacted
and we'll have a one-on-one conversation
to find out a little bit about who you
are and clear up any questions you would
have about yourself you know and um we
tell you the container that we have
created you know for the
experience um that you should have and
that container is mainly
uh our Approach at the moment uh is not
to create people who cannot integrate
properly and not to create people that
will give us too much dramatic
experiences so we have learned a little
bit about how the plant Works how it
interacts and most of the time people
come there they're having human issues
they're not having a issue of life and
the relationship with life they're
having issues between themselves the job
the stifling of their ego and their
gifts the non-c creativity because
they're conformed you know so those are
the things that they are facing and we
have faced those things too so we create
this container of stories and so on that
can evolve a human experience and
conversation that can invoke memory you
know um and that can almost try to
release and loosen some of what people
are calling trauma you know but there
are really in fact we see the traumatic
people as more teachers you know people
who have had an experience that can
share to allow us to evolve and them
themselves to evolve you know so it's
not people you know you're not going to
be there to cry you're going to be there
to woman man up you know and to speak
about your experiences as someone who
has learned something about this
environment of the planet how you have
been going through it and how we can
evolve it and once we you know scratch
that surface and rake it up and allow it
to come out then you know we sort of
introduce you to the plant and then
normally when you go into those
conversations with the plant you won't
be having conversations that you have
never even touched on before I'm not
saying that you will you know the plant
is amazing it can bring up anything
however because of our journey with it
already we kind of have a path we ask
for that direction and then people will
just have an experience that is more
evolving than the experience of human
pain and human issues they can have a
more connected experience with the
Journey of these neighbors you know
these entities that we don't know it's
like going on a first date that's how we
sort of put it you go on this first date
do you really go on a date and bring all
the baggage of yesterday and all the
relationships that never work you sit to
know the person so the idea is that you
are going to sit with this plant you're
going to listen you're going to have
conversations and that's that's a kind
of preparation that we do and then we
because it's a space of drumming and
it's a space of food and it's a space of
nature because the river runs through
the property we're we're having some
problems now though you know especially
with the river
because development is disguise or
destruction is disguise as development
and people are doing a lot of Bill
building so there's a lot of so but we
still want our family to come together
so we can pray for these Rivers because
we know that any imbalance anywhere on
the planet is an imbalance to everywhere
on the planet so it's really a call to
duty that our Retreat is about about how
we can collectively heal you know and um
but integration is the biggest part of
it
so we we really we really know that for
a lot of people you know they come to
these Retreat and they are opened up
many gates are open up of the
possibility of life then you come back
into a office building you come back
waiting two tables you know it's kind of
hard to integrate in that kind of a way
so our journey is about creating a
community you know a community that is
looking to evolve even some of these job
types you know that actually you know a
lot of these industries they are built
to kill customers you know right to see
if we can recreate you know like the
cannabis plant this is why I like uh
these these exchanges within plant
medicines in a particular way that can
be um spiritual economics because it
saves people you know it doesn't kill
people you know what I mean like like
like a lot of the Fast Food Industries
and so on yeah it makes the world a
better place makes the world a much much
better place so you know it's open fire
in the night you know that that um we
keep our interpretations of ser but the
the the main thing about our Retreat is
we call it life is a ceremony which
simply means that it is every single
moment that you're integrating every
single moment you're holding
Consciousness to the thought that you're
having and the implementation of that
thought yeah you know that you're
putting out and that's what we try to
open up you know so people have come to
a retreat and didn't take the medicine
and still feel in a way that they have
you know opened up a lot of
just so many people need to live in the
moment yeah yeah yeah exactly exactly so
it's a very different experience right
um because a lot of the retreats in
Jamaica are at the kind of resorts that
most folks go to a lot of the staff and
facilitators are flown in from overseas
there's often not a whole lot of
connection to Jamaica um a Rastafari
indigenous Village is a real Rastafari
village with Elders with children um
with life and um so it's not like
perfect and manicured like a resort
would be but it's always real um and
guests can go to rosta village.com to
book the Retreats and we're open for
individual bookings we do have a
schedule of of Retreats um uh so that we
will group folks together and if you if
you uh don't see a date that works for
us works for you then you know drop us
an email we'll talk to you we see what
we can work out that works best for
everybody we're also open to retreat
organizers uh so folks who are
organizing Retreats and are looking for
a place that uh is friendly may want to
check out rosta Village and see if it
we're a good fit for for for their needs
so the one of the really distinctive
features of the village is that um we
keep things small and really intimate
because you can't really get to know
each other and have a real cultural exch
change if there's more visitors than
there are Folks at the village and
there's about 20 folks who live at the
village and so generally we don't have
more than about 12 visitors uh at the
Village awesome uh which means that a
family or a company or an advocacy
organization that would like to have
this very very special experience
together can come down and have the
whole village to themselves with as few
as as six people so wow um it's a it's a
very very special uh place for smaller
groups to consider coming and visiting
really
cool well you have to definitely be
ready
for um real yeah authentic yeah it's not
a it's not a space where the
conversations are going to be created
before you come conversation is going to
be with you when you come and what you
bring to the table so you know there are
set of agendas you know of of things
healing practices and so on that we will
definitely offer but for each group for
each set of people you know it's it's
it's us together that is really kind of
doing the work very individual yeah yeah
yeah very very individual you know even
though we are seeing a lot of
commonalities you know people are coming
with the same thing we're also seeing a
lot of difference yeah you know and um
and people are continuing their own
relationship after they leave you know
with each other and so on which is a
very typical sound that is happening in
the Psychedelic space too as well and
you know people are really being
connected you know even the people who
go into the resorts and so on all of
them are having the plant is opening up
a lot of conversation I think I was just
talking to Steve and I was saying to him
that the big the
change narrative now is integration
that's the that's the that's the big
thing you know because when it is um not
legalized or they call it criminalized
or whatever normalized yeah they've like
taken that away and now we're getting
back to the
normalization where we can have a
conversation with about it and you can
really sit down with someone and say to
them you know I've engaged with these
plants and it shows me this you don't
have to feel bad about it and so on and
I think that's going to normalize it and
create a space now where the plants and
human beings can coexist without the
corruption right of it you know um cuz
that's what we do we really corrupt
spirituality corrupt anything that is
intangible you know we find a way how to
impose our perceptions on it and just
make it what we want you know and that's
that's normally a very corrupted way to
deal with it perception is such a
powerful thing it's the only thing it's
my favorite thing you know um it's it's
it's what um I personally um urge people
our our Retreats are really about
perception yeah are really about how do
you view um your interpretation of
struggle you know as you say how
necessary has these struggle been you
know for you so many times you're
panicking in the moment about something
that is happening and then a few years
later you sit down and say man if that
thing never happened I wouldn't be here
today this today you know last night I
was having a conversation with
a young lady and she was doing I hav
remember her name but she was doing
these very beautiful teth you know um at
the conference she was doing these very
beautiful tees and different kinds of
tees and and they tastes amazing too and
you know after during the conversation
um it was really
death a death of her family member you
know that really propelled her to become
this beautiful soul that is sharing
medicine yeah you know to a lot of
people you know so some of these
struggles are really Stepping Stones you
know 100% And and things in life happen
that are bad or good and we really don't
know the effect of until much later yes
you know and so we can be upset about
stuff and but we don't know if that's
really a bad thing or or maybe a good
thing that's going to make our lives
better well you said something profound
you said people don't know how to live
in the moment yes they do with struggle
yeah with
struggle with struggle they're very much
in the moment they're very much
panicking immediately they the impact is
right now with struggle but with with
holistic and with with with relaxation
they can stay in the moment you know
when you're sick the only thing you want
to do is get better right they can't
stay the moment for that at all you know
but with struggles they're right there
fully present you know yeah well yeah
it's been an honor to have you guys on
the show today man this has been a
really good conversation been an honor
to sit with you too you know and to see
the work that the plant is influencing
you to do you know and I think it's an
amazing things seeds are significant for
the for planet to live you know every
kind of seed you know and especially
what what what what ganja can do for the
planet there's not much other plant that
can and say the same thing you know so I
I'm I honor the work that you're doing
and thank you very much just keep doing
it from the right place you know I'm a
you know I'm blessed to be a steward of
the plan I think more than anything I'm
blessed to be able to work in this
career that I've chosen you know to be
able to do this for a living this wasn't
something that I think 20 or 30 years
ago was imaginable you know but with uh
216 and all these other things that have
really kind of evolved and and you know
pushed the way forward I mean it's it's
an amazing time to be alive I'm just I'm
really blessed just to be here and be
part of something so much bigger than
myself you know I I run into young
people now who were born you know after
prohibition was ended in the states that
they live in right so we got the first
post prohibition yeah generation now
that's growing up that is you know
that's not feeling these wounds that
weren't beaten up and man they're like
they're so much they're so much more
forgiving and and and patient and well
balanced human beings you know it's it's
a it's a really beautiful thing to see
totally one more thing about uh
delicioso you know I think last prisoner
project thank you very much for all your
contributions to last prisoner project
and everything that you've done I think
getting guys like oh we we had uh Uncle
Rick Rich Del
on our show not so long ago he's a great
character has amazing stories but last
prisoner project that was one of the
things that you started yeah you know
for me um the the inspiration for last
prisoner project came in
2017 this was after uh prop uh 64 had
been passed in 2016 but before it was
implemented in
2018 and um and all of my competitors
were running out and getting tens of
millions of dollars so I felt like I had
to do the same thing I found myself uh
in Toronto which was at that point the
capital of cannabis capital and I was in
the financial district at the top of a
fancy uh office uh Tower uh sitting at a
very long conference table uh and there
were a bunch of spreadsheets on that
table and they envisioned like literally
hundreds of tons of weed being produced
and more money than you could possibly
imagine and everybody sitting around
that table is feeling really good
because they think that this Market is
going to be opening up nobody sees the
disaster that's coming yet nobody there
has the slightest fear of getting
arrested at all it's not even on the
agenda so in the middle of this meeting
my phone starts buzzing and it's my
buddy Chuck Chuck's calling me from a
prison in Pennsylvania where he's doing
four years four years for bringing 14
pounds of weed from California to
Pennsylvania he didn't even bring it was
just accused of having helped to arrange
the the transport wow uh and so I you
know I I don't normally interrupt
meetings like that but it was my friend
calling from prison so I did and I went
out into the hall and I talked to him
and it was Grim because it's Grim to
talk to your friends in prison yep and
when I walked back into the conference
room that grimness was still clinging to
me and I looked around the room and I
saw everybody there still very happy
with absolutely no fear and I realized
then that if I was going to be a part of
moving this thing forward from that day
forward um and and creating this new
legal industry that we had to make sure
that everybody that was in prison my
friend Chuck and everybody else who was
in prison on cannabis charges was
released and given a decent opportunity
to rebuild the lives that were stolen
from them so that was the inspiration
uh for last prisoner project um it's
been one of the great pleasures of my
life to be able to welcome friends of
mine like Richard delisi home again I
remember when Richard got busted um I
remember his story well uh I remember
the horror at hearings a sentence that
he got um and and I remember then you
know it wasn't an explicit commitment
that I made to myself but uh a regarding
prisoners I was like okay [ __ ]
if it's on then it's on because our
side's not giving up either and so it's
really satisfying after all those 30
years after all the hits that so many of
us took so many of my friends died for
uh to see Richard delisi and Michael
Thompson and the other people who helped
build this Market finally coming home to
their families U before they died as as
a is just one of the very most
pleasurable and gratifying things that
I've seen in my life yeah it's very
impressive yeah thank you very much for
that
and thank you guys for your time you
guys have an Instagram or yes R Retreats
r i Retreats and um yeah and and the
website ww. rage.com on there you will
see our
number
18762 285
4750 we normally use WhatsApp so that's
a good way how to just message us it's
more easier than calling you know we'll
respond fantastic yes sir thank you so
much for today and I look forward to
joining you guys in Jamaica one of these
days James loud you would be proud thank
you very much
[Music]
bless
yeah back
CR
yeah