foreign
[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James loud
podcast today my guest is Lance and he
works with terplock now but we've known
each other for a long time how you doing
Lance I'm doing really good man stoked
to finally be up here dude it's great
having you on uh I guess let's start off
talking about uh Spain in 2019 the best
interview I've ever done that never
aired I know that was frustrating we
slowly hit up Peter for that yeah that
was I'd known about you both of us you
know being from the bay area in
background and it's kind of similar
backgrounds you know I um saved up for
college thanks to flower thanks to this
plant and uh so I've been following you
for a while so when Peter's like hey you
gotta interview James I'm like yeah dude
I'm all about it nice and it was cool it
was nice because you're like right
across from where we were set up with
the company eyes at at the time and uh
dude you're you're doing your thing and
it was nice to see a domestic genetics
company in Spain because like you know
we don't have to go too far now because
you know all about this but
um you know there's two episodes centers
as far as I'm concerned with genetics
and Spain's one and in California is the
other yeah and so you're there and a lot
of people don't know if you're not
familiar with spanibus uh you know start
out as a protestable like most
International but I just did an audit of
the show last year 21 of the exhibitors
are genetics so people don't realize
that and you you know you notice it when
you're walking through because we've
done several of them over the years but
then when you put that in perspective
it's like one out of five booths yeah
our genetics and about five different
companies make the seeds for all of them
XC and you know exactly true as well and
some of them come up and some people
know that and some people don't but uh
but again to see that American
representation there's a few other
companies but you're on an awesome
trajectory and I think the thing that
I've always been a fan about as far as
what you do is is the genetics that
you're into because I'm into the
generational stuff like I'm talking
about more the land race you know like
you know Acapulco Gold and Swahili and
Durban Poison and just all these
genetics that really were at the core
yeah back in the day so that interview I
had uh taken a micro dose of what I
thought was a micro dose of mushrooms
and then the funny part of the story is
that I was uh high on mushrooms I
actually was talking to Mario and to jai
they were arguing actually and so I was
like I gotta get out of here and then
next thing you know you're grabbing my
arm and you're like we need to do this
interview and I'm like
okay
you ended up giving me a hug afterwards
and I was like I think it's the best
interview I've ever done you're like I
think it was a really good interview
yeah and then uh I I went away and you
came back maybe an hour later and you're
like dude we didn't have the sound dude
the sound on the microphone we have the
sound from the yeah the camcorder but
that was it yeah yeah it's frustrating
that the guy who was on site there that
Peter hired which he obviously did not
hire again
um but it was tough yeah because we lost
quite a bit on that and there were some
of the best interviews to your point
like it was so natural and both of us
not to speak for you but I feel like
we're very approachable impersonable and
we're about Good Vibes and we're about
community and you don't have to be from
NorCal to have this mentality but
there's enough of us to do so when you
get a few of us together right it just
flows it's not scripted right and
sometimes talking about like deviating
from talking about genetics and talking
about the passion for the sacred plant
and you know why we're all doing this I
think that's important and you know
sometimes that gets overlooked a little
bit and
you know and you know I just went to
three days of dead and Company and I
think we're here in part to the Grateful
Dead and their their influence on the
Cannabis industry uh you know Brands
like Anchor Steam that we just found out
Anchor Steam is now closing doors after
130 years or something like that it's
insane you know and Fred Maytag he's a
big contributor to the reason cannabis
is legal in my opinion no true and and
we talked about that a little bit before
this like like I was telling you you
know when I people ask me and I love
doing these interviews during 4 20
because people feel like they're still a
Mystique and they don't quite know the
story and I'm like no the story is very
factual like if you're so I'm from Marin
County you know San Anselmo which is
right next to San Rafael and in the
Waldo's like we were discussing you know
who went to school at San Rafael high
and and you know eyes over Sir Francis
Drake but they're a little bit older
than us you know I'm friends with one of
their daughters but they were class of
71 but it's like no this we know this
history we know they're looking for the
Lost crime crop out at the beach and and
we know that all of a sudden they start
you know when the guys started touring
as a roadie with the dad and that kind
of took 420 to that National level and I
mean it's just there is a history in the
one thing I like that nobody argues is
like this really is the epicenter for
the culture and craft while the country
is falling behind on legalization and I
contribute that to extreme capitalism
um you have over three dozen countries
that have legalized already around the
world but no one can argue like and you
know this you travel too man I as in
Thailand in January and people like
you're from NorCal man Humboldt flat
Australia they know humble South America
they know humble you know if some know
the triangle
a few no Mendocino nobody knows Trinity
County that's a funny thing you know the
Emerald Triangle it's actually Three
Counties they're like really and I'm
like can you name it you always love
poison people but there is a lot of
history and there's a lot of influence
um you know post Summer Love post hippie
Hill in a carried through from that 60s
70s and still today with what guys like
you were doing yeah yeah so so when did
you start smoking uh late 80s early 90s
I started yeah oh my gosh man that's a
good uh it was either 89 or 90 yeah as a
young teen I had older siblings so
um pros and cons to that you know I
started partying a little bit younger
and um like we've talked about like I
said you know mine back in the day it
was tough because we got some good stuff
off the hill but as kids it was like
either you got stuff from South of the
Border the brick weed you know Mexi Tire
whatever it was or at the time for me
the coveted was was Northern Lights
because I was really hot back then right
I mean you could come across a little
again a little Swahili or maybe someone
had some Durban or something but that
that was my early experience was either
you're going to be totally blasted or
you can consume it all day you know yeah
and we had a lot of times it was green
Bud you're buying green Bud we bought
green bud and it could have been any
name you know not really knowing what it
was it was there was green and brown
yeah that was it it was green and brown
and then there's snap crackle pop right
like I remember and I'm gonna say man
the kids these days don't know we went
up the hill you know two miles in snow
both ways to school I'm not trying to be
like a fallen old head but dude we were
picking out sticks and stems and and
seeds and you know of course we tried to
grow those seeds I'm sure you did just
like I did and totally and there's good
stuff in there yeah I wish I would had
more stuff saved you know what I mean I
think
especially you know some of the the
Mexican stuff that they that we were
getting I mean there's a lot of good
genetics in there there is it wasn't
grown necessarily the best it wasn't
cured or dried properly and it would get
you really high but a lot of times you
get a headache from smoking it yeah you
would you like a strong debilitating
headache you know tight behind the eyes
not like headband but like in pain in
something else it was yeah it was
different times and you know I remember
slinging and it's something it's
interesting man because I didn't even I
think we talked about it before man you
know I came out of the proverbial Green
Closet in the teens you know because
while flower was a big part of my life
growing up and growing I mean I remember
going down and boarding in Half Moon Bay
my buddy's Uncle grew in Scott's Valley
and we'd swing by there on the way to
Capitola for Pizza My Heart Right for
lunch it's like these memories of
hanging out with these old heads that
they were growing some fantastic stuff
and the bud wasn't highly manicured it
sure as hell wasn't indoor it was either
hoop or outdoor in their Garden buried
between totally you know crops and and
it's just it's nostalgic but it
definitely has changed but it was a
different time and your point sometimes
it's just it was green or it was brown
it was good it was great yeah you know
yeah we got we so we used to drive down
for eighths of weed into Santa Cruz and
it was called the strawberry but it was
skunk it was a skunk but it was the
reason it was called strawberry was
because it was strawberry sized nuggets
had nothing to do with the flavor it was
the structure it was the skunk weed it
was like you know what I would you know
people say road kill skunk whatever but
this stuff was strong skunk not cat piss
they had the ammonia it's just it was
just straight skunk and it tasted skunk
down to the roach and one little butt of
it would just smell everything up which
you don't really see stuff like that
anymore you don't you don't man it's
interesting what some of the guys are
smoking up on the hill like I go up
there and still and you know it was a
little more popular a few years back but
forbidden fruit's a good example of that
you know so we talk about the stuff you
know it's time some it was so I really
felt my age but in a good way when I so
you were at the the Dead Ahead over the
weekend I was at Northern Nights Music
Festival which is Heavy Music yeah they
had you know some great bands and some
great DJs but the undertone is health
and wellness and culture and craft it
takes place on the border of Humboldt
Mendocino County like you're in the
heart of Emerald Triangle right and I'm
sitting kind of preaching to these kids
and telling them some of the stories and
I'm like you know there is a reason why
genetics morphed and changed over the
years especially in the 80s with War on
Drugs because the guys that were grown
up on the hill they need to be mindful
of the smell yeah and the way that they
were able to grow now under hoop now
undercover and so you're right even the
indoor guys though because there was no
filtration like we have no not at all
even in the 90s we did have filtration
but it didn't always work effectively
and not today I mean and we won't call
it names of specific Brands but there's
a few companies that are killing it with
that filtration and you wouldn't be any
of the wiser for what's being produced
but but one cultivar going back to his
forbidden fruit and that stuff so as
explained to them and it's interesting I
kind of I love quizzing people because
I'm a facts guy but I love sharing and
educating so I'm like do you know what
the median THC is of of legal flower
across this country you know and I asked
these five guys and they're all part of
the production team so it's kind of cool
so they've been around it and stuff and
um you know one's like oh 25 21 23 40 15
like will the median THC levels 21 not
that everything revolves around THC I
said so take forbidden fruit what do you
think the median THC is they're like I
want to go through a whole process I'm
like it's about 15 16 yeah but the
terpene percentage we're talking five
percent six when the median's like one
percent so I started explaining to them
you know if if cannabinoids are the
engine the terpenes are the steering
wheel so everyone's putting an emphasis
on THC but be mindful of those smells
and those flavors because that's what
the real experiential is with the flour
right and they were just like Mindless I
started talking about all the different
terpenes they're like and there is an
old head there I mean like this guy
um was named Fred he's been doing AV for
all kinds of shows and huge dead fan and
stuff and he's like I don't even
understand what you're saying he's like
lemon and what Mercy person what like he
you're like dude you need to learn your
turret profile man you'll have that much
better of an experience for sure you
know but it's a whole Evolution compared
to what we grew up with with what's
accessible now both by product and
education right you know so it's it's
fine man I'm loving it yeah it's a
different world now it is a lot of stuff
is hype driven yeah and that's okay too
yeah I mean
you know so you get a little bit of
everything but at the end of the day
quality is quality and it's hard to
argue quality now quality is subjective
to a degree flavor is subjective but I
feel like quality you know it's like if
the if the if the roach tastes good when
you fire it back up you know you got
some good stuff on your hands if it's
just burnt and it's sad and you want to
just keep it out then that's a whole
other story and I agree and you're
you're spot on with the hype like I
don't mean a knock it but I call them
trendy triangle strains and we went down
this road of all these candies and
desserts and everything and there were
some great genetics that kind of got
overlooked like I feel like GMO didn't
get enough time in the light you know
because so many people are wrapped up in
wedding cake then ice cream cake then
gelato you know 41. now RS as I said you
know yeah that was with different groups
too because I feel like GMO really with
our with my friends with Marlin you know
my good friend Marlon Asher like he
loved GMO and but but yeah I guess to a
degree I understand what you're saying
same thing with sunset Sherbert I feel
like that was another one that really
didn't Peak like it should have it
didn't get as much credit as it should
have yeah and then you compare it to
Skittles in runs and you're like is
almost to or GG which they're not back
yeah but to your point it gets hyped up
and it gets into this social media
bubble and people are going after it for
the wrong reasons but I think that's
also the experience again talking on the
legal Market when people walk in and
they're asking I call it PC you know
cannabis Consultants but Bud tenders
sure you know hey what what should we
smoke and they're telling them what the
loudest thing is to smoke or what the
most popular thing is to smoke and
they're not saying hey are you trying to
get help with sleep or do you have a
knee injury or how high you want to get
how do you want to get to like you were
talking about earlier man you're spot on
like there's you know when you're
smoking something like Skittles which
I'm a huge fan of as well it's just this
nice cool Cruise right it's not like out
of your head but then you throw in
something like green crack and someone
isn't expecting that they're like what
did you give me man they're going on a
whole other level well Green Crack is
one of those ones that your body will
adapt to it really quickly yeah but if
you haven't been smoking it it gets you
super high and it Peaks really quickly
and then it drops down actually too but
man it it'll get you to the point where
you need to sit down yeah so exactly
true and just take it all in and it yeah
in everybody's body is different too I
was telling that same group of kids I
was like you know my friend came across
it was a GDP which I know I love the the
old Trooper like purple Urkel and
granddaddy right and so as a GDP crossed
with Harlequin and I explained the two
different genetics and lineages of those
both and I said it was one of those
cultivars where I smoked it and I had to
lay down and listen to Jimi Hendrix like
that was just right that that was the
vibe and it was like this every once in
a while you get into that perfect
balance of heady and body right you know
and it was that perfect heady body for
me and I tell people if you find that
perfect strain stick with it like that's
what your body wants you know yeah and
it may not be the perfect strain forever
because it's all you know it's one of
those things that weed can be it should
be consumed fresh yeah and each batch is
slightly different you're not getting
getting the same expression every time
especially grown you know Boutique
flower yeah
you know and then even the commercial
stuff it's like there's so many
variables if you think of plant flowers
for roughly 70 days there's a lot that
can happen in those 70 days even in an
indoor environment to where it can be
slightly different yeah and I'm at the
mercy of I'm an outdoor and it's nothing
I have a level of respect for for dap
and indoor
but I'm a traditional outdoor full term
and a good example of that to your point
I was given
um some first round genetics from a guy
out of Santa Cruz thanks to Peter he's
like hey will you test run these and I'm
like you know I kind of stick to land
racing he's like well it's a good
Crossing to see what Neo with a Tai and
I didn't know how I was going to express
and I didn't know what to feed it I
didn't have any idea but to your point
we got hit with a heat wave in SoCal
which a lot of people oh you're so lucky
Lance you get to do you know you've got
the perfect climate like not exactly
when you're hitting triple digits and
you're hotter than Vegas in September
like we got hit yeah I mean there's been
some rough Summers I mean the last the
year before that I went to 120 in
Fallbrook when I was down there yeah and
you're like my friends were working so
yeah and what came out of that versus if
I were to rerun that now this season
with El Nino like you said it's it's too
different the expression because people
put and again the the genotype is a huge
Factor but Gino Fino chemo there's these
different elements on how you experience
these inputs they come here right well
an outdoor is like making wine in the
sense that we talked terroir and then we
talk about climate and weather in all
these things that contribute to the
final product exactly exactly you know
beyond drawing and curing there's so
much that goes on with outdoor that it's
different every year and so you're going
to have good vintages you're going to
have bad vintages you're going to have a
lot of stuff in between and even growing
the same exact genetics you're going to
get stuff all over the place every year
no matter what yeah it's very true and
you see it in your bed like I have a
friend uh Greg he's down in Santa Cruz
and uh kind of wild something I wouldn't
think in that climate but he went with a
Google grow format so he's like yeah I
took these logs let them soak all
through winter and now I'm growing these
lines and he's like he got these Jens he
got these pucks that he is running and
he said one of them he's gonna fully
bomb because just is just so the way it
expresses because that thing's like I
don't know four and a half foot now
where its siblings are like three foot
at best and it's it's in the same bed
and it's in the same grow format and
he's used so the same media the same
environment so to your point point the
the variants are great and it's
specially outdoor and I'm a little
jealous of the I call it God growing the
into like I'm I'm dependent on mother
nature but the god going indoor where
you can control the environment and I'm
not saying it's easy but you see that
uniformity you know well and it's
repeatable yeah it's very repeatable
what you need from a medicine standpoint
which I'm a medical I'm not an activist
I'm a medical Advocate first so I fully
respect that again because if you have
Grandma seizures cerebral palsy like if
you find something that works and then
someone goes oh yeah no this is gg4 you
know it's not GG it's it's maybe the
genetics but it's from a completely
different grower growing a completely
different way to your point growing's
half the battle are you cure it how you
dry it and I don't know if you're into
it by age my bud so I actually do two
two and then two months of Aging right
which I learned from the Italians like
but how you handle it like that really
factors into the end product for a
medical patient that matters totally so
I'm really big into aging not because I
want to age it but because I the
quantities you know it's like I want to
some stuff I want to say but for the
most part I want to smoke the best stuff
I have right at that moment but you know
leading into Turf lock you know it's
kind of a game changer because I'm a
mason jar guy I was always you know I
used mason jars forever and I was very
skeptical of the terplock I mentioned on
my podcast uh which will be two podcasts
ago terplock and I think a couple other
ones but I did side-by-side testing and
if you keep it at the same temperature
the terplock has more Terps you know and
as you go longer the longer you go the
more Terps are in the terp block yeah
yeah so it's pretty cool thing I'm with
you so I was again kind of I was taught
grew up with hippies so I was taught the
old way you know and some might consider
them wives tales but there was not
factual information around this because
this plant was suppressed for a century
you know is weaponized so
um we knew what we knew and that's what
always worked and when again the old
guys taught you hey this is how I've
done it and you smoke it and it's fire
or at least five us at that time you're
like okay it is what it is but I was the
same way I ran mason jars and kept them
sterile did all the right process I was
a little uncertain about the terplock
technology because I thought all bags
were created equal like we grew up with
you know Ziploc bags or whatever you
know baggies right when I slang and I
sell them in baggies you know but that
was based out in a set or film canisters
not if you remember we used to literally
the little stash cans but I was kind of
a little skeptical on it and then once
they explained the technology because
I'm one of the and you've probably
figured this out with me I'm being I'm
Community First like I have to believe
in the brand and the product that I'm
representing and and I have to make sure
that the culture and the core values of
that company are represent as well and
I've made a few missteps in my career
here
um you know with companies that were
maybe not necessarily in it for the same
reasons as me but I also got a place in
my career where I'm like I I'm in a good
spot to where I can be a little more
decisive and I can choose it for this a
good match or not so with these guys I
did a side by side test too before I
came to him I took one crop and I split
it and I did jars on one I did terplock
on the other and did what they said you
know hey go through your traditional
dryware 60 60 14 you know trim as you
trim and then put some in here put some
in in the jar
I was floored because never had I not
touched as much as we hate it like you
have to babysit your buds when you're
curing yeah and you know technically you
guys see you don't even need to burp it
yeah I realized that you guys say you
don't need to burp it but I I tend to
want to look at my butt all the time so
I end up burping it without even
thinking that I'm burping it you know
and you are so yeah get getting into
technology to explain on that why you
don't because
um the polymers that we use so again and
this isn't a throwaway bags isn't it
this is you can reuse them yeah for sure
time and time again we people are like
and again you deal with some people on
the hill they're like well I like mason
jars I like glass because it's bare for
the environment I'm like okay first off
the carbon footprint for producing glass
and that Tin Top is exponentially higher
than this right but the carbon footprint
for recycling that material is
exponentially higher than this because
it's recyclable as well and then think
about the logistics like it's even even
if it's a craft grower it's pulling down
500 pounds you're putting that in jars
and you're shipping it all the way to
San Diego or LA how much weight is that
compared to the bags totally so I've
been on podcasts where this guy busts
out a Yeti and he's got all this and you
hear it coming you hear the rattling
right and he pulls up and he's got the
jars and it's also I'm like here's what
I agree last season I keep it in a
turkey bag tin I am old school that way
and it's bags I'm holding it with one
hand and I'm like it's all here but the
technology is cool because what it does
is
um this plant's pretty radical in itself
right so we know that plants when
they're living you know take in that
carbon dioxide put out the oxygen well
when they're dying they do the opposite
so they they release that oxygen to try
to regenerate so this actually pushes
out the oxygen keeps that CO2 in that
environment because oxygen oxidizes
right so it keeps it down to a few
percent so it still allows the maturing
of the buds but on top of that the fact
that you've got antimicrobial
anti-static and UV protectant and even
our clear bags for guys like you because
same thing I started off with clear we
have we call our glasses which is kind
of making fun you know it looks like a
mason jar but it's a bag right but then
you can see your buds but you don't you
don't disrupt that environment but cool
that you figured out a Superman so we
did a test with a lab third party lab
independent we had to give them the
flower and we had to give them the
material to test so we named the jars
and we gave them the bags down in Lompoc
in Santa Barbara County and it was a
long-term test three-month test and they
found that while you get to where you
want to with cure in two weeks the
optimal percentage for both cannabinoids
and terpenes is it two months in our
bags so if you can keep it in longer
you're you're it's not a detriment to
the end product for you to do so yeah
and what happens after two months
because that's what friends have been
asking me it just it just levels off
it's not going to Peak further than that
but it's going to assist and if you keep
it the right temperature I mean you're
looking six months and it's still a good
product yeah the one thing is it's a bag
so you have to be aware of putting it in
a bag and getting it smashed you know
those are those are the things like I
love carrying around a tote with a bunch
of different flavors or whatever you
know and a backpack yeah and if you're
gonna do that you need to put them in
jars or something like that to work
because that's the only thing is you can
get it smashed a little bit yeah we do
have like Squints down in SoCal he uses
trays
um so he'll potenti again that's again
totally respect his craft being a full
indoor guy in his stuff especially is
Wendy is super loud I mean that's one
where I got in a regular bag and you
know bring it back home and my whole
whole house smelled like a skunk came
through so I'm like okay I gotta put
this in another bag but he puts them in
the little trays which does help with
that so that's one factor but to getting
into man this is I I gotta share this
and I gotta tell the story behind this
I've only told a few people so as far as
Segways so I have to share and you
remember the phone call so I was over at
Ed rosenthal's and we were on our way up
to Hall of flowers and I stopped by with
a few buddies and you're you're as good
advice too with that in jail oh yeah
there's they're just lovely they're good
people right we're really good people
and so we brought some flour we consumed
that and then Ed brings out a baggie and
I mean literally I'm like Ed you're
giving me flashbacks of high school man
like what do you do with that bag and
where did you get it and he's like oh
James gave me this stuff and I open it
up like oh my gosh like I knew you were
genetics from a growing standpoint I
didn't know you grew that well like
really I was like my God this stuff is
fire and then my second response was
like what is it doing in a regular bag
so that's why I called you and I'm like
dude smoking your stuff right now Ed
gave it to me but he gave it to me in a
freaking sandwich bag and I'm like we
gotta come up with something so I know
it's the first time of you seeing it
this is really awesome but that's
exactly where you came up it definitely
embodies everything that we're doing it
has that 70s Vibe and I love your 70s
Vibe because that was a big time for you
know for the community for the industry
so totally definitely want to plan this
yeah we came together with the the
collab bags do with them as you will but
awesome that's the one thing I wanted to
come out of it if I ever go back to Ed's
and he has your flower I didn't want
yeah I didn't want to get it in a
sandwich bag you know totally yeah it's
funny how much like polyethylene bags
sandwich bags it's just they they kill
the Terps they do and people don't
understand they have a lot of you know
they have them sitting around and the
thing is is like man unless they're in
the freezer in those bags you're killing
Terps you're losing Terps every day they
go in those bags you are so man it's
it's a hydrocarbon people in in not to
get geeky but that's exactly it man
terpenes and they're they're volatile
hydrocarbons and you get them even 70
degrees and higher and they start this
pain and that's why people like ah this
smells good people keep an opening the
bag and it's like you're losing a little
bit of that love and you you can't get
it back that's the problem is it's Genie
in a Bottle scenario right once you let
it out it's not like I can put all that
goodness back in so be being able to
contain it and maintain it is a huge
factor and even a study a guy who's
doing large scale pre-rolls up here
um he had an R D team that was doing a
study they found that there's up to a 50
terp loss post grind and they're
grinding hundreds of pounds of shift and
they're oh my God how much quality are
we losing what can we do to try to
retain as much as we can post crime but
but through the people process what
they're talking about grinding is
probably putting in a blender yes to be
honest you know I feel like a lot of
guys that do pre-rolls they blend it and
so like the pre-rolls we've been working
on a pre-roll to launch in metric in
California for a while and if we do it
we're gonna do it right it's gonna be
hand
ground everything's you know in milled
we're going to use a you know flower
Mill
that's as I said you know that yeah but
then those the thing is is with the
joints you want to consume them fresh
they're not something you want to sit on
a shelf for two months you don't even
really want to sit on a shelf for a
month if you could get a you know a
pre-roll should be rolled and smoked
relatively quickly I think that uh cold
storage will help these things same
thing you know doing Cold Storage with
these bags it probably last a year and
you absolutely can still maintain really
high quality exactly true we have fresh
frozen bags for guys that are you know
on the concentrate side but exactly your
point you can chill them you can freeze
them
um I agree with you 100 and you pointed
out something a lot of people are not
really aware of or cognizant of we talk
about grinding but there's a difference
between grinding and milling and you
nailed it so grinding is you're
pulverizing that material and what
you're doing is yeah you're ripping
apart the biomass but the most delicate
part of this plant is on the outside not
the inside so that's why I explained to
people who are kind of layman to the
industry they uh well can't you just
handle it this way can't you just
process isn't it the same as mushrooms
or tomatoes or any is like no because
all those things the goodness is on the
inside a lot of them have a protective
layer yeah pineapples oranges every
citrus fruit has this protective layer
but a lot of your your
um gourds and you know a lot of your
your other vegetables have protective
layers as because I'm a gardener across
the board I've got Citrus I've got you
know all kinds of veggies and I've got
my flour and so I explained to them
that's the difference is it's on the
outside and then I explained to him like
have you ever seen a hop and they're
like yeah like you know Hop's the only
cuts into cannabis but something
happened in the evolution of this plant
centuries ago to where it expressed
itself internally and externally a hop
all the goodness is protected inside
right but with a cannabis plant with the
profile everything's outside so we can't
handle it the same way we do others so
to your point grinding you're ripping
the trichomes off that biomass you're
really especially pulverizing you're
just blending it it's the worst yeah and
it's so inconsistent people think you're
you're getting you're homoglizing it but
you're not you're getting an
inconsistency because you're getting
clumps of those Terps and of those oils
and those when you're turning into a
powder yeah yeah you know so yeah it's
so Milling it you know that Mill it and
just have it work with itself in order
to break it down to a bare material so
like you have to do a plug but the flour
Millet twice
great I mean I use my old school grinder
still too but I'm it's delicate you know
so yeah we grew up like you remember the
Mendo Mulcher Mulcher Santa Cruz
Shredder dude the Sweet Leaf was the
first one and I got one of the first 10
prototypes no still Sweet Leaf is like
close to my heart as well you know I
love the flour mill you know I met uh
the guys from Flour Mill a while back
and they hooked me up with some flour
Mills dude yeah good stuff he's on a
mission too he's just like you like you
know that's the owner of a business that
believes in his product but he also
cares about the community and he cares
about the plant and he's out there and
you run it I just saw him a hall of
flowers like you see him on the circuit
you see him working the shows and
representing and it's about being a part
of the community which is a bigger thing
and again it's he believes in his
product and he should his product's a
good product yeah you know he definitely
should he should yeah and I believe in
excited at a scale back when I was
working yeah and there'd be flour Mills
yeah on point being a marketing guy I
love it is the packaging is great uh I
like the fact that you can go with
different size uh grinds so if you want
a coarse grind you can go coarse if you
want a fine grind you can kind of go
fine if people don't understand that
yeah like if you roll up like I'm again
old school so I'm like more of the fine
but if you do like still snapping and
ripping bongs like you go for the course
yeah but people understand like even
that and you mentioned giant wine but
even though it's like so the bigger the
joint the more coarse you want to go you
want the air to be able to travel yeah
you know if it's too tight you're not
gonna you know too tight and they they
grind is too fine you're not going to be
able to get a good hit very true and so
you want to go of course so you get all
those air pockets in there so it travels
that smoke travels down yeah so yeah I
smoked a 24 gram joint over the weekend
with uh with my producer of the show
yeah
so yeah you were the deadhead show yeah
yeah dead and Company was pretty intense
it was pretty amazing it was that final
it was the final three tour dates in San
Francisco
you know different to be here like again
for people who don't understand like
this is Ground Zero oh yeah for that
group and for that movement oh the whole
band everything around the band started
here yeah you know the music started
here Jerry's house was here they grew up
pretty much everybody grew up here and
yeah so yeah yeah it's definitely some
histories when I hit you up and is
asking if you're coming up on the hill
and you're like no and I'm like got it
and then I ran into a few other people
same thing that they're like yeah my
buddy's gonna come up and he's in San
Francisco for the show and it's Legend
especially again when you recognize how
much of an influence it had on the
community and the culture yeah so
definitely well and like the only
requirement to being a deadhead is that
you have good taste in music so you know
it's like you can be an [__] you can
be a good person whatever as long as you
have good taste in music you know it's
usually when you get himself Good Vibes
one of the ladies that was in our little
group because we were 20 feet back from
the stage maybe less maybe like 15 feet
back from the stage which was amazing
but uh one of the ladies pointed out
that the problems are caused by the
people without alcohol and if you look
around the ones with the beer cans in
their hand are the ones that are pushing
and shoving it's not the ones on you
know psychedelics or the ones smoking
weed It's usually the ones with the
alcohol and there's definitely truth to
that I feel like uh alcohol kind of
numbs you and
other things kind of uh you know
heighten your senses and you really for
those kind of shows you want to be
hypersensitive so you're yeah they
provide this hypersensitive experience
for you if you're hypersensitive so
that's right it's an amazing experience
I say the same thing and that's right
again why we get along so well because I
tell people and I kind of just put it as
a summary so I quit drinking back in
2019 and I was never really a big
drinker again I I like the plant because
of the holistic attributes to it and
being a cancer survivor too I think
about okay I need to I need to put good
things in my body so I never want to
come out of remission right but I just
got bored of it and it is interesting
because to your point I was like man
alcohol makes me forget whereas you're
running like cannabis yeah it not only
helps me remember but helps me discover
and that's again this Against The
Stereotype you know when I call out
because I can be a little bit a touch of
activist when I do give my opinion on
the overall stereotype and stigmas and
tabooisms associated with the plant and
I don't just blame anslinger back in the
30s or Nixon in the 70s or Daryl Gates
and Nancy Reagan with the Dare program
in Arya in the 80s but I also blame
Hollywood I'm like okay so they've got
characters like Spicoli and guys trying
to go find White Castle and all this
[__] it's like that's not I maybe a
little bit of short term because I'm so
enthralled in the moment but when I
educate people and help them understand
it re-clocks your brain so that
everything from an experiential I mean
everything music food sex it doesn't
matter everything is enhanced because it
puts more of an enunciation on that
experiential but alcohol numbs you
totally well you know and then there's
guys like Sanjay Gupta who kind of
brought it to the light on 60 Minutes
years ago that that made my parents
aware of the benefits of cannabis and
THC and CBD and all these things and
then we have Elon Musk who he smokes on
The Joe Rogan podcast and he's the
wealthiest person you know in the world
yeah and Sanjay that's a good one man
because he he was he was going against
the grain with us and then totally he
corrected himself and it takes it takes
a big person to say I'm wrong or I
misunderstood right but but the big
thing is is how can you argue with a
parent that wants to help their kid get
better either kid's sick you know and
it's like how how are we to say that
they're wrong correct you know and
that's my biggest argument it's like if
it makes you better and you're not
hurting anybody how can you say that's
wrong yeah that's that's what really in
I don't talk about too much but when I
segue you know because again well it was
such an influence when I was younger I
did go down the mainstream career path
but when I got pulled back in in a good
way in Denver when it legalized moved
out there in 2014 and you know
eventually became GM of the Cannabis but
the thing I got to this pivotal point
because I kind of pulled the Jerry
Maguire because that company is owned by
hedge fund and again it didn't the
beliefs weren't aligned right the
culture and core values weren't aligned
with me and I had friends that were from
from digitalmedia.com marketing and
they're like well it's not too late you
can still come out with you and still
put the parent company under the name
and people don't know and I'm like first
off at this point because I do have such
a lower respect for the plant I wouldn't
work for anyone who holds that against
me just look at let's just look at it
from a business perspective the fastest
growing industry in the world and the
greatest opportunity so if that's a
business person that goes no you worked
in weed I don't support that I went work
for him but second what you touched on
the kids the children it's interesting
because we actually were awarded we did
a great story on all these families that
were moving their children up that were
dealing with Grandma seizures and this
is back in like the early like the
Stanley Brothers Charlotte's Web kind of
ear right and we're covering this and it
really hit home for me because I don't
know I you know way studying school with
juvenile law and everything and and
children's rights and all that and your
point these these parents were being
chastised but they were moving from
places like Texas and Mississippi and
Alabama to bring their kids to a place
because Western medicine failed them and
the side effects of Western medicine was
detrimental to to every aspect of that
individual's life right and they came up
and they're going going from 95 seizures
to five seizures a week how can you
argue with that you can't argue and so
that's that's again I I told we were
talking earlier that's when I came out
of the proverbial green closet and I'm
like I don't care what people think and
you know quite honestly I'm at an age I
really shouldn't give a [__] anyway you
know because what I believe in is what
matters and I'm not saying I'm always
right and I'm not saying word is more
I'm not but when you find out facts like
that and you see how much it improves
life and then you find out that the
biggest studies from both the scientific
and medical standpoint are happening in
Tel Aviv Israel and I tell people like
that is the epicenter of study on this
plant they're like Israel I thought they
were conservative I'm like no they're
open-minded because they know not
everything that can be a solution comes
in a Petri dish and is man-made like
trust Mother Nature she has a lot more
answers for us than than people realize
yeah you know so I definitely I feel the
same way and that's what encouraged me
to just stay and feel like you still
enjoy it you still love it I'm like yeah
I'm going on a decade I I can't imagine
anything else you've been to a lot of
cannabis events
I I have I have how many events have you
been to I just hit my 190th uh yeah this
past month and you know granted it's
been over a decade but a majority of
those happen uh when first with weed
maps and to to now so it really happened
like in the last six years uh the one
thing that I found and I actually wrote
A series on it you probably know for mg
magazine
I wrote a multi-part series on the
history of cannabis by country so I
decided and I know again I've been kind
of pushing more on that than other
people in the space because a lot of
people they kind of start local and Go
Global and I decided to take a different
approach I wanted to support it from a
global level and bring it back home
right so I started looking into
different countries and where they were
and my travels were taking me there I
mean thanks to Weedmaps I went on a tour
and brought the product to Australia and
then went over to Europe and then more
recently Thailand like we talked about
South America Jamaica all these places
I've been to thanks to this plant and
it's interesting because I found that
you know there's Universal languages
one of those things is food all of us
need food we need stuff so we we need
water we need to survive
um but we all music is very Universal
yeah words are not lyrics or not the
beat is is part of that heart and it's
it's kind of like that that theme song
to our life to function cannabis is
another it doesn't matter if I spoke the
language or not I was greeted by Happy
Smiles in the plant and so these are all
just vibrations they are vibrations man
everything in the earth is Shifting and
it's it's moving into a faster vibration
but everything has energy and that's
what it comes back to but man I'm so
thankful I mean some of the the ones
that really stand out is like nimbin uh
Mardi Gras down in immunizer for the
25th anniversary and if you remember
again earlier for us but we know this
happened after the summer love here the
the hippies were kind of pushed out
because the yuppies were coming in the
80s and and hippies were into granola
and patchoulial and all that crazy stuff
yeah so they were pushed out to Scotts
Valley or the locals stayed in Berkeley
but a lot went up to Menace Casino in
Humboldt right you know up the coast
and it was the same thing in Australia a
lot of those hippies moved out of Sydney
and Brisbane and moved down to the
countryside on the border of New South
Wales and Queensland and they started
having this protestable and I went down
there and it was so experiential and it
was so similar to here man I mean like
the hairstyles uh the drum circles the
the bong tossing competitions like all
this stuff I'm like it's like being back
in Northern California but with a
different accent wow but everything else
was like the whole the way they
respected the plant the Good Vibes they
support each other that was pretty
radical spanibus like we talked about
I've been encouraging people for years
I've seen the most people from from our
side of the pond ever last this last
year yeah out in spam this is insane
um Expo weed the circuit down in in
latam
um the Expo weed Chile specifically in
Santiago is phenomenal you get some
great guys that come over from Europe
but from there's a whole culture down
there I don't know why people don't
really pay attention to South America
but that's a whole other scene and they
have a few land race that come out of
there as well social history Africa
Durban and and Johannesburg has a lot
going on but several countries have been
producing for years over there so they
have a whole vibe but I've been enjoying
it man it's really I tell people I there
are places that were never on my bucket
list in the Articles if you get a chance
Man Thailand like do do you know that
the U.S Postal Service has been one of
the biggest drug dealers in history in
my opinion as far as trafficking but
when our troops would go on leave
serving Vietnam they go over to the
shores of Thailand and that's where they
discovered Thai stick and they're using
the U.S Postal Service to ship that back
to their hippie friends back in the 60s
here and then the term bong that's a
Thai term for how they consume cannabis
is bong and that was brought over so I
learned stuff like that in doing that
series and again it brings a whole other
level of respect of how this is very
much a Universal Plant but it's a
universal culture too right so I've been
loving it man and you're you're the same
like that's what I love about you and
your Good Vibes you're like I'm just
along for a phenomenal right and
thankful to be a part of it and like
both of us kind of have the same kind of
yeah Extremely Blessed it's a great
energy it's a great experience to have
you know so definitely good stuff yeah
it's pretty wild and you know the
different cultures all over and then
Amsterdam at one point was the epicenter
to a degree yeah it's changed it's
changed half of the coffee shops have
closed down the mayor who came in office
she's a nice woman but she's been in
since 18 now she's trying to push the
red light district out to the edge of
the city she's trying to push the
Cannabis out to the city they're trying
to make it so you have to be a legal
resident to go into the coffee shops
because they are technically safe havens
right it's illegal to to produce and
Courier it's not technically legal or
gray area until it crosses a threshold
of the coffee shop so it's a system that
did kind of get abused but you and I
both know this the real epicenter of
cannabis in Europe is Spain and and
really is Barcelona you're talking about
Spain there's six 700 Social Clubs it's
still a little more conservative than
almost 10 years ago because 10 years ago
you could go around smoking joints on
the street and you can't really do that
anymore no you can't see it can't smell
it can't hear it can't feel like it's
that kind of space and the cat alone
government has been trying to move it
forward but I'll tell you man it's proof
of concept because like being a member
of like HQ just as an example or dank of
England down there and it proves that
people that choose to consume alcohol
can cohabitate with people who choose to
consume flour and you can have an
environment where where you can get
drinks you can get food you can watch
footy on the TV you can play snooker
whatever right but everyone gets along
and everyone's Good Vibes you know and
so it's like we're we're having this big
debate about social clubs domestically
it's like go to Spain
yeah go experience and see that you you
can bring all these people together do
it and you can watch if you don't smoke
go experience it yeah like 100 yeah it's
it's eye opening you know and we're
talking about places that serve alcohol
that have cannabis a lot of hash and
stuff food or coffee or drinks and
they're not trying to hustle you through
like the coffee shops is come in get
your spliff and your espresso and be
done in 10 minutes that's not the
mentality of the social club it's more
of a co-op environment where you come to
hang with friends and you might be
watching soccer for three four hours
yeah and they're not trying to rush you
out because you're invested in in that
that environment totally so yeah it's
definitely um like I said it's it's been
a great experience and and something
that again both of us I think have fully
enjoyed and enthralled ourselves in you
know absolutely so
so yeah so what's your favorite strain
well you know as far as genetics go what
yeah what what do you I mean you said
forbidden fruit a little bit Yeah but
but as far as like you say I heard land
race is there a particular land race
that you prefer growing what where where
does that mean because land race
encompasses quite a few different things
yeah yeah so I've been nowhere to your
level nowhere to someone like judgery's
level but you know I've been collecting
through my travels and so I'm very
fortunate to have some pure Durbin from
South Africa uh thanks to a good friend
to get some tie from let's talk about
Durban real quick because it's been a
Hot Topic so I believe that the Durban
in the United States is not the same
Durban that we experienced that they
came from yeah Africa correct I believe
it's the super silver haze cross that uh
greenhouse and Scentsy had and and some
other people yep I think uh Simon from
Sirius they had a Durban Poison and but
I believe it was crossed with a haze and
so the haze is very dominant it leans
towards that the real true Durbin is
definitely more musky in my opinion it
is um sandal
that licoricey kind of muskiness yeah
it's a really earthy cultivar and
um I didn't pop the seeds that I got
from over there but I gave him to a good
friend Johnny Ray from Rey's he's about
an hour east of Garberville phenomenal
closed loop has sheep on the hill worms
everything's all I'm a huge he's a hip
neck through and through one of the
smartest guys I've ever met and I gave
my seeds to hit not all of them but gave
a good amount of seeds to him uh he
pulled out full term outdoor right you
know he's got nature to work with
he sent me a picture and he showed me
their trees he should and again this is
another thing you know when it's more
pure not cross because you write a lot
of the the land race came through Europe
and so when you get a land race from
South Africa that's traveling through
Europe or you get something from Asia or
you get something from the Middle East
that's traveling through Europe to your
point they try to hardier they try to
morph it and it's not the same because
there's three different places no it
doesn't you know by butt really quick
tangent so so Northern Knights which I
was just doing there they had their 10
year anniversary and so they wanted to
do a cultivar with Northern Lights which
to answer your question that is one of
my favorite is Northern Lights I like
because I grew up with it and he sends
me video he had three different Farms
including his own grow and he sent me a
video of it and I'm like yeah that's it
the bud structure that's how I didn't
have to smell it I didn't have to taste
it I saw the bud structure I'm like
that's it so that is a Northern Lights
Dom it's crossed with a specific look
yeah it has a very specific look and
especially when you know how it's grown
and that's again I think why I lean
towards outdoor because the manipulation
that occurs indoor the the the bud
structure doesn't always express
correctly in my opinion when I let it go
Outdoors so going back to to John
he showed me a picture he already grows
trees but he had a 12 foot ladder
standing next to this thing and it was
14 foot tall this and I'll show you the
picture it was incredible and that's how
I knew that it wasn't something crossed
with a dwarf or a large or something out
because that's too many people across
based on what's convenient oh this is
something that won't you know
contaminate the rest of my car this is
something that won't get me in trouble
it'll stay stunted or dwarfed like a
Swain yo that's another I'm a huge fan
of sueno nobody knows that it's a 50 50
pretty much of sour d and blue dream too
that we were growing along with AK-47
when we were still pushing packs back in
the late 90s early 2000s nobody likes to
grow because it's a Squatty not easy to
grow high maintenance plant but the
experiential is phenomenal so so going
back to yeah I really I do genuinely
like the land race they are sincerely
hard to find I did find a guy over in
Europe that supposedly has a true
Northern Lights in the meantime I'm okay
with you know I'm gonna get some seeds
from because I think Andrea actually if
I understand he got those from Nat up at
HSC so and it's a it's a Northern Lights
cross with GMO crossed with something
else but that does entice me if you're
looking for a cut of some real Northern
Lights I got your back oh my gosh if you
do it because seriously I've been
looking in the only place everyone keeps
directing me back to it he's a nice guy
I just haven't had the chance to meet
them in person that'd be phenomenal so
yeah my buddy Gordon my buddy Gordon has
done a lot of work he's from Grass
Valley but he's done a lot of work with
Northern Lights and Sour Diesel and you
know he's nice
he's got a huge collection of stuff and
yeah it's definitely accessible I'd love
that because that is a one there's just
something again for me because we know
it's subjective our endocannabinoid
systems yeah that's just always been oh
yeah it's so subjective you know what
works for one person isn't necessarily
going to work for the next some some
person might like this profile it's just
like food and it is and everything else
it is yeah why do you like purple grapes
and I like green grapes you know you
like the sweetness I like the Sour
Whatever It Is and they got some crazy
grapes coming out today cotton candy
grapes are pretty pretty dope but which
is fingers or whatever yeah they're
insane and it's you know as long as it's
natural I'm all for it you know I'm not
about the yeah and I mean a lot of that
stuff we'd heard GMO but like the truth
is like a lot of that stuff is actually
just data driven breeding and actually
experimentation and so but but done on a
different level than I think a lot of
people are dealing with cannabis yeah
but that's that's changing that's that's
slowly changing I mean data-driven
beating is definitely changing I think a
lot of guys that I know that are doing
breeding at scale
are actually using data yeah it's like
you kind of need to now if you're doing
Autoflower breeding you should be doing
using data as well yeah but which we
know how huge that is because you we've
got a lot of similar friends across the
pond and you know of course they use
because of the growing environment where
it is dense population that they're all
about the Autos but it seems like to
your point a lot of them are going more
towards science and in versus the
traditional well you have to to a degree
I mean you can do whatever you know if
you're doing small tents that's one
thing but if you're planting an acre or
two acres or 20 acres you want something
that's consistent and you want to
improve that over Generations if you're
if you're making seeds you might as well
be making better seeds yeah you know
instead of just making seeds to make
seeds I feel like you're either going
one way or another if you're not going
right in the middle every time unless
it's stable which it's not no so that
you see it with regs the inconsistent
going back to when you're when you're
running just plain old seeds you it's a
crap shoot yeah I never know what I'm
gonna get good bad or ugly you know
totally so well and then the thing is is
growing it out multiple times it's like
if you just go from seed Outdoors the
next year you grow that same cut it's
probably going to be different yeah yeah
so besides the environmental stuff it's
genetically you know it's genetically
more mature yeah so yeah very true so
yeah there's there's just sexual
maturity that goes on where if you grow
it
multiple times usually the third time
the fourth time sometimes you hit it
right the first time
but it's those the the third generation
I feel like is is more of a true
expression of where you're going to get
down there what you want yeah yeah
because I've done those what I ran last
year was F1 and it was
little basket case I mean I was
surprised like in veg it was some of the
fast sleeves I ever saw and not just to
stereotype but to a certain extent you
do pay attention to those things and I'm
like wow this is way leaning towards an
indica and I mean even just clonal
Generations so to take in a clone as
opposed to Growing from seed getting
that Colonial generation a couple of
those in so you really know because the
genetics stabilized and then you get the
same expression yeah and then you put in
tissue cultures
what's your opinion on I'm just kind of
curious on um how long to heat moms
around because I have some friends of
like nine ten rounds and I'm like
doesn't it get to a point to where well
so so there's there's a lot of
debate on on the subject and I feel like
if your moms are healthy you can keep
using them but
but yeah from tissue culture we do two
two rounds of clones and then put new
moms in right because we're worried
about uh viral load we're worried about
yeah just just uh renewing the Clones to
keep them at the most optimal point and
so we're doing gen one from tissue
culture so we have the Gen zeros which
are the tissue culture uh plants and
then we take the Clones off of those
those are the Gen ones and we like those
the best nice so I feel like they're the
most consistent they they respond the
most consistently
um not that there's anything wrong with
Gen zeros they're a little bit harder to
work with yeah so it's just one of those
things but yeah two rounds uh but I've
seen people put their you know we I was
talking about DJ Short a while back but
putting them in the ground every year
you've let them veg out and then you
know the the vibrations of the earth
restore the genetics but there is truth
to that you get really rapid growth
Outdoors so you're gonna get really
clean cuts uh so if you don't have
tissue culture that's that's an option
yeah so yeah that's the next best thing
you know nice cool man yeah it's good
stuff yeah man so I guess we get we need
smoke we didn't smoke it we're gonna
smoke something light we're gonna smoke
some uh contest entry here oh no way
it's from the loops love the contest too
I was following that that's great and
you actually wanted the entrants I think
uh you're fourth place it's like we
actually submitted ours in Turf block I
was like that's super dope yeah they did
totally it was great seeing chirp walk
in there and
you know we're doing it from clone next
time we're gonna do tissue culture clone
for the next contest I feel like it'll
even even the playing field out a little
bit more when you give genetics
especially stuff that's not super stable
you get stuff all across the board
yeah kind of taking more to that formula
one type where it's a little more
uniform definitely makes sense
so
to your point Level Playing Field how
it's expressed this is this is uh
that is the way to smoke extremely fat
so I I think a lot of people say that
like I guess that's how I smoke mostly
because I feel like above two grams
you really start getting the flavor
uh I like the way they hit I like the
way they re-fire
um
nice candy chirps in there
it's smooth too yeah
so we've smoked almost all of the
entries no way all gone yeah I mean how
long was from start I'm not trying to be
the interviewer yeah yeah that's okay
I'm kind of curious man because I was
falling as much as I could during my
travels but two week period it wasn't it
felt like it went by so quick yeah it
really wasn't long enough it was 15 days
right okay 15 days and you're smoking
every day in that 15 day period you're
eliminating stuff right off the bat like
there's stuff that just got eliminated
you know I got it down to 10 and then
those I would smoke one and then wait
two hours because I want to feel the
effect yeah it was about the effect but
also about the flavor right and you
don't want to kill your palate and if
you're smoking every day you gotta drink
a ton of water uh you know and then what
you're doing is you're comparing one to
the next one to the next and at the end
sometimes I'd fire both of them up back
and forth and go okay well I like the
way this tastes or I like the way this
this doesn't burn uh and I'm using rice
paper so I do a reverse roll with rice
paper yeah yeah I feel like that gives
you a little more neutral this is
actually a raw paper I like raw papers
too but as far as like for the for the
no burn I like the rice nice so it's
also subjective too you know it is
that's a again it is but I think there's
some things like to your point if you
did early elimination I'm I'm willing to
Guess that those are ones that were kind
of obvious in nothing I'm sure everyone
great on efforts but they probably
failed somewhere along post Harvest
right so something just wasn't I think
the contest was rushed to be 100 honest
we gave people seeds in December
expected them to have flour from seed in
June that's and if you if you waited a
little bit too long to pop those seeds
you're having a harvest early yeah and
that was the main culprit I think for
the problem is people had to harvest a
little early even then some of the stuff
that we've tested you know like we've
popped some of the seeds since we have
something that finishes super early but
not everything's like that and then you
know with growing conditions and
environments you just never know like
even people grow in closets if it's
extra cold it's going to take a little
bit longer you know if you don't have
your environmentals dialed in
but yeah so we're going to be doing
another contest here in a couple months
should be super exciting we love to
sponsor again man is stoked when you hit
me up I mean I know I know you're a fan
like you said I I do the same thing too
I did the Pepsi challenge before I came
on and obviously drank the Kool-Aid yeah
through and through and been nothing but
stoked with the product but when you
reached out and said hey this is why I'm
doing this what I want to do that's what
we want to support that's something that
I've made very clear I I love my CEO he
he gives me the freedom that I desire to
to make it be successful
um but I was very clear and adamant
about how I'm Community First you know I
mean this is and again you don't have to
be from NorCal you don't have to be
brought up by hippies to be culturally
inclined or or to respect the craft but
when it is kind of instilled in you it's
easier for you to know what the right
decisions are in in life and I'm so
fortunate that again you know he allows
that but that's what we're trying to do
more of is supporting the community
because they need it more so than ever I
mean it was like you talked about so you
went to the head I went up to the hill
and I thought I'd see more Growers these
guys aren't coming out and it's tough
times right now you the industry is
going micro macro and I talked to you
earlier about how you can easily compare
the Canadian Market to the California
Market because both of them came out
guns Ablaze and didn't necessarily do
things right you had the wrong guys that
were pushing all the weight now the the
craft guys the culture guys are the ones
that are coming up because they can
stand through storms whereas others
can't right especially when the money
pulls out when everything eventually
comes full circle
into Canada it's like LPS and then even
LP's coming into California though there
was a lot of LPS in California they were
in the beginning yeah there was a move
especially during covid man a lot of the
lp a lot of the Canadian money was
coming in and I mean even like wanna I
would have never thought in a you know
love obviously what Nancy and the team
of Joe hodus I go way back over there
marketing
but I was kind of surprised you know
like some of the inequality was so rough
yeah and then compared to places like
Colorado and Washington that legalized
first yeah their markets stabilized I
mean they've done a whole nother round
of consolidation though over the last
year it's really struggled during covet
everybody had a good covet and so the
ones that over expanded really had a
rough time during the consolidation the
ones that are still around are yeah you
know it's improved yep yeah and it is
you're right it's very and as long as it
isn't uh Federal we're going to talk it
at this level but I did just do a Show
recently in Oklahoma and it was not good
like they're going through a hard reset
but then I also you don't want to be
critical but I'm still a baffled man
being in Colorado and it's weird
everyone's like you got the business in
Colorado and you're from California but
it was a good experience to cut my teeth
in a market like that yeah because I
brought the experience but also saw how
it was for a market that wasn't familiar
with legal is because we legalized a lot
of people I mean we legalized prop P you
know which San Francisco is a city and
county but prophe was legalized in 1990
so people think 96 for medical we
technically have no medical since the
beginning since we were in high school
that way and so going to a market like
Colorado and to your point like I felt
like they did it pretty well they had to
rework it and all the rest of it but
then Washington oh we'll kind of do it
our way we're a little different I
didn't agree with how they oh you don't
need medical anymore
my one of my aunts she's she is Medical
in Washington and she was a medical
grower growing for herself and to tell
her that she can't grow anymore that she
has to go buy it from somebody yep she's
been pushing Organics since the 90s you
know she's one of the longest living
survivors of AIDS in HIV wow and I just
did the walk here in San Francisco over
the weekend it's a pretty wild you know
and she's been a cannabis consumer for a
long time but to tell her that she can't
she can no longer grow legally you know
which I guess they allow a small amount
of plants but it's like they they
technically know I mean that's I tell
people like Washington is one of those
states where it's not even people like
really and I'm like yeah like not
everyone's doing it absolutely right say
well Oregon Oregon Limitless license and
then all of a sudden guys I'm growing
hemp and pushing all that stuff to the
to the other coast that was a whole
crazy oh my gosh and then Oklahoma did
the same I'm like does nobody learn
money the government's like let's just
give her away so we get as much money as
possible and as quickly as possible
that's why I tell people it's short-term
gain or long-term goal and that was very
selfish of the government to say Hey you
know we're going to play the extreme
capitalism card we'll get rich along the
way but what happened let's get rich
quick instead of like look look at the
long term and invest in it yeah you know
unfortunately a lot of people are
short-sighted and it happens in every
aspect of life you know triple they look
at the immediate and they're like oh
look how much we can get for these
licenses let's just get all that money
and then we'll worry about it down the
road we can adjust the laws or we can do
this unfortunately you're getting some
of those people that are producing
amazing flour like in California that
there's this barrier for entry to get in
the legal you know in the legal own
unfortunately if I pay quarter million
dollars for his like just to get legal
from the Shadows phenomenal grower
phenomenal product in his like Lance it
cost me a quarter million and everyone
thinks they have that buried in their
backyard by the way everything said all
the guys on the Hill are still sitting
on a million dollars in in you know shoe
boxes no there's a ton of guys that it
was the barrier for entry and you either
had shitty quality and you couldn't get
in or you had great quality but you
didn't have the money or the resources
very true so yeah but those guys are
kind there's some like I still have
friends too they grow amazing flower
that don't they don't even give a [__]
they do other things you know I mean so
it's like the hobbyist grower and some
of the those guys got the best flower
too and they're making it work they're
smart and then you have the ones who did
come out and now they're worried to go
back into the Shadows so a few of those
guys they're doing organic produce and
going back to farmers markets or GCS
like I know a couple guys and now
they're normally carry general
contractor dude like you know more about
growing than I know about everything in
the world like like you are a master but
they have to be realistic and go hey
it's just not you know totally so but
every Market is it's but I was I was sad
saddened for Oklahoma because it was
It's really hurting you know it's really
hurting out there but well the beauty of
it is they can change we can change we
can all change we can all make a
difference we can recognize the problems
and then have solutions to correct those
problems yeah learn from the wrongs so
where do you see the industry going in
the next five years you know it's oh my
God we have to stabilize a little more
yeah I would assume we definitely do you
know I've been concerned I thought it
was going to happen at the end of
Trump's term and and some say that
there's a possibility during Biden's
term but I still feel like Federal
legalization is going to be a political
Pawn you know I think it's gonna be one
of us
yeah and this is silly this is pewdata
you guys this is not this is not headset
PDS New Frontier this isn't a niche or
industry specific analytics or data
company Pew did a study 85 of the
populace of this country are okay or
pro-cannabis at some either medical
right adult use or both so the fact that
the the old blue hairs on the hill you
know are still trying to play the
splitical angle and it's another article
I wrote like a lot of people like oh but
the big three and for those that don't
know we're not talking Ford Chrysler
Chevy we're talking about pharmaceutical
alcohol and tobacco so I wrote Our call
I'll make you guys that all those dudes
have been in this industry for years
yeah Farm has been in its I mean the
this is where the government contradicts
itself right so it's a schedule one
which didn't even make sense to me when
I study it in school I'm like you
remember Sesame Street where kids both
grew up on it you know three of these
kids are doing their own doing the same
thing one of these kids are doing their
own when I saw all the schedule one
drugs and then saw weed there as like
there's got to be some sort of story and
that's when I started learning more
about the the historical prohibition and
weaponizing it towards minorities but
man it is crazy because this whole
Federal thing it's it's overwhelming as
far as how much support but those big
guys are already here I mean that one so
GW Pharmaceuticals which got acquired by
Jazz for so GW Pharmaceuticals one of
the biggest Pharmaceuticals in the world
based out of the UK during covid and I'm
not conspiracy theorists just
essentially in the Jazz acquired GW
Pharmaceutical which was the biggest
Pharma out of Ireland now they're
actually pushing their organic you know
plant-based cannabinoid Pharmaceuticals
in Asia but they're the ones who
technically have the only one registered
here in the states so out of five that
use synthetic cannabinoids they have the
FDA approval and a drug that uses
organic or plant-based pharmaceutical
right so where things are going to go
farm is already here alcohol has already
been invested for years tobaccos are
even invested I mean big time invested
for years both domestic and in Europe
don't forget I mean that's this isn't
just a domestic thing right I do think
that Federal will come around I hope it
is sooner than later because just like
our education system we're falling
behind yeah like we're really falling
behind Luxembourg just legalized I don't
know if you saw this morning Luxembourg
Luxembourg legalized Malta people might
not hold relevance a few hundred
thousand populists island off the coast
of Italy but Malta legalize and and
they're starting out private before
current commercial which I have a level
of respect for like people are critical
of DC but I I give DC credit for that
like it should be hey I grow great weed
and you're a medical patient let me help
you versus bringing in the suit so it's
Roots over suits and so Malta took that
approach to your point Luxembourg now
he's really really rooting for check
yeah because they decriminalize the drug
back in the 70s but they are actually
waiting for Germany now which is
frustrating because the Czech Republic
is kind of waiting for Germany what
happens yeah because Germany is really
going to set the pace for everybody else
they are and ever since brexit you know
Germany highest GDP highest population
not huge 80 million they're not I mean
we're 43 45 whatever here in in this
state alone but ever since post-brexit
Germany really has in Germany did take
the torch they had a great prime
minister during covet and she really did
say hey like EU we can get through this
so I respect that Germany is like that
but Germany also overthinks things
they over regulate things in the over
engineer things right so that's a
concerns and cars with dogs and cars
that's great yeah we're overthinking
over engineering exactly you look at the
German automobiles you know they're
fantastic yep not saying anything I I
have a Chevy too so but they over
Engineers yeah I have German and Chevy
yeah I'm all you know so but uh
I definitely
think that Germany is setting the pace
and once Germany goes legal it's going
to be a lot easier for the other
countries to follow suit in Europe yes
so yeah it'll definitely happen and
everyone's poaching itching at the bit
as over in England I think I saw more
South Africans at one show than I ever
have because a lot of the South Africans
were actually you know they want to be
the ones who because it's a great
growing climate I mean so it's Portugal
so Spain totally but you you look at the
latitude
and in the South Africans have a lot of
potential and they're itching it the bit
to feed the European market and so is
Colombia and so Israel and so is Canada
and so yeah places like Germany I think
they have a cap of uh 20 000 pounds a
year which is nothing right look there's
companies in California that produce
that per month yeah or something like
that it's insane it's insane when you
look at it in in the amount of
consumption you know everyone can have
their opinion on percentage but um I I
venture to say a fifth of the populace
of most countries including over in
Europe are consumers yeah so the demand
is there and how they're demanding and
demand grows too so it grows
exponentially you know with legalization
there's people uh you know Colorado it
was big they were big into Edibles too
oh my gosh
they really kind of dude they're really
insane scene the edible scenes you go
into shops and they got every type of
edible you could possibly imagine stuff
that I never even thought of they'd have
there and be like whoa yeah
totally some of it yeah that's that's
another topic you're right I mean is
that for that you as Incredibles and
wanna and yeah and I mean even like one
of my favorites was sweet grass kitchen
because everyone was doing short path
you know they're doing CO2 or BHO and
Julie went against the grain and she
went cannabutter she did old school you
know so she wasn't doing the oils she
was doing the can of butter she ran
sueno she actually ran sueno and I was
so impressed because I'm like it's not
the easiest it's not the quickest but
man when it comes to if you want to
clean your house or if you want to lay
on the couch when Edibles would go
through different cultivars that lean
heavy towards you know the Indica
cerebral yeah get you very now and then
you can go on that equatorial kind of
where it like wakes you I tropical
equatorial varieties that lean that way
with Edibles especially if you do like a
full spectrum edible those things can
either kick your ass or do do whatever
they have all kinds of different effects
most people think edible edible yeah
yeah but really that you know but then
you have to do something like can of
butter or you know you start using
distillate you're not going to get those
experience no it's different that's and
that's it's again uh it's just like the
the race to legalization right sometimes
in most of the time the fastest isn't
always the easiest and so that's why
it's a pain in the butt for me to make
cannabutter versus one I've been lazy
I've done olive oil base but I love the
cannabutter because I know I'm gonna
capture as many of those terpenes not
just cannabinoids that I can right but
in in lipitate you know we love more so
when it comes to the two uptake is so
much better with butter and fatty than
it is with oil right because it's oil
and water versus fat right so you start
geeking out and going down these paths
and so fun and that's why it's a
constant education right water soluble
THC now where you can yeah remember
nanotechnology was a total buzzword but
they to your point 45 minutes to an hour
no more I have stuff that I consume it's
a 15 minute onset yeah and it goes away
pretty fast too yeah it does without the
headache because they're actually you
know producing it correctly so yeah yeah
that's a whole airspace love the Edibles
well yeah so let's do another podcast
one of these days and we'll talk about
the the bags and maybe do something for
the contest I think that'll be a lot of
fun maybe send all the people that put
in entries bags so they can return there
I would absolutely I'd love to do them
and like I said I'd love what you guys
are doing totally support it you know
these are definitely just I think one of
many opportunities but these are great
these are really really nice by the way
thanks man I love the skin too this is
it's got the Apple box skin you know did
the soft touch got the little Easter
eggs and the gusset too so that and this
is actually really quick we kind of went
with this sublimation down there but
um this is a seven gram so obviously if
you're pushing indoor you can probably
squeeze 10 you know if you're outdoor
and larfy you know five to seven yeah
but this has the turbo lock technology
we're gonna do a seed release with these
we'll do a special seed release you know
I think we're doing some distribution
stuff so it'd be kind of fun working
with some of these Distributors and
using this for seeds I think 100 I think
it'd be really cool and again upcycle it
man take out the seeds and use it this
is your stash bag so are you is so like
if I have one for Skittles I'll put
Skittles in there if I have one for GMO
I'll put GMO in there the next time so I
kind of try to keep it consistent
I really like storing everything in them
you know the infinity Dr is like these
they're all right too yeah you know
there's nothing wrong with the infinity
jars but I I definitely prefer as far as
for long-term storage the trip lock so
man thank you very much you got it for
sure thanks for having me yeah where can
people find you if they're looking for
terp lock or if they're looking for
Lance yeah great question so
growbags.com or obviously grow bag
handles across all social media for
myself I'm 805 Lance and so I'm pretty
active most people I'm really active on
LinkedIn pretty active on Instagram you
know always tell my story again you know
I'm Advocate not activist so I lead with
education not a closed fist but um yeah
definitely follow me engage with me I
love helping and mentoring people
there's a lot of people I brought into
the community you know like well I'm a
consumer I love growing but and I'm like
hey if if you're passionate that's all
it takes and you got a skill so yeah
feel free to reach out half of its
passion
I have that work ethic man this is not
for the week I mean if people think
they're just getting in for fun and
giggles and free weed yeah yeah that's
you want to be a rock star
exactly exactly true yeah so thanks yeah
man this is great yeah for sure awesome
thank you again
thank you
[Music]