foreign
[Music]
how's it going everybody my name is
James loud welcome to another episode of
the James uh podcast today we've got Ali
from Sunset connect how you doing today
good James how you doing good to be here
fantastic man it's uh it's great having
you here you know we actually have a lot
of mutual friends we you know they go
back into the 90s turns out we do huh
pretty crazy right yeah it's about it's
it's funny talking to people before the
show and then you you realize that [ __ ]
we had Direct connection with a lot of
people you know I think both being from
the area and then the connection to the
Rave scene you know which kind of
evolved into the Cannabis scene to a
degree I agree I mean a lot of those
players a lot of our old friends are now
you know big players yeah I mean even
when the first time I saw your logo it
reminded me of a rave flyer and then
also Panhandle records my friend Elijah
Mayhew from back in the day is like one
of my best friends growing up he had the
Panhandle with the muni style logo and I
love the it's it's just you see it you
recognize it it's ingrained it's like if
you're from the bay you know that logo
right Elijah was definitely an
inspiration by the way I always loved
his brand I love the ESD J Co brand that
was another totally another old school
brand that was around but yeah talking
to you one thing that I realized ever
more is that the big ogs have been
around for a minute and most of us
haven't done anything but cannabis right
yeah I think that's why we grow such
good weeds yeah we've all been smoking
forever you know like the one thing I
can say is that the weed back in the bay
in the 90s was [ __ ] amazing
absolutely it was really really really
good stuff it was incredible uh you know
people talk about how great the flower
is now and I mean I think the stuff that
we would get even the stuff on average
the indoor stuff was up to par with the
best stuff today I agree and it was it
was different right it was not as
homogeneous as today it wasn't all
gelato right and you got you meet a guy
and he gives you something that you've
never smelled or tasted before also
because I think the Breeders weren't
hanging out as much with each other
right so there was less
cross-pollination absolutely and people
were popping seeds and and getting
genetics you know there's a handful of
people popping seeds and you could get
clones from certain places but it's like
there was still stuff you know I mean
we're getting European stuff we were
getting stuff from South America there
was like a mix of all kinds of different
stuff Durbin was going around yeah a lot
of land races yeah that was the beauty
back then a lot of land races and a few
land race Cali wheat crosses for sure
Calio yeah you know Chris that was
another one that I really liked yeah
yeah I mean we had stuff that was going
in the 70s that you just don't see
anymore like the Calio for example right
like I think because it vegged so long
people weren't and at a certain point
everything became an eight-weeker yeah
that's when we lost everything
became an eight week yeah we got
scariest when it went to six weeks yeah
like the four minutes you know for a
minute yeah Lamb's bread was one of
those somebody tried to send sold us a
lamb's breath cut like six weeks the
thing was done you were scoping it and
you're like no way crazy so we did
produce that for a minute I still have a
cut of that so I should that's awesome
I'll give you one of them oh yeah
great I love Lamb's red orange Hill
those Jamaican varieties are super
special I agree and uh the other thing
in the in the bay is back in the day I
realized like you had Growers that
really really concentrated and
specialized in one thing like the GDP or
then you'd meet someone that was only
growing hazes but had the haze Market
sort of on lockdown or the OG guy and
that's all he grew was OG and he
probably got a pound per light with the
older yeah but nobody [ __ ] with him
nobody went and grew the same thing that
there was like this unwritten law of
this is my strain what I'm known for is
what you're known for right and we were
all kind of complimenting each other's
packs not trying to sell the whole box
for sure I think a lot of people got
into breeding that way because they
wanted something that was different than
everybody else wanted to do something of
their own I mean we love Sour Diesel and
so I wanted my own Sour Diesel because I
love all my friends grew sourdie so we
we love Saturday yeah the real Sour is
is super special yes it is so yeah or
you have a room hermed out and next
thing you know you got cookies you know
that could happen too good company some
of these guys you know they're like oh
yeah we got a million seeds what are we
gonna do with them
don't worry about checking them or yeah
you know and I mean early on I learned
my lesson selling stuff that was
untested once and then you know that it
was good I learned it early on you know
and now it's like even still I will sell
stuff that has intersex trades but I
want to make people aware if you go to
my website you look there's a couple of
the genetics that we saw on there they
have intersex trades but I think that's
special but I'm aware of it and I'm like
you know and if you're gonna buy it
you're also aware of it you know the
contest winner uh we'll see we're
announcing our contest winner on
Thursday we loud Loops we sent out 100
packs of seeds a little over 100 in
December we got 18 entries back I've
narrowed it down to ten we're gonna
smoke two of them today but I feel like
some of the people got intersex traits
and maybe part of it is by putting them
into flour too early also it's in the
genetics but I feel like the genetics
are so special when you smoke this stuff
you'll give me your opinion I'm sure but
uh man it's sometimes it's it's worth it
and other times it's not I agree I think
as long as it's disclosed right so we've
been we've been growing the gummies for
about two years now has a lot of
intersex trades yeah it's not very
stable but when it is to your point it's
unbelievable yeah I mean exotic genetics
I feel like Mike has made a whole
company based on stuff that may or may
not have intersex trades but it's all
phenomenal and I love exotic by the way
we definitely are always down to pop and
try totally a point because when you do
find something it's usually just fire
well yeah and one thing I can say about
exotic that I appreciate is something
that he does is he'll take something and
he'll work it into something better so
his red pop I wasn't a huge fan of the
red pop because it has this purple punch
kind of like let down when I was growing
it I was growing it and I was doing some
crosses with it and I'm like smelling
I'm like oh [ __ ] this is like Cherry
Cola this is really really good this is
a special one right and then we at the
end I had one of my friends flower some
out and I went to smoke it and I'm like
oh it's purple punch yeah but then
purple punch but it was one cross away
from being special he crossed it with
the runts and had that that was what the
red runs was and then the red ones runs
was amazing like really really really is
that what red ones was red runts is that
red pop times runs and it's I think it's
great I mess with your orange Blow Pop
loved it totally smelled like orange
crush I grew it and I called all my
girls and like this [ __ ] smells like
orange crush like actual oranges oh yeah
that's a sweet sugary you know Exotics
is yeah his stuff is sugary a lot of it
checks the boxes well we have a
different taste in the bay though yeah
very very particular taste than the veg
we keep going back to Skittles which
that's okay yeah I like Skittles have
you ever tried the Polly Shore the
Polynesian so I I'll give you a cut of
that it's a it's one of those super old
school 90s strains we were talking about
wow probably takes about eight to nine
weeks at least
yeah totally but when you smoke it just
the smoke alone is so thick yeah like
wow okay this is a really special smoke
has like notes of cinnamon earthy and
then some weird funk I always call it
the dog [ __ ] terpene because I can't
really put a better name yeah we always
had cat piss back in the day the smoke I
mean that stuff was I cat pissed in the
90s was amazing that was another one
that only few people grew and there was
a catfish
you got your cat piss from him and only
him you know it's like mine was a guy
named Gus and my buddy Steve but they
they all got it from the same exact guy
and uh it was 60 a straight up we'd buy
ounces for 480 dollars the good old time
good old times yeah and it looked like
[ __ ] in the bag that's the other thing
the cat piss that we got was not chunky
fat buds it was like shredded calyx
sometimes but you opened the bag and
you're like God damn you didn't know it
happened you didn't open the bag you
knew that you know I was like it would
be in your pocket or it would be in a
backpack or be in 10 bags yeah the money
on that was strong so strong though yeah
it wasn't like so my experience with
catfish it wasn't gassy like a lot of
people try to say gassy it was Styles
but it was skunk files like real like
when you talk about roadkill skunk
that's the closest to roadkill skunk
that there is I always thought it had
more of a pungent sort of blue cheese
kind of it was it was so pungent in
their nostrils yeah exactly yeah I mean
I think a lot of people didn't even like
the smell of it they were like no they
didn't yeah absolutely I mean like I
have friends like oh this is gross and
then they would immediately packable
yeah well I remember when the European
genetics really started coming into uh
the bay in the 90s we started getting
through the third floor through some of
the what was the one in Oakland there
was the it was the blue something the
Blue Sky Cafe Blue Sky Cafe and the
Clones in the back yeah you get the
clown from the guy Cafe great clones I
think that's where we got the blue dream
clone from the guy was like uh our
Buddy's dad went to buy clones and the
guy's like give me something that that
not everybody grows and he's like I got
this really sad looking plant here and
it was blue dream and our buddies dad
took it to his house a little finicky
and veg but then it just [ __ ] got
crushed Blue Dream yeah that's how we
were we were some of the people that
hoard out blue dreams as far as Blue
Dream is the apical of structure yield
all those things Blue Dream is it checks
the boxes maybe it doesn't check the
boxes on the terpene profile or the
effect but when it came out it did
everybody wanted to do a dream it was
going for 30. I mean I think people
still like it they just don't want to
admit they like it sure sure but yeah
and you know it's a milder effect so
it's definitely a lighter sativa I feel
like that was the one if we're going on
a hike or if we're going bowling or
whatever we were doing back in the day
that would be like okay let's smoke some
blue that was my road trip we'd if I
have to drive for eight hours I don't
want to get too tired
you're good to go you're smiling the
whole time yeah we had that and green
crack and do the Green Crack was they
they'd grow because the flowering time
was very similar on those so you could
grow them together in the same room
because I liked harvesting all my stuff
I didn't want to have to harvest they
wait two more weeks or three more weeks
have happened to them two rooms oh yeah
yeah seriously wasting your electricity
so I grew them together and the Green
Crack was good for like the first couple
weeks because you get super ripped but
then your tolerance would go so high it
wouldn't even get you high yeah you'd
smoke big old bats of it and then the
next thing you know [ __ ] it's not
getting you high I feel that way about a
lot of the current strains yeah and I
think also the reason people mix up
strain so much is because they all have
a ceiling right you get pretty immune
when most people don't notice it because
they switch so much right but yeah I
think most most of the genetics do have
ceilings but when you when you test it
when you test for yourself dude to judge
if you like the flower my usual rule is
I'll only smoke an ounce of this no
other weed for the next two days and of
course if I like it then I really like
it if I can smoke an ounce in two days
and not want to smoke anything else then
that's a good strain to me yeah it's
it's hard to find yeah those kind of
genetics especially even just the
genetic side but then also the
cultivation and the guys growing I mean
there's a lot of flour out there there's
not a lot of amazing flour out there
it's easy to go read it's hard to grow
good weed right that's kind of what it
is but I think the auto problem is the
automation the fertigation everything
everybody is buying the same [ __ ] from
the same people now so you really it
kind of loses that Personal Touch right
um as well as just back in the day if we
had houses that were closer to the beach
in the sunset that would guaranteed be
done three four days earlier and have a
completely different different
expression than the ones that were up on
the hill say Mom same Cuts absolutely so
that's the that's you know that's kind
of one thing I miss is just the it's
sort of like wine when you're in Napa
when when you have multiple wineries
grow in the same grapes or even similar
clones but just their locations
right yeah yeah I remember especially
with outdoor weed
I mean there was a point where outdoor
was more expensive than indoor I
remember those days I remember the sour
diesel days that were but it was like
you get sour diesel from specific people
and it would come out even though it was
the same cut it would come out two
different ways from two different people
right and the buyer's like that's not
the same yeah it's not even the same
yeah yeah we had a lot of that because I
think that's when the whole name game
started was you know all the way back
then but yeah so let's dive into some of
these
um
is a proper doing snow pun intended
oh
so these ones
I have identified as soil grown
I believe they're soil ground based on
the effect the Cure
and the guys who entered this contest
um
narrowing it down to the top ten these
guys all grew amazing flower you know
some you could tell we're like more of
the cocoa Grill I don't think we got any
rock wool although
we'll find out when I start asking more
questions
do the contestants disclose it oh you
know but I'll I'll ask
it's not a it's not a Fair competition
where you give everybody the same clone
someone's gonna win the lottery and get
better genetics that that person may or
may not be the best cultivator we'll see
this is kind of a unique test
so what is this smoking right here so
this is loud Loops so it's uh zerios
times zbx and zeros is a zerbert times
cereal milk and then zbx is uh the
Skittles back cross with the gelato 41.
okay so there's a good amount of
difference here yeah yeah yeah there's
for sure I there's a little candy chirp
but I think so I've been smoking these
for a week and a half now and what I'm
finding is like a lot of the cereal milk
expression is dominant and then you're
finding a little Skittles here
sherberty and cereal milk and sherbet
kind of have similar like that musky
profile a little bit that I feel like
cereal milk is a little is a little
heavier and shorter it's a little
brighter yeah like has a little bit more
citrus or yeah and so you're getting a
lot of that and then the unicorns are
more of the Z ones and I feel like
It's associated with the structure too
like the ones that don't have quite as
much structure like as nice of a
structure those ones are going to have
more Skittles Terps sure so it just goes
hand in hand sharp has a lot of
structure I remember she does have a lot
of I remember it I was in the sunset and
somebody one of my buddies said take now
Mario might have had a landlord
inspection or something but this guy was
holding some Mom's room yeah and I went
over there and I looked at it and I'd
never seen a Sherwood cup before it's
like 2004 five oh wow oh no 2012 sorry
2012. yeah that sounds more like it 12.
yeah
um and I go into this guy's house and
it's gray it's purple it's orange it's
just got this bud structure that's
bubbly but still little fox Taylor I
mean it was literally what we consider
designer weed today right and I looked
I'm like dude what the [ __ ] is this yeah
it's just called Sunset shirt remember
it was called Sunset Sherbert in the
very beginning and then it turned into
sharbinsky and into Sherbert and I think
Mario is phenomenal by the way he's
always been super kind to me he's a
character
yeah I used to get packs off them back
in the day and I ended up getting uh
this guy Travis some of the packs a
whole Seed Company there was one seed
and that one seed built his seed company
over in Europe I mean at the beginning
of it all it takes you know that's all
it takes was that one to get him on the
map I mean he did a lot of stuff beyond
that but that was like that one seed was
a game changer you know I love that
though those are the best stories some
backseat that turns you into into a name
in the Cannabis industry good for you
seriously especially when the genetics
weren't super prevalent over there
I think we I remember when we were in
college and I would go home to visit I
grew up two hours outside of Amsterdam I
would drive to Amsterdam and get as much
like Euro weed as I could and literally
fly it back with me in like the 90s yeah
through SFO because back then there was
more flavors in in Holland than we had
here right it was like the exact
opposite of today where the now that's
on a completely flip we have totally
thousands of flavors and they're still
grown Amnesia Haze so they've renamed
Amnesia Haze Tech different things two
million times probably by now
um we also sold a lot of blackjack back
in the Legacy yeah I like that was
another one of our kind of signature I
haven't seen that since the 90s yeah for
sure but in on ease in 2017 I think our
Blackjack was the number one selling
flower really yeah well that's amazing
black domino
our Blackjack was black dominant and uh
and Jack yeah just the expression was so
was it it was dark too yeah yeah it was
they had some color it was like a
grayish purple foreign
really nice grayish purple Hue and it
was really uppity most people call it
their workout weed in the city nice yeah
yeah it's you know I think red Congolese
is kind of made a comeback over the last
like four years on and off I've you know
there's a couple of people growing it
and it had hoplite and veroid that was
another The Hop late and beer has [ __ ]
up a lot of genetics so many in
California right now we went back to
popping hella seeds right now yeah
because but even with seeds it's
transmissible we have old seeds yeah
nice there you go we have Knights
heirloom seeds that we've been that
we've been hoarding and collecting which
probably give you some of those better
yeah
I mean there's yeah I mean I love the
genetics and story as long as you store
them they're good for a long time if you
store them correctly right if you just
put them in your drawer yeah good luck
yeah good luck if you live in anywhere
past Oakland you're probably going to be
in trouble you live in Sacramento you're
[ __ ] oh it gets too high unless you
have air conditioning so and even even
then when with that fluctuation in
temperature your seeds know the humidity
you recommend for storing seeds so
humidity low low I put desiccants in my
the drier you store them the better we
use lab fridges that has zero humidity
in there you know but like they're
they're in glass jars and the I mean
I've seen charts and it's like the
longer you plan on storing them the
lower you want that humidity right does
that make sense sure but I mean your
facility is unreal dude this is really
really impressive yeah awesome thank you
very much appreciate it yeah we put some
work into this and I think this is just
accumulation of my partner and I and all
the stuff we've learned along the way to
actually put it into a facility you know
of this scale doing what we're doing
kind of trying to change the game not
just doing what everybody else is doing
you know it's like research and
development we're more of a biotech
company than we are a nursery or a
breeding facility or anything yeah
that's definitely the impression that
yeah when you walk in right but we're
not trying to be anything but ourselves
right we're just trying to do the best
we can and trying to push the bar the
best way we know how
so yeah it's a lot of fun though it's
you know and then coming into this place
every day is not the worst way to go
well that's what I say every day when I
walk into my manufacturing spot I'm like
if I told my 16 year old self that I
have a hash Factory one day totally I'm
growing my own weed and it's all legal
it's [ __ ] no way this is the dream
come true to an extent but it's also a
nightmare with the way that some things
in our industry are right which is like
was like the main reason that I decided
to really be active and try to be the
chairman of the San Francisco oversight
committee and of the state Advisory
Board because I thought people like you
and me that have actually seen this [ __ ]
for 25 [ __ ] years we're not getting a
seat at the table we weren't there's a
bunch of lobbyists and outdoor
cultivation groups which I don't think
they shouldn't have a seat at the table
but they weren't going after the old guy
selling you know hundreds of pounds over
you know in the 90s already so
um I do think California is really
unique and then letting somebody like me
sit at that table and listening to us
but I also realize right now in the
industry the way it's going a lot of
corporates going out of business with
[ __ ] that's happening with herbal right
you see the med man debt the harbor side
that's like oh yeah maybe you should
listen to us more we had an existing
industry we had an existing craft beer
industry that was crushing it you could
have had a thousand anchors teams and
you went for five Budweisers and now
you're surprised at this [ __ ] yeah
you're surprisingly results and it's
like yeah you know I think we talked to
I've talked a little bit about Anchor
Steam with some of the guests but they
kind of we're here in part because of
anchor Steve yeah San Francisco you know
Fred Maytag right so Fred Maytag who
wanted to start his own microbrewery in
the 70s so uh John from Cutting Edge
Uncle John was telling me the story yeah
in the 70s he wanted us then they said
no you need to join one of the big four
and he was like no that's not happening
I'm not gonna do it so he got dirt on
all the politicians he had pis following
the politicians around and it was like
one of the fastest Bills ever changed uh
he's still allowed him yeah and so it's
that kind of change that got us to where
we are today I feel like and it's great
being part of the whole thing in San
Francisco it's funny to say and Christy
when people come to our facility I
always go we kind of consider ourselves
the anchors team yeah of of cannabis we
can do Craft on a pretty industrial
scale totally that's just because we
love what we're doing it's like over all
these years you figure it out right I
mean like I see what you do here it
looks more impressive than most biotech
companies and people don't realize that
yeah if you want clean good genetics
they have to come out of a place like
this they have to yeah there's no
exception and I think we're going into
the direction that everybody's gonna
have to go into it's not like we're
doing something that's going to be you
know once Federal legalization goes in
and there's changes and we have the FDA
uh you know and these organizations
coming in they're going to change it and
make it really hard for a lot of people
so we're I mean we're gearing up for
that that's what I said when we built
our facility I got to build it on a
level that it'll pass a pharmaceutical
grade not because I want to people think
it's like ego and you're doing it for
like Aesthetics it's like no dude this
was built so there's no microbiological
you know hazards here so there's that's
why you do it but yeah I think yeah it's
impressive what you've built and thank
you cool to be here man thanks for
having me so let's talk a little bit
about your company and how you guys got
your start
um yeah we started growing weed in
college my my partners and I met first
day of freshman year at USF a bunch of
18 year olds that couldn't pay for weed
so we started growing they started
growing I was moving a lot of it
um and then
I think that's kind of how we know a few
of our common friends in the Rave scene
started moving packs when I was about 20
um the my crew got popped by the feds
most of us got popped nobody said
anything everybody walked
um I was on probation for a few years my
buddies were still growing because
thankfully they didn't they didn't get
popped um probation for a few years
finished probation super traumatized
didn't want anything to do with weed
right uh moved back to Germany for like
five six years and that's when medical
really took off here and I mean I was
back three times a year hanging out with
my boy so it wasn't like I wasn't coming
home but yeah
um yeah so I was like
2010 my buddies came to Germany said
dude pack up your [ __ ] like you're not
gonna get busted again like this [ __ ] is
legal now right we Supply dispensaries
come back and let's do this again let's
go back to our old Heights so awesome
sort of what we did and um then when
2016 came around we saw the writing on
the wall so decided to really Lobby
first eat at the table to be heard
because we didn't have a warehouse like
we were growing in 30 houses in the
sunset we didn't totally we have a
warehouse we weren't zoned yeah and you
know at that point to your point you
already had a company like gold seal
that was growing red Congo and that had
a warehouse there was a Betty project oh
yeah SF cultivators you had a couple of
outfits that were definitely in the bay
if you could probably transition but we
know that wasn't us because we were
growing in houses and we were producing
our Edibles and hash and stuff in the
back of the plant Cafe Kitchen in the
commissary amazing
um which is actually where I where SF
office of cannabis first tour was we're
like yeah go to the front ask the
cashier or walk you into the back to the
commissary where we're making hash
hilarious it was totally Breaking Bad it
was pretty funny
um yeah so then we had to transition and
I transitioned manufacturing first was
the first manufacturer to open in the
city pulled three out of the first 10
permits hold the first building permit
in San Francisco nice
um and not with like a big crew of
lawyers and [ __ ] dude just my you know
my buddy part of my company is one of
the better attorneys in the space our
Growers are really smart scientific guys
you know we looked at building codes we
figured it out hired an architect and
you know figured it out
um and now Sunset connect is the number
one selling single gram pre-roll in the
state we beat jeters out of that spot
which I'm really proud of for like a
little SF dude and uh and we kind of
have to restructure now because you know
herbo went broke and they're really good
partner of ours and we now have to find
a new distributor but that's how this
game goes you gotta be flexible gotta be
nimble
yeah it's all about being able to Pivot
yeah and having it every day seven times
I mean if there's one thing I learned
from my partner it's always have a plan
B yeah what's our plan B like if this
doesn't work what's you know we're
thinking ahead yeah I always have to
kind of be and then a contingency if
that doesn't come through and that can't
just be another plan C that's you know
unrealistic that's when you go okay if
that happens we contract we expand again
or we kill a few skus so I did that that
was actually one of the things that made
us most successful was setting aside
what I know my small microcosm wanted
and saying okay what is it what's the
data here and the data was the single
Graham joint so you know we started with
one skew
used to sell like 10 000 a month and now
we're at seven of the same kind and saw
like a hundred thousand of them a month
right so but we cut out flowers for them
being for the time being topicals
Edibles we cut out a lot of rationalize
our skews nice so doubling down on what
you're good at yeah getting rid of the
stuff that is questionable Focus right
focused yeah it's all about Focus yeah
that's it so what do we got here
but that's one of the flavors so we have
two sativas two indicas and two hybrids
at any given point this is your morning
commute so it's based on the muni ticket
right that sort of our whole thing so
this is your morning commute and this is
a sunset popsicle which
um is it is actually blow popped
um blow pop sugar trim and sunset sugar
and this is a trim joint that goes out
the door at a dispensary for five bucks
because we were like we felt like dude
that's amazing you they offer nothing to
somebody on a budget that still needs to
smoke a lot and like it still tastes
good probably I'm assuming I don't dry
hit it and it tastes and they're fresh I
mean you know it is a sugar trim joint
like we don't we don't make any we you
know we don't hide that fact but test
that 25 it's fresh I don't think you'll
ever get one that's older than like two
or three weeks in the store uh that's
part of the game too that's one of the
most important parts that I think a lot
of people are dropping the ball on is
realizing that this is a product that
needs to be fresh yeah I don't want the
whole dry shell I don't want three month
old weed like necessarily if it's been
sitting on the shelf maybe if you
harvested it and you stored it correctly
and then you put it out and I get the
week after yeah you know it's like
there's good there's ways you can do
stuff now for sure but I think a lot of
people are dropping the ball on how they
not only how they try and cure it but
how long it sits on the Shelf processing
yeah I mean it's post-processing we're
really particular like
um from batch sizing you have a lot of
you have a lot of influence on your
product if you do it in small batches
you can make 10 small batches but we
grind in like 100 gram batches most big
pre-roll makers grinding five pounds and
it's dust so I got a good solution for
all this this is the best solution
actually it's again I'm taking it from
Lagunitas because that's what they did
uh when they started shipping beer
across the country they had it
refrigerated in refrigerated trucks
going they were the first ones that did
that all the big beer companies right
yeah and they got anchors not Anchor
Steam they got Heineken from over in
Amsterdam to start shipping their beer
in the water to the United States so
it's not skunky like it used to be oh
really
yeah yeah a million dollars for half a
half a billion and then a full billion
and uh but what we could do with the
flour is we could all have it stored at
60 degrees transfer it at 60 degrees and
then the dispensary has it at 60 degrees
so when you get it you're getting the
humidity well yeah for sure 60 Minutes
60 degrees coming in so you're never
getting it out of that environment
you're going to get a better product for
a lot longer people are going to be a
lot more satisfied yeah that's kind of
what I see the consumer thinks that like
if there's no consistency right because
one just and I see it in the numbers one
dispensary moves you know 130 of these a
day and another one does 70.
um so you can you can adjust that by
case sizes so we have 125 and a 250 case
fast movers get the big case medium
movers get the you know the medium the
small case because they move through it
fresh but right you go to dispensaries
and they have four or five month old
Jeff flower jars I mean I don't want
that I don't want that either or a year
old I've seen year old products well not
a year is the cutoff you have to return
it to the vendor that's pushing it 11
months 10 months nine months I mean with
with hash sure I like age cash I
personally age Ash per year yeah and
then I bust it open but um yeah I agree
I think with flower pre-rolls edible
shouldn't be around for a year probably
probably not yeah you know I think well
yeah definitely Edibles have those shelf
lives for them based on food yeah food
but they but they also degrade though I
mean I like my bread fresh too I'm not
going to eat steel bread or anything
like that but yeah that [ __ ] gave me
such cottonmouth
same thing it's like yeah I do have to
do a refire I think it could cure a
little longer still uh-huh this one but
in terms of effect high
great really Pleasant got me proper
ripped and I didn't even finish it yet
yeah
you can taste it on the relay yeah nice
that's nice it's a great song yeah well
a lot of these are you know soil grown
living soil grown these entries and it's
you know I like the skittley though okay
the ones that are that what's that added
layer of flavor that makes it special
it's like a skittles is such a good
flavor enhancer it's kind of like what
what forbidden fruit was but dude it
just forbidden food just [ __ ]
everything up for some reason oh dude
purple punch the thing is with purple
punches purple punch looks amazing on
the plant it's like I think most of the
funeral is a wedding cake are like this
too they look amazing on the planet they
yield really well they look like super
Instagram beautiful and then you go to
smoke them and it's like wait a second
such a letter wait a second where's
where's the Terps and you know I mean
there's so Oreos is like that apple
fritter in my opinion the thing with
apple fritter is I like the effect of
apple fritter but I don't like the fact
that it smells like an apple fritter and
then you go to smoke it and you don't
taste anything of it yeah and I mean
I've said it before but all these things
that aren't that great like Oreos and
purple punch I think they're all one
good cross yeah like the example of the
red pop you know which is actually
purple punched or whatever like whatever
he used but purple Punchy his strawberry
must have purple punch in there some on
some line going from there to the red
pop it's like it just takes work and
effort but all three ones that you named
are impossible to sell they're all three
of them nobody wants nobody wants Andre
like and that's like and then even
buyers that are looking for completely
different things they'll tell you they
don't want Oreos that's for sure yeah no
matter who they are we have uh it's not
Oreos it's zorios
the rename games well the rename game I
got escalated with now the shape bags I
feel like the rename game is now the
shaved bag and rename game the bigger
and the more die cut your shaped bag
I just can't get into that that's kind
of also why we cater I always say we
cater to like the heavy smoker that has
to watch their pocket and just wants a d
decent smokes though yeah that's like
the people that I make stuff for because
I was always kind of selling to Blue
Collar dudes in the city so that's just
that's my you know that's my people yeah
nice
yeah the city is interesting how diverse
it is so we have and that even the
dispensaries back in the day were super
diverse the from Ocean Street all the
way to to the one like spark yeah
in between their Tariq with his Bossa
like you know yeah yeah all these
completely different Vibes
in cannabis remember that one that's
true it was awesome yeah there's some
good ones yeah well you know this is
just it like we said it's pretty amazing
to be have been part of the old
iteration and of the new one and I
always say this is a global experiment
and California is the only place in This
Global experiment that actually matters
in terms of scale yeah and we you know
they are looking at us like everybody's
yeah everybody's watching for sure yeah
so there's only two people in life that
you need to impress it's your 18 year
old self and your 80 year old self right
you're doing okay I hope so yeah we'll
see we'll see whenever you're not quite
a path to go yeah the 18 year old self
for sure yeah he's pretty happy right
now I can yeah I done all right by him
right yeah so where can people find you
if they're looking uh I think we're in
in almost every dispensary in San
Francisco so we're pretty easy to find
around there you can find us at PCF in
Sacramento you can find us at all of the
one plants around the bay and yeah just
follow us on Instagram at Sunset connect
and uh we can always send you the right
way Excellent Man well it's really good
having you on the show yeah thanks for
having me man yeah all right you have to
come back and do it again we'll do uh
we're doing Blind tastings next time I
should bring our breeder San Francisco
he's my partner that'd be fantastic I
try to bring him here today he said he
was slam but you would love to come by
he's we're all big fans of you yeah and
we're constantly going through different
phenos so if you guys want to go check
some stuff awesome thanks for having me
yeah thank you very much
thank you
[Music]
foreign
you guys are missing all the good
content
yeah no we don't want to talk about this
[ __ ] on camera I don't know
no [ __ ] never seen this guy before
yeah yeah