hundreds of did I knock it
out cut cut I almost started a
fire how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James loud
podcast today my guest is Brian from
vital how you doing today I'm doing
great thank you for having me James dud
thank you for coming on I really
appreciate it we've known each other for
a while you you dropped soil off of my
house before
yes sir yes sir appreciate the um the
business and and the trust and
confidence in using my product some on
your level dude you have a great product
you have a really really good product
you guys stand behind your product you
know I love your soil product it's it's
amazing and your nutrients you've always
given me awesome stuff so appreciate
that 17 years deep now wow believe that
pretty amazing yeah so how did you guys
start you want you want to go back and
give us a little history lesson on maybe
even before before that how how did you
start with uh within the industry sure
I'll give you the quick rundown um
industry-wise I mean cannabis you know
found me at a pretty young age and uh
nice I always felt you know drawn to it
you know young young age and then I
realized that it was also like a way to
really you know link with other people
and it was like a good common ground for
to meet people that may not be from your
exact same demographic and just be able
to like open up your like friends circle
on like a huge scale you know yes it's
like the one thing that unites us all
kind of like food does for people I feel
like is very similar you know like you
can have all these different backgrounds
of people that they would normally be
friends but because the plant we're all
connected in that way for sure and I
noticed that even at a young age like in
high school cuz you know all schools are
similar you know my I'm grew up middle
class Pennsylvania West Virginia uh East
Coast you know not much good weed ever
and uh you know but a lot of people
smoked weed yeah and it was it was
Mexican and it was pretty much it if it
was weed it's weed it wasn't like this
weed or that weed or it was just weed
right and uh you know it helped it
definitely helped connect with different
neighborhoods and different types of
people from the football players to the
burnouts to the smart kids to the jocks
to everybody you know so you were
smoking the ' 80s yeah oh yeah for sure
nice 82 83 really was that's awesome
yeah for sure yeah I was like 10 years
after that so it was it was I feel like
it was a little bit of a different scene
after you know in the 90s compared to
the 80s from what I've heard yeah I'm
sure I think the I think the 9s was more
of the like BC weed as far as like
commercial and maybe they were starting
to get some California and some
homegrown weed I think a lot of the
California hom I'm I'm from California
too so never saw that Mexican brick weed
no no I saw Mexican brick weed oh you
did okay sure well good I'm we used to
yeah we used to get pounds of it for you
know it was like $400 a pound or
something like that for sure and uh it
would get you really high and it would
sometimes you'd have like a joint and it
would pop seeds out of the joint you
know you forget to take them all out or
whatever and it was lot of the stuff was
seated but some of it was green some of
it wasn't Brown it was all pressed right
you have to like break it apart and yeah
yeah I didn't start to see the better
Mexican weed until I was like more like
in college and then I finally started
seeing like I'd say by like 888
889 yeah on the East Coast I mean I'd
occasionally see like go on go to a dead
show and like a different area and be
able to get a bag of weed that was like
amazing and and try to just hold on to
that as long as I could right because
that was like the only access to like
really high-grade weed you know I swear
every guest is interconnected with the
Grateful Dead not but not by you know
selection it's just oh I think Grateful
Dead cannabis very very highly tied
together for sure especially you know us
older Statesman you know around and like
let's face it like chem dog you know
that happened because of a Grateful Dead
concert you know and like so many
different you know Growers would like
take their craft weed and go hustle that
on on the dead lot yeah and that was
kind of like the open market then and
sure before that you know like I didn't
know of even good weed so like it opened
my eyes to you know see what the
possibilities were and then it just you
know what kind of genetics do you
remember any of the strain names not
that strain names are like any I
remember smoking real blueberry Bud like
like in like 87 88 but more of like a
sativa right like yeah it was definitely
sativa for sure so my first experience
with any sort of blueberry was a sativa
plant and there was one of the first
things I grew at my house when I got
eight lights in with my buddy and he got
these clones and and they were from
Oregon and it doubled in flower and they
were growing up into the lights and it
was like I didn't really know what I was
doing but we were yeah we were figuring
it out for sure so well I remember
buying bags of weed of this blueberry
and then always like been on the lookout
for it and like occasionally I would I
think once or twice really only is all
that I ever got it and I think that was
the only time I really saw the true DJ
Short Blueberry yeah and then I just
recently got got his oh yeah so DJ is a
short is a very short plan and it's it's
blueberry but the one from Oregon you
don't think it's going to be the one
that I I've been having my memory I
don't think so I don't honest don't
think it might be maybe I'm wrong but
the one I remember is very different
than DJ shorts because I was so excited
to gr DJ shorts and I grew it and I was
like got a completely different plant
and not that it was bad it was just so
different that it was a let down for me
because I was expecting this SAA plant
that doubles in
flow these crazy Frosty nugs and it
didn't have the same profile it was
blueberry but like the one from Oregon
was like this crazy not fely blueberry
but it was like really complex and down
to the roach you could roll joints of it
and you would want to yeah smoke it down
you could pick the roaches up the next
day this this was that and it was from
Oregon yeah but as far as the plant I
got it from somebody who says this is
the DJ Short Blueberry and I don't know
good no DJ Short Blueberry is great too
if you had the experience but the leaves
are super serrated yeah almost to the
point where they like fall the serration
yeah stay is goes inconsistent because
it's like such a a severe serration it
almost just Blends together almost wow
and then there's also even some
variegation in it V well that's cool
yeah so I'm curious to see how it's
going to come out I'm just try it for
sure yeah I I'll let you know for sure
so yeah so let's go into vital how do
you start vital vital um you know I was
I was a grower and I was like always
like lean to the organic Side of
Everything you know grew a lot of my own
vegetables and wanted to like have a
clean organic product and one day I
thought I was using an organic product
and I read the label and and I realized
that there were some ingredients in
there that probably weren't weren't
organic and uh so long story short I
started like just looking more and more
at labels and like realizing that
there's a lot of crappy products out
there that have this visual appeal that
that may like tend to think that the
grower who's looking at it would think
that it was organic right whether it's
like the name or or however they like
you know TST something in your head yeah
exactly so it kind of started to bother
me and I was like you know what I think
you know this is what I need this is
something I need to do and um around the
same time you brought up earlier Israel
yeah um he's a good old friend of mine
and he um was living up in Oregon and
they were they were kind of having
similar issues and you know like we were
all kind of like comparing notes and and
those guys started company up up in um
Oregon at the same time relatively I
also had a um Landscaping um license so
I basically built my store in my U
manufacturing company off of originally
just getting that landscaping license uh
state contractor's license yeah so and
and my company was called vital
Landscaping nice um so anyway long story
short those guys up there you know there
was a couple of them they had a little
bit more Capital put together so they
were a little bit putting some products
out right and uh so we distributed their
products and then I would make products
that would be kind of like um a
companion to some of their products so
like wow their first products was they
had a potting soil and then they had a
grow in a bloom and then my first
product was a um it was a cumic acid and
which is Baseline and still one of our
leading selling products right a liquid
a liquid and a dry version yeah and then
the next product was fish cuz like we
were big on the whole compost tea thing
right so you know getting compost and
worm castings and putting them into
water and adding a few things and mixing
some oxygen into there and and trying to
see what we what came of it was like how
it started and then we kind of learned
about Elaine inham and so on and so
forth so basically 2006 um actually
officially open doors of vital Garden
Supply yeah and um started Distributing
a couple of those products from Oregon
the Vital Earth Brand and so he was
Vital Earth and you were vital Garden
yeah and and they were like they called
me one day and they're like I got a
great idea cuz I was already vital
landscaping and I and I was opening the
store as vital Garden Supply and they're
like we'll be Vital Earth and you'll be
our distributor and I'm like and we were
like I was like sounds good you know
looking back on it you know it
definitely created a little confusion on
the other hand we were all family and
and friends and didn't we we represented
them as it was was our own and like we
were the California you know hub for
them cuz being in Oregon and shipping
and all that it didn't make sense and
you know they were caught up in in
Oregon building their companies and
lives and you know all that too so is
has gone on to do all kinds of stuff
he's down in Columbia right now with
Vital Earth down there and you know
phonics they did you know he's done
genetics we talk very often we're still
very close I've actually been down to
Columbia with him nice um I had a
project in Colombia that didn't all way
pan out but um we went down there
together and we're checking it out in
the early days probably like 5 years ago
almost six when when it was just
starting down there I think it's finally
now starting to click in there that's
actually when I met him was about five
years ago in Colombia at a restaurant
start talking yeah wow he we have mutual
friends and we all went to dinner and it
was like okay yeah really good guy yeah
super good guy for sure he's him him and
his wife are like super close friends
with me and my wife and nice yeah we
we're close they're super cool yeah
definitely we're hoping to retire and
grow old together somewhere together
yeah colia is not a bad way to go you
know I feel like yeah tropical Columbia
is tropical too Columbia is tropical
that's where he definitely wants to have
a place there yeah I'm not sure all way
committed to like being the third world
all the way but I can definitely spend
some time there yeah I'm the same way I
like visiting I think it's a beautiful
country I mean the cost of living down
there is nothing no doubt so cheap no
doubt food is so cheap yeah so fresh and
good
Uber was $2 the most anywhere when I was
in Bogota yeah you go anywhere in the
city and the city is 10 San Francisco
yeah something crazy like that so huge
and I was just blown away because I
would take Uber but then you have to sit
in the front seat because Uber is
illegal so thex driver yeah you have to
make it look like you're friends with
the Uber driver so otherwise you might
get left on the side of the road and the
guy might get arrested so yeah good
experiences we're actually working on
with a group down there um who's got a
American partner up here that to get all
of our products registered cuz they're a
certified organic uh facility already
and they're struggling getting products
so um we're working hand inand with them
in the eeka which is uh Columbia
Department of a um to get all the vital
products registered down there so that's
awesome hopefully within the next six
months or so they'll be available too
wow so that'll be cool open our Horizons
a little more yeah it's a really cool
place and I think they're really
interested in cannabis agriculture all
of it yeah Organics I think there's a
lot of people that are pushing the
Organics down there for sure it seems
like that people are super conscious of
you know what they use and what they put
on the planet and they're you know
they're they care about their land and
right so yeah I love that yeah totally
yeah it's interesting all these uh
different places we expanding all over
the globe totally I mean look at
Portugal right now Portugal's going full
bore for it you know I have a friend who
just left yesterday to go work over
there um but they they got 40 acres 40
acres uh full term wow which I saw the
videos I was like that's really cool you
know you know you hear about stuff and
that's THC yeah 40 acres it's quite a
few yeah I mean not compared to the
United States really but but still I
mean 40 acres I mean I guess it is for
one plot 40 acres is pretty big it looks
pretty amazing too yeah awesome so yeah
love to visit that someday yeah I can I
arrange that anytime for sure awesome
but yeah and I mean it's all over the
globe so it's not just there I mean
we're talking about South Africa we're
talking about you know Thailand
Thailand push yeah yeah I just read the
is the prime minister he he's not for
cannabis read that same article yeah I
was like wow it seems like it's doing
good for their economy a little late a
little late to make that call right
totally yeah it's an interesting time on
the planet for sure between what's
already happening in the economy and
just like between technology and all the
just craziness and then cannabis being
okay in this community but not this one
and this one's good that one's not like
even in our own country yeah you know
it's just it's a strange thing well
we're in strange times yeah for sure and
and for it to be like something that you
know the that's going to be legal for
the whole country yeah is I'd like to
see it happen sure and and like see
California you know cannabis companies
be able to thrive a little bit better
and open their doors to like National
but I it just seems like such a long far
off thing to me because no one's roles
are even close to the same in the same
state let alone the same country look at
how crazy testing is all over the place
just within one state you know yeah as
far as I me we're so off base with a lot
of stuff
but it seems so far away but it's so
close true it is closer than it's ever
been yeah I mean in
1996 it was like I knew it was going to
happen in our lifetimes yeah and now
it's looking like it's really going to
happen I mean but it's still like as
soon as we think it's going to happen
then we'll have a bunch of setbacks yeah
I'm curious to see what goes on with
this potential rescheduling I mean I
feel like it's it's a constant side I'm
not a fan of the whole resched they need
to Desu not
reschedule it doesn't make any sense to
consider it a schedule 3 drug that's
just in my opinion that's silly I mean
it's just going to complicate you see
this is this goes back to what I was
saying like how are we as one nation
going to even be able to agree upon one
set of rules like yeah that's a terrible
route because all these people who are
already like way invested are basically
going to have to throw away their
infrastructure and start over that
doesn't make any sense same thing what
are we going to start scheduling tobacco
and alcohol too then there schedule
three you know what I mean like I don't
know yeah you know it's it's a tough one
yeah but we're in very strange times
because we're in you know it's hard to
say going to happen next year Anything
Could Happen yeah you know it's amazing
we're at where we where we are right now
it's amazing that we've gotten here so
quickly in some ways that's true it's
true so it's a beautiful thing
technology is an amazing thing it's an
amazing tool it's scary at the same time
definitely so and it's it's Advanced you
know I mean look at cultivation and the
advances in cultivation it's made huge
differences in indoor cultivation crazy
evenig green houses and outdoor I was
actually at a facility in Watsonville
and um they were partners with a um a
vegetable farm like on the same property
yeah and they use they share equipment
and they just got this robotic AI
tractor that needs no human wow and it
could do anything from vacuum bugs off
of plants to spray them to harvest them
to to plant them yeah so that's
happening right now like I don't know
what to tell you facilities with people
that you and I both know yeah it's
pretty crazy yeah I mean they have
infrared now too they can detect uh dude
they can detect ethylene in the plants I
guess so they can have infrared sensors
and they'll they'll know if a plant's
going to express intersec traits Herm
basically yeah so yeah I mean and this
is just the infancy of all this stuff
you know Ai and all you know we're we're
just starting to get AI involved with
stuff and you know it's a blessing and a
curse I think
yeah it's every day I feel like
something new is like showing its face
and I just shake my head every day like
holy crap we can do this now yeah like
in some ways it's good in other ways I
feel like it's speeding things up too
fast and kind of even just how they like
made all these rules is like they made
rules without thinking of scaling or
without thinking of how it might be when
we're connected to the state next to us
or there's just so much like not wellth
thought outness if that's a word pollen
mitigation was never a big deal yeah for
sure yeah I mean you hear of it more and
more like especially in like Selenas and
oh yeah yeah I was at a facility last
not this week but the last my last trip
down there and they were like they know
that there's a facility next to them
that's doing some breeding and and they
saw lights on at a certain hour and
they're like starting to like worry and
they're like I know you have males in
there and wow it's creating anxiety and
it's like that will create anxiety for
sure yeah so yeah I mean it's it's one
thing having one male but if you're
making Acres of seeds or something like
that you know it's like you're affecting
the people around you but you can make
them in the offseason what people don't
understand is seed production can be
done in the offseason there's a right
way to do it there's a wrong way to do
it for sure indoor production is a great
way to do it definitely for especially
for consistency because if you're making
seeds and your neighbors making
seeds they're going to get
cross-pollinated you're going to
have open pollination on large scale
acreage is Gary and it's happening it's
happening for sure people are doing it
so you guys are delivering soil all over
the US yeah more or less soil fertilizer
and NES I mean some things make more
sense to ship far than others yeah um
but on the other hand like we're
shipping soil as far as like Michigan
and New York it's it's less than more
yeah um we actually are look we need
strategic Partners in some of those
other states to help us like have
product on the ground there that's one
of my pushes for this this um winter and
spring is to try to just have more
availability cuz like so many people
seem to like reach out to us and say we
want to try your stuff yeah but to buy a
bag of our soil is super reasonable but
to ship it is like maybe 50 bucks right
like it could it could like quadruple
the cost of you know a bag of soil sure
just by like giving it to the postman
right so that's one that's one thing
that's always been a struggle with like
moving soil worm castings compost humus
these heavy things bootprints yeah
moving things around is hard liquids are
a little bit easier but still heavy but
we've we now have some dry soluble
powders um and then we have you know
kelp right and we have smaller sizes for
the home gardeners so our web business
is definitely picked up nice but we do
need to figure out a way to get products
to you know further out um less
expensively and you know that's a trick
in itself yeah so yeah the home hom
Growers and living soil no tail living
soil organic you know I think there's
been a big push more so lately in the
last year than I've seen in a long time
I think there's pushes in every
direction all the time but like I've
seen a lot of guys you know it's it's a
Hot Topic right now yeah um I'm glad you
brought this up because I agree I feel
like this year compared to last year
there's a Resurgence for like people who
really care yeah and like the last two
years be the not this 2023 but 21 and
two was the years of everybody like
scaling back trying to figure out the
cheapest way to grow as much as they can
and cut their costs and what really
suffered is the tpin and what really
suffered suffered is the smokers at the
end of the day because there's a lot of
really crappy weed and you know I don't
want to point any fingers any any
specific names but some of most of it
crap I mean honestly most of it's I I
don't know about crap but most of it is
not a great product not the type of
product that I enjoy consuming yeah you
know as a consumer I want to smoke
something that tastes good that gives me
an amazing pie for sure and I think the
effect is important but the taste it's a
full experience to me you know like yeah
we've been smoking this stuff so long
yeah it gets you high of course but the
experience the flavor the your mouth
getting coated with the Tarpin and the
smoke and right like that's that's what
we're looking for is something to be
like wow wow you know like we want we
want that experience that that wow Mark
you know and like I was saying earlier
is like organic and like well-grown weed
is like so much different than like a
nutrient company that's just trying to
tell you to increase your ppms and sure
push it push it push it push it yep and
what that created was like a whole upset
in our entire industry where like yeah
like people were trying to they'd rather
get it from their friend or their next
door neighbor because they would they
would have an experience where they
would go buy some weed at at a
dispensary and it may even have been a
brand that they trusted before yeah but
because that brand had to cut Corners
because it cost a lot to produce and the
state and I don't even want to blame
that brand like I don't blame them at
all because it's just to survive is is
where status quo right now but th those
people who went to the dispensary and
bought some weed and it was just like
not that great and they're like dang 70
bucks for this it's crazy tastes like
cardboard well so I think there's three
types of consumers there's like the
social smoker that really doesn't care
one way or the other about it right they
just smoke socially then there's the
flavor Chasers yeah and then there's the
dragon Chasers that chase the high yeah
you know I like those are the three
types of consumers out there and a lot
of guys that care about getting high
that's really the main focus like if it
tastes good that's a bonus but they want
stuff that's super super strong and a
lot of guys smoke extract too most of
those guys have gone on to smoke an
extract because flow definitely most of
it has a ceiling although now we're
getting back into those uh like infused
products infused products sativas that
don't have a ceiling we're talking about
some of these you know the P coming back
and the hazes you know it's like they're
definitely making it comeback definitely
but it's interesting because I think
most
people in the other two categories
besides chasing the flavors would
appreciate the flavor if they got to
taste a lot of stuff that we get to
experience you know I think most people
would appreciate it because it's it's
just so distinct and when you smoke
something that taste amazing it's like
oh that's all I want to smoke you don't
want to turn back no you don't want to
turn back and once you smoke it for a
little while then it's like you smoke
everything else and it's just not as
good well that's why I think right now
is a good time for all the Cannabis
Brands and The Growers to like shine
yeah because we kind of went through
this period where like okay dispensaries
were just like this such a novelty where
just the fact that you could go in there
and actually go buy weed products and
and it was just like a mind-blowing uh
situation right but now that people are
kind of like used to that part they want
to have an experience that where they
like enjoy what they're buying and
they're actually like happy with their
purchase and you know what I mean so at
this point they're the the consumer is
getting more educated which is a good
thing and it's I think it's the Grower's
job to put something in their hand
that's going to change the way that they
look at every time they make that
purchase right so well and I like what
you said about educated consumer because
I feel like California is a little
behind as a whole because legalization
happened uh you know earlier in other
states Washington Colorado I feel like
I've I see it up in Washington that that
they're able to not just sell the high
THC stuff they can still sell stuff that
not quite as high a
THC um and they go on brands that they
trust and I think that's happening more
and more in California I think you're I
think you're right it's starting to
shift back to that where yeah the
dispensary isn't necessarily making the
rule where it has to test 30% or you're
not bringing it in the door totally cuz
I think that mentality has gotten a
little bit evolved where people are you
know when it has to because I feel like
some of the best stuff doesn't test 30%
totally you know some of the best flavor
profiles that I like yeah OG rarely
tests like in the in the play where some
of them just shoot up but yeah yeah yeah
I mean I I love good gas and I gas is
making it comeback everybody's talking
about it and it's usually you hear
people talking about it a year later
it's like a big thing for sure so gas
will be back OG's gonna be back maybe it
won't be sfv or the Josh dog or the
Tahoe or the Diablo or the whatever it
is it's going to be these crosses that
are coming out that are really heavy in
the gas and then purple with gas where
it's like real Strong gas I mean I've
seen a bunch of it but it's it's going
to get even even better yeah I agree
people are going to take that those Josh
D's and yeah combine them with some
crazy amazing flavors that original that
is the part about where we are in this
industry that is awesome is because like
people like yourselves are making like
amazing strains and just like opening up
you know tarpine profiles that have
never been you know exposed because of
combining things that you know that's
part of the fun of it yeah you know what
I mean of the pheno hunting process the
selection process is going through and
finding stuff you've never seen before
uh we had fried chicken up in Washington
my partner Jason up there big shout out
to House of cultivar with the fried
chicken feno I know Jason actually yeah
yeah he's a really good friend business
part for yeah those guys are great they
do good work um they're they're just
good people for sure I remember early
days going up there and meeting them and
talking to them and I they even came
down and so do you know Gordon from
Grass Valley yeah yeah yeah yeah he's a
good friend too he crushes I forgot he's
does he have something to do with those
guys or so him and I and Jason work
together we've made some crosses I did
some reversals up there with Jason and
we we made some we've made a bunch of
seeds together and Gordon's made a bunch
of genetics on his own in Grass Valley
that are all Epic yeah so some really
awesome stuff definitely definitely so
he's just he's another guy I really like
Gordon he's a good guy and friend and so
just a very likable person and someone
who loves the plant definitely
definitely those are the people I
gravitate to now too is like when people
love the plant you know it and it's just
obvious typically like you yeah people
that can't stop talking about it and
talking about flavor profiles and just
you know I think it's one of those
things like I'm I'm here because I love
it I love doing you know and yeah there
struggles along with it but I feel like
that's part of life's lessons and for
sure I mean if it was easy everyone
would do it right totally and you know
some of the struggles that we're all
faced with feel like they there's enough
other ones that they these ones
shouldn't be in that in the way yeah
which to me is like the regulation type
stuff and the ridiculous you know things
that they make us go through but on the
other hand the rest of it is part of the
is you know the heart of the struggle
this sweeter the victory yeah and I
think you don't want an easy life I
think it's it's a you know it's it's
it's counterintuitive almost you want
you you don't want your kids to struggle
or you don't want to you know your your
family you don't want your family to
struggle but I think struggle defines
helps Define who you are and what you're
capable of overcoming well if you never
have a struggle then it's hard to learn
anything cuz like well there's no
contrast so like when you're really
successful you don't know the difference
I I think it's the the sour and the
sweet you kind of need both you need to
fail I think you fail and you learn a
lot if you fail well these last three to
five years just in selling like soil and
fertilizer and just dealing with Growers
and you know we've had to completely
evolve how like we communicate and like
help farmers so like one of the things
when when I first started all my
products the first thing I did you know
when I would test them before I would
even like bring them to Market it was to
see how much you could actually use
without burning the plant right cuz you
basically want to like come up with your
application rate and everyone was
worried you don't want to go over over
the line you don't want to tell people
to use too much and burn their plant
right right but now it's more like well
how little can we use and and recommend
it to somebody feel good about their
what their outcome's going to be yeah to
the point where we know they're going to
keep coming back so we've had to like
completely like figure out a way for
them to be able to use our products on a
less expensive you know basis yeah so
you know you got to know how to Pivot
you got to and we also have to work hard
and longer and go further yeah to get
the sale so you got to first you got to
like make sure that the grower
understands how to use it then you may
have to present something to the finance
department just to make sure that
they're going to approve the sale right
and at the end of the day there's like
all these different layers and and it's
just like turned into like all the
where're I feel like we're always
quoting against somebody else but at the
end of the day they need to look at what
we could do for you as a whole instead
of just like what the cost for this
bottle of whatever it is right well it's
so competitive in soil in genetics I
mean like if you look there's so many
seed companies out there what makes you
stand out compared to any other seed
company or me you know what I mean like
what am I doing different you know and
so we really think hard all the time
about like how can we improve our
product how can we make better genetics
using tissue culture parents making sure
our genetics are clean before we even
start making seeds that's you know
that's a part of our goal
you know is like to be able to give
people the best product possible and not
just so we can get the sale so you know
we feel good about what we're doing as
well well I'm in in for the Long Haul
it's not like this is the first year I'm
just trying to get people introduced I'm
trying to keep them well if you're still
around on the nipple if you're still in
the industry I think at this point
you're in it for the long haul it's not
easy money you know it's it's hard work
and it's it's enjoyable work if you love
if you love doing it it's actually
fantastic oh when I all the driving
around I mean this this last week I did
this little like firstly did this event
in Humble yeah and you know in Northern
humble so Arcada is like from Nevada
City like a six-h hour drive so all the
way up the top almost to the top of the
101 before we get to Oregon right did a
3-day event there it was great got to
see a lot of Old Friends people you know
people I've known since I was 18 years
old yeah and it was cool to connect and
see see you know everyone's kind of in
the same place like it's better than it
used it was last year but it sure could
be a lot better and we're glad to see
you're here and you know if we're here
then you know that's a good sign right
right and and then we rolled all the way
down and did I first I stopped in
Selenas and um had a you know a little
consultation down there and did a walk
through at Pacific reserve and checked
out their plants that's a huge facility
um now they're growing all the massive
genetics because he's now part of that
whole um conglomerate now wow so we did
a nice feno hunt there and uh amazing
stuff's GNA come out from that
definitely eye out big yeah for sure not
messing around yeah I was one of the
original Founders there and I'm a
shareholder now it's definitely a bigger
company now and they're also one of
vitals you know best customers and
they've stayed really true to keeping it
organic and doing a really good job with
their their product that's awesome um
and then so then after bouncing from
selenis we did this event in Ventura
which wasn't really cannabis based but
it's the um National heirloom seed Expo
really cool which was like vegetable
seed you know fruits but it you know
that whole seed mentality is the type of
people that we are like all those people
that are looking out for the best of the
best and they really care about what
they're growing and like so we got to
talk to passionate Farmers passionate
gardeners and Growers people making
seeds people buying seeds and at the end
of the day I feel like there is is a
really big movement towards people you
know getting back to the land growing a
little bit more of their own food and
like sure technolog is coming into play
too but I think people still have that
like craving to like be have a
connection to the Earth and grow
something yeah you know house plants are
great but at the end of the day growing
food is very rewarding I mean I think
for sure that's that's my therapy yeah
like if I don't have a garden I feel
like I'd be like wouldn't know what to
do I'd be like what should I be doing
right now yeah and like let's say you
don't want to grow tomatoes or or you
don't want to grow vegetables you know
it's too much you can still grow herbs
you can still grow herbs there's so many
little things that you can do that you
can eat you know in the winter it's not
too late right now you know what I mean
it's never too late there there's always
stuff that can be grown that you can
consume for sure you can have a little
plant of chives in your window to you
know a tomato plant under a grow light
if you wanted so I mean everything now
they make these LEDs that go and you
know you could put them in your window
or whatever you know I've seen people
have these little grow tents with a
veggie garden in it yeah instead of
their cannabis garden they have like
food and I think that's great yeah me I
think that's fun for sure it's good for
families too like if you live in a city
and you want your kids to be exposed to
that I was thinking if you lived in like
a big city right now there's such a huge
disconnection with like natural world
you know I guess that's better than
making your kids
trim but yeah I think I think a good
family experience for everybody you know
it's a great way to teach your kids
about produce and about vegetables and
also to be able to taste the difference
between stuff that you grow and stuff
you buy in the store because I think
most people have never experienced like
okay well yeah I wouldn't say most
people but there's a small percentage of
us that have grown a lot of stuff and
then a lot of people they've only eaten
store-bought vegetables yeah the
difference between a store-bought tomato
and a homegrown tomato even the heirloom
in the stores for sure those aren't
nearly as good as if you got heirlooms
yourself unless you go to Berkeley Bowl
you might find some good stuff during
the season sure there's some great farms
that put out some good produce but you
got to like nail it in that perfect
window it's been trucked it could be
have been on a shelf who knows how many
people put their grimy hands on it
totally you know there's nothing like
that experience of going picking
something ripe and carrying it into your
kitchen cutting it up and eating it or
putting it on a sandwich or well there's
so many places you can buy exotic seeds
so like you don't have to just grow a
plain cucumber you can and a lot of
places sell different cucumbers and
stuff like that but but we talk about
pumpkins cucumbers anything there's
there's multiple varieties that you
could buy seeds of at the very least
seeds I mean Peppers there's so many
tomatoes there's so many different
varieties even cucumbers now I grew a
bunch this year I I love those little
lemon cucumbers and those Armenian
Armenian ones are my favorite those
things would never get bitter so good
they could be like 3 feet long and still
bitter and still sweet
still sweet yeah yeah yeah they love the
sun those things Crush they're good
those are good up in Grass Valley for
sure nice yeah yeah I love all that
stuff same thing with different lettuces
I think different lettuces during the
winter there's so many different things
and it's like that you couldn't even get
in the store if you wanted to well
lettuce is my favorite thing of anything
to grow in the world yeah that's my
favorite because it's a short crop yeah
it's it doesn't even need fertilized
ever right you know you just as long as
you have some like rich soil it's it
grows such a short period of time that
it doesn't need
fertilization and it's that is something
of of all the things that you could grow
yourself and notice the difference
between store-bought yeah like fresh
lettuce when you cut it wash it eat it
compared to it like sitting at least if
if you see in a store it's at least five
days from being cut right so at least at
least that's like probably a lot more
than that that's if you live in like
Santa Cruz or something where it's
getting you know coming from Watsonville
yeah but like most people throughout the
country at least a week or two yeah if
it's in a if it's in a sealed bag a week
or two for sure right so like growing
your own lettuce harvesting that and
eating it is like one of the most
rewarding things I haven't done micro
Greens in a I mean I experimented a long
time ago but my buddy is crushing garden
house farms they're doing micro greens
now nice my buddy makes the best microG
greens and they're super I mean and same
thing with arugula too like arugula you
get you get it from the store it just
tastes green yeah it tastes plain but
then you get some really good TPS yeah
it's got turps It's got pepper you get
strong pepper flavor I love arugula yeah
me too it makes me feel good yeah I need
to eat more of it arugula is actually
another Super it's even shorter than
lettuce you know like 30 days you're
like got baby arugula it's the best when
it's small too micro greens 10 days yeah
you know I love M 10 days you can yeah
and you can set that up under
fluoresence like super easy to do get
those little prop trays and you get a
little baker Rack in your kitchen so
easy super easy yeah and you don't need
much too I think they're super I mean
like as far as nutrient DSE yeah dude
like they're super amazing I mean if you
buy not to just pitch my soil but if you
grew microG Greens in my soil yeah you
definitely don't need to fertilize it
it's not like my soil is tons of
fertilizer but it's Rich because it has
worm castings compost humus yeah it's
like got minerals so it's be you know
nurture your plant but it's also going
to put out some like tasty mineral rich
food yeah yeah what's funny if you grew
micro Greens in all the different soils
they would with the same seed they would
all taste slightly different definitely
in fact that's a great experiment
someone should do let's do it let's do
it you you guys travel all over the US
for events what about are you doing
International stuff soon as far A little
bit like this Columbia thing starting to
pop into place that it's a little tricky
getting product out of the country
because of you know Department of a
regulations and especially the nature
like I'm sure salt based fertilizers are
probably easy to ship because there
they're not so worried about
microorganisms yeah but with with
organic stuff and just there super
paranoia of like microorganisms that are
going to like go into some country and
like you know wreak havoc on some crop
or people or whatever so you know there
there's like it's kind of like that
paranoia of of just germs in general
uhhuh like there's bacteria everywhere
if you're scared of bacteria then you
shouldn't walk outside your door CU it's
floating all around everywhere yeah but
at the end of the day when you tell
someone that you have bacteria or fungi
in a b in a bag or a bottle yeah then
they're just like totally yeah well you
know aspir jillis really screwed up the
Colorado market for Organics and it
almost screwed up the organ market for
sure but then the Growers fought back
and we like aspergilus is on everything
yeah literally it's on pretty much
everything it's probably on us right now
exactly you know and it's it's just but
you get these companies coming in saying
dude we don't want aspil you guys need
to make it illegal to have aspergilus we
need to test for it and if it tests
positive you guys shouldn't be you know
consuming it's [__] yeah th those
same people who tell you to push that
four point whatever ppms are the same
people right trying to like get rid of
you know Organics because they're
worried about aspir jillis but in
reality they just want to pound more
salt and
pollute the planet totally it's wild
yeah it's the Wild Wild West still it
sure is so as far as genetics you know
uh we saw some o or i saw some OG Kush
that was pretty amazing yes sir what
else my favorite yeah that Skittles is
pretty baller that was a cut from that
actually Brandon and Shiloh yeah that
was third gen um when those guys were
still working together yeah been able to
maintain the mom of it for for that long
of a period of time and take good care
of it make sure it didn't get into the
wrong hands and get pop Laden virus or
something else weird because uh that's
one thing that I feel like has H
happened that has hurt the industry as
far as like keeping good genetics around
and I wonder if that's one of the
reasons why like the real Sour is kind
of like this like unicorn that is just
like super hard to find and you know
what I mean cuz Sour's a tricky one
though like I keep seeing people say
this is the one and it's a close but
it's just I still have not all the way
seen it you know I feel you you know I
feel you I mean I had the weasel's
diesel that I got from my friend and
that was pretty amazing but it was still
a little bit different but it smoked
amazing yeah I made some crosses with it
nice we got some zour diesel yeah
Skittles sounds really good yeah that's
a good one I love those two for sure I
think that would be a good that would be
a winner yeah for sure but yeah Sour
Diesel I I think there's
been you know a lot of a lot of [__]
copies but hoplon did a number on sour
diesel
especially we're talking about a really
old plant so you know from the 90s it's
like 30 years old now yeah you know
something like that yeah so the genetics
aren't the same but I mean they's still
good chem dog around still good old
school Kim D around for sure there is
some good sour I just don't have any ony
right now yeah it'' be better if I did
but I'd like to see it for sure but yeah
i' I've grown a couple that were close
and I'm just
like almost but yeah not quite there OG
that one's just been able to be Banger
for super long time so you've had that
for long long time that's awesome OG is
amazing but you know it's also like not
commercial it's not like to grow that on
a large scale would be hard because it
takes a long time to root it you know it
grows funky so you probably don't want
to be growing that in the same room as
other stuff and you know like there's
Dynamics and that's why some of these
strains have gone out of like popularity
is because of it's easy to grow a bunch
of gelados that are like super uniform
and they yield well they're not it's not
a pain in the butt it's consistent yeah
it's good it's good production weed for
sure yeah yeah and there's some fenos
that are really good there some
expression that I really like I love
gelato 41 still you know the bachio cut
you know yeah yeah I like the 33 yeah 33
is good too 33 is great 30 33 is
actually a really
about a gazillion other things too but
yeah and same thing with the 41 there's
a bunch of names but 41's still really
good and even the 45 had its place I
think that was cool yeah yeah it's
trippy how many good Cult of ours came
out of one cross yeah you know when you
start thinking about it you know if if
you like gelato yeah you know if you
like gelato there's there's 10 bangers
that came out of that least man I mean
it's in a lot you know it's in a lot not
all of them breed really well yeah and
they don't wash so it's a little bit you
know yeah everybody hash people popular
now for as far as breeders are concerned
the whole washing thing like yeah does
it wash does it not wash like need
5centers only only only five or six
percenters it's like and there's a
handful of stuff that have a six
percenter yeah CU they're out there for
sure you know and I've I've actually
grown GM bonda GMO and banana cond both
wash over six but you know GMO I was
stoked at the time but everything's GMO
though now but even the guys that have
like five different strains they're all
like GMO based because they wanted to
get that 6% right but in reality like
what tastes the best in rosin is
something like Skittles which is like 2%
Skittles maybe three if you're lucky it
might be the best xjack I mean I love
Skittles I love Rainbow belts is
incredible um so is some good sour uh
actually you know the best sour rosin
that I've tasted comes from that J PL
Speaker Guy oh wow yeah it tastes I get
like an ounce every year yeah I like
trickle it out to myself yeah and it
tastes great nice haven't seen the
finished flower yeah but the rosin my
friend actually gets it and it's awes
it's amazing yeah nice tart there's this
H sour cherry that's like super tart
from soal dank they make this rosin and
that stuff is just tasty it's one of
those ones that you want to keep smoking
even after you're really high you're
like I could still take one more you
know that's kind of how rainbow Bel is
to me cuz it's that gas and that Z TP
mhm and it's strong and it's just like
man makes your mouth like well and it's
it's like Skittle but not Skitty yeah
yeah some of those crosses uh what's the
rainbow belt it's the parent the moonbow
and the moonbow is like one of my
favorites yeah that old school like the
75 or whatever was before the 75 some
moonbo rosin with me it's so good yeah
so yeah I know Adam from archive and he
he crushes they their Ros is really good
some of their I I kind of feel like
they've done the best job yeah you know
you know as far as like getting the
hashers that are really like bangers and
all round you know what I mean their
flower is amazing if you go get their
flower in Oregon it's super top- notot I
believe it so yeah especially that
moonbo I'm a huge fan of the I think the
112 is is the one it's really
good yeah you I'm a huge fan I'm this
guy actually is a Nevada County grower
and his name is scr M you may have heard
of him yeah yeah um he put this out this
was all grown with my stuff too so what
I don't like is Diet Skittles but what I
do like is Skittles crosses that are
complex I don't like a water down if
it's gonna you got to make it complex
and different you don't want it just a
lighter version of Skittles there's no
point really you know what who does a
really good Skittles cross is uh really
good uh lamb from Compassionate Heart
uhhuh his dirty Skittles that is really
good strain it's like Vermont diesel
yeah to Skittles and it makes some
really good rousing really good yeah I
saw some Afghan Skittles you it sounds
good like I was like okay cool it's
probably got like some hashy hashy
funkiness to it like yeah it was just
like a skittles light very very like
you're like oh I I get a little bit but
it wasn't like Skittles is supposed to
be overpowering him you know where like
it's so bright yeah I mean Skittles
needs to be loud yeah and last year I
actually grew a whole garden of it with
a partner in Nevada County yeah so I
thought and I was like it was growing
too good in my mind I was like the whole
time I was doubting it yeah so the
nurser basically gave us a skittles
cross and we don't even know what
exactly it was sure but it took until
about week two or three and I was just
like no that is not zps and sucks I grew
an entire Garden thinking that was going
to all be for rosin and it ended up
being this other strain that came out
okay and it was a good producer for the
guy and stuff but still what my whole
intention and the reason I even like was
involved on that exact Garden was to
like get a whole F of Z yeah know like
those are the things you know there's
certain projects that get me excited
that was one that did I want jars of Z
exact I want like years years Supply
yeah so like multiple years so it didn't
work out last year yeah
the good thing about time is there's
always next year for sure for sure well
what are we going to smoke oh you know
what SM some of this Nemo Skittles
sounds good so where do you see the
market going I mean I think you said
your uh internet has been doing pretty
good as far as web stuff with home
Growers yeah you think that's gonna get
bigger and bigger yeah to be honest
that's another part of my uh winter and
spring focus is like desize downsizing
not getting rid of the big sizes of my
products that I have now yeah but we're
going to offer like a four qu bag of
soil a four qu bag of compost instead of
like one and a half cubic feet that cost
50 bucks to ship across the country and
not everybody needs that much anyway so
we're used to the NorCal grower like who
needs like truckloads worth of stuff but
in reality this whole new wreck market
and like legalization has opened up a
lot of people to just growing their six
plants or depending on what state they
live in you know 6 to 10 or whatever the
number is in every state and not even
just for cannabis but we're seeing home
vegetable gardeners like spend a little
bit of money on their crop because they
care about you know what what their you
know outcome is going to be well and the
Bea beautiful thing about soil and like
your soil especially is it's not like
you throw it out at the end of the
season it keeps going and gets better
and better and better every year yeah
that's something I should say about
Pacific Reserve too is like like we've
really been able to like dial it in
there to be able to you know use this
product line at scale but also to be
able to reuse soil and and and compare
the numbers and look at the um yield
compared to the fresh new soil and like
look side by side plants with new fresh
soil and Reus soil and we have a product
that's called vital soil Builder that's
biochar where I'm casting compost humus
nice and bat and seab beru so we
basically at Pacific Reserve they've
been
doing uh two rounds in the same soil
amending with like a cup of the soil
Builder and a little bit of guano yeah
and stirring it up in the Ed soil and
replanting and the plants are actually
even growing faster um thank you they're
growing even faster in the ReUse soil
because there's still like leftover
nutrients plus they added this like
fresh worm castings compost and humus
there's some biochar in there yeah so
it's like living soil mhm you know round
two you know it's not I'm not going to
go to the extreme of calling it no till
which no till to me is a little bit of a
just catchphrase anyway most of it's low
till anyway yeah I mean who's busting
out a tiller but in reality you got to
pull out the root ball and and if you're
growing Outdoors like let's face it we
got to like turn the soil we got to pull
the weeds out we want to make the soil
fluffy again so that the roots can
penetrate yeah I'm all for reusing soil
don't get me wrong like way all for it
but the no till thing is a little bit of
a marketing thing that's like maybe it
helps sell weed or something but you
know let's face it like you know
compressed soil isn't necessarily your
your best friend yeah so giving a little
bit of fluff isn't isn't like isn't a
sin it's not like dumping a bunch of
salt on it yeah it's not going to take
away from the value of the soil not at
all and you know I don't want to offend
anybody but to me the noil thing is
something that came on like way late in
the game when we were already into
reusing an amending soil right and cover
crop and companion crop and all that I'm
all for it yeah but the term no till is
a little bit to me like not really
describing what it is you're you're
doing living soil I'm all for that term
yeah I love that term because that
that's what we're all about that's what
it is microorganisms in the soil helping
your plant do a better job or helping
your soil do a better job for your
nice what do you think of the smoke
tastes good everybody likes the Z
seriously so have you seen any other
stuff lately that have been you know
like exciting stuff everything's purple
yeah actually there is a little
Resurgence for green weed nice and I
think that's goes to the gases though um
yeah OG's and people still in that
search for uh for the real Sour um it's
seems like there's some Haz starting to
make a Resurgence um sh's doing that big
project yeah um i' I gave him a a plan
or two for that too nice the whole Haze
thing is really cool I think I did too
it's diversity right everybody just
didn't grow Haze because it took too
long there was there was a couple hazes
that gave hay a bad name and it was like
the Jacks yeah but it's not like the old
school Jacks because those were very
good right it's that linear Jack that
doesn't get you high it's like that's
not how hazes hazes get you really high
yeah totally you know hazes should get
you lit well I love the cough you know
dude the four cins cough is ridiculous
so I did some breeding I did that with
the banana Skittles nice I got the fort
cins C from my buddy
Reuben and that plant is amazing it
grows crazy though it's like super super
thin and GRE we just grew a one plant of
it over this winter yeah and it came out
phenomenal and it was during that whole
period when like Nevada City got like
four feet of snow so
long story short there was no power for
like 10 days so there were no lights for
10 days wow it flow it took 14 years 14
years 14 weeks to flower 14 years to
flower would be amazing but it didn't
even like take a hit that 10day period
of being you know out I mean maybe the
structure hazes don't structure great
anyway uhhuh but the the flower came out
amazing tasted amazing that has the
brait stack yeah it's pretty cool though
yeah it's a good one it's it's super
unique as far as like the profile of it
is you know yeah it's it's definitely
equatorial
haish little but it's it's its own thing
for sure yeah so and I guess the like
and it's way different than the piff
yeah which is another version of nl5 by
hay M yeah so there's a lot of diversity
in that the cross for sure for sure so
another thing I did with the shoreline
crosses M did a bunch of Shoreline
crossed it with some of the popular
stuff
now the banana Skittles uh Skittles back
cross grape gas and double Cherry
gelato dude that's the shoreline got
like this musky funkiness to it like
yeah the musk old school I love the musk
yeah yeah that's that's what the cough
has I feel like the basement for sure
yeah yeah and they're both good ones I
got them from the same person too cool
people that like it really like it and
people is a cherry coming out for sure
there's a there's definitely like a sour
cherry nice which I like sour cherry too
I got some dabs with sour Chi too
awesome but I'm a I'm a huge I like
diversity in in the things I eat I like
diversity in things I smoke so I'm not
just like this is the only thing I want
to smoke sometimes I'll get on like
these fits with like Skittles or with
yeah Pluto or with some of these other
ones where that that's what I have and I
have a whole bunch of different
varieties that's all I want to smoke
yeah that one that one bag cuz it's so
good and then when it's gone I'll go
back to other stuff it's kind of like OG
to me I always want to go back to OG
anytime I get good OG I'll smoke it all
just because I like the effect yeah so I
mean I like the taste of it too I like
that especially the good ogs that taste
piny where you got that nice Pine in
Earth yeah you know and the Citrus is
cool like really citrusy kind of OG like
that's that's all right but I really
like that almost where you're tasting
pine needles yeah and that's the mercine
right I think so
yeah I think so
too but yeah and then but it's stronger
than others it's like a combination of
miren and something else because some of
it have like sour has it but not to the
extreme like some of those ogs have it
where you feel like you're standing
under some redwood trees or something
like that yeah which actually you can
eat the new the the new growth off
redwoods I don't know if you've ever
eaten the the Sprouts off the leaves I
haven't they're super good and they're
super piny they taste kind of like OG
Kush wow I have to give it a shot yeah
the new growth anytime it's you know and
these you're eating Organics most of the
time yeah almost always yeah as much as
I possibly can you told me something
earlier about most of the flour that you
smoke is from guys that uh oh yeah that
use vital products they use vital
products yeah I almost feel like a
connection to everybody who's ever using
our products is like yeah an extension
of what it is that I'm all about and you
know I always feel like if somebody is
using a lot of vital products and I know
that they're putting a lot of good
energy into what it is they're growing
for sure and the outcome usually is is
more than prevalent yeah um like as far
as like C customers that have like won
contests and over the years
like as long back as I can remember
people using vital have been coming out
on top um like this past year Emerald
cup Rebel grown he's been a long-term
loyal vital customer for 10 plus years
yeah back in the day when third genen
was sweeping up the the um the cups they
were always on the vital program I don't
know if you've been keeping an eye on
this kid uh cannabis Chris right now but
he's at he just won the smoking jacket
last year and he he won that and then he
won king of zho which was the first uh
cup Chris Castle no not Chris Castle
different Chris okay but they were yeah
okay Chris won the flower yeah he did
win the FL yeah this guy this guy won
the um the rosin nice and he's he also
he's won like five big contests lately
we need get him on the show and yeah you
should and he's been using vital
strictly for a long time that's awesome
and uh I love smoking his hash too and
it just seems like you know you're when
you're proud of what you do and you know
that you put out a good product yeah and
you help other people achieve greatness
then um you
know it's it's like an extra layer of
reward rewarding this
right you know what I mean like it's so
rewarding to like know somebody else
succeeded from it and then smoke the
finished product yeah and and then have
access to it whenever you want well it's
great being part of something that's so
much bigger than yourself for sure that
too that's I think that's what it is
yeah because it it's like really it's
just so much of a bigger like the stuff
we do has impact on good or bad you know
and I care so much too it's it's it's
not just like an ego thing where I need
to smoke the weed that's growing with my
[__] I also like check up on people
growing with my [__] a lot like I love
to visit farms and I love to like give
my input or you know what I mean when
you love flow too so that you know yeah
so it's like you know I think something
you said earlier that really resonates
like this is It's a lifestyle you know
like right now isn't the best economic
time to be in the Cannabis industry but
as far as like being a cannabis lover
it's probably it's the best time ever
like I get to drive around and go to
huge farms and small farms Big Farms
medium Farms talk about what I love help
give advice if if it's wanted or just
learn and hear what they're doing you
know what I mean so fact that we can get
paid to do this stuff is pretty awesome
just to BU that by itself to be able to
do what you
love for sure and we talk about our like
our 18yearold selves and our 80y old s
with the only two people that you really
need to impress and I think my 18yar old
self would be pretty oh my 18-year-old
selfelf is blown away right now yeah now
I got to work on impressing the
80-year-old and make sure that totally I
can still be surviving then right so if
you had one piece of advice to give your
younger self that first started out in
the industry and doing the stuff that
you did with the soil what would be that
one piece of advice I mean most of all
just be confident there's so many times
where I was like had anxiety that you
know something may or may not not work
out yeah and like even to this day I
have to remind myself that it's going to
work out like whether it's trying to get
a big account to buy stuff because sales
aren't great or whether it's somebody
calls with a complaint and you want to
make sure that there there's no reason
for them to complain and you know
like sometimes I I think I care too much
and I don't want to tell my my uh
younger self to not care yeah but on the
other hand believe in your cause and and
just keep your eye on the prize and it's
going to work out because I think I
spent too many years like worrying yeah
like looking
back me and my wife even have these
conversations like I think we've spent
too much time worrying you know I agree
I think those are the kind of lessons
you learn when you're older right like
we you know it takes time to learn that
you don't need to worry yeah because you
have a stack proof of the stuff that's
going on to where it's like all those
times I worried and I'm here for sure
you know because really life you know we
talk about data points on my show a lot
you know through throughout life you get
data points on life and cannabis the
more you smoke the more things you try
you you you know you learn what you like
and what you don't like but you also
learn all the the nuances and diversity
that's out there between each plant
between each smoke all those things and
you know what else is like the amount of
people and the different types of
personalities and yeah like as I
sometimes feel even though I've been a
grower my whole life a whole adult life
since like I've I've always been
involved with growing cannabis since
1988 wow and never had a hiccup since so
I've always been had that connection but
sometimes I have different hats and if I
go in as a vital Garden Supply and you
know not every place knows my history
and not every person does yeah sometimes
I feel like they look at me as like an
outsider as like a sales guy that's just
trying to push some product line MH like
I can I could sense that energy like
when I go to certain places you know
because they get that and like I respect
that they're used to that but it's my
job to make them feel comfortable with
me totally without like bragging or like
acting like I know it all yeah but just
like more like making observations about
what it is that they've done and what
they're doing and try to let them know
that I respect where they're at you know
what I mean cuz for sure it's it's a
tricky game right now and everybody's
Terri torial everybody thinks they their
systems better sure and like you get
back to that competitive thing you know
like there's a million nutrient
companies right now trying to get a sale
and at the end of the day there's always
somebody behind me trying to get the
next guy and I have to just believe in
the fact that you know if they have
success with my product and the and the
finished product comes out as good as
it's supposed to yeah then they're not
going to go anywhere else right if it
ain't broke don't fix it for sure
especially with something like
soil so but replacing your soil is a big
deal especially if you're reusing your
soil yeah I think a lot of people have
tried you know different things and seen
if they could you know skimp on soil or
something and for sure they later find
out that that was probably not the best
route to go yeah I'm not a big fan of
Rockwell one of our last guests is like
hom grower and he loves Rock really yeah
I'm not either I think more so the
effect than anything like you can get
some stuff that looks great smells great
then you go to smoke it usually doesn't
have the turbs and maybe every once in a
while you find some stuff that does but
definitely doesn't have the same effect
I agree like I'm a I'm a soil fan but
I've also learned to appreciate some
people growing just like cocoa parlay
Blends and yeah cocoa because Coco can
attach some microbes yeah it can like
hold some life I feel like rock wol can
right and like half the time I see these
these rock wool grows in like these big
facilities and they're just pounding
them with as much salt as they possibly
can to try to get their like five pounds
of light or whatever it is that they're
getting these days and there's algae
growing on it and it's just like just
doesn't seem right to me you know
totally at least the cocoa is like it
kind of gives gives the plant like
enough space in a home you can get good
flavor with cocoa for sure really good
flavor there's some good there's some
good like I guess people call it
nowadays Sanic you know cocoa grown weed
people using some microbes combined with
some salt and yeah you know coming out
with something that actually has like a
happy in between like a good yield has
that bag appeal but actually has some
turps and some flavors and so yeah
that's another thing that you know I'm
starting to have some appreciation for
and in my younger years I would have
been more critical say no way you can't
you can't I back in the day I thought
that any amount of salt was going to
kill the microbes and it was just like
throwing it out the window but through
years of experience and seeing people
and different grows go through cycles
and like yeah sometimes facility will be
all organic and then the next thing you
know they make a switch because they
want to save money or they hired a new
grower or whatever it is and so like
halfway through the crop they may switch
from vital to whatever brand and then
next thing you know I go there and I see
still growing in the soil and I'm like
wait the salt didn't kill kill the soil
there's still fungus there it's still
alive so that's something I did learn
you know like the first couple years of
like seeing the commercial scale go from
like the backyard grower to Loud Pack
type you know what I mean
so that that's definitely something also
as like a grower and a you know from a
nutrient company standpoint to be able
to see the evolution
and learn how that you can combine
products and there isn't necessarily one
recipe right and you got to got to like
do what works for you as a grower and me
as a provider of products I got to help
the grower understand how my stuff could
fit into what it is they're already
doing
right
totally what do you think of that
Skittles now half still tasty yeah
really nice I pref yeah I mean I prefer
smoking stuff that burns down to the
roach
but if it doesn't something's wrong
right you put it out I think there's a
lot of genetics that just aren't capable
of it too where like you can get that
that's one of my favorite things where
you have a roach you fire it up the next
day and it still tastes really good yeah
makes me smile yeah doesn't have that
stale
flavor then something got done right yep
you ever see the cat piss back in the
day oh yeah definitely like ammonia
ammonia and skunk not gas by the way it
was it was
amonia super skunky yeah a tenth of a
would smell the whole room up and then I
also the shamp the champagne yeah around
the same time champagne from champelli
yeah I was his name came up we were
talking about it the other day like
somebody that I originally like would
work that the OG with yeah also was
working with that champagne and he was
friends with champelli this was like
we're talking yeah no one has that cut
it's long years ago yeah and that was
bag seed from beaser oh wow of champ
pretty
sure yeah cuz nobody has the champagne
cut it does not exist as far as I'm
almost sure that's that that's from bag
seed from beers yeah I I actually need
to ask him that but back in the day
there was tons of those beers in the Bay
Area and tons tons there there was some
good stuff in there too there was a lot
of stuff but they also used some of it
was good yeah that you know I'm not
saying it was a bad thing even though it
was you know beaster but yep yeah long
story
short that all those worlds collided at
one point and you know yeah genetics but
OG Rose to the top OG was like all
anybody longest time for such a long
time like OG was was hard to get real
good OG yeah it wasn't like unless you
were growing it yourself or your friends
were growing it you didn't have it all
the time well and a lot of us who grew
you know like we made packs with each
other to not give it out totally so to
keep that value and it it did all right
for a decent amount of time but
eventually everybody got it then it yeah
then it like turned upside down and
nobody grew it again what happens is
somebody gets a bag seed and then
everybody gets the bag seed so like even
with OG a lot of people that had you
know like there's a lot of bunk cuts of
OG yeah like bag SE so many it's not the
no bag seed is never good with OG that
I've seen
and low turps your OG should be smoking
to the roach for sure you'll enjoy that
for sure nice well thank you for uh
coming on the show today if somebody
wants to find out how or they need to
get a hold of you they want some soil
they want to check out you have an
Instagram absolutely um I'm organic
Brian and then vital Garden Supply also
has its own Instagram under vital Garden
Supply and then we have a website ww.
vital Gardens supply.com
um so if there's a will there's a way to
get a hold of us easily um our products
are available on the web we also are
available on Amazon nice and I do a lot
of events and I love talking to Growers
and people so reach out to me send me a
DM awesome let's grow let's grow let's
grow together sure right on bro thanks
for coming on the show we'll do this
again sometime soon SS
[Music]
good
yeah