[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James Lab podcast
and today my special guest is Tino from
Tino's genetics how you doing today Tino
I'm doing really good thanks for having
me here man so we've been hanging out a
little bit lately uh Brandon brought you
on the show when when we filmed the
first episode we met we went to to lunch
and uh hit it off and man thank you for
coming out yeah it was a it was a blast
that barbecue was really good we got
good barbecue here not like Texas but
it's you know it's good forn I was I was
really impressed yeah but yeah being
able to see the see the facility and
everything the first time I was like
really blown away it's like really cool
what you're doing here and and I really
like it awesome yeah awesome thank you
very much so let's talk about you and
how you get your start in the industry
yeah I got my start kind of um you know
just growing growing uh selling weed you
know I first started out just uh selling
really mhm and uh then I just evolved
into uh growing and making seeds you
know what I mean did you sell before you
smoked or did you start I sold before I
smoked we that's that seems to be a
common theme with a lot of people but I
mean I think I was definitely you know I
got into psychedelics a little first but
yeah I was like more like the athlete
type of guy I got hurt playing sports so
I started selling weed and and then I
started smoking weed I really like fell
in love with it you know and um and then
I was lucky enough to meet somebody that
you know had really good weed and I
became like the guy that had the good
bud you know and um this is like 02 03
type type of air you know and uh so yeah
I met him and and U I just got all this
all this weed like you know we were I
started selling a lot of Bud and uh
being able to see all the different
types and question like where's where's
this stuff coming from who's you know
who's growing this stuff it's like
really good and right seeing all the
different kind come out and uh and it
really was just like you know I want to
I want to get into this I want to grow
and I want to learn how to make seeds
and and um you know I really started
growing like
0607 nice and uh really really got into
like wanting to make seeds you right
away right away right into the growing
so I mean nice did you have friends that
made seeds is that how you desire or the
no no I didn't really have anybody no
forms yeah I'm like total nobody in my
family you know I'm first generation
right you know I just kind of figured it
out like kind of on my own I I got a a
Soma that Som style uhuh that's the only
book I kind of found and I started
reading there and he started talking
about how to make femin seeds right like
naturally like how you naturally reverse
the plant and so I started doing that
like 0708 you know right when I started
uh learning how to grow yeah you know so
it was like um I figured out really
quick it's like I got to learn how to
grow first before I make seeds and you
know I was trying to do both at once and
right and it did it did like develop you
know uh together right you know what I
mean but um so you know my whole thing
was to make feminized seeds and to make
stuff for myself that was really good I
wanted to make you know a strain
everybody knew like you you know back
then you stick your head in a bag you
could be like oh that's that's Bubba
Kush oh that's Blue Dream oh that's this
oh that's this kush or whatever you know
used to be a oh it's purple whatever
you know You' be able to be distinctive
there wasn't like a million strains I
mean there's a lot more but not like
there is now you know there wasn't 300
gelato St yeah exactly a million runs
it's like right you know and then you
got the guys that are kind of making fun
of gelato and Skittles but they like
love runs and everybody's confused you
know totally confused yeah yeah I mean I
think it's confusing quality is
confusing to a lot of people yeah you
know I think there's a lot of people
that are confused by what quality is and
Instagram is 100% to blame you know I
think that before Instagram we saw the
bud and there was a lot more about
effect but then all of a sudden
Instagram came out and we saw these
beautiful photos and people like that's
the onein I want that because the way it
looks it's definitely a Instagram is
there's Instagram weed it's definitely a
thing for sure you know like back then
it it effects is really what What
mattered and uh and the high you know
you want to get want to we want to fill
it you know what I mean and some of this
stuff now is just people are seeing
pictures and basing their breeding off
of that and not even really growing it
out and smoking it you know I laugh at
some people that you know they post a
picture and they're like it's like wheat
six or seven they're like this is my
keeper I'm like so you're you're not
even picking you're not smoking at or
you're just going by how it takes
Instagram pictures yeah it's like okay
come on man like so many people are like
that yeah I totally base everything off
of not not really like tests so much as
like just me smoking it because right
you know I'm I'm the test you know it's
what I want to smoke it's what gets me
high it's what I like cuz that's why I
originally started I didn't originally
start making seeds to sell them I made
them for myself yeah you know and uh
I've done a lot of a lot of testing a
lot of uh a lot of R&amp;D smoking you know
smoking my own strains yeah and then
also stress testing I fully believe in
you know stress testing your plants
growing them out and that's the only way
you're going to really get strong fims I
I really stand behind my fims and I've
done a lot of work like I've been
messing around since 2008 I haven't
really made
serious films till like about 2015
2016 and then um you know my company
started I started up in 2017 so you
started with a lot of stable genetics
though back in the day because I feel
like the stuff back you know 15 years
ago was a lot more stable than it is
today especially sexually stable
definitely no it it really was u a lot
more stable stuff and it was easier for
me to really learn more about uh
breeding and how to make uh good fims
right and you know how it all works
because I'm kind of just you know going
off that Soma book and and uh you know
teaching myself a lot of trial and error
a lot of growing and to get where I'm at
today when you if you cross stuff that's
very distinct if you're Crossing two
gelato it's hard to see what the progyny
is actually getting from the two parents
which one it came from whereas if you
have like a sativa and you have
something that's more that's what I love
to do SE sativa and something small
something tall and then the fos are
really easy to to pick out absolutely
you know it's it's uh that's one of my
favorite things to do like I like uh
doing a lot of breeding with green crack
I have the old green crack uh cut green
it's real short it's a special strain
though special yeah and it's one of
those ones I build a tolerance to it
really really really fast but when you
smoke it for the first time after you've
harvested it it'll rock your world
definitely but then you know by the time
you're sharing it with your friends a
week later you have this big tolerance
to it and they're all just getting their
asses is kicked by it yeah I do the same
thing and and um but still I'll think I
have much tolerance built up to it but
I'll go to smoke it when I want to go to
sleep yeah and I'll just be staring at
the wall for three hours you know just
like oh my gosh like can't can't go to
bed but yeah I like to do some breeding
with the green crack it's a old strain I
found it you know I'm from I'm from
Fresno so it's like a lot of a lot of
good strains a lot of good breeders have
come out of that around that area for
sure that was hay brothers that
originally bred that like blue dream
green cra
yeah yeah a bunch of awesome stuff yeah
it's such a unique strain and so many
people grow it it's really a part of a
part of cannabis history a lot of people
grew it and uh you know and I think it's
just so special
because it grows so much like an indicia
it's so small and it has such a sativa
High yeah it's really really unique
nitrous oxide and beef jerky
yeah the best velous stuff on the planet
yeah no it's it's interesting clamp for
sure yeah just I plan on actually mixing
it with uh Panama Red nice because uh I
actually had it
phos the Green Crack MH and um it's the
furthest a part I know everybody doesn't
like phos or whatever but you know they
kind of fill off a long time ago it's
the furthest apart in the Galaxy yeah I
figure you know there's a lot of
bottlenecking going on like you see the
gelada it's just it's totally crazy and
people don't even realize really what
they're doing to the genetics they don't
understand the genetics well they think
they're making out crosses when they're
in breeding and I think that's one of
the biggest problems today is we get all
these guys that are thinking they're
making new stuff they're they're making
novel stuff and they're not and they're
taken away from the Vigor and they don't
realize you're you're degrading the
genetics you need to find things that
are further apart bring them together
and that's what creates the Vigor and
you find like a special plant like I
make some crosses sometimes I'm just
like man this is this is better than the
the mom and the dad yeah you know what I
mean it's like that's really the goal of
breeding at the end of the day is to
make something better than the and the
dad exactly but you're just like holy
[ __ ] they're complet it's like a
completely new thing it doesn't really
have too much of either Char
accomplished if you make something
better than both of the parents and I
feel like that's where a lot of people
fall short is they make stuff and it's
not better than neither one of the
parents right and they're still they
don't even T put it out there so much
stuff it's a lot of lot of that going on
now we're doing it as a whole within the
industry you know it's like the second
people get fixated on one thing whether
it's candy or whether it's purple or
whether you know we start fixating on
one thing we take away a lot of the
diversity as as an industry and then it
doesn't seem like we're doing it because
everybody's doing it and everyone jumps
on this train and it's not necessarily
the right train right I mean I'm guilty
of it too I have a bunch of gelato
crosses yeah you know what I mean but
it's like at least I'm aware of what's
going on there and well it's what sells
right now right so if you're not
following the trends then you're not
necessarily going to be able to sell
seeds yeah I mean I like to sell taste
the T the weed to taste good when yeah
when I SM smoke it you know what I mean
like a lot of this stuff now I'm just
like oh I feel like uh we could have
hunted this better or you know some of
this stuff is just like not there're
older turps I'm just like where are
these coming from we're already done
with these you know they're branded as
new turps but they've been around for a
long time exactly it's so crazy to hear
some new name on Old I'm like no it's
you know it's uh Jacker is a big one
yeah you know uh well Jack Herer used to
be good people don't understand it's
associated with a bad name but like some
of the Jack the original Jacks that we
were seeing and in the 90s and early
like early 2000s the one I was seeing
was like definitely like more complex it
wasn't so straight trolene limonene
right you know and it definitely got you
ripped off your ass yeah no I don't not
like it it's just when somebody presents
it as something else yeah and then it's
it's clearly this you can't call it that
you cannot call it it's like come on you
know yeah I mean it's blue dream is
another one that got renamed a bunch and
the real blue dream is fire you know I
mean I think it really was the turps got
burnt out you know here in Cali CU so
many people were growing it because it
was so easy to grow you know you're
hitting three AI back on the
double-ended bulbs I mean a single I was
getting 2.2 PBS and like that that back
in the day was like everyone got 1.5 and
then I had gotten 2.2 on that and it was
like I always had the saying that you
could [ __ ] in the reservoir and still
get two pounds of light and with blue
dream you really could I say the same
thing i' be like you could piss on the
on the plant and it'll still come out
good it still come out good it big huge
chunky we doing a like the dwc hydro
back then yeah so let's talk about that
actually we'll dive into that cuz you're
big into the dwc and I think you grow
really good dwc products uh my buddy uh
from Master Yoda he's he's a big dwc guy
as well he wins a bunch of competitions
and stuff and so people people knock it
people knock Hydro they knock three part
they knock all these things but grow you
know weed grown correctly is good weed
you know I feel like weed well is good
good weed I feel like a lot of people uh
on the high Hydro whatever it is
recirculating dwc bubble ponic whatever
it is it's it's all it comes down to the
flush yeah you know and you you can't
it's a short flush and you need to be
flushing with nutrients for a period of
time right and not not just you know
these guys if you give it five seven
days of just water you just ruined your
whole crop yeah you know you go in the
room it's sticky it smells it's good and
then a couple days later it's just dry
and you know I've done it yeah I've done
it I've flushed for too long and um it's
I really feel like it's in the flush and
and really what you're putting in the
system if you have healthy Roots if you
have if your plant is growing healthy
you know it's it's just that little bit
at the end every every medium needs a
different flush yeah you know and I feel
like um I do do the old dwc I do the
General Hydroponics buckets really but I
just made old school with the Halos yeah
with the Halos yeah yeah yeah you know
and uh it's just the the rapid growth
that you get with deep water culture
especially with those Halos you could
totally cheat with the Halos cuz the
water can go down right so the water
level is really important doing dwc and
recirculating but with the Halos it's
totally cheating because the water level
could could almost be empty but as long
as that Halo's still dripping on the top
the plants the plants are still fine I
mean you don't want to do that but so do
you flush with sugars and and like yeah
sugars at the end and magnesium sugar
and just a little
bit I don't really push I just give it
like the regular the regular uh like a
ripen yeah but I just just lower the
ppms yeah just slowly lowering the ppms
all the way down and then uh within that
flush week you know week nine or 10
whatever you decide to do uh it usually
go 63 to 70 days depending on the plant
but a lot of my a lot of my stuff is has
done it 70 days you know so it's a lot
stronger too I feel like the stuff that
goes you know because some of the
genetics I mean it just depends on the
varieties you have but some of the
genetics is like Skittles is like a 53
to 56 Day plant I feel Skittles is so
funny cuz everybody loves Skittles and
it it's like this hash thing and uh it
is really good the turps are just
amazing are good everybody wants these
huge washers right but skills is like
one or two% no it's yeah it doesn't was
it it grows like the worst plant ever
like it it just doesn't want to grow
it's the polar opposite of blue dream
blue dream over here it is the exact
obious like that uh that movie of twins
it's Danny Deo it's Danny Deo it is the
Danny deito of cannabis yeah definitely
yeah that's a great analogy yeah you
know and I think there are some good
Skittle crosses you know you helped me
uh you were you entered in the contest
but you also helped me judge I feel like
much fun to judge everything yeah we had
a lot of good entries in the first and
second place where both Skittle acrosses
on steroids I feel like they were both
stronger than the original yeah and
definitely I wasn't trying to talk bad
about the Skittles is just it really
goes to show that TPS really win in the
end I mean look at that plant it doesn't
wash everybody's washing it doesn't grow
everybody's grow you look at it wrong
and it shrivels up yeah so it's like if
you have the proper TPS you know the
other stuff doesn't matter you know when
we're I'm starting to wash all my
strains and getting into uh into washing
I got um gasman Exotics helping me out
he's a he's big into washing he has a
super good brand that's on the on the
come up right now and he's uh yeah he's
doing great we haven't known him for a
long time I think like 2016 or 17 now
yeah you guys use resend to test for
watch you we have I haven't yet I want
to get into the resin dial I I want to
get one of those for sure it's like a
back order something right now um but
yeah the resin dial is like the next
step but right now you know I'm just
like doing what everybody says you know
how they say you got to it's it's all
funny you know you you put your fingers
on it you do this you see how much comes
off you you want the not the Slicker no
you want the grit right you want the
gritt stuff not greasy you want um they
say like gelato don't wash OG's don't
wash you know stuff like that looks
Frosty cuz the stems you know of the of
the actual Tri Chrome you want you're
looking for like a shorter Tri Chrome
with a bigger head is really that breaks
off easily is is kind of I me not I'm
not an expert don't quote me but it's
kind of more what you or more for the
washing washing side but I'm more into
the TPS I'm going to W you know I'm into
washing all my stuff right now and
getting the proper percentages like to
rosin you know a lot of people are like
oh I got whatever percentage they say 9%
6% uh 19 19% 10% yeah know like all this
crazy stuff I'm just like okay percent
of what is that with the food grade yeah
is that to Hash is or is that pressed
out put in the jars right you know I
want where you know where's that where's
the percentage at you know what I mean
because uh everything that I I'm I'm
doing what's you know the end the end
product you know plus there is a lot of
uh leftover food product like the 160
and the and the uh 40 sure that's what
we make uh like that Edibles we make the
still great for food great for food
great for Edibles all that I'm sure a
lot of people are are mixing it in there
to they get higher percentage and
they're calling it uh full spectrum you
know what I mean I'm just like no like
hold on you're making it sound better
but it's like no it's like you got to
put it in there otherwise it's not full
Spectre it's like yeah right okay yeah
it's funny silly yeah there's a lot of
silly stuff going on in the industry you
know there really is yeah you see a lot
of it on on Instagram is just like you
know a lot of the Instagram breeding is
is crazy the picture breing it's just
it's a lot of uh you know I do my best
to get out there and try to teach people
the right way and and we do a lot of
like hom grower stuff yeah so we try to
really get like new Growers the people
that don't grow you know try to get
people on the page that that don't grow
and then yeah convert him into growing
totally you know what I mean and like be
look this is really easy and I really
try to get them into the deep water
culture uh right off the bat cuz I feel
like it's easy it's I feel like it's
forgiving some people be like it's not
forgiving you know it's really quick
quick but it compared to like soil I fre
I feel like it really is easier to
understand like what's in that bucket if
it's not right you could just dump it
out and it's so funny because I have the
exact opposite feeling because I've
struggled with dwc and and soil has that
buffer and so I like the buffer and then
I like cocoa and I I like the effect of
soil is the main thing but like yeah
it's what you know and on once you've
like mastered it it's very easy whatever
it is right and yeah I have that old
three-part nutrients from uh not the
nutrients the old chart yeah and it just
really works well and it's like really
hard to find online I don't know I don't
know why but um I run that the General
Hydroponics three-part you know in there
and it just it works really well I mean
the growth is just you know three four
weeks I mean I can't grow I can't veg
any longer than that and the plants are
just absolutely huge you know I think
the the biggest one I got was um I mean
I've hit I've hit a pound on the plant
but like consistently is like anywhere
from like 10 oz 12 O you know some 14
but it's like 3 we veg you're getting 10
o on a plant you know it's it's and it's
really fire it's good and and it stinks
you know you do the flush right
everything it comes out and you're
really really here to be like look guys
you could you can still get just as good
as of weed with dwc and yeah I could see
like um Organics being better in the way
of like uh more of a shelf life yeah it
probably has more of longer shelf life
you know and uh and there Organics is is
could be better whatever but it doesn't
mean that dwc is tripless and it's not
good weed no exactly you know I mean
yeah I mean it's all about the grower
too there has a lot to do with the
grower a lot to do with what they're
doing with it and flushing it and all
these things um but a lot of guys they
have stuff that's tasteless too that
that doesn't taste with a lot of tpps
exactly looks amazing and they're giving
everybody else a bad rap right but uh
yeah I've seen a lot of that Organics is
like some of it it's like really good
and some of it's like really just not
that good you know well the funny thing
is is so in the contest that we just
judged which uh the we're I'm announcing
in a couple days but we're actually
filming and this won't be aired for a
couple weeks but we had Coco we had soil
we had dwc so we had Hydroponics all
against each other and the guys who say
living soil is the best hands down they
were wrong as far as what the loudest
Bud was right they was grown in Cocoa
yeah so you know and then the living
soil came in second and you know and and
it's real interesting because you know
people always want to say well this is
the very best way and it's like well
that's the very best way for you right
right it's that's what I really try to
tell like uh people that are starting to
Growing you know we have a yeah like I
said I started the home Growers just
start growing it's like look just
because it's that that guy's doing it
that way or this guy's doing there's a
million different ways you can grow yeah
you just need to find your way like you
can't you're not going to do it exactly
like how I am I'm going to guide you and
you're going to have to find your own
little Groove yeah you know and that's
just how it works for everybody it's not
one one way of growing there's a lot of
different ways and you got to just find
your your way of doing it that you like
to do totally and I mean learning how to
grow in general is just that's an that's
an art and that's probably the best
thing to learn in the beginning is just
how to grow whatever it is just growing
skills it doesn't have to be wheed
either you can grow tomatoes yeah you
can grow you can grow anything I always
run a garden outside with a bunch of
different stuff I I grow I enjoy growing
plants and having a garden and
everything like that it's really
therapeutic you know especially people
are just you know a lot of these guys
that's what they do in their Garden it's
their meditation time you know it's it's
a it's it does a lot of different things
for people not just smoking it growing
it too well and there's there's some
pride and you know people people there's
something special about growing
something and then consuming it whether
you're smoking it or eating it you grow
tomato and you eat that tomato it tastes
extra special that's part of the reason
why everyone thinks they have the best
weed is they grew it and they're like
you know and because there's an
attachment to that plant especially if
you took the time and and like breeding
is the same way but if you're growing a
plant and you've put the days in whether
it's 53 days or 70 days of flower plus
it's a veg you've you've cared for that
plant throughout its entire life and
then consuming it you have a special
relationship with that plant right and
so and not everybody can understand that
but same thing with breeding if you're
taking two things you're Crossing them
together you know breeding is the
marathon right so like it it may take
you years to properly pheno hunt and you
know a year to properly get something
out to where you could even bring it to
Market if you do it correct right but
then that's really special and you
understand the the life that plant and
its parents had and you know you know
what's gone into it yeah you know what's
gone into it and so there's something
special about popping a seed that you
made and seeing it you know to fruition
to where you have flour and that's part
of the beauty and that's why I think
everybody should breed I think I think
there's nothing wrong with people
breeding I think understanding what
you're doing is important but also just
going through the process so you can
understand that fulfillment because I
get fulfillment out of it yeah no
definitely I I encourage everybody to to
make their own seeds and if they have
any questions on how to you know reverse
the plants or anything like that you
know feel free to to ask you know and um
and yeah we we promote you know the hom
Growers to to definitely do do their own
thing and yeah and growing it's like you
know what you you put into that plant
it's and it's like um you're not at the
at the club or buying weed you don't
have no idea what they sprayed on it or
re remediated or whatever that word is
right you know you don't know what's uh
what's on there and if you grow the
plant yourself you grow it up you know
what you put into it the time the effort
you have a a new respect and and uh and
really passion for it I really fell in
love with with growing you know I really
I really liked it when I first started
doing it yeah and it's it's a lot more
challenging than people think but it's
it's very therapeutic at the same time I
mean right I think some people get into
it for the money and then they realize
that it's actual work that's the other
thing it's like this is actual work you
know we're slowly becoming tomato
farmers and I I think tomato Farmers
they deserve a lot of respect yeah you
know it's pretty amazing what tomato
farmers do and I think that cannabis
farmers and tomato Farmers you know it
used to there's this celebrity you know
side of it but that's more or less and
the financial side of it isn't what it
used to be and you know but you can make
a good living whether you're a tomato
farmer or you're a cannabis farmer and
now we can do it legally so yeah it's
been so crazy to see over the last 20
years how Everything's changed in you
know in cannabis it everything uh
rapidly changes all the time rapidly
really quick you know this is the new
strain boom now this is the new strain
it's got to be purple yeah you know it's
just like and seeing uh like the wax uh
you know evolve from us you know you
know blowing butane through a PVC PVC
pipe you know what I mean like in 2006
or seven and to where we got the rosin
now it's like it's totally crazy to to
see it all come through yeah and it was
just all the different techniques along
the way right you know I was there in
the beginning where we we had to go
through all the techniques and it was
really quick oh what are you doing now
to how oh how did you make the pull and
snap or how did you yeah we didn't have
dab eggs back in the day we smoked them
on coals or whatever you put it inot hot
knif hot knife legendary hot knives man
I love the hot knives that's yeah that's
a that's a day
wrecker the first time you got to be
careful of those yeah so for those of
you that don't know hot knifing is where
you hot knives from your parents drawer
from the silverware drawer and you put
them on the stove till they're red hot
and I wouldn't do with rosin but you use
old school hash yeah hash and uh a paper
towel tube or whatever kind of tube you
can I think people have done it with
straws but the paper towel tube is ideal
because you can kind of put the knife
tips as you smash and put it in there
and then just get this big huge hot
gigantic
dab yeah and cough typically super hot
you're just like oh God yeah I think we
got to the point where we weren't
getting to coughs like we didn't cough
you know we got to but but then our
friends did you know I've told the story
about my buddy who he just got so wasted
and then went out and sat in his car
yeah it's like giving somebody their
first dab I used to do it all I was
making the dabs back in like 0 708 like
super early on you know come to your
house they be like Oh I'm going to you
know kind of they're down you know I
wanna I want to like what are you doing
take a dab you know check it out you
know you want to give them a big old dab
but they're like going to chill and
smoke a blunt and buy a sack you know
they're going to hang out just give them
this big huge Destroyer dab all red hot
they hit it you can just see them you
know their whole face they're just you
could see them get high you know their
eyes start watering instantly their ears
are purple yeah like oh I gotta go and
they just they just out here didn't buy
any wheed or nothing they just cut out
yeah with the old dabs we use titanium
too it's like those things you get that
titanium nail real hot it started out
with the little glass the stupid the
swing arm and the glass nail and then we
we thought we really upgraded when we
got the titanium nail right totally we l
like a chest piece originally the quartz
Little Nail we quartz nail right so we
had the quartz nail and then that was
like the first rigs that the quartz nail
would go in and you had the little thing
over the top of it or whatever it's so
crazy to think we were smoking that the
oh yeah yeah I was I was making a lot of
a lot of BHO with
PVC we finally got the glass but yeah
open blasting and did you whip Ed like
Pyrex dishes well that was the thing we
had to figure it all out at first we
didn't wild we first we didn't yeah it
was Pyrex glass we' double boil it and
we like okay if you do this it turns it
yellow you know like we don't know you
know we finally finally figured out you
know we were always not letting it
finish it would always be goopy so I
would just leave it in that hot plate
keep longer and longer and longer and
then it finally would would turn in turn
a wax wax that's how you got the ear wax
butter wax like ear it looked like ear
wax that's why everybody called it ear
wax but yeah once I figured that out it
was over yeah and uh getting slabs as
long as your arm big old chunks yeah and
then after that came like the you know
like shatter and stuff they're putting
it in the The Purge The Purge ovens and
you got the
ovx slabs in the pizza boxes you know
all about that I all about yeah we got
the pizza boxes you have a long history
with pizza boxes I bet yeah yeah
definitely lots of slabs been in the
pizza boxes but yeah that's not how we
we came up with that idea yeah our brand
is uh is pizza Italian involved you know
what I mean my my character is like a
pizza guy you I dress up as him and
where did that evolve from so um it
really evolved from about like
201617 uh I started going to the seses
you know it's before we were like you
know grow everything's a secret I don't
want to know you get away you know like
I just sell the pack to this guy and get
out of here I'll buy it from this guy
you know but now we're like coming out
Instagram and totally you know so I got
a brand I got a a big tint I put this
logo on it right um and it and we
started going to the seses and everybody
thought I was freaking a pizza guy yeah
you know everybody would come up to the
booth and this is before I had this logo
here yeah you know I just had this logo
and big tent and everything and
everybody would come up to the booth
thinking we had pizza for sale you know
like and they're like hey so how much
for a slice I just like yeah we don't
have any pizza right and they would
freaking walk away you know so I was
just like thinking and it happened like
a couple times a couple sessions and I
didn't do very good at the sesh you know
yeah I was like what the hell I got to
come up with I got to figure something
out here so I was like you know I was
just online looking at different
packaging a pizza box came up you put
your logo on it I was like ah I'm just
going to do the pizza box and so I got
the pizza box I was like all right what
am I going to do they come to the booth
like I'm just going to put some weed in
here and some seeds and some wax seeds
you know uh to just to try to lure them
in you know what I mean so they would
come up to the booth and and they would
be like yeah well where's the pizza you
know sure enough you know the next week
I'd be like oh I got some right here you
know I turn around I get I get the box
and and you know I open it up and and
they're like oh you know it's pretty
cool it was like a conversation starter
and then they tried the stuff you I'd
have them because my main goal back then
when I first started coming out was uh
and always is to have uh you know a
really loud fire strin that people was
was really distinctive to smell so I
would have it the SES right the bud mhm
and the the wax that I made I made it
you know grew it myself made the wax
myself and then I'd have the seeds
available so I'd be like all right take
the take a dab free dab you everybody's
taking a dab they like oh it's so good
all right look take a smoke some of the
weed oh man it's buy the Seed I don't
grow well hey we could teach you how to
grow you know and I got a lot of people
growing like that and uh it's just
satisfying to see people grow your stuff
out and really come back and be like man
that was really good and i' you know I
started growing and and they have a big
old huge room now you know that's really
how the the pizza box came and then I
came up with this this guy and I dress
up as him and nice and that's really the
whole story there that's pretty awesome
yeah I like I like the diecut packaging
I feel like it's simple it's cost
effective and uh yeah I mean it's it's
great diecut is in for one thing but
like these are you can put a thousand of
these in one little box right I have
some other packaging too like boxes and
I have some standup packs where it's
like a it's really like a dab container
yeah but it has seeds in it and it just
doesn't work for like the seed banks and
people like oh you know I could only fit
like two of them in a little package
right so it's like to get a big order
for them to hold it at the the seed
banks or whatever it just takes up too
much room and these are perfect I I
really like these a lot of time I put in
a really good guy that uh designed those
for me it's the even the seed that I'm
holding is like a reflective yeah yeah
it's you know I like I like that uh I
like you know details on everything you
know I want to have details I want to
have the best stuff you know that's why
we always started to have that's why I
started growing and want to make my own
stuff because I had so much access
access you know living in Fresno back
then to really good bud I'm interested
about uh snow beef because I'm not a
huge fan of apple fritters because it
smells amazing but I feel like the smell
doesn't carry over in the the the smoke
right if you're smoking a joint of it
but like I always say apple fritters
Oreos purple punch they're one step away
from being good I mean I just feel I'm
not fan of purple punch at all no I
purple punch yeah uh what's the other
one uh Oreos Oreos one I'm thinking of
Oreos uh purple punch yeah it's just
like oh my goodness it's a picture weed
you know it's great on Instagram it
looks amazing they make some decent they
make some really good crosses I think
they yeah I mean that Dante's Inferno I
think it's kind of the same might out a
little bit or whatever but like I think
it's as far as the genetics are concern
man it's got a really unique nose on it
and I could smell the Oreos in there a
little bit but it's got It's it's got
something it's got something and it's
not Oreos I like it much better than
Oreos yeah I grew that in my greenhouse
and I I wasn't really a fan of the Dante
cuz it it was just the weakest genetics
in there it was the first one yeah to go
you know and right and uh I just I'm
about strong genetics I want to bring
back the the rigidity of of the plant
you know like right like um the Green
Crack you know it it's like a pretty PM
resistant you know and I really worked a
lot of strains for the East Coast
outdoor Growers and I really focused on
that for the last couple years right and
I feel like nobody's doing that anymore
nobody's really going on the effects
nobody you know sure the TPS they're
just going off of pictures and and names
and it's just uh it's not the way to do
it you know no and I mean everything you
know we have these es and flows in in
every facet of life and we're we're in
the gelato phase right now and the cany
phase where people are really locked in
but I also see OG making a comeback and
I also see hazes popping up here and
there I seen the piff and the Cuban
black and you know some some old school
Haze I feel like they're making some
comebacks and I feel like definitely the
haze on the East Coast the piff all that
you were saying the other day you you
were smoking some piff yeah I like piff
I love the I love the effect from the
piff right and I like the taste I The
Taste is fantastic you know it smoks
good to the roach it's another one of
those yeah important yeah and it's
subtle but it's it's one of those subtle
TPS it's got subtle tping profile smokes
good down the roads and it has it still
kind of has a ceiling compared to some
hazes you smoke some of the hazes
that'll you know they just kick you kick
you in the dirt there's no coming back
you no I definitely see uh the ogs and
the hazes coming back for the smokers
people that you know like the heavy
smoke sour and they're tired of all the
cookie you know whatever all the cookie
crosses or the just didn't degraded or
like the purple punch you know it just
doesn't get you high like we want to get
high anymore I mean I wouldn't be I
wouldn't be too upset if cookies made it
come back too like the real cookies the
real cookies I really like that I have
some crosses with cookies I'm not a
cookie hater at all but it's just the
real cookies you know not water down sh
diet cookies diet Skittles they're not
for me no man it's like it's just it's
real crazy to see yep you're like oh
this is cooking like no this isn't this
is not cookies bro yeah like the real
original when it first started coming
around was just the cut fishing the cut
fishing has been so rampit over the last
10 years especially with so many
different things uh especially nurseries
wanting to sell stuff
and you know not all of them you know
there there's good nurseries and bad
nurseries but there's been a lot of cut
fishing and other problems like uh seed
junkie selling wedding cake seeds and
then we got 30 different fenos because
there's a lot of different I mean
there's literally 30 different
expressions of of wedding cake right and
there's there's a good one there's maybe
a few good ones there's lots of yeah you
could right there's that one cut
everybody well a lot of people put out
the separate cuts and they hoard the the
best cut for El it's been a practice in
C forever you know since 196 whatever
yeah it's like you know it's yeah that's
what's been going on and to get those
real cuts and and uh to actually breed
with those real Cuts is is important and
that's something I strive to do yeah so
as far as like the genetics you you
talked about Green Crack but what else
were you working with back in the day
you you guys had some hazes I'm sure
yeah when I was just messing around
making seeds I was just making them for
myself you know I had a super silver
haze I had the uh original like purple
Urkel the one that would turn solid
purple like smaller plant real smaller
plant yeah the the super silver haze had
that one big Cola you know I mean but I
was just trying to learn you know really
how to make seeds I didn't really put
any of those out that was just for
myself like the super silver like it
burns your nose kind of like where you
actually have like literally the THS
burn your nose yeah it was really good I
always thought oh this plant this is so
funny cuz I got it right when I first
started started growing yeah and uh and
I learned a lot since then but I would
think uh I always thought the plant
sucked because it had the main Cola and
like I didn't have a proper environment
room so it would mold the main Cola
would mold every time i' like cut it off
and the I mean it was good smoke around
the thing man this plant molds it sucks
no this was actually my fault you know
better grower it was a great plant you
know so it it was this funny stuff
learning stuff like that along the way
just trial and error you know I've done
a lot of trial and error and um I think
that's the best
that's the best way to learn I feel like
a lot of people get almost bombarded
with the amount of information that's
out there nowadays totally you know and
so crazy you know the last 20 years how
much has changed going going from no
information like when we started doing
the BHO yeah making rosin and stuff or
not rosin but wax you know there was you
couldn't look up a YouTube video it
would there was nowhere to find any
information I think the first time it
came out was like in High Times Like '
05 and then that's when people started
trying to blow themselves up and yeah
you yeah I think K from triome
Technologies wrote a paper about butane
extraction in 1998 I believe he was the
first and it kind of slowly caught on um
after that but yeah it was like early
2000s people were doing it on the under
yeah you know it was like and then it
was like Wax butter wax that was pretty
much it uh or bubble has there lots of
bubble hash back then yeah definitely
the bubble hash all that all that stuff
and there's people I still see people
making some really good bubble has
nowadays too I love I love bubble hash
you know I love I love the taste of
bubble has I like putting in my joints I
like you know I mean the same thing with
sift I got some amazing sift here too oh
yeah and uh yeah I love good dry sift
it's it's hard to find right that's I
always use the the trim bins yeah you
know you know get when I was doing seeds
we always I mean I had a 50 lighter we
were doing seeds and we I always use the
trim bins for the stuff and I would end
up with big huge I use the ice cream or
the aotto containers the clear ones with
the black tops yeah and we put them in
there and and then i' you know I'd cure
them out and then put them in there and
put them in the freezer oh nice pull out
these awesome blocks of uh sift oh
that's awesome that's funny it's block
of sift even the Autoflower like the
Autoflower sift was phenomenal so but
you're getting a mix of plants it's not
like one phenotype so right yeah you're
getting you're getting everything with
the autoflowers you can't really can't
take clones of them and no but the more
Generations you have the more stable
they get right the the more even the
profile is the less muddled it becomes
yeah you got to actually really breed
them yeah I tell people I was like you
gota just don't buy Autos off anybody
you know that they're just starting to
don't understand well if you take a lot
of good Autos out there there are good
Autos 100% I make amazing Autos I think
there's a lot of people that make them
not a lot I think uh em seeds is he
makes some really really nice stuff yeah
yeah but typically if you take even if
you take two autos and you breed those
together that doesn't mean you're going
to get good stuff A lot of times it's
just the opposite right you have to do
some refinement you have to do you know
a couple generations of work at the very
least yeah no definitely there's a lot
of work that goes into the into breeding
Autos I see that there's come a long
ways too from when they first yep from
it first came out now like a lot of
people that really put the work into I
hate it I hate lot of people are just
like no they they suck I hated I hated
autos and Mesto changed all that B man
big up some Mesto they really they paved
the way for the rest of us that are
making good autoflowers if it wasn't for
Mesto uh Tim and Mitch killing it you
know yeah D those guys are amazing we
wouldn't be here today without them in
the Autoflower world right so a lot of
people don't give them the proper credit
they deserve but like the autoflowers in
Europe back in the early 2000s 2010 even
2012 they were mediocre at best and
they've they've changed so much the
whole European scene has changed with
utof flowers right but like good
smokable products I mean it's still an
easy plant to grow otof flowers are easy
if you want something if you want to
grow something outside and you have no
experience or you want to grow something
like you'd even put one in your window
sill sort of right window something like
that I see people there's a
misconception I feel like that it's
easier to grow than a regular photo
period in a tent I just like that's just
I don't feel like that's the truth yeah
you know what I mean I feel like Photo
period is is almost easier you know to
to grow you know more what's going on
than an Autoflower I don't know I could
be wrong I've I've never grown really
I've grown like maybe one Autoflower One
Time by accident but I just don't see
like everybody says that there's all
these it grows faster and it does this
and that I just don't well it definitely
is more vigorous right so like the thing
is is like if you even look at the the
seed
start a week later when you basically
germinate it like if you don't
transplant it right away you're going to
get that it's going to get rootbound
right away oh
really so but it has a smaller basically
the root ball is so much it's typically
a lot smaller than a photo period plant
and you're getting a tap rout with it as
opposed to typically if you're clone
growing course yeah the tap there's
definitely some differences but I feel
like it I I think Autos are really easy
to grow you know if you it's fairly you
know you follow steps they come out
really good for somebody who's a no
novice but photo periods are also great
for novices too it just depends on what
you want to do I prefer 20 hours of
light with my flowers indoors I feel
like I get the best results giving them
20 with four hours of sleep nice 20 yeah
20 light 4 Hour Darkness I get the best
results and then same thing with seeds I
get way more seeds when I do it that way
really when I'm breeding yeah like sign
significantly more oh wow so 20 20 hours
on yeah 20 hours on gotta love that
electrical bill like yeah I was thinking
like 20 hours on man yeah that's pretty
that's a long time doubling your bill
there doubling up on the bill you know
yeah but back to this no beef uh you
know uh it has a really unique smell uh
gasman is the one that actually bred it
and he he gave me the his cut and and
the Mel yeah and I've I've uh made the
f2s and we're working together you know
to make a lot of a lot of strains and
it's a zcube and a meat breath a cookie
do dominant uh male yeah with Z cube is
cross and uh it you know it dumps really
good 5% four to 5% Y and uh you know it
comes out really well I brought some we
could try it out and I also brought um
the second place dab right yeah yeah um
and the Seventh Place Eco Clash yeah
that Z Cube's all right it's all right I
I honestly I never really liked the
zcube it was smaller and I didn't really
like the anything that has Skittles TPS
it's the most interesting thing when you
breed Skittles with something you want
you you don't even need to uh smell them
you look for the shittiest plants in the
room that's a skittles cross that lean
Skittles you know it's like you know I
mean he did a really good job because
the plant is nothing like that it
doesn't grow I mean it's very vigorous
the way it grows you got nice big buds
it's super Frosty I mean I show you a
picture of it it's just crazy yeah yeah
and it does it it smokes good and it and
it presses out you know we right I made
about 30 crosses with it now we're
hunting through those and getting those
out to to the testers yeah so is it
candy still or where do the I would say
it's like a little bit of candy yeah you
know in the flavor you could taste it in
the back back end but it's more like uh
really gassy it's real gassy and it has
a really distinct uh its own kind of
it's own kind of flavor you know what I
mean I don't want to say it's like a
white truffle flavor because it's not
it's it's but it's has that gasing I
don't really like white truffle yeah you
know the the the TPS on it you know for
sure but um I have the Ruffles with it
white Shuffle mixed with Skittles again
of course and that's really good you
know it came out amazing and that's uh
can of research uh and fresh Coast
collaboration so z Snow beef do you know
where you got the name because when I
think of snow beef I think of wagu from
Japan and that's my favorite that's well
the strain was originally named wagu
zagu with the Z zwag you know every puts
the Z on it it was this is wagu and and
but this particular feno that we have he
he named is no beef yeah and it has it
just has this special turp to it yeah I
believe snow beef comes from Hokkaido
it's a cold region and that is some of
the best wagu in the world right that's
what he's going for we're going for we
want to make the best stuff we're coming
for that top Spot Not only wagu it's the
best wagon it's the best you know that's
what we want to have the best TPS we
want to have the strongest TPS we want
to have the best stuff in the jar we're
coming you know nice we're do we're
working together to make that happen you
know he's he's on the top of his his
game and and making the Ros and I want
to get the the proper results back like
what this pressed at what it smells like
yeah you know without any you know
having to mess to find a good guy that's
making rosin that I could give my
product to and right and trust him and
everything I known him for years you
know it's and we both have the same
goals to make the best product possible
you know I'm not looking to get the most
out of my plants I'm looking to get the
best sure and that's really what we base
everything off of is just the best we
wanted to we wanted to dump too
eventually but that's like the last
right you know we're going for the turps
quality over quantity all day yeah if we
can get it to dump at the same time
that's that's all the better nice you
know what I mean so absolutely yeah it's
uh it's I'm excited for what we got
coming up and uh with all with all the
strains you know I have a lot of a lot
of good cuts that I got you know I'm
lucky enough to to got to have been able
to meet and get cuts from like like HBK
yeah uh you know he's made like the
Chile Verde MH and I still have his
chile verde Skittles actually that he
gifted me before he went to Thailand oh
wow yeah and uh I was lucky enough to
meet him and I've gotten a lot of cuts
from him like I got the real Papaya real
dual papaya from him and yeah actually
you know we became really good friends
and and U I got his Greenhouse before he
actually
went that's another one that's been
renamed a bunch but the real Papaya so
fire it really is I was just so lucky to
get it from him Jack wise especially
it's one of those xjack smokers and then
I I see it named other things like I'm
like no no exactly that's papaya it's
unmistakable it's it's very unique and
really good it definitely really is it
was you know it's still still one of my
favorites and it's been popular for four
or five years now yeah and you see a lot
of brands with Papaya in their xjack
lineup you know because it's good it
washes well and it [ __ ] smokes
amazing yeah I mean the original
original original one doesn't really
wash that really you know when I you
know it came out probably like 2 3% at
the best you know and everybody's like
oh Papaya's a 5% washer when it's just
really not the real real d one the pink
hair you know you know when you got it
cuz it's got the F1 pink hair you know
and um a lot of people crossed it
because it just doesn't press well yeah
you know I um it's like 40% in the in
the Press we lo you know we lose so it's
like for the real deal one but you cross
it you know and and you know a lot of
people have crossed it and it and it and
it dumps you know what I mean it does
dump more but you're losing that turp
you're losing that that's what it's all
about that turp it's really you need
really hunted they're hunting it for the
percentage and and you need to be
hunting it for the bread percentage with
the tur without taking the turp 100%
it's cuz it's all about that with Papaya
it tastes like papayas like real it's
got a real Papaya flavor real yeah yeah
I just mixed it with the my strawberries
it's coming out of testing right now
like stra the strawberry feno have is um
it's green crack Dosey Do uh Cherry Pie
and and uh gelato it's that sweet thing
from archives mhm and I'm just lucky
enough to find a feno that smells like
real strawberries like a freshly picked
strawberries it's hard it's hard to find
real like specific berries especially
strawberry like a lot of times berries
Al lean we got the raspberry boogies and
the loud Berry is right it's just like
berries it's like a allaround berryy
smell but to get a specific smell in
there it's like I've I've been real
lucky to to look for those and and to
find them you know I have I have a
rotten peaches it's just pure Peach uh
peach candy to like uh almost like burnt
rubber oh yeah it has the burnt rubber
in there from the gorilla glue and and
uh and same thing with the the rotten
pineapples they're they're just sisters
you know they're I just uh two fenos I I
named differently from the different
ways they grow right you know that comes
from the pie maker fenos where they're
just it's a special plant you know every
feno is really good and and really
different most of them at least nice so
what are we going to start smoking on
let's take it let's take some dabs um
like I said I got the I got the first
place or the second place um at the dab
right competition just a couple weeks
ago sounds great the tractor fuel yep
that
U that gas man entered I I didn't have
anything I didn't grow him or have
anything to do with uh yeah I didn't
grow him or have anything to do with um
breeding them or anything like that it's
just him
um it was just him entering enter
uh stuff that he wanted me to bring
and um and show you guys some some fire
that we're going to be working on yeah
and now a special message from our
sponsors hey it's the best seeds in town
beity Boppity seeds so good make your
mustach fly
[Music]
off all right so you want to check them
out yeah yeah yeah let's yeah there's no
beef I haven't had that in the fridge
for about a week it smells like OG cush
it smells really good it smells really
good fire gas to it it's super it's
really nice take this and stir Stir It
Up yeah give it a good stir some Earth
and some Pine
yeah I really like the gassiness of it
oh yeah it's super
Savory it's good really really
nice
yeah I mean this reminds me of like
original OG Kush gas super turpy like I
I love it
yeah wow nice Definitely I'm all into
the cold
starts cold starts I'm gonna get you a a
real dab I said cold starts are for
girls and that's fine yeah that's okay
that's okay old people I'm old like old
people and women yeah n yeah have you
been on that show hot dabs yet no I
haven't hot dabs get this guy on hot
dabs he's into the hot dabs I like the
hot dabs he's ready come in my outfit
this is my Alter Ego here bring some
pizza yeah bring some pizza everywhere I
go you
know the pizza gang guys we have a huge
following shout out to the pizza gang
yeah uh big big time following on on
Instagram and yeah you have a nice group
and you guys go live a lot yeah yeah Die
Hard Die Hard people out there shout out
to all them yeah
even even the haters especially the
haters no shout out to you guys big
shout out to all the haters yeah big
shout out thank you for giving me a
motivation yeah definitely you're my
biggest fan yeah I rent space in your
head for free let's yeah Instagram the
Mean Streets of Instagram is uh pretty
you want a smaller dab right oh yeah
yeah I'm that's perfect yeah all right
yeah I I like taking small dabs so I can
take a bunch of them I'd rather take
something like this size and take five
or 10 dabs definitely especially when
it's this type of quality yeah you don't
need a huge dab you you can tell the
difference of the good stuff yeah for
sure especially you're taking a huge
fatle like it's like okay yeah when it's
all red hot rethink what you're doing
here
but you no less than 800
Degrees let meat this up real quick I
got the the man torch yeah this is the I
feel like the best way to take a dab
is the dab right with the TP slurper is
y is by far my
favorite
um I just it's I mean I took a lot of
dabs a lot of ways and I feel like uh
this is the best way and uh I you know I
let it get really let it get down a ways
you know what I mean like I'd like to
take them colder too but I don't like to
take cold starts cuz I feel like cold
starts are almost hotter than yeah what
I what I like to dab at yeah I go 375 to
400 and yeah exactly same here real cold
where it's not like sizzling when you
put it in there I want it to just to
melt just like that yeah there you go
perfect damn that's good it is really
good dude the
smell rocks when the beauty of it being
so smooth it doesn't make you cough at
all and you get full flavor it's like
yeah it's full full flavor he did he
does an amazing job you know he's he's
show me his whole process I get to I get
to go there with them we're making this
stuff together and and super nice cool
guy uh he's definitely going to make his
Mark he's coming up he's already made a
mark in the industry but I got to I know
he's going to he's going places second
place you know once you try that that
tractor Fu I forget who who made it or
the cross on it right now but um it is a
really nice yeah I really want to try
the tractor feel it's actually
DMT set you you said got you on the air
the air
D yeah I started out that way I I took
LSD 10 times before I smoked weed for
the first time and I ran cross country
in high school and so I didn't want to
[ __ ] my lungs up I'm like well this
little paper can't [ __ ] my lungs
up wow yeah you know 10 times later take
with you the devs with nice yeah totally
and yeah I started smoking weed after
that and being in California like
yourself there's access to really good
weed yeah it's I got really lucky early
on um able to to find a a guy that was
really
um had the best stuff you know and I got
I got a good name of of uh you know
having the best best weed around because
of them you know and it was like you
show up oh you got the best stuff but
then it's like somebody else grew this
and it really really got me thinking uh
you know who's growing this where is it
coming from you know it's a big secret
back then you know where the seeds come
I remember getting a bag of weed and
just praying that there's a seed bag
seed in it you know like there we had no
access like we do now and it's do se's
back in the day were always great yeah
they were always great and it's you know
you get a really fire sack of weed you
know you're never going to see the weed
again you know so much good weed came
and gone like so fast like the phases of
purple so many good purples and then all
the kushes like all the phases of kushes
I the master cush was amazing dude like
the real old school Master Hindu Kush
that was called uh can't remember the
nickname for it but it was an HK and it
was super super super fire not like the
typical stuff that you're seeing today I
feel like it was super special yeah
exciting times I miss all the old
strains I'm I like the new ones too I
mean there's some really great new ones
for sure there's a lot of really good
stuff like um you know it's always good
when you hear the hype strains I'm
always you know you you see the purple
punch and then you see you know uh Oreos
yeah and then you're like okay what's
next so what's Popp oh apples and
bananas is it going to be another dud
and then you get it you're like oh [ __ ]
this is actually really good yeah you
know Banas good one for sure yeah know
finally you know this is actually a good
a good hype stram you know I mean
they're hit and miss but there's some
really good ones there's some really you
know average ones
too gotta love the
mustache
they got baby
dabs but yeah I really like dabbing I
you know fell in love with with dabbing
and making dabs and yeah and uh I just
got out of it I focus more on breeding
nice you know and let let those guys
really take off right experts you know
that's the beauty of the current scene
is is you don't have to do everything
and as you grow and
have a company you really become a
specialist in what you're good at and
you can hire people that are good at
what they're good at and everybody works
synergistically together yeah no
definitely like this podcast here we got
Ryan behind the cameras and we got Ben
helping out and yeah your setup here is
is next level I'm really impressed with
with everything you guys are doing here
especially the grow and what I see that
you guys are going to do here is just
going to be next level you know it's uh
it's exciting to see you know the work
that's going going into and everything
it's a lot of fun too yeah it's a lot of
work but it's a lot of fun I mean I
think I I'm just blessed to be here
doing what I'm doing now could be a lot
worse you want pick another one yeah
we're gonna go with uh some what's this
Ruffles stuffles or the where's the
tractor fuel that's the some tractor
tractor fuel I mean you guys check that
out really
nice and uh he does a really good job on
does all the the all the logos and
everything
himself all right tractor
fuel this has got second place at uh the
dab right competition oh nice
yeah about a quarter of
that especially I can tell you this
one's strong just by the smell it's got
some power to it yeah it's definitely
stronger I wish I could remember who who
bred it and the cross that were on it
but um I'm sure I I could find out for
you I feel like it's
pretty yeah turpy it's got a good good
tur profile it definitely has the best
um it's almost like you know you want it
to transfer over that one almost
transfers over more yeah in the smell I
feel like into the flavor yeah and
that's the that's when you got stuff
like that it's magical that's theic
exactly that's what you're looking for
if it tastes better than it smells
you're on to something it's the first
time you've done the dabs on on the on
the show you are the First with the dabs
on the show all right I'm proud yeah
bringing the dabs yeah I think we got
some we got some episodes coming up
where we'll definitely be doing DS for
you're the first yeah that's sweet I'm
glad to bring it like uh like I said gas
man's really good friend of mine and we
plan on doing a lot of work together
nice yeah I really like his step oh here
you
go be all right
right
you're
right that is the best flavor I've had
in a dab in a long time like
literally it's it smells good it smells
unique but it
tastes tastes super good it it tastes
better than it smells I feel like you
know stronger
well very good it smells very good too
but yeah and it's got this nice floral
character along with it it's not Rose
it's not your
typical floral profile right but it's
got like a little bit of sweetness and a
little bit of
floral and uh yeah almost there's a
little soapiness to it too like in a
good way not like right the reminds me
of like childhood right
right
what's your opinion on the sprayed
turps uh I don't know I feel like that's
like a East Coast thing I don't know
it's a weird thing that's like we don't
have to worry about like that same thing
with the uh the TCA the
Snowballs I don't know if you've seen
the snow cap or the Snowballs where they
they uh shake the bag and put it in oh
yeah putting uh they they're putting the
the weed in a bubble bag with dry ice
totally and shaking it yeah I don't know
what that that was like a thing there
for a little bit I guess no no it's back
it's back in full force it's back in a
bad way I don't understand why you can't
it's it's not that hard just to make
this I mean it it's not easy yeah but
the basics of it you know these guys
have refined it you know serpent
temperature certain everything you know
it's it's real special to be getting it
this good right but the basics of it is
better than sticking dry ice in a bag
and you know I don't know I don't I
don't agree with a lot of weird stuff on
the The Mean Streets of Instagram oh
yeah yeah it's it's kind of strange I
think a lot of people want to create a
product that's different right and
they're willing to sacrifice quality for
one thing or they have inferior quality
and so they want to make their product
better in their opinion right more
marketable right it's like just just
make better products you know just make
better products just do better just do
better just do better that goes for
everybody including myself like let's
just do better yeah
exactly that's what we're striving out
here to do yeah that's the right
mentality I think and to teach you know
that's why I really want to you know
teach uh the new people that are growing
you know the right way about it and yeah
and uh kind of the older way I guess you
would say and uh really promote the
homeg Growers I can't can't really say
it enough uh that homeg growing is is
very important and everybody should be
doing it like you said making your seeds
and everything like
that yeah I think homeg growing I think
it's all great I think do do whatever
you're passionate about just do that and
you know I think the world's a better
place if you do what you're passionate
if you're doing what you're meant to be
doing here I think uh it's pretty
amazing yeah it's awesome to to be able
to do what you you know
really uh want to do you know I feel
really blessed you know um I got a shout
out you know my wife and and everybody
that holds it together and you know we
got a we got a good business going here
but you know she's you I'm not computer
smart or anything like that you know so
it's like it's behind the scenes stuff
going on you know she came up with the
logos and like what to do type of stuff
and nice a lot of help you know I'm not
doing it just all by myself but no and
that's the real world when when you
start getting stuff it's not it's a team
effort on so many levels dude like I you
know I mean people see the podcast it's
a team effort you see what I do here
it's a [ __ ] fully team effort I mean
there's a lot of important components
that you know fill the gaps and that's
as you grow with everything that's it
you know and I love working as a team I
love I mean I know that I can't do it
all by myself um but I love when the
team comes together and like you're a
fine-tune machine and stuff happens and
you know there's es and flows with
everything
but yeah definitely um yeah Teamworks
everything it's it's why you know I have
such a good support on Instagram and
working with a lot of a lot of people
lot lot of stuff I got coming up too I
can't really talk about that working
with some people right now and so we got
a lot of stuff planned for this year
going to be some real exciting stuff
that I'm real happy before we stuff
we've been working on for a long time so
it's like I'm really going to go you
know everybody's like I'm going going
hard in 24 it's like but like yeah we've
been planning for this we're not just
like oh it's 2024 now now we're going to
start going now it's like been building
up for it
and Luigi's Gonna Get You Know I got a
lot of [ __ ] for wearing this you're the
bad guy in Mario Brothers I'm going to
tell you everybody they made me put it
on
okay no a lot I get a lot of stuff for
it uh you know good and bad you know a
lot of people want to take you know it's
good I do it for the for the fans take
pictures and uh you know a lot of people
recognize me at the from being live and
and stuff like that at the at the events
it's just uh I like to have a good time
you know I hate people that are so
serious all the time and it's just not
having fun with it and this and that you
know it's like we like to get out there
and have a good time and and like yeah I
just wanted to you know talk about the
pizza gang really quick they're all over
I mean we got people all over the world
and it's really nice that I'm able to go
to New York and Michigan and uh stay at
people's houses for free and and U them
to show me around and you know
definitely Shout Out New York and
Michigan definitely uh you know we went
to the hash bash a couple times now
we've we've gone out to New York a bunch
of times and nice it's cool to travel
around and and actually meet the people
that you're talking to on Instagram you
know face to face and get people to come
and and talk to you and tell you you
know the best thing feeling is like oh
you grew your seeds and you know it
really changed my grow and it really
helped me out or it really for sure you
know uh you know they're just like
thanking you it's like really uh
satisfying it makes you feel good you
know what I mean so if people are
looking for you how can they find you
Tino genetics.com is the website also uh
Instagram there's a lot of fake accounts
yeah you got like seven real ones too we
got yeah so it's like yeah you got to
fight the haters you know but it's just
tinos genetics tinos with the S genetics
3 would be my main account or 55 tinos
genetics 559 yeah would be like uh my
main
[Music]
account yeah very floral very good yeah
the best thing I like is how clean and
smooth it is you know you can tell has
been made well I feel like the turps are
through the roof though like if you were
to look at the percentage of TPS in
there it's super chirpy yeah very good
yeah super good another place they could
find me is uh on um Darkstar nice darkar
uh genetics he has a really nice oh yeah
seed bank that's a that's all the spots
fantastic thank you for coming on the
show today man I really uh look forward
to hanging out again and uh let's do
some dabs let's smoke some weed I get
some more tests definitely right on
thank you very much thank you
[Music]
yeah