[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James loud
podcast today my special guest is Jason
Hadley from Lighthouse how are you doing
today Jason I am fantastic and it is an
honor and a pleasure to be here thank
you for having me yeah man so we've
known each other a while uh I met you
through uh I want to say we got
connected through Autumn carsy I think
that name maybe Autumn yeah that that
sounds right she's been on the podcast
before right I isn't it crazy how just
like this huge industry but such a small
world I mean it's a little bit
incestuous but you know a good way in a
good way right yeah I mean you're right
I mean because Alabama's not legal right
at this
point they legalized
you so why don't you tell everybody a
little bit about yourself and how you
get your start in the Cannabis industry
yeah for sure um so again you know my
name is Jason Hadley I'm I'm currently
with a company called filter that's
owned by Lighthouse worldwide Solutions
and it's just sort of a funny way that
you like fall into cannabis I was not
one of those I was not the cool kid in
class right and so at some point um I
didn't really discover cannabis until
probably like maybe my senior year of
high school you know and uh and it was
funny because like one when I first
started smoking like it was like close
to the last day of school in high school
and wouldn't you know it who do I see
smoking weed in his park in the parking
lot school but like this rival guy that
used to bully me all the time right and
then it turns out I see him he sees me
we lock eyes and I look at him and I'm
like dude I'm not gonna bust you and we
sat there and we smoked a Dube in the
school parking lot together I've never
seen him since but everything was
squashed in that moment it was just oh
it was wonder that was like one of those
moments where I was like man this thing
really brings people together you know
what I mean like it's one of the few
drugs you do in a circle right for sure
nobody's ever nobody's ever like got
cocaine on a lazy Susan right well not
not in this country maybe right right
anyway but so you know I go to college I
do the rig rule I you know buy the
American dream Hook Line and Sinker type
of thing I'm in a sales job I get laid
off and then a buddy of mine while I was
collecting unemployment a buddy of mine
was like hey do you want to come trim
weed for me or with me for a grower I
know it's cash under the table this was
the Legacy Market days so I was like uh
yeah sure I would love it and um so I go
and I meet this guy Sky Hank if you're
familiar with Sky Hank at all from smoke
mirrors and he yeah actually know him
from Autumn as well yeah right and um
and so uhh it turns out like I'm
trimming for him and because I had like
an actual working career outside of
cannabis it turns out I showed up on
time I knew how to read I knew how to
write you know I was Dependable I'd
follow through like you know stuff
that's like kind of valuable in in
cannabis you don't see a lot of that at
the time right and so then they're like
hey do you want to work for us and so
then I become the weekend guy and I
start learning the ins and outs of plant
management and facility management you
know we're talking like a 5,000 square
foot facility I mean you know by this by
today's standards you know practically
Cottage grow right and uh anyway so then
I go to become the weekend manager and
just like any chef wants to start their
own restaurant um I got it together to
get my own commercial cultivation and we
took over somebody else's problems for
lack of a better term right I mean it
was like the buildout was you know
designed by Dr Seuss and you know
anything that could go wrong would and
you know like grow M Gros would have
never passed compliance testing in
today's age but um you know and then uh
I was run I was running that for a
little while until the cops said yeah
maybe you shouldn't be growing anymore
and uh came in and took the whole thing
down and so then I uh turned out at that
time Sky Hank had had uh invented smart
B
controllers and which was for those of
you that out there that may not know it
was a small it still is it exists it's a
small like wireless communication sensor
device think of it like a wireless troll
Master System for your 50 light and
underc crowd primarily but uh and then
smart B shut down I spent a little time
swimming around at Spectrum King until I
figured out what I wanted to do and it
turned out that the fil filter guys
wanted to buy smart b a long time ago
and I had met them back then and then
they invented this filter product so
they called me up and they said hey do
you want to make a change and they
didn't even have to put the question
mark on the end before I was like yes
let's do this and so I come to find out
that these filter guys who I know
nothing about are part of this much
larger company called Lighthouse
worldwide Solutions and their bread and
butter is like think of it as like FDA
compliant troll master systems so their
primary uh Market is like pharmaceutical
semiconductor Aerospace clean room
manufacturing right and they they do the
systems for that I mean they're not
obviously me you know measuring like DLI
and Par and stuff they're measuring
particles and air differential pressures
coming from different doorways and stuff
like that so you know the sophistication
was a little was a little much you know
it's much for this industry at this
point in the industry at some point the
regulation may call for it but that's a
whole other we talk about that later
yeah um but anyway so you know they're
like listen you know how to grow you
know how to talk to to you know Stoners
you you know the market uh we'll teach
you everything you need to know about
microb control as it pertains to
cannabis and I was like sweet ass where
do I start you know just just a quick
question I heard a rumor that you had to
have a black belt to get into Lighthouse
is and they jumped you in right right
right no I decided to get sexed in I'm
not doing that um no yeah it turns out
so Lighthouse worldwide Solutions it's
start it was started by uh this this
lady named Dr tay young Kim who is the
highest ranking female Taekwondo
practitioner in the world and so somehow
or another I don't know where this leap
came from but at some point she's opened
up a karate school or Taekwondo school
you know she came to from with like
dollars in her pocket and did all of the
American dream stuff to get you know to
owning her own studio and then all of a
sudden she decided she wanted to start
like a particle counting business I
don't know where that comes from but hey
here we are right so it turns out all of
the C team is like her black belt
students so the president of the
company's like a fifth deegree black
belt my boss is a fifth degree black
belt his boss is a fifth degree black
belt inside the lobby of the building
like it was so okay it was a surreal
thing because it's just not used to the
like the corporate environment I've
worked in previously but the lobby had
um was lined with magazines uh Black
Belt Magazine Taekwondo magazine and
like they're all covers that Dr Kim and
all of the C team were like cover models
for like whatever you call that the
equivalent in martial arts publishing
but um you know they're like breaking
boards and catching arrows and stuff
like that even in the break room you
know like the CEO of the company
standing on a rock you know shirtless
with a bandana like you know doing cool
like Mountaintop poses and and and and
with that though I will say that because
of that like that you know made me feel
really good as a company because you
know like typically uh martial arts is
very you know based in like honor
respect you know those types of things
that not not that like backbiting that
you see it like other job environments
you know what I mean and so right
um and and they've been very nurturing
and supporting along the way and help me
to develop my skills they're they're
allowing me to to get certifications in
certain things to grow my knowledge base
so that I can be more effective for my
customers and so you know four years
later here we are uh I think I'm in my
fifth year now now that I'm thinking
about it but uh the time flies by and
they've just been great and you know I I
figured it like this as it's like I
don't need to know more about growing
there's plenty of guys that know how to
grow fire I just need to know more about
one particular aspect of it that
everybody else doesn't right you know
what I'm saying and be able to
specialize in that because you know it's
not just like Haw and air filters and
particle counters it's like it's being
of service it's it's helping these you
know Growers like cut a learning curve
that state compliance through on them
and the problem that they're facing is
like the equivalent of being told you
have ghosts in your building yeah go
find the ghost in your building you know
what I mean um but luckily enough
there's actually a lot a lot of
commonalities between clean room
manufacturing and where cannabis really
should be operating at in order to
maintain consistent uh consistent
testing
success awesome so you work with Peter
Maguire too I do I do
work he is very much a black belt yeah
and he's a really wicked smart dude
anded me along the way and you know
Peter also is a member of the Cannabis
section
ofm so they're coming out with standards
because that's the thing about cannabis
is that as we know in our early days you
had to be part plumber part electrician
part Carpenter you know I almost
electrocuted myself cutting a pigtail
for a cord that was still plugged into
the wall right we we don't know what we
don't know sometimes right yeah and um
there's not a lot of standards in
telling you how you should operate you
know so I often tell my clients like if
sort of like if you were lost in the
forest you'd watch what the rabbits eat
you know and so if you're looking to
like kind of mimic a higher standard a
lot of people tend to kind of glom on to
hospital standard because it's what we
see more often we don't you know not a
lot of people are in clean rooms and
that's by Design actually um and so you
know with that though hospitals are
fighting different things in cannabis is
fighting so you know when it comes to
operating I tell people if you could
live at Pharma at the top end and uh
food manufacturing at the bottom end if
you could live in that butter Zone
you're usually going to be pretty good
from run to run and you should be
running a pretty tight ship
awesome I love what I do I mean that's
the funny part like I found a home in
cannabis as far as like you know maybe
one day I'll be at another company maybe
one day I'll start my own company you
know who knows what the future holds for
me but what I do know is that that this
uh this environment is is very much
Feels Like Home to me compared to other
types of Industries I've worked in in
the past yeah I mean I think it's a
great industry and I think you know
we're lucky to have people like you that
do a lot of handholding in this industry
too like getting getting in and kind of
explaining because I feel like there's
definitely like a learning curve for a
lot of people that are coming from
Cannabis into clean room practices and
you got yourself and you got Peter that
are going around you know Peter's done
some lecturing I've been to some of his
lectures on clean rooms and you know
I've talked to you on the phone when we
were getting our filters installed um
you know I think that that that's great
to be able to have that not just the
expertise but being able to walk people
through knowing that they're uh they're
in a place where they could use help and
to to get them the help that they need
that's going to improve the quality of
what they're doing yeah wholeheartedly I
mean you know it's so often that like
this the industry doesn't know what it
doesn't know you know what I mean and
the what's nice though is is that you
can feel as I was I was saying today to
a client I was like you can feel the
yearning for the learning you know and
um because you know like Legacy Market
Days from a cleanliness standpoint you
know it was more about vanity because
the accountability was you you were only
hold held to weight bag appeal and
potency you know other than that you
just used to cut the bad part off and
put the rest in the turkey bag you know
right and now it's like things have
changed I have to explain to my clients
like dude the reason you're allowed to
operate in the open is because and the
that the state is willing to let you
operate in the open is because you have
to meet a minimum product safety
standard you know what I'm saying that's
the tradeoff okay we'll let you operate
legally but you can't put like moldy
Bunko boof out on the market like that a
you know that's not how that's not how
that's going not in this state no yeah
right overall yeah overall I mean that's
you know sort of the thing the
interesting part is is that while they
put these testing mandates in place you
know it just simply says they don't they
haven't really cared how you operate up
until the point of
testing right you know what I'm saying
in other words like they're not telling
you what you have to do on a day-to-day
basis they're just saying this bag this
turkey bag this pound has to be in X
state of compliance
you know right um and you know that's
starting to change a little bit now and
so it's hilarious because like Peter and
I have you know have been sort of like
I've always kind of felt a little bit
like Chicken Little like a little
alarmist going like stop using single
bucket mops you got to use double and
triple bucket mops you know and I know
sometimes I sound like a crazy person
about it but at the same time it's
like there's not a lot of future
proofing that happens in Canabis because
it's it's not a very proactive industry
as much as it's a reactive industry or
it has been in the past yeah yeah we
correct right I mean yeah in my
observation most of the time like an
investor isn't necessarily Gonna Want To
Build The Grow Room of the cultivator
dreams right you know what I mean
they're they're just like no we want to
be able to make back our investment
maybe when we've made like 5x our
investment we'll start talking about
improvements or whatever that Benchmark
is is you know well and very few people
are prepared for what's coming with
Federal legalization and the
possibilities of you know the the
standards that they will have oh no
absolutely I mean so it's funny because
we you know we've always had these
conversations around the water cooler so
to speak I mean grant that I work at a
home office so it's a rather lonely
water cooler but I'm
kidding but you know just kind of like
as we've talked and strategized over the
years and you know the prevailing theory
was you know that if Federal what if SL
when Federal legalization came that even
if it wasn't necessarily the FDA that
was going to be mandating um operation
standards it would be some sort of
organization under the FDA who would
probably still pull the current FDA
regulations a case in point like a lot
of State uh license criteria was pulled
from something called the US pharmacopia
I mean it was straight lifted right off
the page and copied and pasted right on
their website uh the US pharmacopia is
the organization that develops the
standards that are used in
pharmaceutical manufacturing the FDA is
the enforcement body of the US
pharmacopia and so the US pharmacopia um
you know like I said they they they if
you look it up their St their testing
standards are the same as like Michigan
California you know several others that
have like you know four types of asilas
that are detect non-detect you know if
you if they're rocking that kind of
stuff it's usually like they lifted it
from the USP well so if they're going to
lift the testing standards from the USP
well what are the odds they're probably
going to lift the operating standards
from there as well right and so you're
starting to see a little bit of that
change start to creep in where it's not
necessarily taking the federal level
green light to make things happen some
of these states are starting to take uh
operating standards at a federal level
and apply them at the state level so
take take for example state of New York
just recently legalized and the state of
New York uh is requiring that you be
adherent to ready for this everybody out
in podcast land write this down 21 CFR
part
117 and that is the uh the the
regulations set for the manufacturing of
human
food wow yeah so that's how every cookie
factory operates that's how every Cereal
Factory every you know potato chip one
cookie factory that doesn't operate
right we're not gonna mention them but
yeah fair enough but yeah so so so you
know but but by and large like those
levels of Standards so New York had
baked it right in from the jump as far
as like right when they legalized right
uh and then Michigan is currently
considering the deployment of
117 um specifically Parts a and parts B
Parts A and B um which isn't that big of
a deal at this point I'll say that
because part A is mostly like
definitions like what is a micro what is
you know this what is that part B just
basically starts to say that you are
becoming that you have to be cgmp
compliant Curr current good
manufacturing practice compliant and
then but they Reserve in the fine print
it says we reserve the right to enforce
later subsequent sections that's where
it gets live um um because like for
instance part C you you're going to have
to start to understand something called
HP and HP stands for hazard analysis
critical control points which is uh it's
it's a food safety philosophy and
practice um that originally came about
when uh NASA went to Pillsbury and was
like we need to make sure that there's
no food spoilage in space because who
wants the runs in a space suit right I
can't that got to
suck so anyway so Pillsbury develops
this like methodology of being able to
like analyze their process find faults
in it find Corrections preventative
actions those types of things and and so
you know you're going to start to see
this kind of Brave New World open up and
you know you got the old dogs that are
like well I didn't get into this
business to fill out paperwork it's like
yes but businesses and industries evolve
you know I mean we're not using wheel
spoked cars you know wheel spoked tires
because somebody's like vulcanization
that devil talk you know like nobody
does that like things innovate so
unfortunately most people got into this
industry because they didn't want to
work a day job or pay taxes and you know
so here you are you know yeah I mean
things have definitely evolved yeah no I
I would completely agree and that's
that's the beauty of it and that's where
I find um that I seamlessly slip right
in because you have these people that
want to be at a higher Echelon of
operation and but they don't know where
to turn they don't know where to look
and the good news is is all of that
information is all out there so you know
it's funny because I sell an air
purifier but my my competition isn't the
guy making an air purifier across the
street it's change
discipline uh my buddy says dot dot dot
you know Buddy says you should use this
Bro Science Bro Science and so I'm just
like dude you just need a better class
of buddy that's all right you know so
that's where I try to really pride
myself on I'm not going to put anything
out information wise that isn't backed
up by a source right you know what I
mean and the source is not your buddy
right it's Peter McGuire it's Peter
McGuire totally well he's he's in Oregon
so I'm wondering what your thoughts are
on
aspergillis and everything you know
because Oregon tried to pass the the law
that they were about regarding asilis
and not being and testing for it right
and well they found out they have around
and found out right I exactly everything
had aspergillus in it right exactly yeah
and and I I mean listen from a
cultivator standpoint I totally get it I
feel the pain Point um you know that
that section of the country as far as
their growing methodologies it's it's
very well- entrenched in you know let's
let's call them oldw World methodologies
you know and I respect that I dig it I
you know you'd be surprised what I've
been willing to smoke in my day so I'd
smoke anything from Oregon because I've
smoked stuff from Mexico no problem it's
cool right you know I didn't even know
bud came like in a three-dimensional
form I thought it came as a feather
because I had didn't understand what
Mexican bricks I didn't understand grew
in bricks grew in bricks was like cool I
got the corner of the brick that's
awesome it's like bounties it's like so
uh but anyway so yeah no in Oregon yeah
it's that's it's a tough one because
like I mean I have an unpopular but hot
take on it and and it goes a little
something like this w we can't grow
clean so we're going to try to reform
the laws back to where they originally
were I'm sorry if I pissed off anybody
in Oregon but you know I mean at the end
of the day it's like again that that
product safety standard is coming into
play
and you
know the the propensity for people
getting tainted weed is is not all that
high I understand that but when it hits
you it it's you know it can be
debilitating particularly because we've
been you know calling this medicine to
make it legal for you know 20 30 years
right more right 96 right so it's
like if you're going to grow medicine
then you're going to have to make
medicine the way medicine's
made is kind of the my my take off like
I said hot take unpopular opinion very
unpopular very popular on this podcast
you're gonna get a lot of slack for it
you know I think and I don't honestly
know what the balance is because I think
there's a balance I I want to support
Growers that are growing outdoors in
Oregon you know I mean I feel like
there's a need to support and to support
small business right so at the end of
the day we want to support small
business obviously we want a safe
product that's safe for every everybody
so maybe the thresholds need to be
adjusted I mean I think that's probably
what it's going to come down to I think
so too um you know I mean and especially
because you know if nothing else like
the states are starting to see like
Revenue spikes in in their tax revenue
and Absolut you know they don't want to
go that to go away so yeah if they do
have to like you know make it like
detect non detect or X number of total
coliform
uh you know from your total yeast and
mole count or some some sort of give and
take I mean you know and not only that
but here's the thing is that that law
when it was put into effect was
basically like okay you guys have to
basically change everything you do now
you have an X number like Long window to
make that happen right and now
everything after that has to be tested
so it wasn't it's not fair to The
Growers right you know because like
again you know like a lot of a lot of
the Legacy methodology just simply don't
translate into like a compliant world
you know um so yeah no I
mean you know I let me put it this way I
I I applaud Oregon for being able to get
that repealed yeah you know what I'm
saying I mean because think about it
like no other state is is getting that
kind of lobbying power that that they're
all of a sudden gonna start changing the
rules right you know so my hat's off to
them personally totally well you have
some amazing uh Clean Air Products I do
yeah you want to tell us a little bit
about the product line that you guys
have yeah sure so so we were talking we
mentioned earlier filter so filter is a
commercial grade HEPA air purifier um
it's the same type of HEPA technology
that's used in pharmaceutical clean
rooms um it's what you would call a
capture and removal type of uh device so
you know the philosophy in clean rooms
is is they don't care what's in your air
they just want it out of the air so they
don't care if it's dust if it's mold if
it's you know whatever it's like if you
remove all of the particles which
difficult to do admittedly difficult to
do but like if you reduce the particles
you reduce the threat so most of the
problems that start out in our
facilities typically tend to come from
the air um you know a lot of times our
our facilities are negatively pressured
so they're pulling outside air in
especially if you're near places like if
you're growing near like a garbage dump
or you're growing near other Growers or
other industries that have different uh
requirements around their output and
pollution levels um cereal factories for
example are widely known to you know
remember they get their corn and their
grains and all that stuff on box cars
that are just dumped in silos into the
factory so all of that stuff that's just
sort of rotting is uh it's still usable
for the purpose of making Lucky Charms
or whatever but like cereal has a kill
step in it so the production process so
they can take in like different types of
let's say stuff you wouldn't normally
necessarily eat raw you know under its
current state when it arrives there but
by the time it's made into a box of
cereal it's perfectly edible because
anything that's been you know uh exposed
to that stuff has been killed off in the
production process meanwhile their
Material Handling is constantly like
pluming molds and such that are coming
off of those things and depending if
you're upwind downwind whatever you know
you you definitely there's a propensity
for you to be able to pull those
problems in and I've I've seen it in lab
testing so um so in addition to the HEPA
a purifier which is continually
remediating particles it's like you know
at the end of the day like you need to
be able to not just get rid of particles
but it's also very helpful to be able to
detect them and identify them in your
air so one of the other devices we
manufacture is called an hand it's
called an air particle counter and what
it's designed to do is it's basically
pulling air in through a laser or
through a box it's running it past a
laser it's sizing it it's counting it
it's giving you a number you can then
start to use to understand the volume or
what you would call the particle
pressure the particle burden of of your
of your airspace um and that's something
that you can use to kind of understand
the general cless of your air but also
you can use it to um let's say like
start to capture or how would I say this
uh potentially start to identify
problems that could be in your air um so
like for instance I'm trying to uh as
we're talking here trying to find a a
dock here that I wanted to show you if I
can I share a screen with you absolutely
sweet okay so check this out
so this is a falling particle chart so
if you understand the concept that
heavier particles are going to fall out
of the air faster than smaller particles
you can see here that a 100 Micron
particle which would be like roughly the
width of a human air that's going to
fall out of the ground or just going to
fall to the ground in this particular
case they're saying it's it's falling
one meter so what they did was they took
a glass tube that's one meter long they
drop the particle in it they time to see
how long it takes to fall and so a 100
Micron particle the whd your human hair
like takes less than two seconds to fall
one meter but have to consider that in
cannabis your smallest particle thread
is actually one micron and larger so one
to two microns is like an aspila [__]
Godus Spore probably one of the smaller
ones but a one micron particle will take
almost 5 hours to fall one meter in
perfectly still air undisturbed by
ambient air so if you think of if it
takes five hours to fall in a tube where
it's nothing's disturbing it and then
you go to an indoor facility and you're
dealing with fans on the walls doors
opening and closing HVAC that's you know
perhaps intermittently spaced you know
through the duct work and stuff like
that you're creating what's called a
turbulent airf flow environment so these
one micron particles these smaller mold
spores they can stay a loft
for indefinitely frankly you know yeah
and so um that's where the idea and and
and all they're doing is swirling around
the air and they're succumbing to the
Seas of flow so every time like I'm sure
at some point if you've ever walked past
a like a candle or something like that
and like the wind from your you passing
by disturbs the flame you know that
happens at the particle level too um um
as well those particles are also very
easy to adhere to our clothing and such
so even if somebody's in Scrubs you know
you got to remember like to a one micron
particle like you know threads are like
you know giant like anchor ropes or like
those ropes you use in the gym you know
a little thread that we see in a shirt
right to us it looks like a more like a
hair but to a one micron mold Spore it's
it's much larger so it's able to adhere
easier and uh and then travel about the
facility so with your particle counter I
think one of the coolest things that you
suggested is to actually use it to test
before you're do like when either dring
your build out before you actually have
plants in and then after once you have
the filter installed and you know being
able to test the difference yeah
absolutely so that's called baselining
and that that's the the technical term
is to Baseline a building so what
happens is um you know like let's say
the last nail and screw goes in the
construction crew leaves you do your f
clean up whatever that would be the time
where you would take uh particle counts
to figure out what's going on in there
you would take air samples to see if you
can identify anything in your air uh I
would suggest swab samples as well water
samples um you know just test the just
test the Jesus out of that place right
because you want to know a are there any
problems in there that you might be able
to catch and remediate before you ever
move plants in there because if you grow
plants on top of a problem
you're just proliferating a problem
right um but then the other side of this
too is that you then also have some
benchmarks for cleanliness so now that
you know what the building was like
before plants ever moved in you're
cleaning and testing regimens and stuff
you have something to compare against as
as you as you progress through cycle
after cycle so um you know and then not
for nothing but I I talked to some of my
clients about like you know cuz I'm
always helping them to you know be
successful that so that they scale and
expand and if they're thinking about
buying a second building I'm like let's
go in and take some samples now if you
like the building that much but it's got
a problem and you can prove it then that
might maybe give you some negotiating
power on price totally yeah that makes a
lot of sense yeah yeah I mean you know
or or maybe that you might want to avoid
it all together you know right now
people as opposed to 5 years ago I think
a lot of people are thinking like what's
in the building that I'm going into what
what kind of pathogens are already in
the building yeah oh that's a and and
not only that but understanding the
history of that building too if you're
not building from the ground up from
scratch yeah you know I mean you find
like uh say for instance in the New
England states like your Massachusetts
Rhode Island areas and stuff like that I
mean some of that construction's 100
years old yeah definitely asilis yeah
definitely definitely asilis and you
know um and and so it's like you know
I'm telling them man you got to throw a
lot of epoxy around this place you know
you got to kind of hermetically seal all
these problems in because it's not like
you're going to be replacing wood beams
and stuff like that you know um but yeah
it's it's you know you have old
construction but then you also have like
what was the building used for prior so
you know I might not necessarily want to
move a cannabis cultivation into like a
something that was manufacturing dog
food previously or something like that
you know right you wouldn't want to move
into a slaughterous right um you know
you want businesses that didn't have
anything to do with organic products
prior you know what I'm saying uh
because those things will leave residual
imprint in the building long after that
business has closed and moved on and
it's just waiting for the next client
you know but if I don't know like more
nous business buys an old dog food
factory they're not as susceptible to
the problems it's the plants that are
the issue the plants are are so
sensitive you know and so that's why I
have to explain to people you're not
you're not growing you know cucumbers
and tomatoes that have skin that you can
wash and you can take like some sort of
spray to or something like that you know
you're growing something that's sticky
and catches anything that passes by it
yeah the remediation starts before you
get the plants in yeah absolutely I
couldn't agree with you more yeah yeah
and then you know the other side of it
too is it's it's not even necessarily
like the building has an illness it's
like you know our day-to-day lives from
a microb standpoint are are pretty
Savage by comparison to like the
cleanliness level you you you want in in
a cannabis facility I mean you know both
you and I sitting here right now we have
100,000 skin cells sloughing off of our
body per minute yeah like you know what
I mean like we look like uh we look like
the top of a glass of sprite at like the
you know at the at the we're
effervescent you know at that uh at that
microscopic level and so you know with
that we pick up a lot of things in our
day-to-day lives sitting on the couch
you know ASP perillis spag godess
largest producer of it is our or you
pick up a lot of it from your own
bedding right yeah so you know with that
in mind it's
like people tend to become almost as
much if not more so a danger to the
process compared to the environment that
you're growing in you know totally it's
one thing to grow like in a barn but
it's another thing to grow in street
clothes in a barn you know like you're
just kind of adding to the problem and
so a lot of it has to do with you know
how what are you doing
around you know keeping a barrier
between yourself and your plants right
so can we talk a little bit about using
igar plates and how uh you can test for
path pathogens and and problems in your
buildings let's say let's say you're
moving into a building and you want to
figure out what the problems are this
here is a lighthouse ac100 air microbial
sampler this may look familiar to you I
think in fact you may have used this one
I think I do send this one to you but I
think I see my thumb print on it so so
what you see here and I just want to
make sure that the background doesn't
obscure it but basically you got a cover
for the sampler you have a sampling head
and you can see as I hold it up to the
camera there's a bunch of holes uh that
are embedded in it and then what you
would do is you'd put a petri dish here
you'd snap the cover on you set the
buttons up and you would draw a specific
amount of air for a specific amount of
time onto the petri dish which then you
would cap and then send off to a lab to
have
analog um you know it's it's and we use
malt extract agar you know it it would
be what's suggested um because that's
that and uh I think there's another one
tryptic Soy Agar or potato dextrous I
have to look that up but I always I
always use mea um but you know certain
agars do not play do not capture the
things that you're looking for right you
know um for instance powdery Milo
doesn't play it at
all interesting I know you have to use a
different kind of device in order to to
capture uh powdery mildew um so that
device I don't we don't sell them we
don't make them but we made an adapter
for their testing media and uh so they
used something called I don't know if
you've ever heard of like a zon biop
pump um they take something called an
Aeros cell cassette which is essentially
just to boil it down to like explain
like on five terms it's it's like a
hockey puck small hockey puck shaped
plastic disc uh air can go in and flow
out and inside the center of that is
like an little adhesive Circle and so
air impacts the particles you know the
air flow impacts the particles on an
adhesive uh Circle and that can be
looked at under a microscope for visual
study so you can't necessarily incubate
it and grow something out on it think of
it like a lift tape sample y it's like a
lift tape sample of your air cool yeah
so really good stuff yeah yeah and then
you know I mean obviously I'm a big fan
of swabbing as well um because you know
I just want to know as much data as
possible Right when you open up your
troll Master you open up your aoya or
whatever you want to be able to see like
the graphic representation of the
heartbeat of your garden right you want
to be able to look at that and you can
start to see the interplay between
systems in here so it's like I mean if I
was able to you know for instance uh you
know I can even show you what a lab
report looks like to kind of give you an
idea of what somebody can expect from a
data standpoint I'll share this with you
so this is a uh a lab report where I've
redacted the name to protect the
innocent and uh but you can see here
like if you look at column one does my
mouse show up on this too yes it does
okay if you look over here you see we
tested Hall one Hall two dry cure the
attic area and the reason that Hall this
hallway was actually just one hallway
but I took two tests at it because I one
day when I was there I saw them
transplanting cocoa because they didn't
have any other available workspace and
so they they have to do their work in
the hallway and I was like I want to see
if there's a difference because they're
paying for the testing why not um I want
to see is there a difference between the
area that they work in and the area that
they don't work in uh and then so you
can see here like what it's listing is
then it's listing the sample volumes so
we took 500 liters of air um and I don't
think it has the time on here but you
typically want to note how long of a
sample you took so then you can see
under the the fungal identification list
this is all of the things that they were
looking for if you have specifics in
mind you know you can always mention
them to the lab and and they can make a
note on it to add it to their list of
things to look out for um because some
molds are very industry specific you
know so as you can see in Hall one we
found five Colony forming units of of uh
aspergillis Niger and then the other end
that wasn't being used for transplanting
we only found too but you can see where
the concentration lies um and then we
found some in their dry cure we found a
little up in the attic you know which
kind of says that maybe there was maybe
a leak up there that might start be
beginning to proliferate and then uh by
the way for what it's worth this one
down here cladosporium I don't think
I've ever been in a facility that I've
tested that's ever not had
cladosporoides
oh it's just a common plant pathogen
it's it's everywhere here's where it got
really interesting in this particular
lab report for and this was what was eye
opening was this one here is pen
penicilium
citrome and you can see here this is off
the charts compared to aspergilus Niger
right
192 Colony forming units 302 102 300 I'm
just going like what is this and where
is it coming from because that's not why
they called me to come in oh wow yeah
they called me to come in about because
they were failing for aspir gillus Niger
and I was like well let's just see what
this thing captures right and you could
see they found a few other things like
yeast colonies and and stuff like that I
went to look back at this penicilium
citrinum and discovered that it is a
mold that is on uh decaying matter and
um uh typically grain it it's found on
grains like corn and rice and wheat and
as I think i' mentioned earlier you know
having a cereal factory nearby it turns
out this is where I kind of came up with
this realization and use it as a talking
point was these guys because when I did
a Google over overhead search I
discovered that they were like a quar
mile downwind from a general Mill cereal
processing Factory wow yeah and then at
another point in time I took another
test from the outside of the building
and the penicilium
Citron uh was just as elevated so you
know it's like that's the level of eye
opening this because when you get like a
total yeast and mold count report like
you want to know what total what the
yeasts and the molds are because that's
going to be a key in being able to
figure out the root cause of it you know
what I mean so you know when you get
your asparagus fagas as I said you know
the biggest you know producer of it is
our bedding and you know that might
speak to like a cleanliness issue you
know where like like a a facility
culture hygiene culture issue you know
um very easy for someone to scratch
their head and then go back to touching
plant
oh yeah people t or touch your phone or
touch your pH yeah people do this stuff
all the time yeah your phone has 25,000
microbes per square inch so everybody
that's watching make sure to sanitize
your phone regularly that's what I'm
saying yeah wipe it down I mean you know
obviously best case scenario you leave
it out uh leave it out of the critical
area but I understand that's not
reflective of reality so it's like what
are the measures that you can take some
people will wipe down their phones right
some people will put it in a plas bag
like a ziplock bag for sure I'd be good
with that you know because here's the
other thing about like wiping down your
phones what is contact time right so
contact time for those that don't know
is the minimum amount of time that a
disinfectant needs in order to achieve
the
eradication so if you're wiping down
your phone and you just wipe it wipe it
wipe it and uh you didn't necessarily
like leave it wet for a certain amount
of time or you took another tow and you
dried it off you're not getting the full
potential of that
disinfectant so let's talk about alcohol
because not alcohol all alcohol is
created equal especially if you're
sanitizing surfaces with alcohol which I
would say that bleach is probably a lot
better for hopl and viroid yes but uh as
opposed to alcohol but I learned
something from Peter McGuire a long time
ago and it was the difference between
90% And 70% yep um which I've used that
over and over and over uh in in
conversation but I think it's important
thing for everybody to learn the
difference 90% is great for cleaning
your pipes and bongs all day right but
like the reason that it's 90% alcohol is
because it's only 10% water so if you
dumb down the alcohol uh to like 70% you
have 30% water which means that the
cleansing agent takes longer to
evaporate from the surface and there go
therego gives you more uh a longer
contact time for it to achieve the
eradication because here's the fun thing
about you know contact time if you will
is that you might read on a label that
it says like spray and leave wet for 10
minutes but you have to know how long it
takes for it to dry too because if you
spray it and walk away and go do
something else and it hasn't met that
contact time you're not again not
getting the Full Potential from that
disinfectant so you actually would need
to go back and wet it again you know
like do a SE second application right
that's the stuff that's all buried in
the back on the labels and stuff so um I
mean I I use that example all the time I
mean here I just I have a canal Lysol
right here right because I just carry
can Lysol around that's what I do right
on these labels here it literally says
like you know for uh you know leave
leave uh for SARS Co too on hard
surfaces two minutes killed Roto virus
uh you know left wet for 30 seconds like
so all of these things it depends on
what you're trying to kill surface
contact time is so important yeah no
absolutely absolutely and so uh you know
I'm a huge proponent of reading your
labels I'm a huge proponent of
contacting manufacturers I get questions
all the time like do you recommend this
cleanser or this cleanser and it's
like if you use them properly both of
them should work yeah you know as well
if you use them properly and they're
designed to kill the thing you're trying
to kill then they should both do the job
so but then I always tell people I'm
like call the manufacturer I assure you
a a a a disinfected manufacturer
definitely wants to speak to their
customers because they want to make sure
that their customers are using their
product correctly that they're using it
often so that they can sell you more of
it you know and they they want to make
sure you are as knowledgeable as
possible on their product yeah and most
of them have pretty good customer
service yeah as they should and you know
and I can could tell you like here in
cannabis like man customer service is
key you know I mean people in cannabis
aren't used to customer service though I
think like uh you you have a problem
with your weed or who grew your weed or
whatever you have questions about it a
lot of times Instagram you might you
might be able to get a reply but you
know back in the Legacy years that was
all there was yeah I get it and and it's
like you know and the other thing is is
like you know remember I speak primarily
to cultivators but you know and
cultivators like have historically been
big fish in their Pond you know
and I mean when I was growing I like the
Sinatra treatment you know who doesn't
like the Sinatra treatment just in life
you know and so it's like if these
Growers you know that I speak to on a
day-to-day basis they feel like I know
what I'm talking about they feel like I
I I can answer their questions and that
I pick up the phone and I'm prompt in my
response to them like it's it says
worlds to like building trust you know I
mean because you know I I I I'll say
that it's one thing to get into a
facility and get a bunch of filters up
on the walls and in the ceilings and
stuff like that but that's not much of a
career where the career comes in is
helping these guys get to all the other
questions that are related to microb
control outside of my filter and that
way they scale and expand to site number
two two and then site number three and
then they recommend me to their friends
and then now I'm starting to get into
their Network and you know all for just
being this guy that's like trying to be
of help you know in a day and age where
if you have a problem with Instagram you
can't call Instagram no you know you're
the prodct they make it near impossible
meta makes it near impossible to contact
them you know it's there's there's ways
to contact them and you know through
through chat you're a pain Advertiser
they're more apt to talk to you but
remember like I said the users of
Instagram are the product that's what
they sell right so as far as from a
customer service standpoint if my
account got flaggs because I can't get
shown to non-followers you know because
my content is a little you know toes the
line of good taste let's say that racy
yeah little racy
right we can talk about that ver like
that's the one thing I noticed is that I
love this industry because low brow
humor goes really are for sure you know
what I mean and so I'm in the business
of talking about [__] that's difficult
to explain and isn't very interesting to
learn so but you have to know it so it's
like what's the way that I can make it
palatable you know so if I throw a dick
joke in and yet the text underneath it
actually teaches you something I at
least you know that's the the the photos
you see see in my feed are like more to
generate the shock and awe to get you to
look I mean obviously they're tied to
whatever I want to talk about in the
post that you know in the text right but
but at the end of the day like yeah I
mean I'm you know social media is this
river right think of it as a stream and
if you're standing at the shore
everything's going past you and if
you're not somebody's not standing at
the shore at the moment your information
goes by they miss it you know and so you
know that's where the hashtags come in
and bl blahy blue but
my my point in saying that is is it's
like it softens the blow you know what
I'm saying in the sense of like this
level of information can be really
intimidating for some people and yeah
but let's M make education fun that's
what we're doing here today you know I
feel like we're we're trying to make
education fun and there's no reason
education and learning shouldn't be fun
I completely agree and and not only that
but you're going to retain it more yeah
you know uh the retention level is huge
like you know I get uh I get people that
tell me that they're like you know you
did this picture with this thing and now
I can't unsee it but that means I can't
unforget it you know what I mean or that
means I can't forget it you know yeah so
to make the
last they can and sometimes it has but
you know I've gotten a couple of I'm
triggered please take this post down and
I'm like well you have a right to not
follow me uh you know I mean I get live
yeah right right exactly but um we
sensitive time these days you know it is
what it is you know but I I I definitely
know that like the core of of the
industry loves having a good time
because you know the entire industry is
rooted in you know I mean I don't know
like I just don't get sad in smoke weed
I want to be happy in smoke weed you
know like that's just not yeah I would
say it makes most people happy yeah you
know it's it's it's an uplifting event
you know and I believe it makes the
world a better place I believe people
are in better moods because of it you
know oh sure no absolutely I I you know
I mean I've seen it firsthand with the
effects of of you know from a medicinal
standpoint from people who have like you
know seen an ease in symptoms like uh I
mean I tell you when I was at Spectrum
King I had a I had a boss who had two
bad knees he needed two knee replacement
surgeries and he wasn't getting them for
one reason or another a whole other
story but what I can tell you is that my
uncle here in Michigan makes a Sav out
of his plants and everybody swears by it
and he sent me some and I gave it to my
boss and he's like get me more yeah
please get me more I mean you know and
he's like listen you know my my pain
didn't go away completely but it went
from a nine to like a three wow yeah
exactly exactly I mean you know I I I'm
a big fan of of of you know there's not
enough research is what it comes down to
no and I think we have a stack of
anecdotal proof and we have a stack of
we're starting to get a stack of actual
you know white papers and proof on that
level um and I think like you know you
would watch sanj Gupta on 60 Minutes and
there's a kid that he gets cured of his
uh seizures from from THC or CBD or you
know any of these cannaboids I mean how
can you argue with a parent that wants
to keep their kid healthy and you know I
just it's it's so hard to argue the fact
and the fact that it's still schedule
one is kind of crazy too oh completely I
mean you know I done that that that that
whole story goes back to like paper
mills and yellow journalism of like the
20s and 30s or whatever it was and the
reer madness days where they demonized
everything for social or corporate
interests you know and I mean I I I seem
to remember like historically wasn't
there some period of time where like
every American Farmer was required to
grow some sort of section of hemp on
their Farm
I seem to remember that was a thing like
in the George Washington
days makes a lot of sense I think we
should go back to those ways I
completely agree I mean you know I you
know I mean smoking it aside you know
yeah you get more paper per hectare you
get oils you get all sorts of other
usable things remediation for soil uh
the fact is it produces a lot more
oxygen than trees do there there's all
kinds of benefits yeah no completely and
so you know uh so from that stand I
think it's it's a sad State of Affairs
that there's not enough research but as
I understand it if it does go to
schedule of three that that will open up
the door for a lot more of that research
because the Laboratories that can work
with those that level of study will now
have access to that is that well
schedule three is a scary thing right so
I'm I'm All About descheduling not
rescheduling and I think the last three
episodes we've talked about the
deschedule not reschedule because a
second you make it a schedule three drug
what happens to the wreck Market true
you know and I think there's a lot of
unanswered questions like I I understand
that you know as as a alcohol and
tobacco are controlled substances we
should have it as a controlled substance
but as far as like the fact that they
want to turn it into a schedule three
drug I'm not a huge fan I think we need
to deschedule it
completely yeah no I mean and I I would
say so too there's no reason it should
have ever been so in the first place you
know
so yeah yeah but uh anyway so so yeah I
mean from a from a to get people to that
place where there's
consistently you know clean product on
the market it's like it's just requiring
that you go to a place of you know being
able to analyze your environment and
being able to uh you know take small
mitigation risks uh mitigate or
eliminate risks within the facility so
from that standpoint you know it's not
even just about putting a magic box up
in the ceiling uh before you you know uh
operate it's about you know what kind of
mops are you using um you know what kind
of gowning are you doing uh what kind of
uh you know uh like are you fixing your
cracks in your floors and your windows
and what have
you you know those types of questions
like all those other risks things that
fall under
GMP right for sure it's funny with the
filter uh we had the option of either
putting it hidden up in the ceiling or
putting it so that we can see it and I
feel like I want to see it so I want to
be able to talk about it when people
come in the building I I just you guys
are designed to make it look nice too
thank you no I appreciate that and and
yeah it it the nice part about it is it
does come on uh um you know casters so
you can wheel it around if you want uh
we do have hardware for you to be able
to mount it to the ceiling mounted to a
wall you know what have you I mean you
know uh ceiling in floor real estate in
a in a cultivation facility is pretty uh
pretty premium you know so to be able to
find the balance of the size of a unit
that you can work with that puts out
enough air flow for it to be worth it
that you know still has uh efficacy in
its process right and to be able to you
know they like I mean full disclosure
you know you know we are an h13 HEPA
filter right h14
exists but you lose air flow so there's
a little bit of give and take it's sort
of like you know even going into the
facilities like just their native HVAC
systems you know um there's something
called the Merv rating system for air
filters some people don't know what it
is it stands for minimum efficiency
reporting value and what it is is it's
sort of a standard expectation of
performance for that filter so and it's
given a number so like for example uh a
Merv 13 filter will remove 90% of one
micron and larger particles whereas a
Merv 8 filter will only capture about
60% or something like that in fact do I
have a mve chart I might actually have a
mve chart here I do how do you know um
you can actually see it but here's the
joke of it or the the give and take is
the the higher you go up in uh mve
rating yeah you get better filtration
performance your Mechanicals for your
HVAC have to work a lot harder in order
to push air through so the it the
efficiency pops out because if your HVAC
system can't support the heavier
weighted filter because it can't move
the air through it you're going to
experience cooling capacity issues
you're going to experience um you know
stress on your HVAC system you know
those types of things and so that's
where filter kind of comes in to just
directly attach uh attack the particle
problem so we don't cying into HVAC I
don't even suggest it as a bypass I'm
just like just you put it in the room
let it recirculate its own air and let
the HVAC do its thing and we're
basically supplementing the filtration
because you know when people are
specking in HVAC in their plan more
often than not they're factoring for
cooling capacity versus you know
particle filtration I get it yeah so
with that said it's like I'm not going
to tell you to like rip out and replace
hundreds of thousands of dollars worth
of HVAC equipment I'll tell you to put
of filters in there right no I'm kidding
huh absolutely that's great but no I
mean at the end of the day though it's
like you know it not only can you can
you uh immediately test filtration so
that's the cool part about versus like a
lot of the other guys that that that are
out there the other types of
Technologies is that I can put a
particle counter on the bottom I can put
a particle counter on the top and I can
demonstrate efficacy in real time you
know what I mean so like uh in fact
would you know it uh I might actually
have that handy here and uh let's see
here let me see if I can open this up
and share it with you but I can
literally uh yeah there it is let me
share share screen has stopped as the
share windows closed okay cool well
we're gonna share it again uh here we go
so let me let me roll it back here for a
second just to keep you in suspense here
so we got a filter unit here and you can
see we put a particle counter on one
side and you can see those numbers are
counting and you can see the time clock
in the bottom right where it's counting
seconds so you know it's running show
you the rest of the filter unit and then
we come to the output with a particle
counter running
[Music]
and all zeros so I can prove that this
thing is actually doing something in
real time versus a lot of other
companies that are out there that you
know where you would have to do a lot of
testing of the room in order to be able
to understand if this thing's actually
doing something and well my my buds past
testing is anecdotal but not very
scientific
right I
mean yeah yeah but it's a beautiful
world we live in where we can test this
stuff yeah I agree I I yeah the level of
Awakening to like all of these little
facets is you know at the same time
while it's cool it definitely makes the
industry a lot more complicated you know
um but at at the end of the day you know
it's like so many people take pride in
their
process and oftentimes you don't
necessarily know if the cleaning that
you're doing is actually cleaning so for
example uh and a device common in food
manufacturing it's called an ATP meter
have you heard of one you familiar with
those no I mean I know what ATP is yeah
righto triphosphate or something like
that right endine triphosphate okay so
an ATP meter is basically like every
living cell produces bioluminescence
sort of like you know when you go to the
beach at certain times of year and you
kick the water and it turns blue because
of all the algae right bioluminescent
algae um or whatever animal or thing is
making that bioluminescent so everything
has a natural level of bioluminesence so
this ATP meter is like roughly the size
of like a large cell phone maybe twice
as thick about that size and it comes
with you buy a bunch of sticks where you
break off the end and you swab it on a
surface and then you put it in the
device and it spits out a number and
that's the what what it's calculating is
how much bioluminescence is reflected
back wow so in other words like let's
say you're at a cookie factory and you
want to test your conveyor belt you know
you can you can uh test it beforehand
you get what's called an rli relative
light indicator relative Light number
I'm not familiar with them too deeply
but you get a number that it spits out
and then you execute your cleaning sop
and then you test it again and if you
see a lower number that's a validation
that you've cleaned right and that's you
know a big misconception is because a
lot of people walk into a room and
they're like smells clean smells really
clean in here but it's like in some
cases that could just be fragrance that
the
manufactur could be
yeah exactly exactly right so um you
know it really does take the ability to
you know validate it but I don't know
that cannabis is necessarily there yet
like Pharma manufacturing is very much
there they live and die by validation
every claim they make they have to be
able to validate and that includes
cleaning um you know and and that and
you know following specific like Sops
you know standard operating procedure
are are becoming quite popular I get a
lot of requests for people to you know
from people to write them and I know hom
Growers that write Sops for themselves
you know I don't you know what's funny I
don't write Sops I I mean like high
level I do but like I write Sops for
other people as a service just well
simply because you know when you're um
you have to observe somebody's process
you know what I mean there's not
necessarily like some Cookie Cutter Way
spoiler play sop it's so customed to the
individual environment U you know it's
it's an amazing thing too if you get it
down right I can tell you this while
there's like a million different ways to
do something um the formatting is is
where I think that you're GNA win you
know what I mean so like for instance uh
uh is this the SOP training template
this is the SOP training template so
watch this madness here where is it here
we go so what I did was a while back I
did a webinar it's available on the
filter uh YouTube page and what I did
was I did a webinar on building
Sops and building Sops from a Pharma and
food manufacturing standpoint so I took
what they do and just put it in a
template that makes everything very easy
to understand so and we ran through all
the different various parts so you you
know in in Pharma sop writing um they
have these very specific Parts they have
the scope you know which defines what
the where the procedure applies within
the overall operation of the facility
because people want to know well how
does what I'm doing fit into the process
or the purpose what's the purpose of
doing this thing this way you know um
any specific definitions who's in charge
of what what materials are you going to
need not just cleaning materials and
Equipment but like do you need safety
gear do you need like ladders and you
know pole extendable poles and what have
you you know and then you finally get to
the procedure where you actually list
out the steps if you have references
that you want to to include with there
you do that too and then you know
there's a validation and sign off
section and again you know like cannabis
isn't as huge on validating yet um but I
can tell you this that if it's not
documented it didn't
happen right you know so I have to tell
people as well I'm like you need to
start getting down on documenting
documenting everything you do you know
because everything who cleans the
bathroom and when do they clean it I
mean I those are little things but
they're super important believe it or
not absolutely and you know here's the
thing it's it's not even just
necessarily from a day-to-day operation
standpoint yeah what happens if you have
a recall what happens if you get sued by
an employee who got hurt at your
facility or something like that or got
sick at your facility we we heard about
a case in Massachusetts right we all we
all kind of got familiar with that one
and that had some special nuances to it
and it's unfortunate that it happened
but at the end of the day um you know
it's
it's to be able to to document
everything you did can actually in fact
provide you a legal defense in certain
situations absolutely you know if if you
can sit there and say like you know yes
this happened to this person but it's
not like we've been doing nothing we
have this diligent particle monitoring
program a diligent air sampling program
we document every time we clean
something and every time we change
something and then at least it gives you
some sort of plausible defense around
like versus you know just you're just
growing Backyard Boogie indoors and you
got my client sick or some people don't
document stuff because they want
plausible deniability as well so if you
want to do it the right way then
document it if you don't then whatever
but documenting is the way to go I mean
especially it doesn't matter whether
you're breeding or whether you're doing
tissue culture or whether you're doing
cultivation if you want to improve what
you're doing documentation is where it's
found you you find the the ways and the
paths to improve what you're doing
through documentation right who kept the
grow Journal I kept the grow Journal
right you you kept the grow Journal why
and some of it was just simply as basic
as you wanted to remember what you did
last time so that if it worked you could
do it again for sure you know well I
always changed recipes so often in the
beginning when I was learning stuff I
was always changing stuff around and
there were these really complicated
recipes and way way more than what I
would do now for cultivation but right
yeah when you're just buy like what like
seven different liquids and like most of
them are yeah most of them are 95% water
anyway
seriously you know but I'll tell you
know and and and I will say that um you
know simplifying things making things
easier mcging your way around things
like just because I'm telling people to
live between food and Pharma doesn't
necessarily mean you have to spend
Pharma money to get there right you know
I mean but you got to have the knowledge
that's the one thing you got to have the
knowledge to know what you need to
change you know and and you have to be
able to be willing to look at yourself
like hold the mirror up to your process
and be willing to go okay this is not
working right cut the ego out and
actually look at it you know from an
outside perspective I just said that
today to a client I was at a site visit
earlier today and I was like you know
there is a distinct lack of CEO training
in this industry you know um because I I
I kind of find it disturbing sometimes
because like I'm seing as like like
Ultra Clean guy and really in my reality
I'm like I'm a pig but like as soon as I
get to the facility door as soon as I
get to the facility door that's like you
know I'm showered I'm suited I'm booted
I'm ticked I'm all my equipment sprayed
down I realize the risk that I post and
I also have to be able to live it
because I'm telling my Growers limit
your visitors you know like all those
times you see like um you know glamour
models going into the cultivation
facilities to do like marketing photo
photo shoots for their for their client
you know it's like those classic shots
of like some you know hippie girl like
smelling the butt in her hand and I'm
like do you know you have 10,000
microbes birth wearin no you know like
yeah I get it I I'm I'm definitely the
killjoy of of the industry sometimes you
know and uh but at the same time it's
like you are in a business and right if
you want to do business as business is
done unfortunately there's some give and
take around where your level of fun is
versus where your level of work is
problem I have a serious problem I love
touching plants with my bare hands I
know it's not the best thing but it's
terrible and I try I've I've worked
really diligently on wearing gloves most
of the time I just really enjoy touching
plants with my bare hands and rubbing my
fingers make you a deal if you can start
to deploy a hand sanitizing regimen
before you touch your plants allow it
that's a great idea we have hand
sanitizing stations all over so yeah you
know I tell you what man we've been
taught to wash our our hands since
kindergarten man and
like you know but we were never really
taught how you know well yeah you're
supposed to what say the alphabet is it
three times well I'll tell you what it
actually well no twice like sing Happy
Birthday twice twice right but you know
here's where it where it gets
interesting is it's not even just the
amount of time that you spend it's the
amount of of effort and direction oh
yeah you're what you're looking at right
here is What's called the aseptic
handwashing technique and this is used
in hospitals this is used in dental
offices it's used in Pharma clean rooms
like it is considered an aseptic process
right for aseptic manufacturing and so
what it starts with is you're
traditional rubbing your palms together
and then you're getting the insides of
your fing fingers you're getting the
insides of your fingers you know you're
you're interlacing your fingers you're
getting the backs of your fingernails
you're getting your thumbs you're
getting the fingertips right and uh then
you're getting your wrists and I do this
little exercise when I do site visits
like sometimes what happens is I'll do a
site visit and um I will uh I'll I'll
bring somebody up and I will have them
Dawn a pair of gloves by the way the
technical term for putting on gloves is
Dawning right now we Dawn our gay aaro
fall la la la la right uh the technical
term is doing to take it off Dawning
doing yeah there you go I just Privia
night you're gonna be a beast I'm just
tell um but anyway lungren is what
they're gonna call
me so uh oh my God that's an Instagram
post idea I'm taking um anyway so so
what I'll do is I'll have somebody come
up and I'll say okay I'm gonna put some
hand sanitizer and your gloved hands
right they're dark gloves you can see
the difference between the dry and the
light and the dry the dry and the wet
and I'll say wash your hands like you
would normally wash your hands at home
or here at work after using the bathroom
or something like that and so they'll
wash their hands and I'm like okay now
take a look do you see all the dry spots
you see all the spots that didn't get
hand sanitizer on them and they're like
I do and I'm like okay now try try this
method that I just showed you and we do
it together in front of everybody and
I'm like now take a look at your hands
completely completely covered awesome
yeah yeah and so it's just a great way
of uh you know because any even if you
think about it like when people grab the
gloves out of the middle of the box
right like most glove manufacturers lay
their gloves alternate right like you
know they and you pull it from the
middle like Kleenex right like a tissue
box and uh you know but you're pulling
it with the finger and you're pulling on
the part that is invariably potentially
going to be totally contaminating the
gloves right yeah in in pharmaceutical
environments and in medical environments
and stuff their gloves come individually
wrapped and they're up
and uh and so that that way they could
just slip into them and put them on one
at a time makes
sense and so you know with that uh it's
like you know those little changes and
about keeping that barrier between
people who uh you know because again
it's like humans are oftentimes the
problem until robots are starting to be
able to grow you know which we don't
want to happen anyway and you're never
going to get the same level of quality
sorry smoking that tpless robot weed
that's
right oh my God but anyway so so yeah I
mean that makes me a big you know germ
nerd to the industry unfortunately no I
mean that's really good stuff I think
the people that watch my show are gonna
love it I think uh it's it's always good
the viewers out there are gonna really
enjoy it and I'd love to do a you know
we could do a seminar one of these days
together I would love to I mean if you
wanted to assemble your your your
audience together in one place or maybe
we can run through it like a co-hosted
type of co-branded type of thing you
know and you just leave it out on the on
the web people need to know this
information that's the problem they just
they don't know where to get it and and
that's you know and that's where I want
to try to be of help because when you
better understand the problem the
solution makes more sense and as you can
see or here uh the kids are
calling good stuff man well I really
appreciate you coming on the show today
if somebody wants to find out more about
you where can they get a hold of you
sure um well they can always reach me um
you know via Instagram I'm under
dyslexic Stoner
402 and uh you know with that in mind
it's uh you know I'm very responsive to
my account and uh answer questions all
the time uh and you can always reach out
to filter science.com that's FTR
science.com that's always the best ways
to to be able to find me awesome yeah
well thank you so much for your time and
uh I look forward to talking to you
really soon in the near future we got a
whole bunch of stuff to talk about
outside this
thanks so Bunch man I appreciate it wow
definely you're amazing thank you
[Music]
cheers