foreign
[Music]
how's it going everybody
welcome to the James Lab podcast I have
a special episode today ogs of the
industry we have Uncle Rick rich delisi
and we have Rick delisi and thank you
guys for coming today thank you thank
you for having us I feel blessed to be
here yeah I really appreciate it so we
have a special format for our show today
it's going to be a little bit longer
format we're really diving into uh one
of the ogs of our industry you know
thank you for your contributions
cannabis wouldn't be legal today without
people like yourself and I really
appreciate what you've gone through and
other people like yourself uh so I guess
let's dive back right to the beginning
and tell me how you started smoking pot
I started smoking pot uh when I was like
13.
I was a much bigger guy you know I was I
was a big 13 year old I had a mustache
and all that stuff when I was 13 so I
was
you know with all the food and generic
stuff that they're feeding us today so
we had my my brother-in-law had a 55
Chevy before he was my brother-in-law
and uh we were driving down Flatbush
Avenue in Brooklyn New York
and
his name was Buddy the buddy said to me
uh hey man you want to smoke some some
uh some uh weed
said smoke some weed what do you mean he
said yeah the stuff man you get I get
high on it so I said sure So I was
sitting in the back seat with my friend
Bobby right
and we started smoking
and it was so crazy because I closed my
eyes right
this the first time I ever got off
smoking I closed my eyes
and I thought they they were closed for
like five minutes and when I opened them
we were like almost in the same spot you
know we were going like 60 miles an hour
downfall Avenue
but that was the first time I smoked pot
and then um
I'm not too not too long after that
I started selling pot
right probably before I yeah I was
probably just turned 14 when I started
selling it
because
um we were in front of the stores where
I grew up right in a place called Breezy
Point Rockaway point
and uh
this Jewish kid from the neighborhood
pulls up in a Pontiac Bonneville right I
see like all the kids run over to the
car
so I said to my friend my friend BT Bob
torano I said uh
hey Bob what's the deal with that
everybody running over the car he said
oh the guy's selling pot pot and
and Ash
I said no no parking lot he's not
selling no hash and weed you know that
ain't going on you right and it took us
like about a week and a half
we had the guy's connection and
everything down pat
and that was the end of him coming and
unable it anymore right and we took it
over and then
um
my family decided to move to Florida
and when they did I was already
doing my thing craziness
um
I said yeah man I'll I'll help you guys
you know I'll help the family move I
hope the family move and I wound up
getting an apartment down there and I
realized that it was like it was like no
matter what 1300 miles closer to
Columbia because that was my thing right
that that
so uh one one day one afternoon me and
my brother driving around I had a little
Porsche
we're driving around smoking pot right
we're pulling to us to the uh 7-Eleven
on uh Sample Road and um
Pompano Beach
and we're walking out of the 7-Eleven
and I see there's a car trader you know
the car trader magazine is greater
AutoTrader sure and I see a little house
and it says Columbia house for sale
so I grabbed it
and I said to the guy hey man give me a
roll of quarters I gave my
ten dollar bill when he gave me a roll
of quarters I walked outside and I light
up The Jig and we that we had
my brother says what are you doing I
said we're going to call to Skype this
house is for sale in Columbia
brother said you [ __ ] crazy what
I said we're gonna buy this house
five days later
we didn't even have passports when I
said that to them five days later we
were in Colombia wow five days what we
did was we went to the we went to the
passport office
with tickets already we bought the
tickets without our passports and we
went to the passport office and I said
Hey listen one one of my family members
died in Colombia I have the tickets my
family gave me the tickets to go there
but I don't have a passport they said
you got your birth certificate I said
here it is my brother handed him they
said come back in two hours
wow we had about 10 hours two hours we
had our passports it's a little
different these days
it's whatever I came home I had to wait
26 days for my passport yeah I bet so
what kind of prices were you know like
if you wanted some weed or some hash on
the streets back then and this is in the
60s or 70s this in the in in the 70s the
early 70s well I used to
you know I'd bring like 30 000
once a month well sometimes sixty
thousand once a month I'd maybe put 25
000 on a boat and send it to New York or
to send it to Texas right but my my
planes could hold twenty thousand wow so
I would load up one of my DC my dc6 is
dc4s dc3s sure
I'd load up a dc6
with round-trip gas and it had a
thousand gallon tank inside the cabin
wow and we fly down through the Plano
fly back to Florida Polk County yeah
land on my friend's Ranch unload and
send it to New York and Chicago
amazing
it was uh
and people were saying oh man he was so
crazy for doing that [ __ ] I'd say
crazy you know when I was in the in the
joint they were saying man you got some
pair of balls I said no bro you got the
balls going on the 7-Eleven trying to
rob him and then shooting somebody
You Got Big Balls brass balls this [ __ ]
was like you know no big thing
but um
thank God no one ever got hurt
yeah I've done I brought a
close to a million pounds of weed into
this country wow every pound of it was
sent them on a gold that was my thing
very nice and um
I spent a few years doing it before I
got caught up in you know to Florida
the Florida syndrome it's called you
know like in other words you hire
Florida people yeah as soon as something
goes wrong there
oh wow talking to the police and that's
what happened with me I never got I
never actually got busted not this time
or the time before they actually ratted
me out and they indicted me both times
wow
so tell us a little bit about uh
what happened with that I'd go into
detail you know you you said 37 years I
did I did 32 calendars straight I did a
little bid the first time same type of
deal you know but
but I think they were they were really
aggravated with me that because what
they did was they gave me um
the first time they gave me five five
years since no seven five year sentences
running wild wow so there was a lot of
time I had to knock for a five year off
every time to get to the last five to
the last five to seven so
it was like 35 35 right so um so I knew
it was an illegal sense right when they
gave it to me right
so I said I said to my lawyer I said hey
man what's the deal he said man don't
say a word let's just let them process
everything
so they processed everything they sent
us away to prison
I called my lawyer when I got there he
said oh no problem I got a thing set up
for you for rehearing we went back they
gave me five years so I had to do three
um 369 on a five but I had to I had done
two years in the county so I only had to
do like a year and a half you know right
well and that's when Rick came into the
picture I bet like after well what
happened was I placed that first case
was um I wasn't really in the picture I
was around I was very young I was a baby
oh so you were a baby I was about five
uh when he got out the first time I was
about six years old and my mom had kind
of like kidnapped me and brought me to
Haiti and so you were born in 1977. 77
me too yeah yeah so I it's it's like
basically the first case I wasn't really
involved in because my mother had taken
me and kind of like ran away with me and
then when my pops got out
um
I was I lived with him for I think two
yeah till till he was until he was
arrested again yeah back and forth with
my mom but they were so as far back as
you can remember
he was locking he was locked up
right because we met him for about five
years of my life yeah now this this next
this this two years now so about seven
years until then he started trying to
get me out over 20 years ago yeah so
that's actually how I heard about you
originally because we met in Amsterdam I
think in 2012 yeah originally we hung
out went out to dinner yeah and you told
me the story and you told me your dad's
gonna be free one of these days sooner
than later yeah and look at this I'm
sitting in I'm sitting in your
your place today isn't that something
pretty amazing yeah
and I got my own product yeah yeah
that's that's the wildest thing totally
well so let's go you got you I'm sure
you have some really good stories of uh
smuggling and other things like was
there anything that went wrong where you
guys saved the day or you pulled out of
it where you almost got hit
well there was times you know when we
were coming back with boats and we ran
into like hurricanes and stuff and yeah
so what kind of boats you guys you guys
use like uh speed boats no no we used uh
Nazi trolls and stuff you know big oh
big big yeah you know you can put 30 40
000 pounds inside of it and drive from
Columbia to New York non-stop yeah
and um
I mean I was so crazy here's how here's
how nuts I was
from the beginning I wanted to bring a
load into New York right into where I
grew up people were saying you're crazy
I said hey man I want to bring a load
from Colombia
to Brooklyn where I grew up I want to go
right into the to the bay where I what I
used to swim right and sure enough I did
it wow
I did it I know me and my brother me my
brother Ted he's he was my partner on a
deal right
we uh
we bought a sports fishing boat
you know just the track we put all the
radio equipment and that attract the big
boat yeah you know it's 64 to
65 foot whatever it was
the Maria or the
Ranch we had I had a I had a ship once
you know actually almost was 60 000
pounds just before I got busted
I was getting ready to load sixty
thousand pounds of Thai stick on my
tanker which was called the Bantry Bay
which we took the tanks that used to be
fuel tanks we cleaned them all out and
washed out the tanks and and that's
where the weed was going but I got
popped yeah and we were going to deliver
that to Oregon
wow we had it all set up I had the the
boat never left Singapore yeah we
brought it to Singapore to have some
work done to it and then we were going
to Thailand with it and it never got to
Thailand but we had all the wheat the
weed was all somewhere yeah sitting
somewhere over there yep and we wound up
man it was such a bad deal not coming
with that I had like 10 15 000 pounds of
Buddha sticks I don't know if you
remember them
they were the real the real fat ones
like that yeah about that long
and then the other one's a regular Thai
stick Thai stick with the red oh yeah
they had the bamboo wrapped around it
around the bamboo stick yeah really cool
I've seen him
yeah I've never seen them fresh I've
only seen them really old my friend
pulled one out of a safe maybe 10 years
ago my business partner had one and when
I got up there they're back again now
you know Thailand's legal so every all
that stuff's happening again have you
been to Thailand have I been there yeah
recently no not so you got to remember
I'm only out two years it sounds like a
good place to visit oh I'm going to
Thailand yeah there's no doubt in my
mind he's going there with me yeah
if his wife will let him go if his wife
will let him go yeah she's gonna come
with yeah she'll come with us probably
right yeah nice you got to bring the
brand you know that's the whole yeah I
mean expanding International and we're
doing such and we did such wonderful
things this trip yeah I think this
thing's gonna finally start coming
together
well you know I can at least move out of
the hood where I live right you know I
live in a wild neighborhood the other
day there was five shots at like three
o'clock in the morning in the parking
lot he found this studio on the shelves
he found the shelves that pop out of the
gun when you're shooting it and this is
in Florida it's in my parking lot where
I live wow
working on so I'm in Oakland so I'm like
yeah I'm desensitized all this [ __ ]
because they got people shooting guns
yeah it's a little hardships don't come
you know it's like it's a whole
different world you know you think it's
yeah if you're in Oakland you think
Oakland's the worst but it's like
there's bad places all over yeah yeah I
think there's a hood there's a hood in
Portland yeah yeah Portland's a little
Hood now you know and I got these she
wasn't I got these little crazy things
that happened to me in my life the first
four numbers the first uh three numbers
of my license are 420. really his whole
life my whole life yeah it's really
weird my address where I live is 421
straight
all right
my license place says pow 420 on it wow
unintentional yeah and no that was
intentional like okay
the house we the house we got it because
you got lucky like it's 420 yeah yeah
when you come to your hotel room at 7 10
or 14 right yeah I love that
happens to me right I'll book into a
hotel and the room number before 20.
I had a Volkswagen repair shop me and my
father are my two brothers right
Big Time Volkswagen repair shop the
biggest one in South Florida yeah it was
a square City Block in South Florida
that we repaired Volkswagens all Bugs
and Buses right
so does wife and
and husband used to come in she had a
Volkswagen Bug and he had a bus
so he says to me hey man you smoked pot
and I said yeah smoke pot
I said what you want to smoke something
good
and I got to know this guy right
well he was planning on going to
to Jamaica
yeah and he had he had he had swindled
someone out of a real trick troller
and he says to me hey man can you come
down and look at a boat that I'm working
on uh you know we're gonna go out we're
gonna go down uh in the Caribbean and
we're gonna go diving right
so he says maybe he's not telling me
what he's really doing yet
uh
of course so so I go down and look at
the boat and I'm looking at the boat and
I'm saying oh man I want this thing for
myself
I'd like to have you spoke for myself it
was it was uh patroller
from Lake Michigan yep all Steel
quarter inch steel back to back
the uh the Keel that went from the bow
all the way to the back was a piece of
Steel this big
yeah you know like
like that the length of the boat right
and uh
I started talking to him I said well
what do you what are you what do you
plan on doing with this boat he said oh
yeah we're gonna go down to Jamaica and
we're gonna go diving and blah blah blah
we're going to bring a whole crew with
us right so I said oh okay
so he so I said he said to me hey man
can you do some work on both me on you
on your offside I'm at work I said yeah
I'll get this thing right for you right
it has 671 D's on it so I did all kinds
of work to the thing
and then he hit me with the with the
with the move he said hey man I'll give
you 5 000 bucks
if you go on this boat and keep it
running I'm going to Colombia I'm going
to Jamaica to fill it up with weed
he said man we're gonna do it I got the
weed waiting down there
I said we'll bring it let's go
he said man go shopping
build a boat up with whatever you guys
want to eat you need a partner to come
with you so I called my friend in New
York
and I told my friend in New York I said
hey man I'm sending you a ticket get on
the flight
get on the flight come on down here he
said what's up I said huh
we're gonna go we're gonna go on a boat
trip
so my friend came in from you know he
flew down said well what's up I said oh
we're going to get some weed down in
Jamaica yeah so my friends is like for
real you don't even so hopped up about
it right
we wound up
he wound up coming down
seen the boat he was like really excited
right
I saw on the way back on the way down
I mean
I you know what a dolphin is right oh
yeah yeah all right I caught one
I'll tell you Dorado I'm almost six feet
tall
it was six feet tall really
its eyes were this big yeah they changed
color too he would catch them it was
this wine its head was that wide and it
was that
now you gotta we're sitting up on the
top we're listening to the Grateful Dead
in the Boombox yeah I'm with smoking
Jays right we got the automatic pilot on
which was a rope
hooked to the steering wheel was our
automatic pilot yeah
and uh I had 200 I had 150 foot ski line
out the back
a hundred foot and 150 foot at 150 foot
a hit the dolphin yeah so what's in that
smoking or not oh man you know we're
like you know the bread bag joints yeah
and a red bag joints that's a good term
yeah everyone knows what a red bag is oh
no if you put like four ounces in a tray
you know yeah yeah
so uh
we're sitting up there right and I see
the ski line
bouncing
like there's a skier on it
it's bouncing along but uh
but it it goes I'm looking out the side
of the boat and the thing is trying to
pass the boat but it's it's a doubtful
with a hook in its mouth it's like a
whale I said hey Bobby check this out as
soon as I said that this [ __ ] dolphin
came out of the water and I tell you it
danced on its tail like this yeah
well like
10-15 seconds yeah with the college you
know about the colors with all these
calls I said holy [ __ ] we ran we ran
across the steel top of the boat went
down the steel ladder right
and we're pulling the cake we're pulling
this fish in right this fish ain't going
nowhere right it's got a hook in its
mouth like this
it's got a hook like that in its mouth
yeah because what I was dragging was was
a feather
with a with a 1500 pound test why a
leader up hook to the ski line yeah so
the ski line was 20 feet 25 feet from
the fish yeah and we're pulling this
thing in right
and I tell my I tell my Pawn to Bobby I
said Bobby go get my bat I had a bat in
the boat right pulling this thing in
and Bobby goes gets gloves because he's
got to pull the wire right we bring this
thing in and I
I get the bat and I'm beating this thing
up and the blood is flying everywhere oh
yeah
I'm not the captain on the boat yeah I'm
only like like a first mate and Bobby's
like a first mate right
so we're literally covered from head to
toe with blood from this fish bouncing
around
we finally got it beat it beat its
brains out right yeah I'm covered in
blood and I got the bat right and I
rinse the bat off yeah and I walk up the
side of the boat now I'm covered
and I and I I go hey man here's the bat
and the cap the captain of the boat
looks at me right
he thinks I my friend he thinks I beat
my friend up with the bat
so so he's like he's where's BT
I said BT's in the back
he said tell him to come up here for a
minute I said he's trying to clean we're
getting ready you know to clean off the
deck and everything oh he said okay
because he thought I'd beat him up with
the back
and um oh it was so crazy and then on
the way back we ran into this crazy
crazy February storm
I'm talking 30 40-foot season we're in
there with the boat overloaded up
make a long story short we wound up
losing I'm laying in the bunk
and we're in these
30-foot Seas yeah you know like the
perfect storm type [ __ ] right and I mean
it's crazy right all you see is up or
down yeah we're laying I'm laying in the
bunk and I got two seat belts across me
I'm laying in the bottom bunk and my
front BT's in the top bunk and the
captain and the other guy are taking
care of the boat right yeah
well I hear some kind of freaky noise
right so I unclip my seatbelt my
seatbelt that's holding me in the bunk
yeah and I put my feet on the floor the
water's up to my nose
inside the cabin up to my knees wow
there's no way we're going to survive if
this boat sinks right
is this water coming over it broke the
two front windshields out of the boat a
wave came over the top you know we went
down
went underneath the wave
and then when it popped back up another
wave hit it and knocked out both windows
you know they were about this big right
that was it so we had a
we had to think real fast we turned the
boat around I tore up the carpet I got
this marine plywood off the floor yeah
we had to unbolt it and this is we're
doing this in 30 foot Seas You Gotta
totally and then then I gotta cut this
stuff with a jigsaw and then someone's
got to go outside
with a rope around them and put it up
against the windows and drill holes we
had to do all this in this terrible
storm
and you know it's just unbelievable
I just said God get me home yeah just
get me home this one time I'll never do
this again
um make a long story here I lied to
right God it wasn't your last time no it
wasn't
because I thought I was I I always
thought it was the right thing I was
doing
agreed I never felt that it was like an
unrighteous thing to smuggle you know
there was a few times when I was down in
Colombia
and uh you know I was picking up like 30
000 pounds with the airplane yep
and it'd be some of the somebody you
know the the um
the Colombians like the Goombas
and they'd have like I don't know
fifteen hundred two thousand pounds of
cocaine there and they tell me yeah just
take it to America and
and we'll give you x amount of dollars I
said man I don't take that I don't mess
that [ __ ] that [ __ ] kills people right I
said in my in my wildest dream you
couldn't get me to do that if I was
broke on my ass and but he trade him and
get a break for himself and go party
but I said listen yeah I heard so many
stories of him farting oh but listen I
say to him well you know I'll take one
key
hmm they say you take one I said no I
want one key you know for me and my guys
when I get home and I'd buy a key off to
them and give them like 2 000. you know
when I could have got it for like 800 a
key of coke yeah in Colombia
okay so that was the Maria deal so we're
coming back the windows get sold then
it takes us a bunch of hours to get
everything squared away and we're back
on our on our course yeah so you got the
pump going getting the water out of
there oh man forget about it the boat is
luckily it didn't sink because it had a
a sealed up engine room yeah we get all
the water pumped out
we we go over this Reef in the Bahamas
and we cut a hole through the reefs to
go into this little Lagoon around the
back of the reef
we sat there for three days
with the boat going up and down eight
nine feet at a time yeah
you know with the anchor out
we lost all food
and SEPTA had some fish in the freezer
and that's what we survived on and
here's the wildest part when we were
leaving Jamaica I had met this Rasta guy
down there
which was looking out for us on the
heavy duty Chinese smoke down there you
know the Chinese people down there go to
best smoke so he made sure to laid the
best smoke right he had the dreadlocks I
mean for real
hanging off dead hair you know like for
10 years he had a way down his back
and when I'm leaving he's helping him
load the boat but he comes back after we
got all the weed on the boat and he says
to me
he's waving to me and I'd say hey what's
up he said uh
man I just bought you some food and
stuff he brought me pineapples mangoes
all the stuff right and none of it was
really ripe
so I had two holes in the back
that had propane tanks in it when I only
had one propane tank aboard one of them
big ones you know yeah and the other
hole was empty that there wasn't a tank
in it so I opened it up and I put that
stuff in there and when I closed it the
string that was on it you know I tied
off so it wouldn't lay in the bottom
yeah
and that's what fed us within three or
four days that and and the fish that we
had nice and then we took the wooden
windows down
and we drove right into into Lighthouse
Point with the boat you know like we
were fishing guys and we were coming
home from fishing
and uh
some of the weed got wet
the weed that was in the main in the in
the uh
in the master bedroom yeah underneath
the bed
had got wet it was like 300 pounds right
so after we're all done well what
happened was during the deal the captain
backed out of the deal huh he wanted to
get off the boat I said man
take the dinghy and go do what you got
to do I said I ain't getting nothing I
ain't getting in no Boston well and it's
30 foot Seas you got to be [ __ ] crazy
right so he said will you take over the
steel then
so me and BT took over because when I
got on the boat I said to Bobby
he's a master a master Carpenter Master
a master a artist
I said Bobby you make sure before we
leave this [ __ ] dock if something
happens to these two guys on the boat
that you know how to get us home he said
oh no problem he [ __ ] took out the
the maps and everything you know to
right looked at everything said yeah man
I could do this in the Stars if I have
to with the Stars I can come home wow so
I said you sure I said yeah no problem
bro Bobby Toronto's an amazing human and
that was it
so um
we get back right we unload the boat we
come in we come in Wild deal coming in
yeah we had to stop because it was low
tide in the boat
to draft on the boat couldn't get into
the canal where we wanted to go
so we parked on the intercoastal hmm
at this time
my father and my brother think that I'm
dead they think they're both sunk in the
ocean with me and my friend they've been
watching the weather on the news
nothing's on the news yet nothing oh wow
but my father knows because my brother
had to tell him that what I was doing
actually oh [ __ ] so
and he didn't show up on time I didn't
show and no calls nothing when I got to
the dock I went right up to the phone
booth I called my father's house I said
hey Pop what's going on said have you
heard anything from your brother he
thinks he's talking to my brother Chuck
yeah
I said no I haven't heard from nobody
I'm just calling you you said who is
this I said it's Richard
he said where the [ __ ] are you
I set him down on the intercoastal
dad go to Abbey Road and get me a couple
of steak dinners
and a couple of lobster dinners and
bring them down to the thing
the world is [ __ ] crazy uh lobster
dinner steak and I said dad go get the
[ __ ] steak dinner I have any days so
we [ __ ] went and got all the stuff
right
so he's still gonna go on the boat
meanwhile you can go in the cabin in the
boat and you don't see nothing yeah
he'll walk right inside the cabin and
there's
but the bathroom's loaded you know you
don't want to take a [ __ ] you gotta
unload the bathroom you know crazy
though if you want to shower you got to
unload the bathroom wow but um
so it was like 300 pounds right double
wet so at the end of the day when I
distributed everything to where it was
going because I was in charge then it
went from five grand that I'm gonna make
a lot of money now
and uh when I got back there
Alan richler
which was the guy that wanted to be in
the rat
not already
what's that I see here you want it
already yeah it's this weed so this is
some super silver haze oh yeah
it's a classic super silver you're
making me on I'm gonna try this so I
rolled a smaller one in this but yeah
it's super strong it's grown by flora
and Flame in Oakland it's living soil
it's it's good stuff but it definitely
gets you high it gives me the yawns and
it got it gets me to wake back up so um
so what happens is I tell I tell this
kid Allen I sit down and throw the [ __ ]
in your van take it to the dumpster yeah
up it pole up at uh Winn-Dixie and throw
it in the dumpster sure on the way home
there's no problem I got you
he doesn't take it he puts it in his car
and takes it to his house
then he goes rents a warehouse the next
day
now this kid is going to make like a
hundred grand and this is in 1970 yeah
100 Grand is like 2 million yeah at
least you know and I'm gonna get my I'm
gonna get my share I'm gonna get like me
and my friend are gonna wind up with 50
G's 60 G's right
so he takes I I distributed all the weed
to people that I knew that I was dealing
with
I had to wait like four or five days to
get the money because I fronted
everything I gave all the weed out on
the front on a handshake
but I said in five days
I'm coming north and as I go I want to
collect everything as I'm going to New
York and that's what I did I collected
all the money
we went to New York or I got to New York
I made a deal with somebody to take the
remaining
um money that I owe the Jamaicans Down
To Jamaica
because I had to take care of all that
this kid you know the captain and the
other guy was out of it so now I'm in
charge of all that [ __ ]
and I think the Jamaicans like me much
more than them because I went back there
many times and they were like
always with their arms like this amazing
country yeah it's an amazing country
it's really a wild it's it's uh now it's
really nice you know it's really getting
my friend Steve D'Angelo has a as a
resort down there right now nice yeah I
mean the weed is good it's always been
good you know the funny thing is there's
bat really bad weed there too but then
the good stuff the Orange Hill the
Lamb's breads
yep oh the lamb spread who grows up in
the I don't know if it's one dude or a
group that grow over there by Negril
yeah but the weed went from like decent
until outrageous holy [ __ ] that was the
Chinese people real Landry [ __ ] and
there wasn't wasn't much of that it was
like even Lamb's bread is like hard I
haven't even seen it in Jamaica I never
actually seen it I've seen it here I've
seen some hybrids of it I definitely
know the [ __ ] musky Terps but uh yeah
and so when you were getting flour in
Jamaica do you remember the strains that
they have specific strains or was it
just a good weed or no it was just it
was either the Chinese people had it
yeah what did you make inside it
but did you did Chinese
grew superb read
any of the Chinese smoke that you got
was just like this stuff you know like
like the stuff we used to I just want to
come back to one thing so just uh the
reason why you got busted the first time
oh well I'm gonna go run by that in a
minute it was wet the weed was wet so
the weed was wet so we took it to a
whales
meanwhile I'm doing my thing to get him
his the rest of his money right
and I don't know what's going on with
the I didn't know he had the weed in a
warehouse right
yeah so I started making my moves and
I'm going to New York I'm going to go to
New York buy a van customize it and go
to California and buy a house right on
the west coast nice
so we're making our move going and uh
I get to New York
I buy a Ford van like a two-year-old van
and my friends are Master Carpenter he
tricks it out inside TV you know the
whole deal bunk you know what I mean
really tricked out nice lights and
everything back there
and uh
we drop he buys a common gear while
we're in Florida off my off my family a
brand new like almost a random time of
year
and now we're gonna both drive out to
California I got my friend Joe in the
truck with me or my friend Bobby so
there's going to be four of us in two
cars
we drive out to the coast you know a lot
of stuff happened on our way out there
like
we stopped in Vegas and I had like
I don't know I think I blew like four 20
how much was it 18 000 I blew in the
casino yeah and I went up to get another
five thousand
and my friend that was with me said
don't touch that money bro
Bobby will [ __ ] choke you in the
morning
see [ __ ] give me that money I [ __ ]
took the money went back down
I won like 35 40 000. right nice yeah it
was pretty cool and Bobby never even
found out about that right
so we get to California
and we I'm going in on we're buying a
house right on the right on the Pacific
coast it's got a status electric thing
that goes down to the beach it's called
the steps I don't know if you know about
that place and said by the San Diego
no it's called the steps all the surface
surf out there nice
so we'll buy in the second house from
the steps
and uh I call home my father says to me
hey man
here on the front page of the Sun
Sentinel
I should get a [ __ ] life pop what's
up
he said man you got to come back the U.S
Marshals were here twice today looking
for you I said what's up
he says you know what's up
your boy your boy got caught with some
weed I said who got caught away he says
retsma
he had some weed in a warehouse he was
drying it
and the and the people the Carpenters
that had the warehouse next to it
couldn't stand the smell so they called
the police oh God
I said you got it he says you got to
come home right now
so I'm like [ __ ] I'm getting ready to
buy this thing with my friends right I
had to come home
and that was the first bus I went to two
trials on that Federal
and I'd beat both of them nice
beat both trials the first time uh
I was found innocent oil charges
and then the second time
they indicted me
for perjuring myself
they wanted me to wrap my friend out my
they put my friend into the into my
friend John they bring him into the into
the courtroom they say all right you see
John peglin around anymore where you
know the guy that was on a boat would
you
he's sitting right there at the you know
yeah said he ain't here said well what
do you look like blah blah blah
but I had gave two different I didn't
realize
that when I told him the first time you
know what the guys look like on the boat
when they were asking me I said I don't
know these guys names I only know what
they look like yeah I said I was I was a
prisoner on the boat I couldn't get off
the boat so it hit Florida
and and Richmond said when that boat
touched the dock that I got off it and I
never went back on it well
and that's what he told him in court and
that's that's what actually freed me and
them two guys that ratted Richmond and
his friend they're the guys that did the
time nice after trying to burn off after
trying to burn you yeah yeah so that's
how that one ended the first one
pretty good stuff really nice and then
there was two after that
good flavor look at that oil right yeah
and you know
it's crazy how like that's all just a
bail getting wet you know and then all
from the smell because
trying to you know everybody making a a
group decision like
yeah we're gonna get rid of that because
it's it's trash we don't want people
smoking salt water we and then the dude
being like nah let me go
I'm supposed to drop it off and let me
go put it in the storage space and then
try to dry it right and that decision
I paid him in full yeah because I had
someone when I got to Melbourne
my friend uh dick latree I don't know if
you ever heard of him he was like a very
famous surfer he owned the surf shops in
Cocoa
but he was a famous famous surfer right
and uh
I had sold
I think like 2500 pounds to him
and he had to catch me so I said Hey
listen man I can't go back to South
Florida
to me if he's in Coco so I said man
could you bring this down to Pompano and
give it to this guy
he said who's the guy I said he's my
party he's good meanwhile just [ __ ]
jerk off who's getting ready to rat me
out and I didn't even know it right
so he goes down and pays him I call
britz
oh yeah man I got paid okay man great
everything's good yeah meme always got
this [ __ ] weed in the warehouse
trying it
so I go up get my van my friend
customizes the inside and we're driving
out to California like I said I lost the
morning I get to California
and my phone I call my father who tells
me yeah man you're on the front page of
the Sun Sentinel I said you know I
thought he was [ __ ] kidding me but
meanwhile I was under in the front page
for one month straight wow the Miami
Herald and the Sun Sentinel in Fort
Lauderdale a month straight they had a
story on me every day
and when they arrested me
they are an odd me to my father
no you know not a not a Cash Pawn Yeah
because
when when I was in California I said to
my father I ain't [ __ ] going back to
Florida I'm going to Mexico I said [ __ ]
this house I'll go to Mexico you know
start something going for Mexico right
but my father talked me out of it
and that that was the beginning
of really
all of this all that yeah
and I hate to say it like that and it
sounds very one part of it it sounds
very selfish you're a partner no but but
so so here's my look my Outlook on that
in my opinion is that if it wasn't for
people that pushed the envelope like
yourself there would be none of this
around today like it is now it may be in
some different form but it would
probably still be illegal you know and
there would be a small group but it's
really the people that push the envelope
that made the difference you know for
legalization
yeah so because yeah
and the demand to understand it also so
that's just a product and people start
well there had to be a supply it was so
wild for me when I was a kid yeah
because I couldn't believe it I'd buy a
pound
and I'd nickel it up into nickel bags
yeah now a shot glass was a Nickelback
back when I was growing up and the brown
envelopes you know you folded them in
half you know
stuffed it and everything was just fat
right
so 500 of them in one day wow for five
dollars each
[ __ ] nuts yeah you know when you're a
kid then and I was a kid yeah in the 70s
totally no that that's late 60s that's
before I even started smuggling okay
wow you know I buy a pound nickel it up
maybe make a couple ounces if I had one
of my special guys that I had wanted a
quarter of a pound I'd get a pound and a
quarter would they cost back then for a
pound a pound it was like uh 24 bucks
24 bucks a pound yeah wow
you got to buy like 50. sure and you
know I bought them from I bought them
from Mitch's uh the Goomba that I was
talking to in the hospital the other day
oh my god oh Stevie Gallo yeah you don't
know the Gallo Brothers right from New
York sure Steve Gallo the gangsters
yeah yeah and they they love me I'd go
and I say I am give me give me 30 pounds
cash them right out they'd be like what
the [ __ ] just it's [ __ ] young little
[ __ ] driving a brand new
Corvette
I had to bring a Corvette in a parking
lot nice and that was 1966.
1967. crazy where did the vet go for
then both years I had brand new
Corvettes like nine thousand dollars
something like that 11 000 something
like that 4 800. 4 800. wow
right now at 200 Grand yeah
you want a nice sport 27 67 yeah you
know a spotless one you're going for 200
Grand
matter of fact his buddy which is a
Sheik yeah is trying to get one right
now because of what I told him about the
cars nice well they're only going to
appreciate those cars are just going to
keep going up in value oh yeah
that's the only
I I me and my brother were tripping one
day in my car and we went into Manhattan
and we went to we went to uh
I forgot what the name of the club was
but it was in the East Village
and I mean we got trashed on acid we're
tripping
so my brother says are you gonna be okay
to drive I said yeah man what are you
kidding
so we we go through the Brooklyn Battery
Tunnel yeah I'm going 130 miles an hour
which was in Battery Tunnel on acid
with side pipes you know what side pipes
are the side pipes on the bed yeah yeah
you know what it sounds like when you're
going that fast in the tunnel
whoa
we get through the tunnel and I go
through the the toll booth I go through
the toll booths to like 80 miles an hour
well you know because I knew it was they
were going to be they were going to come
after me right so what I did was instead
of staying on the parkway
I I made the left and went on an Ocean
Parkway off the belt right
and I got away from them but we get
halfway home my brother says where's my
jacket
my wallet's in my jacket
we had to go back to Manhattan but we
couldn't go we couldn't go in the same
path we couldn't go through the battery
we had to go to the Brooklyn Bridge go
over to Brooklyn Bridge and go far
downtown you know to the Village right
and make sure and get everything oh my
God it was so crazy
so uh speaking of acid so you have uh
you used to be our probably are still a
big fan of the Grateful Dead and you you
knew Mickey Hart
yeah oh me and Mickey were tight nice
I'm trying to I'm trying to get with him
while I'm out here right now yeah he's
the one he made me what a thousand
t-shirts
I don't think the t-shirts ever got made
yeah they got Maids did I noticed it was
I noticed it was like 500 of them in in
boxes he made these special t-shirts for
my release he was part of a yeah but he
was part of a deal with someone else and
they did something and he said he
couldn't do it hmm
but yeah I'd love to see Mickey while
I'm out here yeah I got a couple friends
so that could hook up yeah let him know
I'm out here right for sure for sure and
then uh so Grateful Dead what else did
you listen to music wise back then
because those were some of the best
years for music I think oh my God it was
so it was so it was
it was unbelievable the way that
everything went down yeah from when I
started when I when I started hanging
with the dead I met so many Rock people
you know Gracie Slick uh uh Janice
Chaplin I mean I'm Jimi Hendrix I used
to smoke joints for Jimi Hendrix in uh
Steve Paul scene we used to go
downstairs and see Paul scene and man
yeah and smoke joints together
I'm talking about smoking a joint with
Jimi Hendrix you know yeah really cool
and wherever the dude went I was welcome
there you know
I met Santana there I met oh I met so
many people there and I used to hang
around in this place called on Deans I
don't know if you ever hear of it um
this was like the club on the right next
to the 59th Street Bridge
that
it was like this little Club
my friend my friend was a door manner I
could have never ever ever got into
place
it's this little teeny Club but it's
really Swanky yeah and all the people
that are in the music business you know
like this jockeys like murder Decay and
all them guys from New York they all go
there
and they have a little teeny stage and
that's where I met Jim Morrison in the
doors and I'm at uh Cher
nice you know they just my friend said
yes this guy this guy's come from
California it's Jim Morrison he's
supposed to be a wild guy right wow and
uh yeah he wound up being a wild guy
seriously yeah he did
but I've had a I've had a I've had a
pretty crazy life you know yeah and now
it's starting to uh
settle down
you know I'm kind of settling down but
this whole thing that's going on right
now yeah I want to make sure I'm a part
of it I want to go down to History part
of it I think yeah no no I know I have
to be a part of it and you're you're
definitely I need to I need to do this
yeah
now is the time I mean I feel like the
people that are still here
you know we're looking at each other
like hey
we got this yes you know and I mean it's
tough It's been tough in the industry uh
whether you're doing cultivation or
genetics or anything like that there's
more competition but there's a lot of
[ __ ] products on the market I think
there's definitely a place for high-end
Boutique products and authentic people
yep
so I think that's a big part of it
um so tell us a little bit about your
brand so you launched your brand in
Florida so is it in Florida originally
yeah I I launched my brand in Florida
um
Kim Rivers is is a wonderful woman yeah
that whatever she tells you
well whatever she told me
she did she didn't there was no like a
little curve you know okay we said we
were going to do this but we can't do
that now because some can whatever she
told me she was gonna do she did and she
said it's going to take this long to
start building your deal
because when when me and Richie went to
pick out the generics genetics generic
I'm sorry
the weed's good so when we went to pick
out the stuff right they only had a
small amount of what we wanted but we
that's what we wanted so we had to wait
a while
for them to get it going you know get
the mothers going and the babies and
everything and now they got it it's
Trucking nice we went up there the other
day
and it's a first class first class
operation you know it was wild how that
all came about
um
basically my cousin
had gone shout out to my cousin Kenny
is he the one I met in Vegas yeah yeah
what's up Ken Darby we're here we love
you brother yeah
and on simply radio and Kenny Darby
um so he basically went to go meet uh
bread yeah they went thread man invited
us to a party in this mansion in Miami
yeah it was an event where red man had
arranged a party and my cousin went
there and met him
and Kim Rivers was there and I had just
basically asked my cousin to start you
know trying to help me out with my dad
in the whole situation because in the
beginning
yeah I was just it was like almost
unreal to have my father back in my life
and then to figure out how because I was
based in Amsterdam right right so I had
to figure out how to like get back
around him to make something happen and
my cousin has been that conduit
and um yeah he he um basically stepped
to Kim Rivers at that party when she
walked by
and um kind of like
shouted her name and then he said he
goes he goes hey Kim
and she looked over at him right and I'm
standing right next to him and he says
to me oh I'd like you to meet my Uncle
Richard
you looked at me he said I know who your
Uncle Richard is
yeah and I reached out and shook a hand
when I shook her hand and I'm not lying
to you you know when you shake someone's
hands and you click with them yeah it
was there was a click there
and I knew she was for real
and I and we had said uh
um
Kenneth said to her
however you can help us out she goes oh
you know I can't mess with you guys you
guys are with Burner I said why not with
Berna
I wouldn't be stepping to you if I was
with Berna
I said I want to do something with you
she said pre-rolls for starters
and now we got we got three rows
we got live rosin
we got buds flower
and we're gonna have gummies there
shortly we're just truly from Florida
now out here on the West Coast
we're looking to hook up with people
like you nice
excellent
yeah you know I think you guys are doing
and how many dispensaries are you guys
in I think there's 124 shops there's 123
in Florida yeah and I think there's more
there's like I think there's 30 in
Maryland no but um 20 in Maryland or
something just Florida is the only place
we're operating 21 and 121 in Florida
I've been to 85 of them already
well I go there and you know meet the
people take pictures
yeah Tallahassee yeah you know
Moss my stuff
does not stay on the shelf in Florida I
set all new records for for True leaf
it's like it doesn't last more than two
days right and but that now that
it's changed
as soon as it runs out they fill it back
up again well yeah so my my feeling on
wreck and one of the problems with all
this wreck cannabis is that a lot of
it's not fresh if you get Fresh Products
it's a lot better if it moves if the
companies are moving their product but
if you're getting it you know even six
eight weeks after harvest Sometimes some
of these Brands the flour tastes like
[ __ ] even though the genetics were good
it might have even been grown correctly
but yeah I think the flowers were
hitting at what 28 or something I don't
know the 29 yeah and then the uh the
pre-rolls were 23 uh 24 9. yeah he I
love the pre-rolls yeah you know he gets
on me because I bought him when I go
there I buy them you know they charged
me like five bucks
when I'm with him I don't bite them yeah
you know
I mean I buy pre-rolls from dispensaries
just so I could try out the flour yeah
some of this stuff they have pretty good
free rolls that have free rolls
pre-rolls they got pretty good ones out
there now in
Washington and California and Colorado I
feel like are doing a pretty good job
with quality a flower I think it's you
know I think the Market's a lot more
stable in like Washington Seattle area
that Market's really stable you know I
mean they went through their second
um recession but yeah it's it's
interesting up there you know so I work
up there as well okay cool yeah
pretty rose is wild because you know you
can give a
a person like a a more I guess valuable
product from their essay you know what
do you guys think of the pre-rolls that
are infused with either diamonds or
rosin hash holes if it works if people
if there's a market for it I you know I
support it like a lot of the hassles I
know it's a niche market makes a lot of
sense you know right
um some of the some of the infused stuff
can be kind of
yeah I like I like it to be like
some sort of quality kept to it yeah
um but most of the stuff that I see is
like weird Kief and
yeah something but I I have tasted a lot
of good ones I was just uh shout out to
cgo Lifestyle it's just smoking his
Heroes and they were insane like crazy
Donuts just yeah crazy flavors and
rosin that really pairs well with the
flower I don't I think there's a big
market for like good pre-rolls also you
know yeah
I see it through a lot yeah you roll
good joints so like when it's hard to
find pre-rolls that are on that level
there's a guy that was on the show a
while back the professional joint roller
at Instagram that guy rolls amazing
bombers I mean I learned how to roll
from him like I learned a new way to
roll from him that I think is really
cool all right it's this guy yesterday
we met yeah you can go to this class
cost a thousand bucks to learn how to
roll it I think it's like a I think he
was joking when he said that I don't
think he was joking I don't think it's
done yet
this guy rolled a j yeah
we were talking about it I got do I have
one of my jackets I think I got one in
my jacket
yeah nice yeah amazing amazing it's it's
wild how you can roll now I mean these
new tips like did you roll on those tips
or you bought that no no I I got them
from from dude I think okay so you got
it from organic tips.com or something
like that oh I'm not sure I wrote my own
like that's like she got a piece of wood
around it it's like wood not like
this is the same thing yeah oh it's got
a tip in the middle yeah and then you
just put the filter inside super fire
and you just put your filter inside okay
that's why it's like that and as a trick
to folding the filter to go in there to
make it look like that I'm big on paper
tips yeah me too I used to like glass
for a minute but I really think that
weight watching this is annoying yeah I
agree yeah I like I like I feel like the
paper tastes good if you use good tips
like this OG raw tips yeah then you use
those to make a crutch and then using
the the piece of dude you can yeah so
this guy professional joint roller he
does that and he takes like the sticky
part and cuts it off and then uses that
to wrap around and hold the tip together
not so yeah
I mean
you know everybody's making money out
here
we just softened oh I don't know about
everybody I mean there's a good crew
making money yeah
and uh there's so many people that are
still inside for non-violent marijuana
charges and that's insane you know and I
mean did this 40 000 right in us right
in the states without the feds just in
the states
I mean uh
they gave what they give the kid in
Louisiana or something
three lives for for a quarter of a pound
or something lately
there was something crazy like that I
was like still happening
it's so crazy because I feel like most
people I mean you got you got you got
you got organizations like last
prisoners projects Freedom grow
these people were trying to get people
out of prison
they don't care about nothing
they don't even care about making any
money
they care about just getting people home
to their folks right you know where they
can spend time with their children or
the mother and their father you know I
was I I got you know like 32 years that
I did I lost my mom my dad I lost a
couple of children yeah you know it's
not cool it's uh and I can't I can't go
back and say to somebody well you had me
locked up for something that's legal now
yeah I want get back right in Florida
they entrapped me into the deal but they
don't have entrapment lawyer in Florida
wow if it would happen to New York I
would have been found innocent right
because a cop can't set you up yeah
that's what they did
yeah it's wild
so yeah and it you know people being
just this guy this guy Jim White and
Shelly white yep
they owned this place called the naked
lady Ranch
all right
you know he was one of my Pilots
he wound up setting me up put me away on
his last deal wow
so the last deal was with planes
the last deal was a plain deal yeah do
you want to go into that and you know
that uh that whole experience before you
got in trouble and kind of what you were
doing I told them I don't want to do
nothing yeah I said just get me the
money on me had when I when I was in
prison
he stole one of my executive aircrafts
and crashed it
the only reason the guy was breathing
and talking to me on a telephone that
day is because my cousin climbed back up
into the wreckage of the plane unhooked
his seat belt and dropped the sky out of
the plane
when he dropped them the guy
the guy when he dropped him out of the
plane it was like because they were on
top of uh banana watches when the plane
crashed oh wow you know it came apart
wings or you know it all did weed all
over the place
that side of the plane got
bad this side got ripped off so my
cousin got a cut on his knee that was it
he unhooked and dropped out of the plane
because he thought it was going to go up
in Flames wow
he felt the guy propulsed the guy had no
pulse so he dropped down and he crawled
away and threw up he was he was semi in
shock
well he's laying up against the tree
waiting for the Jamaicans to come to get
them to get him right
and he sees the guy left his head up in
the plane
it goes holy [ __ ] I gotta go back he
goes back and climbs up gets him pulls
them out drops and the guy drops if he
was a ball on the ground like this
all his bones are broken in his body
his legs his back his hips falling so
far no from the eye from the plane
when my cousin pulled him out he was he
was when he when he was holding him he
was like seven feet long the guy's only
like five some wow he was like seven
feet and then when he dropped him he
wasn't he was this high on the ground
sad
compound fractures and oh man it was
crazy it's rough and and this guy is the
guy that set me up my cousin saved his
life
crazy
good morning for money
[ __ ] up why are you doing it man
right
people don't
it's just
it blows me away man
it blows me away you know to see a guy
[ __ ] get caught doing something
stitching on something that's from wave
back you know it's just I mean I see so
many people fall the things that they
did 10 years ago
because they did it with somebody they
got in trouble you know we did this one
I just got one dollar on the weekend we
brought in like 35 keys of coke yeah
who's the guy
he was the Kingpin yeah I just worked
for him
and then they go get the guy
years later in Florida crazy yeah and I
get away with it they put the guy away
for Life yeah that's nuts
Lord had a lot of
smuggling going on I mean that's so
corrupt now they all want in on it
all the Congress members up there in
Tallahassee they were all trying to get
their hands on stores and with farms and
they all want to grow weed now right for
the [ __ ] that they gave me 98 years for
they want to grow now and make money off
of it right so yeah so what do you think
of the California scene I love it
we might even get a place in San
Francisco you should
yeah we've been talking about it it's
expensive but it's nice the city's nice
yeah I'll keep a place in Florida
because I really like Florida the one I
would like I like San Francisco it's
nice when it's nice here yeah it's nice
but like we've been trying for two days
in the rain yeah it was nice when you
guys landed oh yeah we made it we made a
beautiful land and we bought beautiful
sunshine and we ran into good Sunshine
again the weather's usually always super
night we're not here I always love San
Francisco yeah we only have a week of
this and it's gonna be nice
three months yeah exactly although we
had really really strange year with
weather yeah we had so much the most
rain I've ever seen in my life more rain
than ever right more rain than ever that
looks scary I was seeing it on the news
every day it looked really kind of it
was it was I think the news makes oh is
that what it is it wasn't scary he was
coming to California for two months he
kept throwing it yeah I'm going to
California
then I call almost two days later okay
what's going on with the California trip
oh I'm not going it's still raining yeah
I mean it was flooding you know so it
was like it seemed like a a good time to
come you know right
but um yeah we're here now
nice then you're off to Hawaii after
this yes sir so your family lives in
Hawaii or yeah Maui nice
yeah right and he wants to get a place
from here in Hawaii too no I want I want
if everything goes right what's going on
yeah I'll have a place away
Florida
New York
San Francisco and San Francisco just
rotate through yeah so hey I gotta go
with that for this week two weeks get
that all straight yeah you know maybe he
ain't with me maybe I got Kenneth's with
me or maybe I got Joe with me or you
know maybe I got Sean with me
I got one somebody with me you know
so what's your favorite food in New York
I guess my all-time favorite food in New
York is of course Italian yeah but the
Chinese in New York the Chinese food see
since I was a kid involved with the
Grateful Dead yeah we used to go to dead
concerts in the Fillmore you know I go
knock on the back door they'd open up
the door and say uh who's ever Rollo
they call me Rollo who's ever Rollo come
on in there was 20 people standing I say
come on
you know people that you know hippies
and [ __ ] come on come on in but most of
the time the 20 people that were there
came right from my neighborhood with me
well you know we all drove together and
uh Volkswagen Vans and Volkswagen bugs
that's what we all had that's nuts
yeah I had an outstanding
child you know when I growing up as a
child and growing up as a teenager good
experiences it was a different world
back then I mean even us growing up is
you know being born in 77 it was a
different world when we were kids 100
friends no completely it's a trip just
like the phone age the phone age yeah we
didn't have cell phones when I was a kid
we had pagers when I was like in high
school yeah later yeah but and then cell
phones but it wasn't like a smartphone
oh forget it I had a phone
I had a belt you had to wear around what
they call it what they call the phone
remember you used to tell me they used
to call them the what the block Rick
phone the brick phone the big old brick
phones oh my God I can remember the
first time I got one yeah I took it to
California with me right I was drag
racing professionally
and I'm standing on the start line in
Pomona and the [ __ ] phone rings
I'm like you gotta be [ __ ] kidding me
you know it rang on my side
vibrated right so I took it over oh no
it was my wife calling me from
I was like you gotta be [ __ ] kidding
me
and now look at this I came out now this
is what they give me when I come out of
the prison after 32 years I was like
what the [ __ ] is that are you used to it
yet yeah hell no
the dopamine every day I don't expect to
imagine that yeah yeah for sure like
dealing with like sensory overload yeah
sensory overload like every day
different ways I learned something I'll
submit with this thing you do video
calls with people all that stuff it's
like oh I got all that movies yeah a lot
of stuff was in the movies in the 70s
and 80s and now it's legit
it's crazy
I mean we used to get like a little
phone in there you know inside the joint
right nothing like this yeah I mean we
had a flip phone you know a little
burner you could send a picture you
could flush it down the toilet right you
know it was a little thing like this pig
if when it closed it was like that big
you could flush it right down and throw
it wow they never catch you with it
so where were you incarcerated
all over Florida okay I was in like 10
different prisons in bed though all
right they trans it was in fed
yeah yeah they leave you somewhere for
and they think you're getting a little
comfortable there and you're they see it
it went on the wardens and stuff sitting
here getting along with all the officers
real good they know that something's
going on you know we got the officers
bringing in whatever we want you know I
mean I didn't I didn't want for much in
there yeah you know I I I was liked
and I helped so many people in there it
was incredible my thing was when I got
off the bus to whatever it is to keep
this brain occupied because this [ __ ]
here will have me hanging inside the
cell I'll hang myself
you know I can't go with that [ __ ] my
wife's looking around out there you know
I just had to all that right you know
and I made it
here I am talking to you amazing
there we go
yeah it's it's been an amazing journey
so in the next five years where do you
guys see your uh company and where do
you see the Cannabis industry going
hmm
yeah that's a really good question
um where do I see the Cannabis industry
going
well I think everybody's kind of like
sitting on a edge of their seats
wondering if this is going to go federal
legal not that that's like encompassing
how everything's gonna go but I think a
lot of people are trying to
structure their next moves around that
you know
um but
I think that cannabis because it's it's
so niche
it's a special plant it's not like
it's not like um a Marlboro cigarette
it's not like a cigarette where you
could be like okay that cigarette just
tastes like that every time it's just
like it's it has to do with like people
really loving new terpenes
um new ways that the plant makes them
feel or makes them heal you know there's
there's different ways that people use
it some people use it recreationally and
some some people use it to heal
themselves I think Dennis perone said
yeah whether uh what is it whether you
believe it or not it's it's medicine I
think whether you know it or not I know
it I know it me and my cousin have
tripped so much of it because we always
smoke so much tree and we're always like
why do we smoke so much [ __ ] treat
why do we love it so much yeah but we
had a very traumatic use
so it's like a way that I know and
almost guarantee that that's how I deal
with my PTSD you know like not having a
parent growing up or
watching The Perils of how you know his
hit what what he went through made our
family go through not even to do with
cannabis just like family [ __ ] you know
right I think the Cannabis will um
always have it's
there'll be a very commercial heavy wave
I think that will just keep happening as
each state conforms to how it deals with
cannabis
you know because each state has
different approach to it it's like
um
and uh
I think that
over time just like good cannabis will
always hold its weight you know like
certain people want really good cannabis
there's always going to be a demand yeah
connoisseur flour yeah I I think and
extracts I think x-ray for sure because
it's always breaking through to like a
new level and they're they're always
coming out with new different forms of
extract it seems like I mean I like the
Ross and I think that's cool but I
really like that at the end of the day
good flower yeah I love melt I love like
all the full melts you know yeah but
flour is definitely like a key
key
cannabis component you know better than
I I kind of feel like
you can't just smoke one or the other
you know what I mean it's good to like
indulge in both variety I like variety
and I like smoking sativas and I like
smoking strong indicas
you know I like I I'm on a mix right you
want to have like if it is the Indica
City because it's all pretty much hybrid
anyway but I like I like floral Terps
yeah I like floral terms yes yes candy I
like Skittles I like anything curves
yeah
which a lot of those are good but I like
old cams I like old ogs I like me too
dude I like the when they punch you in
the face
I think the tricycle G is like stapled
cannabis for anybody's stash for sure
for sure and like that super silver was
good it definitely got me high like the
first hit I took I felt like right off
bow right off
I smoked so much of it in the Amsterdam
so what do you like to smoke
what what are your type uh indica
so do you have any particular strains
you guys sell some strains you guys want
to talk about this strange you guys we
got Flamingo Kush on the market in
Florida Indica which is like a Indica
hybrid
um Indica dominant hybrid I would say
uh it's like uh it's a very very strong
cushy
um
is it like an OG yeah it is it's a it's
a cross of um it's a cushman's Fino
nice so that's it's uh I think they
popped something like 25 different
different uh seeds and then we chose 18.
number 18. yeah
it's out of that batch yeah
and then you know the way Lord goes you
have to rename things so it becomes a
whole like uh with the Department of
Health yeah I'll give it a name you want
to explain that because I'm not even
familiar well I just know that we had to
choose a name and it had to be approved
by the Department of Health oh wow it
was like the first name was not approved
and then it came back to us on the
second round and yeah we were doing
going with an alligator Gator thing you
know and they improve it hmm
because the animal probably goes to
college and all that stuff right now
interesting yeah so what state has the
best weed
in your opinion I mean me I say
California hands down
but yeah I mean some there's some things
growing I'm sure in little I'm sure
there's like little small bat [ __ ] going
in all types of States where there's
just oh yeah every state has certified a
guy shows me something today that he
grew in his spare bedroom yeah you see
that stuff yeah that was crazy
and he showed me the whole setup he said
here's my bedroom
showed me a light system and I was like
it was incredible incredible weed yeah
but I mean that's you know when he's
looking to give me some weird nothing
like [ __ ] bro you making a little
bedroom I guess she's got the bedroom
and he's got his wife and kids and you
know the rest of the house you know what
I mean
I said [ __ ] you only got that little
beard no I don't need nothing I'm good
you know that's how it's all yeah
but it was very pretty pretty purple and
red
with the orange I mean I was like what
the [ __ ] do you remember purple weed
back in the day or was there a bunch of
purple or
yeah there was some purple around it's
gone in and out of favor for the life
you know what it was I can remember
seeing some weed in the 80s late 70s
that the bottom of the leaf yeah was
purple yeah from temperature and the top
of the leaf was green yeah or a reddish
stressed too and then when it would
start to Bud
it'd be like the purple
I mean embedded in it
with the Crystal and then the little bit
of red and the orange yeah and then it's
like
yeah
so and then Colombia was that was that
where your favorite flower came from
that was my favorite flower Colombian
gold dropped it today I wish I could
super strong I'm trying now someone we
met someone today that might know
someone that has some Colombian seeds I
have some Colombian hybrid seeds that I
would like to give you okay so you guys
can pop those and hopefully find
something cool
so and they're they're the biggest seeds
I have I think they're yeah they're
crazy yeah they're like my sheets and my
gold yeah we're giant yeah they were
like little peas right that's exactly
what they look like yeah very wild how
big they are yeah so they're like three
times bigger than some of the seeds and
the birds loved them the birds and my
birds eating they love them yeah
and protein
so yeah
well this has been a wonderful deal yeah
I really appreciate you guys coming on
the show this has been fun
thank you very much for everybody and we
thank you for having us yeah I mean I I
love being able to tell stories for the
world to freaking hear because I feel
like some of these people like yourself
I you know there you guys aren't gonna
be around forever so it's great to be
able to tell them a year from now we're
going to come back and do this again 10
years from now hopefully
you know I think that would be great you
should get your own podcast I think you
would be a great host
so we've been talking about it yeah yeah
I started with the zoom style so you
could always start with just a zoom
style from your your laptop do it at
home and you know I think it's yeah you
got it you got good stories and you know
there's a lot of people I'm sure you can
reconnect with and oh for sure yeah I
wanted to um yeah it's it's like
or when you were breaking down how did
the business come about I kind of wanted
to break down to you how like
probably the first time I ever
had mentioned what what I what what I
thought could be for my father
was probably
um I would say
eight or nine years ago maybe 10 years
ago now huh
we were on a phone call and you know
[ __ ] was just starting to become
transparent that it was legal legalizing
everywhere and kind of normalizing in a
way in people's eyes and I was like yo
he was like you know is it [ __ ] like
he was like kind of tripping like are
people really making money off this [ __ ]
every day is this really happening and I
was like yeah it's really happening I
said you're gonna get out you know
and um I remember saying to him at that
point yo uh we I'll carve a lane out for
you
and we'll make sure that you know
there's there's a restitution kinda
put forth for you so we can make sure
you get something back for all the
sacrifice you've gone through you know
and um it's wild to that's probably how
this all came about you know
a lot of people say it's this or that or
but everything starts with kind of like
an idea you know and I really remember
like tripping even like after meeting
you and seeing span of this and
seeing the whole evolution of the
Cannabis industry it just blew me away
and I knew that it was actually going to
happen that's why I started saying it to
people like you at that point I was
almost confident yeah it's gonna happen
you know you were calling I've been
knocked down again after I said that to
you I I was broken and he was broken
again it was like motions denied and all
types of [ __ ] but yeah thanks too long
we're here now yeah
pretty amazing it is it is thanks to
people very belly yeah thank you Mary
D'Angelo shout out to you
we love you guys
um yeah Kiara and uh Mariah
amazing people that that step forth and
helped us
it's it's I'm super thankful you know
and um
I'm gonna make sure to keep it on the
level so people respect it and it's a
legacy that's uh consistent
and not no [ __ ] you know household
quality right so if people want to
contact you and find out more about your
brand where can they go on Instagram
Instagram your website yeah we got an
Instagram account underscore delicioso
underscore
um there's also free to Lisi at free
delisi uh my cousin at simply radio he's
he's doing he's also my partner in the
delicioso brand
um we have a website free delisi.net
and.com
um and delicioso.com
um there's yeah numerous ways you can
reach out to us and you know if we can
help you or your family in any way
with um
something to do with the non-violent
cannabis events we'd love to so if you
see this I'm that's what we're here for
too you know nice
Matt well thank you guys again for your
time yeah thank you thank you for having
us appreciate you man we're seeing six
months are you I'm ready I'm ready yeah
it's been fun thank you thank you
[Music]
they did not cruising
thank you