[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James Lab podcast
and today my special guest is my good
friend Nick T how you doing today I'm
feeling blessed bro thank you so much
for having me yeah so we go way back uh
but let's let's talk about long hair man
I guess when we first met we both had
long hair you had dreadlocks I had long
long hair have longer hair yeah yeah
yeah I had dreadlocks down in my ankles
bro yeah 13 years yeah so you coined the
term solventless which I disagreed with
back in the day I was like solventless
love you were one of the guys
disagreeing yeah I was like that's the
universal solvent you know it's like but
you know I feel like the the interesting
thing with language is over time when
you have something that makes sense if
enough people use it you can change
language it doesn't have to be a
specific way especially if there's
purpose right and that that's pretty
much what you did which is really
impressive you know from that from
looking back now I'm like well he had a
point it made sense it's pretty crazy
there were definitely a lot of naysayers
a lot of uh scientists that came at me
Waters the universal solvent um just you
know in general there was a lot of hate
with coining a new term and creating a
product that people really hadn't seen
before um but it's pretty cool to see
where it's come today well the evolution
you know you're you're a pioneer as far
as extract and you took it from you know
there there was just regular bubble has
that was amazing back in the 90s I
remember seeing really good bubble hash
but then I met you maybe around 2010
2011 something like that and you took it
up a notch to where it was it was a
whole different thing it it wasn't
bubble has it it was bubble has but it
was like another level of bubble has
that in it of itself created the issue
and that's the point of or the reason I
coin the term solventless because I
started bringing product to the shelves
that I was working with and saying hey
here's my bubble has and they were like
no bubble has is what we already have on
the Shelf yours doesn't look like that
yours doesn't smell like that right
people aren't consuming it the same you
can't call it bubble has really you know
yeah um and uh we were doing things a
little bit differently than what Mark or
bubble man was promoting how he was
processing so we wanted to kind of
create initially a term that separated
us from the rest of course it caught on
and a lot of people started using that
term real quickly after wanting to hoard
that term for just separation I realized
that I needed to teach people what we
were doing in order to really sell the
product that I was selling because
people didn't understand it right and in
doing so everyone wanted to jump on that
solving this train right so um yeah it's
a trip yeah and I mean you completely
changed the the landscape for Rosen and
all these other things I mean you paved
the way for
rosin uh it's really impressive so so
let's take a step back and and talk
about because we're both from California
I'm originally from Oregon but I grew up
in the Bay Area and you grew up in
Northern California originally so let's
talk about cannabis in Northern
California and how you got your roots
yeah you know being you know raised in
Northern California meant that cannabis
was very prevalent in my upbringing and
very accepted um I guess I'm I'm blessed
I'm in a blessed situation where my
family was very accepting of cannabis I
had people in my family that used to be
drivers um I had people in my family
used to be Farmers that are still
Farmers actually um and so I grew up in
a place that cannabis was extremely
accepted and when I started selling weed
it wasn't something that my family was
stoked about by any means but it wasn't
something that they were going to get
mad at me for is what it felt like I
felt like what I was doing was fairly
accepted by my family and that really
allow allowed me to excel in the
Cannabis space from an early age well
before regulation I was definitely
selling cannabis it came to a point
where I was bringing in some money and
some weed into like the family house and
I was like this doesn't feel right so I
actually moved out kind of early on and
started going to junior college instead
of high school early on and um that also
opened up more Avenues to sell more
cannabis is going to a junior high or
Junior College when I was 13 years old
so Big Game Changer yeah so essential
extracts started did it originally start
in Colorado or was yeah it started in
Colorado
2012 maybe a little before that um I was
operating in California and I was DJing
and and doing some promotion promotional
work for True school and we started
something here in Oakland actually and
had some attention some unwanted
attention and we were told that
California wasn't ready for what I was
was doing basically go back to Colorado
oh I believe it um so that's what we did
we went to Colorado Colorado was one of
the first places that really allowed us
to operate um it felt a lot safer than
215 I wanted to sleep at night I've sold
weed my entire life and uh I had just
recently had a kid and I wanted to sleep
at night so I came back to Colorado and
we started essential extracts actually
in 2009 um by 2010 it was a licensed
entity oh wow that's awesome yeah
Colorado is in some ways is a lot I talk
about on my show about being a more
mature Market than California and I feel
like they trust their brands it's it's a
different Market I would not personally
you know as far as cultivation like
indoor cultivation yeah but like it's
it's tough out there it's so dry
Washington is the polar opposite and
then you got California which is like
the perfect weather and I think that
perfect is really according to what
you're trying to do and it stems back to
historically ter are and
hash regions weren't in near the
equatorial but the flower cultivation
regions were so you know for me Colorado
is like that dry cold climate that's
perfect for making hash yeah so it might
not be the best for you know producing
flour or drying and curing flour um but
as far as hash production it's one of
the best places to make hash in the
United States totally so how did you get
your start because now a lot of kids
they have YouTube and they have a lot of
re there's tons of resources it's
endless you know and there's so many
extract
artists uh how did you get your start I
know you work with MAA a little bit at a
certain point but really the start came
from having a family that was accepting
of cannabis so my start was as a
teenager selling weed in the Bay Area um
from there I always wanted it to be on
the up and up I always wanted to sleep
at night I got robbed as a kid I you
know had some issues with the law as a
kid and I was tired of that I wanted to
be Forefront about what I did and um so
I was actually one of the first people
to reach out to the do and to reach out
to them and being like hey I want to pay
taxes on hashish I don't want to play
around I want to be licensed I want to
sleep at night and so I think that's
really where the start happened for the
regulated Community is essential
extracts was one of the very first
licensed hash making companies in the
United States wow um and from there we
had one of the first Labs so I had
companies from all over the world from
micro fluid X who was in the cold brew
coffee industry to other techn
technology Industries Brewing Industries
coming to us being like hey we want to
bring our equipment into your lab
because it's protected yeah really so um
I think that's a big you know reason
that we came up early is we had one of
those first licens protected
Laboratories where big bigger Brands
felt comfortable bring in a quarter
million dollar piece of equipment into
that lab rather than in the homie's
basement or your garage right so let's
talk about solventless what is
solventless for those people that don't
know what is
solventless um you know so initially the
very first term that was coined back in
like 2010 and with the help of Paul
token who was one of I think one of the
first influencers one of the first
YouTube influencers If you will we were
hanging out and I was L trying to evolve
the technology we were producing to
mimic what we were seeing in the
hydrocarbon world so when honey oil
first came to the market butane hash oil
um we I I I made it in reality let's go
back to that I made it when it first
came to Market I bought a honeybee
extractor in the back of high times and
I was making it on my back porch in
Boulder Colorado but there was a lot of
unknowns and I loved the color and I
loved the consistency but I didn't know
what I was giving to my friends and what
I was selling my people so I went to
Amsterdam and I looked into this one of
the first and only cafes that was
willing to share some coas with me was
the Bluebird Cafe back in the day in
fact they were also one of the first
cafes to have a milk alternative for my
lactose intolerant s wow so I I liked
the bluebird but they were able to share
some things with me that showed me that
there was other ISO butane isopentane
and other residuals left behind in that
butane hash or one of the products
obviously there's there were a lot of
different people making it back then um
but it scared me and so I kind of came
back to the United States with this idea
that I wanted to create something that
looked and tasted and and was consumed
like that butane hash oil but without
the use of any chemical solvents that
was my
goal and at that time the product
consistency of ear wax and that term was
really popular yeah so the first term
that you know Paul and I really coined
was solventless wax MH but then we
realized different consistencies were
coming out you know from Sol or from you
know more of a batter likee consistency
the shatter like consistencies more you
know more or less viscosity and I
realized and then we started recreating
with more heat or less heat those
different consistencies utilizing water
hash and
started calling things solventless
shatter and solventless batter and then
solventless really became the overhead
umbrella term and it all happened really
really quickly um I'd say within like a
six-month period we started talking
about solventless wax but then very
quickly it became an umbrella term for
anything that we created mechanically
without the use of any chemical solvents
so I think that's the answered your
question initially you asked what is
solventless um it's mechanically
separated triome heads yeah more
recently you've even worked with
developing cultivars specifically I mean
probably for a long time but I I've
known about it from Recently with my
book you actually help you with the the
stuff on selecting washers you know and
your I say I developed ctiv ours yeah
but definitely have
developed a method of tactile sensation
to fine washers right yeah you want to
talk about that you're a little bit yeah
yeah yeah know I mean I'm down to talk
about it all um I've always been washing
and really it wasn't until 2012 that we
started keeping track of that data 2012
is when we started keeping track of
yield data and we started looking at all
the cultivars at pink house uh the
facility that I was working with and um
we started noticing that some of these
cultivars were yielding way less and
some of them were yielding way more and
it that's really when my eyes opened up
like okay maybe we shouldn't wash this
blue dream maybe we should send that to
hydrocarbon um in reality because I was
seeing like sub
05% on this blue dream cut that we were
still y yielding two and a half pounds
per light back in the day U metric if
you will and um it was still selling for
really high numbers in flower form so
why was I taking all these fresh frozen
or or even dry pounds back then and
processing them if I was going to see
you know a minimal yield and that
minimal yield was never the highest
quality when it was yielding that low
when you're like sub 1% it's never the
highest quality um well Shouldn't Say
Never there's some outliers always yeah
but you know looking at those numbers we
realize that not everything is allocated
or should be allocated to
solventless and so I think that that's
where things changed for us and we
started to hone in on those bigger
washers that also still had the tarpine
representation or you know the volatile
compound representation that we were
after right nice well and then it's
funny how far that's come too as far as
washers you know strawberry banana has
always been known as a good washer and
then all these the banana cond and the
banana Oreos these ones that t 6% 6%
Plus what's the highest test you've seen
you know highest test on paper I saw
personally was the gorilla princess this
was inside the field extracts lab field
extracts was a company that um I
collaborated with for their launch we
won a few cups together um and in that
time we were processing a few different
things from all of our our licensed
friends and uh Fieldy brought over some
gorilla princess and it hit like over 9%
which was crazy to me n [ __ ] crazy to
me didn't make sense totally but and it
and ended up not being something I put
my name on um cuz we were collaborating
so we were finding certain things that I
like could really stand behind and yes
it was a huge yielder but it didn't have
a tpine profile once you get like above
6% I feel like the Tarpin get a little
subdued huh interesting yeah because
it's like same thing when you're above
30 40% THC oftentimes those aren't like
the super turpy strains that I'm looking
for for sure I'm the same sometimes you
know sometimes you find a super tast
strin that's also 35 Plus I'm not
looking for high THC in reality I'm I'm
looking for those I wish we could go
back and take all that stuff away and be
like does it taste good how does it make
you feel yeah you know those two things
it's like if if you can answer those two
things that's all you really need to
know that the THC and and it's great but
it's such a you know it's it's such a
confusing to the consumer it's such a
confusing piece of information that they
think that because it's high THC that
it's it's going to get them more High
yeah we're really trying to dispel that
myth yeah yeah and you work with the
ganier definitely so so you guys you
guys are out there full force trying to
dispill lots of myths which I think is
great really just you know the industry
is still brand new um and we just
started researching the plant not too
long ago on a empirical level if you
will protected level and um so the the
program is constantly evolving and
that's what I like about it it is the
professional platform that I was looking
for as a teacher it's a a constantly
evolving platform you know or constantly
evolving education just as our industry
is constantly evolving so you are one of
the most busiest guys I know so tell us
a little bit more about the ganier and
how that started and how you got
involved with that yeah I shot um a
little TV
series in Southern California at the
greenflower media studio with Derek
Gilman the show was called high
rollers and when I pulled up at the
studio they had like a makeup person and
um you know proper lighting and real
Studio setups and I was like okay this
is what I've been looking for in reality
I've done some teaching for a lot of the
other platforms I'm not going to name
right now um and I've grown up teaching
from swim instruction to Surf
instruction to snowboard instruction I
love teaching so I was looking for a
professional platform and after shooting
high rollers with Derek um I thought
that green flower could be that
professional platform very soon after it
all kind of happened at the right time
too cuz I was looking for that platform
and very soon after high rollers um they
brought another project that they wanted
to involve me in and they also involved
I believe it was 16 or 20 other maybe
more other council members in this
project at the very onset of it I don't
even believe it had a name wow um very
soon after the onset the term Gan became
the name Kevin jodry brought that name
to us it was a name that was previously
given to Kevin um but we utilized it for
the platform and uh there's a lot of
council members that was another reason
that I wanted to work with the platform
because it had peers and mentors of mine
that I looked up to um that I agree with
you know in a lot of the aspects of the
industry so I was excited to be among
people that I like to be around right um
and that I respected so um all of that
kind of came together and we started
ganier program maybe four or five years
ago now and I believe I think we're in
our third year of active um on or
in-person training so the ganier do a uh
a period where they're doing a bunch of
online studies and that period could be
any number of time depending on how long
it takes you to get through it but the
online goes through everything from
cultivation to processing to the law
to
retail it covers a big chunk of our
industry as a
whole and
um then after they've finished or
sometimes they don't have to finish the
online portion but whe they're when
they're confident with the online
portion they can sign up for in-person
training and um of course they have to
finish you know the online and the
in-person training to get certified but
the in-person training consists of two
days where the first day we do some
assessments
um we actually assess some local
Southern humble cultivated flower
generally it's full sun but we also
bring in some other living soil grows um
some living soil indoor grows as well
for assessment purposes and we assess
utilizing the systematic assessment
protocol app which is an application
that we've developed and are constantly
evolving as well to uh assess the flower
because we felt like that was a big need
in the industry what is quality we
wanted to talk about what is quality in
the industry there's a lot of myths out
there as far as what is quality so we do
an assessment and then we also do a farm
tour where we bring the students to a
local uh Southern humble farm and you
know they let they they get to feel the
magic at that point nice you know once
they come up to farm I don't really need
to do too much talking um I love
bringing people on the farm because
especially people from out of state or
people that haven't seen live cannabis
plants it's uh it's a treat
yeah it's an eye opening experience you
know it's pretty amazing I remember the
first time I saw a plant I don't know if
you remember the first time you saw a
plant but first time I don't know I
remember growing a few in the backyard
as a as a little kid but yeah
totally I couldn't believe I mean I I
seen Bud for a while before I saw a
plant the first time I saw a plant I was
like holy
[ __ ] so that's what that's what it is
that we're smoking and you know know
it's like uh all these things are
becoming lost arts and there's a lot of
people that that are out there that have
never actually seen a plant growing just
like they've never seen the vegetables
growing that they're eating that they're
buying from the grocery store sad but
true yeah yeah we live in a strange
world where there's this big disconnect
from how and I think education can solve
a lot of that you know but also
experience so we're trying to provide
both yeah and I'm constantly learning
each and every day it's what keeps me
motivated to teach in reality and that's
why this emerging market so perfect for
me cuz I'm still motivated after 20
something years of doing this yeah um
but thank you to the plant for real
because she keeps me going yeah I mean
we're in a we're in a really strange
time in the industry but we're
definitely you know we're in this
especially in the United States like
this consolidation phase again and so
there are people that are suffering and
people that are having tough times but
we are in the infancy of an industry
that'll be you know 100 years from now
is going to be a very stable industry
and a very different industry in a lot
of ways I think yeah definitely even 10
years from now we should be a little
more
stabilized uh right now you know what's
your thought on all the new genetics
that are coming out we have a top 40s
list and it seems like every three
months there's something new you know
you're an OG guy though so like OG is
like a classic hit that'll be around
Forever Blue Dream that's another one
regardless of how you feel about blue
dream I feel like that's a or anybody
that's watching it's a staple that'll
always be around I haven't seen blue
dream in a minute I have just recently
yeah I mean it's starting to come back
now yeah it's starting to come back now
for sure but it's been uh it's been a
minute um yeah OG's were gone for a
while OG's were like really not in your
world not in my world
everun in fact like I actually ran out
of my little living soil tent recently
just in the last couple days here and I
reached out to somebody and that's
actually what I'm smoking is some
somebody else's living soil OG Skittles
cross and it's [ __ ] amazing and I'm
super blessed to have found this guy
because normally I just smoke my weed
and I haven't run out of my weed in a
long time but um I've been on tour and
some things got a little sidetracked in
the garden and had to do a little reset
if you will um and uh now we're good to
go it just was a you know it was a quick
couple month reset that we haven't
flowered for but I smoked up all my
flowers in those couple months wow yeah
it's there's something special to be
said about growing your own flower and
smoking your own flour you know exactly
what was put into it and what you put
into it is what you get out of it and
especially effect wise definitely is
that what you love about the living soil
the most well what I love about my
personal living soil is I know all the
Amendments and everything that goes into
the soil and I know everything that is
being brewed as a tea we still do hit it
with some teas um but all of my tees are
made by my good friend Rich and Bas
organic I know where his farm is you
know and like it's all very close to
home
and like there's something about Rich's
nutrients that I just it gives me this
certain even just getting them in raw
form there's this smell when I get them
all you know um his veg and his Bloom
there's just this homely smell about it
um when I've tasted other people's
living soil or k&amp;f Gardens often times
I'm tasting like uh a fruit ferment or
I'm tasting something else that's not
really cannabis and with our soil blend
that we've been you know constantly
tweaking over the years there's just for
me anyways because it's it's something
I've gotten used to there's no outliers
I'm tasting really truly what that
phenotypical expression wants me to
taste is how I feel about my garden I'm
not getting any of that extra molasses
or any of that extra fruit juice or
whatever it may be even in an organic
sense they're things that can be done in
a living soil Garden that I don't like
that I don't want to taste um and then
of course on the salt side there's
things as well you know like I don't
want to taste the line cleaner I don't
want to taste you know that extra carb
boost that you pumped it in the end to
give it that bag appeal I don't want to
taste that right yeah you want the full
expression of the plant at the end of
the day you know it might be a little
bit different for each person because
now my pet's train to this you know what
I mean um and this is rare that I find
somebody else's living soil Garden that
I'm like really happy with that I want
to smoke and or actually somebody's
Garden in general it's not just the
living soil somebody's salt grow or
whatever it may be every once in a while
I find like somebody's you know salt
grow that I actually really like and I'm
like whoa what what are you doing cuz
you're running that nutrient brand but
it tastes like this that's rad totally
there's guys that really can pull it off
for sure um living
soil uh how big of scale have you seen
people successfully pull it off at to
where it's stuff that you would enjoy
smoking yeah I think that um one of the
first people that really built out a lot
of the initial living soil grows in
Colorado was this woman named
Cassandra um and she started at this
dispensary called Eminem dispensary Mike
and Mike dispensary and Boulder I
started following around from there
because we started getting product from
them dry material that was washing like
it was fresh frozen yeah so there was
something happening in this Garden I
didn't know at the time it was living
soil I didn't know what the method was
of their cultivation I just knew that
Eminem was giving me the fire and we
ended up winning a cup with some of
their material and then I saw that that
same cultivator went over to places like
Verde um and I was like okay wait and we
had partnered with Verde kind of around
that same time uh Pink House and Verde
created a little Bond if you will and we
shared some things um and Chuck's still
a really really good friend of mine yeah
me too I started noticing I started
noticing this trend of where you know
this girl went and built out these big
living soil beds that I liked that
flower so um big up Cassandra she's a
woman that has really set the stage for
living soil cultivations in Colorado not
of people not a lot of people know about
her and know about it um and know that
that's why that product was different
yeah um but then I've also seen um our
buddies over at Moon Valley cannabis um
in the north bay and they have it's
still not a large facility I think it's
5 to 7,500 maybe 10,000 square ft um but
beautiful large living soil bed indoors
yeah and um it is scalable on in that
sense um and I'd say that those are some
of the bigger ones though that I've seen
are 10K 10,000 foot living soil indoors
yeah I think that there's bigger out
there I just yeah I've never been to
Wrigley in Nevada her they're doing
interesting stuff living soil my friend
Flor Flame Chris Castle uh they're in
Oakland and they're doing double stack
two-tier living soil beds pretty good
stuff okay I love that I love I've been
hearing a lot more about Flor and Flame
lently I love to recently I love to try
their stuff these guys I'm going to show
you this stuff this is a strawberry
banana Skittles okay and this stuff
that's oh we just popped or maybe we're
about to pop these seeds from DNA these
uh um it's not strawberry banana but
it's something banana and Skittles yeah
DNA's got some new stuff coming out they
were just on the show not too long ago
they're doing good good guys nice that's
this is living soil indoor living soil
indoor yeah blown out SMS good yeah it's
not bad it's got nice banana chirps it's
like it's mild on the banana but I kind
of like that it's not super Skittle but
it's candy okay so and it smokes the it
translates in the Smoke which is what I
like so not everything translates in
smoke some stuff you smell purple punch
for an example smells amazing you got to
smoke it the extract's okay don't don't
get me wrong I'm not a big fan fan of
purple punch I'm not Oreos Oreos is
something very Bland to me Oreos the
original Oreos cut looks amazing bag
appeal banging super easy to grow but I
do not want to yeah it's got It's got
bag appeal definitely got a look to it
and if you couldn't smell it you'd think
it was amazing white truffles is another
one I'm not really fond of personally
interesting I really like that Cron's
cut of white truffle um I think it has
this like Petra cor to it that like
speaks to me it has this like Sandalwood
eucalyptus Petra cor thing that I like
it's like similar to biscotti I
definitely preer prefer the biscotti TPS
cuz it's like that same earthy Petra cor
gas eucalyptus but the biscotti also has
the cream and the gas totally well
that's the interesting thing sometimes
until you try the right cut you might
think something sucks so maybe I haven't
I'm one of those people that i' I've
seen that happen so many times in my
life where I'm like oh it sucks it sucks
it sucks and then someone shows me the
good version of it and it's like oh [ __ ]
this is this is what's up uh wedding
cake was the best example of that I'd
seen there's so many fenos out there
that over 30 I think there's over 30
fenos of wedding cake I'd seen a bunch
said I was just in Thailand they're
calling stuff Wedding Crashers and
wedding cake that's so far from it I
think I tasted some lemon tree that was
called Wedding Crashers in Thailand but
um yeah the first time I saw a good
wedding cake I'd probably seen like 10
other fenos of it and I'm just like e
and then it wasn't the biggest yielding
it wasn't the cakest but it had the most
flavor and smoking it it was bready it
was amazing it you know you burned down
the roach the roach tasted good and
that's a that's a big test for me is
like how does it taste of the roach if I
refire it how does it taste definitely
definitely it's interesting we're just
getting all this rain right here so I
was kind of talking to uh my buddy
before I popped in here that this was
burning like super white in Colorado the
same weed but now that it's so much
humidity and I was just out in the rain
basically burning a little darker too
yeah it's interesting some of these guys
are flushing with magnesium now they're
adding magnesium to flush so it burns
it's a trick they're using to make it
burn more white yeah definitely
definitely I think it
increases uh yeah the temperature at
which it combusts um so it burns more
fully which creates more white should be
more flavor the white what's your
thought on White Ash um I like even Ash
for me it doesn't have to be white um
but there's
definitely there's reasons that white
ash I I want my my weed to fully combust
I don't want there to be any carbon left
over and when cannabis fully combusts
it's generally going to be a little bit
lighter in
color I think for me it's a combination
of the water content and the combustion
so that combustion is attributed to what
micronutrients are left behind and what
you know what else is left so there's a
lot of variables to it um I'm definitely
impressed every time I see all white ash
you know I mean where it looks like a
cigarette or a cigar but a lot of that
has to do with the perfect cure too but
I've had all white ash where it just
tastes so
Bland I don't care I don't care that it
burns that clean if it tastes like the
paper I'm smoking yeah I was getting
some stuff from Grass Valley in fact
this year that like it had the blackest
of Ash but it tasted so good and I just
want to keep smoking it yep it's
Greenhouse good stuff and if it burns
even and that darker colored Ash is
actually fully combusting and it's not
leaving a lot of that super hard carbon
behind I'm okay with it but if it's
leaving a lot of carbon behind right
generally even if it tastes good I don't
want to smoke it yeah it's interesting I
just recently tried some um some more
freeze-dried flour I've had freeze-dried
flour in the past um but this this new
batch um of freeze-dried flour it looked
amazing smelled amazing but when I went
to burn it it wasn't like that the the
color of the ash was bothering me it was
the it wasn't satisfying it was such a
light yeah feeling that I wasn't getting
the full smoke satisfaction that I
wanted the freeze d weed trips me out Ed
Rosenthal has been pushing it for years
and these guys I I wanted to come on the
show and I wanted to do a side by side
because they claim it's you know higher
Turpin higher can
avonoids uh and you know it looks weird
though it's like astronaut ice cream but
with weed and I think you will get some
of those if you remove 100% of the water
you know but I think it's also going to
be a balance of not wanting to remove
100% of the water sure and finding like
a a middle ground if you will well and
somebody out there watching is going to
find tuna and they're going to give me
some weed at spannabis or one of these
events that I'm going to oh I think cash
treemason freeze dried flour is some of
the best freeze-dried flour I've had so
I've had freeze-dried flour that smokes
proper what I want I have yet to try
some yeah it costs a lot of money yeah
it should I mean things that are good
that are yeah you should try some of
that yeah you should try uh you should
try some of some of Cash's freeze-dried
flour cuz I thought it was actually good
um and I've had you know some that is
not not as I think the concept is great
so at the end of the day I think the
concept is really good I mean I like
freeze dryers and you know well and to
be able to control it if you can control
it down to uh you know below a percent a
tenth of a percent and you can control
the moisture and all these things I
think that the science is there that you
know it's hard to argue with science I
have yet to try it and as soon as I do
I'll I'll be a big proponent of it but
until I do I'm going to be like well the
stuff Ed gave me his house wasn't really
great yeah no there's some variables to
the freeze drying process in in all
aspects in in the hash world for us yeah
um and in freeze drying flower for sure
nice so in 2014 we did a Dabo with douge
and Mila San
Francisco uh we need to do another one
next year but let's talk about Davido a
little bit you got involved with me and
Mila so when did you uh start hanging
out and uh with Mila I believe I first
met Mila in early 2000s
2004 um probably at the latest but um I
feel like I had gone previous to that
trip in 2004 but the most memorable
memorable trip for me was
2004 um when I like got a washing
machine from Mila we actually put a uh
one of these big I believe it was like a
Swedish or a press from Switzerland it
was like these big hand press and they
were 100% stainless there were tons of
knockoffs in the United States at the
time but they were all aluminum and if
you like used one of those aluminum
knockoffs you bought at the head shop
like they looked really fancy they came
in a nice velvet box and everything but
like after the first or second time
you'd start shaving aluminum into your
hash so real soon after like we saw
these knockoffs come to the states I was
like I need the real one and Mila was
selling the these real presses so I put
it inside of a washing machine I bought
from Mil we ended up shipping it back
when it landed the washing machine was
busted because the Press was so heavy it
busted out the plexiglass oh man I ended
up fixing it with some bat epoxy and I
still have that washing machine but um
yeah that same year is when I bought
those papaya seeds from MAA that have
made a huge wave in the United States
yeah that papaya has gone everywhere
yeah um and it's really cool to see
people latch on to that one it's a big
extra for sure yeah um but yeah that
year is when I got those seeds um from
mivia and Nirvana but um yeah Mila
that's when I'm started hanging out with
Mila is in those early 2000s days I
first traveled to Amsterdam and I was
told that I need to find Mila Jansen the
hash queen and I was like okay you know
I was a hash guy already right um and so
people are like you need to meet this
woman you know and multiple people told
me that I would like go down the path of
trying to find these Mammoth tus
crutches so I used these crutches yeah
use those big long crutches and I found
these Mammoth tus so big up py in the
mammoth TUS later on in life I found out
who actually was making these and became
friends with him was crazy um but there
was a point where I was trying to track
down as many of them as I could find
it's an extinct animal so it's a rare
item I wanted these Mammoth tus crutches
and I heard that Mila had a lot of them
for sale so that's really kind of what
brought me initially to Mila's warehouse
and where my eyes opened up to a whole
wall of hash from around the world that
her fans had made her with using her
equipment right you've got like this
wall with like letters and Ziploc bags
and like little pieces of hash taped on
the wall and stuff um and uh I ended up
just picking Mila's brain th those trips
um because there wasn't a lot about
hashish and how to make it written down
there were forums popping up and people
were talking about it um but there
really wasn't a lot of books about
hashish so you had to kind of go study
and MAA was one of those people that I
wanted to study
under so I would go to her shop her
Warehouse where she would sell the
pollinator and the bags and all that and
I would just basically sit down with her
and bug her and ask her question after
question after question um and she was
out smoking me and still does to this
day but like I remember her smoking like
five spliffs to every one of mine I was
like trying to keep up and like coughing
up a lung and here this this uh woman
that was a little older than me is just
chiefing and she's just rolling up one
after the another and very patient she's
very patient yeah and she was patient
with me then and and now still to this
day Mila is traveling just as much as me
if not more and I thought I did a lot of
Road mil toally she rocks it out
crushing yeah [ __ ] love that woman
yeah she's amazing yeah there's there's
uh she she's super rare you just don't
find people like that now she's like
she's been so so impactful to so many of
our lives too there's so many of us that
she's touched and you know really really
made a difference in our lives yeah so
yeah much love me though yeah she was it
was great she stayed at my house with
when she was here for the awards she got
the Lifetime Achievement Award and so
she stayed with us for a week nice it
was great
2014 we went out on the bay in a
sailboat and almost died so that crazy
story oh waa she tells the story good
too so yeah the captain was drunk and
the the winds kicked up and you know how
in the bay when the winds kick up it's
like it was like being on the oce want
out there yeah yeah you don't want to be
out there so we were trying to get back
and we went into a boat we collided with
another boat we were fine but it was
pretty scary whoa you know and we were
all smoking weed and then we got the
guys drinking and it it was yeah it was
an adventure little hairy on the bay all
right yeah yeah yeah so good stuff I've
been blessed to get out on the bay on
calm days and bring in some
halet yeah it's so nice so nice still
still I I used to work on a fishing boat
a long time ago we used to go out to the
fairon islands and go out in the bay you
know there's so many different types of
fish and cool stuff to see so yeah so
let's talk about you being a DJ because
that's I mean you you got five different
things you're you're doing right now
that are all in this day and age you've
got to do it all I feel like for me
anyways to survive I can't just judge an
event you know it's hard for the
organizers to pay me just to judge so
I'm often times wanting to couple my
DJing or you know having a console on
the ground wherever I'm traveling set up
or a class or hosting an event um I
really like to do a lot but yeah DJ 2013
Marlon Asher uh opening up for uh Big
Mike and LP in Amsterdam you djed that
that was a good one yeah that was fun we
got really I took dabs on stage that was
pretty crazy that was fun yeah yeah yeah
and I actually I think that was the
first time I performed with Mar and I
there was no preparation and and uh I
was a little nervous cuz like this is an
artist who I've looked up to and I've
played his 7in records for probably 10
years before that event you know what I
mean so it was it was a trip to get
Marlin's you know TV tracks or to get
his tracks sent to me and for me to plug
them up and just perform them without
even listening to them in front of 3,000
people it was great that was ni I think
it was great I mean I had a good time
afterwards I was still like hey did I do
okay he's like bro we crushed it all
right it was a good event for sure yeah
those old High Times like there's
there's an
interesting group of us they're not not
interesting but they're good good group
of people that started that went to all
the High Times events you were one of
them Alfred you know and there was so
many Al from NorCal genetics he was on
the show you remember him okay okay oh I
know you're talking about yeah but
there's there's so many yeah yeah yeah
there's so many definitely OG and there
was some that would go to some but but
like and then spannabis was always a big
one and then
Amsterdam yeah yeah then you know we
were falling High Times around for a
little bit for sure um they tried to
bring it to Jamaica I went out to
Jamaica with it um it was a little bit
of drama on the ground there I guess but
uh I don't think it's been back to
Jamaica since I I didn't go to Jamaica
so that was one of the ones I missed it
was different it was fun though um I got
to speak which was a trip you know being
um you know just being a white person in
Jamaica speaking on an educational level
to Jamaicans who been farming for you
know Generations it was it was hard for
me number one cuz I'm like I kind of
wanted those guys to be on the stage
with me you know reality but I had muda
baruka in the the crowd basically muda
is the the voice of the people in
Jamaica and so for him to be in the
crowd and I remember him standing up and
asking me a question and like um it was
a pretty
direct straightforward militant style
question and I answered it and I
answered it you know to the best of my
ability and I remember him like you know
saying all right respect and having that
you know from somebody who was the voice
of the people to Jamaica was a trip so
there were definitely some highlights to
that event um and I think on that same
trip or maybe even a similar year I was
going to Jamaica quite a bit I got to
hang out in Bob's house and do a little
interview with muda oh wow
yeah yeah really cool yeah Marlin's been
on a couple episodes I love Marlin he's
such a good happy positive energy a
great to be for sure so yeah he's got
his his Marlin's choice is like his
California brand that he's doing and all
right yeah so we got some genetics
together he's doing his thing still
playing his music he has a new album
coming out and it's been coming out
since earlier this year but it is coming
out it's really good all right all right
I'm stoked to hear it yeah what's up
yeah he's just a good person he's down
in h he's down by mon not by mon Base by
Santa Cruz all right his wife down there
and that's what's up yeah speaking of
DJing and and the reggae music I started
as a reggae music DJ and I was spinning
7inch records 45 straight from Jama and
that's all I spun for years I would
travel around with like tackle boxes
yeah and film cases and stuff whatever I
could find that would fit 45s perfectly
um and I would travel around doing that
and it got to a point where it was a lot
of Records even though there were
smaller records it was a lot um and I'd
say once I finally converted to digital
and started playing with Sado um I
started broadening my music selection
started with roots started with reggae
and Roots reggae then it got into
dancehall a little slackness and some
'90s you know bashment if you will which
is you know a form of a little bit more
up paced reggae music from Jamaica but a
little bit more rude and raw um and then
I'd say that things really
changed maybe it was almost 10 years ago
now when it was it was Mila's 70th
birthday party that I djed in Amsterdam
and she wanted me to play 60s rock music
yeah I was like okay okay and she wanted
you know she gave me a list of artists
and I was like okay some of these
artists I really get down with and so
like I went back to the the drawing
board and I was like now that I have
this digital AA availability to me I'm
going to make some remixes or fine
remixes so I called up all my producer
friends and got a bunch of remixes of
like more rock Style music but like
reggae style or little bit of some house
remixes for the end of the night and
just kind of switched it up and I was
still able to perform the songs I think
I even played some dead she wanted Dead
you know to be performed so I played
everything all bunch of genres for MAA
and people were getting down and I had
like dead heads that were there it was a
full pack crowd at the milk wag still
and dead head's being like yo that
recording of that that show that you
played up there like that was amazing I
was there and like so I feel like I hit
a bunch of different people that were
like dude nicot is not just a reggae DJ
right and I got some of that respect and
so now being a DJ that's really focused
on these cannabis events I'm playing
everything like I just played in Vegas a
couple nights ago and I played
everything from 90s hip hop to Alma
piano afro beats afro house I played
some funk and some soul like I I play a
little of everything now nice um and I
really have fun with it I just saw Steve
aoke and I was pretty impressed actually
with his performance in Vegas yeah and
he kind of goes all over the board with
stuff that's he's yeah he's really
animated and he's really full of energy
that's what's up so yeah I need to see
yeah a bigger performance like that I'm
constantly working on my DJ stuff like I
feel like my library is almost there but
it's it's never there I've got gigs and
gigs and I'm constantly digging for more
stuff it just keep con I mean my boy dj3
just sent me a remix pack this morning
I'm like excited to get home and pull it
out
check it out see what he sent me well so
and then you've been spending a lot of
time in South America too lately over
you got married yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah
congratulations that's great I met your
wife at spannabis this year yeah yeah
yeah yeah I met her at in Spain as well
uh probably seven eight years ago wow
yeah and we I mean we had we weren't
dating back then but it was uh yeah it
was cool that I met her in Spain yeah
she's big into hash she smokes she is uh
an amazing hash maker an amazing
educator she probably smokes a lot more
than me too just like me the women in my
life yeah the women that smoke really
smoke yeah there's there's a bunch of
them yeah she's rad my wife is uh yeah
she's a boss yeah I think I was on
mushrooms when I when I bumped into you
guys I I surprised myself too we were at
strain Hunter club and it's dark
there and so uh yeah everything you
dropped me of some fire I was smoking
good thanks to James loud out in
Barcelona thank you yeah there was
definitely there's some good weed out
there in fact some my my friends are
growing really [ __ ] amazing weed in
Spain U you know everywhere though
Mexico my friends in Mexico are crushing
it you know it's like even just in
Thailand where I was at I smoked really
really proper yeah yeah that's awesome
especially when they're growing it there
oh yeah no I didn't smoke any import
while I was in Thailand um that was my
goal I didn't want to smoke what I can
already smoke at home um but yeah I got
to tour some amazing facilities out
there and uh smoke a bunch of really
good local stuff it might not have been
labeled right or sure
but um yeah did you see any good land
race stuff in Thailand they call things
land race that I don't think was land
race yeah there been a lot ofing yeah
there been a lot of inbreeding I did not
personally I know that exists but I
think that you know even you know it's
funny you travel all around the world
and like you get people saying hey this
is the land race and I smell things and
I'm like no a lot of that came from
Amsterdam sorry but like back in the day
and you might have had it for a long
long time but no I'm smelling tpine in
smelling whatever it may
be yeah sorry some White
Widow but yeah that terpinolene lemine
or terpinolene line it's like it's it's
all over with stuff you know it's funny
because some you you might even get that
from Crossing stuff that doesn't have it
it'll come out surprise it's there you
know yep yep so F4 all of a sudden we
have some random occurrence yeah I see
that with where do you think that came
from that
turine I would say the I mean it came
from Colombian too but like you also get
it in African genetics I mean there's
some in there but like the Colombian I
think it's extremely dominant with the
the Colombian stuff I think it's like
naturally when you're in those extreme
environments that like that like those
desert likee environments that
terpinolene really helps protect the
plant almost so like a protective
measure but yeah and it really stands
out you know it's like uh I got some
piff and some Cuban black and it's it's
subtle in there it's not like it's not
like some of the hazes they punch you in
the face I think that was the difference
between the piff like for me I actually
liked the pffs that I've seen because it
had way less if none none at all of the
terpinolene side of you know those
uplifting Cult of ours if you will for
me like a Jamaican land race and piff is
very similar and it I like it because
it's uplifting without terpinolene
terpinolene gives me anxiety so any of
that spice any of that you much give me
yeah I me I want the lemoning yeah but
terpinolene anything with the Citrus and
the spice to me just gives me a little
bit too racy in my own head and um I'm
blessed these days to really only smoke
what I want to smoke these days and know
what I'm looking for know how it affects
me I like it sometimes I like that racy
feeling sometimes where you're like am I
gonna be okay I'm so I have some strains
that have like you know similar tpine
representations as like a piff or a land
race Jamaican that that don't have that
terpinolene and those still make me racy
but I would prefer that style of racy
any tinge of terpinolene for some reason
just sends me over the edge thinking
about it talking about it it's making me
a little anxious bro it does it'll do
that yeah you start talking about it
you're like heartbeat goes up about 10
beats per
minute yeah it's funny I really like
Lamb's bread and you know Jamaican
Jamaican genetics are pretty amazing I
mean I'm sure the genetic layout has
changed quite a bit with all the
moves towards legalization that's
happened down there and guys coming from
Canada and United States and everything
else but some of those old Jamaican
varieties are amazing so hard to find
the the true ones because Jamaicans love
a breed yeah right yeah I mean but even
like Sunny Chiba Shane he's got he's got
a lamb's bread cross that's like a dead
ringer for that musky lamb bre Lambs
bread tur I'd love to try it yeah it's
really
good yeah Jamaica's a fun place for sure
I always bring it back to that just cuz
like for me that Jamaican land race is
like what I want if it's a land race cuz
I feel like it's got a little bit more
depth to it some of these like very
stringy land races that just you know
are almost unsm smokable and you're like
picking each individual 4 inch bracks in
the back they're like that
th you can roll it up in the yeah it's
it's pretty cool though uh all these
different varieties from all over you
know how they're contributing you know I
guess it can go back to about six
different varieties for what we have in
the United States pretty much six
different regions contributed to all of
the genetics that we're smoking today
yeah makes sense so but yeah I you know
I like land R stuff I'm curious about
land R stuff more than anything like
even if it tastes harsh or it's not
grown correctly I'm still curious about
these flavors yeah so and I feel like
diversity is the ticket like we've we've
inbred this stuff so much that we have
problems like hop plate and
verid uh and you know we have weak
plants we have weak genetics compared to
what we could have and genetic diversity
is the key but it's like the right kind
of genetic diversity that that people
will appreciate you know I think
durban's good I mean there's a lot of
Durban and stuff already I've started
really collecting a lot of those old
school genetics and like housed them
again you know from the UK cheese that
we just kind of got recently thank you
good old zenie um and uh I've kept all
these ogs and recently my best friend in
breeder who's also kept I'd say 75% of
these ogs for us as a family over the
last uh couple decades here he just
recently moved to the east coast and
before he moved I wanted to make sure I
grabbed like all the other little ones
that we hadn't had in just under our
roof so yeah I feel like I've gotten
back most of the things that I really
wanted to keep from back in the day so
I've got the ghost OG got the sfv the
triangle uh [ __ ] there's a few others um
you gave me samples of them they're all
really good they were all good all those
samples you gave you gave me some
blueberry as well I think the blueberry
is different it's got this tinge of
spice not a terpinolene spice but like a
little bit of a almost like a blue dream
spice to me that's not the DJ Shar
blueberry that's a different no it was
given to me as the
1992 or the 92 blueberry the Oregon
blueberry yeah I really don't know um it
was given to me by bike uh get seeds
here or get seeds right here good friend
of mine who I've worked with for years
and years and years um and just been you
know friends with uh for years he just
keeps passing me interesting Cuts he's
like yo you just need to grow this out
and then like let me know what you think
nice and at first I was hoping that it
was like this original blueberry that we
used to grow back in like the late 90s
early 2000s in Boulder um was it a
sativa no the we had a sativa from
Oregon okay no this was way more like
big super fat Leaf huge colas I don't
know if what we were growing back in
Boulder Colorado was DJ shorts blueberry
whatever it was it was blueberry
smelling in just huge colas yeah we were
also growing at aeroponic Le it was a
shorter plant with wide leaves yeah yeah
I think DJ's was pretty his is you a
shorter plant wide leaves and it's
changed over the years because he's done
so many generations too but that
original blueberry is what I thought
bike was giving me but when we flowered
it out I was like oh no this is
different it but I'm not mad at it
because that original blueberry never
really made good water hash for us the
one that bike gave me hits 4% and does
pretty good so um tast get in a joint
too for me that one like I've kept it
now as like a washer instead of what it
was supposed to be what I was looking
for these big big holes and the the
weight isn't bad on her on her either on
the flower side but she washes okay and
the blue Essence carries through but
it's like this spicy blue it's not
exactly what I'm looking for but it's
something cool to have in the catalog
yeah yeah yeah the ogs man we we just
got this crippy cut that uh it's like a
sativa OG okay so real thin leaves cppy
sativo yeah that reminds me of something
we're seeing like down in Colombia or
it's real interesting because it has
that pine cone Bud shape where the buds
are like pine cones bad node spacing
sativa leaves very you know wants to
flop over needs support but uh man it's
gassier than gas but it's not really I
mean it's almost OG gas but it's like
how OG for me it's like how OG gas was
back in the 90s which I haven't seen in
a while all right all right yeah yeah so
yeah so what's your favorite new genetic
that's popping
off
new you know in the last year I like the
direction of like the RS 11 and some of
those things um I still do like smoking
candy flavored things even though I'm an
OG head and that's what I need for like
the high side of things there's some of
these new flavors that I really do enjoy
um I like yeah rainbow sherb runs all
the crosses in between you grow a
rainbow Sher at one of them right you
grow the 54 the 17 or it's this cross
that was given to me by this guy OG
flare he really didn't know the original
Origins just to break it down um he gave
me an idea of what was in the garden
what he thinks pollinated it and I kind
of came to conclusions in reality um so
we really don't know what's in that we I
call it rs15 yeah it's tury yeah I
really really enjoy it it's candy for me
um it definitely has a similar you know
profile as those rainbow sherbs and yeah
things in that world so yeah so there's
this trend going on right now and I
don't know if you seen it's like called
snow snowballs or snow caps or uh buff
down weed where they coat it with thca
powder they're saying haven't even seen
this it smells it smells fake it's it
looks like a flocked Christmas tree
stuff pretty wild the the over Satur
oversaturation has really like tanked
the flower price all around the world
and so people are doing all kinds of
weird things and I'm that's also why I'm
just smoking my own flour right now got
some sprinkles sell flour I don't really
buy flour I just smoke this is the first
thing I've bought in a minute wow yeah a
long time like when you grow it
correctly yeah that's all you need you
need you just need the plant you know
and for me I like the flower I do like
extract too I like rosin I I like Roos
and hits I like micro dabs yeah I want
turpy Rosen dabs for sure um I still
enjoy a spliff and just the art of grow
or you know rolling it um but I also
like all the new technology in the dab
world and that's actually what's made me
more of a Dabber is doing the the
cleaning of the slurper and using the
Q-tip and then put it in the alcohol and
all the little things to keep it you
know free from cross-contamination
really yeah um and keeping your [ __ ]
fresh and looking clean um I like that
about it so like I like my you know new
little heady rig setup I like my control
tower from task yeah um I think that
anybody who's trying to do Innovation I
think is good it's all good for the
industry I I'm happy with uh the direct
in a lot of ways I'm happy with the way
the industry is going and unfortunately
there's a consolidation phase where the
guys that have middle of the road weed
or they're get you're done like you need
to move on to something else or grow
better weed like at the end of the day
hopefully yeah hopefully that's what's
happening I'm still seeing a lot of like
pretty weed that doesn't taste that good
so much and there's a lot of uninformed
uneducated buyers still there is so
there's going to be that type of weed
that's still going to run a muck right
and I want to educate against having
that in the market I agree 100% to me
it's like pretend to kind and I don't
even know if like there's some people
that are like out there talking of [ __ ]
about everyone else's weed calling
everyone else's weed is mids cuz their
weed looks amazing in a bag but that to
me that weed that bag a peel weed that
looks amazing but doesn't smoke right or
doesn't taste right that's the mids to
me well so for me I think the future and
what I want to push is pre-rolls and
quality pre-rolls you don't ever get to
see the weed you don't need to because
how does it make you feel how does it
taste as long as those two things are
proll are running the market already
right now you know and you look at the
numbers pre roll cruss well yeah and but
you have to have a brand that people
trust because if they see the pictures
of this stuff and it's all scraggly
online they probably won't want it yeah
but who cares at the end of the day who
cares what it looks like cat piss was
the best [ __ ] ever and that was the
ugliest weed I've ever seen it was also
the most expensive in the best Skittles
you know Skittles is not pretty it's not
easy to grow not big yielding but I love
it totally I love it it's super turpy
it's it's one of those ones that like I
keep going back to Skittles I always
have Skittles at the house yep so yep
there's a couple different cuts of
Skittles now too so there's ones that
are I think even better than the
original U as far as crosses though I
don't know that there's a better cross
with Skittles in it then Skittles Moon
Bow's good there's some really
interesting ones but as far good work
with it um yeah I don't know if better
is a good adjective for it there's
different I have this like pink zugar
that we're growing right now that I love
it's Skittles time straw guava yeah and
it's just like Skittles with a little
bit more of a like a round creamy nature
it has less of the Citrus that Skittles
tends to have less of the lime yeah
exactly um and I I really enjoy it I
think that it has a little bit more of a
punch than like the original Skittles so
like I've been leaning towards smoking
that when I like need to smoke because
it tastes amazing gives you know a
little bit extra totally yeah it's
interesting though um skitt I still love
a skittles you know when I'm not like
trying to get high it's not it's I'm not
saying that in a disc but like when I'm
just trying to taste that flavor that's
the flavor I want and there's nothing
that compares but when I need a little
bit of extra something to get me through
that day or whatever it may be the the
situation um some of the crosses have
been
Skittles gets you here it has a ceiling
you can only get here you don't break
through the ceiling the more you smoke
I'm not saying it as like a it's it's a
flavor thing for sure it's flavor it's
amazing flavor you know it's like
zootopia there's this new cut zootopia I
don't know who read it but it's amazing
it's super turpy all right there's a
couple crosses out there I'm a huge
moonbow fan too though that [ __ ] is yeah
Fletcher's crushed it with his crosses
yeah that's what I'm smoking right now
that what I just finished was not moonbo
but it was a face off OG time Z yeah
what is that that's a we were just
talking about that last night I don't
know I need Fletcher to answer the
actual question because I I'll speculate
for days but yeah there's there's some
good crosses out there for sure so and
I'm excited to see where it goes I can't
wait till it goes back towards gas and
sour I mean I know it's coming it's got
to come I can't keep my ogs now that's
also why I don't have any right now
because I finally started talking you
know and was like Hey I I actually do
have all these things still right um and
people were like wait what and then
people pulled up on
and I and I don't have anym flour to
when your stuff is clean and it's still
gassy cuz I wanted to share it with
everyone I was like oh wait like yeah no
I actually have the ghost here try it
totally you know I've got this try it
please and then now I don't have anymore
what's your favorite OG out of all ghost
ghost yeah it's the classic ghost is
like the original OG with Josh D ghost
is all the same cut there's I think a
lot of the cuts that are named certain
things are probably the same but this
ghost compared to the sfv that I have
just has a little little bit it grows
almost identical the buds almost look
identical almost smell identical but the
ghost just has a little bit more of this
Rich Anis to it compared to the sfv as
far as the flavor a little more earthy
just a little bit more of the Anis or I
don't know what it is less of tennis
ball chunk buds on both yeah they still
look the same um and then the feeling on
the ghost is way different than the sfv
even though everything else is the same
you know in our garden cuz sfv was a a
little more piny a little more earthy I
think they they the flavor-wise is
almost identical on the two cuts that I
have anyways um but the ghost just gives
me this narcotic feeling wow just
narcotic and it makes me eat so like for
any cancer patients or people that are
lacking uh appetite I give them ghost or
ghost Edibles or ghost something that's
like what I save that strain for it
saved a lot of people in my family and a
lot of people in my life you know and
that's one of those ones you can smoke
in the morning afternoon evening right
before you go to bed'll for everyone but
yeah not for everybody but it will get
you high every time you smoke it every
single time for for 15 years or whatever
how long I've I've been running it um or
smoking it Scott reach uh rare dankness
is the first guy that gave me The Ghost
and the sfv and he would sell me the
flowers right one week Scott would give
me two ounces of ghost right um the next
week Scott would give me 2 ounces of sfv
and I would notice my moods were
different huh like the flower tasted the
same but I would notice my moods were
different when I was like smoking on
ghost for a week compared to smoking on
sfv and then eventually I got those
exact Cuts so Scott gave me the sfv
thank you Scott and later down the line
I always wanted the ghost Scott wouldn't
give it to me later down the line Rich
who was partners with Scott gave me
sorry Scott but Rich gave Rich gave me
the ghost you ever smoked the star
killer from Scott yeah that shit's fire
yeah but it's not like real OG to me if
it's an OG cross just like you were
saying about you know these these
hybridized things um I don't like OG if
it's a cross I only want the Clone only
if I'm going to smoke gas I actually
can't smoke sour really or chem anymore
I only want clone only OG s and the chem
just doesn't give me the same effect I
need my ghost OG like right [ __ ]
weird I need it no and I feel like the
the Star Killer has a amazing effect and
it's a long effect I feel like it's
longer than the typical yeah I'd agree
it's a little more uplifting it's a
little more racy um for me I can't do it
I I need the ghost I need my clone only
so you don't like ghost Jane Hayes then
I guess no there was one feno that we'd
like to wash because it was super rare
that anything with terpinolene would
actually wash but we had this ghost
train Haze that smelled and tasted like
lemon lime like Sprite yeah I think we
called it Sprite feno um and it would
wash so that I like
um and I liked that it didn't really
have too much trinoline it had just
enough to give it the Sprite sensation
or that flavor but not taste like
terpinolene it was more on the limiting
side of things right yeah so where do
you see the industry going in the next
five
years um a lot of directions yeah I
think technolog is going to Prevail
automation I think that a lot of these
larger scale you know equipment
companies are going to be doing
well um there's going to be less manual
because it costs a lot to put your hands
on things every touching Point costs a
lot so we can eliminate those touching
points yeah um you're going to save your
company a lot of money it's unfortunate
I'm very craft oriented and Hands-On but
I think that's where the future is going
if they're going to be cutting us you
know little guys out um things like that
will prevail
yeah you have to trip I mean I mean even
with breeding the tools we have now for
breeding it's it's a game Cher and
genomics marker driven breeding I mean
it's all it's all going to change the
industry drastically in some ways so
especially getting from point A to point
Z being able to
skip yeah skip multiple steps speed up
the process Brands and money will always
control everything yeah like no matter
what we're doing like that's what's
going to that's what's going to take
over so you just got to stick with the
at the end of the day it's all about for
me it's all about quality like having
the best product because you have a
better product then you have a leg up on
other people so yeah no no I'm I'm
blessed to stay smoking my own little
living soil grow totally and finding
some homies that also have living soil
grows that don't add too much sweetener
or this or that you know yeah keeping it
real with the living soil yeah yeah so
if you could go back to to the younger
Nick that was in industry for maybe two
years you had one piece of advice uh
trust your instinct oh [ __ ] that was for
me that was just like my natural yeah
yeah trust your instinct um but also
take initiative um this industry is
still emerging it's still brand new in a
lot of places throughout the world so
take initiative um be creative yeah
because I think this just our world in
general right now is so opened up for
the creative you can you you know go
viral with one post type of situation
and just look at that on a on a big
scale be creative in the space and find
your own passion too so like finding
something that's different um that
you're passionate about could change
game for our industry and for the world
yeah I feel like if you have drive and
determination there's a lot of people
that don't so if you do you can do
anything like if you if you do anything
that you're you know it's especially
anything that you're passionate about if
you're passionate about it and you got
the drive and determination you can
conquer conquer whatever that is you
know and you can be a a force in that
whether you want to do cultivation
genetics there and there's so many
different things when we started in the
industry when it was the gray Market the
black market whatever you want to call
it the Legacy Market you had to do
everything you had to be the grower you
had to be the construction guy you had
to be the extract artist I mean I I did
all that stuff graic designer
packaging I mean I was one of the first
guys and my group of friends that had
like packaging on my on my flower you
know and I had some blueberry back then
I I made labels for I think I still have
one and that was in like the early 2000s
yeah so but yeah you had to do
everything now you can be a specialist
you can be a perfectionist in one one
yeah one uh one study so whether you
want to do genetics or you want to do
extract and you want to you know you do
a lot of stuff you know it's like with
the
DJing a lot you know I've got like an
amazing team behind me with a lot of the
things that I'm doing you know for these
essential education classes um that I'm
teaching I've got like a team of graphic
designers and web designers and just a
support system so um I do it a lot but
also I'm trying to be more focused in
what I know I'm good at I am not good at
the back end I'm not good at the graphic
design I'm not good at um you know a lot
of those things so I've been I think a
big learning point in the industry also
is uh delegation but not overd
delegating right you know delegating
what you're not good at but if you overd
delegate you can learn a lesson real
quick because I learned that lesson as a
kid a couple years into the industry you
know honesty is so important not just
with other people but with yourself I
think you need to people need to take a
hard look in the mirror and realize what
they're good at and what they're not
good at and be real about it and focus
on your strengths and you know that's
that's the best way definitely and yeah
constantly evolve constantly pivot
because in this industry and in this
world if you're stagnant if you stuck
with one thing you're going to get ran
over yeah and you're in the past yeah so
I think that's another reason I'm I'm
blessed to still be here is I've
constantly pivoted as the industry is
evolved yeah and there's nothing wrong
with Reinventing yourself or whatever I
mean I've seen multiple people douge is
the best example of that douge is
someone who has reinvented
himself several times since I've known
him and freaking comes out on top every
time and crushes I love douge I've
always supported douge um because Doug's
always been good to me um and I've
always been good to douge um right now
um I'm hoping I'm coming back down here
to Cali for the best of California but
we're still figuring some things out
totally yeah he's another Pioneer that
just he he uh he goes through stuff and
he takes the good with the bad I mean
I've seen him go through tough times and
I've seen him on top and he's just he
he's a fighter going though yeah he's a
fighter he's one of those dudes who's
just going to he's not giving up and
he's super passionate loves weed uh you
know he has a lot to say about it it's
you know and he's just a really good guy
at the end of the day he's a really good
guy who gives a [ __ ] yep so for sure
yeah yeah we may be having to do a dabad
do next year yeah I guess when they when
they air this episode it will be 2024 so
later this year we will probably have to
do another 10-y year anniversary dabad
do with MAA in the Bay Area I'm down bro
I'm down yeah so yeah I'll host it I'll
find the location we get douge in on it
I think it'd be fun for the the four of
us I'm down I'm down you're going to
cook too right I'm going to cook I I
will cook actually I'll probably pay
people to cook but I have good friends
that are chefs and I'll have the most
amazing food and uh yeah yeah it'll be a
good time that's what's up bro but yeah
thank you so much for coming on the show
today if somebody's interested in
getting a hold of you where can they
find you say the easiest way is
Instagram n i kka
aore t Nick on Instagram you can you can
also check out my website Nick tan.com
or DJ nick.com pretty easy to find me
online that'll actually send you if you
go to that Hub it'll send you to my
business websites it'll send you to the
current events that are happening right
now but yeah we're throwing a lot of
events so you can uh check out the
website to keep current on all the
events that we're doing awesome thank
you so much for coming on the show today
man it's been great we're going to have
to do this again soon I appreciate you
having me bro
Che
we fli it out the
[Music]
cruising back
Cru
yeah