we were talking about how we don't dab
very much
10 episodes later we're dabbing
[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James loud
podcast this is our 10th episode Marlon
was our first guest and I wanted to
invite him back to talk about his summer
tour and everything that's going on
how you doing I'm good man nice to be
here it's been a while you know it's
been a while yeah we started filming
like six months ago our first one and
that wasn't even our first real you know
we've done several podcasts over the
past after a couple years so yeah well
you know the first one was
it was nice to see but it's really nice
to see the progressor on the podcast you
know I mean I I've been watching and
yeah I like what I see it's nice yeah
we've been having a lot of fun with it
you know tuning everything in dialing
everything in yo we got a good team you
know working behind the cameras they're
doing some fun stuff and yeah man I hope
uh I hope the people taking uh heat to
the information that is being passed on
this podcast it's very informative and
you know
I hope that the people really appreciate
that yes
so what have you been up to I haven't
seen you very much lately usually we're
hanging out like once a week but yeah
well I've been to Japan and I've been to
Antigua Trinidad I've been traveling a
little bit you know I'm promoting my new
album you know so it's kind of been a
lot of travels a lot of videos shooting
a lot of music recording yeah it's been
a while nice yeah man yeah you've been
shooting music videos and yeah yeah all
over the world yeah well you know this
production it's my fourth studio album
and this is I must say the most
extensive production I've ever been
involved in yeah it's been you know hard
work but you know I appreciate the fact
that you know I'm getting to put the
music out there and still you know carry
a message to people and be able to
perform out there you know nice so
when's the big release date uh well
pre-orders will be June 30th and like
two weeks after that the album is gonna
drop nice uh yeah we're doing a
extensive run because we're trying to
promote this album Hard differently from
the ones before you know yeah yeah so
all kinds of stuff we were at the
emerald cup together yeah the award
ceremony that was pretty cool yeah that
was nice nice to see Mila
yep yeah nice seeing Milan and of course
that lifetime award was perfect you know
pretty special yeah it was special man
so yeah we actually have some uh Belle
from Heritage hash company gave me some
of the Orange turbo and I've been saving
it so we could try it together ah man I
can't wait I've of course tried it a
couple times but
I've heard about it though yeah so this
is the hash I got from Belle when I went
on to uh the tour with Mila at Heritage
and uh this is some of Frenchy's
favorite uh this is his favorite
genetics the Orange turbo which I think
is awesome and we're gonna smoke it
yeah I've always heard about the orange
too but never had a chance to really
taste it and all the flavors in it
but I think it's going to be nice cause
you know
turbo Orange turbo that says it all yeah
all right what do you think about those
rigs I really like mine I I really like
it I like the control and I I like lower
temp yeah and I like smaller depth so
this is perfect for me yeah and uh
especially when you could regulate you
know the Heat and right
really nice flavor
it's nice yeah man oh
citrusy turbo yeah a little terrible way
there for sure little citrusy turbine I
like the Citrus in it I could smell the
Citrus in there it's really cool it's
nice
oh I like that temperature what
temperature is that on 420 429 no 365.
oh wow I do like 420 but 365 for that
390 anywhere in there I think is great
but 365 for that low temp yeah yeah
that's like a really low temp dab
tastes good though
yeah so uh
what's on the agenda for the rest of the
summer well
we head into
Jamaica for album release party
and then we'll be heading to a few
islands in the Caribbean Trinidad and
Tobago included
we have uh
I have to finish up a few video shoot
yeah because this album has a lot of
videos
well as a audio you know
and uh yeah I'll be kind of moving I got
a few shows for the summer
uh Northwest Reggae Fest is one the
first one to come July 22nd I believe
yeah I'll be
pretty much you know busy for the rest
of the year trying to get things in
order
you know yeah also this summer
you know I sold those seeds yeah so I'm
trying to put them in the ground and you
know have them
so I can kind of I'm doing the Marlin
Asher's Choice yeah Marlin Master's
choice in California it's gonna be on
the
direct scene coming here very soon what
are your favorite uh crosses well the
favorite well I was looking at the
skittle banana
yeah that was you know something I'm
kind of hoping comes out yeah real good
because I really like the idea of you
know yeah the banana and Skittle yeah uh
I also like the
that's the banana Skittles back to the
Skittles yeah also anxious to see what
the purple ganja Cowboy comes out yeah
yeah I'm anxious to see what that looks
like you know so a few of the strains in
there that I'm kind of excited because I
know there's gonna be
you know one or two good good mix in
there that is really going to come out
good and yeah we're gonna take it from
there launch some pre-rolls
practice flowers some you know yeah
eight quarters
half you know it goes uh yeah I'm trying
to bring something different
something different something unique
unique yeah yeah you know I saw some
pictures this morning from Josh Freeman
Joshua Silverback Freeman yeah he's
doing some piff right now and some Cuban
black Haze looks really cool yeah oh
gosh so man so I I want the people to
appreciate
The Strain that I'm giving to them yeah
you know so this is some I'm taking
pride in and I really want it to be a
success nice yeah for sure
yeah we gotta go visit Josh check out
his flower yeah definitely I I I it's
been a while since I've seen him too
yeah that one crazy Emerald cup it was
freezing cold that one year but it was
raining
it was definitely a freezing one yeah we
did some good weather huh yeah we've
been through some weather we've been
through some weather and you know storms
you know yeah man but you know all in
all the life was good to us man I
you know I appreciate the Cannabis
industry yeah throughout the years how
is Trinidad looking right now well I
must say Trinidad is looking very
promising uh I just went down there and
your name was being called a latte nice
because you know everyone is looking to
change for genetics for Trinidad
because you know we kind of
showed them that we have intention of
doing that so yeah you know I went down
there and uh it was crazy man I I
we had some genetics that I I took a few
packs down there a while ago and I
got a phone call saying hey remember
those seeds you give me back then the
kanja farmer seed from the ganja
Pharmacy company I said oh yeah you see
I think you gave me some TKO I still got
it right on my page TKO and jelly bean I
said all right he said I got some smokes
for you oh my god James
I swear I was in California no way I
swear crazy it's amazing how the world
markets are changing and getting more
geared towards you know I mean with the
same thing being able to grow the same
way man I was that indoor or was that
outdoor that was outdoor I also huh I
met a guy who had a little indoor grow
in Trinidad yeah and his stuff was
phenomenal you know so I plan to
give him some guns or pharmacies and see
how it works yeah yeah I'd love to see
the stuff on St Vincent uh fruition too
you know Bobby and said Vincent he
called me the other day and he's saying
he can see himself working with no one
else but uh so he's doing his best to
get himself straight and so if we ever
come there you'll have everything ready
for us you know right yeah so Saint
Vincent is you know
something that we have on the calendar
and we got to pursue and pick up on that
soon you know right right yeah yeah for
sure and then Japan let's talk more
about Japan that's some legendary stuff
right there oh my God Japan man Japan
was off the train man I was blown away
by the technology in Japan
from the bullet train to the Billboards
that popped out 3D
to the crosswalks it was you know Japan
is a
it's a big place too you know and it's
very beautiful I must say that how many
shows did you guys play 13 shows 13
shows in in uh for how how long 13 days
yeah
that's the way to do it yeah 13 shows 13
days a lot of traveling and a lot of
sightseeing
anybody that thinks the music industry
is easy
I just saw Adam saying oh you know what
I don't like to be a DJ because
everybody think being a DJ is so easy
yeah well it's kind of the same thing
for being an Entertainer everyone sees
the glamor and glitter on the stage but
man there's a lot behind that that makes
that movement special yeah yeah
sometimes for years years and Amanda I
know traveling takes away
from your you know your being you know
you you're away from family your loved
ones and but traveling you know is so
enlightening to me I see so much
different people I see so much different
families that I could love and so
you know for me being a musician is I
think is everything that you know it's
worth living yeah yeah man for real it's
been an interesting Journey so
definitely have
and then music videos usually where
you've been shooting music videos you
shot some in uh Jamaica yeah yeah I had
uh like four or five videos maybe six
six yeah shot in Jamaica wow because
most of the
art is that collab with me on the album
is from Jamaica so I had to go meet with
them to shoot the video yeah also to
recall and yellow so it was a blessed
visit to Jamaica I had a lot of you know
good Runnings with
some of the legendary artists that I
knew from growing up and yeah yeah so it
was it was blessed Jamaica is great food
is good food is good water is good you
know relations good yeah Jamaica is a
nice place to visit always yeah I
haven't been there in a while but I'm
already go back yeah I'm ready to take a
bunch of friends over there yeah yeah
exactly so I'm ready for us to make a
trip down there uh
you know a lot of people in the Cannabis
industry you know look up to you James
and it's a blessing
that wherever I go I could hear your
name mentioned in positive ways so you
know Jamaica is just one of those place
so we gotta make a trip down there soon
for sure yeah yeah so let's see what
we're gonna try next
we got some so we got some really good
stuff it's sour cherries from SoCal dank
oh man this stuff is pretty special
let's say What's it live
so uh
yes it's uh it's rosin yeah yeah and
this stuff is just
special oh my God as much as the Orange
turbo is special this stuff is just as
special and it's got this nice cherry
flavor you know lately it's been nice to
take a dab since I have my rig
yeah you know we were talking about how
we don't dab very much
episodes later we're dabbing
and uh perfect I mean I enjoy I enjoy
this rig a lot
[Music]
um
when Mila was in town Sam
from uh Focus V came and gave me gave me
a rig and was telling me it's
you know it's really good and it works
really well and
I'm kind of skeptical usually of
everything
uh but I really like the way it works I
think it's solid it's a solid piece
yeah my Minds is very
convenient to cause
you know sometimes you want to smoke and
you can't blow clouds in certain places
you know for sure this is have you tried
on the airplane yet oh no yeah I'm just
kidding
why are we going to Jamaica we probably
try that nice
yeah I think these are efficient the I
mean I think I read some of the comments
online about the battery not being very
good my battery seems to be just fine I
haven't had problems with it too much
how's that taste oh that is phenomenal I
like the lemon flavor in it lemon juice
it's like so it's sour cherries and it's
definitely got that cherry kind of like
citrusy cherry
smooth I like I like the way they get
the Terps in when they it's live resin
you know it really hits the spot
yeah I feel like this is just so smooth
too Lemon Cherry
I like
taking dabs or hitting pens I have a
rosin cart
before I go to the gym I take one good
hit yeah yeah keeps me focused I feel
like
I prefer doing dabs typically in the
morning
but these aren't even like real dabs
like not like we used to do or no we're
heating up some some yeah nail and then
some crazy nails
yeah and then people looking at us funny
like we're doing something wrong yeah
man it's it's nice where it's it's at
now though yeah I could dab in my car I
feel like the extracts are good yeah you
can dab it yeah this fits in your cup
holder very nice yeah not today
no but but it does it yeah I think I
like everything about it it's cool I
like the color they got a army green one
forest green I think yeah I got a I got
a black one too yeah the black one's
cool this is the one that changes all
the colors yeah uh if you wanted to yeah
mice I think they all do that though oh
yeah yeah mine's change color nice so
you're yeah I love the focus too yeah I
got it or the Carter twos yeah I got it
set away man I I ate some mushroom and
then I was then I was dabbing with that
and the lights was just changing on
changing moods that was nice what do you
think about all the mushroom products
that are out right now man I'm all for
it you know I you know I like mushroom a
lot so you know I'm all for the mushroom
the new products that coming out from it
you know some of them are pretty good
too you know I've had some nice
chocolate bars that really
not too harsh and not too mellow it's
just right you know so yeah I'm all for
the mushroom products right now yeah I'm
kind of liking that they definitely
taste better yeah yeah it was easier on
everyone to you know get some Vibes have
a trip because now you don't have to
worry about that teeth but I still like
eating
the mushroom caps you know yeah it's
just getting those mushrooms stuck in
your teeth yeah it's just something that
I still do cardboard and sunflower seeds
that's kind of what it tastes like
exactly I think I've grown to you know
appreciate the taste yeah yeah of course
after the taste comes out beautiful you
know moment that only a personal
mushroom can appreciate so yeah yeah I
do
like eating the mushrooms still
yeah so we're gonna launch some more
more genetics too in the near future oh
yeah so right now we're trying to get
some Blends together and make you know
grow out some stuff and make sure that
we have the right you know we we put out
genetics but
we always put out the best that we have
you know so kind of Pharmacy that's
definitely coming stronger in the near
future yeah yeah you can expect to see
more stuff on the James loud genetics
website and also through distribution
we're talking to maybe some Distributors
seats here now has some of the stuff and
we'll be uh launching some new gear
really soon yep definitely that's
something you guys can look out for is
coming that last dab there was that a
good one yeah of course let me tell you
this it changed the mood and the high
that I was feeling before so that is
definitely a nice one
so yeah we got some
BP Times Wilson that was given to me by
uh Sam at one of the events they had
BP Plus from rosin Tech yeah BP I'm not
sure if that's blue Power
there could be any number of genetics
I'm not 100 sure
smells really good
yeah and that cream tape too
it smells good I give the last one a 10
on it that's like yeah yeah I think
that's the one that I like that's a tent
yeah
for flavor and like I still taste it
yeah exactly
so this year has been your most
productive year ever how many tour dates
are scheduled and have you done this
year like combined is you gonna do uh
this year was my most productive year
even though I had to do less shows
oh really yeah I had to do less shows
this year to facilitate uh recording and
all of that stuff
for this new album
and coming up I got a lot of shows
coming up to finish here because the
album is finished now so we started
taking bookings again
and that is something that I'm kind of
I've been missing performing so it's I
had my first show a few last weekend and
you know it was it was real nice the
band was sharp everyone was loving the
music and the feeling of being back on
the stage again was very you know it was
overwhelming at times I felt so alive
you know yeah so definitely going
forward
you know on tour
and we had a conversation with my
booking agent and we now looking to put
together
uh album run
tours for the album so yeah definitely
it's gonna be tour dates starts from
July 22nd
so I'll be back on the road back on the
road on the road until the end of the
year yep uh till February
wow I've already been getting bookings
for February so it's gonna be from now
summer is always a nice time for an
artist to be around you know because we
got some nice shows out there the
Caribbean the you know Canada Europe
Africa so yeah
it's a it's gonna be nice I can't wait
to be back on the road you know
traveling doing music on the road and
yeah it's
it's gonna be fun yeah
all right
just like old times
taking dabs that's pretty good right
that is good
that one is
burning of the nose
yeah Jane that one is strong
yep
that's a good one yeah I think you're
gonna be
giving that one a 10 to
not so much for flavor it's not as
flavorful but no but it's it does have
good flavor yeah but it's kind of strong
too yeah it's the strongest one so far
yeah so far
we did it in the right order
um
has by far the strongest one
I wonder what determines the potency in
the
dabs well it's just like with the
flowers the cannabinoids and the
terpenes and the Entourage effect
between the two of them and I think that
high THC does now is give you the
strongest High yeah and some of these
yeah definitely these terpenes and
flavonoids affect your your high
significantly
enhance the high because of the flavor
and taste that you constantly get in
your palette so yeah
yeah I'm all about tasting yeah it's
good it's good we're gonna do ten more
yeah I could do 10. I know you could I
don't know if I could
[Music]
yeah you know we we we kind of pace
ourselves differently over the years
when it comes to dabbing going with that
back to back like for hours we just sit
around yeah yeah and the high was crazy
too back then you would be like I feel
like we had high tolerance too though so
it was different we'd sit and shoot the
[ __ ] and drink worm Heinekens yeah I'm
goodness yeah hot goodness this guy hot
Guinness so that is a tradition that
goes back a long time in the Caribbean
right yeah well in the Caribbean people
think that you got nothing in their
stomach that is cold you know no
refrigerator down there I heard I heard
from somebody down there that it's like
uh Viagra yeah it's like it's a liquid
that's what I'm seeing yeah so you have
nothing cool down there so if you drink
some cold you have to heat it up your
body will have to heat it up before you
can
even use what you know what you you just
drank coal right but when you drink it
room temperature now it goes directly
to your bloodstream so it just it just
gives you that boost of energy and you
know it makes you powerful so yeah it's
I like drinking it warm because you know
I sing and cool stuff kind of mess my
vocal up so having a hug Guinness is
hard against what's your secret with tea
I know you got a secret like honey honey
and lemon probably some peppermint
sometimes uh tea you know
is very important to relax your vocal
you know cause
sometimes we
as a singer you're not really supposed
to be
talking all day
right having your vocals and you end up
talking and smoking yes before you
perform yeah because I am that kind of
person I I like to interact with the
crowd I like to you know so I always
find myself in the crowd talking with
somebody smoking before I show so yeah
so it definitely helps me to have a hot
cup of tea before I go on the stage yeah
yes
Davin just reminds me of we're at the
catch a fire you're you're uh
San Francisco and we go backstage and
these guys have like the old hot knife
rig oh man they they were crazy they
dabbing like they just found out about
the evolution
1995 again you know like we used to do
hot knife hits yep uh I went through a
bunch of my parents lives even when I
was a kid we would take him and put them
on the burner and get him put you know
old school hash rosin doesn't work like
that on those hard times you can't hit
them up that much but man and then we'd
use a cardboard tube and if you weren't
used to doing it man it would take you
out
[Laughter]
yeah
was definitely crazy hot knife
man
I I I must say
catch a fire
and seeing them dabbing that way brought
back a lot of memories because you know
when we were just starting we would not
know that we didn't want to dab on a hot
nail yeah you know what I'm saying and
it's over the years we started realizing
oh man we should make it a little cooler
and yeah catch a fire is from New
Zealand yeah yeah definitely so so it
was It was kind of strange to see it
there but then it brought back the
memories of I wouldn't normally do one
of those dabs but they were so into it
yeah they were doing it like like it's
nothing but but for me
they were dabbing Bud like that too yeah
yeah exactly on the hot nights pressing
the hot knives together with the thing
and then they had a tube yep yeah it was
a trip yeah so for me
I couldn't see myself doing too much of
that no that ruins your throat too yeah
exactly because the heat yeah
was not uh
good for any vocal after that
but it was nice though I don't know how
they do it and sing too yeah it's it's
trippy
but I guess willpower yeah yeah I must
be man must be
yeah
well yeah so if people want to find out
about what you're doing where where can
they go to find more about your tour
dates and everything else is Instagram
the best place or website you know any
so any media platform any social media
platform you know that
I always make sure and pretty big
Facebook following too I think you got
like a million followers on Facebook
yeah oh well I always try to keep my
fans on who's interested in what I'm
doing you know yeah I always try to keep
them informed so I put up a lot of
content on what I'm doing when I'm doing
it so
everyone who knows Mother Nature knows
where to find me Mr marlonasha Instagram
you know Facebook Marlon sobers you know
Marlon Ganja Farmer Asher Facebook you
know so
everyone knows where to find me on the
social media platform so I guess you
know I'll keep you know putting out in
for their I hope hope it reach you know
the broader Mass
and when are we going back to St Vincent
ah man we should go to Saint Vincent
soon because you know I'm going to
Trinidad with like within the next
couple weeks yeah I'm gonna go down
there and do some shows nice I'm gonna
try to
have some seeds back there yeah
and do a few experiments nice because I
want to see
how the average person will grow the
seed down there yeah you know not the
guys we've given out quite a few seeds
all over the world and they always grow
the weed down a Trinidad and smoke it
and then say oh my God yeah the weed was
good but this is the first guy that
actually saved some for me nice and yeah
that was it's nice to see that it grew
so well but I would also like to see how
the average person I wanna I wanna give
some seed to just some random people who
oh I got two trees at home you know just
to see how it would grow with them too
yeah yeah
so that will definitely give me an idea
on how on what seed to give right and
what seed to use down in Trinidad nice
so yeah
yeah the funny thing with that is that a
lot of people want the OG Kush down
there and it's like not that there's
anything wrong with OG Kush but I think
breeding it it's a hard I don't think
they have the experience with OG as yet
to climatizing that genetic to that
environment is kind of rough as we've
seen yeah it's gonna be rough it don't
really grow down there it's this short
on the ground and so yeah so I'm not
sure how
you know the people down there perceived
the growing of OG yeah but I can tell
that they don't really have the
experience
and the strain is not really climately
it's for yeah that weather down there
yeah I think over the next five years
they're going to get a lot more stuff
down there and definite so I I think the
banana is going to do good down there we
got a bunch of bananas yeah for
specifically for Saint Vincent maybe
some fraternity banana crosses that I
think will do well that are definitely
more on that tropical equatorial leaning
man we gotta
we gotta definitely go to Trinidad right
now and because
I've been asked a lot of questions about
soil
content and you know yeah so it'll be
nice to go visit a few places and
you know kind of give them an Insight on
how to really
neutralize and keep their soil alive for
planting you know yeah testing their
soil I think that's the biggest thing if
you watch the scamness from Crest of
soil episode he was talking about living
soil yeah yeah microbiology and I think
that stuff is really important testing
in soil I mean to know what's in your
soil especially exactly so I think they
have a lot of fertile soil though yeah
they have a lot of fertile soil they
have fertile soil because we had a lot
of agriculture in Trinidad
but at the same time I don't know what
they were using to grow as far as
chemicals and sure all of that so but
the soil is fertile but I don't know
what the farmers were putting in the
soil while they were growing so that's
why you know it's very necessary to test
the soil down there and see how you know
what is in there and What needs to come
out for sure yeah yeah well thank you
for coming on as a guest for the 10th
episode man it's been great we'll get
you on the 100th episode as well
definitely so that's just a snap click
and a jump away so
yeah man thanks for having me and I must
say you know it's always a pleasure to
sit with you James you know
I love you as a brother so we'll always
be you know sitting together and having
a good day thanks for having me man for
sure
[Music]
we got really hot like I'm high as [ __ ]
from that day yeah from that third dad
bro yeah that last one was like oh man
nah