foreign
[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James loud
podcast today we're doing a remote from
my house and my special guest for today
is Brandon rust from bokashi Earthworks
how you doing Brandon
I'm doing great how you doing fantastic
so yeah you have a you have a long
history with the plant you have a long
history with podcasting from future
cannabis projects to several other
podcasts I'm glad to have you as a guest
today thanks yeah I really enjoy uh
plant science and I have a lot I have a
large library of knowledge that I've got
gotten to take deep uh dives into I lead
I read a lot of uh science white papers
too and I you know find out and I've
kind of figured out what the practical
application for a lot of the Sciences
for some of these different
processes that are happening in nature
and how we can apply them into uh
systems and uh
replicate that and show it on data
really cool so for our guests that don't
know who you are uh give us a little
background on how you got started in
cannabis and then what you do
oh sure yeah uh my name is Brandon rust
I've been cultivating since about 2001
2002 right around there you know I got
into it because
uh some of my dad's younger homies which
were my older homies kind of brought me
under their wing and they had already
been ground for a couple of years and uh
I was just doing a bunch of [ __ ]
working with those guys they were having
me like mow their yard and wash their
dog and I was just a kid back then you
know I was a teenager
and uh you know washing hydrocorn Rock
and [ __ ] so they could reuse it in their
Hydro System doing stuff like that and I
knew what they were doing but they kind
of tested me I did it for a while before
I ever got to see the inside of a garden
so I was kind of like it's kind of like
their little [ __ ]
approach some karate kid Mr Miyagi
approach
it it really was dude they kind of
tested me they wanted to see if I was
willing to put in the work
um and they were also also being
cautious because they wanted to [ __ ]
protect their own asses hey I have a
interesting story because I actually
grew up in foster care but I met my
father who was who got sent to prison in
96 and he's still in prison
but I got in touch with him through my
um my mom after uh
I became an adult when I turned 18.
and
uh he basically was like hey go meet
some of my friends you know and so I did
and that's kind of how those
relationships built uh so they knew who
I was but they you know they couldn't
vouch for me back then you know I was
just uh I was just some [ __ ] punk kid
you know and so I I you know I did all
the things and I worked worked my way in
and I got to know the guys and they
finally brought me and uh first thing I
actually did
when they brought me in was
um I cut open a galvanized steel conduit
to steal power because one of them was
an actual electrician
so he knew how to do all the electric
work but uh he needed wires to clamp
onto so uh that's all that's the first
thing that I that like really got me in
there because after I did that they were
like I mean they paid me like two grand
I was super [ __ ] stoked I was like
yeah this is such a come up dude I was
you know because I
that was like at the time probably uh
you know one of the times where I just
got a big ass chunk of change while I
was like [ __ ] yeah dude I just got
[ __ ] paid two G's right there okay
cool yeah that's like 10 grand in
today's terms
yeah so
um yeah but I started working with those
guys I worked with those guys uh Dirty
Harry and triple D down in San Diego uh
they actually are the ones who created
The Afghani bull rider not to be
confused with the original bull rider
but this was um
the original bull ride across to an
Afghan and we ran that from probably
about 2001 to real hard until about 2009
but I worked with them for about two
years then I had my own partners that I
worked with and had you know different
grows here and there and you know got
into trouble went to prison a couple
times
wow I ended up you know every time I was
locked up I was like I gotta get the
hell out of California this place and as
soon as I did everything kind of changed
I got out here to Oklahoma I I started
working in the legal Market out here you
know I was able to take the business
that I had started in San Diego and
Incorporated it out here and I've been
able to really focus in on the Cannabis
Agronomy and microbiology side and you
know taking a look at the cultivation
system holistically
well everything from you know
biosecurity and integrated Pest
Management to
um soil fertility health and management
data collection environmental you know
management or you know everything that
we do in
cannabis cultivation nice and so then
tell us about uh bukashi Earthworks
oh it initially started with I went on
to this Facebook book group in like 2014
it was called the probiotic Farmers
Alliance and they were talking about
you know soil microbiology and about you
know bokashi which is usually a like a
fermented organic waste that you that
you can use as basically a bio
fertilizer
so there's a whole group that was
dedicated and that that group still
exists my knowledge it sparked my
interest and I was at a time
this was around 2014 when the price of
cannabis started to really drop because
when we started we were selling pounds
for forty eight hundred dollars a pound
or 300 an ounce all the way up no matter
how much you got like it didn't matter
that was the price and people were
willing to pay it and then we would you
know go to Northern California to the
people that would be running diesel
generators and they'd have like 200 or
200 likes which we couldn't really bust
that big we had multiple houses we'd
have like 12 lights here maybe like four
lights over here another four lights
over here uh but we would go pick up
like larger packs up in uh Northern
California and bring those down and
but uh
the prices started to decrease over time
and I remember specifically it was
2014 I was in San Diego and all the uh
the way that they did like the
permitting you couldn't like
you could get uh like a dispensary
license but it wouldn't be like zone so
you would just get fine
and so people were just like okay cool
we'll just take fine so all these shops
started popping up and then everybody
started cultivating and it was like and
the landscape started to change
that's the like the like the period for
me when I really started noticing it
because pounds were at like 25 or 2 400
dollars
and I was like damn dude I was like I
wonder if it's gonna you know like it
left me in a place thinking like okay
I'm gonna have to rethink like the way
that I'm doing this because I need to
decrease my overhead
um that's what actually drove me into
Organics it was because I wanted to
figure out how to reduce my my overhead
and
um you know
I just went for it because I was like
let's let's try it I delved into some of
the the
the Bro Science I guess I looked at a
lot of the old recipes like
uh sub cool recipe and Coots recipe and
you know different
recipes that I could find online I
didn't have a great success and I was
running
um you know I ran the two gallon ebb and
flow buckets you know with the hydrocorn
rocks and the little you know little
four lighter pattern Checker and some of
the you know I remember the first the
first
um grow that we ever did it was a four
bedroom house and the whole place was
converted had three 4 000 watt flowering
rooms a thousand watt bedroom and we'd
be pulling out
36 plants
in for every room every like two weeks
or something like that you know and we
had a little checkerboard metal halide
HPS doing the ebb and flow and I did
that same exact system for like 11 years
and I ran
I think I ran General
uh three-part General with some like
maybe some additives here and there
I did that part by itself was good
though I mean I think a lot of us grew
up using three-part for for the time
that was what a lot of us had to work
with it was good though I mean we were
doing the same thing we had our BR or
Hannah meter that was like the size of a
brick you know and it was like they're
indestructible yeah we'd be still
measuring our ppms measuring our our pH
and topping off our rezies and all that
[ __ ] you know it's I ended up like
losing a whole room because like the AC
failed or like a pump failed I don't
even know what it was but it was like
something mechanical in the room failed
and it was like [ __ ] whole room went
down lost it and I was like [ __ ] like
this [ __ ] sucks dude that's like
thousands of dollars thousands of
[ __ ] dollars that were [ __ ] lost
you know and so
um I ended up kind of just switching
over to
like potting mix but I was still running
uh I was still running newts you know
and I did that for like a year before I
switched out completely over to organic
and and I had to relearn everything
because once I started trying to build
soils and like figure it out
all right dude I I was like I don't know
what the [ __ ] I'm doing like I gotta
figure this out that's what that's
basically what happened I've been doing
a certain thing that worked really
really well but once I like changed up
the protocol
and like veered from something else it
was like I had to relearn and like
understand the science and what I was
like why do I need to add this why do I
need to add this what's you know and
finding out all the the nuances of what
elements are there for what and what how
the levels of where those should be in
accordance to you know total soluble
nutrition of that nutrient in the soil
right
so you went to school for um Agronomy or
did you was that later or you you're all
self-taught
no I'm all self-taught so
um
what I ended up doing was I started to
before I ever got into the commercial
side of cultivation
I was doing soil testing because I
wanted to understand
uh the you know the soil levels I I
wanted to try to figure that out so I
could like you know create a program
that was
that was basically organic that was all
organic that I could Implement into a
program a complete program and not have
to guess at you know because it here's
the issue like
I've always been able to grow a great
week but if I have an issue
that
like let's say appears during week for a
flower and I am addressing it as that uh
deficiency symptom appears or that or
whatever that symptom of whatever it
might be appears
by the time that symptom appears we're
already probably about 50 percent into
like a deficiency for example so if I'm
like
running my plants and all of a sudden
dude everything's [ __ ] getting yellow
at the bottoms and I'm running out of
nitrogen it's like oh [ __ ] uh that I
shouldn't be doing I shouldn't be
running out of nitrogen I want to know
how much I should have had in that
system at the beginning
so that we're not running out through
the system so that we we can do
you know basic you know soil builds that
contain the proper amount of nutrition
that'll allow us to do very very minimal
maintenance and get
great results not just quality but that
can compete on the quantity side as well
right and consistency so every time you
do it you get the same results or
similar results
yeah and so here's the thing so like
when whenever we're running a program or
like anybody people that I work with
so
in the in the in the instance that
they're using my soil my soil comes
built it already meets the target
nutritional levels that are built for
cannabis so I've I already know what
they are as far as the total amount of
nutrition that needs to be in soil how
it falls into solution and when we're
looking at how we do that we're looking
at standard soil tests and then a
saturated Pace test so a standard test
will show you collectively what's in the
soil and then a saturated Pace test
allows you to see every single element
in the parts per million that's falling
into solution so as you water that soil
as the the mineral ions that the plant
observes the mineral nutrition whether
it's the phosphate anion or the divalent
form of calcium magnesium potassium any
of those things they all uh they fall
into the solution right and they're
uptaken in or diffuse across the
membranes with the water
and we can actually look at all of the
mineral ions that are in the water with
the saturated paste test so instead of
just looking at the EC and the PPM
I can look at
those two factors plus I can look at
every single individual individual
element I can look at phosphorus and
calcium and potassium and I can also
look at all my secondary all my
micronutrients I can look at things that
are antagonistic like bicarbonate and
sodium and chloride and things that I
know if they're going to be high in soil
is going to cause antagonisms in that
system can be out of balance if those
those things are too high so I'm able to
look at different types of data on soil
and be able to determine what I need to
add into that soil if I don't meet a
Target on that solution so if my target
PPM is between 8 and 1000 PPM and then
let's say calcium is between 150 and 200
PPM and magnesium is between 32 and 40
PPM and uh potassium is between
um 125 and 150 PPM right and we're
looking at all of these different
elements in the actual amount of
availability I know all those targets
right so if we're looking at a soil and
it's not meeting that Target I know what
I need to add of what certain element to
bring that Target up to a sufficient
level
so if if someone had a soil and they
came to me and they're like hey can you
do a test for me and I can look at their
soil I could look at their pH I could pH
balance it I could and let's say it's
only a 400 parts per million total
soluble salts and everything's just kind
of low I can look at that soil and say
this is what you're going to need to add
in in the exact quantity to be able to
balance the soil out and so what I've
done is I've provided you know those
types of services to the people that I
work with and then I also provide them
with all of those individual base
elements so most people will buy a
branded Pro product right like I do have
branded products because I take all the
stuff that we're buying in bulk and I
distribute this for like home Growers
and stuff but like when I'm working with
commercial producers I'm selling them 50
pound bags you know and they're very
cost effective because if you buy a bag
of magnesium sulfate and that's pretty
much your sole source for magnesium
it's going to be very very efficient to
be able to get that into that system
it's very soluble you can also use it in
the foiler spray and it's only about
maybe 25 bucks for a 50 pound bag
right you know and that so that's going
to last you know a commercial producer a
long time
just that small amount you know and so
the larger you scale if you're buying in
bulk these things get even cheaper and
so it becomes you're basically operating
the same way that uh
conventional agriculture but you're
using organic amendments you know you're
using natural like organic amendments
and natural minerals you know things
like Epsom salt or gypsum gypsum is you
know calcium sulfate now that is
considered a salt but it's natural it
just they it just
in their abundance you can pull it out
with a front loader and then they just
micronize it to make it soluble you know
they crush it up so it's not treated in
any way it's just kind of pulled out of
the ground and crushed and then like
here you go here's this mineral so we
have you know complete lists of what we
can use as far as mineral inputs for
different elements and so I try to stick
with single use elements to address
single elements that need to be
addressed so as far as testing
um and all this started if we go a step
back you started this as something it
was you were doing it for yourself and
then it evolved into a business where
you're helping others yeah well I was
always producing cannabis to support
myself that was what I that you know
that's what I did for forever
you know and I still grow weed at home
and [ __ ] you know what I mean right but
so it's always been a business but it
was always just you know
[ __ ]
you know slanging weed to the [ __ ]
homeboys and people that have run that
are running delivery services and you
know you know how it goes dude we're
just we're trapping
yeah so but this has evolved into a real
business uh you know because when I got
into the commercial side and people were
looking at me to like hey like we need
to like make sure I like I need to make
sure I have to collect data somehow I
need to be able to replicate the system
over and over and over again right and
so that's what drove me even harder on
the Agronomy because before I got into
the commercial space or the legal space
out here in Oklahoma
because I'm originally from San Diego
but uh before I got into the the legal
space I was already testing and I was
already like looking into it and playing
around with it but it was like I really
hit it hard and started learning started
getting books started you know taking a
uh Agronomy courses and things of that
so I could really really educate myself
and really understand
the the not just the soil science but
actually like the what do I need to add
in which quantities because that's what
Agronomy really is it's being able to
unlock the key to the castle if if you
only have
you know
75 PPM of calcium how much uh gypsum do
you need to add into that system to
bring it up to 150 right I know what
though all those are and I built like
calculators that can all do it automated
for me now but
it it's figuring all that out and then
and then putting it to practical use
because if you have a Target level for
cannabis right that starts with testing
that was done out of the 70s and there's
a book called plant analysis handbook
which is where the information comes
from like it started off with the leaf
tissue analysis and like what the
percentage of calcium should be what the
percentage of nitrogen be all those
elements you can get a baseline because
we can do not just the soil testing but
we can do
the leaf tissue analysis and if we know
we're hitting the specific Targets on
our saturated pace and it's equating to
the right percentage that we're looking
for in tissue then we know those are the
right levels but we can also look at
like the overall health like and if
you're not guessing and you know like
how to grow good weed to begin with and
you can map something out
you can see what it's like to be able to
push those targets and see what the
standard Target is that's been that's
been
um published in literature versus like
what your healthiest crop looks like you
know oh hey I have
you know six percent calcium versus the
three three and a half that they suggest
you know because they're Cal I think the
calcium was like 2.2 to
uh three three point one percent calcium
uh if you're looking at that book if my
memory serves me
but it's like ideally I see that like
four and a half to five and a half
is is better but I've seen all the way
up to like eight percent in and seen
plants that were massive and they were
just crushing right so you know that you
can you can learn stuff from the data
too like understanding that it's that
you can almost not get too much calcium
it's just that that calcium does have
antagonisms especially with phosphorus
and other cations and so delivering too
much might upsell upset the nutrient
balance but if you can keep giving it to
it you know it's not going to have a
negative
consequence like I don't think anybody's
ever complained about calcium toxicity
you know right for sure so uh data
points you collect a lot of data points
sounds like you collect a bunch it's
it's one of the topics that I keep going
back to on my shows with different
people is like collecting data points
whether you're developing your palette
or you're you know looking at what
potential problems are or how to improve
your soil I think data points are
everything you know in life in life in
general you want to improve data points
of the way to do it
well and think about it from a business
perspective too if you cannot sit down
and say hey these are the targets that
we're reaching for this is you know the
soil that I'm about to give you this is
what we've you know and be able to show
them and say Here's the data here's how
this thing functions and works as a
whole and you can map it out and you can
replicate it over and over again that's
what people want to see so they can have
that assurance and confidence that
they're going to be able to run a
program that's data driven that is going
to be replicable over and over and over
so they can not so much have to bump uh
focus on trying to address deficiencies
or try to figure stuff in the back end
of their grow when they can be focusing
more on their brand and their marketing
and their distribution and their taxes
and their you know metric if they have
metric you know they're reporting all
the stuff that's included in these
vertically integrated business models so
the you know ideally that the the thing
is to reduce overhead
by using these types of systems and a
good example of this is if you were to
take something like
let's take a a farm I'm not going to
mention the name out in New Mexico that
I visited they had one Greenhouse
that was 80 000 square feet okay and
they were all running cocoa in two
gallon pots now at the end of their
they were doing terrible by the way but
at the end of their run what they do is
they cut all their plant matter they
removed that they remove all of the
fertigation lines from their pots they
take all those pots they dump all of
their cocoa in a pile someone would
they'd pay to have that cocoa removed
from the facility
and then they'd go wash all those
buckets they'd go refill them with cocoa
they'd go reset them on the table hook
up all the fertigation lines right
so that's a massive amount of Labor in a
soil system you would be cutting down
the material removing it for uh drying
and curing then you would be going in
there you would top draw you would you
would test your soil be pre-harvest to
get it to the lab because it takes five
days for the lab analytics to come back
and then you can get a recipe that
basically says what needs to be added to
that soil to bring it back up to
nutritional sufficiency so basically
what you do is you harvest
you top dress you plant back into that
media and then you run your program
again and so you're not it's less labor
intensive and it's more cost effective
because you're not also
using a bunch of uh fertigation salts
like synthetics that have really low
nutrient use efficiency only about 10
percent of what you're putting in there
actually is a is observed by the plant
and that's why you have to constantly
feed over and that's why there's so much
waste
now in these types of systems you have
better nutrient use efficiency
especially if you're using something
like a smart carbon human fertilizers
and you're and you're using top dress
nutrients because you're addressing
carbon
that holds on to plant mineral ions and
deliver them into solution and you can
see how they're delivering them into
solution to the data and we're not just
looking at pH and EC and temperature but
we can look at every single plant
mineral ion and adjust it based off of
what we add into that soil based off of
that top dress but it's just less labor
intensive it's more cost effective
and so it's about
you know Bringing Down the production
costs for people because look here's the
thing dude
when we're talking about cannabis it's
become an agricultural commodity
regardless of whether it's craft
you're using it for medicinal or adult
use it doesn't really matter anymore
because now it's become so
commercialized and the only way that the
small guy is going to be able to take
advantage of this is going to be able to
by decreasing their overhead just like a
you know small sustainable Farms do
right how do we do that in cannabis well
we need to start by reducing our
overhead reducing our inputs reducing
our water usage our nutrient inputs
reducing our labor costs
those are all things that are all
possible to do and scale with these
types of systems and it allows people to
focus on the business side because it's
so difficult to to run a small business
because there's so much competition you
have to have good marketing and you have
to have good sales and distribution and
then you also have to worry about all
the back-end business stuff I know as a
business person you know that you're
accounting and you're bookkeeping and
your taxes and your reporting and dude
that's so important man right which it's
just about making it easy dude
simplifying it and making it easy yeah
for sure
yeah it's not easy to run a business I
mean I think
growing cannabis isn't easy but your
business on top of that is like a whole
nother thing because I feel like and
it's not typically you're not just you
have one person they're not doing it all
you got you got several people you know
we all in like my business we we all
wear many hats but there's still several
people and we all work synergistically
together and it's it's not easy these
days and the price of cannabis has been
low I think there's been a lot of people
struggling and so yeah lowering the cost
of your inputs being as efficient as
possible is going to guarantee you
success for years to come if you do it
right
yeah and so that's you know that's been
my main focus I work with a lot of
uh independent owner operators I worked
with a lot of people all over the
country but I work with
a really great great group of people
that I'm like close to because they're
local to me here in Oklahoma and I even
put together like this craft Farmers
Alliance where I'm just trying to help
get everybody in the same room all
together
so that way we can help with cross
branding and marketing making sure
people aren't growing all the same stuff
trying to compete for shelf space uh
help with you know education when it
comes to the legislation and helping
push back against shitty legislation
that they're always trying to push in
cannabis which is like higher taxes more
reporting uh you know more you know
increased uh
I could go on and on for sure you know
dude the regulations that basically kill
businesses kill small businesses you
know and it's like they're designed to
and and you know and so the thing the
thing is and what I've learned because
I'm right down the street from the
Capitol and I've worked out here with
another guy Jed green and he runs uh
Oklahoma responsible cannabis action and
I've been up to the Capitol several
times and the only people that are up
there are people that are representing
business interests right and so there's
no balance there's not anybody
representing independent Independent
Business you know there's not a bunch of
independent people that are in business
up there because they're all
independently running their own
businesses
no and it's like they can't go in they
can't go run a business and be at the
Capitol to try to Lobby so that they can
stay in business and it's like this
vicious [ __ ] crazy cycle that like it
doesn't make sense that the average
American person would have to
essentially hire lobbyists just so small
independent operators can function in
this country but that's exactly what's
[ __ ] happening because the only
[ __ ] people that are up there talking
to these legislators
our business interests lobbyists
sure yeah I mean there's minimal
representation for the small guy that's
what we try to do is we want to be able
to collectively represent and find
people that'll that'll represent uh us
as a group and not just because look
when you are a good operator and you're
transparent with what you do and you
grow good product and you have your skus
lined up and you work with people people
will will come to you you can build a
brand if you have can if you're
consistent and people know what you're
bringing to the table you can build a
brand
sure and I see it all the time but it's
hard dude with all the regulations yeah
I mean I believe the one percent rule so
if you're you know you're in that one
percent you're usually going to be doing
good you want to strive for that you
know that a plus but you want to strive
for that but you know anymore you want
to strive for that point one percent to
be really successful yeah so let's dive
into a conversation about cultivars and
we were talking a little earlier before
the podcast started about uh you have
ways of dialing in specific cultivars
cultivar specific nutrition so as you
and I'm sure all your listeners have
experience there are a lot of different
nuances with the nutritional needs
between cultivars now a good example of
this is
you know maybe you might have some
Afghan dominant variety that doesn't
need as much nitrogen it requires drier
climates doesn't require as much
humidity and you know so you end up kind
of seeing that it has some weird things
with calcium that's going on that's a
good example of seeing things that I've
seen versus maybe something that's a
more equatorial varietal it grows
lengthier longer Intermodal spacing uh
narrow Leaf dominant characteristics
that kind of is spindly and requires
uh you know maybe a shitload more
calcium to nitrogen ratio to keep them a
little more Stout because of the way
that they've you know kind of tend to
tend to grow
so there's different nuances whatever
those nuances may be cultivar dependent
they're usually
environmental but also nutritional uh
dependent these kind of variances
and so you know we mentioned the the
different types of tests we have what's
called a standard soil test and that
gives us just an overall view of what's
in the soil as a total percentage so
we're looking at on that we're looking
at our our four major soil cations which
is going to be calcium magnesium
potassium and sodium we want to see
calcium around 60 percent magnesium
12 to 15 and then for cannabis uh
potassium we want to see uh five to
eight percent and then sodium as low as
possible it's antagonistic to all of
those and the right reason why we want
to have them in those ratios is because
if you have 60 of the soil solution
calcium uh 15 or 12 to 15 mag and five
to eight of potassium when you look at
the PPM on how they fall into solution
the parts per million of that solution
will be balanced and you're going to see
kind of what we're we're looking for and
so that's what we're looking on that
we're also looking at the amount of
total micronutrients that's in that
system overall
and we're looking at nitrogen levels and
then when we're looking at the saturated
Pace we can see how that soil falls into
solution now if let's say everything
meets you know where it's supposed to be
and we're meeting those targets we can
also take a look at
um the the leaf tissue and the leaf
tissue also has a Target so nitrogen has
a percentage of the leaf that it should
be
potassium magnesium all the
micronutrients secondary nutrients all
that
and so we can gauge that and if we have
a target for a cultivar and let's say it
is uh between four and a half and five
and a half percent in the leaf tissue
calcium and we're meeting our Target
which is let's say it's uh
uh 200 PPM of calcium that's the the
target of the parts per million that we
want to see on a saturated paste test
because that's basically our nutrient
solution that the plant is going to see
in this soil
if we're seeing it that and it's at 200
PPM but we're only seeing maybe two
percent of calcium in the leaf
we there's a couple of things that we
can
that we can uh
analyze with that so one is calcium is
dependent on VPD so it's dependent on
the movement and transport of water
through the plant the reason is is
because
the plant cannot translocate calcium
from its lower parts to newer growth
to supplement for what it needs for New
Growth it needs to be available in
Solution that's why I have such a high
percentage of it percentage of calcium
needs to be in solution it's so that we
can have an abundance of calcium in that
in that leaf so that way we can have all
the signaling molecules it's the
backbone of a lot of the the lignin and
cellulose and all uh the other cellular
components when we're looking at that
and there's two ways that we can
approach it if we're not getting the the
adequate amount of calcium in the tissue
but it's meeting that range where it's
supposed to be at 200 PPM then we have
to look at the environment because maybe
our soil is too dry or VPD is off and so
we're not getting adequate transpiration
and that's what's responsible for
calcium because calcium moves in water
right it's it's dependent on water
movement so if we don't have
transpiration taking place and water
movement going through the plant the
calcium then calcium isn't going to get
to where it needs to be
we can look at we my immediate would be
oh we need to be looking at BPD because
calcium is highly dependent on VPD so if
we're looking and all our VPD is in
range rates right where it should be
then we know for that particular
nutrient we need to increase it so we
need to increase the the nutrient
concentration and the percentage of
calcium on the standard soil so we'll
see an increase in the PPM maybe we go
up to 225 PPM or 250 PPM these are
really high levels by the way I don't
recommend this
um 150 to 200 is usually Max for uh
calcium
but let's say it is a variety that needs
more of it we could push it by doing
that and then we could take another uh
tissue sample and if we see okay we're
now at that four and a half percent
range by increasing the available of
availability of calcium then we know
that we've reached our Target goal okay
so for this specific cultivar instead of
having 200 PPM
of calcium we need 250 PPM of calcium
and so to get to that I already know how
much of what element like it might be
calcium silica it might be gypsum it
might be oyster shell it might be bone
meal it just depends on the nutrition of
the soil what I'll add to bring it up to
that Target level for that specific
variety
and then there's another part of it too
so I can do that for all the different
elements
if nitrogen is low as a percentage and
I'm looking at it to be three percent
it's only one percent then I need then I
know that I need to increase the
nitrogen levels for that for that plant
so it works really easy it's just
numbers and it's like I already have it
all plugged in like it's it
for me it makes a lot of sense I don't
know if I'm explaining it well enough
but
um I can just adjust those levels and
then what we're doing is we're taking an
additional test to to see what happens
when we've adjusted those levels and
then there's another thing what we can
do is called sap analysis and sap
analysis is two different tests where
you're testing fully developed
photosynthetic top leaves and fully
developed uh photosynthetic with sheer
bottom leaves and it gives a difference
in nutrition and it allows you to see
how mobile nutrients like magnesium
potassium nitrogen phosphorus how they
move
or if they're being translocated before
they'll ever show as a deficiency
symptom so if you see that like nitrogen
is lower on the bottom than it is on the
top then you know that it's pulling from
the lower to it's not getting enough in
solution to sat to satisfy both the
bottom portion and the top portion so
the plant is actually pulling nutrition
it's catabolizing itself it's uh any
stored amino acids or anything like that
will break those down release nitrogen
and phosphorus and it'll send that up
into the plant to where the new growth
needs it right and so you can see that
with a sap analysis because it'll show
which nutrients are being catabolized at
the bottom of the plant and being taken
to the top and so if you're seeing that
nitrogen is lower at the bottom you can
also increase your Target on your uh on
your saturated Pace test to make sure
that you have an adequate amount of that
Target nutrient so that way they're
basically level you want to see on on
the both the bottom and the top on a
graph you want to see and be level that
means that it's not pulling from the
bottom if the bottom graph is lower it
means it's pulling from the bottom part
of the plant and here's the thing you
can look at one of those tests before
it'll ever show a deficiency symptom and
preemptively act and so that's one of
the benefits because if you're
addressing a nitrogen deficiency or
potassium or phosphorus deficiency
you're usually addressing it after it's
about 50 already into that deficiency
symptom yeah before it's even observable
you can test get this get a sap test and
you'll be able to to see it yeah have
you done any sap testing no but I'm
super interested in it sounds awesome
okay so new age Labs it's kind of a
complicated process I did it for the I
did it for two cultivars and like this
is how I built out the the program
because I I knew I could do it and I
wanted to test it out
and so
um the process is really complicated but
you're basically taking three or four
standard soil saturated paste Leaf
tissue and sap tests during the span of
one cultivation cycle so from the
beginning of edge to the end of flower
and so you're click you're basically
taking a data set for a cultivar and
you're mapping it out with all of this
with all of the the the
um the data that you're collecting from
each individual one of those tests but
New Age Labs what you'll do is you take
like you'd go and take let's say you
have your Greenhouse right and you want
to test this row that has all you know
your Sour Diesel in it right sap you'll
take bottom from all the plant and
you'll categorize that as the bottom
you'll take all the leaves from the top
and you'll take like I don't know 80
grams of each and then you bag them up
I usually put like paper towels so so
that way you can seal the bag and not
have a mold but you ship them next day
in a little ice chest container and then
they'll then they'll test them like
within a day and then they'll give you
an analysis so it's uh
it's not real time but it's it's it's
pretty efficient one day is pretty good
yeah
yeah it's really cool it's really cool
the way they do it
that's awesome and and then Logan Labs
is the lab that I use for all my testing
that's uh there's you know some really
good books too like there's a book
called uh the art of balancing soil
nutrition he's by uh Bill McKibbon he's
a corn and soil agronomist and he uses
Logan labs and they have such great
comprehensive data sets and being able
to start for anybody who's interested in
this stuff those that's a really great
place to start because you can look at
different types of soil you can look at
different types of media and like when
you would want to have frequent low dose
fertigation events for different types
of soil like in outdoor soils or like
nutrient or soils that hold a lot of
nutrition that you don't need to
fertilize a lot you know so you can
figure out all the different types of
nuances in soil as well and you know how
those things will react with each other
the other elements and like how biology
we're working those systems as well to
help keep things in a form that's going
to be available for the plant really
cool well let's talk about genetics a
little bit what you like what's uh
what's on the horizon I I guess Oklahoma
is probably different than California
right now it's like the the purple craze
drives me nuts a little bit but uh
yeah that's that's the scene in
California and I feel like there'll
always be a place which ones are which
ones are real popular right now where
you're at well you know it's like I mean
we're still on like the RS 11 you know
we got the the there's a lot of stuff
but I think in yeah those type of things
you get the zop star s11s the do farm
stuff is definitely popular right now
and I mean
there's lit Farms is doing crosses with
them as well with the permanent marker
from jbz so like a lot of those
permanent marker crosses are now
starting to hit the streets but same
thing with the rs11 crosses and the zope
crosses those are definitely hitting the
streets from other people
um but I still feel like we're gonna go
back towards gas uh you know purple
candy gas is what they want now but I
feel like the green gas will make its
comeback the ogs the classic OG's logs
have their place on the market South
there's a demand for sour diesel but
it's just not available nobody's and the
thing is is it's a long flowering
cultivar so it's a real Sour Diesel is
it's it's a difficult one because of
plant maintenance and flowering time and
along with that additional flowering
time again it's it comes with additional
nutritional requirements too so it's
it's just one of those
you know the sour diesel that was real
prevalent around San Diego was you know
about 84 days yeah if you wanted to uh
if you wanted to do it right and
I but you know I feel like that profile
like it's one like that's sour because I
was smoking
um I was smoking some Sour dub
out in L.A when I was out there laugh
and it was like oh this is this I was
immediately as Nostalgia because it was
the like the what we called the Sour OG
down in San Diego right
yeah for sure the same it was the same
it was the same cultivar like it I knew
it immediately because it was so
nostalgic and I had grown it for such a
long time it was one of my favorites for
a really long time and so sours like
that you know those I love those I love
the PK man that was a big one but I'm
I'm not uh I'm not super picky when it
comes to like my cannabis like I love
all different flavors I don't have
anything that I don't specific
specifically like there's some things
that I'd like to see that I haven't seen
in a long time like
um I haven't smoked anything mentholated
like I remember growing this variety
called jaw rule
I think or jaw love or something like
that it smelled like sage like if you
walk into a room where it had been burnt
somebody was smoking it it smelled like
white sage like distinctly smelled like
white sage and I remember that was one
of the characteristics of that specific
variety
and when you smoked it it was it was
like a heavy mentholated Pine you know
was it wasn't like Smoky flavored it
wasn't uh didn't have like the sherb or
oh you know it was it was really
distinct it was a really distinct flavor
and I haven't seen anything like that
really long time yeah not incensey but
but a lot of stuff like we get Menthol
stuff occasionally but we cull most of
the Menthol like any of the I don't know
we go through so many different things
and uh we find some interesting stuff
and like Menthol it
it depends on what level of Menthol like
I can see it as negative but I know what
you're talking about as as something
that's actually tastes amazing and kind
of adds to it especially if you get some
Pine in there everything that I've been
smoking right right now is this [ __ ]
[ __ ] this is what everybody's wanting
this is what I mean
don't get me wrong it's great [ __ ]
weed somebody just dropped by that grows
organic soil too and they gave me but
it's like that purple you know like or
jealousy it all has that
it all has that chopped cookies uh
cookies chirps where it's like various
orange a little bit you get a little
like a Tangy in there but not heavy yeah
it's it's that uh that like
that artificial kind of grapey that has
a little bit of like citrus in it I
don't hate it I like smoking it but it
seems like a lot of stuff have that in
it around here at least where we're at
and so
um
I'd rather just see I like you know I
like garlics I like oh geez I like gas I
love Jack I love Jack I uh I got an
ounce uh from my boy the other day not
the other day I actually smoked through
it it was probably a month ago but
My Boy Aaron he grows some just amazing
old-school Jack dude and it's still the
really old school Jack was way better
yeah I mean the stuff we see is J as
Jack in California is typically
very well Jay I like J1 J1 and then Jay
went out of bubblegum I made the J1
bubble gum cross a long time ago but uh
J1 I I think is great uh this the Jack
Flash is great the classic Jack that was
more of like musky and very complex
compared to like the very lemony
torpinoline limonene Jack that's very
very linear I don't like that but I like
the old Jacks yeah because the old Jack
it's got this peppery incense along with
this kind of really earthy earthy musk
even though it does have that that lemon
and Pine in there
it's it's mixed really well with that
type of peppery incense and that that
that overall musk and so I don't know
what it is but the stuff gets me high
and this stuff the stuff doesn't doesn't
just just doesn't do it and it's purple
it's all purple weed you know it's all
purple I like purple weed nothing
against purple weed
um it's just I think that's what sells
man I think that's what people have
always loved purple weed and it is what
it is I think that you just kind of have
to
um grow what your market demand is you
know yeah and that that's going to
change over time I mean it's stuff is
like popular for two months and then
it's on to something new and it seems
like it's it's popular but that
eventually is gonna stabilize because I
mean even with all these purple
cultivars in these different profiles
they're not all that different So
eventually the market is going to
stabilize a lot more people are going to
go with stuff they like I mean yeah we
like trying new stuff but like
I I don't see it as being this way in
five years I think it's gonna you know
people are gonna have their one flavor
that they're known for their five
flavors that they're known for and
that's that's what I've preach because I
tell I tell people all the time like I
don't advocate for like hat like I don't
want deli style taken away I don't want
legislation taken away I want people to
be able to still have that type of
experience but I tell people that the
consumer is visually driven and so if
you have a SKU and a package and things
you know a label and everything else and
it's consistent in the product inside
it's going to build brand recognition
and and the way that you know I've
always told people when I'm talking
about you know building out a brand is
you know
the the large percent of the consumer
Market isn't a really highly educated on
the products that they're consuming so
if you can make a product that's highly
relatable to them like having something
like blueberry somebody understands
blueberry or they understand root beer
or they understand watermelon blast you
know it doesn't like if you can if you
can kind of get something that matches
the description of what you're giving
them and make it kind of General I think
that's why so many of the the candy
brands and stuff like that have worked
so well is because they're relatable to
the General Public
and you don't necessarily need to have
uh a lot of hype I think it just needs
to be relatable to to people who who are
interested because I've been smoking for
a long ass time and I forget there's
there's new consumers daily another
thing too is I see a lot of success
working with like the craft Farmers
Alliance when we're all working together
we're not all growing the same thing not
everybody's growing permanent marker
right now not everybody's growing
rainbow sure not everybody's growing you
know Mach One every you know like Red
Dirt will be growing his meat and jam
and his papaya and then banana seat
bananicals is going to be doing her
Lemon Cherry gelato and her warm cookie
cut crosses and then 4-H Farms is going
to be running you know something
different you know completely different
and so it's kind of like keeping a
community networked together that can
help facilitate skus so like okay these
are their skus for these for these
people so we're not all grown the same
thing absolutely well man it was really
great having you on today if if somebody
is out there and they want to get in
touch with you they want to find out
more about uh
your company about what you do they want
to get some testing done how do they get
a hold of you okay earthworks.com
which is uh
b-o-k-a-s-h-i Earthworks all one word
you can also find me on Instagram at
rust dot Brandon and bokashi Earthworks
and uh
reach out I'm I have made myself pretty
accessible to people so they can ask
questions and I like to help people be
successful especially if they're using
my products I want to advocate for the
people that are doing that and make sure
that they can
continue to have success so
Reach Out DM me uh I'm always willing to
chat and give advice so uh thanks I
appreciate having me on the show dude
yeah man you next time you're in
California come to the come to the
facility come check us out I'd love to
give you a tour get you on another
podcast we can dive into some really
cool stuff yeah I'd love to share some
of my uh stuff I'm working on with you
privately I get a book coming out so
we'll talk about that soon nice yeah
that'd be great man if you need any help
with any of the nutrient type stuff and
if you hey and also if you want to check
out any of the products man uh just hit
me up I can send you all kinds of stuff
I've got a lot of cool stuff man that
you that you probably probably dig
really awesome well thank you again man
we appreciate it and I look forward to
seeing you soon cool dude I'll talk to
you soon
[Music]
foreign