you could just throw it in the dirt and
piss on it and get five pounds off it
you know what I mean
[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James loud
podcast today is my good friend Al from
NorCal genetics the original NorCal
genetics we go way back 2012. how are
you doing today doing good brother how
you been I'm fantastic so you
disappeared off the face of the Earth
in 2018 so let's just talk about that
real quick because we we hadn't talked
until after I did the podcast with
Caesar who has now NorCal genetics which
is the same name but but you were
definitely the original the the crew
yeah the first NorCal genetics to my
knowledge yeah no definitely so yeah
um yeah end of 2018 in November uh we
had the campfire come to Northern
California yeah and uh decimate
everybody 100 people killed uh tens of
thousands of buildings I lost all my
buildings I lost everything boats cars
everything I had from gain from
traveling around the world just
everything closed everything and I kind
of had to restart
I ended up uh becoming a single father
like two months later so it was like
lose all your stuff then lose half your
kid and your wife whatever deal with all
that kind of stuff and so
it's been rebuilding and trying to take
my land back you know what I mean after
the fire like
just uh you know trying to to slowly
climb the mountain back to where I was
and I had to just take some time off of
the wildlife was just too crazy I had to
take a had to kill all my social media
phones just everything and you
completely unplugged I did I completely
unplugged it was for years yeah yeah
it's pretty impressive next four years I
did that yeah
it hurt you know I got a lot of people I
love bro you included you know what I
mean like uh but I needed to focus and
my kid was
not even barely two yet it's 18 you know
what I mean so it was kind of like I
needed to that was well that was the
first time so then
19 yeah he would have been four at the
time so then uh yeah you know being a
single father I homeschooled my child as
well so I'm in the at that point I'm in
the process of like teaching them how to
read that takes a lot of time you know
just everything and my animals you know
I saved uh all of my dogs and all but
two of my cats
there's a lot man I had a big farm you
know I had uh Duck's chickens geese pigs
all that had to stay I mean I opened the
doors you know they run off into the
forest or whatever but uh yeah no none
of them survived and uh
having I'm kind of hard-headed with my
love you know like I have all these
animals and uh I love them like my
children I don't want to get rid of them
so
you know the fire happens and I have
this big farm with this working
infrastructure and I can manage having
all these animals with this working
infrastructure I got automatic feeders I
got automatic waterers I got a kindling
system for the dogs so I've got all
these systems in place to be able to
just be me and on the farm and also take
care of all these animals in a righteous
way and then after the fire burn down
all my infrastructure now life's much
harder I don't have a working will I
have to go down to town to get water I
have to pour water but you know what I
mean there's so much I gotta run
generators I gotta pour gas in the
generator three times a day I gotta
every gallon of water that comes out of
my sink or my bathroom how to move a big
travel trailer up and everything you
know everything I have to put in there
you know I have to you know the dogs uh
and and all the cats as well like it
just became too much you know with with
everything that I was doing I couldn't
uh I couldn't righteously look at myself
and and say okay well you have time to
maintain all of these fret ships and
networks and you have time to get taken
up by like nonsense on YouTube or you
know what I mean stuff like that and
like I needed I I can't do it part-time
I gotta cut it cold turkey right like
just super focus and so that's what I
did and uh
it was good it helped me progress
farther and faster uh it was lonely it
was sad uh definitely but uh I was able
to kind of crawl out of that and uh
about
six weeks ago now and it's two months
ago maybe I turned it back on I haven't
made any announcements or anything yet
but I've just turned it back on and then
reached out to all the individuals I
wanted to reconnect with and slowly and
kind of let them know what was going on
and you know what I mean sorry I haven't
been able to connect and whatnot but
like hopefully that's not the case
anymore right it's all good man and and
so when I talked to you for the first
time in four four years four and a half
years you're in Thailand yeah so you've
done you know you've been planning all
these things and been very strategic
about what you've done yes yeah um
for the last four years also while doing
that I've been trying to find the right
situation you know what I mean and as we
all know those of us that have been in
this in a long time in the pre
pre-medical medical like all of that you
know and I mean the the knowledges that
we have from doing something for 20
years the skill sets that we have
they're a wanted skill set right you
know but necessarily whether you're not
you have the right funding or investment
strategies or whatever to get the right
Licensing in whatever state a lot of
it's luck of the draw a lot of it's just
big money you know so maybe you have
enough money but not enough money you
know I mean you think you should be able
to open up a business but because the
regulations cost blah blah blah or in my
case here in California like my County's
locked out they hate it they don't want
to ever let anything in ever ever and
they'll continue to try to be like that
so then I have to look outside my county
and then when you have places where
they'll have like moratoriums or you
have to buy the property
first and then make an application right
that's non-refundable and can say no and
then I'm in on this property for how
much money now land is expensive here in
California you know what I mean so
before you even get to even start
talking about real licensing and setting
up the infrastructure of a business
you're already in half a million well
you've been a self-sufficient guy your
whole we've been friends for over 10
years yes right longer than that but
more than that yeah and you've been a
self-sufficient guy from the beginning
you know you've been into genetics for a
long time we partied all over the world
together yeah you know so so it's great
so yeah there's a huge barrier for entry
in California it doesn't matter how much
you care about quality and
you know there's definitely a financial
barrier for entry yeah and then so
Thailand tell us about Thailand well
before I even get to Thailand I want to
tell you so I really looked I really
looked and but the problems are is that
like guys like me and then the guys that
end up opening these places there's all
their need they need the weed guy you
know what I mean the soil to oil guy you
know I mean they need that but they're
dirty they didn't get that much money
being straight up good businessmen most
of them you know what I mean a lot of
them are Cut Throat businessmen they
know how to do things and I've watched
friend after friend after friend in our
position similar position make deals
with people get [ __ ] out of things
have bring an entire Crews and genetics
lace Out full farms and greenhouses to
have the doors locked with armed guards
two weeks before Harvest I've seen that
in multiple you know we were talking
about Django earlier he's got a great
story about that bless rest in peace uh
yeah we've lost some good ones yeah we
have but uh you know there's all these
[ __ ] deals so then I've been kind of
know I've been made some I've had some
offers made and I've kind of been
weaving my way through it trying to find
the right situation ended up going to
Washington not last year but the year
before and uh Northwest cannabis rent
went up there and helped run that place
for like four months our warehouse
manufacturing facility yeah tried to
work out a ownership deal right there
for a percentage uh didn't see eye to
eye after the four months but I was
commuting up there it's ridiculous every
week I was going up and back it's like
13 hours one way you know what I mean so
26 hours of my week was just driving
there and back but uh it was all right
um and then I took off I took off a year
and uh
starting to get a little bitter you know
what I mean starting to get a little sad
starting to like
how can I have all this knowledge all
these skill sets all this network all
these friends that are like at the top
level at the top of the game and
I can't seem to make that work you know
it it starts to get disheartening after
a little while I I you know I really
wanted to try to to figure out the right
thing well uh
my buddy Vinnie gave me a call uh he
used to be one of our partners for
NorCal genetics back when we were doing
our thing over in Amsterdam and uh um
he's like dude you know what's been
going on in Thailand right and I said
yeah he says you need to get out there
he says you need to absolutely get out
there right now I want you to go out
there and this is back in like December
it's like I was like all right I'm gonna
try to get out there in January
January didn't end up working out
he calls me back he's like did you go
out to Thailand I said no he's like what
the [ __ ] are you doing you need to go
out to Thailand man get the [ __ ] he's
like hang the phone up with me get on
the [ __ ] online go order yourself a
ticket and get over to [ __ ] Thailand
and I was like all right bro all right
and if I can hung up the phone with him
took a dab
and I was like [ __ ] you know what he's
right let me look at my [ __ ] Calendar
let me move some things around it's hard
for me to get out if I'm gonna go out
I'm gonna go out for a month the first
time straight I'm not going out to talk
to anybody that I know or I didn't even
think about reaching out to anybody I
know I did like the thought didn't even
cross my mind I went out there
completely with a blank slate my goal
was I'm gonna do the entire country I'm
gonna go to every corner of the country
all the major cities I'm gonna see what
the legalities are like in those places
what what is it what is actually on the
ground happening you know I've done that
to every country that's legalized so far
except Uruguay I've been to every single
country that's legalized or done
medicinal and because I do what I call
like a boots on the ground like Portugal
was first I went out to Portugal like
okay you decriminalize what is that what
does that mean right you know what I
mean like what's the real face of that
so that was the the mission to go out to
Thailand is to to
to basically do three things to see what
the legalities are actually like to see
if as a foreigner I could come in and
legitimately work within the framework
of how they're setting up the laws and
everything whether it's lawyers
licensing all that kind of stuff and
then to find the best place to set up
the first shop and to find the best
place to put a farm in and then with all
of that knowledge
to come up with some kind of package
some kind of [ __ ] thing and come back
and find some of my boys and get
together and say let's go do this right
and uh so I did and I went out there and
I did all of that I went to 700 shops in
the first month that I was out there I
did another 200 shops this happened to
900 shops I haven't even scratched the
surface but it was a good to see like
okay what's the quality what do you
actually have on the Shelf you know what
I mean what is the quality
[ __ ] yeah I mean like you have to look
for for like really good top shelf you
really have to look I mean top top shelf
probably pretty much non-existent yeah
so they have how about compared to
Amsterdam not comparable just different
too it's completely different so first
of all
I know you smoked some Thai strains
before sure they have a different
flavors I call it a spice to it they
have a a all of the genetics any
genetics if it's coming from Thailand is
it has like this uh this this almost
Savory spicy kind of uh
incensey kind of incense yeah yeah I
know exactly what you mean with the
incency with the Thai strains so you
know they're all right they're good you
know what I mean but are they what
necessarily everybody wants to buy or
the tourist or what's going to sell or
whatever okay not are they compared to
California to Amsterdam no not so much
so when you go out there I could
automatically see I can tell by smelling
the weed from the nutrients okay
let's say 50 of the total stock in every
store out there is imported wow yeah
yeah and let's say of that 50 that's
imported
40 10 35 15 California Amsterdam oh wow
yeah yeah and the Amsterdam [ __ ] smell
are stands out ridiculously right
because it has their own look you know
they have their own yeah yeah they
elongate a little bit and they they all
use Mills out there you know what I mean
yeah it has the same smells and [ __ ]
yeah yeah how about the effect
um it's nice if you like something
mellow if you're not a proper Stoner if
you're like an old hippie that wants to
have a cup of tea and smoke a joint and
do some [ __ ] you know what I mean it's
nice like that right right right but uh
the problem is just like in Jamaica or
any of the other places with high
humidity it's high humidity right and uh
they allow it to ruin all of their flour
wow like
out of all those shops I went to uh
maybe three or four of all of those
shops right like actually kept their
weed appropriately or kept like or had
high grade cash and kept that
appropriately yeah I saw one
refrigerator with hash in it wow okay
yeah with good passion and like wow yeah
yeah and then like so all of their
flowers so they'll grow and I've met
some amazing growers in Thailand
um I'm I'm gonna I have a good friend
out there and he is
I would call him my equal in Thailand
what I can do here with outdoor and with
Greenhouse in California he's the
equivalent of in Thailand yeah and
amazing [ __ ] grower and uh but the
the problem is is after the Cure and
curing they don't do any kind of
mitigation or any kind of like hardcore
because you need to do hardcore
procedures with in maintaining that
proper cure right it sucks up weed or
sucks up water out of the air and then
they're putting it in jars and whatever
and it's [ __ ] getting anaerobic
bacteria in there and it's cat pissing
out and just oh wow it smells it smells
like straight ammonia it's dark it's not
the ammonia yeah and that loses his
color 85 90 of any weed that you saw get
sold anywhere whether it's on a street
on the table you know what this I I
don't know if you've been gone on the
scene for a little bit but this is the
Grove terplock bag right here okay
this is what you want to cure your stuff
in I I'm a firm believer at first I was
like but then we did side by side
compared to jars even and this stuff as
far as curing and they make these in
different they have tote sizes gram size
I'm a bucket guy you want to carry them
they have bucket sizes yeah I usually
buckets so literally I have a whole
recipe this this controls the humidity
right so you just have to control your
temperature down to like 60 degrees
it's essentially technology oh there's
technology in the bag for sure because
it's not just a mylar bag but uh it's
not just a [ __ ] Ziploc bag it's not
just a small proof bag it is not just a
smell pretty although it is molecular
technology there is some technology that
goes into it yeah it's pretty impressive
I pretty much switched over from jars
because we've been using jars forever
because that's what there was before we
there was you know do you know when it
got ridiculous it was just back in the
day when when prices were you know 3 800
a pound for outdoor okay jars were fine
and and Walmarts around Northern
California would always be out of
[ __ ] jars out out you had absolutely
you had to buy them in like February
March you know what I mean stock up
because if you try to buy them at the
end of the summer it was never in the
fall it wasn't going to happen and uh it
got ridiculous is when one time I went
to a boy's house
and I think it's Cur maybe it's ball
yeah they make a like a [ __ ] three or
five gallon jar right with like a
latching top totally my boy was putting
packs in there and [ __ ] I was just like
okay bro this is getting expensive and
ridiculous but for sure 3 800 a pound
you can afford to spend absolutely
dollars on a jar or whatever the [ __ ] it
was you know like now it's like we got
two dollars to spend on it you got a
Home Depot bucket or sure back in the
day I was Hardcore I used to use uh food
grade black buckets don't let no light
in I remember the blue ones I don't
remember the black ones as much as the
blue ones where you you know you hit the
lid on the paint I think there are paint
ones and they're the plastic paint ones
and everybody up in Humboldt that I used
to work you had to use the special
plastic wrench to get off and it had
that Rubber seal on the inside and [ __ ]
like that yeah yeah those were smell
proof and you could stack them in
storage units or whatever absolutely
they were all over the place those
things yeah those are great and I
developed a pretty decent curing system
with with buckets I do hang I do
depending on what it is and you know
what I'm doing or whatever there's
certain parts of the process that I'll
add or subtract and then I'll do a hang
for a while and then I'll do a breakdown
and then I'll do a bucket cure yeah and
then I do the bucket cure with tossing
all that so that way my trimmers are
working on all cured you know either I'm
going to wet trim and if I can figure
out all that [ __ ] and I'm gonna hang in
bags and Nets and [ __ ] yeah or if I do
my bucket trimming the thing that I
liked about the bucket trimming is if
you're not a poor man then at back in
the day you didn't have to sit around
and wait uh for everybody to bicker and
let the prices go down and all the
craziness to happen in October you know
what I mean you could you could cure
your whole crop and then slowly just let
you know the trimmers come through you
can you can control your trim group if
you want to have 30 [ __ ] hippies
there on a bus going [ __ ] mad and
having drama you could do that yeah and
if you want to have like six solid
people or ten solid people if whatever
you could do that and you would strip
the fan leaves off and let the Sugar
Leaf protect the flower yeah yeah yeah
so it depends so like for for
competition [ __ ] I would hang hole
anything competition or like super high
grade that I was trying to like keep I
let hang hole to protect
when it became a thing of like I need to
manage time and I need to manage space
right then it becomes okay I'm gonna put
together instead of having a two-man
Harvest team that's just basically
hanging cutting and hanging cutting and
hanging yeah you bring together a
four-person team you have a cutter a
walker you have somebody like you get
like a I love trim Pro and they have
these nice little table fans that can
clip onto anything little I think
they're half horsepower or one
horsepower [ __ ] motor oh they're
beautiful and then you can just cut down
like
you know branches and then just kind of
run them over kind of lightly and just
to take the families off in seconds yeah
and then you know back in the day when
prices were higher and people can afford
to spend money on stupid [ __ ] right then
you could have hippies out in the garden
lollipopping and Defan leaf and
everything totally seven six seven eight
ten days 12 days before Harvest yeah and
we used to like to do it because it
would stress the plant out and [ __ ]
get more get a little bit more love on
there it's more cannabinoids yeah for
sure so you want a bunch of Cups you
want cannabis cups
cannabis Cubs yeah it's uh this this uh
this hoodie this is the NorCal genetics
hoodie this is from our 2000
2012 or 14 Spanish cup and that's like
the first something I think it was 13
actually because it's 7 10 7 10
technician like oil is just like so I
have a picture I have a picture us
together there's a couple other people
but yeah I have some good photos of us
back in the day when you won and you
know those were good years man those
were really good years I missed that
time bro yeah we had a lot of fun we
partied in Spain in Amsterdam a lot I
missed that time bro I tell you what uh
it'll never happen again
it'll never ever happen again it was
because of all of the circumstances
around the world you had illegality
right all around the world and for a man
mostly 99.9 a man to take
certain responsibilities and actions in
this illegal realm that existed uh it
took a certain type personality type
mindset would have some balls regardless
of culture regardless of culture right
regardless of how you're raised
regardless of religion regardless of
race uh regardless of age yeah it took
it took there's there was commonalities
in these mindsets and here this shining
thing was once a year for an entire week
10 days there was a [ __ ] Cannabis Cup
this this celebrated cup that everybody
around the world thinks you're gonna get
there it's going to be like the Super
Bowl but when the reality is you get
there it's some [ __ ] background
Warehouse [ __ ] you know what I mean
creeping through alleys and doing like
cannabis coffee shop crawls but uh
people would go because that was the
only game in town in the world yeah and
people would show up and it was the most
beautiful thing to see a room of bosses
of [ __ ] bosses that run [ __ ] in their
respective areas in their towns and
their you know countries and [ __ ] like
that all Alphas yeah and no [ __ ] no
no [ __ ] ego check hit you know what I
mean obviously there's a little drama
and we get to see it now a little bit
more because again
like if you talk [ __ ] about someone you
get your ass kicked yeah we have friends
they got yeah yeah they definitely
kicked other people's asses at cups
before people don't talk about on that
yeah so I'm definitely got it coming
dude some funny [ __ ] though but like way
different with social media and people
talking trash dude like it's just way
different and so yeah and the whole like
uh click baits and all that [ __ ]
today and all that goes on yeah so but
uh it was beautiful to see that man and
then you know friendships were forged
and relationships were had and
visits were made to other countries hey
bro why don't you come see how I do
things why don't you come see how I do
things and and uh you know as and
speaking from the Breeders from breeders
uh we knew everybody bro like we all
knew each other yeah we all know each
other at the [ __ ] top level that if
you were [ __ ] around you know what I
mean if you had uh uh your genetics in
multiple countries or whatever everybody
we know we all know who each other are
even if even most of them even if like
you were old school legends like uh
um
uh oh blueberry boy
yeah who went into you know like his
[ __ ] was awesome we all knew it here for
a long time and then he was often kind
of kind of the cuts for a while and then
all of a sudden when all this [ __ ]
opened up all of a sudden oh pow he get
to come out and do his thing or whatever
Ashanti you know what I mean same same
totally so good breeders are able to
come out and like you know I remember
the first time I met DJ Short he told me
you need to put the seed under your
tongue and let it acclimate to your
genetics your DNA okay so that it'll
respond better to you I love it you know
and there's some crazy stuff he said but
he was the first person that said that I
didn't need to do tissue clay it was
interesting because tissue culture I was
super stoked on tissue culture Bill
Graham and all that stuff back in the
day and he's like dude you don't need
tissue culture you need to put your
plant in the ground let it veg out and
then take clippings off that veg plant
and the thing is is like
there is truth to what he's saying about
like regenerating the health of a plant
you know and that's very
old school but yeah we we had a whole
bunch of friends and then the science
you know there was Bro Science back in
the day too and
all kinds of stuff
yeah
there's Bro Science and there was
politics
yeah yeah so this is number 18.
with uh there's three of the different
Fino hunts
uh three of the different cultivars that
we've selected
in there and it's pretty candy that is
delicious smooth
yeah so we're going through some stuff
right now I'm working with SF Canna on a
72 seed Fino hunt and really kind of
diving into each each one this is the
second some of them it's the third time
we've they've that they've grown it out
and you you see the difference in the
sexual maturity of the plant and how
it's stabilizing and you're getting the
expressions
uh you really need to grow stuff out at
least three times yeah for sure
absolutely and they definitely change
even if you're an in guy just to your
situation and how you do things you know
what I mean because you're you're your
own God you're creating your own
environment you know totally everybody's
a little bit different
so as far as genetics what's your
favorite what do you like working with
what do you like breeding with I mean
you've done a lot of breeding over the
years you've done a lot of growing yeah
uh I like kushes and citrus yeah yeah
and the the like uh like citrusy ogs or
like citrusy like tangies like citrus
cogs I love Tangy yeah I absolutely love
Tangy I wish it was stronger I wish you
got me hot I wish it was Stronger Yeah I
like the flavor
how do you knock on something that
tastes like fresh squeezed orange juice
like out with that seed pack or what bro
oh which one the purple see the Purple
OG Steve right that's OG Steve's purple
Tangy he got orange juice yeah he held
on to that [ __ ] right so I go
over the spot talk to him and [ __ ] all
the time you know our dogs uh we had our
dogs breeding [ __ ] he has one of my yeah
pups and [ __ ] like that we have like a
line of Shepherds that are [ __ ]
amazing [ __ ] you know royalty
cannabis royalty Shepherds and [ __ ] I
was thinking about doing some [ __ ] for a
while but anyway uh I go over there and
he don't give that up
who I think gave it to somebody but yeah
they did they got [ __ ] in Oklahoma
right so there was a deal I mean he's
he's had a string of bad luck he's he's
a real good person and the problem is is
people take advantage of good people
well you know and I've learned that over
the years too you know I feel like I've
I've been on the line of where I've been
too good of a person you have to cut
back you have to pull it back in a
little bit well you can always be yeah
you have to be extremely careful you
know what I mean you gotta you gotta you
gotta always make sure there's insurance
policies and your [ __ ] shit's covered
in a real way when you start committing
like that you know poor Steve he held on
to that cut for must have been three
years before he found the right
situation yeah and uh there was a a
farmer who had land and had commercial
greenhouses massive commercial
greenhouses several of them yeah and uh
he applied for the permit got the permit
and uh but didn't know [ __ ] about
growing weed and didn't have the right
genetics yes somehow him and Steve got
put together and uh Steve says look I
will bring in my genetics I will bring
in my workers to take care of the whole
thing blah blah blah blah right he did
the whole [ __ ] thing and he's one of
the guys that had that happened to were
two weeks out they show up in the
[ __ ] Gates locked to the farm and
they would get through these are the
worst stories and there's armed guards
and [ __ ] and like you're not getting in
like you're not [ __ ] like you know
it's happened to a bunch of our friends
too over the years and so basically cut
him out of 50 or whatever the deal was
or you know what I mean who knows
whatever the deal was but uh and that
was his big foreign I watched that
happen he was the third guy I saw happen
now another friend of ours rest in peace
Django yeah he uh he is one of the most
Savvy businessmen that was in this
[ __ ] game he was [ __ ] sharp and he
was a hustler and he's a hustler hustler
for sure he's a [ __ ] Hustler for sure
[ __ ] love that guy
um
he ran into a situation uh with like
reservation and you know what I mean
with the natives and uh where they had a
thing where they were going to be like
you know we only have to do by fed law
and we're going to do whatever the [ __ ]
we want so [ __ ] it yeah we don't know
what we're doing can you come and do
that same type of similar situation
right and they locked him out and
instead of [ __ ] like proper security
around garage they showed up a couple
weeks out and there's a bunch of gang
bangers yeah a bunch of gang bangers are
rifles [ __ ] standing in the field and
my uh he tell he tells me the story I
hope I'm not speaking out a turn but uh
he told me the story like uh as soon as
he saw that he knew what was like what
time it was yeah and he [ __ ] made
sure that [ __ ] he said a little
something to his his man and made sure
to take care of things while he went and
talked to the Chief and sure enough went
up there and they were like yeah no
you're out of here blah blah blah blah
yeah and uh okay yeah thanks for the six
months of work and the [ __ ] 10
employees and the totally and the
genetics and the you know what I mean
and the genetics I mean people have lost
their genetics and the knowledge bro
yeah our knowledge and our skill sets
you see it you see it in everything and
that's what science is right science is
developing techniques okay how do you
get microspheres or whatever a certain
size or whatever yeah you gotta do these
set and set techniques and then it
happens well the same thing is in the
weed world the hash world you know what
I mean if you know the techniques then
you can make things happen if you don't
know the techniques you ain't going to
get it to that point yeah so this this
knowledge is important and so I've been
uh trying to figure out a way to make
the knowledge work you know and not get
it stolen because that's what
everybody's happening they're getting
their genetics and their knowledge once
you've got my knowledge what the [ __ ]
use am I to you right you know what I
mean so I need to make sure yeah once
I've built your [ __ ] Kingdom for you
you better make sure you have good
contracts nowadays contracts do mean
something you know I mean
I still will only you know I try to work
with people I'd do a handshake deal with
yeah I think that's the best like if you
wouldn't do a handshake deal with them
why would you do a contract deal if you
don't trust them enough but uh let's
jump back into Thailand let's stop
talking to Thailand okay we'll talk
about Thailand Okay and then we want to
talk yeah we got a lot to talk about
this yeah my friend yes sir yes sir so
Thailand Okay so Thailand so uh did the
work did did all this
and then I'm going to tell I'm gonna
this will be the first public telling of
this story but I want it to be out there
things happen over the most
ridiculous innate object I've had
meetings in Amsterdam where I've shared
a Choco Mill with somebody and it ended
up being
you know the neck of the most lucrative
thing I'm doing for the next couple of
years or whatever right totally
in Thailand on my last week and a half
I'm sitting at a street food cart yeah
getting waiting for my fried shrimp to
be cooked up
these two guys come up one of them
orders some shrimp they're just standing
there I decided you know two white guys
look like they're English on go ahead
and say some [ __ ] to them yeah hey how
you doing what's going on it's a little
small talk
taking their time with the shrimp have a
little time to have a conversation
and they seem pretty cool seem like
smokers so I was like when one of them
says
so uh you know what are you doing what
are you doing out here and I said well
you know tell you the truth
I'm out here looking at the weed game
kind of see what's available and
probably come come out here open up shop
out here
and I'm just trying to find uh you know
where to open up my shop and you know
what the you know all the right
situation and they kind of stop and they
both look at each other and then they
just start laughing and I was like oh
it's in my red eyes like something
something's going on in a negative way I
was like this has been something and
they turned back around like so are we
and I was like really and like yeah so
then that started leading into a another
conversation and another conversation
then it started leading into like oh who
do you know in this area you're doing
that and like co-signing is happening
and people are reaching out you know
this guy you know that guy whatever
[ __ ] you know uh it's pretty cool
[ __ ] uh they're repping uh terp tenders
shout out to terp tenders out there in
England
but uh yeah but anyway so uh you know
over the next couple of months you know
uh We've uh wined and dined and romanced
each other and yeah and uh created a
[ __ ] pretty strong team and now we're
at the point uh we've got our farm
um it's in its building phase right now
or a couple weeks in
um I imagine by the end of August we'll
probably have our first Greenhouse up
nice and running
um getting getting uh have or getting
licensing for every single thing out
there so that's fun and uh we just
finished the final negotiation for our
shop we gotta we got a really nice shop
that we're gonna go out there and it's
going to be a NorCal genetic shop with
the terp tenders uh kind of Lounge
situation in there and so that's what
we've talked about so far it might
change whatever but so that's what we've
talked about but one of the things we
want to do is I want to be able to like
represent you know NorCal companies you
know what I mean especially like all the
ogs that have been in it for a long time
and all the genetics from all of our
friends that have been doing this for
decades right not the kids bless their
heart they're coming up with some good
[ __ ] it's nice you know I'll keep doing
your thing I appreciate you yeah but uh
I wanna I wanna reach out to the old
school you know what I mean to those of
us who have been doing this for a minute
you know and uh and help raise them up
you know and get their brands out there
and get them you know a space in
Thailand where people can get their [ __ ]
or see their [ __ ] or buy their merch or
whatever
so yeah man you gotta get Steve out
there yeah yeah yeah yeah dude so so
let's talk about Denver
in 2013 uh
we had we stayed we threw some parties
out there honeycomb hideouts dude that
was the most epic house as far as houses
that I rented for cups and we've got
together and you've rented right now
that was the one bro that was that was
the one with the basement that had a bar
that was like 40 40 feet long full bar
yeah there was there was like 20 stools
yeah yeah it was pretty crazy and there
was more dab rigs than I've ever seen
expensive dab rigs lined up on the bar I
spun fire at that too I remember yeah
you absolutely did uh man we had such a
good time you know the thing was we kept
doing all these shows all around the
world and then when stuff started coming
out over here it was like oh [ __ ] like
this is we got to do it by that time by
uh by Colorado's by the time that they
opened up for recreation uh
we had already won uh cannabis cups in
Amsterdam and uh we were on the special
list right and so when Colorado came up
it was like hey do you guys want to come
judge and what do you want and it was
like I got to John got to there was like
four or five of us and uh I was like all
right [ __ ] that let's all pick the
different you know good [ __ ] different
[ __ ] we'll go out there because we had
to go out there anyway like a week early
let's go out there 10 days early we're
gonna rent an RV and just [ __ ] around in
Colorado drive around and eat and smoke
and drink weed all the [ __ ] time and
do our little judge kits and the whole
thing and so uh I uh very meticulously
chose every time that I've been a judge
like a secret judge yeah like I picked
specifically for the location extract
that year no no no no no no no no
because we're in Cali so our game was
stronger than their game absolutely as
as good you know what I mean there was a
period for about two years where they
got a little bit better than us but not
on the whole we've been [ __ ] smashing
ask sorry sorry Colorado as far as
extracted yeah flower as far as extracts
I mean even the nicotiza there he's from
here so you know I mean I feel like he's
doing so amazing if you're a transplant
from Cali then yeah I'm gonna take that
credit I'm sorry absolutely
but yeah that was so that was the year I
entered holy water right so we had I was
working with holy water with Noel and
Mike back when everybody was together as
holy water yep and the judges didn't
know how to judge it remember we were
pouring dude we we went through ounces
of holy water pouring pouring it out of
you know Tony and [ __ ] yeah right yeah I
think so yeah yeah
um dude I so like when I did Amsterdam
when I was a secret judge in Amsterdam
when I finally got that coveted spot I
had to win a cup to get it yeah but like
I was that's what I wanted to do I
didn't give a [ __ ] about winning a cup
that was nice that's to be like okay go
going on the [ __ ] down stage yes
people right party like a [ __ ] rock
star for the night yeah that's great uh
Emmy speeds but I wanted I wanted the
ability to be a secret judge that's what
I really wanted because essentially
you're tasting the world's best [ __ ]
[ __ ] for a week sure yeah you get a box
given to you a [ __ ] absolutely like
not what the normal judges for those of
you that think you've been a judge at
high times before that's not that it's
when you come in like a week early to in
the high time special
crew puts together boxes and [ __ ] you
got to go to a safe house and you pick
up your [ __ ] box of drugs it was all
about safe houses back in the day
literally Amsterdam was the safe house
drop off it was you know they had that
they had the house and
yeah I mean those those were old school
you know where it wasn't like it was
still illegal yeah it was still
dangerous to a degree
I took for that one I was like okay what
does Amsterdam do the best what does
Amsterdam offer I'm gonna let me ask you
before I tell you what does Amsterdam
offer there that as a as a selection
that you really can't get anywhere else
including here in California lounges yes
but as far as like a product as far as
like as far as a product like one of the
competitions so I would say dude that's
a tough idea either because but I think
there is better weed and better hash
than there was back in the day let me
let me throw this out to you yeah
sativas
that's it that's all there's still a
handful of people doing sativas here but
it's really unless you know somebody you
cannot get a sativa right so like you go
there yeah you can get proper sativas
all day long do you know why why is it
because they have a pricing structure
that [ __ ] that that represents that
right so you can get a 12 or 15 eurogram
of Indica there yeah but if you want a
pure sativa there you got to pay 20
grams or 20 euros yeah yeah so like now
I think something like that maybe it's a
little bit more now yeah but uh yeah you
our economy was based on illegal economy
you know what I mean so it how as a
grower are you gonna [ __ ] keep your
lights on in a room and your risk up for
an extra you know 30 days or whatever
sure when you don't need to and you're
not going to get more or the markets so
saturated out here that you're you're
you typically aren't ever going to get
more versatile than you are for an
Indica no because they can't sell for
more although I don't know the pith
stuff
power diesel Sour Diesel is not a city
it's a hybrid I love Sour Diesel too
[ __ ] my favorite strain it's
definitely
it's interesting because the structure
is very sativa leaning and the effect is
some hybrid-ish [ __ ] amazing couch
back in the day was couch lock weed at
14 depends it also depends on what Sour
Diesel you had whether it was East Coast
Sour Diesel which I didn't consider Sour
Diesel like even what Amsterdam
considers Sour Diesel I don't consider
Saturday so like us here in Northern
California had
maybe six or seven strains double bubble
all these uh seven times they're all
these different little uh sour strains
and they were all Sour Diesel they were
all slightly different but like some of
them had better yields than others some
of them are ridiculous I remember I had
one that I grew for about five years
that you act do the the resin glands on
there after if so I hang dry yeah and so
I would put down a panda plastic
underneath and then when I'm moving them
and starting to go just the tips would
be a little bit crispy when I'm trying
to bucket them up yeah and so like hash
would fall off you know the resin glands
will fall off and normally it's like
whatever it's just going to be part of
the [ __ ] dirt on the floor with this
particular should I scrape it up because
the resin glands were full melt out of
the [ __ ] gate like I would barely
have to put it through a a shitty silk
screen kefir yeah from old school before
they had oh you got to use Micron you
know what I mean before all that right
and dude it would just you just touch a
lighter to it and it would just pool up
yeah you know yeah so the best Sour
Diesel was it where I saw was that you
know Sonoma was like the northernmost
part of Sonoma which is uh cazadero Josh
Freeman he grew the best Sour Diesel
back in the day that was outdoor but I
think it was the East Coast we just call
it Sour Diesel but I think it was ecsd
but everybody has a different opinion on
what sour was what cut and you know it's
like there's crazy stories about all of
them but the real Sour Diesel was the
real Sour Diesel there was only one real
[ __ ] super fire one and then there
was like a lemony they called AJ's is
what we got it but apparently that's not
a true story that AJ didn't have his own
cut but it was just ecsd or sour d but
that's a whole nother podcast yeah
that's a whole nother podcast yeah if
you listen to if you listen to someone
tell the story no but so much it's
already so different and that's right
his is his yeah that's that's not really
so yeah that's New York City Diesel or
yeah yeah but then the seeds that came
from some of those packs that Don and
Aaron got right that turned into some of
the more citrusy type of apparently
that's the literally the lion the Soma I
think said from from that would be like
Tangy and [ __ ] like that and all the
yeah lemony she almost was straight
grapefruit so his was a grapefruit
[ __ ] massive yielder but nothing like
the East Coast Sour Diesel and they were
both New York's the New York Diesel and
then the sour diesel were so far off
from what I knew was Sour Diesel I like
the New York City Diesel too it's cool
it's got a nice [ __ ] grapefruit like
that Ruby Red Grapefruit I love smoking
that too it's great but I like the high
from the sour diesel and it used to [ __ ]
you up the outdoor that was 14 15 that
[ __ ] used to wreck you more this stuff
is 30 today oh yeah that [ __ ] was
delicious I ours was uh we had in our
area a sour bubble was like the biggest
the best one there's like four five good
really really good ones you could take
that it had when it cured out it had
peach colored Fair like very light
orange peach colored hairs yeah it
wasn't like you know like the New York
would be like a darker color hair like
almost like a red hair yeah nothing like
that and uh you could just throw it in
the dirt and piss on it and get five
pounds off it you know what I mean like
let alone when you those are blue that
was our blue jeans
you know you start to think like oh you
get comfortable with these things oh
I've been working with this thing for so
long it's so prevalent in the area I'll
be able if I if I let it go this year
you know what I mean because we all have
size restrictions on our mother rooms
you know what I mean some things make
the cut some things don't and then when
things don't start to perform on the
other end you're like oh maybe I gotta
Cut You Down a little better yeah the
chem sour stuff yields it yields fat
like sourdies there's pictures of me
from
15 years ago behind 12 foot Sour Diesel
plastic you know what else you know it
was a [ __ ] massive one one of the
biggest planets I've ever seen was a
afghoo yeah Afghan was fired it just got
[ __ ] mad I don't even think people a
lot of people don't even know the real
napkins you know because that after that
sweet after that was like
Frosty as Frosty could be it was as
white as white could get yeah it was
just like
today if you had that people wouldn't
care they would pay indoor prices for
that [ __ ] if you agree right you know I
mean because it was also spongy because
it was oily and yeah yeah but it was
yeah I mean we we weren't even [ __ ] I
saw 15 Pounders on the regular with that
and I saw an 18 pounder not that I did
personally but [ __ ] one of my boys
did yeah a [ __ ] goddamn orange tree
but they grew they did a technique where
like they pushed them down with water
yeah every day and they grew more like a
hedge style so instead of being like a
big tall orange tree style yeah they
grew like a massive [ __ ] hedge yeah
and where they find it out and then then
yeah it's pretty cool yeah that was to
[ __ ] bro I was like what I was like
this from in law enforcement whatever
from Camp you'd run them on the ground
and then [ __ ] they'd grow up
you got to protect for wind and [ __ ] too
you know what I mean you [ __ ] around and
we catch windstorms all throughout the
fall so you could take care of some [ __ ]
baby at work at work at work it work it
and then all of a sudden after all that
hard work you catch one Windstorm in the
middle of night and you didn't put up
your support system where you didn't
build a support system into it new
people go out there yeah stupid [ __ ]
like oh I'll just go get some [ __ ]
some two inch by two inch wooden Stakes
pound those into the ground tie my
trellis into that oh hey well the first
time it rains and the ground gets soft
that shit's coming up your plant's going
in the [ __ ] dirt and welcome to mud
town and all of your weed like that's
going to be pissing you off right so
it's like yeah you know use proper [ __ ]
get some 10-foot t-posts and [ __ ]
build a do it right build [ __ ] that
can't [ __ ] fail you know what I mean
yeah
so
I really appreciate you coming on the
show man word it's been great it's been
good catching up dude we'll have to
catch up some more in Thailand we need
to do a podcast from Thailand we have to
tell everybody about your experiences
you do on pool side oh I mean I'll call
you from here I'm probably not going out
till November but I'll come pick you up
at the airport bro let me know but yeah
let me know podcast from here to over
there we'll do it overseas you open a
limo bro with a [ __ ] dab rig in the
back bro yeah that's the way to do it
that's it bro so dude so tell us a
little bit about where everybody can
find you now that you're back on the
scene well they're gonna find us in
Thailand here in a couple of months
because we got all licensing we'll have
the shop open all of that stuff but uh
right now we're still keeping it a
little bit low-key we're doing our big
launch we just had our new logo because
it's a collaboration of teams yeah so
we've all keep we're all maintaining our
independence and keeping our Our Brands
that we've kind of built you know what I
mean but then we have a collaborative
brand called cannabis Continental nice
and because we're all you know going to
be all around the world and we're made
up of people from all around the world
right so uh yeah we're gonna look
forward look for seeing that uh you know
we've got a Instagram cannabis
Continental page to go ahead and like us
we ain't got no content on there but uh
give me a couple weeks and I'll have
some good [ __ ] for you dude thank you
very much and [ __ ] I'll talk to you soon
I love you brother thank you thank you
[Music]
foreign