foreign
[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to this
week's episode of the James loud show I
have my friend Scott from cressive Soil
Solutions how you doing today yeah I'm
doing fantastic man uh thanks for having
me on it's it's an honor to be on your
show when we're down in the single digit
episodes so yeah man it's just great to
be here I'm Scott skamness my wife and I
run a business called crest of soil
Services we do agricultural Consulting
of all types but we primarily spend time
in the Cannabis space and you know
that's how we met James and I guess
that's why we're here today yeah yeah we
met originally at the black sheep boot
camp I think five years ago almost now
uh we we did some events where you were
talking about soil and I was talking
about genetics and uh a lot of fun
there's some there was a good group of
people I mean we had some of the top
people in the industry talking about a
lot of fun stuff
yeah man I've I've definitely been
fortunate to participate in some really
cool talks and conventions and I've been
invited on stage next to extremely
qualified people of which I'm extremely
grateful for and you know just to be on
a show with you with somebody with as
much time in the Cannabis industry is
definitely an honor and obviously right
now being on the James loud show is
pretty damn cool you know awesome thank
you very much so let's talk to everybody
about how you uh got on the show today
you gave me a call last week and we had
an opening but but beyond that you had
seen one of the episodes so tell us a
little bit about it yeah man I've been
uh keeping in touch you know you and I
talk periodically when I've got a large
client that needs seeds you're pretty
much the only person that I go to and uh
so we talk here and there and keep up on
the industry stuff and I've been
watching some of your episodes and
trying to keep track of them all and you
just had Chris Castle on who's a living
Soul grower in Northern California and I
kind of remember exactly what you said
but in the first few minutes you're
talking about how you've seen some
significant obstacles with living soil
at scale and maybe even haven't seen a
real solid example of successful living
soil which I would agree with there's a
lot of uh well obstacles I guess you
could say to doing living soil scale and
to be honest most people haven't figured
it out really and most people haven't
seen really solid examples of successful
living soil and you know I like to pride
myself on that the Consulting that my
wife and I do are is directing some of
those um very successful examples that
you might know and what's really
interesting about living soil and I
guess really any Market is is that those
that are working in extremely
competitive environments they don't
exactly produce a Manifesto and a how-to
of what they're doing to be successful
and especially now in these early years
of regulated cannabis there's not a lot
of people that are actually just telling
you exactly what they're doing so that's
leading to a lot of Confusion And I
think there's the added complexity of as
if you're having a conversation with a
hydroponic Farm they just say I'm doing
rock wool and that's pretty
straightforward you can expect a tray
table with Rockwell cubes if you're
doing undercurrent you say you're doing
undercurrent right and but if somebody's
in soil using bags of grow more and
spraying Eagle 20 they're calling it
living soil so there's people that are
taking a lot of liberties with the word
living Soul right now and I think I
think that's part of the problem
actually so you know living soil is
becoming a popular buzzword and so
people are trying to jump on that train
which I think leads to some of the
confusion yeah 100 agreed I mean there's
a lot of stuff out there that I I will
tell you right now it is not living soil
and if it is I I don't know what to tell
you yeah yeah and I'm definitely a
believer in living soil and you know I
come from a really qualified hydroponic
background one of my main mentors was a
guy named Randall
um and he built a facility called
candescent and regardless of how you
feel about candescent or what they did
they were the first to have the most
flour on the Shelf in the entire State
of California which is most people's
goal they're trying to dominate those
markets and so you know I I came up in
what I would assume is a similar type
and quality of hydroponic culture and
success of what you were doing the Bay
Area and just most of my connections
were in SoCal so it was all hydroponic
like I didn't read any I didn't meet any
real uh NorCal organic people until like
2014 2015 and um
you know the organic people that I met
growing up there's only like two dudes
the entire time that I met the dude
Organics and it was it was for the
passion it was for the Hobby and they
definitely were not paying the bills so
in my you know Inner Circle and culture
of Hydroponics that I came up in you
know we were plain and simple we were
making fun of those guys and so when I
found Dr Elaine and started getting into
living so I started becoming one of
those guys they made fun of and you know
I I get it there there was successful
Organics going on in other regions I
just was not in those regions so I
didn't see it and you know I didn't get
into my first Northern California
organic farm until like 2014 2015 and
that was the first time I ever saw like
truly really legit you know Organics
doing well and paying the bills well
some of those hobby guys still grow some
of the best stuff you know but it's in
such small batches you know and it's
like so much easier to control your
inputs and everything else if you're
going in a small environment a small
batch so
which is what most people learn when
they go to scale in general and that's a
lot that's where a lot of our services
come in handy and we started guiding
commercial Farms back in 2014 started
getting into the Colorado markets in
2016. you know I come from an
agricultural family so in those earlier
years of cannabis Growers getting the
first opportunity to do large scales or
even outdoor open acreages you know
comparatively I had a lot of scale
experience because I grew up in a
produce brokerage office I grew up
around Farmers that were doing hundreds
or thousands of Acres
and I guess you could say that that was
a lot of experience for the time so
combining that with my cannabis
experience and what we knew from other
hydroponic techniques I was able to
provide analytics and assistance to
those to those farmers at that time but
but basically what my mindset was is you
know if I saw a guy take a Bubba Kush
variety or OG or whatever it was and you
put it in an undercurrent system and you
got a certain result and if he put it
into a Rockwell system and got a certain
result if we weren't getting those same
results in Organics I personally believe
that it was something that we were doing
as a cultivator that was limiting the
genetic potential of that plant because
clearly that plant had a certain genetic
potential to do something in different
systems like current culture or excuse
me under current uh you know dwc
I'm not trying to name anybody by name
sorry about that
um but I basically became obsessed with
why is this organic system growing
slower producing less when the same
exact variety could go into another
system and significantly out produce
those results so I just became basically
obsessed with what were the conditions
that led to a fast-growing plant as
translated to soil-based organic systems
well and there's so many other things
like pathogens like hot plate and Vera
do you know I think operate virid is the
big topic right now and you you have
living soil beds and you get up late and
veroid in your your soil bed I mean
you're pretty [ __ ]
well I mean I would actually disagree
because that that's where living soil
gives its greatest advantage in the
regulated market because you bring in
these functions of nature that humans
can't just do right so
um one of the main advantages of living
soil is that these biological creatures
do all these magical things for us when
we put them into the right situation and
conditions so what we learned from Dr
Lane Ingham is that
when the plant has proper nutritional
balance and high biological activity all
these other different biological
functions are able to be performed and
problems are able to be dealt with that
you don't get in a hydroponic system so
one of the interesting things about
living soil is if you get to a certain
point of biological activity and ratios
between bacteria and things that eat
bacteria and beneficial fungi is that
the plant has the ability to actually
quarantine off the virus material and
sometimes what it does is it'll make
like a callus so if the the branch is
coming up or whatever that virus
material will get calloused off and make
like a weird knuckle halfway up the
branch and then typically everything
above that tends to be clean of
uh the different virus material and
sometimes it will then coordinate off to
an entire Branch so a lot of times
you'll see a plant that looks pretty
healthy but then one branch will just
look all dudded and shiny or you know
variegated or whatever it is and you
know I I personally believe based on my
observation of working with literally
millions of square feet of regulated and
unregulated cannabis is that as our IPM
choices went up in frequency so did the
virus material as well and so back in
the older days we'd make one light
application of Eagle 20. I'm not saying
it was kosher or healthy or tasty or
even past testing now but people were
doing like one single application for
powdered mildew now people are
absolutely bombarding the plants with
citric acids uh oils and rubbing
alcohol-based pesticides over and over
and over and over and so as somebody
that creates monitors and provides
analytics to the Cannabis space I can
tell you very clearly the overlapping of
of Trends or you know dead on right so I
think most of this virus material is
because of our choices in this
repetitive over and over applications of
IPM which in living soil you can't
really do that so in order to get these
high biological populations in order to
have the plant clean out its own virus
material you also can't be spraying IPM
products right so it it's I think all
this virus boogeyman is mostly due to
our current set of behaviors and
cultural practices within the Cannabis
space which weren't going on in Prior
times when this virus is not around so
so with hoplite I mean what I've seen is
there's there's guys that have it and
they they deal with it and it's not a
big deal they'll pull out like the the
dotted branches and not just hop late
and we're talking about like pythium and
you know there's so many different
things there's some so many different
pathogens I mean and there's there's
some that you know they don't do a lot
and there's some that definitely
copulating that is definitely affecting
people but I see some Grows Where guys
have it and it doesn't really affect
them or it affects branches and then
they give clones to another guy and then
it just decimates the whole facility
yeah yeah so so I would argue again that
that there's still an underlying
nutritional issue so with the cultivator
that only has a branch here and there
that's being affected I would say that's
the hydroponic nutritional
manifestation of what I was just
describing from a biological standpoint
so if you're if your mineral chemistry
is on with your feeding strategy you can
through mineral nutrition allow the
plant to do the same type of virus
cleaning of its of its plant material
and that would be the guy that has just
one branch kind of Go Daddy and you cut
it off and they're not that affected by
it but if you've got somebody that their
entire crop gets decimated by the
viruses I bet you paychecks that if you
analyze their Reservoir it's all out of
whack right so probably way too high in
nitrogen not near the amount of calcium
and probably way too much potassium so
kind of what's happened just through
experiential evidence or observational
science which I think Legacy cannabis
Growers are experts in making a way
without data and analytics you know they
just started tweaking the recipes until
it worked right and and I think what
kind of ended up is long story short you
end up with low levels of calcium high
levels of potassium and phosphorus which
leads to a more stable substrate so that
as you're not managing water content of
that root Zone you still get stability
of the nutrients and you don't get an
uneven stacking as they would say which
creates maybe short spindly plants low
yields or handy buggy problems so that's
why crop steering is so influential
right now because yeah the yield
increases significant when you start to
actually manage the water content in
that substrate properly to be able to
stack those nutrients in a way that's
productive right so under that type of
water chemistry when you're running
significantly deficient calcium high
levels of phosphorus and potassium and
all these nitrogen usually
you will get the yield you will get the
bag appeal you will get the potency and
the quality but there's typically going
to be some sort of susceptibility
depending on the variety and context I
guess if your environment's good or not
good you tend to get either powdery
mildew or Mite issues and then how we
start to control those might and mildew
issues I believe is where this
virus material started to come in
because
um most of the Consulting that we do
splits into two basic groups those that
just had catastrophic crop loss in the
regulated market that are trying to find
a way around it or those that are doing
quite well and are trying to find Peak
Performance so we don't really work with
a lot of like Middle Ground we're
working with
after everything went to hell or those
that are respected doing quite well and
they're trying to get an extra Edge and
in that Journey we've done a tremendous
amount of analytics of
I guess we say problems that arise and
then we then the first thing that I do
is start taking the data points so
analyze the reservoir check out the
environment things like that and these
very consistent patterns reveal
themselves when virus material is more
common I guess we could say
but the but the reason why I'm such a
fan of living soil is that nature has a
solution for these things and that's
you know kind of hard to wrap your mind
around but what we see experientially is
if you take a plant with high levels of
virus material in it and you put it into
a properly balanced soil from a
chemistry standpoint and then you get
the biological activity up to and above
the minimum thresholds defined by Dr
Lane's work the plant now has other
abilities to deal with problems so if
there is virus material in that plant it
either shuttles it to one branch and
then that Branch looks like [ __ ] or
it'll form like a callus around a
certain point and everything above it
grows clean so I would I would assume
that those people in your network that
you know that the viruses aren't a
problem are likely running more ideally
balanced nutrient Solutions and you can
also do this from a nutritional
management standpoint you just have to
be dialed in on your nutritional
management if you're not dialed in on
your nutritional management and you're
running deficient in calcium or what I
would Define as deficient in calcium
high in nitrogen phosphorus and
potassium those plants from a from a
mechanism of nutrition are going to be
more susceptible to that virus material
decimating I think that's why that
happens no no I would say the data we've
observed shows that's really why it's
happening so I believe that you
absolutely can clean up virus material
through hydroponic means I think just
um
industry-wide by and large most people
aren't
um will say specifically analyzing what
they're feeding you know to to know what
these targets and ratios are I think a
lot of people just get really good at
running a brand so to speak like within
reasonable ranges
but then from Harvest to harvest
sometimes there's fluctuation and those
fluctuation and results are I would I
would say is coming from a fluctuation
in the products you're using
but most people aren't doing
you know most people aren't analyzing
their fertilization basically
interesting yeah yeah pretty crazy let's
talk about aggressive soil what you guys
do you and Sarah are uh you know pretty
booked up and you have a group as well
of people that you work with
yeah we we do we've we've worked with
quite an interesting mix of people along
the way like I said I come from a
hydroponic World I'll still periodically
pick up hydroponic Farms not very often
anymore I'm really selective at this
point but to me I just want to see
anybody that's been doing it stay in it
and so along the way I've been able to
help some pretty well respected
hydroponic names uh mostly from like
procedural standpoints so you can take
somebody that was world famous in the
Legacy markets they're still new to the
regulated process right so one of the
main ways I help some of the you know
salt-based Farmers is just managing the
regulated aspect and you know keeping
from test fails uh we also help people
with analytics of what they're feeding
or fertilizing in the living soil world
you know I'd like to think that we were
a major influential part in one of the
reasons why it's popular because my wife
and I were the first people to put the
analytics to the process so what's
interesting is like I said I come from a
very data driven
you know kind of almost militant
hydroponic culture you know that was
very strict in their behavior and
dealings and and how they did things and
then when I got into Organics everybody
wants to be like
you know and that's just that just ain't
good for me and and
um you know in in the hydroponic World
there there are data and analytics that
you can do you can measure your
environment you can manage VPD you can
if you have the tools available measure
the water content of your substrate and
in Organics when I started to follow Dr
Lane and take her courses and and you
know I met nobody
really for years it was doing any level
of analytics you'd meet the random
person here or there that would do the
occasional soil chemistry analysis and
that you know basically I'm an obsessor
I'll stay up all night thinking about
stuff and
by taking data points it allowed me to
sleep at night and so that was basically
what we offered to the organic
cultivators in the regulated space was
we would come into a legal facility that
either recently had a problem or was
afraid of having a problem and we'd take
a bunch of soil chemistry we do a lot of
biological assessment organize that into
some sort of
digestible format and then present it to
the farmers so that they could act on
that and in the case of living soil if
you start doing a biological assessment
of your facility either from corner to
corner or rows or whatever it starts to
reveal a picture of where the problems
are starting from basically and from our
Viewpoint we've done so many of these
um analysis of farms of all size there's
some very clear patterns from my
standpoint so basically what we do is
try to direct the farm through data
to change their procedural
what we would call cultural practices so
how they water how they dispense
nutrients how they do teas or don't do
teas or what have you and try to
streamline that into a process or
package that leads to desirable numbers
on these various tests and once you do
that in living soil most of if not all
the problems go away which I realize is
a pretty bold statement but that's
really the truth of it if you're if
you're doing a microscope assessment of
your soil and managing Behavior based on
those results powdery mildew is the
easiest thing to remove from your
facility it's a pretty clear percentage
and the ratio between what we call oh my
seats and what we would categorize as
benefit beneficial fungi so if you
manage your watering manage your
techniques to reduce those levels then
powdery mildew is not really a thing
which I know is a pretty bold statement
but that's how it goes so even VPD even
VPD is like so so going from like the
Legacy Market as a legacy grower and all
of a sudden you're approach with these
GPD numbers I think for for a lot of us
that have been growing for 30 years you
always had your humidity below 50
percent which is almost the exact
opposite of what you want to do if
you're cultivating correctly but it's a
scary thing you know
it's terrifying to most people yeah
having high humidity because we
associate powder milk with high humidity
which is a reasonable concern you know
and
um the first time I ever saw the VPD of
con VPD as a concept was one of the guys
that I would Define as my mentors was a
pretty solid grower and he had some
equipment fail and they were you know
Bubba Kush
60 degree room I mean they were sub
cooling the [ __ ] out of their buildings
and
um some of his equipment broke and all
of a sudden he was like mid 80s and high
humidity and at towards the end of
harvest he like brought us into this
room he's like you guys check this out
and that was the biggest nugs any of us
have ever seen were like what are you
doing in here he's like I don't know the
equipment broke and I just went with it
it just kind of like through the hand of
God put him into like the VP dark you
know the green on the chart or whatever
I don't know and that was mind-blowing
to me because that entire
group there was you know like I said
they were growing Bubba cushions and you
know trying to get it to 60 or whatever
they were doing and to walk into a room
that was like 83 degrees 80 humidity
we were just mind-blown that it was
still working I I think we can attribute
some of the increases in yields to
actual VPD adjustments I mean I would
say that that's one of the biggest
changes over the last you know 15 years
where we were excited that that's when
we went from getting two pounds of light
on a four by four to getting three or
more
yeah agreed yeah and it's crazy how
these like little incremental changes of
being able to use data to guide your
process now I don't like to make data or
analytics like the the only holy thing
you still have to I still believe that
the farmer is the best calibrated tool
right but
what's happening with VPD is so they
call it the vapor pressure deficit which
basically is there's a differential
between the osmotic pressure on the
outside of the leaf and on the inside of
the leaf so in hydroponic systems That's
essential for drawing water nutrients
through the plant out through the leaves
on transpiration which is how you fill
up fat flowers basically so when we were
keeping it below 50 humidity we might
have been mitigating powdery mildew
but in a rock wool or cocoa or other
hydroponic techniques you're limiting
the plant's ability to transpire which
is basically sweating and that's how
they move nutrients they are literally
moving nutrients through
I guess a change in osmotic pressure
between
I guess you could say all the way from
the root Zone up and out the leaves and
that's how all that humidity gets into
the air is because the water movement is
bringing the nutrients to the highest
growth tip
um and so that's why sometimes in a Hot
Corner you've got some spider mites
because that difference difference in
temperature that's maybe slightly hot is
affecting this vapor pressure deficit
and it seems to impact calcium the most
and as you get as you start to have
Calcium deficiency you run into Mite
issues often
typically too much nitrogen will produce
powdery mildew issues not enough calcium
will start to be more like a might pest
issue so yeah and if you're making seeds
you want to run High nitrogen so exactly
that's the seeds are seeds are made of
nitrogen right so yeah that makes sense
when you said that in our little group
that kind of blew my mind like I never
even thought about that but we use seed
in our composting because it's high in
nitrogen and so I don't even think about
that
um that was pretty interesting little
tidbit
yeah yeah yeah so you had some uh you
had some uh diagrams that you wanted to
share with the group oh yeah let's uh
yeah let's do that so I guess I'm really
big on slideshows and keynote I like to
show visual examples
um you have some good ones too you
absolutely yeah I think I do so let me
try and give a couple so this is to
answer the question as to why your
living soil may not be working the way
that you want to
um and so one of the main Concepts that
I think is actually the biggest barrier
to success in living soil biologically
driven systems is something called
ecological succession so ecological
succession is the scientific term for
what nature is doing on an ecosystem so
it starts at bare rock or what they
would call primary ecosystem so lava
flow flood whatever and then it starts
to what they call early successional
grasses shrubs and small trees
um the other type of trees and then
eventually an old growth forest and this
progression I guess this progression
would be
um called ecological succession and what
people completely are missing I believe
in in all areas of cultivation whether
it's carrots tomatoes or cannabis is
that
as this ecological succession takes
um takes its process on and plants get
more diverse as you go the biological
system that supports these various
systems becomes more complex and
actually starts to change so over here
in a primary ecosystem you have mostly
or if not all bacteria you start to get
a little bit of fungi which are these
orange dots As you move higher in
succession and when you get finally to
an old growth forest you start to
actually have more fungi than bacteria
and I think this is one of the reasons
why there was such success had when
people went into the forests of Humboldt
and Mendocino and Northern California
and plop their plants in you were
plopping it into this system and as
canvas got more and more legal we
cleared these trees out and all this
system kind of fell apart and based on
the work of Dr Lane and the stuff that
I've seen you could generally put
cannabis into this range so if you're
relying on packaged bacteria products
you're over here if you're not using any
sort of compost that legitimately has
the proper quantities and ratios of
biological organisms which we would turn
biologically complete compost or Dr
lean's trademark term of bile complete
compost biocomplete and biologically
complete just means that your compost is
taken into consideration these other
organisms that need to be in there so
basically what happens is
if cannabis evolved on the planet in
this type of ecosystem and from a
biological standpoint your system is
only providing this bacteria you're not
supporting this system with any of the
things that it's accustomed to and that
basically is the Cascade of events that
leads to past slow growth and what have
you the most common pests in living soil
people call thrips Susan Wade rat would
argue that it's not always thrips but
whatever the specificity of it the the
the the bug that leaves little shiny
holes in the leaves the drive living
soil Growers nuts
100 of the time I have analyzed the
biological assessment of a soil that is
claiming to have thrips is way over here
and what I would assert that to is
without this level of biological
activity nutrients are not being
delivered to that plant at a rate that's
fast enough that equals the demand on
growth we're putting on this plant with
high intensity lighting short life
cycles fast flips and all that stuff so
in order for living soil to have the
growth rates proper you need to be I
mean you got to at least get into this
first realm and once you start to get
basically what we would Define as
nutrient cycling which is happening over
here most of your problems start to go
away pretty heroic things start to
happen over here and those would be the
situations that most people don't talk
about and what we would Define as fish
stories because when you do try to talk
about them people just interrupt you
with your line right so but if you get
into this range pretty magical things
start to happen
um and from a soil chemistry standpoint
that's actually one of the bigger issues
because most people aren't looking at
this the people that design your soil
don't seem to care as much as they
should I think and so chemistry in the
soils we're working with is wacky as can
be so from a general standpoint a
healthy soil so an actual soil whether
that's native soil or potting soil that
you've manufactured should have
somewhere roughly around 68 to 72
percent of that mineral being calcium
somewhere between 10 and 14 percent of
that mineral nutrition as magnesium and
somewhere between four and seven percent
as potassium if we go and look at a um
maybe say like Fox Farms or something
it's going to have this breakdown it's
going to be like 50 40 and 20. if you
look at any of the dry mineral top dress
products that we like and a lot of them
are great products but the problem is if
they put this much calcium into the mix
the three numbers on the bag would be
zero zero zero because you diluted the
potassium so low so at best you get 10
calcium and like five to seven percent
potassium because nobody is going to go
into the store and buy a zero zero zero
so it's not
uh you know I don't know but basically
what happens is if you buy any of the
pre-packaged mineral dry top dress
products and rely on those for your
mineral nutrition and the soil based
system every time you add them to your
soil you are maintaining the same
dysfunctional mineral chemistry balance
and it doesn't really take any sort of
scientists to realize that if this is
what the plant needs to see in your soil
based system and this is what you're
getting there's going to be some
problems so the consequence of this
mineral chemistry over here is you have
a functional deficiency in calcium some
advisors would argue that 80 percent of
the plant's biomass requires calcium
and magnesium and cannabis is a yield in
quality killer so once you get above
let's say 20 percent
magnesium you start to significantly
impact bag appeal yield Frost potency
things like that and when you start to
get a significant quantity of potassium
you're creating weak and watery cells
because the way that the plant wants to
build a cells it brings calcium up into
that plant and it builds the main
structure of that cell with calcium
starts to fill with all the other stuff
um if you're feeling it with potassium
or rather if there's a deficiency of
calcium the plant can substitute it with
potassium to keep its life cycle moving
but you're now creating a cell filled
with an electrolyte which potassium is
an electrolyte which creates a weak
watery cell which is kind of what I was
talking about earlier about how under
this condition of high Potassium and low
calcium
in a way you're making your plants more
uh susceptible to really any problem and
especially some of the virus material
and these are some pictures this is my
wife here she's like five foot one I
think five two something like that this
was a project we did in 2018 when I met
my wife she had was living in Utah was
not around any cannabis cultivation at
all and so when we started Consulting
together in 2014 I had all the Cannabis
experience so she would do the
microscope assessment and I would
basically handle all the Cannabis
related uh functionality and so by 2018
she had done so much Consulting with me
that she was becoming her own little
cannabis
um uh official I guess and so this was a
project in 2018 with two cultivators we
had worked two two years prior to that
as a guy named Sean used to go by push
farms and Sarah LED this entire project
without me so I just kind of took
pictures and hung out but this was kind
of like Sarah's senior project
um of cannabis and she led all the
fertilization all the stuff I just kind
of hung out but basically what you're
looking at is this is our control so
um we like to try and maintain a control
anytime we we're trying to do research
and so this is
um seed plants dug into a hole and just
planted there was no soil prep there was
no biological treatments these plants
did receive the same fertilization they
did receive the same foliar feeding but
they didn't receive any biological
treatments native soil native soil 100
yeah this is native soil and obviously
there's some like weird gaps here
because like we said we're trying to
keep this as a control this was at the
top of one of the plots
um and so we didn't get like a full
planting density obviously we were
mostly looking at plant growth response
yield potential and whatnot but if you
were to take this size plant and do
proper planting density do proper row
count per acre you'd end up somewhere
around a thousand you might get maybe
1200 pounds per acre or something like
that and at this time in 2017 2018 most
of the farmers that were hiring us for
broad acre scale work you know their
main goal was like if they've got 12 to
1500 pounds per acre they would feel
pretty good about themselves if they had
two thousand pounds per acre they would
be stoked right so just kind of as a
visual size this might get you about a
thousand pounds per acre at a proper
planting density and and row structure
over here on this side these are the
same genetics same seeds same grower
same cultivator same property
but this row got
um what's called a yeoman plow so the
plow does a deep rib that goes about 30
inches deep and it breaks up the
compaction and we hooked up a compost
extract tank that would inject compost
extract deep down into that hole so
basically what we were doing is we were
breaking up the agriculture compaction
and we made sure that the top 30 inches
of soil were properly inoculated with
Biology and then once we transplanted we
did another compost extract treatment
and I believe they received two more in
the course of this thing so both are
coming from the same seed stock same
breeders same crew same cultivator same
fertilization same foliar feeding same
canopy management this one was just
plopped into a hole this one got up to
you know what we would call uh let me
see here go back up to this guy
so from a biological standpoint they got
into this range right
yeah and that's the difference so plants
on the left it's this range plants on
the right are kind of maybe this range I
guess you could say there was kind of a
bit of obstacles at this type of scale
gets really hard to do everything there
was some significant budget constraints
on this property
um so we weren't able to do everything
that we wanted but nonetheless there's a
significant change in plant growth and
on this side they ended up with four
thousand pounds per acre of durable
flour I have some COA somewhere on my
computer but they're all 26 to 28 THC
highly desirable outcome and so you know
you know when you said living soil kind
of struggles this is the image I think
you had in your head and then when I
heard it this is the image I have in my
head it's like well when you're truly
doing living soil
um that's you know it looks a little bit
different and that's what most people
are kind of unaware of and I think
that's one of the biggest issues with
just kind of the organic culture and I
gotta be really careful when I say this
because I don't want to be inflammatory
or or I'm not trying to say this trying
to be a jerk but
um
there's some significant cultural
differences between the hydroponic world
and the organic living soil world and in
the living soil World results are less
important right so if you go to like
jungle Boys on Instagram they're not
like writing you poetry and stuff they
just put a picture of their grow and
says
you know I forget you know Double
Diamond cookies
June 2023. you know what I'm saying they
just this is what I did today you know
what I mean like they're not they're not
even necessarily talking about what they
did or they're not giving you recipes
they're just like yo this is what I did
you know and like if you go to the
organic world and especially the living
soil world the community is the most
valuable thing
um being non-threatening is the most
important thing supporting the gurus is
the most important thing I guess we
could say right in Hydroponics nobody
cares about that [ __ ] and where I came
from like you weren't even allowed
just to say I read on the internet you
would get slapped like a like a meme or
something like get out of here kid you
know what I mean it was like if you
started a sentence with I read on the
internet they'd be like nope not here
player and they'd be like go apply to
your garden
bring the flower we'll smoke it and if
it's worth the [ __ ] we'll talk about
what you read on the internet like it
was so disallowed almost violently and
in the organic world we just have this
Echo chamber of things that don't work
have not worked have never worked are
probably never going to work but
everybody wants to be part of the
community talking about these things
right and so especially if you're just
like a normal grower trying to decipher
how to take a pathway into living soil
and you're only outlet for information
is Instagram or some of the forums it is
extremely difficult to truly be
successful I think and you know
especially because the predominant
narrative in living soil the ironic part
about it is there's a lot of really loud
voices to try to silence anybody talking
about quantifying biology and I think
you know part of that is by Design you
know the other major difference is you
know I worked for a hydroponic um
organization very massive very well
known you definitely know who they are
and you definitely know their investors
um this is a 2018 and they hired me for
the value I could provide to their Farm
but at the same time they had a lobbyist
on the organic regulation board for
California called ocal to make it more
difficult for organic cultivators right
so in 2018 and I would say so we're
working with the first indoor Farm to be
okal certified I've worked with
literally hundreds of organic farms none
of them know anything about they don't
even know it's called ocal but you go to
the hydroponic world or the chemical
World they have lobbyists making it more
difficult for the Organics right and I
don't go too much more down that rabbit
hole sounding like a kook but that's
another major issue is there's people
from different areas of chemical
agriculture that infiltrate
misinformation in order to make it
difficult for you to be successful so if
you're if you don't have any commercial
connections you know like I know you you
know like if there's something going on
popular Trend I'd be like hey James what
do you think about these things going on
be like yeah no that's
that's a pay to play I don't think
they're really doing it you know that's
a sponsored deal yeah right
you know like but in the organic world
there's a tremendous amount of effort on
these pay-to-plays I've worked for some
of these Farms I kind of take a major
stance to not do any of those anymore
um or well if I'm working with a farm
that's just doing something to promote a
product I usually don't mess with those
kind of people
um I need you to be about what you're
doing and not just taking a sponsorship
deal you know people don't realize you
know in NASCAR the stickers on the car
and cannabis the sticker's not on the
car right there's still sponsored deals
there's right there's still stuff right
imagine imagine these guys though with
jackets and cannabis it'd be kind of
goofy
I think it would be funny is to see the
organic gurus with a syngenta sticker on
their back right yep um because that's
definitely a deal but so you know for
the commercial cultivators that have
commercial connections it's a little bit
easier because you're in a certain
Community adding to a certain point if
you get to a certain scale and you've
made it this far you're able to discern
on your own if a new trend is going to
be real or not right like if somebody
popped up some new hydroponic Trend you
have enough personal experience to go
yeah I don't think that's going to shake
out you know what I mean like
yeah right and so 100 right so but most
your average living soil people don't
have that and a large majority of the
people getting into living soil are
coming from other areas of
Agriculture and that's most of my
clientele
um I get a lot of flack for that from
people in the living soil Community but
again I'm here because I came from a
qualified crew I was not the lead grower
I was not the facility owner I was the
guy that did Anna data and analytics and
help people be in business way back when
I was calculating kilowatt hours I was
helping people manage you know I just
was the nerdy math guy and the group and
so as legalization continued forward
that's still my role and so I'm here
because I'm trying to keep people with
cannabis experience in the Cannabis game
and so if you previously did Coco core
drained a waste or hydroponic whatever
and you want to now do living soil I'm
probably going to help you do that you
know and and again like if you're just
trying to succeed with your growing
system in rockwool sometimes I'll still
help you too right
um and
and I think for the new entrance to the
market so to speak good luck deciphering
what's shared on Instagram or whatever
it's a real good way to go out of
business and right now there's some
really popular trends that are the
swiftest way to end your career in
cannabis you know by following what
they're talking about on the internet
and
you know I I used to kind of try to be a
little more vocal to try and stop some
of those things I've just gotten out of
the way of that train I just kind of
work privately behind the doors almost
exclusively and so yeah I just don't
even bother anymore
um which again that's why I was here I
want to be an educator we used to do um
presentations and workshops we don't
really do those anymore uh you know I
think one of the last ones I did was
probably with you and black sheep I
think I maybe done one since then
um but now we do classes so now we have
what we call master classes where
I mean we work with 4x4 tent Growers you
know we've got a couple other commercial
Farms that go through our um our master
classes but basically we've distilled
down the full complexity of our
Consulting work into five and eight week
modules where we meet through Zoom like
this and we have a private forum and we
meet once a month with all members which
is what you came to so you came to and
was a really our first guest speaker to
our monthly meetings which was pretty
badass people are just raving about that
show dude that was cool you have a great
group too I think I do yeah a lot of
passionate people and you know it's the
four light Growers if you're growing
four lights you're passionate about it
it's not about money anymore there's no
way
so yeah it's a beautiful thing seeing
people really growing with you know four
lights or even one light you know in a
four by four
yeah and sometimes that's where the
greatest Innovation comes from actually
and so I you know at the same time we
were working with some of the largest
Farms on the planet literally by
definition and at the same time still
doing one-on-one Consulting calls for
four light Growers single tank Growers
and a lot of times some of the most
interesting things of innovation are
coming from those little two by fours
and just you know nobody from the
industry that just comes up with a
different angle or some random product
from their hardware store or something
and sometimes a lot of the most
interesting things come from those
smaller Growers but in years past our
business was not set up to help those
smaller Growers and that was kind of
some of the Flack we got from the living
soil Industries you know they thought we
were just helping some of the biggest
farms which that's just what I like to
do you know like I came from you know
some legitimate
you know company back in the day and you
know two of my cousins that are like my
brothers went on to be NASCAR crew
chiefs like I'm not trying to be third
place like I want to be in the biggest
stadiums I want to have the biggest
impact I want to do the coolest [ __ ] and
so that that took us to just some big
that's just what I like and but what I
like now we're still doing those jobs
but now we've got a functional format
for the smaller Growers or even now hell
everybody's pinched on money right now
and so we're we're helping some
commercial farms in our master classes
because it's a minor fraction of what
our personal Consulting costs and
actually uh we just had our first
student win a cup so we've been working
with Cup winners since day one we now
just had our first student and he won
the emerald cup and he won uh a High
Times cup I'm not which not sure which
one
yeah and and so that's for hemp flower
so he's got
um I think about 6 000 square feet of
greenhouse in Illinois his name is
Justin his Brand's called Stony Branch
who would have thought Illinois you know
this place I think they grow good
cannabis but it's not the first place
that's for sure and I mean I have my
friend Rick mosca from Moscone you know
there's there's people crushing in
Illinois and you know all over the
United States yeah and that's the trippy
part about this last couple years like
they're popping up all over the place
man like
you'd never think man you know we
especially us from California you from
the bay me from you know basically San
Fernando Valley Orange County San Diego
like some real players came from that
zone so it's hard to think oh someday
someone from Illinois is going to crush
it you're like yeah right we got it
thanks you know or Utah Utah so the
highest THC tested Autos I I have some
of my that have tested above 30 for
Autoflower and this is grown at scale
and you know this is not an average but
this individual plants testing above 30.
that was in Utah
get out of here who would have thought
yeah so that's where I live now I never
thought I'd end up in Utah and uh we
haven't been involved with any of the
farms around here we had a client from
California that applied and Utah is kind
of it's like one of the most good old
boy place kind of New Yorkie or
something and uh they assigned like nine
or 12 licenses I think our client got
like 15th out of I think they only
signed nine or something but I think
they're all hydroponic Farms too I don't
think they awarded any organic farms at
all wow um yeah so it's kind of
interesting uh how that works here but I
like living here but yeah the weed sucks
so gotta grow your own yeah I don't know
man we do so we do so much zoom and
we're so high profile man I'm I'm
terrified to light my house up but I I
will never not have a plant in my
backyard never it's always you know it's
like I made some seeds in my backyard I
love I just like having plants right now
I'm with you do this hard for me I mean
I've scalped all kinds of bedrooms to
keep going in the back and when we lived
in Northern California was able to do
the first full-term outdoor which was
cool I've only done three outdoor runs
because I only lived there for three
years
um but yeah it's way I mean this is the
snitch state so you gotta be real
careful people don't even talk about
smoking weed here it's pretty sketchy
um so right now I'm doing chickens I got
a chicken coop and I'm gonna do some
selective breeding it's nice
so I'm applying the principles of
cannabis to my chicken coop and that's
kind of cool yeah but yeah hopefully
someday I'll be able to sneak a planet
I'm just still I'm only been here one
year I'm a little nervous you know so
yeah yeah it's Gotta Go some CBG or CBD
I know right just out of the backyard
all boom big old 12-footer yeah
we live up against the mountain and we
get legitimate like 70 mile an hour
winds coming off the mountain into the
back of our house and we set up a garden
that blows down the street so I ordered
I ordered a little two by two light for
Sarah and we're gonna set up a little
tomato inside the kitchen by the front
door
um so I'm gonna grow a tomato plant for
inside because that poor Sarah that
outdoor Garden just keeps blowing down
the street like we can't even hardly
it's crazy so I got a question for you
where do you see the industry in the
next five years and in the next 10 years
from what aspect from where we're at now
from where we were before to where we're
at now as far as
companies quality uh where do you see
the genetics going uh you think more
people will be going to scale are we
going to have less indoor and more
Greenhouse supplemental lighting which I
I kind of think is the perfect
environment
yeah I I love I love uh light up
Greenhouse
um it's kind of The Best of Both Worlds
uh we work with a lot of indoor Growers
and it's it's hard to say how long
economically that's going to pan out
um I think there's some brands that will
always be around regardless of Economics
right so I've worked with some of those
girls that their brand will carry on
um I know this one guy Sam he's the lead
cultivator of a farm in Northern
California I think they're the largest
permit holder in Northern California
something like that
um but he said his analytic team made
the claim that here in the next year or
so the only flower in the state of
California that's going to maintain an
eighth price over fifty dollars will be
a living soil grown aside from the
cookies you know those handful of brands
that will always maintain that
um which is pretty interesting to me
um you know I've done a lot of Economics
for all types of farms that's part of
what I do for my Consulting
um you know I also have a business
degree and the weed knowledge so I'm
able to sit at the table with the grower
and the business guys I do a lot of
spreadsheet analytics forecasting things
like that so I know all the economics
the cost of production and things like
that and you know back in 2018 everybody
was kind of saying or even really 2016
2017 a lot of people were kind of
professing you need to be below 600
below 400 all in cost per pound and in
like 2018 people we're still like 890
920 you know nowhere near that
um I think you can get that with any
cultivation style but you have to be on
point and I think what I see shaking out
is regardless if you're growing
Hydroponics or regardless if you're
growing living soil if you're not data
driven in some way I mean you still need
to be an artist you still need to be the
cultivator but if you're not measuring
your process I don't think you're going
to survive right whether you're Legacy
or legal because it's getting down to I
was having this conversation yesterday
with one of my classes it's like you
know when pounds were four thousand
dollars you could afford to cut a crop
down if it went sideways you could
afford to scrub a room down you can
afford to shut down you could afford to
not look at your numbers
you could and more importantly nailed it
on the head you could afford to not even
care about financials and I say this in
the most loving way possible but most of
us were very sloppy Financial myself
included like I still barely manage my
finances the way I should even though
that's part of my job you know helping
people keep their money straight and
annabis made me sloppy with my
profitability so to speak and if you're
not I think on a basic level if you
start with all the things you can
quantify if you're not analyzing what
you're feeding every Harvest I don't
think you're gonna make it because you
don't know why things go sideways you
don't know why things go well if
somebody comes to me it's usually when
things aren't going well and then they
start taking a data point you're like
okay great you now have a numerical
assessment of not good when things are
going well you need to analyze that so
that you can at least get back to it
that's how I learned what these targets
were well things are going well let's
send an analysis of our fertilization
recipe to Wallace labs for example in El
Segundo they're fantastic fantastic I
think they provide the most accurate
um assessment of a fertilization recipe
you know whether that's Organics or
water chemistry so I didn't get bare
minimum you need to be doing regular
water chemistry tests because your water
changes in Denver Colorado half the year
your water is a 6.2 and comes from a
certain water source another part of the
year it's 8.4 and comes from another
water source if you're pouring the same
mils per gallon of your Advanced
Nutrients or whatever in there
you're gonna have one good part of the
year and one bad part of the year in a
really simple fashion
more important than that no matter how
much you like your products they vary
quite wildly sometimes throughout the
year and so part of the analytics I do
are four products helping them be more
consistent you know like right now
Athena is really popular I think Athena
is really popular simply because they're
doing some of these analytics right so
they're trying to produce a higher
quality and I don't even necessarily
care for them I just think that's why
people are jumping on it and like having
a little bit more success I think Athena
is doing a little bit more
due diligence so to speak you know and
there's other good brands too you know
and CES I think has been pretty good
he's a extremely data driven uh guy
there you know so there's other brands
that are good some of this stuff might
be a 300 variation in what's in that
bottle yeah so I I like Cutting Edge I'm
a big fan of Cutting Edge I'm a big fan
of United you know there's a lot of
stuff and then you know Emerald Harvest
as far as organic
you know I think they have interesting
they have interesting products for sure
yeah you know but I'm not married to any
one product I'm not sponsored by anybody
we don't I don't you know I don't take
endorsement money so no no no yeah I
don't think that even needs to be said
with you but so if you just talk about
like a cost production standpoint so you
know some of the larger hydroponic Farms
that I've worked with you know they come
in running heavy 16 running Advanced
yeah uh you know running
um
what was the other one
the San Fernando Valley guys I can
picture the label I can't think of my
name right now but anyways in 2018 that
stuff was 350 a square foot nutrient
input cost per Harvest
most things have gone up 40 to 50 to 100
so I'd say in 2023 if you're running
heavy 16 Advanced
um
uh you know any of those you're probably
three four maybe five dollars a square
foot nutrient input cost I know CES is a
little bit cheaper um but if you talk
about like General Hydroponics you're
probably two to fifty per square foot if
you're using floor Pro I think floor Pro
is a little cheaper you know you're
using some salt Salt's floor Pro is
actually a pretty good product if we're
talking you know something that's a
two-part that's a salt mix you know I've
used it for seed production and I I
basically will try anything I love
especially for seed production I love
trying different things and seeing what
kind of results I get you know we we hit
the mark the other the other day when we
harvested it over 45 000 seeds per 4x4
which is that's crazy yeah it's pretty
wild that's been crazy
so back when I started if you would have
told me those are the kind of numbers we
could get I would have really strived a
lot harder to get those numbers
right it's like the four minute mile
nobody nobody strove for it they didn't
know it was possible you know and that's
I think that's the best part about
legalization and it brought stuff out
into the open and I think it gave people
something to chase you know there was
all those little pockets of dudes
crushing it and once you got to be able
to put it on Instagram I think it's like
the four minute mile it's like wow I can
do that yeah you know but but if you're
not measuring these things you're gonna
you're gonna struggle to stay relevant
whether you're well financed or not and
you know one of the things that I do is
I help transition people from bottles to
just bag soft formulations so you can go
from like you know three four five
dollars a square foot down to a dollar a
square foot and get the same production
or sometimes better if you're balancing
the npnk and all that stuff living soil
comparatively so my full program Guild
you know you know push to the max put
pushing industry leading quality you
know it's like a dollar dollar twenty
square foot all in yeah and so you
compare that to the absolute lowest
price bag salt which is about a buck
right now and you know you're two three
four dollars a square foot it's not
going to take very long for living soil
to get a significant advantage over that
just from your reoccurring costs you
know and yeah and it pays for itself
right so like over time absolutely pays
for itself your your investment is
initial right so like in your soil and
then
as you go it gets cheaper and cheaper
and cheaper
yeah yeah I think both can be managed
though but like if you're in that two
three four dollars a square foot you
probably better take a look at that
moving into the future and
more importantly you can't afford to
have one fall off like you need to know
why you had a 20 loss on this run you
know you need to know why that's
happening you know five years from now
where do you see the industry
my honest answer yep I I see the only
people still able to cultivate whether
it's Legacy or regulated are those
people that are incorporating the
available analytic tools and the tools
to guide your cultivation process I'm
not saying we're not going to be artists
anymore I'm not saying the cultivator is
not the best thing anymore but I'm
saying if you're not analyzing your
water if you're not analyzing your feed
every time you buy nutrients you just
will not make it I think and I don't
know I think just that's a broad
statement that if you're not you know if
you're in Hydroponics and you're not
measuring volumetric water content
you're going to get smoked by the people
that are absolutely smoked and you can
buy little handheld meters you don't
need to buy some like crazy growing
stuff you can buy a handheld meter just
like a pH pen
and in the living soil world you're not
you're not going to make it if you're
not analyze if you're not paying
attention to soil chemistry numbers
because the people that are producing
soil aren't hitting the numbers for you
there's not and if you're not paying
attention to the biological numbers
you're going to have slow growth
production so they're not going to make
it and you know with all the tools that
are available to now you know even troll
Master grow link Arroyo like things have
changed in the last couple years like I
like with these faux lights and the
growl links and just all these
analytical tools man it's got me
scratching trying to light up another
room just be like I want to use these
tools you know and I'm not saying you
got to go spend a bunch of money to be
productive but if you're not starting
with a 90 water test or even Logan Labs
can do a 40 water test if you're not
starting there you're not going to be
able to build a foundation to remain
relevant and I see that I see that I
mean I've worked with straight up famous
people you know like to know names it
doesn't matter it doesn't matter if
you're famous doesn't matter if you're
running a two by four
I do these analytics a 68 soil test
always comes back in profitability and
yield in a 4x4 10 always
you know when people look at these
numbers like an obstacle so if you look
at the cost of doing business as an
obstacle I don't think you're gonna make
it right you have to you have to figure
out I'm not saying blow money that's the
other thing we're great at as we guys
are just like throwing money at problems
not saying that but like if you look at
from a scarcity mindset that your pie is
shrinking and you say I get this every
day I can't afford a 68 wire test I can
tell you as somebody with a finance
degree that does economics for the
Cannabis industry that return on
investment comes out of 4x4 10. you
don't you know so if you're in any size
commercial facility and you're not doing
that every Harvest you're not going to
make it you're gonna get blown by the
people that are and a lot of those
people are new entrants and that's what
kind of sucks like you know I come from
these you know pedigrees and there's
less and less people with experience as
I go and that bums me out
um but the reality is this Market's
going to move on with or without you and
if you're stuck in this position
unwilling to move to this next
requirement of you you're going to get
left behind regardless of who you are
and I think that goes for everybody and
that's why you wear are where you are
because in your world you're doing that
you're one of the most data driven Hydro
dudes I've met there's only one other
guy I can think of that does similar
type things to you and he would be
considered world famous like you you
know and there's a lot of other people
that could get good at managing genetics
managing process managing employees
having a good out having a good Market
far away
that's all fine but if your strategy is
to ship it to Virginia like that market
is shrinking you maybe got one more year
for that yeah yeah if that like that's
wrapping up pretty quick and it's just
simply because
I think that goes back to the Eagle 20
talk of why that is the consumer's tired
of ringing ears tingling tongues and
burning throats yeah and a lot of the
Legacy Growers are still laying on the
Eagle 20 Avid and floramite and the
consumers over that and so if that's the
product you're producing not that many
people want that anymore and they don't
want to pay 35 in taxes for an eighth or
whatever the hell it is right now but it
doesn't make your ears ring doesn't make
your tongue tingle and so if if your
legacy grower that's trying to continue
moving you have to find out what's wrong
nutritionally as to why you need that
eagle 20. because in the regulated
market we figured that out it's math
it's nitrogen levels it's calcium
quantities it's not pushing potassium so
hard you don't need that stuff anymore
yeah so you got you gotta put down and
now to be fair what I said earlier that
information is very hard to come into
contact you can just Google this stuff
so I'm sympathetic to that obstacles
um but I didn't know it before I knew it
you just got to put in the work you know
right or reach out or reach out to
someone you know I help I hope nobody's
all the time you know people that nobody
knows and
sure and I think if you're watching this
and you don't know the difference
between living soil as far as why it's a
better product I it's the it's the end
product in my opinion it's the effect
more than anything else it's the effect
from the living soil you can take two
cultivars grow one with cocoa and you're
gonna get good results you give you your
Skittles in both you grow any of these
cultivars that are popular right now
you're going to get good results in both
but the effect hands down I mean I think
flavor wise you can get good flavoring
cocoa you can get great flavor but the
effect and the effect and the flavor you
know and the structure I feel like
there's you know there's something
special about living soil and the way it
cures out too it's very different than
stuff that's grown in other substrates
so I think the main difference for that
is and what I would you know what I
would attribute to as the greatest
Advantage when you compare just
Hydroponics to living any type to living
soil as the as the market moves forward
I think the greatest Advantage is while
Hydro is Flushing I'm still feeding and
we don't flush in living soil because in
Hydroponics you're taking a nutrient
that takes a salt and sticks it to a
mineral and that's called chelate or
yeah chelate it's a hard word to think
of the context but anyways you're they
have they have to stick that nutrient to
something so they stick it to a salt so
when you water that plant with that
salt-based fertilizers both those go
into the plant and then towards the end
of the Harvest cycle you got to take
that salt out and so I don't know that
just the salt comes out I think you're
pulling things back out in order to get
that clean burning flavor and we don't
contribute anything that needs to be
flushed and it's not a good idea to
flush in living soil you create a whole
other problem and so in those several
weeks while people are flushing we're
still pushing and so I think that's
where that added complexity comes from
um and where those at I guess whatever
the stuff that pops up on the test and
things we haven't even figured out how
to measure yet I think that's the one
single
one of the one of the main single
advantages honestly other than stability
if you know what you're doing with
living soil and you're quantifying these
things it's very resilient you know if
you're not paying attention to the
microbial population it feels like a
[ __ ] show you know yeah so it's that
extra buffer as far as a cultivator you
do get buffer from soil as opposed to
rockwool
yeah yeah but you can do some great
things in those I'm not at all you know
like I said I'm working with a 30 000
square foot Rockwell facility right now
um I just
I've been in the kitchen and in the
laundry room of all of them and you know
so I can see what's potential and what's
problematic and so that's why I've
doubled down so hard on living soil
is just on the powdery mildew issue it's
not an issue for us if you're managing
these things it doesn't even exist
um usually in our Consulting work we do
four month packages most Farms
get to the point of no Patty mildew in
that first harvest
um some of them takes a little bit
longer into the Second Harvest but once
they understand what we're teaching them
and they implement it and it has that
effect even after we leave years after
the powder middle doesn't come back
because they continue to manage for
those things so that's another
tremendous Advantage like we don't have
a powdery milde protocol We Don't Spray
nothing for it we don't try to control
it we use math and microscope
assessments to stay out of
the Realms of powdery mildew now in
Hydroponics you can do that as well but
it has to do with nitrogen and calcium
and calcium and potassium and then
obviously your environment so I just
think most people aren't aren't really
doing that that's what I really enjoy
the most I just a math nerd you know
right so yeah
well if people want to hear more about
what you're doing and follow uh follow
your footsteps or uh check everything oh
there we go you make it so easy
I zoom all day long dude one of the one
of those things with Kobe is I had to
become a virtual assistant here so yeah
but my website's crashesol.org like I
said coming out of Legacy markets out of
stone one day and pick a hard to spell
hard to write word thinking that'd make
me hard to find had no clue by that
point they already had um audio
thumbprints of us all logged in the
system you know but anyways uh my
personal email is Scott chrysosol.org if
you got a specific question
um like I said we we do Consulting for
any size Farm
um we've worked with foreign governments
famous dudes people you've never heard
of two by four hobbyist Growers
um I just I just like growing cannabis
man and I like I like to see people have
that moment you know I don't care if
you're a hydro grower or a living soil
grower I like it when it clicks in you
and we change one minor thing and
everything becomes better and there's
just like something really cool about
that where it just clicks and then my
favorite thing to hear people say is
I've been growing this many years I've
never seen that from my genetics that's
my favorite favorite thing to do and you
can do that through nutritional
management Hydroponics measuring your
substrate and hydroponics or just living
soil in general Done Right does that as
well and that's just my favorite thing
you know we're getting ready to fire off
another Master Class today's you know
June 2nd I think next Friday our next
master class starts we do those a few
times a year where we take people
through our Consulting programs I've got
a mineral chemistry class coming up in
July where I teach people the math on
how to do their own mineral chemistry
whether you're a consultant or a
hobbyist grower or a farm it's all good
we have everybody in between in there I
think mineral chemistry is one of the
biggest lacks in all living soil there's
only a handful of dudes that are doing
it and I just one of my main goals right
now is get way more people equipped to
professionally and properly manage
mineral chemistry of their soil because
that's a major issue in the whole
industry you know and then obviously we
do the microscope my wife teaches a
microscope class so that's the thing
we've been teaching the longest in 2013
2014 I started teaching organic Growers
how to use the microscope for their
needs my wife Sarah now teaches a class
it's about five weeks long lasts for an
entire year but you have five in-person
sessions and monthly meetings and she
basically sets you up through zoom on
how to use the microscope as an actual
analytical tool which I think if you're
any soil based system if you're not
incorporating the microscope assessment
in any way this can't is not likely to
be fruitful for you moving into the
future you got to get on that I think
you want to talk about that a little bit
more about what you guys do Under the
microscope because I think a lot of
people are curious
oh yeah exactly is what you guys are
what you guys are doing under the
microscope yeah so so we use a you know
what's called a compound light
microscope
um so there's two main types of
microscope a stereo which you look down
like to look for bugs on a leaf we use
one where light shines through the
bottom you put a cover slip and look for
bugs like in science class in high
school
um and Dr Lane Ingham is the person that
kind of took these
uh scientific tools and turned it into
an agricultural assessment and she all
through the 90s early 2000s I think by
1997 2003 she had it dialed
um she's gotten a lot of flack and a lot
of resistance I'm not saying everything
that she says right but I I would put
her at the top of my list of influential
people in my life and I became qualified
to guide commercial Farms because of her
guidance you know she taught me how to
be a professional analyst she taught me
how to manage
um cultivators basically I was good at
growing weed basically working
one-on-one with her taught me how to be
a professional
um and how to truly guide people to
success and and using the microscope
method to keep it to a data point my
favorite saying is we got to move it off
of the emotion and onto a data point you
know and and so we take the soil we're
counting bacteria we're counting um
oxygen loving aerobic what I would say
beneficial fungi we're comparing those
two uh we're looking at the predators of
bacteria they're called protozoa so
we're counting them and then we count
nematodes beneficial non-beneficial and
then what we would call the anaerobic
indicators or decreased oxygen organisms
so there's like a light switch that
turns on in biology they have very
specific functions under certain
conditions so when oxygen drops below
four parts per million a whole Suite of
organisms go to sleep and go to
endorment stage and then a whole bunch
of other organisms wake up and start
functioning that transition is where all
disease takes place so when you talk
about pythium fusarium Antonio I don't
even care about the name it means you're
on this side of decrease oxygen and you
need to address it so
there's basic patterns inside these
um different organism ratios for example
powdery mildew we did a major project in
2018 in um in Santa Barbara after the
major fires and floods and we had a one
acre greenhouse full of 30 gallon pots
of moms where some had powdery mildew
and some did not have powdery mildew we
went through each 2200 square foot Bay
and we counted all the soil from plants
that didn't have powdery mildew and we
counted all the soils from plants that
were showing visible signs of powder
mildew through all uh 16 of those Bays
um
there was a pattern within four percent
of a certain ratio so the ratio between
what we call oh my seats which are water
molds powdery mildew causing basically
molds and those that are oxygen loving
aerobic organisms there was about a four
or six percent difference in that ratio
in the plants that showed Perry mildew
and those that did not show powdery
mildew and that pattern continues to be
the most undeniable consistent thing
doesn't matter if you're growing in
Zimbabwe in the ground or in Southern
California in a back bedroom the
relationship between this thing we call
oh my seats and beneficial fungi
determines most of the outcome
um and if your your threshold for
powdery mildew so that's basically how
we use that microscope we're looking for
patterns we're looking for quantities
and there's certain
ranges I guess you could say where good
things happen and there's certain ranges
where all the problems happen and so
that's what we're doing with a
commercial facility if if you've been
growing at a smaller scale and you now
go to this any larger scale sometimes
massive scale
with the most stringent constraints ever
devised for plant cultivation not even
cannabis we're what you and I are doing
in regulated cannabis is the most
stringent production of plants on the
planet right from what I understand
absolutely not even close right and the
most stringent would be GMP weed for the
European market which has even stricter
parameters in California California is
one of the strictest and so when you're
entering that activity
you need to be precise right so
basically what we do is we chop up the
facility do a bunch of biological
assessments
and instead of spraying for powdery
mildew every plant every week we say
zone four is out of whack let's address
zone four everything else is fine so we
basically help people identify where
their vulnerabilities are
um through biological means and then
usually making those slight Corrections
changes most things uh when we first
started really getting into the
commercial markets in late 2016 early
2017 the only thing that I did was
biological assessment and Corrections
because I was not at all about to
profess that I knew what to do in these
600 light rooms you know yeah I had a
great legacy but I'm not going to try
and tell people what to do at that stage
so we only did microscope assessment and
made suggestions now obviously we do
full design and the whole whole
everything but
um at that point all we were doing was
biological assessment and the people
that were respected well known when you
tuned up that biological thing right off
the bat you get 30 to 40 percent more of
everything you'd get 30 to 40 percent
faster growth rates which led to a week
less of vegetative time across the board
you'd get 30 to 40 percent increase in
yield you'd also get 30 to 40 percent
increase in potency all these
combinations would translate to also 30
to 40 percent reduction in cost because
you're not fighting problems you're
making more yield increasing profit
basically
um so you're never going to convince me
that biology is not worth measuring like
it's you know that's that's the main
Drive of what we're doing and so what we
do we've termed at the crash of method
for cultivation simply because we're
doing something different and what we're
doing is
any decision we make if it affects that
biological assessment negatively is out
and it doesn't matter what it is there's
been all kinds of things along the way
that I was like this is going to be a
great idea this is going to work great
we do it those biological numbers go
down or in some other ways sideways it's
out
and and it doesn't matter what it is if
it's popular Trend we put it to the test
numbers go up numbers go down if it goes
down it's out I don't care how popular
it is and that's
and that's why I think the microscope
stuff gets so much resistance because
there's a lot of people trying to push
stuff that's not that helpful
and within 40 minutes of a microscope
assessment you could see if that was
good or bad or you know no no yeah so
that that's basically what we're doing
with the microscope assessment and you
can see everything like my favorite
example is the very first facility that
ever brought us in Colorado's early 2016
they had five benches in a greenhouse
and they had four greenhouses
identically mirrored they'd bring plants
in on a conveyor belt going from right
to left each week they'd bring in new
plants and all four greenhouses the two
outer sides were producing significantly
more than the three inner rows and they
were banging their head against the wall
they're not even from the same
populations they're you know just
whatever it was and so each of these
four greenhouses measurable yield
increase on outside two rows and it got
less as they got towards the center and
the middle row had the least production
regardless of what week it came in or
what Greenhouse it was in it was wild so
my wife and I went in there did about 30
microscope assessments of the farm diced
It Up This Way dice it up this way
remarkable variation in biological
populations from corner to corner from
group to group that were identical in
each greenhouse and basically what was
happening was they would have a batch
tank in the center of each Greenhouse
with a big hose reel and once a week
they would get their predatory nematodes
which are actually bacterial feeding
nematodes which produce growth and they
cycle nitrogen and phosphorus so the HB
nematodes heterabdidus nematodes that we
use for thrips and whatever they're
commonly used there's SF SC and HB the
hb1 actually eats bacteria long story
short increases growth even though you
think you're doing it to control mass
and so they would dump those nematodes
into the tank in the center of the
greenhouse nematodes are heavier than
water they go straight to the bottom the
pump is drying from the bottom so the
heaviest thing goes to the first place
they water so us canvas people like to
do everything the same so they would
walk into Greenhouse one they would
stretch out the hose go up in water in
the far left since the hose is
completely stretched out they go to the
far right over here and water that one
they wheel up the hose a little bit hit
this lane hit this Lane wheel it up a
little bit more hit the center and they
did that every time what ends up
happening is you end up with a billion
nematodes over here a billion nematodes
over here you know a third of a billion
here and none in the center and with
track and Trace data as much as people
want to grown and moan and complain
about it that is extremely efficient
data if you can apply it and for the
first time ever Growers were forced to
get a per plant yield is undeniable it's
not just a mashing of an average light
yield it's this corner is producing more
than this corner right and so one of the
things that we did was use that data and
if you're a commercial cultivator you
should take that track and Trace data
make an overlay of your facility and
place the plant data and the yield and
color code it where it's located in your
building and it will bring up a heat mat
of dysfunction in your facility really
tell you exactly where the problems are
wow and so yeah it's great that's my
favorite thing
um when I because I didn't get asked for
too much stuff until a certain point of
success and then finally someone goes
what do you think we should do and I
said I give my right arm for some
organization of this track and Trace
data that's everybody's complaining
about and they had a computer guy and
he's like well what would you like to
see and I was like put it where it
belongs and color code it and um he was
like all right about a week or so later
he produced two maps one had per four by
four one had per plant and colored it
red yellow and green and green was
basically what it shook down of what
they needed for yield to be profitable
was roughly 60 pounds per thousand
square feet break that down into however
many four by fours you got and then
color code it there's remarkable
patterns that reveal themselves and
that's what we start to investigate so
in this particular facility we hadn't
done that analytics yet but we did the
microscope assessment and every single
Greenhouse had the same pattern
um and so what we did was change their
method for delivering those beneficial
nematodes into a smaller container
little squirt bottle and put them
directly into the beds and then all
yields leveled out so that one single
change which was basically nothing we
didn't change anything except for the
way they're Distributing the nematodes
leads to a 30 increase in yield because
now everything's performing the same wow
so most cultivators are like man they
all say the same stuff doesn't matter if
you're Hydro or living soil big or small
if I could just get another 20 if I
could just get another 30 sometimes if I
get another 40 percent
that that percentage increase that the
cultivator is Desiring
is always in variation so if everything
performed as your good performers you
would find that 20 to 40 percent
increase but cultivators don't know how
to look for that variation right and so
basically what we do is teach you how to
identify that variation and in living
soil it's through microscope assessment
in Hydroponics it's water delivery rates
so what we do in Hydroponics is you get
some one liter pitchers or something and
you go diagonally across your bet your
you know one in this corner one in the
middle one in this corner do that on a
tray do that on the room
and Trigger your irrigation
um I've been in one single facility that
had equal distribution of liquid from
corner to corner one single facility
um that was in some guys from the San
Fernando Valley affiliated with rappers
doing big things
um and they just one of the dudes from
the valley was good at plumbing and he
built a badass system and when he got to
the bigger scale continued building
badass systems most of us cannabis
Growers build atrocious irrigation
systems at scale and so if you're
dumping sometimes 200 300 400 500
percent variation in fertilization to
different plants that variation is where
the bugs start right 100 so the over
watered ones sometimes they get the bugs
the underwater ones sometimes they get
the bugs the ones that are Goldilocks
are fine okay well you need to trim your
irrigation system to get at least
reasonably consistent distribution
that one change will get you that 30
yield because now everything's doing the
same right you got to come by check out
our facility and see what we're doing
because I feel you yeah let's see I feel
like as I said one of three extremely
data driven people I've met in my
journey I'm sure your [ __ ] style you
know so yeah I would love to it's been a
little while here we got we got hit by a
semi truck in February that really shook
our world up and we're still kind of
recovering yeah dude so not really up
for road trips for a minute because the
last last site visit we were doing we
got smoke by a semi truck and a
snowstorm uh so yeah I still still a
little shook up we're getting better
everything will be fine but um I'm still
a couple months out from a road trip but
as soon as I'm ready yeah I would love
to come see what you're doing 100 yeah
yeah
well yeah I really appreciate you coming
on the show today man it's been a good
show it's been very informative uh man I
look forward to having you back again
we'll have to do one in person when you
guys can make it 100 yeah and I'll bring
Sarah with me next time and yeah I'm
just thankful to be around you know I'd
still probably be stuck in Spain if it
wasn't for you I traveled to cannabis in
2020 I didn't even I don't watch TV I
don't watch the news I don't even know
what coronavirus was and you're like
brother you better leave tonight and I'm
like you're tripping I'm like you're
tripping you're like uh you need to go
and I went home checked my hotel sure
[ __ ] our tickets were canceled and I got
one of the last tickets out of that
country I would not I would have been
one of the people stuck so I'm still
eternally grateful for that that was my
honeymoon too so I would have been stuck
in a hostel in Spain or some [ __ ] if it
wasn't for you for my honeymoon so at
least I got to get home and and make
something worth of it but
um yeah dude eternally grateful and I
just I just have a lot of respect for
the way you conduct yourself in this
industry and you know the guys that I
came up with behaved a certain way I'm
not saying they were perfect but there
were certain things that they did that
were non-negotiable and you're one of
like three dudes I've met my journey
Journey that maintains that same ethos
Creed and code and I mean anything I can
do to help your journey you let me know
I don't know if they're even there's
anything I can do but anything I can do
reciprocate you saving me from getting
stuck in Spain you're in a world shut
down I got your back you know and I just
I just have a lot of respect for how you
move through the industry and you know
there's a lot of people especially in
the breeding world to do some kooky
stuff and you know they're not real and
transparent and if I ever have anybody
that needs a bunch of seeds there's one
name I call is James that's it I don't
think there's nobody else you know and
you the few people I've sent your way
have had nothing but good things to say
and I just I appreciate that because my
results a lot of times are dictated by
the genetics if I got bad genetics I can
only do so much with it and if I got a
hemp grower that gets a bunch of hot
Hermie BS that's a problem you know what
I mean and you know I can trust that
your autoflowers are gonna work they're
not going to be some 1992 nonsense like
they're real you know and thank you
people can count on what you're doing
and I'm still I'm still trying to help
the push that auto flowers are real I
got some crazy faces from people when I
recommend autoflowers but I believe it
and I believe that you've put in the
work and I I hope that other people are
able to identify it and recognize that
and I'm sure you're going to be
successful just because the way you move
and there's a reason you're still around
you know so well I feel the same way
about you you you and Sarah do amazing
stuff and you know I think even with
people trying to put down living soil
and saying it doesn't yield you know
there's no way to do it at scale you
guys have always been like no this is
how you do it this is this is what you
everybody should be doing so yeah if
it's for you for sure if not but if not
I could still help you balance the rest
yeah yeah yeah yeah whatever sure
well I appreciate you coming on again
and uh say hi to the wife and I look
forward to having you guys come on the
show again soon
yeah man good talking to you yep cheers
[Music]
foreign