[Music]
how's it going everybody Welcome to the
James loud podcast and today my special
guest is Jason Brooks one of my good
friends from Colorado we've known each
other since about
2013 Denver at the cup we met in line
when I was waiting to get in that's
right yep totally yeah man that's when
uh you're at the peak of your High Times
experiences and yeah I had been a i'
I've been caught up in the chef world
for a long time at that point cannabis
had just become legal in Denver and uh
the medal side of things and uh so yeah
I was really focused on being a chef at
that time but I was still picking up
High Times every once in a while and I
remember seeing you quite a bit in there
yeah yeah walking into the show I was I
kind of got a a little Fanboy I remember
I was like hey dude that's that's James
loud you know like what's up man dude it
was it was a well it was an amazing time
for cannabis in general and then you I
could tell you P about week and you seen
me in high times and I had extra
wristbands and I think we became friends
over that wristband absolutely got you
in the show and then we hung out and
then you invited me to your farm cuz you
were working at a farm too at the time
yeah we had the big um 43,000 foot
underglass in Lafayette Colorado so it
was one acre underglass yeah um pretty
sure was the biggest operation in
Colorado at the time it was it was a
spectacle too and I think a lot of
people had never seen like that was a
big grow back then it was pretty amazing
and impressive and you know I think you
guys struggled in a lot of ways too like
in the beginning whoever you know
starting out there's always struggle in
trying to figure out and navigate how
you do it when you go to scale like that
absolutely the craziest part was we
found that property and um I believe it
they were growing carnations back in the
80s and before they moved the Cut Flower
business down to South America yeah so
we found the property and there was
literally mocking birds nests in the
roofing of the
greenhouse it was completely naked there
was you know no skins on the greenhouse
it had no no heat it had you know
terrible water the soil had been
polluted from the years of chemical
flower production yeah so it was pretty
much everything learning the building
completing the grow you know the
buildout um and this is kind of before
there was just a dude you could pick up
the phone and say hey man I need a
greenhouse you know of course there's
like Farm Tech and guys like that sure
those guys jumped in but like it it
wasn't obvious and it wasn't it wasn't
apparent you didn't jump on the internet
and it wasn't like now like it is now no
you had to you had to really take some
time sit in the office and dig it out
and find that help find the person that
was willing to work with you you know
like even when it came down to testing
genetics we I was running up plants to
CSU and getting chased out of the
University by people that were like get
that cannabis off the property you know
they wouldn't even work with you that
way yeah yeah so what was your first
experience with cannabis my first
experience with cannabis was just like
an after school special man like it
really was um my best friend keep his
name quiet cuz he works for the
government at this point he's got some
kind of secret whatever past stuff he
can't get in trouble with but um I mean
it literally was like that like his
uncle came in town like left some weed
behind you know we went around the side
of the house we smoked a little bowl I
was 15 years old
um it was kind of at the time I was down
in South Florida so a lot of my friends
were starting to experiment with alcohol
and stuff like that and I quickly
realized it was it was pretty apparent
when you were drunk versus you know you
could smoke a little weed and I mean
maybe your eyes got a little red but you
still coherent and you were still with
it depending on how much back the
quality you know it was a little preppy
you know like we started off with some
swaggy stuff but moved quickly into the
[ __ ] but um yeah it went along really
well with my skateboarding and my
surfing and stuff like that so yeah
stuck with it so let's talk about the
crippy your experience with the crippy
so we had mango on here and we've had
some other people from Florida and
crippy was pretty much all the good
stuff stuff right yeah that's yeah that
was it it was kind of a loose ter for
kind bud you know
um most of the time it was homegrown uh
there was some dudes down there that
were really cranking it out like uh yeah
just remember meeting people randomly
like at the beach or something like that
they're like oh you smoke weed and then
invite that guy to the party and that
guy would show up with like an Igloo
cooler full of the same Cola of crippy
like just sea of green crippy and um
yeah it taught me really quick like
flavors everything in cannabis you know
like if you're going to do something
especially highly illegal at the time
yeah it might as well taste good and
make you feel good um yeah so yeah that
was kind of the well and I feel like
it's one of those things if you've never
experienced it you don't know what good
weed tastes like you don't you don't
know what you're missing and then the
second you taste it whether it's at a
young age or whether it's older then you
realize the contrast between everything
else and then the good stuff absolutely
yep and uh I would say like that that
experience in life really paved the road
to me becoming a chef yeah cuz I was
like well Everybody Eats all day long
but are you putting quality in your
mouth you know what what are you doing
right so yeah that it definitely was a
big influence on it has a huge like
working in the kitchen has so much uh as
far as so much in common with cannabis
like those two Fields I feel like
they're both passion driven Fields like
I think a lot of people see the
financial aspect or did in the past of
cannabis but I think also people watch
TV and they're like oh these celebrity
chefs and it's like all glammed out and
that's not the real kitchen you know
that's not the real world is you know
it's like but there is like like uh
water boys and dishwashers have a lot in
common you know it's like absolutely um
and I think it's valuable to learn all
those things together it's amazing um
how many similarities there are and then
pallet wise too like I feel like that's
where I develop I develop my pette from
both you know I feel I feel most of us
that worked in the kitchen it's like
it's all from collecting data points
right so like the more data points you
have over time the more developed your
pallet is and the more things you
experience you you figure out what you
like what you don't like and then at a
certain point you can figure out what
other people like too I feel like that's
one of the things uh that makes cooking
special too it's not always about what
you like but but understanding what
everybody likes or what most people
would like going in there what they
would be impressed with or or you know
add to the experience because at the end
of the day it's all about an experience
yeah absolutely I mean um for a
restaurant to be successful there has to
be some form of a Mass Appeal you know
something's got to hit and right
resonate with everyone and I think
that's where you get certain strains of
cannabis that become legendary for a
long time you know like the cppy down in
the South uh Blue Dream out here in Cali
you know like those things hit and they
resonated for a long time well the
crippy somehow turned into OG Kush right
right but it was cppy was kind of
encompassing but then it emerged as the
OG Kush cut that we know today is OG
Kush which is like that earthy piny gas
totally yeah I think that that was um
you know the successful growers in
Florida that were able to attract some a
little bit of gravits and attention and
you know they got the the West Coast
people paying attention and um they were
able to come out here and make OG like a
California thing you know like I I I
don't think of OG is or like crippy is
Florida but OG is California absolutely
yeah thanks to St talk Ricky Palamino
cypr Hill Cypress Hill all those guys
yeah for sure yeah so yeah and those
guys were pushing the envelope public
you know it's it's pretty impressive
absolutely yeah the cool thing about
cannabis for me man is it just um I mean
it's brought my best friends into my
life um it brought my wife into my life
um you know I was running around Athens
Georgia for a little while in the 90s um
we were definitely we were selling swag
to buy good bud you know yeah and um we
actually got to a point where we make
enough money that we we rented Bon Joy's
tour bus and his driver to take us down
to the Dead shows oh wow Athens to
Atlanta in 95 and um that's where I met
my wife Man On A Grateful Dead lot you
know like I was like hey you want to get
on the bus and come check it out and she
got on the bus and never got off you
know so yeah yeah and that was in mid
90s 9 April or March 31st 95 wow awesome
yeah yeah that's great yeah it's cool
it's it's funny how the Grateful Dead
has so much influence over or not not
even influence but impact on the
industry I think the Cannabis industry
wouldn't be what the cannabis industry
is without the impact from the Grateful
Dead and there so many of us have
stories that revolve around either the
lot or around the genetics that came
from there absolutely you know it's it's
pretty yeah like in in Athens you know
like as soon as the kids left town after
school got out um typically there was a
huge drought all through the summer yeah
and that's where like summer tours of
the Grateful Dead coming through would
absolutely save the summer you know like
you'd load up on your glass you load up
on your mushrooms you load up on your
you know your jars of weed and totally
try to make it through you know pinch it
pinch it through till till everything
came back around in the spring you know
right but that's yeah why I started
growing is because I I was like why what
this is a plant why are we running out
of it you know if we can just grow it
let's grow it so when did you start
growing um let's see my first plants
were in high school uh 1994 um there was
a window in my basement I planted a
bunch of plants in my window and I
actually went away on a little trip I
came back home and all my plants are
sitting on the kitchen table and my my
parents were basically like uh you know
you said this was basil
and I have a really cool uncle and he he
was like that's that's not basil you
know so he blew it he blew uh he blew my
cover but it all worked out well because
I was able to you know I graduated from
high school and then went up the road to
Athens um the the first plant I was
gifted was a mother plant of big bud in
1996 oh wow it was huge this thing had
been topped forever I mean it probably
had 50 Tops on it when I got it it
showed up in one of the big old school
TV boxes you remember used to
be now they're flat but it took up the
whole thing and um one of my good
buddies is like we need a grow light and
you know back then you couldn't just go
to the grow store so or you had to go to
the electrical shop and build one and
that was outside of my realm of
knowledge right so we stole one from my
Community College you know it's like a
400 watt HPS or something like that you
know when the light was on also like you
know like could have lost a good friend
in that process but we didn't and yeah
that thing went into a closet and um
what doesn't kill you right only only
makes a career right but yeah man so
that was the first PL it was pretty good
you know I mean it was 90s big bud so
yeah it was impressive the the smoke
wasn't all that great but and then I got
into you know it still Georgia in the
90s um so a lot of penalties be paid if
you got caught yeah so uh mostly Gorilla
growing and stuff like that um I
remember yeah I remember my dad sitting
down at the kitchen table and being like
I don't know whose plants those were in
the woods but they just had crop failure
you like like trying not to react at the
dinner table you know oh man yeah but um
yeah man I grew all the way so yeah the
Athens thing went good for a while till
it didn't we actually had um some we had
a federal thing happen and one of my
buddies a really my kind of my best
friend at the time started wearing a
wire and actually yeah it was it was it
was a weird time everybody's houses
started getting kicked in and um we
didn't know what was going on you know
but it was kind of strange my best
friend at the time like the guy that had
all the weed and the best weed all of a
sudden didn't have any weed you know and
he was asking us for weed and things
just got weird you know yeah but um one
by one they all got in trouble and um I
think I don't really know exactly cuz I
never talked to I didn't ever talk to
any officers about it yeah but I guess I
was so low on the totem pole you know I
think they had who they wanted yeah so
they usually go for the big fish yeah
you know that's kind of especially back
then it's like get them you know hit
them hard yeah I mean they hit people
hard they hit people hard man yeah a lot
of my friends uh you know like their
parents had to put their houses up to
keep their kids out of jail and you know
like just stuff like that and oh yeah
they' seize property too SE property
yeah so uh asset forfeiture sucks it's
you know I mean this the whole the the
road has been so weird but um that's
what sent me to culinary school you know
I was like I got to learn a trade I need
to get out of this and get into
something else and yeah so I went to the
Art Institute of Atlanta and learned to
become a chef and nice yeah and then did
that for a while did that forever man
and I was drinking the Kool-Aid man I
was like not doing anything else besides
being a chef the beauty of being a chef
is you you're a chef forever you learn
how once you learn how to cook
it just changes your life it's just like
learning how to grow though it's I feel
like absolutely you once you understand
the plant once you understand the
kitchen and there's a formula to it and
everybody makes their own formula up as
you go along you learn things and you
pick up things from different cultures
but you understand how Food Works
together and that's it's an amazing
thing to be able to just kind of create
and and there's there's an artistic side
to it too absolutely yeah I think it's
cool like you know culinary school gives
you the the intros and the hows and the
wise and then once you learn that it's
it's kind of like all cuisine's pretty
much the same you just have a different
set of ingredients to work with and you
know um yeah same with canab was same
with growing you know like I I KN I I
instantly realized like I didn't want to
work at at chilies I didn't want to cook
something out of a bag and pour it in
and call that soup of the day like that
wasn't me and that that approach worked
for me in cannabis too I was like I'm
not a hydro guy like I don't want to
take part a Part B and then throw in
some C and then call it my creation you
know I don't think that's no shame on
anybody doing it you know it's just not
me I like to like oh I made this input
and I put that input on to ground up
both ways yeah yeah when it reflects in
your flour too like at the end of the
day yeah you got some good flour you I
love I love smoking every time I go to
Colorado that's one of the places I look
forward to going to is to I always love
to see you show up man and show you what
I've been working with for sure but you
know it was that big flood we had in
Colorado when I was running that
Greenhouse we had a huge flood come
through and I believe it was I think
it's 10 years ago September um yeah but
it literally cut my town in half you
know like we had to drive all the way
around just to get to town but my
Greenhouse I remember waking up at 4
o'clock in the morning and turning on
the news and seeing that Lafayette was
underwater and I jumped in my truck at 5
o'clock in the morning and drove to that
greenhouse and every it was like an
episode of Ghost Hunters like the trash
cans floating across the room you know
it's just the kitty cat that we had
Durban was all the way in the rafters
like he was hiding out and but because
of that it locked up the ground so bad
and we were in the ground organic or
trying to be as organic as possible yeah
um but we couldn't grow anything like we
were getting every kind of anything you
could imagine like if it was fungal
based it was in the soil I mean it was
just anything just a nightmare to deal
with it was almost like a bad Bugs Bunny
cartoon like when the little all the
carrots start disappearing you know
going down the road right we'd water a
plant and it would die we'd water a
plant and it would die and I so we had
two or three Growers at the time and we
all kind of you know we headbutting a
little bit on things but um every time
we put chemicals into the soil it was
worse like salt-based stuff just would
kill things so that's when um I got to
know Brian from vital um absolutely yeah
like Carl Gorka from photosynthesis plus
micro life like yeah I started reaching
out to all these organic guys and I was
like Hey like how do how do we stop this
you know and um Brian's answer was
compost he you know and I was like okay
you know I'm with that I brought in a
master horticulturist he was like
compost tea I was like okay all right
now we're getting somewhere so we
started bringing in better supplies we
couldn't water anything because as soon
as water hit the ground it locked up
everything wow um so we started folar
feeding compost teas and we turned that
grow around I mean it took we still got
a crop in I if I remember correctly I
think I watered the crop one time in 90
days and everything else was Fuller and
dude we had Jurassic leav on these
plants and I'm like
okay I'm starting to see the connection
here you know and so yeah through the
Organics you know I learned about
probiotics which brought me to Alan
ainson and
gashi um using his products and then
watching everything change watching the
soil change watching the composition of
the soil change watching the pH of the
soil change right and like yeah uh I
guess my point is like feeding cannabis
in that situation taught me how to feed
myself you know I was like why am I not
drinking coconut water why do I not take
aloe you know like why do I not eat
probiotics totally and I was I was just
coming out of my chef you know career
which they tell you in culinary school
like fat is Flavor you know like anytime
you can throw more butter in there hit
it with some cream you know like it I
don't believe Fat's the problem just
personally I think I mean you know I do
love I I do love it and I think it's a
good energy I think the problem right
now today with people's eating is that
they're eating processed foods totally
you know I mean I think Butter's okay in
my opinion Butter's okay I think
exercise and eating raw ingredients is
the most important thing I think so too
and yeah yeah like and now I understand
like through like fermented products you
know like your kimch and your kombuchas
and your sauerkraut it's like totally
now we're looking at knf right and it's
like these guys are just fermenting
things and micronizing those things and
applying them straight to the plant the
plant's eating itself or the plant's
eating whatever it wants to eat right
when we're we're doing that eating the
fermented stuff everything's micronized
for us it's easier for our bodies to
uptake you know it's good for our body
pH yeah it's very similar you know um I
actually just read an article about how
similar the root system is in soil
versus our gut system in our
microbiota and um one of the cool
takeaways from the article was you know
like if people have um like surgeries
and stuff like that and their their
probiotics completely shut down you know
like and they're basically of like
diarrhea and dentary AAL transplant that
you can do you know where you actually
take
somebody's it doesn't sound like what it
is you're basically eating a pill right
it's eating a pill but it I have uler of
colitis so I know all about these things
there you go yeah that's why I do coal
plch there you go so but I read in this
article that a compost tea is just like
doing a feal transplant for the soil
which totally made sense to me you know
I was like okay so yeah it's just like
when things aren't right you take what
is right and apply it in and then yeah
let the symbiotic process occur you know
yeah yeah it's cool totally yeah yeah
it's a trip and we're starting to learn
so much more science about like uh GI
issues and also about cannabis all at
the same time science is just kind of
there's a lot of stuff we knew but we're
learning a lot of stuff you know I think
you know especially about eating things
that aren't sprayed with pesticides dude
totally and when I was saying like fat
is Flavor like there's a big difference
between like grass-fed beef butter you
know like grass butter or
whirl you know like we like I worked
place like grab the Whirl and put it on
the green beans you're like what the
[ __ ] is whirl you know like and it's
just some crazy oil some hydrogenated
hydrogenated oil that tastes like butter
you know like it's made for a buffet so
your butter your butter never breaks you
know it's cheap butter it's cheap butter
but that's kind of that's kind of stuff
that I was looking at and it's the spice
of butter it is yes like how [ __ ] is to
cannabis right right exactly yeah yeah
yeah trip but yeah man so it became like
I realized quickly the best way to raise
and if you can I know it's not for
everybody but the best way to over
raisee cannabis in my book is to feed it
organically yeah and you know I just I
mean I do shop at Whole Foods I eat
mostly organic food I strictly organ
paycheck yeah whole paycheck exactly
yeah they freaking out the other day
when you can check out with your palm
now have you seen that I know it's
really weird I'm like I think I'll skip
that Tech but I appreciate your celery
juice you know yeah blood
sample no big deal finger prick you know
right right but yeah it's it's
interesting and how how these things
relate and there's so much crossover
totally you know in life and then with
your family and then you're raising your
kid on these things and absolutely yeah
absolutely I know I know my wife thinks
I'm crazy because I'm always you know
like if I'm cook rice then I'm shaking
it in rice water and I'm making my own
Labs you know there's always a project
on my counter like right now I know
there's there's a huge thing of garlic
fermenting and honey on the counter um
but no it does become a lifestyle and I
think you're right the problem that's
going on right now is you know we're
sending our kids off to school with
heads full of sugar and artificial
colors and you know and then they can't
concentrate at school and then it's your
kid's fault you know and then you get
mad at the teacher for not engaging your
kid and it's
like no like feed your kid Whole Foods
and you teach your kid how to grow you
know I think that's what's really cool
like stop the disconnect your kids how
to grow you know I think also like if
you're a meat eater I don't vegetarian
whatever that's fine but like if you eat
meat you should understand the process
of how animals come to end up on your
plate absolutely I I love the whole
process of all that stuff I do and
understanding but I mean all these
things are Lost Art absolutely yeah I
would love since I'm in Colorado I'd
love to um Embrace more hunting and
stuff like that and always have like a
full freezer of some good elk and stuff
to go to yeah Elk's my favorite Elk's my
favorite so I I like a lot of different
kinds of meat I like bear bear jerky too
Bear's great I shot a big old bear and
we made some stew out of it it was it
was interesting it works and bear can
vary so much from animal to animal yeah
oh yeah yeah it's kind of what they're
eating on and stuff like that you can
get the trash bear out of PR much all
animals totally yeah but no yeah it's I
mean cannabis has taught me how to feed
myself completely and yeah there's
really not much difference between like
the amount of salt we can take you know
you well and salt and and what we think
of as salt like for us it's like there's
different types of salt too it's like
you know there's table salt which is
very linear and then there's sea salt
right which is very complex right it's
and then there's all the components also
like magnesiums and all those other
things and like they all in those plants
I mean we know like growing cannabis is
all about your micronutrients you know
and same same like that's gotten me
every morning taking a little Celtic Sea
salt and dropping it under my tongue and
getting all you know getting all my good
vitamins in that way right so again I
mean she's she's the one man she's the
goddess she's like the number one woman
of the world you know what I mean like I
personally think it's really hard to
wrap around my head that like an orange
could taste like cannabis or a cannabis
can taste like orange but a cannabis can
also taste like any other thing like
like Green Dot Dave's got the A5 wagu
out right now yeah if you haven't tried
that I mean it's a greasy meaty it's an
experience you know I've had some uh
fried chicken turps before Fried Chicken
turps for sure like that lemon G um that
lemon g i I don't know if I got the
lemon G from you I got it from someone
in Colorado but that lemon G is fire
it's so fire but it's also got like a
funky Fried Chicken Gas Station like
bathroom in a Alabama gas station where
they fry their own chicken tur like
you're back there borderline offensive
yeah yeah and it really comes through in
the concentrate too like I love you love
borderline offensive too though yeah you
you grow a lot of borderline offensive
weed your GMOs and your chems the 91
chem dog you you uh that that was one of
the best Expressions I've ever had of
chem do thank you was what I smoked the
Yer well you know man um my Rhino gig
led me to hang out at Elite cannabis
they kind of brought me in as a
consultant because they were moving into
the hemp fields and so we needed a
little you know I wanted to help them
with a little bit more production stuff
and um dude that was that was the most
loaded bench of Growers I've ever gotten
to hang out with we had yeah grah from
crickets inada we had Duke diamond we
had Jamie who's famous for the headband
we had a dude named Jack love Matt for I
um daon villan which I mean he's a
gangster himself I don't know if you
kept like paying attention it like
pained guitars and stuff he's doing now
nice the dude got to go on Slayer World
Tour the last tour wow as their weed
Tech like taking all the weed that we
grew around the world with Slayer that's
funny it's badass and then yeah somehow
he became Carrie King's guitar tech like
through the tour yeah that's wild but
yeah man we I mean this this group of
Growers that I got to hang out with
every
morning uh I mean we started work at
7:00 which meant smoking OG at like 7:15
and drinking coffee and then we would
leave the table at like
10:30 higher coffee is the balance
though higher than giraffe [ __ ] you
know what I mean just like way up there
and then like okay let's get to work and
it's like uh let's get to lunch you know
right but the the the information that I
gathered from all those guys and you
know this is still this is a couple
years back so it's like a lot of Bro
Science still you know but sure just the
EXP pushing to figure it out so we can
we could get to the where we where we
are today you know I mean I feel like it
takes a lot of trial and a a lot of
people don't understand because we're
standing on the shoulders of giants and
these are such big giants that we don't
even really see the work that they've
done necessarily yep but like the work's
been going on for 40 50 years really and
then even 2,000 years in the making but
we're standing on the shoulders of some
amazing Giants and there's a lot of
trial and error to get to where we are
today to get funneled into gelato
you're right dude you're right I just
grew some outdoor runs this year in
Colorado and I was like see why it's got
you know I see why it's got its good
reputation it's delicious but I totally
love the appeal of some of this stuff
and I totally love the flavor but I also
love diversity and I think that comes
from the chef background too absolutely
yeah I I yeah cannabis is not just like
sitting around getting stoned for me you
know it's like okay what's going to
start my day get my get my processes
going you know get my whether it's get
my exercise in get the dog out for a
walk like just make a list you know
whatever it is and then there's like the
midday stuff and then like once I'm done
working like I'm 47 now man my body
hurts you know so I'm ready to like feel
smoke some of that dog walker or
something like that that's just going to
put me in the couch and put me you know
in a good space getting ready to gets
you to relax at least I feel like
stimulants are good in the daytime the
sedative stuff at night sure but I I
have like things like OG Kush where I
can smoke them day or night Skittles
another one I smoke it in the morning I
smoke it at night yep uh it's it's
interesting and I'm constantly changing
when I'm smoking and probably smoking
whatever the best [ __ ] I have is what I
smoke first yep y totally yeah um I
think I you know I have built up a
tolerance for all the Kims and all the
ogs so I can still function but I I
personally like to be a little scared
when I'm done smoking weed like there's
something about it it just I don't know
it like brings me Clos yeah it brings me
more I'm more attentive actually to like
everything around me Hyper sensitive
almost but yeah um not in a bad way not
in a paranoid way but just you know like
no but where you can be comfortable in
that borderline place like that's kind
of how mushrooms work too yeah like once
you get like At first it's like it can
be borderline like not micro do I'm not
talking about micro do but I'm talking
about like a real dose like we do grew
up doing and I think right uh now
everyone's on the micro do kick but like
technically you get the most benefit
from doing the larger uh doses of
mushrooms and it is borderline scary and
then once you learn that how to relax
then you can really appreciate um
everything it has to offer yep yeah
mushrooms are amazing like that um I
last time I had one of those trips was
about a year and a half ago and it was
3.5 grams of this Brazilian strain that
my buddy grows and instead of lemon Tech
I did grapefruit Tech you know i' heard
I'm like okay heard is works better
whatever yeah so I made this little
grapefruit thingy and um it was 3.5
grams and then I blended it into this
tiny little grapefruit margarita it was
like a little tiny tequila and a little
tiny grandma yeah it I mean it was a
shot yeah and I shot that thing down and
by the time I could clean the blender I
was having like DMT visuals like I don't
know what was going on but yeah it hit
me so hard it was the strongest trip and
I was thinking back I'm like there's no
way I could be in a public setting right
now I mean I felt like I was DNA going
through somebody's like Bloods
[Music]
like but yeah man it was awesome and
yeah but I do micro do a lot I do micro
do like five times or five days a week
try to take couple days off I think you
were the first person to get me on micro
dois to be honest you gave me some pills
in Denver one time that had a whole
bunch of different mushrooms including
the 15 mushroom blend yeah it was like
the 15 mushroom blend and those were
like real micros too and they were like
you weren't taking them to get high you
were taking them for the mushroom
benefit absolutely yeah man y yeah I
think you know like everybody's got
their traumas and stuff like that and
you know the more I learn about the
brain and like uh concussion and stuff
like that like how I mean I I did surf I
skateboarded I played a little bit of
football you know like yeah I've taken
and I fought I used to be a fighter you
know so I've taken some shots and um now
yeah now that I'm in my 40s I'm like
okay we got to protect this noodle you
know because I'm looking at the next 40
and I don't want to be you know useless
as far as my brain or my my vocabulary
and stuff like that so yeah I I do I
spend a lot of time um trying to rebuild
those things and I think that's the way
to do it yeah I talk talk about cold
plunge a lot I'm a huge cold plunge fan
and I I do these longer plunges now
which is like goes goes against a lot of
stuff you read but I feel like you got
to listen to your body and give your
body what it wants and you know I do
days where I do 15 minute plunges now oh
my God and so well Joe Rogan did like 20
and then Rick Rubin he did like a 30 he
says he did a 30 but I saw Joe Rogan's
20 minute plunge and so I realized that
anything's possible you just listen to
your body and if it's too much like as
you're building it up you don't go past
that didn't go past 5 minutes for the
longest time I think three 3 minutes and
30 seconds has been about it depends on
the temperature too so I get a little
warmer temperature so I can go for
longer but you get in more of like a
meditating type meditative State like
you I feel like it's in a you're in a
different state of mind especially with
the cold like then you start breathing
through it and relaxing you're in the
moment too because you're cold yeah the
the yeah for me the very first initial
plunge is it's pretty ugly you know I'm
like not in control of my vote I'm
you know like yeah yeah it it I do I do
it every day now too so I do it every
day first thing in the morning right
when I get out of bed so I'm not really
thinking about it and then you're hot
from sleeping so then when you get in
it's almost like going in the SAA that's
cool but I need to get one for my house
um you know I live in Colorado so cold
plunge can literally be just run outside
the in the snow literally at this time
of year you could probably just put a
trough out yeah exactly yeah yeah like a
baby pool and just go crack the ice and
jump in there but I you know I was
thinking like this has been theast
couple years have been the year of the
cold plunges so yeah I was like oh maybe
I'll just wait and see what pops up on
Craigslist and snack ABS you can I mean
you can buy the $10,000 ones on the
Internet or you know the Morosco which I
think is badass it's $10,000 but then
you can make one for $2,000 it works
just fine um you know and if you're in a
cold enough region I just I'm so worried
about balancing out everything like
chemical wise because you can if you
don't do it right you can get bacteria
infections and die yeah that's the other
thing you know I'd worry about kind of
doing it by yourself s or like fainting
you know from like holding your breath
or not you know well okay so this is the
thing I the first when I first started
doing it I'm like what if I have a heart
attack that was kind of like going
through my head the first time I did it
I used to dump H ice and I did it we had
a jacuzzi tub and I go in the jacuzzi
tub and it was super cold but after a
week you start realizing like I even not
doing it every day you start realizing
that you're fine and now even at the
cold temperatures I can go in them and I
don't feel like I'm going to faint like
you feel a little lightheaded at first
but like it's all about breathing and
knowing that you're safe I think that's
the doing it regularly you develop that
too where you realize that you're safe
even if you're going extreme yeah it
really is amazing the power of breath in
your brain and like if you can if you
connect those too uh my yoga teacher
back in Colorado you know she's like
watch how fast your heart changes when
you focus on your breathing you know and
like or just how like how your shoulders
settle you know and everything your face
is tight you relax your face all those
things like all of a sudden you realize
your tongue's not pressing against the
top of your throat all the time you know
like relax when time really slows down
when you're doing co- plunging my my day
goes by like this I mean it seems like I
wake up and I'm doing all these things
and the next thing you know is the next
day that's awesome and I think part of
that getting older but also we can look
at life in perspective but that that
small amount of time in the morning
whether it's five or 10 or 15 minutes
it's not 15 minutes every day but I've
been doing like building up to the 15
minutes very impressive man like that's
a lot um but yeah so like it really
slows life down and then I don't drink
coffee first thing in the morning either
I feel like gives me what I need to wake
up and be I'll drink coffee in the
afternoon or if I smoke a bunch of weed
and then I'm like I feel a little tired
I'll yeah coffee is the balance I love
coffee I love the way it makes me
feeling coffee and cannabis I feel like
those two are meant to go together like
one chefs and coffee working as a
chef yeah I mean we're working long
hours like coffee is just part of the
job and then with cannabis it kind of
balances it used to be with drinking and
being a chef you know now it's like
growing weed and making seeds and
everything and then like smoking weed
all day you gotta have the coffee to
kind of balance it yeah for sure I have
appreciated getting older and not having
such a like crazy head esteem you know
like when you're younger it's just like
all right dude put your head down and
plow through everything and right um
yeah getting older is definitely like
okay like separating things and taking
time to listen to your body and heal
your body and yeah um you know some it's
it's not all go go go these days you
know I gotta have some downtime yeah
well it's funny because there's there's
different ways of doing stuff in life
and I feel like part of the chef
mentality is uh because you're you're
working so fast and everything's you're
only as good as your last plate to a
degree absolutely right so like you have
to make snap decisions and you have to
be right the first time every time yep
right and and the thing is is like yeah
you make mistakes and you learn from
your mistakes but eventually like in the
restaurant because it's repetition time
and time again you learn how to navigate
through those so like you can correct
mistakes where you almost make mistake
and you correct it right I mean there's
nights on the line where you're cooking
too where it's like everything's almost
falling apart literally almost falling
apart and you feel like you're failing
the whole time but you pull it off
nobody else
knows years exactly it's you know and
the papers D like your [ __ ] tickets
just keeps stacking up I think those
experiences in the kitchen yeah made
every day in the grow that much easier
you know because I'm like you're not
going to burn yourself you're not gonna
you might cut yourself but it's going to
be a little Nick of some scissors or
something but to deal with all those
like you just said all those problems
and all those things that arose all the
time and having to put out the fire
pivot put out the fire pivot replace it
that yeah well yeah I mean those are
those are the the things that define you
to a degree and like me mentally also
prepare you you know those type of
moments it's like they really prepare
you for other things in life and you
realize how small some of the things
that we worry about so much are too and
it's like that that phrase this two
Shall Pass right like this two shall the
hard times and the good times absolutely
it's like you know and no matter how bad
it seems like it is it's like you're
going to pass into something else
eventually no matter what and so
breathing getting through those moments
you know it's like I don't know how many
times over the last 10 years it's like
seemed like it was just tough and it was
gonna [ __ ] everything was you know at at
the lows but then your lows become highs
and then your highs then become lows ex
somewhere in between and yeah you know
at the end of the day you just have to
put one foot in front of the other and
uh you know there there's days where you
just got to get up and suck it up and
you know you don't just get to stay in
bed you just get up and you you power
through yeah yeah um I had one I was
growing you know you you've been out to
the hemp Farm um there was we were
getting ready for one season and man I
think starting in like November December
I started all the plants I had these
plants perfect like the best looking
mothers completely organic nothing going
on with them as far as bugs which no
bugs in a greenhouse in Colorado is
pretty easy you know because everything
outside's dead yeah but um we got into
the cloning and first set of cloning
went great we needed to cut I think it
was 125,000 clones to populate the field
um first 25,000 went fine the next
100,000 clones uh we would cut them they
would look perfect we'd walk in the
greenhouse and these things were folded
over within 24 hours and nobody knew
what was going on you know we some
people oh too much airf flow too much
humidity you know there all these
opinions but no it was it was some kind
of pathogen that was inside that
Greenhouse that was just jumping in
there and knocking these things out and
um we didn't even talk about pathogens
back then I know that was just it you
know you're like what is it is it
pythium is it you know we don't know
again we're bro scientists at this point
you you know just trying to figure it
out and but you're right like getting up
every morning to go check that
Greenhouse 24 hours after I cut those
clones like I didn't even I couldn't
even drink coffee I was so stressed out
I mean sweat would be pouring out of my
hands on the steering wheel and then
just a whip open that Greenhouse door
and see them all folded over yeah you
know I was like okay like pull in the
Bobcat throw all these in the bucket
bucket goes to compost file you know and
like fo in front of the next do it again
yep yeah and C cutting that many clones
that I mean that's like being on the
Viking ship and somebody's just like
boom yeah boom you know you just got to
keep going you got to keep going so how
did you go from being a chef to
transition and doing it scale when we
met you you were at scale you've been
working at scale with Farmers hemp
Farmers growing you know massive amounts
of acres for hemp and huge green houses
how did you go from being a homeg grower
and a chef to get into that so the
little bit of medical time um as soon as
medical popped off a buddy of mine I was
living on an 80 Acre Farm in Colorado um
we decided to push the envelopes a
little bit we built four big green
houses um I was basically going off of
what I had seen in Greenhouse production
in in California like through High Times
or what you know I kind of was like okay
these plants need to be big they need to
fill out the space but we still got to
have some air flow whatever so I had um
I think it was two seasons under my belt
Colorado outdoor and these big green
houses and that's when all the the
venture capitalist and all that started
to come to Colorado yeah um so yeah a
bunch of dudes are coming in town with a
bunch of money
and this one guy had walked through my
Greenhouse with an iPad and you know
taken a bunch of pictures or whatever
and um he showed it to one of these guys
and this guy showed up and he's like
you're hired you know you're fired you
know like this whole it was crazy wow
and I was like well what are we doing
he's like I want you to look at this
property and he showed me this property
and he's like we got to rebuild this
thing and I want you to do it exact like
you did it over there and so yeah man I
went from four green houses that were
like I don't know 312s to 43,000 square
feet you know that's crazy I think what
it is is like it's just like being a
chef you know it's like it really
doesn't matter if you're cooking one
cover or if you're cooking a thousand
covers you just got to prepare for it
you know and and yeah just see it all
the little stuff first all the way out
to the big picture and that's you know I
um I didn't have any staff at the time
so I went to the local skate park I I I
love skateboarders are my dudes like if
I'm going to hire anybody they're either
going to be a wrestler from high school
or a skateboarder cuz those two people
are some of the most driven people that
you could ever imagine you know like to
be able to ride a skateboard on a ramp
or in a park and to fall down repeatedly
exactly do it over and over it over and
over get back up and think about what
you did wrong and do it again fall down
seven stay up eight yep shout out to
little Jason Henderson little Jay I was
Big Jay he was little Jay that guy
followed me you know helped me out a ton
at that place and went to Washington
with me and yeah yeah man he was a guy
that could like he knew vegetation and
cloning like just like that was just in
his blood you know yeah it's funny those
life lessons that you can apply to
cannabis too it's like you and not even
cannabis but doing everything it kind of
all follows suit like if you want to be
good at something doesn't matter whether
it's growing or or breeding or whatever
it's like you want to play the guitar
you want to learn how to do this or that
you w to you know you got to fail a
bunch along the way to really learn how
to do it properly or to be really good
at it yep yeah it's it's very much using
your eyes you know it's using your brain
and using your eyes and uh looking at
things and yeah you should be able to
read a plant just by looking at it you
know like what's going on with that
plant like is it are the stems green all
the way through or does it have any
little purple streaks going through it
like oh looks like you missed out on
some night right there dude you know
like just being yeah just being able to
read those plants like that and read it
from afar and well in repetition over
and over and over and learning how to do
it your own way yep and and you know all
these cultivars they're all just like
anybody else in your life you know like
you know certain things about them it's
like okay like that Afghan or that hash
plant you know like she likes to be a
little bit wider and a little bit lomer
soil she doesn't like all that water she
doesn't like dense soil you know um OG
ge's as little of water as possible but
as often as possible you know with a ton
of calcium and magnesium to help things
move around in that little spaghetti
like stem you know like it's just yeah
they all have their nuances and OG you
don't je like my favorite stuff but dude
yeah it's just like come on girl like
stand up straight um yeah it's just yeah
it's getting to know them all and um and
how they work for you you know and I
think like that's what we saw like
especially in Colorado um you know like
it's really hard to find a dispensary
that's got like pre98 Bubba Kush now
because like the pl there's a whole
bigger oh it fit into the I mean it
finished early there was definitely
benefits but the pre-98 isn't really
what you see today you see a Bubba cush
that the one that finishes in like 50
days I think I think that's Burgers
right I'm pretty sure um yeah yeah that
was just it you know like it it was a
little bit longer to clone so it kind of
screwed up your twoe routine and your
and your clone there and then as opposed
to having it ready for the feel in 21
days it might need 35 so then it screwed
up your time and veg and then you know
you got this huge canopy I mean you saw
it had 14 foot 14 foot wide blue dreams
or whatever you know Super Lemon hazes
yeah then you got this little Fu dream
or this little bubba cush you know
hanging out and you know investors are
walking by they're like what's wrong
with that one yeah you're like
absolutely nothing it just doesn't look
like that one you know right well
California we had the mids Market was
filled with Bubba and they grew it at
scale like you wouldn't believe yeah um
so but then that's kind of transitioned
into the runs gelato Lemon Cherry gelato
runs yeah you know gelato all the
different gelato 33 41s you guys it's
crazy because I'm you know in Colorado
I'm always about 2 and a half years
behind what you guys are up to like it
takes that long for us to actually get
our hands on it typically unless you
know you got the plug over here that's
eventually it's GNA come back all the
way
around yeah I think it's I think it's
fun to watch new markets open up because
that's when you find some of these trins
that we considered gone you know it's
like well some dude in Oklahoma's had it
in his closet for 20 years just talking
to Crockett we were talking about Green
Crack I like green crack yeah I really
like green crack now it doesn't
necessarily fit into
the commercially popular varieties of
cannabis that we're enjoying today on
the the wreck Market but it could make
it comeb back but either way I like the
I like some of the traits I like the
effect especially um you know the the
effect where it just hits you hard but
then you build a tolerance to it yeah
it's a fun one to grow and it's quick
you know like I mean it's it's
definitely like it's a userfriendly
plant pretty much from A to Z like um
yeah definitely has a spot to be
appreciated totally so with food you
kind of I think one of the biggest
things is you build this foundation and
you learn how to make a dish and then
make your own twist to it as a chef
right so like if you're coming in
whereas with breeding it's like a
different thought process but you've
been getting into breeding too over the
last year how's that going it's good um
I look at it more of like a part of me
wants to be a preservation breeder you
know and increase what's already I I
would hate for something to go away just
because people lost interest in it you
know I'm I'm old enough to know that
like one day jenos are going to come
back you know what I mean like all these
oh jenos are like $400 a pair on eBay
like I saw somebody wearing doc Marts
the other day I'm like wow that reminds
me of 1994 in high school you know punk
rock scene which is even older than that
but yeah I think it all um it all comes
back around so what I was first
concerned about um I wanted to I want to
push as many canabo into a plant as I
could yeah and that was kind of coming
from the Hempfield to the lab um because
it used to be kind of a pain in the ass
to be like oh well I've got this CBG
strain here that's this section of the
field I've got this CBC over here this
is CBD yeah this is all my
vas and I would have to you know batch
them for the lab to figure it out versus
knowing what happens in the lab and the
fact that they can just spill over
whatever they want to spill over and and
grab it right so I started working on a
project I called it the Noid it dates me
from the old Domino's commercials you
know like avoid the Noid uh so just the
canabo plant and I really wanted to just
push as much as I could into that and I
wasn't really you were looking for the
most amount of diversity or complexity
as POS as you could possibly push into a
plant yep and what I ended up with I
mean this thing is nasty like she is uh
loaded with d g lot lots of c um but
she's stinky she is very much like a
Hindu Kush um so then I took that and I
put it into other things like Puck you
know like old more hash plans just yeah
just to kind of go B BX on that and
because because the fact like that that
puck was that's one of the hardest
plants I've ever had to hang on to like
she is so finicky and yeah um so yeah
kind of do an increase on that and
then I also wanted to do for the hemp
Farmers I wanted to do you know triple
crop was becoming a big thing um you
know to get your seed um your fiber and
your canabo all in one plant the perfect
plant yeah so I was trying to go for
something that was like 14 feet tall you
know with like no offshoots at all and
then I was packing on like about a foot
foot and a half tall Cola on the top
that's just load to with seeds so
basically breeding the interex traits
into it and having the complete yeah yep
yeah because I was realizing you know as
modern well hemp farming in Europe you
know they take the tops off the plant
grab everything they want there and then
they let it you know basically sit in
the field for a little bit longer and
that outter it'll decorticate itself
really It'll like take the just sheath
off you know yeah so then you got that
pure fiber down below it so I was trying
to go for that where I was like okay
Harvest your canabo and your food
products first and then come back and
get your fiber content
last but yeah now I'm like I don't know
I I I I love like all this purple gassy
stuff like we were just talking about
Star Killer and stuff like that I love
star killer I I yeah I mean the thing is
is with the green I feel
like you want stronger stuff it's going
to be green and not purple right um so
yeah as far as people people always want
what they can't have they want this
purple stuff and then they want it to be
super potent and it's like there is some
stuff that's borderline strong but
there's not it's not like the gassy
stuff no that gassy stuff was its own
era or the hazy stuff again yeah like
wow you know like some of the first good
weed that I got um there's a dude around
Athens Georgia that was growing this
swazi oh dude the swazi yeah the swazi
and like I mean you could take five
little kexes and put put it into a bowl
and go throw a frisbee for 4 hours you
know it's like completely psychedelic
and I mean it's completely ceiling the
higher you the more you smoke the higher
you got um most of the stuff isn't like
that now it's not like that at all and a
quarter of it was like that big you know
yeah you see a lot of stuff in Europe
too seriously yeah 16 weeks not it's not
announced like nope it's just it's just
a big quarter yeah that's funny but yeah
that stuff I was tripping on acid one
night and the homie came through with a
jar of it and
it literally shut down my ability to
speak like I had to had to totally shut
it just like I can't talk right yeah so
uh what is the favorite what's your
favorite thing to grow and what's the
the best thing you've ever smoked oo
um man right now my favorite thing to
grow um and it was a total accident it
came out of my old trap I had a room
full of Kim and I had a room full of
crippy and I found one seed in a crippy
Bud and I popped that thing and it
turned into this like OG KB looking
plant slow
growing silver purple it's got like this
almost like a soapy piffy smell to it
really heavy buzz like it's really
crippy in the
buzz um I called it the ducky because
it's got just a complete duck leaf and
that's my son's nickname just by
coincidence so the ducky is my favorite
to grow right now it's definitely not
it'll never be a production strain
there's no way it can be it's just too
slow um but I am you know I try to run
through all the hypy stuff you know I
get it I flower it I check it out um I
really like everything that um Chris has
been doing I know I don't think he's
with compound anymore but yeah like that
guy's stuff is
amazing Chris compound that's not with
compound yeah I don't know his last name
is Christopher Lynch oh I did know that
my bad sorry
yeah Chris is a good dude yeah no yeah
he's awesome I've only had good
experiences with Chris yeah man um I've
popped a bunch of his Joker stuff the
asai was awesome I think everything he's
doing I think it's all solid work um uh
Fletch from archive I think consistently
puts out the hits and I think he puts
out the hits that people talk about yeah
um Scott reach is a dear friend anything
red anness does I love it he does some
good work he does some great work man
yeah that star killer is epic it's so
good epic that yeah I got some Star
Killer flower that's we've had the same
cut going around for a long time that
we've kept alive and nice uh but yeah
I'm a huge fan yeah he passed me a Star
Killer cut and a flow OG and that flow
OG went on to win second place and the
Adam Dunn thing a couple years back nice
well date myself five years Adam is a
character Adam is a total character yeah
he's I just I was on the phone with him
earlier he's awesome he's yeah we got so
at MJ Biz this year him and I are
releasing Sage Against the Machine
crosses oh [ __ ] so yeah is that part of
the sage and sour project yeah that was
the sage and sour I made the seeds and
he yeah he helped curate the man the
stuff and he did the packaging and all
that but I did the breeding work I was
on his show we smoked some sage and sour
that a buddy had sifted and was it sage
and sour crosses or was it was it actual
Sage s it was a sage and sour from a few
years back it was wild man it was really
I love sage and sour I love the one that
has the open bud structure the most
where it's not the nested not the nested
bra but very open and yeah podil where
the bra stack but like that that stuff
we had it Harbor we used to get it at
Harborside too okay that stuff tasted
crazy it tasted it tasted like a blend
of sour and Sage with a lot of gas in it
and it was just really that's awesome it
was a really unique flavor yeah man I
love all the Diesels like I I still hang
on to the day record um I've got a
couple I've got like an East Coast Sour
Diesel I like a lot I just um I've got
an Alban s diesel that I'm really
digging on um yeah so I like those old
flavor flors but you know I'm not scared
to try anything new um I just don't I
don't I don't get the potency on some of
the newer stuff that I prefer the taste
is amazing you know I think back on my
younger self I'm like man if I was
smoking this when I was 19 like I I
wouldn't leave the couch you know I just
sit here and smoke this all day it
tastes so good and it tastes so good so
I find myself with some of these rosins
where I'll like have them in a jar and
while I'm watching TV or something I
keep smelling it over and over taking
the TPS away from it but you know it's
like
yeah taking all the aroma out of it but
yeah I mean I enjoy just the smell of
the stuff and I feel like that's one of
the the beauties of the cannabis plant
is like it has these amazing profiles
that we can really relate to and we get
excited about totally man it's such a
diverse plant and that's kind of like
what I was saying earlier I feel like
it's and you know I'm just a dude but
like I feel I find it impossible that
everything else like cannabis can smell
like everything like how is that
possible like it seems like that has to
be like the first plant that it created
tpin and like everything else like
evolved into well it's interesting CU
you think you could take cucumbers and
breed them into all kinds of I mean
there lemon cucumbers right so cannabis
is the most cultivated plant on the
planet there is more variet not not most
cultivated but there's more diversity in
cultivated cannabis than anything else
so what if we applied all that same
diversity to cucumbers or you know
anything cruciferous related from yeah
yeah my latest pivot man I kind of you
know
I'm not done with cannabis by any means
but the industry is just in a place
where I'm not as involved right now you
know kind of taking a step back watching
the plan Circle The Runway a little bit
um doing some behind the scenes work
that you know I I feel will be prudent
work whenever I want to pop it back in
but um I met a really awesome dude Grant
my man um this guy's got a a a a flower
farm yeah and uh dude that's been the
biggest pivot for me is like growing
these dollas and um like checking out
you talk about a diverse plant you know
like these dollas they have I forget the
set of chromosomes they have but it's
very similar to cannabis where you know
you can start breeding something and you
might not get anything that looks like
mother or father you know totally with
all these recessive traits and then
inbreeding too yeah but yeah it's funny
like if you look at
cruciferous and how it evolved into like
rasa like wild mustard how it evolved
into all these different things they're
talking about broccoli cabbage yeah I
mean it's wild all these all these
different expressions like there's that
amount of diversity too like if you go
back into something like wild mustard
but like the potential for what we can
do with the plant even more we're we're
just it's not that we're scratching the
surface we've done a lot of interesting
stuff but in some ways with technology
we're scratching the surface the
potential is going to be even more
amazing I think in the future yeah I
think you're right man we're you
know back when we were playing with it
it wasn't you know you weren't allowed
to play with this stuff you know so
everything had to be kept quiet you know
it was very much of quiet Society you
know and now it's like we can share the
information we can share the cut
everybody's talking about it you know
it's like yeah or you know like you're
going to have the ability to sell
somebody their favorite cut and it'll
show up 24 hours after they click a
button you know like yeah that's amazing
like before it used to be dude start
going through the Old Hippie Rolodex and
see who you knew and track it down or
you know whatever and yeah make a long
trip a road trip a dangerous one
dangerous one yeah cuz you got your weed
on you totally yeah so you grew you well
you've grown in both Colorado and
Washington so you were in Washington for
a little while and those are the most
opposite places on the whole planet as
far as cultivation is concerned you're
talking about super dry Colorado versus
super humid Washington and I was 20 22
miles from the beach so it was yeah man
fog rolled in every morning um big
learning curve there big learning curve
um and that again that's when I really
started to figure out like the
microbiology behind things you know yeah
like if you keep the traderma pumping
you're going to keep a lot of those
problems away um we brought some strains
up from Colorado that were hitters you
know like this old Purple Diesel we had
it th it was was that like the Oregon
diesel um one of the purple fenos of it
or you know I don't know it came from my
experience it came out of a dispensary
in Colorado I think when we were when we
were sourcing plants in the very
beginning I remember Purple Diesel from
Colorado it was good and it it it
performed really well and the yield was
really well but we took that strain to
Washington State and um we set up a
little like kind of R&amp;D medical
Greenhouse you know whatever and uh I
remember putting like 22 of these plants
out and seeing a little bit of Bud rot
and I was like okay you know we're all
right we're yeah we'll carve that out
yeah the next day you could walk up and
just like slop the whole thing on the
ground I was like okay you know we got
to we got to learn a lot about how to
move this air around and dry this air
out and yeah yeah
yeah struggles huge well then genetics
it's like field testing the stuff that
works good in Colorado does not
necessarily work in Washington
especially for outdoor so doing proper
field testing and being able to identify
what works well it's so different than
indoor people don't really always
understand how much different and how
plants respond in a different you could
have the same exact cultivar in in
Washington or in Colorado you're going
to get a different expression of the
plant 100% And I think you know a lot of
that's UV a lot of it you know like um
altitude is a big thing too you know
like in Boulder Colorado we're kind of
sitting similar to like a Hindu Kush
Afghani environment you know we're kind
of high desert very Aid cold weather
cold nights dry as dry as and so like
yeah these plants want to stay close to
the ground they want to spread their
feet out you know versus some of these
tropical varieties that want to shoot up
like a pole to out compete anything that
might be near them right you know
they've got a kind of a narrow root
stock that doesn't go out too far that
way you can pack them in tighter yeah um
yeah it's just all these different it's
been cool and you know I think about
like Oklahoma I'm like okay now you kind
of got Colorado but then you're throwing
in all that humidity and that heat and
then you already have like natural
fungus blowing around in that wind
totally I mean there's tons of stuff and
then you go further south it's like I
mean Tomatoes yeah they grow great in
the South but they also get tons of
pathogens you know for sure and then you
go to Florida yeah you know now you're
growing in a swamp you know so it yeah
indoor versus anything else you have to
have the it's so different and nothing
against a good indoor grower you know
because I mean it it takes the eyes and
it takes the effort whatever you're
doing to get it whatever you're doing
yeah if there's passion involved like I
mean and it's not easy that's the thing
is it's like it's it's easy to every
once in a while get lucky in a small hom
grower you know to to do it at scale is
so different right like yeah and to be a
able to produce good flower at scale it
takes a special eye and it doesn't
matter whether it's outdoor at scale or
indoor at scale or whatever it is like
there's learning curves to all of it and
being able to move past the tough times
yeah and everybody you know everybody
likes doing anything the first time when
it's fun and it looks good you know it's
like oh man we got this brand new
facility we're gonna crank out let's see
what we can hit you know but then you
got to keep doing it you got to keep
doing it you got to keep doing it you
got to keep showing up you know and
right you can't get comfortable with
what you think you're doing because
eventually you're going to fall off your
own path you know like takes almost
somebody else to be like hey man let's
bring it back this way you know right so
yeah it's it's very much like you got to
be your own cheerleader you got to be a
lot that's life though that's you got to
be your cheerleader in life but that's a
great example of yeah you know
motivating other people to be there with
you you know you're like all right man
like we got a thousand plans to take
down a day you know like we don't stop
at 12 yeah yeah well I mean I used to
sleep a lot less and now I'm forcing
myself to sleep more but I you know it's
like as we've gotten older it's like I
when I was in my 30s I'm like I only
need four hours 5 hours of sleep maybe
and and you know in partying when I was
younger that was different but then I
went through this phase where I'm like I
don't need a lot of sleep I can do it
but like I value sleep now because I
feel like for for health for health for
health I value sleep and you know it's
like and then being as productive as
possible during the day is you know
agreed um I love my wife for giving me
that right now you know she's like dude
you need to get that morning sleep you
know you need to rest like because as a
farmer the past what Henry's 11 I've
been doing it longer than that you know
for cannabis so yeah I mean man we're up
at 5:00 4:30 5:00 you know in the field
by 6 in the greenhouse by 6:30 7 o'clock
but I mean it's a greenhouse so you got
to be out of there by like 2:30 you're
still going to you know you're going to
have a life but Life Starts early and
then you take all that stress and then
years and years and years and years of
that compound and all of a sudden you
know I don't know some days I'm going
down the stairs I feel like an old
uncooked spaghetti noodle I'm crack
crack crack and it's like I know the
feeling interes with cooking it's better
than not that it's better than cooking
it's different than cooking being a chef
and that that's a whole different sort
of toll that that takes on your body too
I agree and and different kind of stress
we have different stresses now about
plants rather than food but it's like
and all those things are character
building for sure man I wouldn't trade a
thing like being a chef taught me
yeah it put my like this is how you
become a man this is how you stay a man
like you know these are the things
you're going to focus or you're going to
have to face and focus on and if you
don't then you're not going to be a chef
very long or you're not going to be a
top you know a head chef very long no
and and I think if you want to be a chef
or if you want to be a girl the biggest
thing is realizing where you're really
at and you know it's like because you
can improve if you know that you can
improve you can improve but if you think
you've got it all figured out that's
when you you know you failed to a degree
because there's always Improvement
there's always room for improvement and
going through life it's like whether
you're a chef like being able to take a
step back and get rid of the ego I think
that's ties into the mushrooms too even
like yeah I mean being able to get rid
of your ego and real realize who you are
and authenticity is such a big thing now
too as we've gotten older it's like I
think being authentic is so
important yeah I I thought that I worked
with a lot of egotistical Maniacs in The
Culinary world but
nothing on these breeders when I got
into cannabis man I'm like wow like yeah
cannabis is a whole another like and I
think is like the whole Rockstar side of
it but the funny thing is is like as
funny as like the whole Rockstar side of
these guys and people wanting to be you
know pot celebrities or whatever we're
going back to being tomato farmers and
you got to do it because you love it
exactly and it's not like the rock star
image that you know I mean there were
cannabis rock stars sure you know it's
like look at Arian from Greenhouse he's
definitely like the can abis Rockstar
lives up to that he's done it and you
know a handful of other guys as well but
we're going back into agriculture to a
degree and farming and doing stuff
because you love it we're tomato Farmers
to a degree and right maybe not tomato
Farmers but we're still it's similar I
feel like cannabis right now is going
through what like culinary went through
when the slow food movement started yeah
and it was like you know what dude like
you may think you know how to make a
tomato sauce but like where your
Tomatoes coming from let's go all the
way back down to the field Tomatoes
tomatoes are important in the but
quality Tomatoes it's funny CU like
there's such
a a difference and a wide variety of
tomatoes and the quality of the tomatoes
and how how impactful that is to food
absolutely and that that goes across the
board with all the vegetables that are
that are cultivated out there yeah you
know and I think a lot of times we only
see one one or two expressions of those
things in the store but like with
potatoes there's I don't know thousands
thousand thousands right thousands of
different cultivars of potatoes or
varieties of potatoes I almost think
this is the gift that cannabis is going
to give us it's going to teach a bunch
of people how to grow it yeah and then
they're going to get the tools and then
they're going to use those tools to go
grow dollia so they're gonna grow yeah
you know like Go Geek out on something
else and I think that's one more of her
her gifts you know she's going to
educate you to the point where you're
like why am I not growing celery or you
know what can I do in my backyard and
totally especially if you're following
you know these like build a soil and I
mean you can yeah you do living soil so
we talked about yeah you do and it's
it's a low tail living soil right yeah I
can't say it's no till because I do top
dress and scratch and stuff like that
and I mean if if a Situation's bad
enough I will dig up some soil and
replace it um but yeah no uh this year
my outdoor crop I have it's F sixy year
living soil from builda soil yeah um in
my backyard 200 gallon pots I put out 21
plants I could have 24 yeah kept it a
little under just keep them off the off
my back um but dude it was water only
that was it this year I was like you
know what I don't have the time I don't
want to I I was I was kind of I was kind
of put all the it was fire it was great
it's fire it's hanging out it's hanging
like a bat right now like I cut down the
last day record yesterday before I got
on the plane that's awesome yeah so and
it I mean but yeah so that same thing I
can throw like I did um that three
sisters technique this year where you're
growing corn melons and beans together
yeah same soil no fertilizer and what's
that called complimentary planting
something like that yeah so you're using
the corn to grow tall the beans will
grow up the corn and then the melon will
ground cover but the beans are also
nitrogen fixing the soil for the corn
correct it's just yeah it's just it's
really cool and everything came out
awesome we you know we've got a couple
fun little pumpkins to play around with
for Halloween and yeah dude I had way
too many be green beans this year like
green beans are awesome though green
beans are awesome yeah yeah it's one
thing my kid will definitely Chow Down
on so yeah dude I I love vegetables yeah
like
vegetables yeah I mean like you said
about tomatoes I just every Every Spring
I'm like okay I need one of these
Tomatoes I need five of these different
peppers you know I got a little geeked
out backyard but yeah shout out to all
the Tomato Farmers out there man yeah
man right doing it guys yeah all the
farmers all the farmers they all need a
big pat on the back and a big hug yeah
including the Cannabis ones I think but
anybody who's still doing it whether
it's you know agriculture cannabis
whatever man fact is times are tough and
we're going to make it through this just
like everything else and there's always
going to be a need for food and I think
the more awareness there is about
quality the more we're seeing it with
cannabis Colorado is a more mature
market and Washington's a more mature
Market than California and I feel like
in Colorado brands have become
established and they're not going off
the hype as much as they are Brands and
brand awareness is a big thing and the
THC percentage that stuff's all going to
go away we're going to be talking
about Aroma and other things in effect
yep yeah in Colorado it's now it's
definite like you have your bargain
shoppers who you know that's kind of the
dude that buys the mountain Thunder
instead of buying Mountain Dew you know
what I mean he goes to Walmart and buys
the knockoff soda there's there's plenty
of that weed out there you know there's
plenty of what you know people are
calling mids or whatever like it's it's
salty weed that is not that great yeah
but the brands that are doing really
good and the brands that can sell their
pounds of weed or their extracts are all
about quality and they're breeding their
own in-house cultiv ours that nobody
else has so it you know separates them
there um they're separating themselves
through the technique or whatever it may
be yeah um yeah the Mass Appeal that's
like for the back of the The Westward
Magazine you know like if you're looking
for a $50 ounce it's out there probably
even cheaper prob I mean I saw $10
ounces in Oregon like advertised like
but you know like Green Dot like that
that you know Green Dot Dave that guy
like constantly raising the bar every
time they make a drop the bar is raised
and have you heard of NorCal Nemo no so
NorCal Nemo sells the $1,800 ounces of
Skittles And1 th000 ounces
of uh guava gas and so and the stuff is
phenomenal it's like organic organic
yeah it's it's amazing that's awesome uh
obviously super turpy super flavorful
good effect but like I love those
stories and some people are like oh
that's not worth it whatever but I love
hearing stories about somebody
succeeding like that on that level uh
especially if they're true because it
adds the it increases the value of
everything anybody else is doing it
quality right I agree so because at a
certain point when we're talking about
the most amazing stuff that we like to
smoke and that that's of the highest
quality the a plus stuff I think that
has flavor and effect and all that it's
all uh subjective to the individual it's
almost like art yep like tattoos tattoos
yeah exactly yeah very good yeah great
example you know you can go get
scratched on by some guy down on Main
Street for you know 20 bucks or you can
you know pay $1,000 for a couple hours
from your favorite artist you know or go
to Japan get hammered on get Hammer yeah
yeah exactly yeah go somewhere and get a
whole different technique you know like
yeah it's wild man yeah I think cannabis
there's I don't feel like anybody should
feel like their ship is left the harbor
whatever the saying is like there's
plenty of room at the table for
everybody but you do need to pull up
your own seat you do need to be present
and yeah yeah and just yeah like pick a
reason to do it but do it for a good
reason passion should drive you and
that's so this is one thing I know we
can agree on is it passion should drive
you in everything in life and it's like
being a chef you really get that like
passion driven because you wouldn't work
those long hours and do those shitty
days that you know there's good days to
come along with it but but there's
shitty days too and you wouldn't suck it
all up if you didn't love it same thing
with cannabis and I feel like as we get
older it's like there's other ways to
make money too but it's like being able
to be in cannabis and to be able to
contribute to something that's so much
bigger than us I feel like is an amazing
thing and it's an amazing opportunity
that we're blessed to be a part of it is
man it really is like you know it taught
me how to feed myself it helped me I
mean I've helped I don't even know how
many people with different problems you
know like I mean my brother-in-law had
stage four gleo blastoma and got six
months to live and CBD man like just
huge fat sing syringes of CBD it's a
game CBD is a game changer he's doing
he's rad you know he's great he's
fineing yeah yeah man it's just it's
saves lives it saves lives it makes the
world a better place I think that's the
biggest thing is is like it saves lives
it does all these things it brings us
together we wouldn't be here today
without it we wouldn't be having this
conversation would have walked right
past you if I never e the weed you know
yeah I mean it's such a big part of my
life big part of your life and and a lot
of the people that watch the show it's
just such a special plant and special on
so many levels and it's like you know
it's definitely part of uh everything
that we
do yep I mean it's sometimes it's the
reason I can't go on that super long
vacation I want to go on with my wife
and my family and sure you know there's
a lot of sacrifice man to hang I've had
PL I've had longer than my son you know
like I've kept a little plant longer
than I've had my son you know and yeah
it is awesome it it's it presents so
many opportunities in this in this world
so yeah uh it gives back it does for
sure what you put in you get out of it
and there's not a lot of things you can
say about that in life you know
relationships are another one you you
get what what comes out is what you put
into it and I think or it should but you
learn real quick with relationships with
relationships yeah you start coasting
you take your foot off the gas and you
start coasting and things start getting
real swervy you know like you got to
stay focused and well with relationship
until it gets tough you really don't
know the relationship or the person it's
when you go through tough times that
that's when you really see who people
are and what people are made of yeah
who's there for you and who's not and uh
you know and it's important to go
through those things in life struggle is
it's like I I wanted to run away from
struggle as a kid you know whatever like
I thought the struggle was bad we wanted
to like live a comfortable life and
comfort isn't what life's all about and
uh it's real interesting because as I've
gotten older I feel like struggle is
what makes you great but it's also what
makes life great yeah like experiencing
struggle and to be able to make it past
that and growing and to be able to grow
a plant and experience those type of
things or you know dogs are another
you're a big dog guy I'm I lost my dog
my dog lost my dog almost three months
ago now oh man I'm sorry it was like my
my best friend in the whole world the
best hellos and the worst goodbye man
like dogs are on a whole another level
dude but Senior Dogs I have a new
appreciation for Senior Dogs man I
didn't realize I always thought the
puppy stage is like the best part until
we had a senior dog that like the senior
years were the best where she wanted to
be with us all the time yeah yeah it's
interesting and dogs are so amazing they
are man like once you bring them into
your life they're like okay I got one
one job and it's to hang with this guy
you know and make sure he's all right
and I mean I have a 130 PB Rottweiler
and the big head he's a big dude yeah
and all he wants to do is hang out with
my son or by you know the
that's his job he knows it and I think
he was named after one of the best
country music singers of all time sturg
simpon sturg Simpson man yeah like I
fell in love with Sturgill Simpson and
you turned me on to sturg Simpson back
of the day long long time ago I hope his
voice gets better apparently like he's
got some Voice issues or something
so he went from like this amazing
country to doing amazing Bluegrass
too those those two albums are are just
next level but I me all his stuff is
great and he's another passionate guy
yeah yeah exactly that's what I liked
about him he like kind of like that old
70s hillbilly talking about weed but
he's talking about like DMT and turtles
and you know like turtle turtles all the
way down and stuff and like yeah that
definitely yeah Sturgill's the man like
yeah I love all this stuff yeah but yeah
Big sturge I thought it'd be a good name
for a big old goofy rwe totally yeah
it's funny because like his music is
kind of in line with the Grateful Dead
there's there's some alignment there
with the message yeah you know and it's
also yeah it's it just music is an
amazing thing this vibration yeah you
got to catch those last Ed shows yeah
the last oh dude I stayed 20 minutes
from the I was 20 feet not 20 minutes it
felt like 20 minutes but 20 feet from
the stage uh all three nights and I
didn't go to the restroom during
intermission any of those nights W and
the only night I had to go to the
bathroom was the third night at
intermission I'm like damn it I wish I
could go I just sucked it up yeah it was
a great time Bobby man what an
inspiration I love that guy's IG he's
just like working out every town he goes
to seriously like swinging [ __ ] around
his head he's got yeah he's got some
cool cool stuff yeah I like him yeah
he's I mean he he's in inspirational
especially for moving into the older
years of our lives like going to that
next stage it's like well that's going
to be okay too yeah but when I was a kid
I thought 40 year olds were old when I
was 18 I was like man that dude's hella
old and he was like 40 and really you
know like now that I'm past 40 it's like
I don't feel all that old no and I think
it's important now because you know you
you're a healthy guy and you're focused
on your health and I I am similar to I
you know take a lot of supplements and
stuff like that but I'm 47 now like but
I'm not going to be
47 you know here in the next couple
years so I think it's really important
to start thinking about that like okay
man like here comes 55 and what's that
look like you know because I got a man I
got a 11 and a half year old he's almost
12 like you know it's not all like it
used to be just do what you want to do
for you you know right now I got people
to look out for and there's a bigger
picture sturge to feed sturge yeah I
love the dogs though yeah no yeah um
yeah so I want to stick around for as
long as possible man I mean there's a
reason I don't do hard drugs or smoke
cigarettes or whatever I asked you a
question but I didn't get the answer
what your favorite thing to smoke was
I'm gonna have to
say my desert island strain would be dog
walker OG nice if I was just going to
sit on you know if I had just to enjoy
just to be high and not one thing you
could only smoke for the rest of your
life while you lived on that desert
island yeah I think it would you know it
make me paranoid enough to keep moving
it would get me stoned enough to go to
sleep you know like it's great when
Theon those tolerant free strands to
where like there's no
tolerance uh this the tolerance free
where like doesn't matter how long you
smoke it you don't fully build a
tolerance to it where it'll still get
you high in the morning yeah yeah or or
even in the evening after You' been
smoking all day for for like three
months of the like green crack after a
week that's it yeah you know there's a
lot of stuff like that I would say cam
91 but it's just like if you even like
look at that wrong it's gonna turn out
different than it did the time before
it's just she takes a lot of effort and
a lot of knowledge and so yeah I think
my yeah my go-to is at dog walker
because I can grow her big and strong
and yeah I like it and all the
concentrates are great from her I bet
but yeah she's a head head ringer man
yeah potent potent triangle cush too
like all those I like the TK the lime
green TK is fire I brought some TK for
you to try I love TK some motor breath
you know so yeah you know I like all
those Kims and those yeah that's for
sure the Grateful Dead Weed Man all the
Grateful Dead yeah I mean all this stuff
is nostalgic it is it is the music but
then all these experiences every once in
a while like yeah I think it's cool too
like where you grew up you know like
these New York cats are like oh it's all
about to sour bro you know it's like
sour the sour you know dude it is about
the sour you know it is but it's also
about everything else too yeah and it
fits it fits the electricity of New York
City you know what I mean like it's like
that kind of weed like you can like
float through the city with you know
we're going to smoke some good sour in a
minute here sounds perfect yeah so if
you had or if you had the opportunity to
go back and talk to your younger self
that had' been in the industry for just
about a
year what would you tell your younger
self number one would be get rid of the
chef ego day one right cuz like that was
out of control I was trying to like it
was just like a kitchen and I was trying
to climb up the ladder and like if
you're in my way I was a little rough
dude and you know I think I would have
been a little bit more
Kumbaya um I think I did a good job on
keeping my eyes and my ears open but I
would now with all the research there is
like especially with the socials and the
patreons and all that I would I would
dive deep into all that stuff right now
like what Brandon Russ is talking about
like I mean he's been on the show he's
the man he's the man like I just was
listen to him on uh first smoke of the
day the other day and like I mean yeah
those kind of dudes there's like so much
knowledge to gain and I don't care like
if you want to run selftaught that's
it's the beauty of it right you don't
have to if you don't want to go to
school you don't have to go to school no
yeah no like yeah just it's all about
reverse engineering what you really love
you know like if it's like dude I love
mountain biking it's like well don't not
go to college because you want to ride
your mountain bike go work at a bike
shop or go get sponsored or you know
like yeah start getting some coins
from something you didn't start early
doesn't mean you can't do it that's the
beauty you know like I've learned to
reinvent myself over the years with
doing different things cannabis has
always kind of been a constant I've
always smoked you know so but as far as
like I've worked in it I've done all
kinds of different stuff worked as a
chef so and also had a backup plan so
yeah when [ __ ] goes sideways I you have
to Pivot you know and I think in this
like this day and age you can like back
you know back in the day it was kind of
like you picked a career and you had to
stick with that career or yeah you know
change to a really other boring career
well for since the beginning of time you
did what your father did right so like
and I think there's some beauty in that
as well is like perfecting something
that you know I like I've lik to try to
do everything and you know I've I've
like to experience different things find
out what I like but there is a beauty to
doing one thing that you love your whole
life and mastering that to the next
level where you are in the very elite of
that and so and that stuff takes time
but also can be a combination of
different things that lead you there
like you know yeah yeah I think the
plans led me to understanding soil and
and you know vegetables and and growing
and then that would be my my gift to my
son would be like hey man like I
remember when Henry was I think about
four years old his uh his nephew was in
town or my nephew was in town the kid's
like 11 years old yeah and Henry's in
the garden like pulling things out and
showing this kid like this is what how
carrots grow you know the guy's like
carrot you know and he's like I thought
he they came inside and the kid was like
I thought all this stuff just came from
the grocery store yeah you know and I
was like that's cool that my little kid
is showing you what's underground you
know like he knew what the leaf looked
like to pull the carrot you know he
didn't get to see a carrot yeah so yeah
like yeah I think that's the gift yeah
it's it's gonna be really amazing to see
what the kids of these yeah like your
kids and my friends kids I don't have
kids but these kids in and the things
that they do my nieces and nephews like
the things that they're doing and the
things that you know as as young adults
and then as your kid as he's going to
grow up in a whole different world which
different it's gonna be amazing yeah and
uh you know and all of it is beautiful
like everything in life is beautiful
from the right
angle well not everything but you know a
lot of stuff you know there's the good
the good in the dark but a lot of the
stuff that we think is bad is
necessarily not bad and it you know yeah
it's funny like my kid has kind of like
a bad taste in his mouth about America
right now you know he's like I don't
know like he's like why do why why is
all this crap going on and we actually
went to Europe over like after Christmas
break yeah and so he got to see both
sides and he's still like all right when
we move to Europe you know yeah which I
mean with cannabis now Barcelona I was
gonna say here we go oh man the food is
good over there I know you got to go
spannabis it's the one I was gonna go
the Year everybody got Co and had to
spend a little extra time yeah but um
yeah I definitely need to get over there
and do that yeah it's a fun trip for
sure so yeah if somebody's looking to
find out more information about you they
want to hit you up uh where would they
go man so I keep my Facebook stuff kind
of at this point like if I don't know
you I'm probably not adding you too much
my Facebook is private I don't my
Facebook's kind of turned into like
family stuff and stuff like that but um
brooksies buds b r o o k s i e buds yeah
um that'll kind of show you what I'm up
to um that's pretty much it man like I'm
kind of that edge of the generations
that like I'm a private person you know
like I don't have to show off everything
all the time um but I do want to get
caught up on you know patreon and
discords and stuff like that and like
even some Reddit stuff and stuff like
that are you going to be selling your
seeds in the future I think there's a
lot of people interested in the breeding
that work that you're doing yeah um we
have one ready to go right now um we're
calling it make America grape again and
it's it's basically we reversed our
favorite grape drink it's a strain in
Colorado it's a hilarious it's great
dude it's I mean it tastes like the
purple Barrel grape drink from Walmart
but I got that on Gary and I got that on
all the currents so they're fims so it'
be an easy you know an easy thing to
release and I'm already moving past that
so um yeah I would like to get that one
out there and a couple others awesome
yeah so we didn't really bring up our
friend Leland you introduced me to
Leland love yeah dude big shout out to
Leland Leland you're the man thanks for
the NES you know I really appreciate
everything I think he's doing some cool
breeding stuff too dude his trth
oh my God yeah we get I'm sure Leland
will send you some he appreciates good
genetics he appreciates FL so big shout
out to Leland uh we got to get you on
the show you were supposed to bring a
hat for me from Leland yeah he he gave
me he gave me three jars of weed that
were growing the front row yeah but I
got nervous at the last minute going
through TSA and I left him at home I was
like but no he never gave me any swag so
he said he's got swag for you um yeah
yep front row we get you all hooked up
they they have those dope work shirts
you know the new um slick work shirts
like the a
shirts they Crush there so yeah there's
a handful I'm not set on just one
nutrient line as far as for salts but I
think they do a good job you know
there's a handful of other guys that do
as well what I appreciate oh sorry go
yeah so I just I just really like the
the fact that the people that work there
give a [ __ ] too and and are about the
plant yep and about making the plant the
best expression it can be yep and their
customer service is really good too
that's what I was going to to say man
like their real like heads growing the
plants that they they spend a lot of
money to PE put people out there in your
grow to figure out what's going on and
how they can fix it or you know if it's
a pro problem with their product which
they did have a couple run-ins in the
beginning like everybody does their part
B yeah a micronization it was like a
hammer Mill it was like literally a
hammer Mill that was screwing up the
whole thing yeah so pretty wild but
still good yeah they fix it I mean in
these yeah that's what happens with
everything man no everybody I put on
front row like I still got a bunch of
home in Colorado that are just hom
Growers and they're like oh man you know
living soil is fine but keep the dirty
dirt outside you know yeah and I put
them on front row and they're just like
dude like so impressed and their plants
look amazing and they smoke really well
they smoke really great yeah yeah I
can't hate on front row um my buddy
Stacy up at Harvest House in Netherland
has been growing the front row and I
just got some Gary Payton and some
Alpine guava from him phenomenal like
Phenom he's actually got a 72y old mom
helping so yeah shout out to OG old
grandma but yeah she's growing some fire
with the front row man that stuff grows
great weed so and it's really it's very
simple it's super easy to use yeah I
mean it's it's one of the easier
nutrient lines to actually use and
execute flawlessly 100% yeah I feel yeah
it's kind of like you just got to know
how to make some really good Kool-Aid
and you're there dude yeah it's that
simple so right yep yeah and you can use
it in line too yeah I love Leland man
like yeah I got to work with Leland over
a spot and I met him in Boulder at a at
a at a grow and he used to breed lizards
and stuff like this guy I mean he's
there's so much to Leland he's awesome
like I love that dude yeah and he's
actually my neighbor he just bought a
house right next to me that's awesome
yeah yeah right around the corner well
man it's been great having you on the
show today thanks for coming on and
we'll have to do this again I hope you
enjoy your time in California thank you
so much for having me out man and this
the compound holy smokes dude like mind
blown aw I mean this is it's already put
together but I can I can see what's
going to happen here very shortly and
yeah couldn't be more proud of you bro
thank you thank you so much sir going
yep good
[Music]
stuff
Cru