foreign
[Music]
how's it going everybody Welcome to
today's episode of the James Lab podcast
my special guest is mosca Rick from
Moscow Negra seeds how you doing today
Rick good James glad to be here man so
it's been a while it's been a year since
we like well I guess we hung out as
cannabis this year yes yes spanibus what
a great event that is really tremendous
so we've been doing booths together for
the last few years it's bannabis uh we
we spend time hanging out traveling the
world together here yep so yeah it's
great to have you on the show thanks for
having me James awesome so I guess let's
get started and talk about your history
and how you came up in the industry well
you know it was really it's always been
a love for the plant and when I was 13
um my uh relatives who lived in Iowa
showed me these huge 15-foot uh hemp
plants asking us if we knew what that
was we had no clue we got a a garbage
paper garbage bag full of flour and uh
we took it home with us back to Illinois
thinking that uh this is really potent
good stuff and it did nothing but give
us headaches we tried to cure it in
mason jars with apple slices oranges and
all I did was mold yeah it uh yeah that
that was the beginning of it and then
you know uh throughout
um uh going to school in the Summers I
worked at an orchid farm near my home
and that that's really where I learned
more about cultivation growing
and then uh
I traveled to Amsterdam back in 1999
and to me to be able to see people
smoking freely uh in coffee shops uh was
just an eye-opening experience and at
that time for me uh my whole goal was to
grow flower as good as I could buy in
Amsterdam coffee shops oh wow and uh
weren't setting your goals too high yeah
so was this in the 90s yeah late 1999
was the first time was it Amsterdam
awesome and the green the greenhouse was
one of the first ones I went to and I
still have a big blown up portrait of
their menu and I keep up on my wall just
to remind me of uh really cool again
yeah I still have my bobble head from
Aryan oh right the Cannabis yes yes yeah
that was great uh share space uh at his
Booth this year at spanubus yeah that
was really cool that was really cool it
was I I hate to say but I think it was
my best fan of us ever like I had a
really good time I think we had a lot of
fun
for me it was more fun than it's been in
the past even though we worked our asses
off I wasn't having to manage multiple
seed companies it was just you and I
hanging out with Greenhouse you know
that that by itself was a lot of fun
yeah much more efficient I think and
um to see all our old friends from you
know our past and that was really
tremendous to see old faces and to
connect uh with Mila yeah at the uh the
squash off that was that was fantastic
one of our highlights definitely
squash off was really cool you know I
I've seen it before many times this was
the first time I judged and I've been
friends with Uncle Stoner for a long
time long time yeah he's a good guy he's
a real character he's he's a
one-of-a-kind you know genuine dude he's
very authentic
and he wears his heart on his sleeve
yeah it was a really great event I
thought it was a lot of fun uh being
able to contribute Ken Estes was there
it was yeah a lot of people I haven't
seen in a while and uh yeah spanibus
it's it's just a beautiful thing a
beautiful event for cannabis people
coming together
uh I just I I can't speak highly enough
of the event
um it's my favorite Gathering of friends
especially right and see that number of
people and just having a great time you
know talking having a lot of social
aspect but then also there's a business
aspect to it right and so just a great
balance and uh what there's no better
City to have it in no and the food is
amazing I mean we have a great time yeah
you know and I think
we don't have to worry about covid now
so that makes it a little better there
was a couple you know it was I was
worried a little bit this year because
the year before we had to wear masks you
know and that was kind of like it was a
little bummer the the
the amount of people attending wasn't
very high the previous year this year
was like kova didn't exist it was great
yeah yeah the the amount of people it
just it was no holds bar there was just
so Betty yeah tremendous time so going
back so you started smoking uh early 90s
late 80s
um I've I've always smoked like uh
through the 80s 90s yeah nice yeah and
uh you know growing up in the midwest
it's uh it's really hard to find good
flour I bet
um but that's all changed now but back
in the day I mean it was all brick weed
occasionally get some Thai stick but uh
there really wasn't a lot to choose from
yeah
so how did you transition from going as
a cultivator into breeding and when did
that occur was that a long time ago you
saw that was in the early 2000s like
2003 for
um I became uh very good friends with uh
had it slot who owned Magus genetics out
of Amsterdam uh I had met him actually I
had bought seeds from uh the Bluebird
Coffee Shop
um in Amsterdam and out of the 20 packs
that I bought the the Warlock was one of
my favorites and
um so I went to the High Times cup like
a year later and uh Garrett or had it
had a booth at the High Times cup and so
I went up to him started talking to him
and and I said you know your uh
Holland's best kept secret it because
the genetics that I found from those
those seeds were just some of my
favorite and we talked for four hours
straight and we really connected and he
was really My Mentor in uh selection for
plants and uh because I had smoked the
Cinderella 99
seeds that I had and
um I really connected with the plant
this was I'd love the cerebral high but
it had like an Indica
um
aftertaste to it so it was like a roller
coaster to me that complexity was really
interesting and it's something that
really motivated me so
um I talked to uh Garrett about how can
I keep this in case I lose my mother
plants and uh so he helped me with
selection what to look for and so I went
I took five different families of the
Cinderella 99 that was available at that
time this was back in the Egyptian
Urbana days so I bred uh the different
uh selected plants to come up with what
I ended up calling the Cinderella 99
back cross and so that was my first
project and
um Garrett told me that
um gypsy one of his favorite strains was
the a Cinderella 99 he said well you
know if you have so many seeds why don't
you send them some and you know he can
distribute them I'll come out of his
freebies I'm like okay this was a great
idea so I did that and
um uh Gypsy gave some of those seeds to
Crazy composer who used to be a senior
editor for high times and he did a Blog
on it and he said it was the best
example of pineapple Fino of the
Cinderella 99 he's ever grown and all
sudden everybody wanted them right and
then
Gypsy said to me well I guess this time
you get uh your own page and so I had to
all sudden put a seed company together
and it was all based on the Cinderella
99 and they sold out like with uh within
the the first 15 minutes it was just it
it started with the bang that's awesome
uh I've done uh projects that uh
included the moonshine one of DJ shorts
sure uh short-lived strains he stopped
working with it because of the high
number of mutations in the line and so I
had sourced two packs from some Icy
Maggers and uh
um started working with them and found
uh some male and female keepers
and then did that line and then I
started doing projects on my own based
on
um you know different strains that I
liked and
um you know that was a good uh 17 years
ago that have been growing
professionally now that's awesome yeah
so you're in Illinois right now yes
how is uh how's the market over there
the market is very strong
um yeah there's uh the dispensaries that
keep adding dispensaries
um the numbers wise
um they're selling um you know hundreds
of millions dollars a month right
through dispensaries we've been
fortunate that some of our strains have
been included in the dispensaries we've
worked with a company called New Era now
Legacy IL uh but they've put our
raspberry Boogie into the dispensaries
and then now uh under release strain
called root beer Mac and so mean genes
uh root beer yeah uh with capillators uh
Mac and uh is it hazy because I feel
like everything bred with that Mac ends
up hazy yeah there is definitely a haze
like this dominance yeah there's this
dominance that comes from that Mac yeah
you know that Colombian side of you know
good or bad however you want to take it
it's it's a hard breeder you know and
it's
I think Mach One is a beautiful plant I
think it's amazing looking but it's a
really tough plant to breed with
properly yeah yeah and uh so you know it
all comes down to selection right you
know and that's it's a numbers game so
the larger sample size you have the more
more likely that you're gonna find what
you're looking for
yeah especially with something like that
where you have something so dominant you
want a larger gene pool to select from
100 I agree uh some stuff you don't need
a thousand seeds to go through you might
need a hundred you might need 150 you
know I I think
over a thousand is a little crazy some
people do that but you know what's your
magic number for uh selections uh we
like to do
um 50 okay but then
um like if we've done a run outdoors I
mean we've done 300 yeah
um but I think
um if you select your uh parental stock
properly then
um you're gonna get uh what you want out
of you know a 50 sample size right so
well the more you know the line the
better I think at the end of the day
what people don't understand is like the
more you breed with stuff you understand
what the male and what the female or
donor or male or donor or what the
female is contributing and you a lot of
times know what you're looking for so it
makes it a lot easier and you know if
you're gonna have to pop 100 seeds or
you're gonna have to pop 50 seeds or
you'll probably find what you're looking
for in a smaller amount like 15 or 20.
yeah true true and
um you know the the whole final Hunt is
the entire process because it starts
from labeling correctly from when you
plant those seeds because if you're
doing you know
um three four five strains a 50 each you
need to make sure everything's
documented properly and sometimes more
than just one label do you do a steak
and a collar tag yeah yeah we've talked
about this before both we're on the same
page on this one for sure
and it's so easy to get stuff mixed up
and also just getting rid of the wrong
plants when you're doing the selection
process growing them out multiple times
I used to grow them out once and do my
selections and that's really not the way
to do it
um so how many times do you grow them
out
um at least two but preferably three
yeah
and what are you typically looking for
uh when you're doing your selections so
um I I believe that with selections you
you have to look for the most ideal
plants of what we consider ideal and so
for me
um it's the bud does it have
um when the dry is that bag appeal does
it have that loud Aroma to it
um what's the high like
um so
um
you know there's things like that people
talk about oh they they want a really
heavy yielder well that's not
necessarily you know the the best for
quality in today's market California
Illinois you know everywhere it's all
about quality
um and once you start doing proper Fino
hunts and working the whole lines
through a process
you understand what that means right and
you don't necessarily want to prioritize
Quality quality not quality sorry
prioritize uh yield right I think
prioritizing quality is the most
important thing
and yield can be down on the list of
things because there's a commercial
viability aspect of it especially at
scale when people are growing you know
rooms of it for instance
but you know I think the first thing for
me is always flavor effect yeah effect
is super important too right but like
Flavor speaks highly flavor Chasers I'm
a flavor Chaser you're a flavor Chaser
you know we're doing some projects
together we're all we're all about
chasing flavors at the end of the day I
like
a variety of flavors too so jumping into
that what are the flavors that you like
you know I like the the whole Spectrum I
mean I love the ogs I love fruity I love
um something that's unique and different
um like your cereals yeah I mean that
brings a lot to the mix it's just
um the the taste is really something
really special so it's not just one
thing it's definitely multiple things
but those are the flavors that uh I like
but I like something
um
that I I really like like the Skittles
yeah you know I smoked uh a joint the
other day at this concert and it was
just I had some hash in it his Skittles
hash with the Skittles flower it was off
off the hook well you should taste that
because that one right there is just a
flower and I don't think you need any
hash with it all right I think that's
the one we'll do
so I got myself I'm Fino hunting so I
need to go through some of these flavors
but I got this is a
zero zbx so it's the soul yeah
so the loops
and uh
we found some candy ones which is great
you know going back through them and
uh oh yeah
pretty good flavor though right off the
bat you taste it yeah yeah and it's down
to that roach if you were to re-fire the
roach a month later you'd probably taste
it
that says something right there
you know and when you find flour that
tastes like it smells
that's special
yeah I mean
you do a lot of funeral hunting as well
and
going through it's like
there's a lot of stuff that can be
misleading where the nose in the bag is
so amazing and then you go to smoke it
and it's a letdown
you know it's it's all over the Spectrum
yeah or even the look it may have great
bag appeal so much stuff they're the
Oreos yeah right Oreos has great bag of
peel it looks super sexy but then when
it comes to smoking it it's like
cardboard chips I'm not really into
those
terp profiles like that where it does
have Terps it just has like this
chocolatey funkiness that I'm not super
yeah I'm not impressed by but I'm not
it's not something I I go out and look
for right right yeah
um
yeah but it is uh
it is really great to Define some good
combinations uh like uh I brought some
of the flour for you to uh to look at
the cereals raspberry Boogie
um because to me that does hit on all
cylinders but uh yeah so that's what
we're looking for people know about the
zeros but let's talk about the raspberry
Boogie so this is our collaboration that
we've been working on for God we've been
working over a year yeah yep
um yeah two years we've exchanged yeah
almost two years we've exchanged a bunch
of genetics and we share stuff and uh
you know and we're able to hang out
enough to where we can smoke stuff
together and kind of talk about it but
let's talk about the raspberry boogie in
the history of that yeah so the
raspberry boogie that's the sour
raspberry to the pink 2.0 uh Pink 2.0 is
from Mike exotic and uh
you know that is one that I've worked uh
the longest on and the one that uh
really has been you know our Flagship
strain
um it's our most popular uh over time
and uh really has raspberry Terps tour
the uh the flower has a real deep purple
to a magenta coloration
and uh just very tasty
um you know she tests in the high 20s 28
and uh yeah she's she's been cultivated
I think in every single state that's
awesome and worldwide so she's uh yeah
we've been selling seeds that for a
while over in Europe in fact we met us a
guy from Norway who really loved the
raspberry Boogie yes yes
um yeah and that was all from like IC
magazine right you know because there's
a lot of Europe scenes that belong to uh
the group and uh yeah it's uh great to
so do you still have your IC magazine
magazines or did you ever have them I
never had them yeah but you were part of
the Forum yes yes going back along
that's where I learned a lot
um and then some of my really good
friends including totally uh BJ so nice
it uh yeah still see like uh true
cannabis yeah you know
um Barry Barry I partied with Barry in
Amsterdam we have some crazy stories
about him and I and uh
Dr Green which is Marcus from Greenhouse
he was on the Trinidad episode of Strain
Hunters but uh yeah partying with him at
voyagers and all over Amsterdam and good
people yeah he's hilarious Barry's a
really and he's really into weed he's
super passionate yeah
yeah and I ran into him at Spanish uh
when we were there yeah yeah
fantastic yeah so what are you uh
working on right now so right now
um I just finished uh growing out a lot
of offspring of projects I've worked on
uh we just released
um our Mountain Dew uh that has been
um really well received
um what is it uh Mountain Dew is Sour
Kush uh to the pink nice and uh Cassie
gassy has like this almost lemon lime
aftertaste that resonates on your
palette it's kind of like a black line
Reserve
kind of yeah like lemony Sprite tasting
almost like yes where it's super lime
and you taste the lime but it's Sprite
yep yes yeah candy but not Skittles I
like that exactly and I brought some
flour for you to try out nice yeah that
is awesome so yeah so working on uh the
Mountain Dews I have some others in the
works
um and so you know as a breeder in
developing new cultivars
um you know I've learned that if you
have like a a strain uh that you're
working on and for example
um I've been working on unicorn poop
Cross of the pink animal crackers
great bag appeal great structure
phenomenal High Tour but she doesn't
have that loud nose and we've grown out
you know hundreds of does it smoke loud
or no it smokes loud smoke does not
taste loud so the funny thing is is like
for me personally like I don't at the
end of the day if it tastes loud and it
tastes amazing I don't mind if it's not
loud in the bag it's okay like I mean I
wanted I want it to be because it's a
good selling point but at the end of the
day if it's like a sleeper and nobody
knows about it and it smokes amazing
that's okay too especially if the high
is good yeah so this is more like a
sleeper
um but I wanted to give her some flavor
so I crossed her to the raspberry Boogie
yeah because she delivers and it comes
to that and
um brought some flour for you to sample
yeah you grow really really really
Frosty good delicious flour everything
I've had from you has been that the
raspberry Boogie uh zerios was amazing
it had seeds in it and I Still Smoked it
you know I kept the seeds obviously but
yeah man that was some good stuff like
and it's it's funky it's got a funky
like uh almost sour raspberry like sour
cherry and raspberry flavor to it which
is really special yeah and um a very uh
Thick Smoke to her yeah um that is yeah
like a creaminess is that that so the
cereal milk in the cereals with the it's
like zerbert which has the skittle
sherbet and then that's cereal milk it
adds this nice creaminess to a lot of
the Finos so you look at the the loops
that we were doing a lot of them had
that bready creaminess that like really
it makes it for a Thick Smoke yeah a lot
of fun yeah it sure is
um and then a third project that I've
been working on uh is collaborate
operation with BJ SOG Army and that's
um working with pink ZaZa and we've done
some crosses with her yeah he's a really
good dude in fact that's one of the
people you're visiting here in
California yes yes uh we've been uh
together for three days visiting Farms
going to the concerts going to concerts
yes yes
in Oakland great time just really good
times I sold out for like three days
cool good stuff
so let's dive into some breeding talk
okay so as far as reversals you know
we've been chatting on the phone about
reversals for the last five years yes
yes so yeah and I think you uh you were
at a point where you're struggling and
you have worked it all out and I it's
it's such an individual thing for people
the reversal side I think it's a lot
more difficult than people think and
there's a lot of trial and error
involved and each room is different you
know I can write an sop for it but that
doesn't mean that it's going to work
perfectly the first time in your room
right
looking back with everything that you
know now what would you tell yourself
about that uh when you first started
um
take the time
to really think through the different
steps of the process because you know we
as farmers are very busy all the time
because there's you know a hundred and
one things that need to be done so you
prioritize those and really take the
time take them through so that way you
ensure that each each step of uh
breeding or reversal is done properly
yeah because I have found if I look back
at my steps of you know either
something's gone perfect you know better
than expected or uh terrible you know
it's not things are not working properly
and a lot of times you don't know until
after taking notes is one of your big
ones yeah yeah definitely keep a
notebook yep for each room that you're
working on because you know I mentioned
that we were doing four or five
reversals at a time yeah you got to keep
them all separate and keep them all
organized so yeah yeah we have a 14
light reversal room here where we we're
testing we're doing a lot of r d in
there as well but yeah taking notes is
essential
um not using LEDs is great I mean some
people get great results and that's fine
I'm glad they do my light spectrum of
choice is HPS ah okay 600 thousands what
whatever single ended doubling it used
to be 600s now without I use thousands
it's great but yeah the Des the HPS I
think is the way to go and then cutting
the nutrition by 50 percent
nice nice
yeah so uh do you find that when you do
that the plants turn more yellow on the
lower leaves I would say that the plants
stress more uh with the HPS and then
cutting the nutrition
um you could even cut the ppfd a little
bit but what you're trying to do is
stress the plant out and uh in
combination with the silver and the
stress I use a nano silver that's
sprayed every other day from about seven
to ten days before depending on the
cultivar till about seven to ten days
after depending on once you start seeing
signs but yeah what's what's your method
so we use STS and I use Garrett slots
proprietary method is that the four four
to one but it's a proprietary yeah but
yeah yeah yeah yeah so it is proprietary
but I will tell you that it's very
stable we start like a month before the
reversal oh wow um to uh spraying up in
two weeks into so it's a dose of STS yes
yes definitely not the four to one maybe
yeah so it's not stressful on the plant
yeah and because it's a very stressful
thing for the plant to reverse its sex
you know so let's not add to that and
I've had Distributors uh say like pure
sativa that
um the seeds produced with that reversal
there's zero intersex traits he never
gets complaints about our seeds or
Garrett seeds yeah and because it works
so I would rather take a longer time
reversing a plant knowing that the
outcome is going to be what we want it
to be right so but you know Mother
Nature still does her thing so what is
it one out of every 4 000 will be a male
oh no I mean you can have the the
express males and especially if you're
field testing that's a whole different
story yeah you know one in a thousand is
likely to express some sort of uh male
you know male plant but you can get full
male expression and it's just very
cultivar specific or cross-specific like
if you're dealing with Autos it's
depending on
um
a lot of factors and but you know really
stable stuff it should be like one in a
thousand like that's considered stable
if you have one in four thousand that's
awesome that is just yeah that's that's
what uh some books and some of these
yeah I mean the the Autoflower varieties
yeah if you're getting like one in a
thousand that's that's not too bad but
fifty but you got to think if you're
putting 15 000 of those out per acre
you're gonna have 15 plants you've got
to pull yeah right you know and I think
in the beginning a lot of guys were just
they just let it do their thing and
stuff will get seated but you know if
you have a good trained staff you can
pull those out you can you can identify
them before they're an issue especially
especially the ones that are fully
expressing yeah but you got to take the
time to be in there with the plants to
really be able to uh identify because
they were walking through the fields
yeah that's a lot of walking but you
know it is what it is yeah but you know
um it's a beautiful thing yeah it really
is so
yeah seeing Acres of Autoflower just
makes me smile right no no crappy days
there no I I agree with you
um proper reversal techniques are so so
important for breeding because now
everyone every once one wants to grow uh
feminized seeds uh uh for you know the
the different state requirements for how
many personal plants you can have at
home growing so
um would you say that 75 of your seed
sales are feminized and 25 are reg or
would you say it's even more I would say
mine is probably 90 10. mine's actually
more we still offer a few strains
regular because there are people still
looking yeah I have them too I offer a
lot regular but as far as what people
buy people really buy feminized seeds
mostly and uh yeah we're like 95 now so
yeah now 95 98 we'll we'll see you know
the occasional pink lemonade or um
um Mountain Dew other breeders buying
them I get other breeders and I'm super
happy you know to be honest I'm super
happy when other people buy my rigs to
breed with I think that's a good thing
some readers are like oh you should ask
permission don't you buy someone's
regular seeds right they don't ask
permission go ahead and use them go
ahead and breed with them breed your
heart's content and you know I'm just
happy people are you know buying my
genetics and are happy with them I think
you know there's it's you know it's a
personal thing but also it's like we're
breeding for other people and we're
breeding for the world I breed for what
I like a lot of times but I also am
aware of where the Market's going and
what people like and I want to have a
variety of all this stuff yeah no I I
think that's good because you know when
you
um look at the different states east
coast is different than West Coast
totally Midwest is different and so you
know what might be popular like uh Sour
Diesel in New York you know it might be
Skittles something here yeah they got
some pith your pith is a big thing now
yeah yeah those hazes I mean the pith
yeah the pif is super big the the black
Cuban Haze yes those are all real
popular
they started here though by the way just
so people remember I started in Santa
Cruz with the haze you know the Hayes
Brothers yes yes
uh back in the day uh I grew Neville's
Haze yeah you know greenhouse seeds and
I love Neville's I love the A5 the A5 is
a Neville's Haze yes and that was the
closest thing there is to cat piss
without being cat pissed it was straight
ammonia it just didn't have the skunk
behind it yeah yeah no that she's she's
great I've run her uh many times yeah
beautiful plant but uh so yeah so
depending on you know what's popular or
what they're looking for
um you know Oklahoma whatever
um then it's good to have that variety
yeah because somebody wants it somewhere
so totally you know and I think as
breeders we we want to make sure we're
giving people a good selection that's
right that's what we do yeah and they've
given people options you know because we
want variety we want people to breed
variety
um you know but the funny thing is you
know in the United States just like in
Europe they went towards everything
Hayes before Hayes there was a lot more
variety there too but we bottleneck
because we get so excited about stuff
and then there's the hype and then you
know these exotic streams now it's like
yeah everyone's jumped on and I gotta
have gelato and really there's so much
other stuff out there gelato is great I
have no problem with it but there's a
ton of other stuff
you know going through like like what
we're doing with our project with the
raspberry Boogie zeros yes yeah so
totally different direction and you know
what I think that's the beauty of a a
good collaboration yeah is you're going
to come up with something that's
um you know from the best from both of
us right it's a piece of piece of two
different people yeah right and put
together to make something better and I
think
breeding with intention is so important
and I think it's a lot of time
overlooked they're like I just crossed
this with this like I believe in
intentional reading and the the stuff we
do together that's intentional breeding
we're purposely Crossing these things
together with the intent of getting
something that's somewhere in the middle
that has something that's part of each
that's beautiful you know yeah some some
good contributing factor and the
raspberry Boogie's got a lot of Terps
zerios has a lot of chirps you know
together you're getting stuff that's
real terpy but raspberry then you get
creamy candy from the zerio so it's you
know it's it's just a good complex thing
and breeding with intent like that
you're gonna improve the gene pool
rather than either you know stay the
same or bring it down it's like it's
constant Improvement these little
constant things that we're improving and
you know you do something good and it
could be around forever true true yeah
we we all know a whole bunch that are
like that but you know that's the the
interesting thing is you know like an
AK-47 yeah it's phenomenal I mean it
always has been it's funny it was
mentioned on the last show too oh the
Cherry yeah or the one before yeah no
the AK-47 oh Cherry not Jerry no no no
the original AK gotcha so which is we'll
come back we'll get Simon on the show
one of these days yeah yeah he's he's a
good dude he is a real true F1 breeder
mm-hmm
yes because uh I think he was a biology
teacher wasn't he yeah something like
professionally and then
super smart yes he is yeah good people
and he's always good to see it's fanabus
yeah what's your favorite old school
strain
um probably Cinderella 99. nice yeah and
I still have
um an original mom yeah so she's uh
true Cinderella pineapple that's really
cool yeah where can people find out more
about you Instagram your website let's
talk about that yeah so Instagram uh uh
harmonica her name is uh mosca seeds so
at mosca seeds and our website is
moscaseeds.com
um you know we have a lot of information
on our site and
um it's actually one of the top ten in
the world so we also have another
collaboration that we've done that you
can find those seeds on your website yes
yes we have them on our website so yeah
the James loud mosca collaborations go
to moscaseeds.com check them out you're
on Instagram at mosca seeds not Moscow
Dash seeds not musket do you have a
bunch of fake accounts we try to get
them to take them down but yeah there's
like five different ones and if you
don't type in mosca seeds perfectly like
you'll get the other ones yes yes very
sure yeah well it's a pleasure having
you on the show today man a lot of fun
good seeing you will uh have to do this
again sometime soon when we announce our
next collaboration we're going to do
some Zoom style podcasts in the near
future so it'd be great to come out and
check out your farm oh absolutely thank
you for coming on the show and we'll
talk to you soon cheers
[Music]
hey everybody don't forget to like And
subscribe
[Music]