foreign
[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James loud
podcast today my special guest is Jason
skunk VA uh Steward of the plant uh he's
the guy responsible for uh being the
steward specifically for the chem dog
plant the chem the 91 chem dog and he's
in Montana now and he's got his own
Lucky Dog dispensary he started Lucky
Dog Seed Company years ago and uh
welcome to the show
Thanks James good to be here thanks for
having me definitely man so my big
question to start everything off is how
do you get to Montana
well that's a crazy story so I uh you
know I've been in the Bay Area since uh
you know a little bit before the
Grateful Dead ended in the 90s
um that's kind of where you get
deposited when you get deep into that
stuff which it was and uh you know I
ended up moving up to Sonoma County and
I was there for 30 years almost almost
30 years uh you know I had my daughter
there and got married got divorced lived
life there all the stuff it's okay to
grow weed there so that's kind of where
I was at love the place and then uh as
things got going with the legalization
in California prop 64 I just kind of I
was on probation for uh some some
cannabis crimes uh kind of kind of had a
lot of feelings pretty serious case you
know as far as uh how it can be these
days in California with cannabis I got
arrested in 2014 and I just uh as as I
saw legalization coming on probation and
kind of going through my case I just
started to dawn on me I wasn't going to
really be able to pull it together there
you know they when they come to you they
come with a wrecking ball you know and
they wreck everything for you and any
kind of convenience you think you might
want or with it or what they think you
may want they'll take that away from you
a day and they did a good job they
really did a good job of that so
um you know I I did pretty good there uh
getting through that but then once I got
through it I still wanted to you know I
had plans for legal cannabis and and my
place in it you know as far as clones
and seeds and of course flour
um and so I uh just kind of randomly got
asked by someone I used to know to come
up here and check it out in Bozeman
Montana never thought I'd even be here
to be honest with I've been everywhere
in the United States days but I never
came through Montana and I came up here
scoped it out right right before the
pandemic hit
um and you know fell in love with the
place it seemed like a good idea it
seemed like a beautiful place low-key
low-scale not not too much pressure not
you know a commitment as can you know
these things can be but uh so got the
ball rolling and then the pandemic hit
you know which slowed the inspections
and the licensing and I was planning on
spending probably half my time here it's
a beautiful place it's one of the most
beautiful places I've ever even been and
uh you know it's a lot of work as you
know and I had a partner who uh was you
know in it for a minute and then he just
saw how much it was and how difficult
it's going to be and you know it's not
going to be like a grand slam right when
we hit up the plate and so he bailed
that summer and kind of left me holding
the bag so uh well that would have been
uh let's see we've got our license in
like October of 2020 and like I said
there was just nothing going on until
um you know 21 2021 and then we finally
opened the doors to The Dispensary
um in 21. so uh I've been up here since
then I left in April of 21 for the last
time not really knowing what where I was
going to be and how long I was going to
be there and I just never left because
you know this stuff uh as you know
consumes all every bit of your time and
energy so
um that's pretty much why I'm here but
then you know on the on the same coin I
just I love this place it's amazing it
kind of reminds me of what the Bay Area
was you know and people around here
would hate to hear this but but um kind
of what it was like and uh then then you
know the late 90s the early 2000s where
things were you know people wave to you
as they drive by and people say hi and
things like that so that's kind of it
you know and things are going good I'm
really grateful that it happened I'm
grateful to be here and I like I said
when I was talking to you before we
started here that I was back in Sonoma
County and uh April for Memorial and you
know I I uh I found myself full of
gratitude that I was no longer there as
hard as that was to to face because it's
just you know
you know the people my circles were like
people who were deep in the black market
very much scaled up and it just it's not
it's not it's not going well you know
none of it's going well so so many
people are struggling yeah yes it was
really sad yeah it was really sad
yeah yeah yeah and so
it's really interesting because I see
what you're doing over there in Montana
and you have a lot of green flower as
far as what I could gather from you know
in the Bay Area everybody's like
demanding it's got to have purple color
and all these things and you're still
back you know you stuck with your roots
you got chem 91 you've got the the tits
and a lot of your genetics as well yeah
we we started off about 56 cultivars
here that I've been holding on to for
you know various amounts of time but all
long time you know like the chem dog
I've had in my possession for well
except for when I got arrested was a
short period of time but
um for almost 30 years now
um well I guess about 20 28 years yeah
and but we have uh We've gathered a lot
of other genetics
um and yeah we were running we started
off just running clone only is that
everyone's heard of just thinking hey
what you know that's odd the obvious
strategy and
um get people to come through the doors
because uh you know people have up here
it's a little different like it's more
homegrown more wholesome the customers
are I would say and they're like they're
not really interested in what they heard
about in fact they probably didn't hear
about it you know right and it could be
the demographic of this person can be
anywhere from 25 to 75 but it's the same
like some people come through the door
and they've heard of strains and they
want to check them out and so we've
tried to get stuff that falls into that
line you know
um and we've done pretty good we've
we've done some nice selecting but the
idea was to kind of get things you've
heard of you know the classics and then
now this now this year we're doing our
own selections we're gonna put those
selections out we're getting you know
really good response and
um it's starting to go out wholesale
around the state the lucky dog stuff and
you know it's making me really happy
because I always hope that would be you
know part of the journey you know that's
awesome yeah I do strains here now I
think that we offer
um and we have any day we have 54
streams out available for the customer
to choose from you know so what size
cultivation space do you guys have oh
it's pretty small we're under 2 000 feet
right now 2 000 square feet so
um and some of that's for breeding some
of that's for the nursery
um but you know it's the thing about
Montana that's interesting that I think
might people might be interested in is
that uh when when I came here was
medical and there was a thing called
tethering so you had to be Tethered to a
medical a medical dispensary as a
patient you couldn't shop around you had
to pick one and be Tethered to it
um now I don't know if they were allowed
to be if you could go to others but you
definitely had to be Tethered to at
least one
um so and then the other part was is
that it was vertically integrated forced
vertical integration so whatever you
grow whatever you produce the hash you
make the Horizon you make whatever it is
you have to sell yourself you can't sell
to other companies this is in the
beginning right and then uh you so when
I got here I honestly hadn't really
thought too much about oh my God we're
gonna have to build [ __ ] dispensary
um so we did and it's gorgeous and I
love it it's actually been like uh on
the rough days some of my you know it's
almost like meditation to be able to go
in there and kind of put you know my
artwork on the wall and you know build
the place out make it look nice and then
they got rid of vertical integration
um in uh January of 21-22 uh when the
full wreck went into effect here and uh
now we can sell wholesale we can receive
wholesale you know of course the
customers can go anywhere they want
so it's really interesting
yeah that's really cool I mean I like
the boutique aspect of it that is
vertical integration but on a boutique
level which you don't really see in
California very often if at all yeah I
would say it's kind of harder to do that
there I'm sure there's I know there's
some people who do it some companies but
we grow the Cannabis in the same place
we sell it to the customer
um our our solventless lab is in the
same facility
um our all of our breeding and Nursery
space is in the same facility so I mean
really it's kind of amazing because you
know you come to work and it's just
everything is here you feel like going
to make cash today then you go make cash
if you feel like you know whatever it is
you want to do like you know it's right
here so it allows us to have like a very
small team that's super dedicated to
what we're doing
yeah I love it it's perfect for me I
don't really I'm not a big scale guy
like I don't feel like there's always
just endless amounts I have to do I I
feel like you find that little sweet
spot where you can find some comfort and
happiness in your life but also you know
be creative and do the things that you
want you set out to do you know
um our tissue culture lab is upstairs
um you know so it's pretty awesome I
love it here it's not like what people
think it's very different you know
yeah that's really cool it sounds
awesome so let's take a let's take a
stab at the past and talk about uh how
you got your start in the industry not
even that let's talk about how you
started smoking in the Grateful Dead and
uh kind of dive into that
okay well I mean I started smoking when
I was you know a young boy in Virginia
14. I'm sure I smoked some swag buds
first and you know I was into it it was
it was pretty awesome I love the way it
felt my friends were into it uh but then
uh we were living my mom and my dad got
divorced my mom and my sister and I
moved into this little apartment complex
and there was some definitely some shady
people there uh in Richmond Virginia and
it was this cat across the street he was
uh I don't know if he was Puerto Rican
or I think it was Cuban actually yeah he
had like the hair and the gold rim
glasses and he was missing a leg I won't
forget that it was missing a leg it was
always by the pool and everybody else's
and all the other adults were at work
you know
um you know in the summertime when we
were raging out there with kids and then
I don't know what it was but one day he
invited me and my friend into his
apartment and he had an Alaskan Thunder
[ __ ] plant he said and he just wanted to
show it to us for some reason you know
we were I don't know 14 or 15 and uh now
when you open the closet door you had
one beautiful plant in there under a
metal halide light that looked like it
got shaken from a Street Lamp and it
just was like it was like holy [ __ ] look
at that the smell came at me and just
that humidity that life the humidity
came out of there and just wafted me and
that was it I fell in love and that was
it was Off to the Races you know and
then you know of course dead tour I
think everybody knows and if they don't
they should that uh you know the
Grateful Dead tour was like a bizarre I
mean you know you could get whatever you
wanted out there it was like what true
capitalism is you know you buy low and
you sell High
um and can't kind bud was always a part
of it you know so when I saw that first
plan of that Alaskan Thunder [ __ ] I mean
that was the first time I'd ever seen
kind bud
um smoked it shortly thereafter and in
Richmond you know you know we were
really we had an interesting little uh
kind of a culture there we like we had
like phenomenal herb When We Were Young
um it was just these older older this
old this circle of older dudes who were
growing you know the Nigerian and the
Afghan and the Beatrix choice and the
super skunk of course and Northern
Lights Number two but we just caught it
Northern Lights but I think it would
have been the number two as they say now
um you know the knights the Hayes I mean
we just had like an array of like
top-notch genetics that were you know
clearly selected by you know someone who
knew what the hell they were doing it
really was working and uh you know these
circles are small but in at the time of
Virginia you know like one plant would
get you five to forty years of
penitentiary and where does that number
come from well during the drug war 5 to
40 sounds good on a commercial on a
campaign ad and you know so it was
serious business and you know
um
you know growing up there was different
because like the drug war was we were on
the front line there even without even
knowing it I mean it was just you know
that it was just a lot of people being
incarcerated for cannabis and
psychedelics and you know uh those types
of things so it's like you kind of you
know you learned at a young age how
serious this stuff can be and how uh you
know when you make choices it can it can
affect the rest of your life potentially
because you could you know you would see
it happen to a guy that you know that a
friend of yours knows or whatever and so
grew to have a respect for these people
you know for these older folks who are
doing this because you know I could put
to connect the dots and like wow what a
dedication that is to like take that
risk
um you know yeah the weed's great is
amazing but it's also a lifestyle and to
take that risk for that lifestyle I just
always it just took me back you know and
kind of I don't know it was kind of like
mythical to me and you know I just
wanted to know more and so as as it as
as it goes in the you know early 90s and
late 80s late 80s really um The Grateful
Dead come through town quite often they
were actually banned from Virginia but
they still would pop through under a
different name surprised they were
actually banned by the state legislature
in 1985.
which is interesting I don't think that
happens to rock and roll bands or
anything else of that size but that uh I
think they probably wore that as a badge
of honor um but anyway
so you know eventually as I tell people
you know they came through and
brainwashed you know kidnapped me and
brainwashed me and dragged me all around
North America
asked me to do some shady stuff which
was really nice Shady it was all light
but definitely against the law and
always in the background always every
single day cannabis was the the you know
the focus because you know when you go
to a dead show and you're a kid and you
got you know you can make a little money
I mean in a Grateful Dead parking lot as
they say you just reach your hand up and
grab yours you know it's it's floating
there you just gotta go get it you don't
have to take some risks but
um so at the end of the day like you
know you wanted a ticket a place to you
know gas to get to the next show you
wanted uh you know maybe a place to
sleep some floor space in a hotel and
most importantly maybe the well the
ticket was always but most importantly
after the ticket was of sack of kind
buds
um that was the medicine you know that
kept you kept you okay on the road
because it wasn't like it wasn't like a
big fantasy it was a lot of you know
you're in big cities in America you know
it's it wasn't like exactly Spirals and
rainbows every today and there was a lot
of stress believe that and you know kind
buds what can you say so you know if you
get into it and then and then after a
while you start to say hey geez you know
like every time I go to a show I'm in a
different region I can be in Ohio like
I'm in New York or in the Boston area
and you know sure Virginia even Miami we
found a a grower down there that would
you know come and look for us one that
we would get to town and they would
bring boatloads of cannas and you know
you could sell 30 40 pounds of weed in
the parking lot in a day and and you
know drink fancy beers tonight you know
so it was a lifestyle and it was a big
part there's a lot of other things
around it that you know you can't really
talk about in public yet but but the
Cannabis was always like the focus and
so you know after a while as a 17 year
old kind of I wasn't really a runaway
but like a young person out on the road
in America like my big goal was like one
day I'm gonna you know save up enough
duckets I'm gonna get myself some grow
lights and and some clones from Virginia
hopefully I'll bump into one of these
older dudes they'll hook me up and uh
and grow some wheat that was the big
plan and lo and behold that's exactly
what happened luckily for me so
um you know and then when Jerry died I
was uh like I said they when you when
you uh when you follow the Grateful Dead
you're you certainly are going to get to
the Bay Area at some point San Francisco
Bay area and that's what happened to me
and you know there was no place for many
of us to go after the tour was over and
we weren't all the way on the road you
know there would be winter tour spring
tours summer tour fall tour but there
was days between and what to do where to
go and you know where can we be safe and
where can we just kind of be ourselves
without causing a scene and the Bay Area
certainly is a place like that Sanford
psycho is always well it's different
these days but it was always welcoming
to Freaks Like Us and uh but then how to
get to how do you like eat where do you
sleep how do you get gas how do you feed
your dog how your girlfriend like well
we sold weed in the park you know we
sold weed in panhandle Park you know
strangers and every Tuesday or Wednesday
you know they try to switch it up it was
only says today's sfpd would roll
through the park on dirt bikes and you
know they were always watching and you
know it's a lot you know it's like this
one little spot in the Panhandle we'd
skateboard do rail slides and hang out
and then you know with all kinds of
people in the city would come down there
you know and risk their own freedom to
get their their cannabis
um you know I sold weed the age patients
and cancer patients and just all kinds
of people who you know
you know like you could see that it was
the stress it was for them to have to
come down to the park and just cop wheat
from us [ __ ] kids was you know
um probably really stressful for them
but I would say that some of them they
had no choice there was no other place
for them to go and it helped them I
would imagine and of course there was a
lot of other people who were just
getting off work and just you know the
normal guy or you know who wanted to buy
some weed so you know weed was really
expensive in the city back then it was
four and a quarter for weight you know
and it was always outdoor never in the
indoor
um so it was hard it was a struggle and
that's where the word hate comes from
because you know we would take uh an
ounce of weed and make 10 8 out of it
and those extra two would be a little
extra cash for us and the rest of it
would go right back to the guy who had
the weight up on Waller Street and
um so anyway that's uh that's kind of
how it went and then I met a gentleman
from uh Staten Island kind of
coincidentally and he's the one who
ended up giving me the Kim dog we met in
the Park actually
um and he brought some indoor weed down
uh from Sonoma County he had moved out
from Staten Island from New York and was
trying to live out his uh you know
Grateful Dead Fantasy seeing Jerry
Garcia at The Warfield on Market Street
kind of like you know the Apex of
Grateful Dead Land is to be able to see
him see Jerry Garcia at The Warfield and
um he actually had a bunch of indoor
weed and it was 300 an ounce and so it's
just trippy because like you know a lot
of those people who we I went through
they're still like my brothers and
sisters a lot of them are gone now and
uh for various reasons but there are
still a few around and we have like this
special connection because it was not
easy you know it was you know you know
people getting robbed with guns I mean
my friends got shot on the street you
know and brought daylight I mean those
cops were always there you know like
some people who maybe got further into
drugs would you know kind of not leave
to go back on tour and they would stay
in the city and you're like you know
very of disappointing and sad to see but
then you'd come back and they're gone
after tour what happened so and so you
know what happened to Kathy you know oh
she's she's in she got locked up man she
got her second felony for holding weed
and you know she's going to be away for
a minute you know or or you know another
gentleman Moon you know he he became a
fixture in San Quentin because he's he
got caught too many times up on the
street there and you know changed who he
was of course like prison will do so it
wasn't always easy it was a lot of
stress it was just the days between
trying to get to the next thing and
anyway
um I think uh I think I'm going on a
little too much about that but but no
that's great this that's that's what
this show is all about you know I mean I
think
telling your story and and the story of
the other side of the Grateful Dead
because people hear one side about the
music and there's a whole nother side
you know on the other side of Shakedown
Street that uh you know I think people
need to hear and as we get older there's
less and less people to tell the story
to
you know that's something I've realized
and I've kind of I've always kind of
realized it but I somehow separated
myself from that thing and you know I
think lately I've just kind of accepted
that like you know I I have a good
memory of what those days were like and
I I have a vivid memory of it and
um you know if you look around like you
know Jerry used to say about what we
were doing that this is the last great
American Adventure he called the whole
thing you know and the whole thing is
it's it's okay we were on tour we were
following a band but it really was so
much more than that it was it was a
whole culture that went Generations deep
you know and uh I mean just like whole
like aspects of culture were developed
and became tradition and you know around
smoking even you know
um so it's just like I do think it's
it's kind of neat to be able to tell
people because you know we a lot of us
we were very reserved and you know you
you could you could uh definitely find
yourself not having anyone to hang out
with if you talk too much about what was
going on out there I mean weed was just
one thing you know that was just a a
small aspect a large aspect but like a
more minor aspect of some of the work we
were trying to do to kind of you know
bring some light into the world and you
know into a rather Dark World and um so
you know I'm kind of I'm so grateful
that that happened to me you know like I
do feel like I got you know kidnapped in
a sense and brainwashed in a sense and
uh and I'm I thank God every day for it
you know it took me to the Bay Area I
met my daughter's mother you know and I
have my beautiful daughter and you know
these things were all
you know
you know seemingly coincidence but when
you look back on it it wasn't it was
just it's been you know it's added up to
in my opinion for my life an amazing
life and I it hasn't been boring hasn't
been easy but it hasn't been boring and
I have that whole thing to think to that
for me it was that that you know broke
me out of that what would have happened
if it if I didn't decide to not go back
to Richmond which was a tough decision
you know hitchhiking from Kansas to the
barrier with nothing you know not even a
dollar was because the van broke down
this is a whole long story but you know
it was not an easy decision you know but
I'm glad I took the next step for it I
kept walking to Florida kept what's the
next adventure like what's this all lead
to and you know I'm grateful for it so
and it is a big part of it and that
gentleman who I met in the park who gave
me the Kim dog he was very grateful for
me sewing all this weed that day so he
could keep his California Dream alive
you know he's still a friend of mine he
just texted me a minute ago and um
uh you know like he told me hey you know
he was so grateful for for what I did
for him that day and I was more grateful
to him he just I don't think I expressed
it well enough but he um he's like when
this is all over he was a deadhead but
he wasn't on a tour anymore he was a
little bit older and a lot of the older
people were not into the new keyboard
player and so he uh he told me well this
is all over you know if you want to get
a house and some you know if you want to
do what you say you want to do I'll hook
you up with clones and I'll uh you know
show you what I know and he he pulled he
came through on that after Jerry died in
1995 and I never looked back that's
that's always well not what I've been
doing so
it's just you know one thing leads to
another and here we are you know we
gotta lead on on the shelf that
strangers can come in and buy it looks
like my living room but it's not it's a
long strange trip like very long
seriously yeah and I I feel like we are
the you know there's the evolution of
the Grateful Dead that turned into dead
and Company but we are the evolution of
the Grateful Dead especially working in
cannabis you know even Lagunitas Brewery
I think Tony McGee from Lagunitas he to
a degree in their company is the
evolution of the Grateful Dead and where
they went uh you know Craft products
uh yeah and it's it's just an amazing
beautiful thing and we're just so
blessed to have been able to get on this
path stay on this path and be where
we're at now I agree with you yeah I
like those Lagunitas guys they're uh I
like their style when I first came here
the regulations as you know are just you
know you can't keep up with it to change
none of it makes any sense I don't know
who makes this stuff up but anyone who
knows anything about this stuff but when
I first came here my uh the logo I have
has a pot leaf on it out of hanging out
of dogs nothing the inspector came he's
like oh you can't have that I'm like I
can't have that and at first right when
he told me I was like oh I got an idea
because I remember those guys in uh
Petaluma there they uh they had that
beer chronic I don't know if you
remember those
r-o-m-i-k and ATF came and raided them
and caught some smoking weed in the in
the uh in the brewery down there and
shut them down so they were like they
had to shut down ale right and I was
like that's funny and then the whoever I
don't know who it was at the company
sounds like you know those folks but
they uh decided to put censored over
chronic yeah and then every year the
sensor gets just a little bit smaller so
you can see chronic behind it with a K
that's I don't know how that could be
problem for people but
um so that was like okay we'll just do
that we'll just do what laganies do
we'll just put the sensor thing out in
front of the leaf and and then see what
they think about that you know totally
yeah boundary pushers I mean they're
boundary pushers you're a boundary
Pusher I've been pushing boundaries my
whole life and I mean I think that's how
we make progress is doing stuff we
believe in yeah yeah I totally agree so
let's let's dive into this this scale
let's let's talk about
the name skunk VA and how it got
associated with chemdog because I think
that's a great story you were on the
forums that was your name on the forums
I take it uh but where did it come from
well it was it did come from overgrowth
so I uh
um we have a mutual friend uh boundary
Pusher as well he says and uh he grew up
with uh
um he grew up in the Northeast you know
in New Hampshire and he somehow met a
you know G Kim dog at a official I
believe and you know he got turned onto
the chem dog before I met him we did
some dead tour together and uh you know
as things kind of progressed I had I got
the kill dog but I I didn't even know
this guy you know I was only hearing it
from my friend who you know who met him
back there and I thought it was really
interesting and you know that I got this
cut from this guy who I didn't know at
the time but he got it from him when
they did a trade for a super skunk cut
and uh in in the tri-state area kind of
in New York um some friends of mine in
Virginia came up and traded the number
six Super Skunk it's an F2 Super Skunk
for uh Kim dog and so at that point
um my friend from Staten Island who you
know I'm speaking about he he was the
one who went out and uh he got that cut
and brought it back so that's how I got
it I didn't know anything about the
origins it wasn't really a story to go
with it you know as you know because
you're you're my demographic that you
know those things did they didn't really
matter that much then like they were
just getting talked about because you
know you're really just basically
telling someone else's business you know
so then that's a No-No
um so we were rocking it out and and
going for it but then I saw High Times
article
um in I think it was 2005. I can't it
must have been 2005 and it was an
interview they were doing with with G
and I was like hey man that's your buddy
right here look at this he's got these
other chem dog sisters from the original
seat Pop I was like you know you said is
your friend he sent those t-shirts out
to us you know you you know why don't
you give them a call let's go get some
of this I wanted to get the sister I
wanted to I saw the sister in the
magazine I was like God damn that looks
like the chem dog would just better you
know like not better but stronger yeah
exactly and so yeah he was you know uh
he just wasn't he it seemed like too
much and so
um I don't remember exactly how I got on
to like the overgrow because I it wasn't
something that I was doing or even
really knew about but somehow maybe I
Googled something I really don't know
what it was but I saw that he was on
there I saw a picture of it these people
were talking about the Kim dog so I
joined it the overgrow thing and you
know I was like I just want to send this
guy a message I was like this might be
my one chance so
um I uh I did all the things and like I
said he set these t-shirts out with this
uh I might even have right here the chem
Dog logo like uh this one right here it
was on the front of the T-shirt right oh
yeah and yeah like that one right there
um and he had uh uh he sent a super
skunk went out because like I said he
got the super skunk from my friends in
Virginia
so he had the Kim dog since 1991 on the
front and then he had the dog smoking it
was a cool shirt and then and nobody
else had it was just like you know it
was a gift from him to my friend to me
and it was like it meant a lot to me of
course you know and so I was like oh I
got an idea when they let me make the
Avatar I was like I'll take a picture of
my shirt and he'll definitely recognize
it and then we can start chit-chatting
you know because I want to go get this
cut and and truth be told I saw on the
High Times article I was I was I read it
I noticed there was no chem dog anywhere
we had all these other chem strains but
not the chem dog and I said hmm maybe he
doesn't have it you know or something so
um so anyways I I did just that I put up
some pictures of my plants up my chem
dog pictures and my super skunks
um my sour diesels actually at the time
I didn't have a super skunk at that time
um my super skunk pictures were
polarized anyways different story but so
um and it worked he was like where'd you
get that shirt you know and we started
talking and oh oh so the skunk VA so I
had to like you have to give yourself a
name you know absolutely like hey we all
do this we have like everyone's got a
thousand different you know social media
things and you got to have the special
little name and everything like that but
this was like first time I'd ever seen
anything like this or maybe maybe there
wasn't much of this anywhere to be seen
anyway uh 2005 you know so I was like
skunk Super Skunk Virginia VA skunk VA
you know so that's what I did and um and
yeah then we got to talking and then a
month later I'm in New York with a
couple of chem dog cuts in a hotel in
SoHo
um and we met up and ended up not giving
me the sister you know give me the Kim D
and and what turns out to be the mass
Super Skunk
um don't know what what happened but the
the number six somehow got turned into
the mass Super Skunk
um grew took it back to California flew
back to California and grew them out
um the Kim D you know spit out a bunch
of bananas on it the first run uh we
were over feeding it and then
um and then the super skunk turned out
to be a I guess we didn't know at the
time it had similarities but it wasn't
the same one so we kind of passed on I
grew twice two crops of it let it go
wasn't didn't smell like super skunks it
was like it may have been good herb to
some but to me with the bias that I had
in my mind of the super skunk it just it
just it just was a disappointment to the
point where I didn't want to do that
anymore
um so yeah so that you know but the good
news is we brought the chem the chem D
out to the West Coast for the first time
it was out 2006 February and and then he
I gave him a couple of very healthy cuts
of the chem dog you know so it's uh
that's that's how I went that's how it
happened I never went back on there
again and and then I actually kind of
forgot about it you know because I just
did I just went through this whole
overgrowth just to kind of like get this
get this cuts from this guy or meet up
with him in this so
um you know fast forward six years
someone gave me some cuts that were sick
and or they weren't sick when they gave
them to it a few weeks later they were
definitely sick and then my plants were
definitely sick and you know I'm
searching the soil with a microscope and
you know trying to figure out everything
I can think of and so I'm like I came to
a loss I was like I don't know what the
hell's wrong with these plants they look
like they're being poisoned though and
uh so I I went on to uh one of the
um one of the newer Foreman forums and
uh you know I called myself the good old
dog you know because you still had to do
a name I forgot all about this [ __ ] and
then I posted the exact same pictures
because I didn't I really wasn't taking
a lot of pictures of my weed during
those
you know years of producing packs as we
say
um and somebody was like I got like well
not somebody I got like 45 people at
once
where did you get those photos did you
steal them from skunk VA and I was like
and they kind of I was like where have I
heard that before oh yeah that's right
and so I didn't even know you know until
then 2012 or 13. and then and then a
friend of mine came over uh uh and he
was like have you ever Googled chem dog
before I was like no not really what you
know why would it do that because just
to Google it and I was like all right so
I pulled out my phone that said skunk VA
cut Kim though I was like you gotta be
[ __ ] kidding me that's hilarious
I was like man I'm in the dark over here
I had no idea you know but that's how it
is you're running those packs those
years like uh you don't have time to you
know pay attention to all that stuff you
know so whether or not you're part of it
or not you're not you just didn't have
time or I didn't so never really thought
much about it until all that you know
yeah through through Micah's mutual
friends back in the day when our mutual
friend Micah who's my ex well one of my
business partners ex-business partner
whatever good friend we had a New York
basically the New York City Diesel it
wasn't so much it was the chem 91 and
they called it New York City Diesel we
had the sour diesel the New York City
Diesel and we had the dog d-a-w-g and
that was like the dog butt or whatever
and so when I thought chem dog I I
thought it was Kim d-a-w-g I didn't you
know
we didn't have the information as
accessible at the time and uh you know
but but the structure definitely the 91
uh has a very unique structure that you
can't miss with the with this like very
very similar to Sour Diesel with the
with the green leaves in that burnt Tire
on the nose you know I feel like it's
unmistakable it's not like for me it's
nostalgic every time I smell it I'm like
[ __ ] chem 91 from back in the day you
know yeah it does it lights up the
memory bank for sure for me too I agree
I love that part about it actually you
know it's like it's just it's not a
particular memory it's just like a
collage of just like the past and you
know you know in some ways better days
you know not to say these days are no
good but just you know more Adventure
more fun and just like really just hit
you right in the heart and I love that
about it I totally agree and I know
exactly what you mean
yes sour Diesel's another one it's like
all the all the genetics if you if you
were to smell the same stuff now it'd
bring you right back and that's the
beauty of of uh these Aromas you know
and I mean it's tied to so much more
than just oh it's good smoke man these
are tied to experiences we've had in the
past oh yeah yeah yeah I I I feel that
too and I mean I I would say my memory
my mom always used to point out to me
that you know she said ever since you're
born the first thing you do when you
find a new object you know a piece of
fruit or something she knew that I
didn't have experience the first thing
you do is stick it up your nose and
smell it and I could really she goes I
know that I noticed it because I'm the
same way you know and uh so I think my
memory is very much associated with with
my nose you know yeah me too and I mean
I think so so breeding and cooking and
all these experiences that revolve
around things like food and wine and
even even tobacco it's all Based on data
points right so like the more data
points you have the more of a library
you have in your head the the easier it
is to come up with combinations but also
you have these libraries built around
experiences it's true yeah that's like a
tribe of Terps I love it you know it's
uh I mean it's so you know and the thing
about it is it's like we in cannabis
were very much keyed into that part of
it like that's where we're at now you
know like the cannabinoid thing is not
all figured out but definitely we have a
lot of information when it comes to the
cannabinoids and now the next Frontier
is the chirpings how do they affect the
experience of cannabis you know like of
course things smell good or don't smell
good to people uh but they smell like
something and they definitely draw a
reaction from you and and uh you know
it's it's it's the new frontier like we
are just on the you know we're just
learning about it however these things
are not new they're everywhere on Earth
every human has had experience with
something that smells good something
that smells bad something that smells
dangerous something that smells and so
it's a part of the human experience it's
part of our DNA it's part of our our you
know our synapse system it's it's all in
our head and it's it's meant to be here
for us and we're here for it as it turns
out too as you know Growers and breeders
and you know in all kinds of fields
across not just cannabis of course but
right um I love that I think that's
amazing I think it's it's always
something more interesting coming down
the pike with it never gets old right
when it gets old you know and now that
things are going legal it's like now
scientists can get involved in
universities and bigger you know bigger
and more powerful and more well-funded
organizations can kind of get into this
stuff and break it down and we all get
to see what happens we all get to learn
about it and how it relates to us and
the relationship we have with these
things and the combinations of them and
what they do to our psyche what they how
do they impact our life even
um how do they enhance our life you know
and it's it's amazing you know and it's
it's been around since the beginning of
time on Earth and you know now we're you
know we're Alchemists of Terps now in a
sense Styles you know files like the the
skunks and the gas like basically the
gas the the rocket feel all these things
are Styles and it that's why it's also
so hard to measure them in terpenes
because they're not terpenes necessarily
the things that we really appreciate
where the gas were you know you can talk
about terpenoline and limonene for hazes
and we can talk about mercy and some
other things but once we start talking
about thiles tiles are really where
there's there's a lot of magic and
there's a lot of stuff we don't
understand and uh these relationships
with the cannabinoids and terpenes and
we're just starting to scratch the
surface of it I really believe that you
know we'll have a better understanding
over the next five to ten years
but uh you know it's it's amazing to be
on the frontier it is I agree with you I
I've thought about it and it's uh you
know when people come through the door
they you know they want the all right
what's your highest percentage of THC
and so the that of course I can't help
myself and you know the people who work
here with me my team we're all on the
same page with this like you can't help
yourself take a moment and just see can
we talk about that with this individual
for a minute and try to educate this
individual about why that's not that
important why it really doesn't mean
that much
um and we have some strains uh on the
table here that have low uh THC and you
know 19
[Music]
um and but they're amazing experiences
it's almost
uh you can't say that something with 10
more is actually stronger and it you
know why do why is it like that well I
mean we know a little bit we know that
brain chemistry changes from Individual
to individuals well that's a big part of
it we know that the cannabinoids are you
know they fit together in different ways
like a puzzle to
um you know to impress the THC on your
on your on your you know nervous system
your endocannabinoid system and uh and
that can change the experience
regardless of the THC and then now we're
at the point like you said we're at the
point now where we're starting to
discover that different combinations of
terpenes have different effects on
cannabinoids and how they relate and
communicate with our brain and our
nervous system and under endocannabinoid
system all through our body and it's
like we're just on the cusp of this and
to think that like I'll always like to
use lavender as an example because it's
like a single plant like cannabis is so
it's like when you smell no one's ever
repulsed by that like I don't think I've
ever heard anyone go I can't stand the
smell of lavender you know even in large
doses of it I think it's like it's a
universal kind of calming you know
relaxing kind of like bringing peace and
like changes your breathing it changes
your heart rate even and that's science
you know that's not because it smells
good it is but there's more to it than
that your brain is interacting with
those terpenes and allowing you to have
that experience of just calmness you
know and cannabis is that on steroids
it's it's when it's good it works it's
it's uh it can enhance your life to a
degree that it's it's hard to measure
you know it's hard for anyone to measure
you know even us you know day in and day
out this is what we do it's hard to
measure how important that can be you
know I've always known this about well
I've known this for a long time about
cannabis that we have a symbiotic and a
real time relationship with cannabis
that you know where as as Growers we're
like what do you need you know we're
like we're checking you out you can't
speak to me you know you can't like you
can't point you can't do anything but
you're still speaking to me you're
trying to tell me what do you need and
the plants also
was probably a much more success than we
have with it because you know we're like
kind of monkey brain you know we think
too fast and you know pay attention
enough we're hardly listen enough the
plan has no choice but to listen that
plant can't get up and walk across the
room and take care of its own needs and
so it has to communicate with us and you
know like we were just saying it
communicates through the cannabinoid
system of course and also uh you know
the camera the cannabinoids in it and
also the terpenes in it and and I think
that's where we're at now like you know
we've all been stoned out of our mind on
THC and um combinations of caminoids but
now the terpenes have got another thing
to tell us and I think that's where
we're at I think they're the plants are
trying to speak up and say hey we have a
solution here you know you just got to
listen you got to listen you got to take
a moment you got to stop and smell the
[ __ ] roses and it's going to be okay
you know everyone loves this I know you
do I do we all do you know I know you do
because we're all humans you know right
and that's our nature you know so it's
just amazing because we're you know like
you said we're right we're on a frontier
at the beginning of it and you know I
can't wait to see what's going to happen
next for sure for sure so let's talk
about breeding because you're you're
into breeding you you do breeding you do
funeral hunting you got lucky dog seed
company which I love it because I feel
like there's only a handful of guys that
are really stuck to their Roots you know
I'm I'm more of about diversity as far
as my palate has always been concerned
I'm always trying to explore and find
the new thing but you really kind of
have stuck to your roots with the chem
dog with the genetics and doing uh some
cool back crosses and you you do
incorporate some new genetics as well
but I feel like you've you know JJ from
Top Dog he's another one I feel like you
guys have really held strong in your
beliefs
right well the way I look at it and it
this is not something I had like a you
know a strategy at one point it's
something that's kind of happened and
here we are but
um you know I love the chem dog you know
like I I tell people this I have I have
you know you know you go through life
and you have you say the love of my life
right and what the hell does that mean
you start off and for me it was my mom
you know she was like you know a saint
you know like a goddess to me like she
no nothing could outdo her I fell in
love with it I still always will and
then you know and then you know I love
football so when I was a young man I
fell in love with the San Francisco
49ers long before I even counted the Bay
Area and that's the love of my life like
I can't wait till the season starts and
then what's next well a lot of stuff
happened after but it came to the
chemdot you know and I love her and I I
like to believe that she loves me too
she all I I think that these things find
their stewards whatever it's nothing
special about me that's not what I'm
saying but I'm it's what I tell people
is like you know when I talk to my
customers about having a clone for you
know 28 years
um you know it takes them a minute to
process that and when they do I'm like
you know
um you know it's like I've been through
all this stuff in life you know and you
know deaths friends dying dogs dying you
know the worst pains the highest of ties
the joys you know marriage divorce
raising a kid and there she is she's
still right there you know and so
um I just want to inject what we've done
in the past what back into it you know
so you know at some time you're like
well I was just getting stale well for
me it's not because that's what we're
still doing you know and it's it's a lot
of fun you know because you go through
the you know the mothers you know like
the pollen receivers that you're you
know potential and you you get to learn
them you find out them you give flavors
the experience the like the effect all
these things and then we cross it with
our chem dog and then we have a whole
new thing and it happens that way and
the funny thing about Kim dog is is that
even though she's old old girl like
she's dominating when she when you cross
her and that was the hardest part about
developing that that stud that I've been
using is that that the first several
attempts
um it was just too dominating you know
like everything came too much like Kim
dog because when you do back crosses you
know that's what you're selecting for
um so I started to kind of change my
strategy of selecting as I was going
through it and maybe just you know
finding certain aspects I love just
about a plant not necessarily like Kim
dog but like you know Vigor and
structure and just explosive growth and
you know I want someone to pop a seed
and just it just blows up and blows
their [ __ ] mind you know and that's
that's to me is has to be part of it you
know a person is going to grow you know
have a lightener and attend their house
like you know they don't want to they're
not gonna go through a hundred thousand
cuts to find the one they want to you
know they want to have like they want
some success and they may be limited on
their knowledge they may be limited on
their resources on what they can apply
to their project and I want them to be
happy so so I started kind of selecting
not just for chemdog traits as far as
Aroma flavor and effect though but also
like structure it's Vigor you know
um and then that kind of once I went
down that road everything kind of
happened quick and we found one that and
so how did we find that out like how do
we know we found it well we crossed it
to a lot of things that that I I when I
say we I mean me cross it to a lot of
things and then finding out that you're
getting some unique crosses you know
like f ones that are actually unique and
then bringing up the F1 you know
generation also not too much variety
like what when you buy a pack of seeds
of course you want to like kind of get
what you think you're getting you know
like you want to be surprised pleasantly
but you don't want to just be like I
don't know I don't know what they're all
different you know you don't want that
so I guess I if I'm a breeder it would
be because what I do is I make those and
then I go through them and I try to weed
out the stuff that has got too wide of a
variety or of course if they're just not
not a good mix and it's not desirable
um and then the win the ones that make
it through they got you know you could
say two three you know different types
of phenos that you can count on being in
there but certainly one that you planned
on seeing if that's who you are and if
you wanted to be surprised but you
wanted some really strong powerful tasty
gorgeous can well you know mostly words
scans depending on how you look at
um you would want to uh you that can be
in there as well you know so that's all
it is and you know we have we're now
branching out different ways we're going
to be doing we got some collaborations
coming up with breeders you've heard of
that are you know just in the beginning
stages
um but to up to to this point this is
what we we've been doing and we're going
to always continue doing that but now
it's time to Branch out now we're
breeding with our own in-house things
that we've made you know like Steps
along the way that we found
um so you know now it's going to change
a little bit it's going to expand and
I'm more focused on what I would like to
see from Lucky Dog seed company is kind
of like you know like there's there's
like a division in cannabis culture like
you have like this old school like you
say gassy and you know ogs and cushions
maybe and you know that kind of stuff
and then you have like the newer thing
you know and the newer thing is just
taking off and that's amazing it's
amazing to see but
um it would be instead you know what
I've learned about the older school
people is they're jaded you know as
older folks get you know like oh well
back of my day I mean I get caught I
caught my I catch myself doing that too
but I don't think that's useful to sit
in the corner and Snicker at the others
you know at other aspects of cannabis
culture I don't think that's useful I
never have thought that like division
was helpful
um of course it's inevitable at times
depending but I would rather like do
collaborations with with some of those
breeders and and and that style of of
cannabis that part of the culture and
just kind of like you know maybe a
little educating maybe a little bit of
just like enhancing and maybe just like
creating things that are even better
than either either side of that I mean I
think that's the goal is to you know
it's like if you're just breeding to
cross these things together and you're
not improving the genetics on either
side what are you doing it for you know
at the end of the day we're trying to
improve things and like I think chem 91
is an amazing classic but there's
definitely improvements that can be made
with the structure that's a good example
exactly you know and that would be like
reverse what I'm saying and that's I've
had that experience like I get plants
you know now that I'm like wow look at
that it's amazing but it smells you know
to me it's like the unique odor and you
know Aromas and flavors
um that I'm into I mean the high is
always going to be top for me because I
just some stuff you know in my customers
verifies like oh yeah you know I was
getting this such and such this place
and it just doesn't get me stoned I
smoke every day I love it everything but
it's got to get me stone you know and
I'm like yeah I get it and then I pull
out you know some Crossroad chem I'm
like I think you're gonna love the
flavor of this I think it's going to hit
you hard and I think it's going to get
you stoned exactly every time you smoke
it and it's true you know because Kim
dog has that magical cape you know
character you know and uh Sour Diesel
all these types of things they're always
going to get you rip roller Stone the
way you like to be no matter what and
for sure I mean really it comes down to
that you know yeah and there's not a lot
of stuff that you you you know you build
a tolerance to it to a degree but it's
not like so many other things you have
the green cracks out there and stuff
that you know where it's like a week
later it doesn't get you high chem box
Sour Diesel Sour Diesel at 14 will give
you couch lock you know oh yeah plus the
Terps you know I think refiring the
joints uh is a true test and the the
chem 91 all the all the chem dogs sour
diesels a lot of the crosses even you
get that you know Roach Burn where you
fire a road chip and it still tastes
good exactly yeah that's important too
like all the way down to the end that
sweet sweet grippy you know
gotta happen so uh as far as uh what
substrate do you grow in what kind of
nutrients are you using what it what is
uh your philosophy on growing and
cultivation
well we here keep an even open mind when
it comes to our nutrients we grow in
Cocoa we grow in pots we we uh you know
drain the waste of course we try to do a
little crop steering you know dick
around that
um lately what we've been doing is uh
we've tried different when I opened this
place uh several of the nutrient
companies that are well known they
reached out to do their marketing and
the way a lot of it goes down is I'm
sure you understand that they'll like
send you a whole crop load of of their
products and say hey will you run this
you know you know this and that see what
you think so we did that and my program
that I had down in uh Sonoma County for
for a good while now for almost you know
almost 20 years really always works well
for me you know
um you know I used to grow organically
in the 90s and in the early 2000s and I
had a lot of success with it but as
things got bigger it just wasn't it
wasn't sustainable for me
um to have the keep the quality up the
way it needed to be and so uh you know I
got turned onto Hydroponics and and you
know salt-based nutrients and such and
um so up here I couldn't get some of
that stuff the shipping on liquids is
really expensive and you know a lot of
it's not even available here so I had to
kind of open up you know the mind and
think outside the box and so we've tried
all kinds of stuff we've tried the
Athena it was okay we had a we had
pretty good success with it I mean the
buds were big and all that but it didn't
uh it kind of the the final product was
a little less than desirable for me yeah
for me it all tastes like Athena that's
my my complaint with Athena it looks
great but I feel like that it tastes
like Athena and not you know I think a
lot of people get good results with
Athena but it's not my cup of tea yeah
um and I agree with that and uh however
so you know we right now we're running a
veg Bloom from hydroponic research and
we like it just fine
um so we we had this interesting
experience you know like the Athena has
that new product called fade where they
you know people a lot of people were
complaining about how harsh the weed was
too much nitrogen at the end or whatever
and so uh you know they sent some of
that out we tried it out and we actually
for the first time in a long time I have
to be honest like they said you know
plant Health at the ends you know the
problem with hydroponic growing is the
flush you know of course we all know and
the plant starts eating itself and Kim
dog is like it's like that times 10 like
it gets bad you know it's like it's kind
of sad like you got to get your pictures
on day 56 you know
um maybe even looking for it
um so you know it starts to eat itself
it starts to consume itself and so
um we've been like you know getting some
data from uh Leaf analysis the different
points of time
um we're delving into that to kind of
see like when at what point does these
things start to become consumed you know
like what we what day do they start to
get consumed and like what can we do
about it and while we're doing this we
know we're [ __ ] around with calcium
and you know all these things and
um you know not really a lot of success
maybe some you know somewhat something
notable uh but we did run their fate I
gotta say I don't want to do like an
Hatter but we did run it and the plants
looked green and healthy at the end you
know like when I say green they had you
know a lot a lot more color they weren't
like brown eaten leaves is what I mean
nice and you know it's like I know they
recommended we did what they said
um and we went and all the way through
probably gave them fresh water for three
days I think and I was like yeah this
shit's gonna burn bad it's gonna [ __ ]
hurt us
um and the thing the first thing I
noticed we didn't have one little tiny
Speck of Atrius and well I always have
it you know the butt when the big buds I
always have a little bit like it's not
you know and it always occurs in those
last two weeks you know it always occurs
in those last seven days I mean in the
in the mind it's like well of course it
does you know the plant's not growing
anymore it's just kind of finishing out
you know the mold's always there the
spores are always there
um you know you try to keep them out but
they're they get in
um and so in in your mind you're like
well of course you know that's just part
of the deal right it's always been part
of the deal but so we actually didn't
have any and that was like it caught me
off guard I was like damn because they
didn't mention that when they talked to
me about it when they're asking me to
try it out and I was like wow that's
interesting so
um so then what we did is we we switched
back over to uh we did one with the veg
Bloom program we just stuck with the pro
ground we didn't do anything too far we
added some some gypsumen some calcium
carbonate and stuff like that overloaded
it with that and you know
um those things are a little bit more
uh they didn't I don't see the results
that I hear about with that like I I see
some result but that the impact is not
as what I hear it's in my experience you
know
so and then you know we had a little bit
of tryitis and we already got it well
then eventually we smoked that crap
where we only gave it plain water if
there's a smooth as smooth as can be so
what we're doing now is we're going to
do The Cutting Edge four part uh soluble
powder system
um and then we're gonna switch over in
the powder powder yeah
good stuff I like Uncle John I think
they got a good product I think the the
flavor at the end of the day I'm a
flavor guy and I want my way to taste
good and I think in a cocoa type
environment it works really well I
totally agree with you and and we were
when I was talking about what I used to
run before that's what it was that was
the base with many other things to kind
of enhance it but that was the Basin I
was always so happy but and like I said
Uncle John and they're good folks man
like they get it you know like you know
there's a reason why I can't get it here
that sucks for me but the reason I
actually am I'm okay with it they don't
go to the big distributor to have them
they're like no we don't want to be part
of that you know we'll be smaller scale
we won't be able to reach everybody but
at least we'll stay more true to our
values and I respect that and that I do
like being part of that so
um and that's what you can't get up here
so but however we're gonna
um we are gonna try that just one way
through all the way we haven't done that
one yet we're gonna try that all the way
through once and just see what the
results are and then but really I think
what our strategy is going to end up
being is we're going to leave that in
the last two weeks we're just going to
do Bloom and fate and so uh you know
that's kind of why I tried it out but
this the fade stuff like um it worked
like this the smoke was smooth and
smooth as can be we still had all the
flavor
um and I think we're going to be able to
do even better when we when we start to
mix and match we don't run just one
program we just take what's what works
and we apply it when it needs to be you
know when it needs to be used you know
so I think that's kind of our strategy
that the long story short is that we
just try to think outside the box
understand what we're doing you know
never ever do something without knowing
why you're doing it because I think
that's a big problem out there is like
this is what you do and it's like well
why do you do that and if something goes
wrong do you know what to do you know if
something starts to go a different way
if you're trying to enhance the Terps
you know what to do if you're are you
trying to you know different strains
require different you know uh nutrient
you know requirements and so you know
that's kind of you know what our
strategy is it's like to I guess that's
what I've been my answer to that is you
know we're just trying to mix and match
and find what works with us but Athena
Fades part of it no that's awesome I
love hearing stories like that
so I got a question for you okay if you
were to uh
with all the knowledge that you've
gathered over the years and you were to
go talk to your younger self that had
been doing this for about two years what
piece of advice would you give yourself
well the first piece of advice that
still stands true today
that I did get was uh never ever ever
think you haven't figured out never ever
ever
um
speak when someone else is telling you
something you know like if someone's
sharing what their experience is and
their knowledge if they've been growing
for one year to have it you should still
listen because you're probably still
going to learn something from the minute
and this is the way I was presented to
be the minute you think you have it all
figured out is the minute you're gonna
start failing because you know your
confidence and let's just say ego and
you know you've made it by yourself now
and so that that advice still Rings true
like I always remember that yeah I have
learned a lot you know I surely have but
that doesn't mean I can't learn
something from someone much younger than
me and less experience for me and so
that was good advice and if I had to
give myself advice then I would say
share what you've learned you know like
as you learn things be more open about a
share it you know
um that's pretty much it though I guess
you know I don't really have a great
answer for that one I don't really know
I mean I think that was a great answer
to be honest with you I think that was
really good
right on yeah because I feel like it was
it's it's been difficult for me to come
out of the shows like I've had a hard
time with it you know like we of course
we were going cannabis of course that
could get you a lot of trouble we were
also involved with some other crazy [ __ ]
and it's just you know it was a culture
of like you got to keep your lips sipped
you got to like you gotta walk the line
don't let anyone know what you're doing
you know like I I've done years people
great good friends close friends can
come to my house and they would be you
know they buy weed from it they get
tupperware's super skunk and chem dog
from me they knew I was growing it they
never would hear me admit it you know
they would they stopped asking me like
do you grow this week I'm like dude I
told you you know I don't know and don't
ask me that you know so I took that a
little too far I think and I would if I
had anything to change about my somewhat
younger self I would I would have made
that decision sooner for me the law
enforcement did that for me you know
ironically
um you know when they came and rated me
in 2014 well they took everything from
me Plants included
um I got arrested for uh like nine
felonies you know manufacturing
controlled substance all the way down to
possession with the intent and control
you know manuf uh possession of
concentrated cannabis you know uh you
know and of course the manufacturing of
a controlled substance being the most
serious of those crimes it's a very
serious crime it it carries a potential
of seven years in the penitentiary in
California so you know they had every in
their mind they had every right to take
my life away from me
um and they did a very very good job at
that you know um I mean my daughter was
living with me more than half the time
she had more uh her custody was uh with
me more than 50 percent of the time uh
because her mom worked a lot more than I
you know I worked at home because I had
grows around the county and down in
Oakland and so I had more flexible
schedules that was the reason why but
that all suddenly ended the day they
came and kicked the door in you know
what I mean all the doors influenced you
know and so
um you know my life changed quickly and
rapidly and it seemed like a kick in the
[ __ ] nuts and of course it was but it
didn't take me too long after that
um to realize that they actually done me
a favor I was on a hamster wheel that
was going nowhere I mean I was just
working my ass off to pay the bills so I
could grow another crop you know and you
know maybe I mean I was having a lot of
fun in life of course we were making
money but you know
um but the bottom line is is like I was
working too much it was just too much
um and it was going nowhere it was the
beginning of the end for that lifestyle
I guess you could say in California at
least and really everywhere now probably
most places and so it allowed me to
forcefully
you know put me in a different position
where it's like well what now you know
and and uh and then that's when I
started to say you know what I you know
I'm gonna focus on on making good
genetics you know and sharing with
people people always ask me that you
know for clones and for genetics and you
know for seeds and stuff like that and
so it just seemed like an opportunity
all of a sudden and just get through the
probation get through all the the things
that I had to do the community service
and all the stuff that they make you do
and you know all the sleepless nights of
oh my God I'm still growing weed up in a
house I know they know where I live I
mean not that I told them but they know
where I live and
um they could come any minute and you
know so lots of stress and you know I'm
actually grateful that it happened to me
I really am I mean it was hard and you
know losing everything that you've
worked for in a Flash is nothing not
never going to be easily accepted or
it's never going to be easy no and you
know it's like uh but but these
opportunities give us chances to start
over and you know they really really
help you learn who you who you really
are you know I think everything in life
I think things happen for a reason I
mean I I've seen too many things in life
to know the things in life happen for a
reason and we have setbacks and you know
that there's there's always ups and
downs and that you know if you're up
there's always going to be times where
you're gonna be down and if you're down
you're up again yeah and you can't
appreciate one of the other you know
without the other you know you got to
have that contrast you know and right
it's just life I mean you know you don't
when you do what we do like sitting
around feeling sorry for yourself is it
ain't gonna work out like you got to
keep on moving but it was it was
humbling because you know I was you know
40 something and I'm 50 now I was 40
something and I'm like now I'm around
all my friends who I've been giving cuts
to you know oh my God I lost the chem
dog cut again can you give me another
now they're building like businesses and
you're over here going you're struggling
you know and it was humbling it was hard
and the character building really like I
got back to my roots about who I am like
the things about me who that I was
starting not to like like you know those
things were not important anymore you
know like they weren't part of who I was
suddenly and I was grateful for that
like truly grateful for that and I still
am and you know it's like you said it's
like one thing leads to another you know
and that I'm in Bozeman Montana it's the
last grace place on Earth I mean it just
doesn't get for me it doesn't get any
better than this I love the people here
I can walk you know 10 minutes away I've
got my hot springs you know 20 minutes
away I've got like the most beautiful
hike that you can imagine if I want I
can go 25 miles out into the Wilderness
you got to bring your bare mace the
Moose is the most dangerous animals out
here but besides that I mean it's heaven
on Earth and I love it and so without
that event happening to me in 2014 I
wouldn't be sitting here and I'm fully
aware of that and there's not not been a
moment where I wasn't aware of it and
I'm grateful even on the hardest of days
I'm grateful so yeah yeah it's contrast
you know it's a it's it's how you
appreciate life it's how you appreciate
things it's how you not become bored and
complacent is by having things in your
life that have happened that you can
look back and go man I can't believe I
went through that I'm still I'm still
here you know when you get knocked down
you get back up and you keep working and
I think
you know I've had bouts of depression
through my life or whatever but I think
the biggest thing for me is just to keep
working and keep driving and I don't
have a lot of work-life balance with
what I do right now but I will someday
and I I'm okay with that you know yeah I
don't either at all but I mean I I live
in the shop I I have built an apartment
here because you know it's what I had to
do you know like going out it's very
expensive here a lot of people don't
understand that about this place it's
you know Tom Brady lives here you know
like Bill Gates lived here you know like
it's a very very wealthy place and so
you know buying or renting a house
around here is is it's it's gonna take a
lot you know so I live here and I don't
mind it at all I love it being near my
plants I get up my dispensaries my
living room it's where I sit and watch
popcorn and watch my TV show you know
it's it ain't that bad yeah when you
love what you do man it's not that bad I
I totally get it exactly yeah yeah so
let's uh talk for a second about how
everybody could find you if they're
looking for seeds or they're looking you
know genetic seeds if they're looking
for flower where can they find you
well we got a website I think that's the
best source we have it's uh
www.luckydogcannabisco.com
um we have on that website you know we
have our Flower menu we have an
integrated Flower menu
um about what we have daily and then we
also have you know like if we ever had a
strain even if we didn't keep it we'll
still keep the the photos in the library
there and it's just discontinued
um because you know we're not going to
try to forget it you know that doesn't
mean it was you know we lose a thing
every now and again we've lost
two strains since we've had other people
besides me taking care of it you know
luckily nothing too crazy but it happens
a little mix up here and there
um so there's that and then there's a
whole other section on the seed uh side
of it where you can find vendors that
sell Lucky Dog Seed Company seeds and
you know learn a little bit about our
seeds
um and then we have a fun thing going on
my cultivator his name is uh Eli but he
goes by Ginger grower on the Instagram
he's kind of he's kind of a big deal
he's kind of famous you know but uh so
he's the cultivator here he's like my
right hand man when it comes to the
plants and I'm lucky because if we see
eye to eye like we totally we don't ever
like see things differently which
you know is amazing really when it comes
to the plants you know like he
understands that the plants are living
creatures like our dogs and cats and our
loved ones and that they need to be
taken care of accordingly
um and he does a great job I don't think
that I could have found and I'm so lucky
it wasn't anything I did it's just it
was a lot pure luck uh someone who cares
so much about it to the point where I
don't even think about it when I can't
be part of that process and that happens
when I'm running this business and
that's been a hard part for me letting
go of that somewhat I've never been able
to do that now I have to do it and I
trust him but we have a new thing where
we go out on that uh Trail I was talking
about the Cottonwood South Cottonwood
Trail um so we got a new blog we just
started it was an idea we just popped in
her head we walked out about
um it's about three miles out to this
Rock by the Gallatin River and we take
one of our pre-rolls just one of our
strains and we go out there me him and
my dog El Toro and we smoke it and we
just kind of recorded our experience and
we try to be vocal about you know know
how we feel about it and it doesn't have
to be just okay this strain and then it
could you know how cannabis it is like
it can like like we were talking earlier
it can kind of invoke a thought or a
memory or you know an idea and so we're
trying to like do that every we're going
to be doing every Sunday before the shop
opens because we have to get back to the
shop because on Sunday it's just me and
him working here so I got to run the
counter and he has to go out you know
he's doing his plant thing but we do
this first and it's going to be fun I'm
really looking forward to it so you know
some pictures we could be talking about
dogs or flowers but we're gonna base it
around a strain every week you know
um and and I I think that's good so I
think you can come there and enjoy that
with us if you like it's just beginning
so bear with me as I get it going but
yeah I would say that's the central
we're trying to make that the central
spot for the seed company and everything
Lucky Dog cannabis you know that's
awesome
man I really appreciate you coming on
the show today it's been a pleasure
yeah it's been great man I uh I really
appreciate it thanks a lot James this
has been awesome man I've never done one
of these with the video and I'm doing
all right all right yeah doing great man
I'd love to have you come out to the
studio come check out the facility see
what we're doing here uh maybe line up a
collaboration at some point man I I
think I'll be down there actually pretty
soon like in this month so if you want
to hang out I'd be happy to man that'd
be great yeah absolutely the part about
pillar flower to show you oh I I bet you
do me man you I was telling my uh
girlfriend uh she owns breeders direct
seed company and I was talking she was
like who's uh James loud and I was like
he's a he's been breeding cannabis for a
while and he's been you know he's had a
couple different companies this is what
I knew about you and he's made a lot of
things a lot of amazing things you know
um and then on top of that I said but to
me the thing that I like about his
um you know your feed or your your like
your social media thing is like if you
want to know about actual seed
production or if you want to know like
actual seed protection on the scale and
what it takes and even like you know
what I mean by that is like making the
seeds you know like it's not that
complicated to make sense but on scale
it can be rather complicated especially
when you're doing feminized things like
that you know and I've actually learned
a lot from you about
um scaled up seed production which I'm
fascinated with it you know so you know
kudos for that you know I gotta say so
I've learned a lot from you truly I got
a reading book coming out that should be
out by Thanksgiving we've been working
on it for a long time it's been over
five years and it's really detailed and
it really has a lot of good information
and I have some of the best people
besides myself some of the best people
in the industry that have contributed to
it and I'm super excited to have it out
and I'll definitely be giving you a book
so that's cool man I I remember reading
about that at some point somewhere so
that's going to be amazing it's like
there isn't a lot of that out there you
know there's not a lot of books about
breeding period I mean what what do we
got botany that's about it right so yeah
I mean I think the Cannabis breeders
Bible uh it's it's outdated though it's
you know that was 25 years ago you know
around the time Jerry passed I think
that came out so 23 years ago maybe
right yeah anything from that time we
can't be outdated because you know the
information was so limited you know so
like tissue culture is a great example
that like we're delving deep into that
I've always been under I've been working
under a hood for a long time doing other
things and yeah um we're gonna actually
be teaching tissue culture classes in
Southern California
hopefully starting right around the new
year you know life is so busy it's hard
to get everything done but
um we're going to be teaching classes
there we have a uh
um like a rather a large house near
Disneyland that my girlfriend owns
um and we're going to turn the garage
into like a lab I mean it's already as a
lab now but like a lab where we can
teach you know cool
um so we can you know have companies or
individuals of all types come out you
know and it's like a bed and breakfast
you stay five days you four days
Hands-On you get a day off in the middle
to go to the beach or you know go enjoy
the area whatever you want Disneyland
whatever you stay there we're going to
feed you you know amazing food
um it's like paradise you know and so
it's gonna be cool you know I'm looking
forward to that that's like the next
thing we're doing you know here so
looking forward to that really cool kind
of like I think the to solve the problem
of some of the pathogens and you know
the uh you know hop Layton is the one
the buzzword now and a good serious
thing but there's more coming you know
like oh yeah there's so many more
pathogens people don't understand and
there's systemic bacteria and there's so
much you know it's like we have a tissue
culture lab here we do mirror stem
excision we have a yeah we have
We have basically clean tests for we
have dirty tests that we have clean
tests with our plants my partner Justin
Gibbons does some amazing work and uh
yeah I'm all about tissue culture it's
the it's a it's a it's a good answer to
a really shitty problem it is and it's
but the thing and it's we were talking
about the outdated book and it made me
think of it as like
um so you know like tissue culture is
not a new thing it's been around since
the 1800s yeah every Orchid you buy as
you know comes from tissue culture but
people you know the first time I got
turned on to it someone handed me a
tissue culture kit from uh uh yeah yeah
Graham that's it he's like here take
this go figure it out and tell me what
this is good for you know so I did it
was like 2006 pulled it off I have
things notable tissue culture going on I
don't even think we caught it at the
point just tissue culture and then he's
like what's it good for I said honestly
I don't really know I think if you
wanted to take a plant to Barcelona this
would be the way to go but besides that
and then the answer for all of our
problems was right there and know that
well not all of our problems but some of
our problems you know now was right
there so luckily I got a little Hands-On
then and uh I was actually excited to
know like oh man I'm gonna have to learn
I'm gonna have to have a tissue culture
that because I love doing lab work it's
like my thing I like being under the
hood I love
sterile environments not you know like
creating them and just I don't know what
it is I just love it so it's it's good
but I think in order for us to get
through this we're gonna have to do more
than a few of us offering clean you know
stock we're gonna have to actually show
people like this is the protocol this is
how you don't spread it this is how you
do the testing you know we're learning
all these things in real time but more
importantly this is what you can do to
cure something don't throw it away if
you if you know what you know what what
I know if I can share that with you and
if you can apply that you know you don't
have to throw that very rare cultivar
away you can maybe save it it's worth a
try you have an opportunity here you
know or or just keeping it clean in
general like you were talking about
systemic pathogens just nodal tissue
culture helps with that you know so you
know all these things like if you don't
grow roots for you know months then
eventually those path the systemic
pathogens in the root system they're
eventually gonna they have no food
they're gonna die they're gonna go
somewhere else you know so
um I love it man I'm into it oh yeah
just I was gonna mention one more thing
that a lucky dog Seed Company we just
had another drop drop today we've been
working on this particular drop since
January with the testing and getting
everything ready and selecting making
sure we have what we want I just want to
let everybody know that if you go to our
website
www.luckydog cannabisco and you go to
the seed page you can see all of our
vendors that will be carrying our drop
those vendors should have all those next
week uh stuff like dog Beach to Virginia
Beach Afghani cross with the chem dog
and pull dog skunk dog cross with the uh
uh with the chem dog as well and many
many others we have 11 11 to choose from
several are unfortunately rather limited
but uh pretty special we have all the
photos and we're selling a lot of the
the product here at the shop so check it
out I think it's uh worth a look see
well I really appreciate your time today
man I look forward to seeing you in the
near future yeah you too man thanks for
having me on awesome have a great day
all right YouTube Take It Easy
[Music]
hey everybody don't forget to like And
subscribe
foreign
[Music]