[Music]
[Applause]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James loud
podcast and today our special guest is
John from greenb how are you doing today
John I'm doing really good man thanks
for having me absolutely thanks for
coming out thanks for driving down uh
you missed TP Oni but you still made it
for the podcast this week you know after
leaving Vegas had to get up and you know
check in with the fam up there and you
know get the kids set up and then come
back down so it wild I went back toback
from Vegas to tpami to a podcast
yesterday and now a podcast today we we
sometimes we don't film one a week like
it looks but a lot of fun yeah no that's
sick looks like you've been active you
know I was I was out in Michigan then
drove all the way back to Oregon drove
down to Vegas did the whole MJ and then
drove back up home and then come back
serious driving serious living luckily
you know with the Vans these days you
can you know have your little studio
apartment in there too you know oh yeah
it's like a house on Wheels it's pretty
amazing it works good you know y so what
have you been up to lately um really
just uh doing some work with uh reverse
the Sour OG through that by a bunch of
cams um just trying to find some good
you know OG camline varieties just
because that's my favorite and that's
kind of what I'm liking I feel like it's
making a huge comeback you know I got
some real Sour Diesel flour in my bag
right now and I've got some good OG as
well but like OG and and sour and those
chems are I feel like making a comeback
maybe not in the bay or in La as much as
in the Hills right so the guys I know
from Humble the guys I know from Oregon
we're all talking about sour and OG and
where can we get the gas well that's
kind of what we've been talking about
for like a couple decades now you know
we're for sure you know the late late
90s early 2000s at least in Eugene it
was you know we had that's what was
rolling through and everyone was doing
the sour diesel you know it's different
than ajs the East Coast sour d and AJ
sour d but like the East Coast sour d
that everyone was rocking and you know
doing their thing with and but that was
you know a lot of us were smoking when
the ogs came up and everything obviously
they're just super um desired at least
from the old heads that like that kind
of because we had we had Trinity up
there too yeah no I mean I'm I'm very
familiar with the Trinity the fourway
the
snow snow dude the corn oh I got this
chauffeur that reminds me of the old
corn no way that's so amazing yeah I
mean and then we had we had the snowbud
that not the there's a couple different
snow buds but there was one from we got
from Eugene that was amazing the super
cracked out one that's not like burnt
rubber and was just yeah it was a little
pod oh my God amazing that one was so
good yeah I mean so a lot of our
genetics not not a lot of them but a lot
of the good ones through our group of
friends came from Eugene you we got the
dog Bud from Eugene which was the it was
a chem a chem dog bag seed I think West
Coast dog the dog was my first
introduction to the chem family
oh yeah and I got it and I was like
smelled like chlorine and gas and it was
like
crazy chical you know was so good I wish
I had that actually that feno still
because that was I think it's still
around okay it's still around yeah and
that's like a yeah it's wild because it
grows very much like the sour and then
it finishes different like different
structure at the end without a doubt it
was it was so cool and yeah good times
yeah so you've been around a while yeah
a little bit you know yeah yeah yeah
especially from the areas that I know I
mean let me know what you think of that
nice and we had Dave from
budo with the old school sour this is so
I was kind of thinking my mind was
playing tricks on me uh because so many
people have they showing me sour over
the last two years especially and I've
been looking for the sour cut and then
this guy Dave comes up to me at re in
the river with buds in his hand he goes
tell me when you think of this you know
and you can be honest and so I'm like
Dave Dave from Eugene Dave no Dave from
budel different Dave da Dave from he's
from Yukaya and uh from budo Dave
Perkins he's also he works for Amsterdam
he's a star he's one of those witnesses
that that yeah he's he's really great so
but but he had the real deal and and it
reminded me of the original sour that we
had when there was only one sour totally
yeah no that the one that was going I
mean at least from what I knew the the
sour around Eugene it wasn't even really
called East Coast Sour Diesel then it
was called sour you know exactly and it
was an amazing cut really I mean what's
sad is I let it go just because I was
over it you know I mean I didn't because
we had other things going and I just
didn't you know I was like ah whatever
you know I wish I wouldn't have but um I
was smart and gave it to a family member
and had gotten it back six times before
they ended up getting rid of it you know
so so I really had to go back up into
Washington to get it a bunch of times I
wish I would have did that with the
original um that big sir holy cut that
was going around Eugene the purple stem
you know it was one of my favorites and
you know some of those ones you just
don't do that with you know right over
the time you know I've lost so many good
things over the years I mean there was a
there was a we had a shaman that was
like a Romulan Shaman backcross that was
it should have been called the shaman
but it was called the
shaman and that was some amazing stuff
and I just I I can smell it to this day
like in the back of my nose the perfumey
incens of it and there's so many like
things like that that we had that you
know got lost along the Wayside we
didn't have the preservation techniques
that we have today no no and we didn't
you know we weren't thinking like that
then I mean I was saving a lot of things
cuz if I liked it I felt like I had to
save it hold it give it to my friends or
at least the family that you want them
to have that blessing you know and that
experience of what you're you know
because it's it's not to say it's rare
there's a lot of amazing keeper fenos
that are going around of all types of
cultivars but the ones that you're that
are drawing you from growth stage all
the way to the right when you're
lighting the bong or whatever and it's
like right when it starts to go you know
like it's registering there it's a
keeper there you know you know like
those ones those are the ones that you
can have in your jar for 10 20 plus
years like and always have it you know
those are I really have um felt a you
know kind of a stewardship in my own
mind to hold some of those of what I've
what have crossed this boundary you know
because we all have our own bio assay
right so like for me I have what works
for me but it you know if it isn't
strong and powerful on a tarpine and a
you know cannaboid level it's probably
not making it through you know but when
they do and you notice all the elites
that people are holding on they are up
in that upper threshold most of them are
you know in between 20 and 30% most of
them are pretty high tur profile and
unique you know right so yeah I mean I
think I refocused and I talk about a lot
of my podcast but I really refocused
since 420 and this year on effect and
going back in that direction how does it
make me feel and how does it make other
people feel totally we've Instagram has
taken us in this direction where it's
like how does it look guys you know bro
it's good it's so Frosty it's so and
it's like but that doesn't tell you how
it tastes and how it makes you feel and
I mean there's so many things out there
effect wise that I'm revisiting where
I'm like whoa you know that creeper weed
that kicks in after 15 minutes it really
gets you right and you're all bugged out
a little bit you're like hm yeah where
you I took a full bong rip and I was
like I'm not even high so I took another
one and then like literally 5 minutes
later I'm like oh yeah this is that
creeper and uh it was some Mother's weed
from Johnny at Huckleberry Hill Farms
that stuff is pretty special um you know
he has the white Thorn Rose which is
very like I've heard of that one not
Indica not sativa where you know
everyone wants to classify these things
as indic ctiv but it's it's a hybrid in
the middle and it it's Feelgood weed it
makes you just feel good you can smoke
it in the morning afternoon evening the
rosin's purple it's something special
and the effect of it is extremely
special and then he has a basically the
same progyny he has another plant and it
does a it has a very different effect it
does different things to your to your
mind and it creeps up on you and it it
makes you feel good but it really kind
of it's it's a more intense version of
that effect and I love that you know I
love strains like that like I have the
hazy Kush and I you know it was actually
my attempt to recreate the Big Sir holy
you know not different genetics but
looking for the similar effect and
similar style and morphology and things
like that but it's one of those strains
that like if you're on a good one yeah
it'll really put you on a good one
euphoric super stimulating super
energizing but if you're on a bad one
and in a kind of depressed state it'll
make you like on a dud you're like what
you know what I mean it's um you know
one time this uh you know this U artist
that we worked with gift a gab from
black alicious you know and he's passed
now rest so like uh we did a show with
him and my friend gave him a chunk of
hazy Kush right off the top of the jar
you know and he went out and smoked a
joint you know and my buddy's like hey
bro I go I busted in your jar and gave
him gave him a nug gave gab a nug I was
like hopefully it wasn't that one off
the top bro he's all like oh it was dude
I was like that was the hazy bro he's
all no you know because this dude my
friend couldn't even smoke this weed
because it like wow you know kind of put
him on one you know right sure enough 30
minutes into gab's set he comes off
stage cuz he threw his back out you know
first thing they're coming backstage
down the hall and my buddy's like hey
man here's my do John you know just I'm
like hey what's up he oh dude my back
bro my back he's all how do I sound you
know I was like oh was like that you
know I was like oh he's sounding good
bro let's go like you know so we we we
worked it out did a meditation you know
did some breathing you know and then
they went it was a New Year's Eve shows
and then they went out and crushed it at
New Year's but like it was an hour of
like you know sometimes weed will put a
put a HTT on someone that's not a you
know all day user kind of guy 100% yeah
and it's so subjective to the individual
and you know we all are so different in
in what we like I mean there's stuff
that I think we can agree on across the
board at times but then we're also you
know as far as tolerances and other
things like that I mean some people love
the you know the uplifting and some
people love the narcotic totally and you
can go and the beauty of the plan is you
can go in any direction with it you know
there's so many different oh yeah salads
I love salads too flavor-wise right um
and you know I think that's coming as
far as rosin guys blending their rosin
flavors I mean it's it's a great they've
done it with wine and other things
forever for sure for sure yeah no that's
the thing is there's it's so there's so
many people and so many styles of
chemistry you know so like to be able to
offer that and people have to understand
their own chemistry and what works for
them you know like for me I you know I
consistently smoke about three different
strains and even though I may have 30
jars I'm literally still picking from
three of those jars yeah and I put you
know a nug from each one of those jars
in my jar for the day and like that's
kind of like how I roll you know and and
that'll change but there's some that
have lasted through time that are been
that way for 10 15 20 years now you know
and like and those ones you know like
and like like I was you know was telling
you at the show you know it's like I'm
definitely not I don't consider myself a
breeder in any way but I can select
decently you know and what I'm selecting
and how I'm selecting I'm I'm really
selecting for myself but because I know
I'm a pretty big critic and what I can
offer others through my own selection
you know cuz I am extreme critic I think
think they'll appreciate it at least you
know and like totally well I honestly
feel like that's more important than
being able to make seeds because as a
breeder the breeding part is doing this
selection right so at the end of the day
you know everybody's like Oh I'm a
breeder I'm a breeder well what kind of
selections are you making you know it's
like yeah you made some seeds that's
cool but show me show me uh some years
of progress and where you went with it
and what you're doing and you know have
you improveed the the gene pool or you
just you know trying to make some money
and I think there's and there's nothing
wrong with either one but let's just be
real about it like breeding you know in
in my book I kind of go into it as well
but the breeding is really through the
selection process and that's what makes
a good breeder is like okay well you can
take 50 seeds and you can pick the best
one or maybe the best three or whatever
it is you know and be able to have that
translated into something that's long
lasting for sure I mean and that's why
I've done um doing a lot of work with
the 89 nl5 you know um SBD gave me these
seeds they come from Melvin eics work
that you know they did with uh the 89
nl5 from Neville you know and right well
I was kind of skeptical about it because
I had some stuff from Jim from himba and
you know before he passed and amazing
amazing nl5 but it was what I was
expecting right you know what I mean it
was what I was expecting it wasn't as
strong you know it wasn't current day
cannabis what I was expecting but it was
was what I was expecting on a you know
on that kind of set but then I had this
89 NL right by it and at first I was
like oh they weren't growing as fast so
I was kind of you know but then I
noticed some really interesting
traits and I'm not kidding over the next
three weeks the way they formed and I
mean one of them was straight Afghani
you know like
chocolate ACD look you know reminded me
of purple Bubba kind of you know right
and then the other one reminded me of a
chem sour you know so I was like oh this
I'm like and what was crazy is I'm like
oh this must something must be not right
do you know what I mean and and then um
but I was really impressed but I'm like
between these two plants I'm looking at
80% of cannabis right now between these
two you know what I mean and what that
can create there and luckily like um hor
santes came into town and um came over
and he stayed with me for like a week
you know and at at that time when I had
those pollinated MH on the deck you know
just two plants on my deck you know
actually just cuz I was just letting
them go longer I had to do stuff with
that room you know you get it totally
and I was like hey man can you verify
these cuz you're you were around you
know you were like and he's like that's
dude what you know he was so shocked he
got Ron krift on the phone which was one
of Neville's main apprentices you know
wow how we are like FaceTiming and he
was there were just like I was just
tripping you know cu the level of
quality that then that made sense how
the lore made it that long so right um
putting that into it you'll see some
stuff from over here and I've put that
by a lot of things and you know things
like the sour best [ __ ] ever which is
you know there's a lot of you know
misinformation about that strain in my
opinion it's one of the best OG Cuts you
know right um so like putting the 89 NL
to that making these super stinky chem
you know very interesting you know like
I it's kind of um to see and this and
you know Jimmy from original breeders
League he um did a huge you know he did
his huge thing you know [ __ ] very
beautiful impressive thing and but did
some um you know testing on the 89 NL
and that was extremely stable you know
and and I see the breeding tress through
all the breeding it creates such
beautiful potential but still holds true
a lot of its morphology a lot of its
Tendencies which in that case is good
you know and so I'm trying to basically
bring that into all the the current day
Elite
and kind of revigor revigor the you know
not saying I'm like oh I'm going to make
the Jean Pool better or nothing like
that but no no well you're not taken
away from it that's for sure but I feel
like uh you know I'm doing something
similar I'm taking old school cuts and
mirring to New School Cuts Fort Collins
cough old chems uh and I really like
that approach because I feel like we're
bottlenecking ourselves into these
gelato and runts and Skittles and these
things we we tend to do that just as as
it's human nature right
double down on it right yeah for sure
yeah it's I mean with medicine it's like
oh it works good so let's take twice as
much right I mean that that's just human
nature it's okay with mushrooms but most
other things exactly with your mushrooms
yeah I mean you learn real quick you
know but medicinal mushrooms are like
you know like Lion's man stuff y from
when I heard Michael Symbio talking he's
like you should be eating so much of
those that you smell like mushrooms I
was like ah that sounds medicinal that
sounds extremely medicinal you're swea
and sweating Lion's man smell you know I
love being able to sneak old school
stuff into the new market where it's
like people like oh yeah I love that and
it's like I have a blue dream double
Lemon Cherry right that has a little bit
of that blue what's special about blue
dream and it has like it's unmistakable
blue dream with a with a structure of of
a gelato or these lemon cherries you
know and so I love being able to kind of
sneak that in under the rug where people
are like whoa that's freaking amazing
and they're haters of Blue Dream you
know and I I love Blue Dream for its own
in its own right Blue Dream is one of
the best plants out there as far as
struct structure it's the apical of
structure it yields well it's you know
resistant it might not have the the
effect that everybody's looking for but
it sure is special in its own right for
the soccer moms bro it's ideal bro for
sure and for people that aren't looking
for that like kick you in the head yeah
there's something for everybody and it's
like you want you want a turned up
version of that there's Strawberry Cough
it's very much like that but it's like
the turned up version of Blue Dream you
know that's so funny totally yeah so
tell me how you got your start in the
industry how long has it been um I guess
I started growing you know in the
industry I guess there wasn't really an
industry there you know you know when I
was when I was a kid like selling sacks
and all that but like when I came to
Eugene in 9 end of 96 um I had really
bad allergies and I was growing all
these different pepper plants you know
habanero D to like all and just like
basically just eating him raw wow you
know cuz I was like man this allergies
is like
level you know they call it the what is
the valley of sickness or something
Valley anyhow um so then I just I popped
a couple you know obviously I was
smoking weed and I come I was working
with a friend that was like connected to
you know I think still one of the last
holders of the Trinity because I'm you
know I gave it back to him I've been
looking for it forever Trinity Bob was
supposed to give me a c I don't know if
you know Bob from from up there in
Eugene Bob Bob Dole
Bob oh no this this guy's super pierced
up up guy different but he's different
but yeah he goes by Bob Dole but he's
the one that like his name's Andrew but
when he when I first got in contact with
Trinity it was from him in 97 you know
wow so but anyway I gave ended up giving
him the cut back and nice you know but
um you know becoming a part of this
friend group you know which is in Eugene
in the 90s there's like clicks you know
what I mean for sure you know snog grass
batom family click you the dog Kingdom
click silver people and these other kind
of Crews and then these kind of Out of
Towners you know they were coming there
to grow weed my good buddies were from
whis now um goes you know Devin Devon
Somerville kungl Stein he's pretty
pretty uh popular kind of um you know
does these kind of like old school Adam
Smasher cameleons and like like amazing
dab rggs but then I saw him make this
little corn cob pipe and I was like o
make me a three- hole one on the top so
I can you know do full melt in there
yeah yeah we used to call those Adam
Smashers I don't know what they call
them now but yeah that's where they use
the hot rod you mean use the hot rod you
SM [ __ ] in there well this is what this
is what I use to smoke um bong heads
flower you know like I'll just put a nug
in there torch us up red hot and Bong H
head like that it's a great way I think
I got four five of them and then I got a
the the actual down stem that for for
the bong for sure yeah the three hole
remember the elf one where we put the
old school hash in it you know like
before all this new before all these new
Rigs and all the technology we were you
can't even barely handle some of this
hash it's like 90u like full melt my
buddy Buck New Rose Farms you know so
it's like you look at that stuff it's
like how do you even like it's hard to
work with you know what I mean in this
stuff you can't really hot knife either
I mean you can but that's what beauty of
this thing here is like you put a ball
of that in here and then it's amazing
you know you put that hot rod to that
and that's like about as hot knife as it
gets you know and it's it's really I
like it a lot you know and that's kind
of my favorite but so anyway like I um I
just put a couple seeds in a spider
plant in my bedroom right and they
sprouted and I was like oh got to build
a spav for you know so then you know had
this foam and all hanging in my closet
it was like light leaks everywhere it
was like it was junk man it was like
about as junk as it gets and then I was
like well I'm not going to do it like
that I'm going to do it right actually
this time so I built a little box you
know I had like a 250 watt um you know
uh light off of someone's parking lot
you know and then I got 150 watt HPS
from like a Home Depot you know there
just a little one had that in this wood
closet that you know box that I built
and you know I got blueberry Trin I got
Trin Big Sir holy and the strain IDK
this kind of Afghan ster I don't know
you know but uh and with good genetics
and I went out and dug my soil out from
King of state's uh apple orchard just
dug that took it home mixed it with pith
and perlite and you know oyster shell
whatever green sand didn't realize at
that time green sand takes so long to
break down you don't even like it's like
but like there's some green sand in
there some guos and just water and was
[ __ ] sick you know like it was like
so dank and so bum and I was like oh
okay genetics genetics the genetics you
know because if because really you know
with good genetics if you don't
overwater underwater overfeed or you
know you can underfeed good genetics
you'll still be Dang if you're good soil
and good genetics you're you're halfway
there you know like and then there's the
drawing and that's a whole another
conversation but yeah I mean genetics
it's plays such a huge role in the end
product totally I mean it's so you know
discovering that and then you know
classic style just doubled every time
and you know I was a you know you
remember Greg from American a up in
Portland you know like I was the first
one to get him to get a carbon filter
you know like I went up there and it was
98 or 99 I can't remember but like my
buddy that supposedly brother shis Berry
um Adam he owned a um a washing machine
kind of repair thing and we used his
business to get the wholesale account
you know so we can get lights for
cheaper and you know they were building
their lights there and I went up to Greg
and I was like hey man I saw this thing
it's a like activated carbon air filter
for like exhaust he's like what I was
like yeah can you order me one you know
such a game changer dude cuz I mean you
grow in Trinity Big Sir you know like
two bedrooms full no filter just using
the box fan with the like attic fan on
it you know making a box with the attic
fan and the V you know the ducting out
of it like that was your setup you know
to plug that into a carbon filter I mean
I remember one time I pulled I I pulled
up to my house you know getting ready to
turn in I can smell the trend you know
just like on the road oh yeah this had
multiple times and right when I was
about to turn in four
sheriffs just right in front of my house
I'm like oh my God and then they went
two blocks two houses down they just
stopped and then they drove two houses
down I pulled in and they were like
getting the guy I was just like oh my
god oh man bugging bro you know yeah
they were such a game changer CU I mean
I remember growing some Kem back in the
day and and it just the whole whole
house smelled but even the neighbors
down the street were like there's a
skunk there's have you guys seen the
skunk and I thought they were [ __ ]
with me but they really thought it was a
skunk like literally thought it was a
skunk because it was so strong for sure
well it smells so much like a live skunk
uhuh yeah especially a lot of stuff we
had back in the day compared especially
Trinity even you know I mean to be
honest I haven't smelled anything more
skunky than that than the original Royal
Tren yeah I have a trinity cut now it's
the future Trend cuz you know we had the
Trinity and then this other Trinity came
like after and we called it the future
Trend a little more dense a little more
that's the one going around right now
it's not the old school one there's a
lot of things that are like that where
they're like durban's another one like
it's a different Durban than I remember
the Durban wasn't a terpinolene dominant
you know Aroma on it it was like it was
cherries and it was funky and you know
anise ah so it was like licorice
cherries and strong and pungent and then
the stuff now that I see is Durban and
super hazy ah yeah you know and it's
very very Haz likee and that wasn't the
Durban that I remember the Durban we had
was like orange like orange yarn hair
growing over that would cover like it
didn't look like it had tricomes on it
you P pulled the hairs back a little
interesting but yeah so many things were
like that but yeah that Trinity
extremely extremely special for sure U
yeah and it's like finding it yeah
that's pretty amazing well yeah one
person I know has it but you know
obviously getting old school genetics
from Old School TP types of people it's
a it's a process in itself you know what
I mean for sure well there's a reason
they're not out there probably a good
reason a lot of stuff you know you know
I have things that I won't let go you
know like um Graham you know he gave me
the phk and I did some breeding with it
but I won't let that cut go right it
won't um same with Brandon he gave me
the Afghani bull rider same thing I'm
you know it's well I think we're
stewards of these plants it's our job to
protect them not just to keep them alive
and share them with everybody which a
lot of people think oh yeah you should
share them with everybody no I mean as a
steward you should be responsible with
them for sure just like I mean just like
everything you know we see what's
happening in the industry and the
stewardship that is happening and that
isn't that could be you know there's a
there's a big thing that's happening um
but there's more that could happen
especially with notoriety and um
publicity a lot of people are getting if
they were to utilize that and really
turn it instead of for financial gain
and still keep the financial gain part
but really do it for philanthropic
reasons for the right reason stewarding
I agree you know whatever their even
their perspective of relationship is
with the plan but if they stewarded that
for others you know instead of it being
more superficial and right you know well
once it's authentic it's just and the
thing is all these things they come
across as either authentic or not we you
can see right through all the [ __ ] a
lot of times you know well I think the
plan helps with that too you know it
sure does um shed the veil and cut the
veil and you know really um in our own
self and our own behavior and mental
dispositions and in the outside world
too well you know I was so excited at TP
Nami this last weekend because of the
quality level level of breeders that
were there all in one place a lot of
emerald cut people right uh but
more sativa leaning hybrids or sativas
that I'd ever seen in one place at one
time that outnumbered the gelato and
outnumbered the cookie crosses and the
stuff that we've really seen to as
modern cannabis the you know the PE
there was a lot of people from the hills
coming down which I love it and we were
seeing these long flowering varieties in
in abundance in from all over Jesse from
B Vex we had mark from Gray shock uh we
had you know Jackson was there mean
jeene and rebel grown and and a bunch of
people coming together with all these
old school genetics and all old school
Expressions stuff that you know maybe
it's a new cross but a lot of stuff I've
seen before you know 15 years ago 20
years ago that gets me excited and it
gives me hope for the future to be
honest I feel like that kind of stuff
when there's all these great people we
got a group photo of everybody sh was
there uh you know and then we had Arian
from Greenhouse coming out and he was
like shaking his head like what are
these Americans doing I've never seen
this happen before and uh you know so
that gives me hope that we can get
ourselves out of this bottleneck where
it's all gelato and I feel like there's
nothing wrong with gelados there's
nothing wrong with these purple candy
gas varieties but there's more to
cannabis than just those things for sure
there's more than Instagram you know
there's nothing wrong with Instagram and
it can be used as a positive tool I
think it has its benefits it has
benefits for both of us you know I think
it helps us promote our Brands but at
the same time you don't get to smell it
you don't get to taste it and you don't
get to feel the effect exactly and I
mean I think that's what's um really
it's education and I think that's what a
lot of us that have been around a while
should be doing just my personal opinion
is informing everyone you know because
if if I have you know a few different
cookie crosses a few different gelato
things and then a you know others say
OG's or hazes or chams and I'm
continually going over of these hazes
and chems and ogs you know people should
take note of that why because we have
the we can you know we have the best of
both yeah and when you have the best of
both you're going to choose what
registers in your own chemistry well and
I think once people understand that they
should
actually maybe not seek out what's hype
and hyping but seek out what's you know
the who's growing it how it's grown
methodology and how old the genetic line
is maybe and try to discover something
new because you might realize that hey
this older stuff really Vibes with me
more actually because the hives maybe
more stimulating more invigorating more
you know like cerebral and you know more
rushy and you know these kind of
feelings are like kind of what the you
know the old schoolers are are liking
and have been liking for years hence why
you know at tpami you see this you know
everyone's like check it out what we've
been doing you know like yeah no same
thing we've all been doing for a long
time but it's not but hpe bottleneck
it's creativity and effect expressed you
know well the modern world has changed
things so much you know it's like back
in the day you used to know where your
vegetables were coming from you you used
to know who was raising your cattle and
same thing with breeding your flowers or
growing your cannabis it's like there's
a big disconnect you know I'm I have
some of my Snoop dogs selling some of my
genetics I just saw jars with the loud
loops on there but there's this big
disconnect and I think they're not
giving necessarily the Breeders credit
or the cator credit they're just
marketing flower and there it is what it
is but I feel like there's there's a
there's a better story and a deeper
Story and there's deeper understanding
to be had about all this stuff
especially like Farmers up in Humble
right like I use them as the example but
it's really Farmers everywhere being
able to tell their Story Farm to Table
where you can go to the farm you can see
them produce it there you can talk to
the grower you can talk to the breeder
the extract artist whoever that is where
where there's like more of a story and
then you have a deeper connection to
that flower
and I mean Canabis is about Community
anyway and I feel like that's part that
we've kind of gone away from that we
really need to go back to yeah and I
think that's what I think that's what's
coming back around I think that's why
obviously these podcasts are so popular
for people and because you have you know
a lot of really cool people and
expressions of Humanity on these
different podcasts that are you know
being able to connect with a different
um set of you know viewers and a whole
different sphere and to be able to you
know just it's
really you know enlightening for
everyone and really endearing for all of
us to be you know be able to share what
we've experienced the fight the
struggles that we've you know because as
you you know it's been a smaller time
that it's been legal of us doing this
than it's been illegal of us doing this
you know and and a lot of us you know we
did a lot of work for the states and
different things you know um you know I
did a lot of work with Oregon and their
legalization push and multiple rules
advisory committees head grower advisor
got things like unlimited PL count
written into law you know when it was
like 100 plant you know Federal right
like 99 and under no no call to the FED
100 and over they could call the FED 101
you know you're like you're like buming
you know so like to be able to get
things like unlimited plant count
written in and you know like really
holding that seat for the people yeah
really is a p a people's voice you know
because even at the end right at the
very end when that got signed into law
that got switched up a little bit so you
know there's even in when it's even it
lobbying makes a difference yeah and we
have short memories so I feel like
people have short memories there's new
people coming online all the time that
they weren't there to experience it so
it's great to be able to remind people
or the younger Generations that are
coming online to be able to watch this
now or watch this podcast that we're
having five years from now 50 years from
now 100 years from now right and you
know understand what was going on in
2024 it's going to be a different thing
in 2030 even and you know this next 5
years next 10 years is going to be crazy
for cannabis you know who knows what's
going to happen but it's not going to be
less right you know what I mean it's not
going to be less and it's going
direction for sure everyone's already
you know you remember how it was when it
was you know what Colorado you know
Washington Oregon or Oregon Washington I
can't remember you it's like and then it
Cali then it just like it was like I
mean now look at it it's International
scale we got Germany which is a very big
country I mean it's a very big deal and
I think a lot of people are like oh it's
just another country no it's a big big
big country that's going online with
recreational con to all the EU yeah and
they have the highest the German EU GMP
is is the highest of its standards as
far as like German GMP standards are
higher than anywhere else in the world
wow and so I think it's great I you know
we had Arn talking about it about how
you know the stacks of paperwork to get
the
cgmp uh done is like you know four feet
tall wow so but yeah real pro pro stuff
you know real Pro stuff hard to
bootstrap hard to yeah very hard to
bootstrap very hard for to go from the
ground up you know but I mean I think
that stuff is great I think I'm big on
testing oversight I think that we need
more of that in the United States for
sure I'm not super big on government
oversight and more government but I am
in favor of universal testing that
that's uh puts us in line with other
countries uh you know I feel like our
there's so much motivation to have
higher testing results for the for the
farmer for the breeder for the lab and
then the person who suffers is the end
user because they're not getting true
results well and that's the thing is
it's like you know when we are getting
true results it's harder to sell you
know like even you know like our good
buddies SC Labs you know and um Al like
they I've been KNN him for a long time
and he's been helping me through that
whole process with Oregon and to see how
you know what we're getting testing wise
with him consistently for I use SC as
well so I I feel like they're Straight
Shooters yeah they're real you know but
then when you're getting a 22 or a 19 or
23 you know 23 maybe is more marketable
but when you're get in the 19 to 21
range it's so much harder to Market that
flower in the wreck reality because
people think that it's more it's
supposed to be around 30 and that's not
that's actually not true you know it's
when you know what I talk to them even
Addison you know like um when I you know
at Steep Hill back in the day when first
brought him the golden at that time you
know he tested it at 24.7 I think and
the highest that he had tested at that
point was 194 or something like that so
it was a huge deal to jump that much you
know um but even then he was talking
about it when they started doing these
hash testing and different things and
flower testing you can't have it that
high it's not like actually physically
possible you know so you know to have
these like 40% it's like H it's pretty
sus you know it's it is you know I have
some testing results that are like 40%
total canab 40 40 1% total canabo and
it's like it's pretty wild if you think
of that amount if we look at a bud like
40% of that is canabo that's it's wild
right and you're like huh um I want to
believe it you know I have a lot of
really good tests and a lot of good coas
that are really you know you can show
them off but it kind I don't have
anything from Steve Hill that tests in
the 40s
nothing I um you know like in Oregon
there's some Labs that get some high
testing and you know SC labs always been
you know like true yeah and most cuz
most of the gear that I'm selecting
naturally tests between 22 and 26% just
what my kind of you know bio ACI what
what that's kind of you know Desiring is
that range just naturally I think the
best flavors come in that low 20s you
know and there's some stuff that there's
anomalies that you know that I think are
in the 30s that do have amazing flavor
and their high tpin but it's very rare
because canabo compete with tpin so
typically the high the cannaboids the
lower the Tarpin and vice versa but and
then it's not all about just tpin uh now
the word flavorant has come to mind uh
recently abstracts Tech did some white
they wrote some white papers on
flavoring you know sulfur based
compounds and THS basically you know
we've been talking about THS for a long
time and now they're categorizing THS
and showing how they contribute to the
flavor and Aroma which I think is great
well those are all kind of the more like
I mean is it like a microle or thle is
that a it's a it's a you know basically
uh it's a style of tpine still right
it's a smaller flavor molecule okay yeah
it's a lot harder to test for well
that's why I think that like you know me
personally like I like fresh herb you
know after it's been dried for about
seven days from that point to about a
month is my favorite Sweet Spot
personally yeah um and I'm assuming it's
because all the you know tpin and the
micro thyes and the THS are all in a
combination there and you know the more
um you know ones that degenerate you
know quicker they're not going to be
around in a in a in a month you know or
you know people like oh curing it Slow
and Low this that and the other that's
great I I get it but for me personally I
just I just like the range of what
happens from when it's fres dry I Like
it Loud right yeah you know to to to to
you know and it's like even my buddy
Steve you know like um from Green life
he he's like man like what's a deal you
know like I want my jar to [ __ ] smack
you know I want it to you know and I'm
like man he's like when I open your jar
just hits you know and I'm like man
because I love fresh weed yeah you know
well and I think it's it's also
subjective to the cultivar and there's
there's factors that play but like
Skittles for example it is the best when
it's fresh right when it's done drying
and it's like maybe cured for a couple
days you don't need to burp it anymore
whatever you do that's when it is the
very best and it doesn't get better on
the nose it still smokes good for a lot
longer but that first like week and a
half it's just loud it just hits you in
the face and there's Sour's kind of like
that too sour the sour will smoke good
for a long time but like the real the
loudness of the sour when you open it
the fresher the better well it's like
even with like ogs you know it's like
after a week is when they really start
to punch harder you know like exact you
know you're like fresh you want to smoke
it right like REM me because it has its
thing but after a week it's like that
anes and the whole like thing starts to
come out more it's like more piny and
earthy and yeah for sure and then
there's like Jack Jacks have their own
thing right Jacks I I feel like the
lyine stuff that's really high in Li
lanine actually deteriorates pretty fast
so they don't last even in like the TPL
blcks we do a bunch of trials with stuff
and some of that line line r seem to age
faster and I'm not sure exactly why but
it's definitely one of those things like
six months later they're they're Never
As Good well maybe because that tpine
you know what I mean it's like I it's a
solvent in a lot of you know industry so
sure maybe that's kind of degradating
the other tpin the use of that solvent
and yeah it works really good on those
varieties you know for sure so yeah so
what's your favorite thing to smoke I've
been liking this uhsse by 89 NL um and
there's some things in that um jar pack
that I really like a lot um and that
one's uh it's nice just the 89 anal I
really like the high what it's doing and
you know earthy thing going on it's good
for sure you know it kind of reminds me
like of a dog walker smell almost a
little bit you know yeah yeah so those
are you know I like that one a lot um
the lemon punch by 89 I've been liking a
lot phk Afghani yeah you know kind of
just um you know like I said I have a
you know pretty good selection of things
to choose from but I keep going to these
specific ones and you know some of them
are new but like the hazy Kush it's a
terpinolene aamine humulene kind of
strain right but it'll always have a
place for me you know people like oh I'm
not really into the terpinolene at all I
was like well had the right combination
[ __ ] smells like candy and it's like
really good you know and if it's done
right it's epic and the high that's you
know comb when those tpin are combined
with high THC it's something special
happens you know and the same with all
of it you know the reason people
understand the reason a lot of they like
something it's not the cannaboids it's
[ __ ] tpin you know and and and that
combination you know when you have all
these cannaboids that we do understand
and ones we don't you combine that with
Tarpin we do understand and ones we
don't you know there's just a range and
and then when you start talking of like
Organics versus conventionals and all
the you know enzymatic stuff and you
know when you really there's a there's a
micron nuances that we just don't
understand yet that you know that for
some reason it's a calling us but we
just don't know why scientifically yet
yeah we're just scratching the surface
of it for sure so yeah I I I would 100%
agree and I I love soil and I use coco
but I also love smoking soil you know we
have a closed loop facility so I'm not
trying to bring bugs in right that's the
disant whole giant biome right exactly
like I mean in in a perfect world yeah
we could do that but but here we're
confined to the constraints totally of
of cleanliness especially and and trying
to be um yeah as sterile as possible you
know one of the cleaner spots I've been
to period like really and the protocols
perfect yeah our Sops are pretty dialed
and we're just constantly trying to
prevent pests you know cu can come in
from the outside they can come shirt we
don't allow people typically in our
Nursery
ever you know we have a pretty dense
plant c in
there oh this stuff got me it smells
amazing though right from the from the
from the non-smoked TP you're like
you're like because remember you were
saying the cams like get
you you're like what this is I'm
allergic to this one for sure so I got a
question for you organ let's talk about
a genetic that everyone hates talking
about in Oregon is Jagger what's your
opinion on jger um I mean it's a feno
like the Hindu is from what I've
understood even like you know um you
look at Graham's purple Hindu Kush you
know it's like smells like tangerine and
citrus yeah purple cracked out looks
like cookies kind of like um and you
know he told me he's like dude I I
sourced this out of Hindu cush seeds you
know just so I'm assuming the Jagger's
same deal it's a purple Hindu Kush
meaning a Hindu Kush that was purple
yeah and it made it through you know
people love it and it's you know
resistant and I think it's like run its
course through the outdoor Community
yeah it was like blue dream in the
beginning everyone loved it like
literally it's another blue dream where
it was like in the beginning it was like
whoa what is this everybody had to have
it the cuts got out everywhere and
that's part of like the stewardship of
stuff you know but uh you know we keep
going back to the stewardship but that's
another one it's like it became popular
and then people started hating on it
yeah I mean I it's it's a unique
smelling plant and the highest you know
is what it is but I think there's just a
lot better and you know anything um that
people blast out that hard is going to
have some Kickback just sure normal
eventually I mean people hate on cookies
now too and cookies in the back in the
day the real original cookies was
special ex I still have that cut I got
it from Alec actually from SC labs in
200 I think 11 or something did youever
when it was just cookies right only
cookies it was small producer like I had
so the original was more like burnt
rubber Funk like extremely strong lior
yeah exactly it was that cut that's the
one I'm Still rocking you know well and
I believe that some people some people
question the fact that there's Durban in
there and I totally firmly believe that
that anise that licorice comes from
Durban okay unmistakably because the
Durban we had had that same licorice in
it right Bay my friend Josh Freeman he's
the one who brought down seeds of Durban
from Canada that he'd gotten up there uh
with my other friend Joe
and that was the anise and I feel like
first time I smelled cookies I was like
whoa that reminds me of the Durban and
next thing you know they're saying oh
it's Durban in there I'm like 100% I
agree that it's probably Durban in there
that gives it that anise oh cool uh but
we got the original cookies we got
wasn't the Forum cut it wasn't the thin
minute it was just the
cookies uh my buddy Paulie had gotten it
from think $5,000 for the cut he' gotten
it from the hydro shop that was in
Berkeley I believe on Fourth Street
right by the think there's a a pet shop
that sold lizards and stuff like that
right there but anyway there was a guy
that sold it to him and then he got it
for our group and we shared it but uh it
was this crazy cookies that was really
small producing but it reminded me of OG
in the sense that the node spacing was
terrible and if you didn't support it up
it would just spaghetti over so but yeah
and it was so strong you know and it
half a pound of light was what we were
getting yield wise right I still grew it
for half a pound of light when we were
all you know we had other stuff at the
time that would yield a lot more right
yeah know I I like that I made some made
some things out of it it's U it was you
know I still have that cut that's the
cut that I'm still holding and right a
special one obviously made it this far
it's not just the branding that made it
this far you know well it made it into
everything all the new [ __ ] has cookies
in it like literally all the stuff that
we're smoking now that has purple
there's cookies in it right for sure so
as much as people want to hate on stuff
it's like they hate on stuff for the
wrong reason the other thing that gets
me right now is purple weed is so
popular when I feel like when I'm phenoh
hunting the Expressions that are louder
in the same progyny we'll have green and
purple in different Hues but the more
green it is the usually louder they are
for sure so people want what they can't
have they always want the anomalies and
I think we value stuff that's not
necessarily important and part of that
social media but totally do you find
that the um you know green versus purple
and the hashing and everything that
you're like you know more they be more
hash Potentials in purples or more hash
Potentials in Greens you know cuz I've
I've been seeing a lot of the at least a
lot of The Greener stuff that I work
with it's pretty greasy yeah and you
know you know like the ogs and stuff
like that some of them sour and ogs are
super greasy with hash you know rosin
yeah so the you know the spsc 89 um my
buddy Buck he uh he made some amazing
rosin out of it amazing hash full melts
and everything but the yields weren't
like as you know as much but right
versus like say if you're doing some you
know more animal mints or something like
that that's just like f an all tricomes
and a little more totally you know waxy
but well then there's the GMOs they just
dump and dump and dump you know and
that's a turp that I can get sick of
that I really like but I can get sick of
it pretty because it's just so it's so
strong and it's good but like it's they
put it in everything and then I like the
original GMOs I mean I like chmd to be
honest I really like the it's like I
feel like it's not as loud as GMO but
it's very nostalgic for me I get that
smell and it reminds me of the 90s oh
yeah that's why I got something in there
I you know really the AJ sour diesel
reminds me of GMO a little bit mixed
with OG it has that kind of little more
rank smell you know that's the sour
decut that's going around now more than
anything the the sour d that's more
citrusy that's bright that's really loud
in the bag with its complexity is the
one that I grew up with yeah same yeah
when I when I got this AJ um sour d from
crazy composer Dave you know like I uh
Ian I was like bro is I was like is this
normally like GMO smelling like OG GMO
smelling he's all oh yeah that's this
one I was like well that's not the one
that was going out here forever right
he's all no it's not no I believe that
sour is a bag seed from Chev 91 there's
lots of different theories on it you
know there's different stories about who
read it and you know they're in my book
if people want to read it but uh just
from what I've seen with the dog butt
that we had with the sours that I've
grown and similarly uh the lab results
that I've seen in fingerprinting and you
know we were talking about homozygosity
earlier right and you know you look at
the s1's uh as being typically more
homozygous and you can look at chem dog
and then you can look at these other and
and how it pans out on paper it's really
interesting but uh you know and there a
lot of these are very similar and hity
and so well there's a good chance in my
opinion that it's just an S1 yeah and uh
a really special S1 and there's nothing
wrong I mean some of the best things are
bag seeds that we I mean and single bag
seeds not like you accidentally
pollinated something but when you just
find a couple
seeds those are the best those those are
my favorite too and I still have
collections I you know I think the real
smokers the ones that find the real back
seeds and that's where the real magic is
at totally and then you know I mean I'm
I'm kind of esoteric with this whole
thing so maybe that's just the plan
offering certain people the the jewel
you know offering them something that
they're going to Steward properly that
Pearl you know getting it like here's
your offering for being such a devoted
uh you know yeah and you know talking
about devotion I think that's really the
direction this industry is the people
that are thriving you know the old
school people especially because they're
devotional right they're devoted to this
plan stewards we could talk about
stewards but as far as a devotion like
whether you're a musician you're devoted
to music or whether you're devoted to
this plant when it becomes devotional
where you wouldn't do this no matter
what happens whether it's illegal legal
where there's money or no money that's
when the special stuff happens for sure
and I mean I'm sure we've all
experienced it over the last little bit
of years you know like you know
different kind of things going which way
or the other or whatever it's like you
know kind of kind of some fears or
whatever kind of coming to play and you
know really it's like [ __ ] man there
ain't nothing else to do you know except
work with this plan you know I'm like
I'm I'm in there for for the rest I'm in
there for the rest well and it's funny
because once mushrooms got pop more
popular a couple they kind of went
mainstream about five years ago people
like dude you should start breeding
mushrooms you know this is 2018 right
and people were like dude you should
start breeding mushrooms too you know
you like breeding why why aren't you
breeding mushrooms and then I had some
friends that were getting some spots
30,000 square foot warehouse and I'm
like I've already went through this with
cannabis dude I don't want to start over
man I feel like this is my life's
calling and I love cooking and I love
cannabis those are the two main main
things I have in my life that I feel
like I'm good at something that I've
devoted my whole life to and then taking
on mushrooms I enjoy mushrooms as a
spectator you know from the outside I
love mushrooms and I I love medicine and
I think it's so special but as far as
like what I'm going to devote my time to
and my energy cannabis is where it's at
cannabis is where it's going to end up
and uh yeah I love it I love being part
of the community I love this Comm I just
love the community as a whole for sure I
mean it's a a really special Community
too you know it's a it's
so you know for myself I kind of uh feel
the same way and like as you do with the
cooking and the the herb you know it's
like these are really tangible things
that we can entangle our intentions into
like actually and it's right you know
just look at you know our grandmothers
or mothers or fathers or you know even
with M Roto with the you know hidden
messages of water and all these kind of
or you know that old book secret life of
plants you know this is like this is
some esoteric information that we all
understand meaning like when our when
someone really loves us and we consume
something from that person shit's
noticeable right you know and we feel it
and you know if you don't then you know
you you know should be more aware
because it's like really obvious in a
lot of ways you know and I think this
plant um and cooking is something that
really is we can you know and acts as a
server of that intention and love and
compassion that we can that we're
sharing ourself you know and our
entanglement of something with a very
special thing whether it be food or the
sacred wisdom plant you know it's you
know we're very lucky to be able to even
be conversing about this really you know
totally yeah it's it's a beautiful thing
and then when you're able to share that
energy with somebody else and they get
it it's just so much better to and like
and there's a whole community of people
that get it which is great for sure so a
lot of them in Oregon you I'm originally
I'm from Oregon originally I have a lot
of good friends from Oregon a lot of
great people in our industry are either
transplants that live there now or have
lived there in their past there's
something special about Oregon I feel
like it has one of the best climates in
the world but uh it's also the mindset
of the people that live in Oregon
totally and the water you know we got
really good clean water up there and uh
clean water yep with lithium in it in
some places you know and the mindset you
know obviously with the Oregon Country
Fair and you know like the kind of
Eugene community of what was created
there and that kind of spread through
and Grateful Dead influence you know I
love California too don't get me wrong I
I'm here in California I love it I love
the West Coast I love Seattle but
there's definitely something special
about you know Portland all the way down
to ashin right well I mean though when
we talk about stewardship of genetics
you know it's like it was happening
there and it was happening long before I
started growing that's for sure you know
if I'm growing end
9697 you know and people been doing it
for decades prior to that and like you
know some really Global reputable
breeders coming through there picking up
genetics taking them back to you know
Europe and doing the thing and you know
I just feel like I got blessed with
synchronicity really and just kind of
had my ears open and mind open at the
right times and luckily um you know with
that community and bringing the right
people together to where you can glean
what you can and obviously work with
this plan ways because you know I was
when I moved to Eugene I was qu kind of
kind of a violent guy you know I got a
lot of fist fights half Korean half
white moved around every couple years so
kind of you know didn't like bullies and
kind of you know when you come to Eugene
it's like it was you know we're doing a
lot of you know we're growing and you
know doing a lot of hustling and pools
so you get kind of Rowdy and you take
someone for 100 bucks or something and
you know you get kind of this thing and
that Community really helped with the
plant just kind of nullify a lot of that
you know by go this direction don't go
that direction you know and the whole
atmosphere of the community is like that
you know if you're being a punk it's not
as cool you know if you're being you
know altruistically minded or at least
not harming others that's more cool you
know and that Oregon Community is really
um I like that about Oregon for sure and
especially about Eugene and Eugene has
its own Vibe too I mean each each
Community whether it's you know Medford
Eugene Portland you know the coast you
know there's there's places on the coast
that are amazing too they all have their
own energy and Vibe but there's
something special about Eugene even the
food scene in Eugene is kind of special
no for real my buddy owns this place
called party downtown and it's a you
know he started a little food truck by
friendly Street Market my other you know
um friend's lady owns a friendly Street
Market and it just basically like all
these kind of hip younger you know our
age kind of grew up there or been there
a lot wanted to bring the goodness there
and you know and there it proliferates
you know people accept it and support it
when it's good and cuz you know Oregon
has a weird um snobby and like a
snobbish kind of to beer and and food
trucks for sure well I mean look at
Portland they made a whole movie about
it you or I mean a whole like TV show
about it and that shit's real you know
what I'm saying like the you know the
will frell with the the chicken farm
thing or whatever it's like yeah that I
mean that's the vibe in a lot of ways
there because people are so if it isn't
perfect then it isn't tasty and it isn't
headyy and it isn't like you know it's
not cool even like you know late early
2000s there if you come if your weed
wasn't at a certain level there no sense
I'm pulling it out you know cuz it's
going to be obvious that you're you know
you're not going to get like shunned but
you might get sh you know you might you
know all these like the glass culture
and the that that nature when people are
you know the finest of the fine Organics
you oh yeah no Chinese glass up there
you it was it was years before Chinese
glass actually made it into organ you
know well shoot man it's like really uh
it was a unique scene there you know and
really really special scene with all the
you know snog grass family like the 420
parties where all the kids come and
before they'd go out on tour and you
know over the for the summer for all the
you know jam band shows and all the good
stuff man all the good stuff yeah and
the Grateful Dead influence I mean on
our whole Community is so profound and
so big and it's it's a it's a positive
impact you know I mean some things in
the industry there's negative impact
from Big Business and stuff like that
and there's some positive but mostly bad
Grateful Dead it was only positive you
know on the community and within the
community and the Grateful Dead
Community which they're slightly
different but they're also completely
tied in with each other for sure you
know rainbow family Grateful Dead all
these things and and the Cannabis
Community it's all tied in together they
have their own niches and their own
clicks but everybody's kind of tied in
together because of cannabis totally and
I mean even like you see from the Bay
Area to Eugene with the like you know
key prank sters Dead all this kind of
stuff and all the you know even the
shulan family and that you know that
kind of rest in peace yes he's the
legend Sasha shogan yeah and then even
Nick I was at a party with Sasha and an
and Nick Sans and you know all the
doctors from John Hopkins University
when they were working on the micology
stuff this is like 20 years ago you know
and I was like I didn't know actually I
was like the weed guy you know I didn't
really
know I knew but I didn't know you you
know when Nick started telling us
stories about making 100 grams of orange
Sunshine a day and like you know and the
kind of you know he told us this one
story about breaking down the lab
throwing it all in the van driving it
across town like he's getting chased by
the cops you know he gets the safe house
and like it just like he was just
tripping you know you know yeah so Sasha
shulan was one of my neighbors he lived
in between Pleasant he lived in
Lafayette but between like Walnut Creek
Pleasant Hill and then it goes over the
hill into Lafayette and he lived up at
the top of there oh cool so yeah I mean
good good energy all over that area well
it was crazy to like be at that party
and to hear you know like you know and
to see those those hop John Hopkins
University myologist were the ones that
push this whole thing you know now years
later you know because they slept it for
a while because obviously the government
and everything and to hear you know
Sasha telling stories of you know and
then he had like the retired head of the
western division forensics of the DEA
was there it was a like interesting
party it was you know only 50 of us up
in like near the Bohemian Grove it was
kind of like a you know it's like did
this really happen you know what I mean
like really and I'm like we're there and
you know had all the different molecules
there and him telling all about it and
like just the you know him and his two
best friends um you know were there and
you know these these these people were
in their like late 70s look like 80s you
know maybe and and they were with it
yeah and to be the you know Sasha is
quite the legend because it wasn't like
he like people he tested it all on
himself you know like if he got high
before he got sick that was good in that
good direction to go and that's some
like OG [ __ ] bro yeah serous ball for
one thing but also he believed in it
that much right and so a devotional in
the same way word devotional for
cannabis totally his impact I mean
profound I mean imagine the amount of um
good feelings that he's brought to
fruition in the world and the Continuum
of you know just those couple things and
the derivatives of those things even and
well yeah and it's like I feel like
we're an evolution of the Grateful Dead
right to a degree and he is that there's
an evolution of him that's that's
prevalent around the world you know
that's for sure that he had impact on
and still has impact on and you know
it's amazing when we can pass on that
energy whether it's via cannabis or
cannabis seeds or genetics or whatever
it is that you or even molecular
structures you structures music whatever
it is that you do that you love where
you can contribute that part I mean
that's what life is all about I think at
end of the day it's like finding out
what you're good at doing that to the
best of your ability so that you're
passing on something in the form of an
energy totally to to everybody else yeah
like a wisdom energy based in altruism
you know and really to be able to share
that is I mean you know as you just said
it's like our a lot of us is life goal
here and once you can actually come to
fruition with that the happiness that um
is experienced is something quite
special and unique you know yeah it's
something you can't buy the beauty of it
is you you can't buy it no way not even
it's not in the same realm it's just
like you know even with marketing and
advertising some of this stuff you know
you can buy advertising but some of the
stuff you can't you know and the history
and the time and the people's commitment
and devotion like you say it's like
that's an unbought thing and that's
something that happens spontaneously
organically and naturally in the human
mind that's like that's one of our
special traits here you know yeah and
happiness is such an interesting thing
because I think happiness comes from
devotion a lot of times and I think
happiness a lot of people are like well
I don't want to work I'd be happy if I
didn't work and I feel like I'm the
opposite I think that work is what makes
me happy being able to do what I do
every day that makes me happy I'm super
happy that I'm able to do that stuff and
hard work keeps us out of trouble hard
work hard work is so you know I think
hard work is great and you know I think
when we're committed to one thing and
devotional we can you know almost with
blinders on that's when you can find
real happiness on a different level and
then work doesn't seem so tough it's
still work and you know we're getting
older so like our bodies get more beat
up every year a little bit but uh you
know as far as like happiness is very
subjective totally I
mean you know like really if if that was
most of our focuses and what we were
doing was based in that kind of momentum
of you know happiness altruism
compassion love these kind of things
that would really like as a society as a
community as a peoples if we focus on
that generate more of that and just do
what we love really I think the you know
the Ripple effects of that it's like
it's world changing you know and and I
and I think that we're actually seeing
that in real time because all of us and
even the generations before us because
we're kind of in that weird interm um
generation of cannabis it seems like
because there's the ones in their you
know 60s 7s 80s past and then us in our
40s or whatever and then you know the
sets below us but you know we really
um it's really something's quite special
that we got to take this torch on you
know and we really um I remember like
when Michael bacas Morpheus you know
with um he had a doctor chemist Mark and
they wanted me and Mark to get together
to Run montel's Greenhouse in DC that
first big one you know and I was like
why does he I said bro why do you want
me dude you know like like I'm just like
grow Boutique level organic flower like
it's all bro we want you for your
intuitional ability we want to put you
with Mark he's a doctorate chemist you
know and yeah what happens there then
that's what we're looking for and I was
like ah so then I took that back home to
Oregon you know I'm like well if they
want me here then I'm going to take this
back to Oregon and help the government
like with this process and you know it's
funny we got the orgon country fair that
basically Grateful Dead kind of was the
ban Hell's Angels was security back in
the day and oh yeah now it's like what
it is you know a little more corporate
obviously but like yeah you know the
senator um one of the backup managers
there a good friend uh good friend of
mine and you know that's how I got in
contact with the government system cuz
he's a senator and he is basically the
one of the main champions of he you know
was a champion for medical got it to go
and Champion for these kind of you know
next bills that went and so I went back
and contacted him and got in contact
with him and he kind of put me under his
wing and had me help him how I can Al
from SC Labs getting me all the
pesticide information to get every right
things on thew the rule list you know
like yeah yeah like you know so a lot of
people don't understand you know we
might be like a brand or you know us
sitting here they recogniz this maybe
for seeds or genetics or highend organic
flour or whatever but the reality is is
we're doing a lot of work behind the
scenes a lot of the times to really help
this momentum happen and continue to
happen by getting proper laws put in
place getting proper stewardship in the
ways that at least the government can
understand that you know someone that
smokes all day every day can be
accountable can be you know eloquent can
be aware intelligent high IQ these
things happen without any hindrance from
this plant and actually and more ex
expression of awareness through the
plant and they can you know and that's
really helped I think because I saw we
we consulted we went and consulted us uh
finance committee US Congress n DC you
know with it's like multiple politicians
there and everything it's like they
wanted to hear from us because we can
speak awar we can do these kind of
things with the the plant in a way that
was out of their understanding at the
time you know in the you know 2012 13 14
15 16 now now it's like oh yeah they're
like oh yeah all these smart people
smoke weed no big deal you know totally
well yeah I mean you know people are
kind of slow to get it but this plant
makes the world a better place you know
at the end of the day you know and it's
funny because I think even my parents
generation they had a hard time with me
wanting to be involved with cannabis
growing and everything thing you know I
was pretty honest with my parents
especially they come and visit us and
stay at our house and I'd be like we got
plants in the garage and my dad's like
oh yeah you got plant I'm like I got
plants in the garage I just want to let
you know I got plants he's like you have
plants oh oh and you know it's like but
it was kind of a shock and then he was
kind of disappointed he was pretty
impressed with the you know our basic
our carpentry skills and everything else
but he was a little bit worried about
the legality of it and me getting in
trouble and then sanj gupa you know
comes on 60 Minutes and and he changed
the world in a whole different
perspective showing kids that benefited
from cannabis for sure you know and from
cannaboids and I think for sure it's
hard to argue that this plant doesn't
make a the world a better place you know
I'm working in St Vincent in the
Grenadines out in in I work with the
government down there I donated 30,000
seeds and I created
a strategy that should help Infuse a lot
of money in the community if they do
their own breeding on the island and
they have an identity uh for export and
I think the potential for that is huge
but the government down there is very in
support of using the plant to make the
world a better place and their Community
a better place and I love that amazing
yeah that's the I mean that's really the
in my opinion the plants intention you
know I know it's just a plant whatever
but you know for us to have such a
high receptor base for the cannaboid
molecules and even like a lot of our
favorite animal like the dog has one of
the largest cannaboid receptor systems
in of all animals you know for it to be
our you know co-pilot in a lot of this
for a lot it's like you know there's
something special about this plant
that's on a deep level right you know
and that we're all seeing it and sharing
it and being a part of it I mean I don't
hear anyone being like Oh no man like
you know unless you know you people like
to drink a lot of booze seem like they
have a kind of issue with weed you know
if they you know alcoholics or whatever
they don't like to smoke weed because
maybe it makes them drink less it makes
you drink less they're like no that's a
it's like what I always think with like
alcohol you know it's like kind of like
Corps in a in an ant's brain you know
it's like the alcoholism is going to
basically manipulate you and coarse you
to doing its task you know what I mean
and and weed comes in the thing that's
going to make you drink less and so
that's a that's a problem the weed is
you know because the alcohol wants to be
part of it more you know so it's like
NOP less alcohol no weed then you know
it's like um I've noticed that kind kind
of correlation people that drink too
much they don't they don't like to get
high you know because yeah oh I have my
I get a weird trip you know weird head
trip you know I'll get anxious or it's
like yeah man you for sure
will yeah I mean I think for sure if you
smoke first and then drink you're going
to drink way less totally and uh you
might get sick if you're a drinker and
then you're just an occasional smoker
you might get sick if you smoke too like
at the end you might get yeah you might
get the spins or whatever totally but uh
you know it's like but I think you
definitely drink less when you're
smoking like that's just across the
board for sure you know and I do have
friends that Crossfade a little too much
you know we all do we all we all have
the you know it's you know like I it's
really like moderation is key with
everything even with cannabis you know
and um because you know once our
receptors are full they're full and you
know how much more you need early
actually you don't need to waste it you
know you can for sure you know there's
there's a you know it's like you know
you get it when you're just smoking hash
hash after hash and rosing and hash and
hash at a certain point is just like
it's all flavor you know cuz it's ain't
nothing much more happen you're not
going up any higher you know there are
certain things uh Durban Poison being
one of them and allow it that don't have
ceilings where you can just keep smoking
you can go you can go places you never
thought you could go you're like this
feels like LSD yeah exact I've been
there before or edibles you know from
some of the African genetics it's like
wow you you just you do get a
psychedelic experience and there's
people that'll argue it but I've been
there so I know firsthand and I've done
plenty of psychedelics so I know in
comparison like I've had more of a
psychedelic experience with some of
these varieties with Edibles drinking
bang where they mix it with hot milk for
sure well that was what they you know a
lot of the Buddhist practitioners way
back there's you know certain practices
where that that's in combination with
the practice you know yeah little bit of
bong you know whole bottle go into their
Retreat cave and you know do their
meditation I mean you're like whoa you
know it's a you know I used to make this
uh back in the day you know we put just
pack a crock poot with Sugar Leaf oh
yeah and then just put olive oil in
there and do like a slow cook on it
through the day and then just you know
stract that basically just pour that off
in filter and just take spoonfuls you
know and like you know one teaspoon
you're like you know one tablespoon you
know like my buddy one time my buddy's
like took like three tablespoon he calls
me the next day he's all bro I swear my
heart stopped and it was beating like
one time every couple minutes you know
oh I've been there yeah we back in the
90s there wasn't a ton of literature
there was like one book on the chemistry
of it but we really liked exploring and
trying different stuff and we had all
this trim always right so we would make
tinctures and we would do bicardi 151
and put it on the you know double burner
and uh cook it in there and we had
different ways of making butter and
everything else but we had so much extra
trim that it was always like what can we
do with it now and this was you know
then we started making bubble hat and
that all changed so it's like oh now we
got extract all the time well it's even
making like the making the tinctures out
of bubble hash or like you know the the
220 or the whatever the 160
love you'd like take all that and dry it
and make the tincture out of that and
like sure that's like you know what I
like to do is I like to heat the
material just a little bit before cuz
like when I make the tincture when I
don't heat it you know it kind of does
the fermentation thing and starts to
like expand [ __ ] right and then you
decarb it right from the beginning you
decarb it when it's in flower form or in
hash form and then put that to the
extract and it's like just little easier
to work with you know I found for sure
yeah I mean we always used to make
different stuff and different drinks and
Cocktails and we never knew the
milligrams back in the day you just you
know you would be rushing you knew off
the first shot you know like somebody
knew off the first yeah like sometimes
even the first 15 minutes you know some
of this stuff when your face starts
getting crunchy and hot or something
you're like oh that was a little
stronger start getting purple the only
time that happens is when I eat peppers
peppers are strong strong strong texures
dude I love I mean that's what I like I
used to just carry around a bottle
tinure because like you know three four
drops under the tongue and you're like
wow you you know gets like like you're
saying that you know because they well
they do say that like cannaboids through
the body through the stomach through the
you know that kind of whole system is
going to create more of a psychedelic
experience you at a certain range you
know and you if you've eaten enough if
youve you know 200 whatever milligrams
thousand 500 whatever yeah yeah like
it's like it starts to happen yeah you
know and I've told I work with a lot of
people with cancer and everything and
you know obviously with tinctures and
stuff like that and you know I've talked
to this one woman she had um I forgot
what it's called I think some trans
transrenal neuralgia type of brain
cancer that was on the optic nerve and
um brain stem very severe pain one I
think that's also term that suicide
disease because it's so bad you know and
W I gave her the medicine and you know
and I told her she's like well how much
do I take you know I was like I was like
as much as you can you know and you're
trying to get to a grma day and she's
like you know I'm kind of scared you
know and I said yeah it's it'll be scary
you know but are you more scared of the
medicine or you more scared of happens
if you know right and what's crazy is
she took the medicine and at that dose
and five weeks she called me frantic you
know I heard this pop in her head went
to the doctor got CAT scans MRIs and
there was just Halos where those tumors
were there were size of one was the size
of a um like apricot small apricot the
other one was size of a ping pong ball
oh man and gone you know and I and you
know like and she told me she's like the
beginning was really hard cuz the amount
and when you're having a terminal
illness there's a lot of other things
psychologically going on right when
you're that level of being high and your
fear of deaths and these things you know
like the very mortal things happen and
you know and she told me and but then it
kind of eased off and had this
experience and you know it's sick that
was H I don't know maybe seven eight
years ago and still watch her on
Facebook with her husband they did you
know coffee shop watched her daughter
graduate college you know and like to be
able to you know we have lots of and I'm
sure you do too lots of you know stories
like that and it's no [ __ ] better
blessing than that you know to be able
to to see that and to share that and to
you know share our experience of
creating this medicine in a you know
holistic way to where you know where it
does make the world a better place and I
think a lot of us even an extra day one
one extra day longer it's all worth it
right and if can give you that extra day
I've had friends that have used cannabis
and and lost their battles you knowt and
I've had friends that have beat cancer
with cannabis and so and maybe it's not
right for every type of cancer but it's
worth exploring and I think the other
thing is it is scary if you're not a
cannabis user going into trying cannabis
you have cancer that's scary enough and
now you got to take this drug that a lot
of times seems scary on the outside and
a lot of times you have to build your
tolerance up to it a grma day is a lot
wow you know it's it's a wow you know
but and my friend month to build up you
know yeah my friend Dave mesford he he
lost the battle you he he fought for I
think three years four years uh and he
was taking a gram a day and he built up
to that tolerance but like that's a lot
you know I think he was at two grams a
day at one point wow and that's that's a
a lot and you know but but if you can
get an extra day or extra month or an
extra year of life I think that's you
know that's that's amazing for sure it's
worth every
aspect of it you know because we we
don't understand that like you know
that's what people you know there's a
lot of this Chase but really in those
last phases it's going to be family what
how you treated people you know like how
you were loved how you love and those
are going to be the important things and
one thing about this plant it shows you
that too right it can show you that
before those you know in more terminal
phases even you know and if we utilize
it as a holistic medicine it can be as a
preventative in some ways just in our
own psyche you know feeling more love
acceptance these kind of things you yeah
it's a great way to deal with trauma you
know and some PE you know people use
alcohol to escape and to tune out
whereas I feel like plant medicine
psychedelics cannabis especially Tunes
Us in right it Tunes you into music it
Tunes you into reality it Tunes you back
into what's important and that's you
know that's why we're here today for
sure that's uh I think that is one of
the big beauties of the planet is the
you know just like it does in our body
yeah the connectivity it does in
community you know and the the reach and
what it's I mean look at it's what's
happened to the world right now with
cannabis
it's at one point it was a huge facet in
our industrial um formulation and
agricultural formulation with Humanity
right and kind of then got pushed under
the rug you know intentionally
unintentionally um but it couldn't be
held back right and now it's it's over
you know the whole globe is infatuated
with it in a way that it's like maybe
this is one of our last um last Great
Hopes you know yeah to evolve Humanity
as a race to give us fuel food and you
know structural building tools to
actually change this kind of Continuum
of what we've created it's has
everything well it's such a complete
part of our existence you know and it
can be used for so many different things
besides healing and all the other things
that are you know obvious to us I guess
maybe not to other people but very
obvious to us as far as building yeah we
can build with it we can build houses
with it we can build concrete flame
[ __ ] yeah there's just and there's
so many things you know they've been
using it for for rope for the longest
time and textiles and well even I heard
the first Ford like Model A all the
fabrics and the Plastics were made of
hemp yeah well hemp is so much it lasts
so much longer than cotton nobody in the
cotton industry wants to hear it but you
know that's you know it's a superior
product on so many levels for sure you
know and it's a perfect protein you know
if we look at the protein and the fats
the quality of nutrition that it can
give us and give to places that you know
are malnourished I mean I think there's
just so much potential for it yeah I
think the potential is really Limitless
you know we haven't even we barely
cracked the surface on it in my opinion
and what we're going to do and what
you're seeing you know because like I
mean every a lot of people are on you
know Instagram but you go to LinkedIn
and you know you're like holy [ __ ]
there's like professionals doing like
real professional [ __ ] on here you know
I mean like at huge levels you know it's
uh some the scientists just I mean even
in breeding you know you hear stuff on
my show we talk a little bit about data
driven breeding but the potential for
breeding and and marker driven breeding
you know it's like uh for for traits and
for drug Discovery I mean totally that
gets me excited I mean I think plant
medicine full spectrum plant medicine as
a whole it's like we were on this this
trajectory that was completely the
opposite of that where they're like oh
you just take this one molecule and
it'll hopefully kill you for this but
look at all the side effects right and
now we're like oh well we have this full
spectrum thing that has no side effects
or very minimal side effects that does
all these different things and we can
use that and go in all these different
directions once we start understanding
it better totally and I I think that's
the beauty of right now what's happening
that I mean even
um you know at the conference I was
talking to guy Martin and he was telling
me all these different things of you
know basically the science of seeing all
these different markers that are
released from different sugars light you
know whatever and you can manipulate the
genetic cycle the plants growth all this
stuff just through these you know
different markers it's like ah and
imagine the range of those because I was
telling it's like okay if this is just
structural and say conventional farming
what about say like non-conventional
farming where you do have living soil
biome and all these kind of things the
enzymatic response and all that and
that's creating more of these factors
right and there's more you know just the
net of factors and the range of
possibilities just he's it just keeps
growing you know you're just like wow
chemotyping can totally change you know
it's like and that's what people don't
it's like we've we've got our our
phenotypes that everybody understands
we've got the genotypes that are hidden
inside and then we've got the chemotype
Expressions that that we're looking for
these chemical Expressions they get
changed you know they could be changed
by the environment they can get changed
by the nutrition just like the phenotype
can well you know that's what like um we
know when philos come online and uh you
know the beginning and everything we
started working with them and gave them
all the ogs that we had you know it be
koser Kush uh you know ghost OG Fire OG
sour best [ __ ] ever Skywalker OG and you
know that that headband that was the OG
one you know right and they're like this
is all the same cut yeah all the same
I'm like I'm like oh I don't know man
the highs are different you know and
I've kept I kept them really healthy and
so where they weren't having like
morphology issues of through degradation
and stuff and they're you know I'm like
still to this day I'm like I don't know
if they're the same cut or if they're
s1's but they're really close well I'll
tell you that Josh D and the ghost they
they had the same cut they went through
different paths right and then I got
them back and grew them side by side and
they grew very differently uh but they
were definitely related like they seem
L's headband [ __ ] cuts the same you know
it's all the same you know and yeah so
we had the headband cut that our friend
NL had brought so he's the one that
brought it to NorCal as headband he had
got it from Josh and Josh was like you
can't call it OG and so he called it
headband and he told he lied to us for
years and we all we all called it
headband but it was just the Josh dog
and it it yielded really well and the
ghost that I had didn't yield nearly as
well but uh yeah like the Skywalker OG I
have yields amazing you know it's like
you know that g-cut one whatever crowned
out you know Stacks really well the SPs
kind of looks similar but doesn't stack
as well um but but I you know for me
there is high differences and you know
so I'm like okay well and epigenetic
changes that probably happen along the
way because people have put their energy
into it right and then we've along with
you know bacteria there's like systemic
bacteria that that's in the plant
there's all these things that happen to
the life techniques of Horticultural you
know expression
right so we have stress whether it's
pest or whether it's pathogen or you
know or environmental we have these
stressers that are going to manipulate
the plant and you know to say it's the
same plant after it goes through these
paths in different directions it's it's
not the same plant so tissue culture
whether it can take it back you know
that's there's the argument of okay well
we can take off these epigenetic changes
I don't believe that fully U you know
and they're studying methylation now and
some different
things uh but you know it's all exciting
and I think we're just scratching the
surface of it um and in 10 years we're
going to know a lot more about the plant
we're going to know a lot more about
ourselves uh you know and we're in this
beautiful place dud like I feel like
we're in the infancy of something that's
going to be longstanding that's going to
have great impact over the next 100 200
300 years if we're alive as as you know
as mankind as long as we're alive we're
going to have impact on the future
totally I mean even look at like um you
know that uh the Chinese pharmacopia
from you know pre 2000 or pre you know
over 2,000 years ago right yeah you know
where they you know the plant was they
called it what the plant of a 100 cures
or something you know had more medicinal
uses than any other plant in the book
right back then to where where now 2,000
plus years later still talking about
that book then and it being
representative of what this plant can
offer in you know preindustrial times MH
it's huge you know and you know we're
discovering that okay first agricultural
set of cannabis was in Tibet you know
they're finding now you know when they
just discovered they're like well this
predates what we knew before so they
were obviously growing this for some
reasons back then already you know and
you know I think that just like with the
dog and these things you know certain
plants uh helped our
agricultural um kind of evolution in
ways that other plants didn't you know
and if these medicinal plants like even
you look at iasa you know how who who
who knew to combine manister opsis copy
and chuno these two plants together to
make this potion right who who told them
that how did that bit discover you know
you know so like even like when you know
I was like six years old I'm in Nebraska
right in Lincoln these plants were in
this dude's backyard you know you know
me and my friend we you my neighbor
friend we just see him you know and I
was like they were [ __ ] calling me
you know I'm like what I jumped the
fence ripped them all out the ground
took them back to my house had one of
those blue little plastic swimming pools
fil put them in there filled it with
water and me and my friend were just
like with our feet Barefoot tromping on
it you know my dad comes out it's like
what the [ __ ] you know like military guy
you know like you know
so and he you know he didn't smoke weed
he didn't you know he smoked cigarettes
but didn't like you know there was no
reference of drug culture nature
anything like that but there's this
thing that's saying like you're
attracted to me mhm you know and so
you know as societies and tribes and
cultures over
Millennia how much of how much has that
plant guided our Evolution you know and
here we are into this phase of the most
technical time of humanity I mean in
current you know day um and here's this
plant fully embedded and entangled all
of it you know it's so strange that the
prohibition happened when it happened
right and like right when technolog is
kicking off there's this cannabis
prohibition you know it's like and it's
right around around the same time the
technology kind of boomed right so but
and then now you know 50 years later
we're or 40 years later we're coming
back to it and understanding that hey
it's not such a bad thing it actually
makes the world a better place it's
something that needs to be studied for
sure I mean even like you know you can
see what it does even myself you know I
was super aggressive when I was younger
and yeah you know and it just made it
rounded the edges you know and it really
um helped me see myself in a way that I
didn't need to be aggressive I didn't
need to be that guy I can be softer more
patient you know more understanding I
can be less arrogant and you know less
of an egomaniac and I can see those
things and the plant really shows you
that you know really you know like it's
like if you say something that was maybe
self-centered or rude or something you
smoke some weed and everyone's gone
you'll be thinking about that thing
right you know and thinking that that
wasn't the right thing to do and say why
cuz this plant you know it's trying it's
doing its best to make it better you
know for sure well and on a deeper level
I think that we are who we are because
of the experiences we've had and the
trauma that we've had and so we all have
this unique lens that we see the world
through and then when you're able to
smoke cannabis some of those traumas can
kind of get moved over here and then we
can see the world how it really is I
mean I think psychedelics will even do
that further they'll take more of those
filters off and then you're like whoa
cuz ego really makes us not not necessar
who we are but ego can totally screw us
up you know and make us see the world
from a completely different perspective
have negative impact and the more we can
kind of strip away that ego the more we
can become good people and make the
world a better place so for sure I mean
it it lies to us consistently you know
to get what it needs which it wants to
be permanent it wants to be stagnant it
wants to be there yeah and you know
Freedom doesn't happen there you know
and so like if we can you know utilize
this plant step back see the ego see its
entanglement of aversion of attachment
and what it's kind of doing to our to
our brain yeah you know and through a
fear response or basically or a you know
desire response or something so if we
can see that by just you know stepping
aside well ego so desperately wants you
to feel special you know you want to
feel special ego tells you that you need
to special that you need to be different
you deserve it that you deserve to be
special or that you deserve to be
different than everybody else and and
really I think our job is to just come
come here do what we're best at to the
best of our ability and try to leave
something good for everybody else by
totally I mean I think um you know we
have this term called bodhichitta you
know which is the altruistic mind that
wishes to achieve enlightenment for the
sake of all other beings you know and
you know there's a being called abhava
which has taken that mind as its Core
Essence of you know experience here and
really altruistically tries to help
others in a way that's ultimate you know
and I think this plant
really you know can help that and that
is where the true happiness will come
from yeah you know when we're when we're
not based in our arrogant egoic
entanglement and we can step back and
see things altruistically and really
help others you know there's this uh you
know saying you know for as long as
space remains for as long as sentient
beings remain until then may I too
remain to dispel the miseries of the
world and you know and that's kind of
the essence of the bodh of mind which
really this plant in my you know eyes
fully entangles that Essence and
everyone that it doesn't matter what you
believe what you think what you you know
eat what you drink usually people that
consume cannabis when they do it they
feel better right they feel happier well
they they whether they know it or not
they're on the path to spiritual
enlightenment you know I love that right
in the whole buddh is the principles
behind it I think it's amazing because
spiritual enlightenment is something
that whether you know you're on that
path or or not if you're smoking
cannabis or you take plant medicine
you're on that path for sure because you
know that Evolution process is something
that you know most of us are not going
to escape in our lifetimes you know it's
it's really I think uh the human nature
and I think it's all beings nature
actually and because you can set see
that even if you put a flame towards a
bug it's going to go away from the flame
not into the flame right so even on a
ant level it doesn't want to suffer
right and you can see that most the
reason most people are doing the things
they're doing is because they don't want
to suffer and they think that they're
going to do the things that are going to
eliminate that suffering or they're not
going to suffer you know but most of us
are doing the things that make us suffer
because we are not informed you know um
but but I think if people really focus
on love you know compassion and really
um you know selflessness you know which
happens from mindfulness you know you
don't have to be in your thought pattern
of your ego of what you're trying to
convince your brain to believe through
being special or you know if you can
just be in a breath and be
aware moment and shut that off a lot of
times most people don't even know how to
do that I think and it took me a long
time of even trying to do that before I
learned how to shut it off you know like
to where I'm living in the moment I'm
living in that breath totally that that
flow State mind really like you know if
you're an athlete or high level athlete
or musician you can really relate with
it well you know but you know it's kind
of it's similar you know Jiu-Jitsu
changed my mind changed my it changed my
life for that especially that flow State
and combining it with cannabis is
another one where all the jits studes
love cannabis yeah and the reason all
everybody that does jiujitsu or martial
arts I mean I think a lot of guys
because you can get in that state where
you're not thinking you're just uh
reacting and you're moving and flowing
without having to think about what am I
doing next because the second you start
thinking about what you're doing next
you're going a lot slower than you would
if you're just reacting and flowing
totally without a doubt you know it's
like and I'm not even that good at
Jiu-Jitsu I'm not good at all at
Jiu-Jitsu but I love Jiu-Jitsu and I
love what it does for my body and for my
mind and it's something that I need to
do a lot more of so yeah no it's a
really um amazing thing I wrestled you
know all through school and and did some
jits and my K did some jits and uh you
know like it's that anything that you're
going to be doing an intense active
sport yeah that you have to like you
said you have to be mindful and you know
um present and not be thinking or you're
not going to perform well whether it be
surfing snowboarding you know like deep
powdering trees and or climbing you know
it's all these things take a focus that
if you're thinking I mean don't get me
wrong cling analytical but like it's
less Flow State but I've seen my friend
that climbs you know free solo like you
know 500,000 foot stuff free solo that
dude's in the Flow State he ain't
thinking you know he's like well it's
the same thing cooking on the line when
you're working in a kitchen or when
you're cooking or whether you're doing
Jiu-Jitsu it's all about preparation
right so if you're
prepared even growing to a degree like
if you're prepared ahead of time you're
going to have a lot better results you
know you might get lucky you might get
lucky in Jiu-Jitsu you might get lucky
in the kitchen but uh if you're not
prepared you're not going to have as
good results and the thing is is like
because you don't have to really think
about what you're doing you can flow
even in the kitchen you have all your
ingredients laid out in front of you
you're going to have a lot better
results than if you're scrambling around
the kitchen finding stuff you know at
the last doubt so and it translates to
so many things like at the you know
buying stuff you you go to the grow shop
and they're out of the thing that you
needed that day you know and that
happens all the time I mean a lot of
people and it's like if you're prepared
in advance you're going to have a lot
more success holy creating that
foundation in anything that you're going
to basically have success in is clutch
you know and really really um you know
understanding the causal nature of
things and then breaking down that
formula and you know and getting
prepared it's it's a huge part of
anything especially spiritual practice
cultivation music martial arts any high
level sport yeah you know it's like even
with surfing if you can surf and you can
be good but if you're not in shape yeah
you can [ __ ] drown you know like with
a quick you know like it's like you
think you you know well last time I
surfed I could surf this this size you
know you get out there and C paddle and
you be like in the Impact Zone just like
you know yeah rethinking life oh yeah
you know like yeah or you get caught in
the wrong side of a set and you have
another wave crashing on you and uh yeah
it's all bad yeah no it's you really get
um nothing's you know I've you know I've
climbed a lot of stuff in Yus and stuff
and um but nothing's um put a uh reality
check on me more than almost drowning
and big set or you know because it's
like you get to a point where you can't
even breathe even though you're above
surface you know you're so exhausted and
winded from holding your breath and like
taking beatings that you come up and
you're like like hyperventilated almost
that you can't even breathe even though
you're above the surface it's like
experience yeah I've got a lot of water
in my lungs before and it's not fun you
know and thought I was going to die and
I experienced that at a very young age
so kind of it's It's funny those things
that you experience at a young age can
be really beneficial especially
near-death experiences you learn how
fragile life is to a deg it took me a
long time you know I was in my 30s
before I really understood but I
understood life a lot more from almost
dying as a kid um you know I I almost
ODed as a kid as well and so I think
those kind of things put the you know
the the experience of life and the
fragility of life into perspective a
little bit more without a doubt you know
I think a lot of us we just we were
Invincible in our 20s you know it was it
wasn't until 30s yeah it's like you
start and I think you start losing
friends you know from from everything
and as you get into your 40s now I'm
getting in my 40s and I was talking to
some my friends in their 50s and they're
like yeah just wait 50s is where you
really start losing your friends your
health starts to go you know your 40s
you might lose your vision a little bit
you know you might lose your hairline
you know but but yeah it's interesting
aging is really interesting and it's
funny the knowledge that you get over
time it's it's like the years move
faster every year seems a little bit bit
faster than the year before and one of
my uncles put it into perspective that
uh you know when you're 5 years old a
year is 20% of your life but when you're
50 you know it's it's a 125th of your
life or a 100 it's it's a 1% of your
life you know so really put I mean
that's a really bad analogy right there
but like as far as like every year it
it's basically that one year is shorter
and so it seems like they just go from
one season to the next a lot faster
without a doubt even if you're good at
mindfulness practice and breath Focus
you know cuz I've you know I I try to
stay pretty present and try not to think
about even you know my first teacher
told me he like bro your brain's already
like clogged up with memories and stuff
he's like you got to eliminate a lot of
that stuff so you can memorize things
and get makes the space you know yeah um
but what I realized over the time is if
I'm not looking back on the past and
being present and aware and what's
happening time's non-existent it's like
when I look back at the things and the
moments and you know and the the the
range and how you know it seems really
quick but if I start to go from this
moment back throughout this day than
yesterday you know like it's quite long
and all the experiences are quite Rich
you know right but if I'm looking from
here to there wow man that sucks you
know I don't like to do that so much
Thanksgiving to Christmas it's just wow
yeah like even watching my son grow up
and everything and yeah become you know
start to become a young man and like
like [ __ ] man it was like he was so
sweet dude like now it's like you're
like bro you're like you don't even want
me to hug you in public barely bro like
totally you know yeah it's amazing how
fast time passes in some ways and how
slow it is in others and it's all just
perception and perspective you know well
that's the thing is it's you know they
say in a from a Buddhist perspective
they don't you know they believe time's
an illusion right and really because it
impermanence is a truth so there's a
continual flux in all things
everything's impermanent that's a truth
so um you know the all these planetary
structures and their movement and
everything they're always in flow and
always in a continual flux so there is
no fixed moment actually you know it's
like what's happened what's happening
and what's yet to happen you know is how
it would be broke down but time you know
that's the stagnation that we're trying
to fixate our you know our ego wants to
make it real you know make it stable and
make it make it solid and still you know
we want it to last forever and even our
point of view you know that's the ego
wants it to be solid and you know this
is real this with truth you know the
reality is it's not like you think with
most things you know even if we're
accurate you know even like with
impermanence you know it's a permanent
thing you know there's like whatever 16
some types of permanences but like
impermanence being one of them but even
all the conceptual aspects of it and
everything they're still representations
of our awareness and how we're
perceiving things but in its true
Essence all those fade away right yeah
and it is how it is and what what's
happening is what's happening but once
we start to make it relative to our
experience and whatever we're we're
still taking away of the depth and the
subtleties of it actually on a true
level at least you know in my opinion
you know it's it's like really uh what's
crazy is it's so subtle so vast so
simple and so deep you know all in the
same aspects and you know time's a good
one to kind of get lost in or you know
the fact that it doesn't exist actually
but the fourth dimension yeah totally
yeah it's wild
uh you know so I had a psychedelic
experience from nitrous oxide when I was
a kid and that was it's funny because
like we talk about nitrous and people
think of it hippie crack or whatever you
know it's a strong one it's a strong it
can be a strong one you know and I had a
full melt the First full melt DMT trip I
ever had was on nitrous oxide oh yeah
did they do the combo no no no no no I
got the experience from the nitrous
oxide and I was at a rave wow and I was
in the VIP area and there was a bean bag
and someone just handed me a big
punching ball
balloon and I had hit this I'm like oh
there's a there's a bean bag right there
yeah I was like perfect uh I had a full
melt experience and I basically went to
this place and I understood everything
right stuff that you can't understand I
couldn't put it into words coming back
here but I really I I woke up and I
don't know how long I was out for but it
felt like a very long time and my
friends like well where were you and I
was like dude you guys got I Tred to get
all my friends together yeah there was
no balloon when I woke up right
and literally I had to get all my
friends to tell them everything that I
understood because I understood
everything I understood existence I
understood everything and got my friends
together and I couldn't put it into
words and it was the most frustrating
thing ever because I had totally
understood it but in this dimension in
this plane I could not put it into words
because it's more than we can comprehend
in this existence but the one thing I
took away from this whole experience and
this was I was 17 years old is that
we're all going to be okay and so that
stuck with me I'm 47 now so that's like
literally 30 years ago I had that we're
all going to be okay no matter what in
the end we're all okay totally so yeah
yeah I me I I remember one time smoking
a grandma DMT one night and you know got
pretty high obviously with that hitting
it out the bong you know back when we
didn't really know how to smoke it as
well you know like 20 some years ago and
I remember seeing the plant on the table
you know and the soil and the container
and myself and I remember seeing the
plant and me exact same energy yeah you
know but the
table was different the soil was a
little different and the pot was
different but me and the plant were the
same and I was like ah you know really
having that realization that all living
things are sharing you know the similar
type of energy right you know and and
then they even proved with DMT that they
say that all you know carbon based life
has DMT in it you know and it's like
you're like wow you know big lessons
come from these psychedelic EXP
experiences a lot of times and we can't
really explain the depth of them a lot
of ways but one thing that this common
um you know thing is that everything's
interconnected MH they're all of the
same Source you know energy source light
whatever you know yeah and and there's a
similarity that's much larger than a
difference for sure you know and that's
like you know it can come in all kinds
of different ways and the perspectives
and you know perceptions but well DMT is
so wild because you can have so many
different types of trips it's not just
the same experience every
time no it's not thank God thank God
yeah Salvia is a wicked one man that's
that's like when it comes to plant
medicine Salvia is basically not a good
starting point for most people that's
like the end point and maybe you only do
it a couple times or once you yeah you
shouldn't start there because you may
never want to do anything else ever if
you think that's what psychedelics are
about then you're probably yeah yeah for
sure wild yeah no that's the I have the
most respect for salvie actually you you
have to yeah if you don't you're going
to be in big trouble it's like one of
those things it's like uh you know it's
it's
wild it's definitely wild you know I was
like well you know that's like the
opposite of DMT experience you know but
like similar message you know like I
mean similar message different yeah
different path way different approach
like well yeah man yeah I mean
psychedelics are pretty wild U and then
you know mushrooms it's funny now
mushrooms
people take micro does now and I
appreciate micro does I I like micro
does for public speaking and stuff like
that but yeah me too as far as we never
did micro does back in the day it was
like a half an eighth if you only could
eat a gram you were like disappointed
you half an e is the the starting point
for for the real ones you know yeah and
and maybe we had more mild mushrooms I
don't care but we always had trips so we
weren't we weren't taking mushrooms just
to feel okay we were taking mushrooms to
experience something that lasted a while
and you know it changed our
state of mind it wasn't just like oh
we're not going to drink tonight we're
going to eat a littleit you want the
whole Forest to breathe you know right
exactly the the ground should be
breathing you know everything should be
coming alive for sure so yeah but it's
interesting they're micro doing LSD
they're micro doing mushrooms they're
doing micro does of everything including
cannabis cannabis is like heavily micro
doed now compared to what we were doing
when we were younger well yeah even the
LSD thing you know like I've been micro
doing for decades because you know when
you when you have the vial I mean you
can get yourself the trouble you know if
you're at a show or something you know
and this when I realized it it's like oh
every time I remember I was at a
Widespread Panic show at the cuer you
know and it was my friend and you know
we're I'm dosing everyone you know
little micros you know you know Clear
Eyes bottle but you don't realize that a
drop out of a clear eyes bottle like
three hits really you know it's like and
so you're just like you're actually
giving real hits and you're like every
time I'll take another I'll take another
next thing you know you don't hear
anything you just you know seeing all
the sound come out in light and can't
even talk or think anymore it's like oh
you know so you know even back then I
started micro doing you know meaning
deluding yeah so it's more safe you know
you don't have to like you know you know
it's like oh you have to take 10 drops
actually to get one drop you know one
hit so that's like safe you know it's
way safer actually that's that's a great
yeah the 10 10 to one is a great
approach for sure you know you got to
get yourself in trouble on purpose with
that one you know it's not like you're
like even you know doing events or doing
talks or podcasts it's like you know
know it's like are you going to really
you don't need that many you just take
one and then you know you have energy
two whatever but you know you're not
going on stage you know you don't want
to be like you know so it's different
you know um like with the cactus for me
I you know I took Cactus every day for
like three years and yeah um you know
and that was kind you micro do it too or
I guess you could say that but you know
I would take a you know I mean I would
take the same amount now that I'd take
if I me me and the lady are going out
for a night and having a good time
whatever I'm you know five 10 15 Mills
of this gel that my you know family
makes very special recipe and um so I
took that every day for 3 years on my
preliminary stuff you know an upper
division UFO stuff and you know really
uh utilized it as like kind of like the
Limitless pill you know from that movie
you know it's like you know just like
micros and LSD similar thing you can you
memorize really well you have a lot of
energy stamina awareness you know and it
can creativity outside the box thinking
all that good stuff yeah yeah you know
you see a lot of these upper you know
hedge funds CEOs or whatever those dudes
are all micro doing you know they're all
you know all the PE not all but most
people I know at upper echelon thinking
and creativity and action yeah they're
on psychedelics just in one form or
another for sure you know and so well
now there's so many options too it's not
like back in the day there was like one
or two now it's like there's a wide
spectrum of you know for sure I mean I I
hear even there's MDMA pens you know I
know there's DMT pens mushroom pens you
know like all these things you're like
really and I'll just keep it simple like
how it's always I like old school myself
but yeah it's wild everything want you
know it's funny cuz we've we've started
to go in this direction of convenience
and I do love the pre-roll hand roll
model for cannabis I'm not a huge hash
hole guy we may do a hash hole in
metrics one of these days but as far as
I do like the convenience for the hand
roll but everything's gone into pen so
like Rosen carts I think it's cool I
think Rosen carts are good but you got
to use them right away they don't taste
for me like Rosen cards aren't good
after well even a couple weeks yeah even
if you know the first 10 hits Roz and
Carter all right but yeah then they go
it goes downhill really fast and so you
see these two G carts now I'm like why
would you have a two gr cart like I
would prefer a half gram cart especially
a Rosen cart a half gram rosin cart over
two grams of anything because after the
first gram it's all garbage like I don't
I don't want it I would much color
change oh yeah you go from this nice
light color to this dark color
something's going
on so yeah but we do live in this world
of convenience so with everything people
are like oh how can I how can I get it
easily and how how is it easily
accessible and I understand that the
pre-roll because I want people to
experience the same kind of joint I get
to smoke and I I take the time and
effort to roll these perfect joints
totally and I would love to share that
with the whole world you know I'm like
that excites me totally but uh it gets
to a level where they want overc
convenience for sure next thing it's
just a patch you know it's like yeah
it's like I just want the Cannabis
patch and you know maybe that's for you
that's fine but that's not yeah some
people they they'll get that and they'll
enjoy it but for me it's like there's
got to be the I like this smoking side
of it I like that whole experience the
ritual aspect of it absolutely you know
I like roll you know how it is it's like
I mean that's kind of how even I started
back in the day I was you know I loved
herb so you know get into high school
out of high school you got you you get
the ounce you sell the three quarters
and you keep the quarter and then you're
like well I need more you know you sell
the 4 ounces you need the you get the
ounce oh you need you sell the you know
3/4 of a pound you keep the quarter
pound all the home you know it's like
just kind of builds you know and so like
that aspect is just something that's
really
um sweet and special and to really be
the one that's having the herb and then
rolling the joint and doing the thing
and being that kind of Provider right
all the way to now it's like there was a
ritual aspect in that now I mean now I
like to basically roll a joint I like to
put it in the grinder and I put rosin or
hash in the grinder I grind it up
together oh and I roll a cone that way
and I smoke you know people like will be
you know like even at MJ it's like dude
this this thing went around this six
person Circle six eight times you know
yeah no dude it's like a [ __ ] quarter
third gram of rosin in there too like Ah
that's what's yeah no that's how it
makes it around totally otherwise
otherwise it just gets to or or it runs
like crazy sometimes people want to hit
them too hard God oh cuz they're like
you know they're like oh joint oh and
tastes good oh yeah exactly the second
the first hit they might take a small
one the second hit they're like trying
to yeah they're they're trying to take
it out totally you know things like you
know so like you know rolling them with
the rosin or the hash that keeps them U
or even like the old School hash that
like you know what I'd like to do is um
do like 70 to you know 120 or 70 to 160
and just granulate it and air dry and
then you just put that you know grind
that in with that's the best I love I
love good bubble hash I mean I was
raised on good bubble hash from the
early 90s before we had Bubble Bags my
my buddy Micah showed me how to make
them on silk screens and we had like
this ritual a five gallon bucket you had
to S It One Direction had to STW it in
the other direction you had to let it
settle and then with a solo cup you were
scooping it over you know you were
literally scooping it over the silk
screen and we let it dry on the silk
screen we didn't know any better know
any different and but the hash was
amazing and so it was like we discovered
gold you know at that point I mean back
then it was gold because I remember
doing the like you know whatever early
2000 like you know with the bags yeah
and but then the like the 20 25 28 and
40 were like the cream because like
we're doing dry trim catching like you
know these hay strains or golden
pineapple whatever and that those bars
were each one of those you know I'd make
a you know 28 25 bar I'd make a 40 bar
make a 70 bar and really you know
putting it in the three hole three hole
Bowls the elf back then you know and
like so the 20 the 20-some and the
40-some were the best of that CU you
know I think it's catching the smallest
tricomes but after they've shriveled up
so it's actually like probably a 70 it's
catching you know and totally and so
like but it's just different I remember
making these bricks and like pressing
like you know like silk screen on silk
screen paper towel underneath and just
pressing all the water Wild colors out
of them to you know when you break them
like after they you know some of them
would look like [ __ ] on the outside but
you break it it'd be so gold like a
little gold bar and you're like
oh oh yeah yeah that 45 we get some
amazing tones like different Hues of of
red sometimes or orange some really cool
stuff yeah I mean those were amazing
days dude when I remember I remember
making some out in like you know I was
out in crestwell out in my you know I
remember snow and I was doing this
golden pineapple you know wash and I
don't know what happened I know I wasn't
micro doing but like when the tricomb
started to release heavy it looked like
almost like an iridescence in the foam
you know I was like [ __ ] something's
happening you know cuz it was so cold it
was so snowy and it was just like
everything was perfect you know and it
was just releasing and the mountain it
was dumping you're just like [ __ ] you
know this is Si you got a big old
Spoonful at the bottom those were the
best you know oh my goodness there was
sometimes we'd wash stuff and we didn't
know the genetics or something we' wash
it and there'd be nothing and then other
times you'd be like well we got cuz we
did a lot of Frozen too so we would have
Frozen sugar trim once we figured that
out it was a game changer but not
everything watchs the same it still
doesn't totally right so you'd be trying
something for the first time excited and
you'd be like oh there's not even a
spoonful in there or it'd be kind of
junky you know you're like oh this isn't
you know and that's what I noticed like
some of the ones that like with the dry
trim method with the big tricomb you're
like the mount you're catching in the
like you know in the 120 the 160 you're
like what dude that's look crazy lookt
you know and then or versus you know
some of the stuff that say will give you
that'll ghost you on a a fresh frozen
wash you know like golden or Trinity
they'll straight ghost you you know but
then you dry it and it's like what this
is this is like full m you know like
it's like crazy some of the strains that
on a fresh frozen will give you a ghost
but then on a dry trim will give you
some I mean the shit'll look like fresh
frow it'll you know crazy you know it's
like yeah it's so amazing and hash is so
wild and and you know they're just
really dialing in the genetics now too
so it's really amazing the directions
they're going I love rosin but I still
just love good bubble hash you know for
for me U you know dabbable bubble hash
is pretty great too well that's why I
mean this 90u full melt and stuff it's
you know melt it's like better than
rosin and anything and you know like not
to try to be a I'm not trying to say
this or be a hater to rosin or anything
but I don't know you know like pressure
Heat
parchment you know that combo with all
this microplastic and stuff you know
like I I can't really um you know I
don't know if there's something in there
so I do know for sure in like some 90u
full melt that's just caught with the
bag there's less chances of micr plastic
and stuff in there then there is some
pressurized squashed plastic thing you
know so well I'm excited about all these
static machines coming out now too I
think straight great Statics awesome
because we talk about you know
solventless and they say bubble hash
solvent water in my chemistry book in
High School it says water is the master
Sol it right like you know it'll go
through granite it'll do yeah totally
like literally in big bold letters going
back I was like whoa and then
solventless comes out I love niik and I
think it's great he coined a term it's
very unique and still accepted today and
that's how we change language and stuff
but uh true
solventless is static bubble hat you I
mean not bubble has but the second we
put it through water any sort of sift
and I loved sift back in the day I loved
Keef well remember when Cuban grower
came on dude
he was like with a microscope pulling
particles out you know like yeah you
know and it's funny cuz like the cameras
that we had back then weren't like the
cameras we have now and it's like there
was still incredible photos on Instagram
you know back in the day this was over
10 years ago well I mean even like you
know like Eric n shot's a good friend of
mine and everything you know and like
seeing the transition from you know
what's happening with you know like him
Nick with you know you know land Zoom
Gardens you know what I mean Nick and
then also like Marvin surface area these
you know it's insane bro like what's
happening you're just like wow and to be
able to see down on such a high
scientific level that even you know only
people that are really doing that level
stacking are like bug bug Shooters and
you know like people like shooting stuff
like that oh yeah it's totally amazing
Dynasty genetics know like his stuff his
photography is just like some of these
guys are just so skilled uh the quality
of photos they're photography they're
artists artists because there's and
there's so much to it a lot of people
just see the picture and they get
excited about this picture they don't
know what it's just like with genetics
and other things they don't know really
what went into it they see the end
result and they're like oh that's
amazing but they don't understand look
how much Clarity there is on that flower
harvesting that plant and preparing that
plant and getting it at the right moment
and then stacking those photos properly
and having the light perfect and all
these things that have to happen for you
to get that photo you know it's it's
pretty exciting and I get excited
because I mean I've seen the process and
I understand it a little bit more and
once you start understanding it's like
wow it's really especially if you have a
photographer that's like trying to learn
how to do it and you're like well it
doesn't look like that and it's because
of this this this and this totally and
even the cultivation like if you use
stuff where you have burnt tips on your
leaves if you're using stuff salts that
burn burn your tips your leaves a little
bit it's not going to look as good you
know the photo is not going to look
nearly as good well even if the flowers
pushed hard it's you can tell you know
especially people that can tell when you
can tell you can tell yeah swollen where
they're like over swollen you know it's
like you know it's like someone doing
steroids or someone like being like you
know hey organic you know fed Grass
Grass you know Fred beef dude and it has
a glow to it right like they both have a
glow to it in different ways you yeah
for sure without a doubt that you know
and that's I think that's the cool thing
is you know whatever floats your boat
with this one and and this plant has
countless expressions and and there's
something for everybody and humans have
countless expressions and so like I
think that combination is is is a is a
beautiful thing you know whatever you
want to do just grow more weed and you
know plant more seeds and like do more
you know that's if you love it double
down on it it's one of those things and
you know I think not doing it for money
doing it because you love it and you're
devoted to it and it's one of those
things that you feel aligned with well
that was back in the day I would never
consult anyone or give them information
if they're doing it for money yeah they
had to love the plant they had to love
the you know because you know the money
can be a side product yeah you know if
you're devoted and you're giving it your
all for sure what whatever field you're
in doesn't have to be weed but money is
g to come yeah but that that devotion
and that heart and that care that's rare
totally and that's what I love about
capulator the Mac 1 say what you want
about Mac one as a genetic or you like
the smoke don't like the smoke but the
way he gave out the cuts that that's
pretty special and you know it it's not
seen across the board typically these
days where or or if it is people don't
talk about it Mac one was something that
was never supposed to be sold it was
supposed to be given and shared with
good people and you know I I love that
about the plant and I feel like that's
just one of those good examples that we
can all learn from for sure I mean that
kind of intention and that kind of like
um you know stewardship right really
that means something you know and that's
something special and those kind of um
Vibes should be you know something that
we're like you know seeing and emulating
in whatever way we can you know we had a
we got to give our heart um however
we're doing it and you know that's a
good that's a good that's a good example
of that for sure y that was a special
plan at that time and what it was you
know the look The turp the structure
what it was doing and what it did for
it's an anomaly too within that cross
like for for you to get those TPS and
then some of the other crosses that I've
seen within the progyny some of the
other
plants uh yeah we had a the max 69 which
was very hazy very Colombian
uh and then you got this Mac one that's
very soft and it looks amazing too like
I've seen it in some amazing grows
outdoors in Greenhouse where it's like
you look across from 50 feet away and
you're like what is that it has that one
glowing over there that pink glow it
like has this pink glow and it's super
Frosty and it's like they're not tall
plants they're like these amazing
delicate you know extremely special yeah
it reminds me of a plant that was going
around Eugene we called it the dawn um
it was or you know they called it the
Kid Next Door or neighbor kid whatever
but it was uh you know train wreck by
purple afy and it was similar you know
like see it across the room pink blah
you know like whatever and it's like you
know those ones are cool really would
that kind of give that glow no matter
how big the field is or how big the room
is you see those you know out there and
two 2018 Leo ferma fish Auto I got some
of his seeds from th Caesar my one of my
buddies and he gave me these seeds and
they were super expensive and I was like
this is crazy $2,500 on the aftermarket
is what they were going for you know for
a 10 pack and I was like [ __ ] it I'm
going to pop them right I want to see I
don't care about this aftermarket thing
I want to see how good these seeds are
because I didn't really know Leo as a
friend at the time we're friends now and
and maybe it was earlier than that but
when I popped them we had popped 800
seeds or something like that and we were
popping them my buddy's backyard and
there was this little patch that you
could see from 30 feet away and
everybody would be like what are those
and it it wasn't just the way they
looked because you know there's a lot of
stuff Oreos and some of the stuff that
looks really good it has a really
amazing look that would attract you to
it this stuff it was like the look the
smell the structure everything about
every one of the plants was amazing like
you could see it and all these different
Expressions because there's so many
different seeds out there but it was
like this little patch and that's a
super special one Leo's got some uh some
of those still around he's supposed to
drop some off I'm waiting for the sick
but yeah good and that changed my mind
about about like the value of seeds and
I know he was selling his 200 bucks a
pack even back then and the value of
seeds and and it's all subjective to the
individual you know he sold them for 200
but it's like these SB Dunks that go for
$5,000 these pairs of Nikes you know
it's like Nike doesn't sell for that
much but the secondary Market it is what
it is and the sell value of a seed is so
subjective to the individual totally
what they can do with it I mean I've
always have like high respect for ficado
and Leo and like packaging what he did
branding Wise It's like it's beautiful
you know you can't if you if you argue
with it you're just a hater you know
shit's pimp you know yeah and he's given
me his drops over the last couple years
when he has new drops he's given me
packs and like I think his Z had the
actual gold plant tags in him and I'm
like dude that is just he's always an
outside the box thinker he wants it to
be elegant and I I love the the wax
stamps on the stuff and just the way he
takes it to a different level and makes
it his own for sure it's I mean it's
it's beautiful and he was the first like
that period And there's been a lot of
knockoffs since then but like you know
like even I waxed my you know quirks for
a while because you know I was like oh
that's sick what he's doing I don't know
wax the [ __ ] cork you know C and it
has this craft feel to it I love that
it's really I mean it's Louis Vuitton
and craft combo kind of it's like really
what it reminds me of is that like
crossover of yeah you know fine fine and
you know it's like it's like when you
take the finest foods and you you know
have a dinner in Humble or something for
sure it' be one thing if his genetics
didn't back it but his genetics are good
like he is a great breeder he's a great
person first of all but he's a great
breeder and his seeds that he put in
those expensive packages where he did
spend some money and there was a lot of
thought that went into it but they're
all good genetics i' I've always been
super happy with everything that I
popped of his well I mean that 78 ay is
in a lot of the work you know I put the
78 ay to the saour OG made the tens in
and like you know I mean I I've done a
lot of work with that and it I'm not
kidding like every single feno that
popped out of that 78 ay by the sour OG
was epic you know and I I kept the the
two and the four the T cush two and four
but it's only because there just wasn't
that many of them and that's what was
left and they were winners you know the
three was a winner too but these two
were better so I was just like ah you
know just and like ended up doing quite
a bit of work with it just because for
that fact it was it was good you know
nice yeah so if you had one piece of
advice for your younger
self what would that one piece ofice be
go bigger no go bigger go harder yeah
I'm just kidding I think sometimes going
bigger um you know not going big keeps
you out of trouble yeah um to really
just focus more on helping instead of
focusing on myself yeah and really you
know I I went with that pretty hard but
if I would have did it more more
pure-minded
more um wholesomely you know I did it
the best I could but I could have did it
better you know would have would have
created more more happiness I think even
I'm quite a happy guy now but you know I
go through my phases but I think if I
did things more with an altruistic
intention from the beginning yeah it
would have just created better results
in the end you know and and the results
are good but you know you know how we
are when our when we're in our early 20s
you know and late teens early 20s we do
a lot of arrogant stupid [ __ ] you know
yeah we think the world's a lot
different than it really is totally and
I think we gain experience and knowledge
over time and you know it's
like for me the beauty of this podcast I
saw Joe Rogan doing his podcast and I
felt like watching him over the years he
got smarter right and I'm like dude this
guy's he's more int he talks more
intelligently for one thing but he gets
all these perspectives from all these
different
people high level people and I feel like
I get high level cannabis people and
people that have experience in I get a
piece of each one of those people when I
do this podcast so having you on today
has been a great great great podcast a
great time and I feel like it's one of
those ones where I've got somebody in
the industry who's experienced a lot who
knows a lot about cannabis who loves the
plant who's a true Steward of the plant
so if people are looking to find out
more about you where can they go um
green.org GB genetics.com um those are
my two you know web- based realities um
Instagram's greenb and the real green B
obviously LinkedIn John Bay's green B
whatever and you know Twitter X whatever
green B it's like kind of those are the
those are the those are the those are
the where you're going to find me but
you know I I suggest the the website
really you know because you selling
seeds on your website selling seeds on
um GB genetics.com and we're doing some
uh Consulting for like hom Growers and
stuff uh they could reach me through
through green.org just kind of trying to
help people keep it simple and just give
this information because you know at a
scaled level people aren't really
interested in Organics you know they
want they've got to goow Convention
because of GMP and these different
aspects but on a boutique level you know
Organics is kind of our Forte so I
really want to offer that Simplicity and
that information to as many people as I
can because you know [ __ ] man we need
more people growing weed in their closet
and their garage and their bedroom and
their every room in their house and live
in their living room you know whatever
it takes like the old days you know
that's sleeping next to their plants you
know I used to do that now I have
allergies I don't know you know dude I
used to cure and I remember you know
like i' I'd cure and dry everything in
my bedroom yep and just you know that
and as as you know in those first few
days the man the turps are powerful you
know oh yeah you're just like whoa am I
not even sleep yeah my my buddy Joe I'm
sure if I went to his house during
trimming he still has black uh clone
trays where he trims in and he falls
asleep next to him even still I mean I
we used to do that all the time but he's
still living and he's up in Oregon yeah
sick it's popular up there for sure it's
like we're we're committed committed to
this PL and yeah I mean the prices these
days you have have to be I mean you know
so it's it's not all about money anymore
and I think we're becoming Farmers now
and I think that Rockstar lifestyle I
mean there's still some people whatever
but like it's not about that Rockstar
life you know it's it's it's about
something more for sure I mean we live
that one too but uh yeah now it's a lot
different and you know if you're still
getting good good money for your herb
that's good you know and um you deserve
it if you are because it's not an easy
feat these days but uh you know really
it's for the heart of it I think these
days and Shar the information and really
actually the stewardship of being able
to teach people how to do it their own
you know people give them the genetics
and the tools to be able to do it good
on their own and and the variety and the
potentials to be able for them to have a
multitude of different aspects yeah of
this plant you know once people
understand you know how many you know
different ranges there is it's it's it's
Limitless so don't get stuck in one
little lane you know really like get
outside the box and start to discover
these things cuz you know as you know
and much out there [ __ ] man change
everyone's lives here you know well if
you're in Oregon you might want to look
to some other place like Washington and
if you're in California you might want
to look to Oregon for some good genetics
like we did back in the day I feel like
it's a straight great great straight
direction to go you know going right
from the bay up
to seriously and you know and humble has
some amazing stuff Mendo has some
amazing stuff you know Trinity all these
places Grass Valley you know
that's where everyone from the bay went
right they went all the grass Valle
Grass Valley Mendo but really there's
even places further outside but now it's
like okay we can go to Colorado we can
get good stuff we can go to Arizona and
there's a lot of people that are
passionate about it for sure and holding
on to the good stuff is really um you
know a lot of people have done that so
it's out there yeah and if you're
like-minded there's other like-minded
people out there you know there that
love cannabis so yeah man thank you so
much for coming on the show today man
thank you so much it been a real honor
and really a pleasure and you know it's
just awesome to sit with like-minded
people and especially you know Legends
like you it's just really been an honor
so thank you you know for sure thank you
very much yeah it's it's great having
well I I've been having a lot of people
my age on the show and so it's great
like we have similar sto similar War
stor similar experiences and we think
about life in the same way I feel like
you know I'm over the hill now and I I
love these things yeah know it's sick
it's uh it's been a lot of years and
really uh such a blessing this plant and
the people the community and you know I
just every day just so thankful so thank
you for sure thank
you thank you guys for watching please
like And subscribe down below