[Music]
how's it going everybody I'm James loud
and welcome to another episode of the
James loud podcast today our special
guest is Dave from Gast Town how you
doing Dave super good just here in
California just taking it all in really
happy to be here yeah so Gast town is up
in Canada you guys are based out in
Canada we met in
Barcelona at spannabis two years ago and
then we also we shared a booth with uh
Greenhouse seed company and then also
did it again uh this recent spannabis
and it was a amazing adventure you know
you smoke good weed I smoke good weed we
both like good weed so yeah so thanks
for coming on the show my absolute
pleasure you're forgetting one other
time that we met is at our mutual
friend's place we did I don't know if or
not but we did we met in Amsterdam at
the apartments yes absolutely you were
staying there you stay there pretty
religiously no actually at another
friend's house uh our our wizard friend
who we have shared some experiences my
God yeah we absolutely it's well you
were staying at the apartments though
right I st theart and I was staying at
the apartments and we went to dinner
with s that's right and that was okay
usually I remember I think we even cross
past like at his place we did and then
that's when it was I know something
about that the buo adventures that's
right that's right so so when you've had
a mutual experience like that that is
very you know life-changing and
monumental that's a big connection for
me yeah someone's pretty special he is a
a one in a trillion you know it's like
not one in a million not one in a
billion one in a trillion there's nobody
I've ever met quite like him and I never
will meet another person quite like s
he's extremely special and I have a lot
of love for S and uh you know spiritual
guidance and whatever I think he's just
a all
round good person I think he uh loves
his family and friends and uh I just got
a lot of love for Som he's always he's
always done me right um yeah and just a
nice guy so yeah I just feel like his
intentions are just always so pure and
genuine yeah and just the way he talks
to people there's no it's just pure and
genuine and what more could you want out
of any relation he's freaking character
he he's actually he's a he's a character
you know and uh I've tripped on things
and actually seen some
in ADV even though he wasn't there I've
seen him and had experiences with him
outside of this existence which is wild
because I can't say that with a lot of
about a lot of people there's a handful
of them and uh yeah spiritual guide or
whatever s's always there looking over
us so yeah the spiritual experience that
I did have with him was extremely
life-changing and helped me um just be
extra sure of my path and and and part
of the reason I'm sitting here right now
to be honest yeah so yeah so you're a
lover of Amsterdam uh Barcelona you're a
world traveler you've been to Thailand
I've seen you in Thailand on Instagram
at least I've never been to Thailand I
plan on going this year no way yeah I'm
super excited I'm going to check out
some genetics and stuff like that that
are growing over there I think this fall
dope so our mutual friend Arion was a
big motivational factor for me when I
went there it was also part of the
reason I was in Amsterdam yeah um my
father passed away he had a license in
Denmark and I was kind of there trying
to put together the pieces after he
suddenly passed away at his facility got
crushed and um that was part of also the
spiritual guidance through CA I kind of
got into a dead end where I didn't know
where to go with the whole situation
yeah and uh Arian gave me the suggestion
to go to Thailand and to go check it out
and that there's lots of opportunity
there and this and that and he kind of
gave me you know a push to go yeah and
so I went like a month later and I had
an amazing time I got to check out their
facility and got to get super motivated
by what him industri doing watching
their team just execute on just a high
level the partners who they partnered
with just the whole thing is just like a
dream come true and just see the spark
in Arian and I've known him for I want
to say six to eight years yeah and I've
never in my whole time knowing him seen
any sort of spark in him like I've seen
with this whole Thailand thing he really
it's a really cool passion project and
it's got him so motivated you can see
him when he does his presentations and
everything and it's everything you can
see him at spanis I I love it because uh
when I first met him he was excited and
he did some fun stuff you know but then
Franco passed and with the passing of
Franco I think there was a lot of
sadness not just with Arian but within
the industry uh but especially Arian
losing his best friend and somebody who
was his like the yin and yang balance to
him and
finding where you belong in the world
after something like that happens you
know takes some time and like I mean
it's pretty amazing
with Thailand you know from going to the
Congo and all the stuff they've done in
their career but now Reinventing
themselves in Thailand on another level
I mean it's pretty it's pretty amazing
watching from from this you know the the
cheap seats watching them on Instagram
and seeing the stuff they're doing the
new Strain Hunters and I mean they're
they're so passionate about cannabis
dust is just he's great he's super
passionate as well they love the plant
and I feel like they're just super
passionate about what they're doing yeah
the and just the level that they do
things and they showed that kind of in
the Congo with the the the how many you
know like the amount count the feno
Hunts they did and in this industry of
genetics as we both know your
credibility comes from Big feno hunts
you're not going to get any credibility
doing a three seed feno hun and finding
a winner no or bag seat or whatever you
know you got a 100 you know 20 plus is
kind of like 30 plus is kind of like the
minimum and and he's out here doing
10,000 3,000 minimum per per strain so I
mean I think that's little extreme
person I think it's great and you're
really finding outliers and stuff like
that in there I mean I prefer smaller
funo hunts three is not enough three
three doesn't tell you anything about
your genetics right 10 it really might
tell you if it's worth looking through
more right you know but me I mean I
think like that 20 to 50 range is really
good uh you know some some genetics it's
worth going through 100 and some you
know you're going to find kind of what
you're looking for in a smaller amount
but uh you know when you have the space
and you have the money that is the way
to do it is doing larger hunts and you
can do several genetics when you're
doing them that size and you know I
think there's there's gold in those uh
those hunts the team is extra important
too the team that they have established
down there is is is really Next Level
and to be able to keep all those still
alive while they grow through their
whole life cycle is another huge
undertaking and and I think if not the
biggest undertaking in the whole process
if you're going to do that big of a fena
hunt right so it's my hat to them and
their whole team for even attempting the
process and then now executing on such a
high level it's really really cool to
see and just even witness the whole
situation really cool been to watch the
last couple years totally well when when
you see your friend's success it's
always amazing you know at the the level
they can do it on is just it's pretty
mind-blowing um and when it's your
friends being successful it's even
better you know I love watching my
friends succeed and my friends kick ass
and you know especially taking stuff to
a new level and it requires commitment
and dedication and you know we talk
about being business owners getting
kicked to the nuts every day and waking
up and smiling about it I mean it's
really you know I think we were meant to
do something on this plane of existence
on on this planet and I feel like
working with cannabis is where I belong
where you belong where Aran and
Greenhouse belong and and dust and dust
and and Mr X we got Oscar Crush dud his
photography and all the guys over there
I mean they have a I've been holding
back saying this whole time the number
one word is team and what they have
created what Arian has created is a team
and he really knows how to pump
everybody up and make them feel special
yeah and that's another huge thing I
learned from s on the whole experience
with the buo is like all you have on
this world is the opportunity to make
people feel special and and how you make
people feel is all that matters you know
and aran's good at making people feel
special and his team feels special
working for him so that's why he gets
with gets out of them it's really cool
to just watch and be a part of it it
just feels super special even being
there the time I have it's been really
cool totally yeah it's funny because so
being in this industry you're able to
observe different leadership styles and
and and different companies and
different people and you know it's it's
funny the people that I've I've been
exposed to and that have mentored me
like Arian and a handful of other people
that I feel like have told me the truth
even when I didn't want to hear it you
know and then there's the the ego and
losing the ego is so important and I
feel like that also happens when you get
a little bit older the second you start
getting in your like late 30s early 40s
you really start losing your ego and
quitting quit you quit caring what other
people think as much and also you become
a good Storyteller along the way because
to become a good Storyteller some people
are great from the G but after you've
been through enough experiences then you
can really start telling your story and
uh I think that's an important part of
the Cannabis history of the oral history
of cannabis like the show and stuff that
we're doing I feel like the Cannabis
history is just so important to the
world that we live in and to the Next
Generation and the generation after that
and so on and so forth down the line
because we've got all these
revolutionaries and people changing the
game and it's great being able to tell
stories about them that's documented
couldn't agree more yeah um and Arian
and S are couple great examples of that
totally their ation what they've lived
through from The High Times cups to the
current cups now um I just messaged AR
the other day he like yo do you realize
that you guys want a Billy's award he's
like what's a Billy's award and I'm like
dude this big thing like you know
important third place second place
sativa for super silver hay Super Lemon
Haze Super Lemon Haze yeah for Super
Lemon Haze second place still winning
award how many cups do Super Lemon Haze
won over the years you know what I mean
whether it's a cross or the ex many I
bet one of the top I BET's one of the
top all time winning trins Super Lemon
Haze Super Silver Haze yeah for sure
absolutely I mean he has a gazan them
all now but like you know what I'm
saying no but back in the day it was the
one there wasn't many Haze hay uh cups
now either so no you don't see Hayes
winning cups but I do see Hayes making a
comeback for sure and everything will
Super Silver making a comeback too I
mean for sure yeah Super Lemon Haze and
all these different hazes I mean piff is
really popular now here uh are becoming
more popular have you much uh experience
with like Congo or Malawi gold sure I've
smoked it's so funny cuz like the Durban
the Congo and the Malawi are all very uh
sacred to me I smoked some red Congo
from gold leaf on one of the future
cannabis projects episodes with
Marlin uh and I'm never doing that again
we got too high on the air there's a
handful of times all squirly and like
well it was so the red Congo and the
Malo and the Durban all have different
effects right like sure you might say
they taste similar but to me they don't
but but they're all they're all similar
because they're kind of you know they're
they're land racy I guess Airy but like
the flavor on them is different and the
effect is extremely different I couldn't
agree more dude that red Congo makes me
giggle and laugh and like I just have
amazing time on it but like Marlin and I
we do these things where we get too
[ __ ] up whether it's weed or mushrooms
or whatever and then we just laugh and
every time I looked at him he he would
laugh and every time he he looked back
at me I would laugh and then I try not
to laugh and then I can't hold it
anymore and I'm [ __ ] laughing
bursting out yeah where the Durban just
kicks your ass I feel like the Durban is
super strong and uh more
introspective you say it's more like of
a OG buzz like a gas Buzz or is it still
in that sativa realm as the other two um
I I would say there's more sedative
characteristics of it it is super strong
der for me and same thing maloi is
really strong too and but maloi is like
line hallucinogenic interesting U and
Durban can be too in extremes like if
you make bang with it where you know
like the the milk where you infuse it
into the milk like fat or whatever and
then inest it like MCT oil type thing
you can do MCT oil but bang is actually
like uh milk that's been infused with it
and you drink it okay and yeah it's like
a
Indian tradition and it's super strong
and potent and it hits you pretty quick
but like those psychedelic ones they
really you really feel the effects of
them I had a and I thought when I was
first making my brand like 2016 yeah um
Congo is a popular thing going on around
and we finally had that was also when
bhos first came around we actually had
some really nice extract of Congo and
because it was such a low yielder and
such a long flowering plant there wasn't
much of the extract around it was like
really rare and so I had some and I
remember excited I was and what I did is
I started my day with it for a few days
in a row but I couldn't get anything
done in the morning I was so
scatterbrained I could like my regular
routine I could not get anything done
and I had to sit there and realize what
the difference was that I was doing and
it was this extract and I just couldn't
do a dab of Congo in the morning I was
going to do it as my morning coffee with
sativa sure but it ended up ruining my
whole morning where I couldn't even do
anything I had to wait till the buzz
wore off to even like I could have like
drawn or maybe done a sport or done
something but as soon as I had to apply
myself I could not I could not apply
myself I couldn't focus on anything I
don't think I mean Durban same thing I
don't think I can apply myself it's it's
super strong I wouldn't say that Durban
is like OG necessarily but it doesn't
have a ceiling so the more you smoke the
higher you get there is no ceiling to
how high you can get a lot of these
modern genetics that people are creating
they have ceilings you know and it's
like you can smoke them and you only get
so high and then you smoke them
throughout the day you never get higher
than right here whereas like Durban and
Malo and Congo and Colombian you smoke
some real [ __ ] Colombian dud like the
real Colombian genetics that stuff does
not have a ceiling you just keep getting
higher and higher the more you smoke and
it's like there's no limit to how high
you can get from that stuff oh yeah so
do we line one up now uh we can
definitely do that this is branded you
guys or Ridgeline Farms now this is ridg
line Farms they're gonna be on the
podcast in two episodes from now okay
and so they're doing big things up in
Humble dope and this is the Lance and
it's well I'll let you taste it yourself
want my honest op what's that want my
honest opinion I want your honest
opinion I think it's great I think it's
great for a commercial
pre-roll um I believe it's Greenhouse
grown uh it's got a lot of
flavor got a
unique well it's very
runy it's okay yeah I get a little like
in the almost like uh sour taste in my
mhm my palette yeah I got don't know if
it's that's like the the NES or what
but oh it's living soil
organic it's okay I don't I don't love
the turps but the buzz I'm liking I'm
liking what I'm liking the buzz that I'm
getting from it getting some actual like
hey Buzz I don't I wouldn't like I'm not
like enjoying the turps personally it's
not my so you what like so let's talk
about TS so you're super picky but you
smoke a lot of xtract too so you're all
about turbs I'm definitely a flower guy
like I'm I'm been flower guy since I was
16 we smoked a bunch of joints in I'm
definitely a flower guy um and I've
evolved into the extract uh scene now I
there was a period in the early 2000s
before hash or before bubble hash was
like really super popular yeah where we
were washing in Vancouver and making ice
hash and but we didn't know what the
hell were doing right
um there wasn't a lot of knowledge on it
and I think everybody was kind of
learning as they go and I think that's a
lot what hash church was was people
sharing their experiences learning and
then that was able to elevate it hash
Church yeah is huge Community yeah um
one of the most important communities
for the hash movement tip my hat to him
for that big time Mark killing it to
this day still killing it yeah yeah for
sure for sure but yeah the profiles that
I do like are like I love gelados I love
runs um but for me like I really like
that like clean taste so that not
getting affected by like that almost
like nutrient do you want it floral do
you want it gassy do you want a little
bit floral a little bit gassy I don't
mind I don't so like personally like my
favorite profiles I like to smoke
different stuff throughout the day like
I like to start in the morning with a
nice Z and then I'll move into like
something that's a little bit more
fruity um how do you feel about the
effects of Z you like I feel like it's a
good it's not it's up but not too upy
you know it doesn't get me you still get
high from it yeah exactly but it's not
like it's I feel like it's one of those
ones with the ceiling like you can still
get high but it doesn't take you over
the top it's it's a clean high you can
keep smoking it too and it's not like I
don't know it's still tasty I like still
all the way down to the roach exactly
exactly um and and yeah you can get sick
as you get sick of anything for sure and
that's my whole thing like I like
smoking a different joint every joint I
smoke throughout the day I feel like I
never really got sick of Sour Diesel we
had a lot of Sour Diesel that's the only
thing I would say though cat piss and
the sour diesel are the two things that
we go back that I don't think I ever get
sick of those I feel like a lot of that
would have to do whoever grew that for
you and like I bet you if you got that
same gr who always grew that fire batch
as some other strains too I bet you'd
maybe have same connection to that too
cuz I feel like most strains unless you
really have like a negative adverse
effect to it are awesome if grown
correctly um and that's just my
experience and and so when that's why I
also like having a lot of different
varieties because I feel like they all
send you in a different direction and I
kind of apply for a different function
throughout the day right whether it's
going up for lunch whether it's playing
a sport whether it's watching a movie
playing a video game I like smoking
different stuff for everything or the
same few things for the same few things
I'm the same way and I'm always trying
new stuff because I like I like the new
experience of being able to find
something that I've never seen before or
I'm always waiting for that lottery
ticket you know what I mean where you're
like oh what the [ __ ] is that that new
have you tried the new toad Venom it's
pretty nice I've not tried weed toad
Venom yeah it's called yeah exactly go
yeah no that maybe that's why I like it
so much I don't know but no it's a new
one out I forget the group but it's like
the hot new thing in New York when I was
there everybody's on it and the hash
from it's super fire too it's a z Blend
or a z cross I'm pretty sure yeah not
diet Skittles by the way no no diet Z
right it's not diet Z well it probably
is Diet on the Z end of it because it's
obviously diluted sure but like no it's
not like whatever yeah I'm okay with
stuff where it's diluted but it's
complex this I just don't like a lighter
Skittles it's not as turpy which is a
lot of the stuff though a lot of the
Skittles crosses the Skittles s1's a lot
of those
end up being not as turpy as Skittles
and I feel like why would you have
something why would you want to grow
something that's not as good as the
maybe has a little better structure or
whatever but Sour Diesel is like this
too I find Sour Diesel crosses I find
the original sour the real Sour
absolutely the real Sour they're never
on that level as the original sour no
there's only a handful of them I think
you know my partner and I back in the
day um did some Sour back crosses and
stuff like that and we were doing I
think we were doing really good work but
JJ from top dog is doing it aish a has
SAU crosses Karma's got some SAU crosses
like just out the gate those three guys
are all doing some good sour work some
of the best in the game yeah yeah for
sure but a lot of sour like sour Sour's
tough to work with as a cross sour
structure the recessive traits coming
through in whatever you're trying to get
it's like what are you shooting for
right and I think that's maybe a lot of
what's happening is maybe they're not
searching for the real original sour
traits or I don't know but I haven't
found many you probably got to go
through a lot more too I would say that
that was the thing with us back in the
day was being able to go through a lot
and you know it's like then selecting
and finding ones that are really sour
where it does Justice to the sour I
think that like there's fire crosses for
sure but I'm just saying it's not like
the sour you know like that sour was so
special and I think a lot of the Z
crosses are doing the same thing you
know when you when you see the Z name on
the jar you see the sour name on the jar
you have a certain expectation attached
to it and then that's probably what's
not being bad for the longest time OG
was like that you have like some OG
cross that was just not quite great and
there was no OG seeds for the longest
time you couldn't get real OG you get
like OG Widow OG critical from the guys
in Europe or whatever and it was like
nothing like the OG that we liked and
then there's the variant of like region
to region of the OG like you know what I
mean there's definitely different
there's a lemon one that I find out
there there more gassy ones there's
definitely a few yeah there's definitely
more piny and there's more citrusy ones
and more earthy ones and they have ones
that lean directions all three of those
directions and I like all three of those
I do like Pine though for sure I do like
the the original one hey the original
one the original it was Piney and the
sfv had like Pine and it was lemon and
Pine in Earth Canada so a lot of what I
going on a second information when I ask
questions to people who I really look up
to and respect and that's kind of what
I've got from most of the people is that
the original OG was a piny gassy so good
um fire pine cones chunky pine cones
dude it would grow pine cones like not
that great in node spacing but like
amazing buds that [ __ ] you smoke
those down to the roach it was gassy all
the way down Brian from vital and jaw
Mikey W they got some good ones then
there's some other guys can't think of
the brand right now but they're in h
Selenas living soil we're in we're in us
or in the world is the best OG from and
still so there's it's a multi answer a
question but like the best so if we go
down into La yeah I feel like if you
wanted the best OG like La was where you
go to get OG then if you wanted to go
get cookies like this is like 10 years
ago but if you wanted cookies you came
up to the Bay cookies sherbet gelato
right all that stuff got pumped out of
the bay um before that it was blue dream
when blue dream was [ __ ] cool that
was coming out of the Bay right that was
the original hype stram New York so we
talk about New York and New York had the
sour but came from California to New
York interesting right but then there's
an interesting thing that happened in
the late 90s early 2000s we got these
beaster
strains we got the Canadian be I know
anything about those yeah so that that
was like before your time right no that
was my that was your day yeah so we got
the beers I had to bring it up on the
show yeah we got the beers and so they
would come down to the bay and they were
like a football that was a pound was
this big and a pound should be this big
okay so you maybe got the beers then
yeah all the stuff pretty dense a step
further never mind I didn't see them at
that step i' seen them before then yeah
so I mean this was like 97 to
200 you know 4 2005 probably maybe a
little before that but okay there was
this period where the beers the BC Bud
took over uh a lot of this stuff and it
was it was interesting as far as like
that there were bigger numbers of stuff
so you could get a hundred of this or
whatever uh but
a lot of stuff they ran 03 to it so it
didn't smell and so there was like a hay
smell to it some of the stuff looked
really good but it was also compressed
right so there's the orange crush I
remember we had really good orange crush
and some other a bunch of other genetics
do you remember the names of them
so let's see cuz I remember the names I
can after I jog so Jamaican was like the
main one it was the Jamaican big bud it
was just these big huge donkey like lime
green and their bud like they were 12 in
buds though yeah I remember seeing bus
they didn't smoke worth of [ __ ] like
they were just they were horrible smoke
they looked amazing bag of Peel through
the roof and they smell kind of like hey
like they didn't really have much smell
and a lot of the buyers were approving
the packs without actually opening the
bags so you'd bring like a 20 pack and
they'd be in sleeves yeah back sleeves
and they would just look and they'd see
the big long donks in the lime green as
long as they were like the right trim
and they were like great look they just
would approve them well a lot of times
you'd have to go up to Seattle or
wherever they were going to get them and
you'd have to go into a garage and of
somebody's house typically and you pull
in and there's a bunch of packs and
you're actually going through some of
them opening them up to find the right
ones then you got to go on look to find
the rest if you're going for 200 you
don't have time to open every single one
of them so what You' do is you would
basically look for specific ones you'd
open it you'd remember what it looks
like and you try it hopefully you picked
all the ones that look like that if
you're good you hit it 100% if you were
bad you hit it a lot less but yeah you
were going for the 100% because there
could be mixed ones in there that just
had no smell to them some of them didn't
even look good right you know but like
because it was all mixed
together but yeah wild interesting
talking someone on either end of it um I
definitely was only a part of like like
the rounding it up so I don't know what
they did beyond that but I definitely
was uh Juicy Fruit came down from Canada
so this the same strain so Jamaican
juicy fruit is the same thing just
renamed okay so that's the same strain
the same from what I from what I was
taught as a as a young lad um and then
there was Louie which is Lui Legends of
ultimate indicia it was Sugar Shack they
tasted like smell like carrots kind of a
little bit red hair some other strains
were just like the hash plant back in
the day was a little bit higher end and
the lizard was another pheno of that the
jir um God Bud was another really
popular godd I remember Shish is another
one for sure and then there's uh
Hawaiian the Hawaiian big buds M and a
couple others blueberry and a couple
others were around too blueberry yeah
it's funny because there's a few
different blueberries on the mar
grapefruit yeah you like s grapefruit
you ever tried s's grapefruit New York
City Diesel no that one's pretty special
tooa I don't know it [ __ ] it it yields
like crazy it's a huge plant and it's
super grapefruit like it is grapefruit
chps it is the most grapefruit out of
anything I've tried over the years maybe
that cuz like a lot of the grapefruit
pack we were getting were from the
Vietnamese people and there's a really
good chance that they just got seeds or
whatever that it was so gra fruit like
they had this and it was like orange
hair like super orange hairs little golf
balls up to like the size of an orange
well yeah the buds would stack really
really good you get big I mean even
indoor you got chunky big colas okay so
see a green these guys used to just yeah
totally small plants and like flip them
yeah like they used to get a room and
like the the Gorilla growing they would
do in Canada was like you have your room
whatever the dimensions were that would
be the your bed and they would just make
one big bed the whole room yeah and they
would just put the seeds or Cuts all in
the room and they would just grow and
they were just wrecking houses and
that's why growing gave such a bad name
in BC because these guys were literally
like ruining houses totally yeah when it
was all grown in houses back in the day
just like it was here in California I
mean I guess there was maybe a handful
of people that figured out how to get
scale but right most people and stuff
yeah bunkers warehouses early days uh
but yeah grown in houses so how did you
start getting or when did you get into
cultivation I was uh
18 well for a while I was a kid like not
even 16 I was doing seeds in my backyard
lived in the highlands which was kind of
a rural area and I never successfully
flowered anything out they always died
before I could but I was like a kid and
I was already playing around and then
when I was 18 19 I started working at
the shipyard yeah and my dad was kind of
like a legendary biker in the area so
all the guys at theard knew who I was
nice so this one guy that I guess looked
up to my dad's stuff was like took me in
he's like yo come I'll show you how to
grow up my place blah blah blah blah and
I got him some genetics and that was
actually the first place I washed at and
I was like yo I want to make hash out of
your Smalls and your and your trim and
he's like okay and that was the first
hash I ever made was his and I was
working at the shipyard and I would just
go by there and water before people
started selling trim or after way before
this is
19989 so I remember those years too
because people did not sell trim like
you you could get it for free a lot of
times it be fan leaves mixed you get
free till 2005 you get free yeah I mean
and a lot of it like my friends trimmed
wet not all of them but for the most
part we trimmed wet right and then I was
like I need to buy a chest freezer and
that's when we used to make bubble hat
and I get the free it'd be mixed in with
the fan leaves but it was still really
good and it was fresh frozen you know so
we froze it we whipped it in a freaking
paint mixer I didn't so I did that when
I decided I was going commercial with it
but like when we started out it was a 5
gallon bucket okay pre-bubble bag you
stir with a wooden spoon in ice who
you're kind of and and then you pour
yeah you use a red Solo cup and this is
my buddy Luke taught me this way back in
the day you use the Red Solo Cup to
scoop the ice out right okay and then
any plant material ice you scoop it out
and then till you keep scooping it down
and then you pour the very end so the
hash gets poured over to silk screen we
used to dry it on the silk screen this
is 90 damn 798 maybe this is pre-bubble
bags they're before yeah we got Bubble
Bags shortly after that you get the idea
from Europe like from no he got it from
some hippies up in in uh Sonoma I
believe cool uh he had a spot in
ocidental or whatever and but they uh
yeah and so pretty [ __ ] amazing
though we were smoking badass hash it
was super amazing bubble hash that
really bubbled because you weren't
agitating it hard right and you you
being super gentle and you're doing the
paddle Tech where is we were like
grabbing paint mixer or drywall mud
mixers and we went straight to the
industrial cuz I already knew I had
multiple people with huge garbage bags
full of the product and like it was
going bad in the garbage bags and so we
had to do it right away I didn't even we
didn't even think about freezing it at
first we just left it in the garage in
the garbage bags it wasn't until later
we're like why don't we freeze this
stuff like yeah oh yeah and it wasn't
until later and it works okay with dry
PL material but the Frozen is where it's
at for sure especially TPS uh I got so
we were doing that we were getting free
and I had a big Oak Tree in my backyard
mhm and so we had lines that went over
the oak tree so I could do three bubble
bags at a time with pulley on them right
right and so we did the pulley system
where you could tie it down so it would
pull it up and it would drain where you
didn't have to break your back because
we were doing the big 20 gallons there's
a tech you can do where you don't have
to break your back but but this was we
didn't know anything to figure out so we
bought it's so funny cuz we were so far
ahead of our time in some ways we had
bought a washing machine thinking dude
wouldn't it be great to be able to use a
washing machine now it's just is like
kind of the it became the standard and
this was 20 years before it became the
standard yeah you're you're ahead of
your time with the paddle and you're
ahead of your time with the washing
machine yeah my buddy who yeah we tried
we actually tried using a washing
machine we brought it over we [ __ ]
didn't figure out how to make it work
had we done that maybe the mash bag
wasn't on the idea exactly we would have
been revolutionaries had we done that
properly and you never know hey man you
were you were like this close bunch of
Stoners yeah and then uh but it's all
about the passion right like why are you
doing that cuz you and you made some
fire
you forever to do it yeah all that stuff
is super fun and exciting and you feel
like you're uh creating something new or
inventing stuff there's there's some
excitement that I get from exp yeah
exactly like your Uncharted territories
Christopher Columbus exactly right I
mean he's not the best example but no
but you're like an inventor like you
know what I mean exactly you're Albert
Einstein Einstein's a great example
Thomas Edison Albert Einstein you know
like weed light bulbs totally but uh
yeah and then BHL we started doing be B
early 2000s before they had dab rcks
right and so we were blasting B was the
first B blast you ever did and I'll tell
you mine so we had a table and we had
slots in the table I the first was just
uh tubes PVC tubes with with ones and
then my buddy came over the same guy who
actually taught me how to make bubble
has came over and was like dude we're
gonna we're gonna do this it's open
blasting right and we did in uh four
tubes in each after bubble right yeah
this is so after this is yours after
bubble but you know there I guess people
started doing it probably in '98 K from
triome Technologies wrote a paper on it
in '98 right okay we started doing it
over 2000s I didn't know him back then
but we had a table it had four PVC tubes
in it and each PVC tube would get two
cans of butane and we would take it had
three holes on one side one hole on the
other we'd have a [ __ ] coffee filter
that was cut that it would go through
and we would pack it down with plant
material buds whatever we you know I
mean but you would [ __ ] pump so you
have two at a time so you go here you do
these you go these ones you go these
ones and then after you get to all four
you go back to the beginning you try one
more time because it goes you get like
one little blast out of it then you jump
onto the second can and you do those
same thing and we go into Pyrex dish
with the double burner it was like a
camp uh griddle that we used on the
bottom like a flame one what's that not
a flame one [ __ ] you electric electric
griddle and so the electric griddle
would work as a double burner cuz
the water in it and whatever uh below
the Pyrex yep and we the water and the
water be hot and it would warm up the
utan so would bubble very slowly warm up
the butane and it would burn the butane
off and you'd be left with the butter
that you whip at the end you know we
yeah I think that was like prey shatter
that was the original was the butter and
uh on like a Pyrex Square dish correct
the same thing we had and you would get
slabs that you would peel off and it was
super turpy and the funny thing is my
buddy came back cuz I was like man that
stuff's so toxic and gross I can't
believe we use PVC we probably poisoned
ourselves and all our friends and and
then he came back in 2015 had gotten
these tests run on it there was no zero
well no he been he made a batch and then
wanted to test it with the same Tech and
I was like PVC bro I you can't smoke PVC
bro that's hella bad and I could talk
[ __ ] about it he came at me with a COA
where he had every possible test run and
all these things zero butane and so he's
like told you so and I'm like I don't
know but like definitely plastic PVC is
not the way to blast people that do that
that's not a good idea now we know
better for sure for sure for sure not we
smoked a lot of it
though yeah I uh I didn't smoke too much
of that and I didn't I didn't want to
share the tech CU I was worried about
people blowing themselves up but my
first experience was just on my patio on
my deck my condo and we used a turkey
Bas here at the grocery store they had
like a metal turkey Bas or like kind of
a high quality one and then used a hose
clamp with a with the coffee filter on
the bottom end and then we just put the
thing right just pack the turkey baser
full of the flowers and then and then
just put the butane on the top end and
it passed through all the butane and it
would leak into the Pyrex of the coffee
filter gravity would go through it all
and then you have your liquid in there
and then you just put it in the seems
like hella work yeah probably but but
again it was like small batch just like
trying to make some oil for Dabs at the
time you know and and it's just
experimenting it was just like it's
pretty ingenious though I feel like
that's I mean that's you know that's the
it's way better than PVC right right
right right you know in the same in the
same note you it's a lot of work it
seems like it was actually really easy
just pack the thing put the host clamp
in coffee filter and the host clamp held
the coffee filter and then the butane in
the top right where it usually squirts
out and it would just pass through right
and it would drip into the the bowl the
BS in hot water just like you did same
thing with the whipping same thing dude
that stuff is great and it was turpy and
it was good I mean for being a 1.0
version of something that's now turned
into my was always racing doing it
though I didn't like the fact that the
gases and everything I was definitely
always on edge doing it so I always wore
a mask when I was doing I always I there
was people that that blew themselves up
shortly after we started and I was like
I want to blow myself up like that when
I got given the tack I was given it with
a lot of warning and I just didn't want
to I didn't want to live with sharing it
with someone and them having something
to do with them so I just like left it
there and and then over the next years
it obviously evolved to what it did um
but I kind of just stuck with bubble
hash at that point how did you smoke it
when you first started doing did you
smoke it on coal where you you heat the
coal up and then use a straw or no I
think we either put it in were we
dabbing then I think we're almost
dabbing like back then we were smoking
our bubble hash in a RAR bong from
Germany and we Ed these angle bowls and
they would be smoked on a screen so
maybe we would put like the oil on Ash
and then use a hemp Wick and light it
yeah maybe that or we would just like
mix it in our joints I think we might
have a titanium nail by this point I'm
not 100% sure I'm not sure exact 2004
yeah it it was a while after that that I
I think it was like maybe 2005 or six
that I remember da RS maybe it was a
little after that even but titanium
nails were the first I don't think we
were I was I don't think I was quite
using a titanium nail then but but I
knew people who were and and I wasn't I
wasn't about it with the the quality of
the just knowing the butane everything I
wasn't like I was just sus with it I
just didn't totally totally trust it
yeah I didn't know what it was so I was
like I'm like I knew it got me really
high though I knew that for sure so but
I was definitely I'm like we don't know
what we're doing here we don't know what
heavy metals are left in this and I
don't trust it so I'm going to I came
from the world of hot knives Right Where
You me to dude the hot knives you know
maybe that's what we did that's probably
what we did we probably hot knifed it
the hot knives were the way I think I
remember the bubble has wooden Hot Knife
had burn off before you could get a real
hit because it was too liquidy I'm not
sure we always did the old school like
Moroccan style but like some old classic
has that they made in Humble we could we
could hit the hot knives and just get
wrecked yeah I was hot knifing right up
until dabbing now obviously it was doing
it way less but like whenever like there
was that person that just wanted to get
like the extra high we bust them out and
be like okay you know the flowers just
aren't doing it or you want to go to
that place let's do this exactly exactly
and and we do it but like it was like
once a year maybe you know gravity bongs
you guys gravity bongs too yeah and we I
was talking to a guy today he's like
those gravity bongs doing now those
aren't gravity bongs like the real
gravity bongs have a have a valve and
they have water in them and when it's
time to do it you that water goes down
and that toe gets SL like slammed in you
hold the thing up and then yeah yeah and
like that's the real gravity bong I'm
like okay you tap people out people
would never want to smoke again after
that if they did their first time they
probably wouldn't want to smoke again a
lot of people and and it's interesting
how like that was like fun for us back
in the day but if you really think about
it it's not the way you want you want
people to but that goes into the
Explorer part of ourselves you know that
you know the guy who wants to try or go
on the adventure of different methods
you know it's like some of these guys
smoke out of apples and watermelons and
whatever else to go to that you know
they want to go through those phases and
it's like for me that was fun when I was
younger though even bongs like I still
smoke a bong but not all the time but
like I have a bong ready to go I still
enjoy the bongers but I don't enjoy the
seven-footers or the four-footers
anymore even it's like a little I think
I'm more referring to like beginner
smokers who get uh deterred from smoking
by people who kind of mess them up with
too strong of a dose that's kind of what
I'm eating yeah for sure and then and
then they they could be potentially
uh consuming a substance that could make
their every day or every week life
better but they're so scared of it that
they can't even they won't even try it
and I I know we know all know people
like this and that's something I think
we should all try not to do so much yeah
a lot of times we do it unintentionally
like with these slurpers and these dabs
now are pretty potent and I think a lot
of yeah for sure there's a lot of potent
ways to smoke now like for if you're a
real smoker there's ways to get there
and and very
easily uh but I I like the fact that
there's mild Edibles that people were
taking small doses of you know cuz we
didn't measure anything back in the day
we're like how much [ __ ] can we put in
this Brownie and I wouldn't do Edibles
for time because of how what we did to
each other and it wasn't until there was
actually milligrams on items and and I
like very cautiously tried them and then
I built a confidence for it that yeah I
was scared from Edibles completely just
from what we' done to each other in the
in the early 2000s totally where you're
tripping for a day it's like literally
what happens yeah seriously going to
regy on the river eating a whole dude
whole one whole brownie that was
probably like a 500 or 700 milligram
brownie than having like trippy
experience yeah some people like that
some people don't some people can't
handle it I think a huge part of it is a
fight ORF flight response I think and if
you try to fight a buzz that's already
going to happen you got to kind of ride
it out and so once you accept it in your
head and you can just enjoy the Buzz for
what it is then it's dope but if you're
sitting there trying to fight something
that you can't beat it's going to be a
long journey it's going to be a struggle
be a struggle yeah I think there's a lot
of life lessons from stuff like that
that relate to everything fair fair fair
you know I think yeah accepting
accepting everything especially when
you're tripping dude like you definitely
have to just
breathe yeah let's do another let's let
another joint up dude so uh appreciate
you having me appreciate you having
bunch of pre-rolls here too my mank
absolutely the California hospitality
has been Next Level I've only been here
for few days in New York too like
considering it has the rep it does of
people being you know mean and nasty in
this uh I had such a nice response out
there and met so many really great
people especially like hash makers and
Growers and just like the level of
passion because of like the hardships of
where they came from because of how
illegal it was is is really always cool
to see in all walks of life all over the
world I find the most passionate awesome
people come from the hardest uh most
illegal places a lot of times totally
not always from Humble somewhere so free
you know you know s from right yeah kind
of Florida or New York or New York he
still got the accent actually yeah yeah
yeah Ed Ed Rosenthal New York he's
another New Yorker okay the most
stubborn guys AR from New York
interesting because they've had to deal
with a lot I guess or maybe and it's a
huge City a lot of attitude I loved it
it was so cool yeah I think it's great
that so much flare legalization has
really happened over there and I feel
like they're doing it right very much
agree you know from back in the day
where they could uh stop and search you
for no reason at all right what what an
evolution yeah being from the west coast
of Canada New York has always been the
top buyer for product they've always
paid more than anybody there's yeah you
knew if you were tapped into the buyer
circles there was always one guy that
knew a New York buyer and they would pay
more than anybody else and the way it
worked when the beaser days were going
on is La saw or whatever the West Coast
saw most of the gear yeah and New York
saw like another level of gear and then
Toronto would see like whatever was left
over just because the dollar right it's
just straight up and eventually as the
beers slowed down a lot of that was
trying to be pushed to New York but I
don't think they took a lot of it
somebody went to Chicago from what I
know and a lot of it started just go
east to Toronto and like further east
yeah across Canada right because the
people are still growing all this large
amount of volume and like what the [ __ ]
we going to do with it you know what I
mean so Toronto went from like not like
getting like those juicies and stuff
like that and not really knowing what
good flour was to being some of the most
picky people around because they slowly
but surely as The Bard tightened they
started getting all the gear yeah and
and and now they they get it all and and
and they you have producers growing
really good flour now too for sure for
sure and I'd say Toronto gets like a
huge portion of like the best flower
that's grown in Canada because they have
the biggest uh uh population in buying
power they make more money there than
anywhere in Canada so on and so forth so
yeah yeah we were talking about Skittles
earlier what else are you guys getting
up there genetics wise that's
amazing so there's not a lot of real
Skittles in Canada like I can count on
one hand same here the amount of people
that I would um can reach out and know
that they're sending me real Z and and
even I'd say half those five aren't even
the original cut they're like a a z a
oneoff z Cross or something or very Z
leaning cross you know what I mean
rainbow belts 2.0 or whatever exactly
yeah and a lot of the belts that I'm
finding in Canada aren't very Z leaning
at all because a lot of them um either
didn't know what to hunt for when they
hunted it right because they don't
they've never seen the real Z so how do
you know what to hunt for you know go
for looks
then or if it's a grower probably
biomass right totally so whereas you
want the candy but then the candy one
doesn't have a good structure and so
anytime you breed with Skittles they
breed towards the structure anything
that's going to be real Skitty goes hand
in hand with
the the structure that's not quite as
nice it's not yeah it's a little looser
uh you the tricomes don't form up on it
quite as good and as a fenal Hunter it's
a lot of the characteristics you're not
going to look for except for the profile
that one is if you're going for the
Skittles you have to look yeah it's
about the profile that's more than
anything because it's not about the
looks it's not about the Vigor it's not
about a lot of stuff but uh you know
finding something in the middle or that
blends good with moonbo moonbo from
archive that that one's fire that's why
the belts was what it was right yeah
exactly so um and I I'm fortunate enough
to have that cut interesting story how I
got it um during Co someone from New
Mexico said they're going to send it to
me and I was kind of like yeah right and
then I don't know where it showed up and
then I had to mail him something back
but I couldn't really get to the post
office in Eno because anyway it's co
stuff and blah blah blah I end up
getting him some seeds eventually but
yeah I have a I have a good rainbow
belts cut ni um from a saw dude that
sent it from New Mexico and the Z I uh
had to get back myself in another in
other ways yeah and um but I have both
those cuts and and I really like I
really like both of them they're
probably two of my favorite strains we
have nice and a big part of that is cuz
during when I went to Amsterdam last
year I didn't do much hunting I had a
new grower kind of take over my facility
so I was just kind of happy with my 30
to 40 cultivars keeping them alive mhm
versus trying to like cross them and log
a whole fenal hunt right so um I'm a
little bit behind on a lot of my hunting
right now um but this year this last
year all the seeds we made I gave a
bunch away in Thailand and we're doing a
huge hunt now so we're back on it this
year but uh I took a a year off and it's
what I realized is I actually kind of
feel two years behind yeah because I
felt the year behind that I didn't hunt
but then it takes another you to hunt
yeah so I actually felt two years behind
so um the lesson here is don't ever stop
hunting don't ever stop hunting you got
to keep it going for sure yeah otherwise
you're going to rely on other people's
stuff so when did you start breeding
because you've been making seeds for a
while now
so I think 90 99 wow 99 we started uh in
2015 I started to go to Emerald cup and
bring I saw there was a void in Canada
of like lack of genetics from all my
Growers and I could I felt like we had
the quality of Growers seeing how long
we've been doing this for what we were
lacking was the genetics so I took it
upon myself to go to Emerald cup and
first go to different dispensaries and
figure out what genetics I wanted yeah
and then figure out who bred those
genetics and then I made my list and
went to Emerald and I bought the
genetics directly from said breeders
sure um it was symbiotic it was Oni
exotic uh canado yeah um those were the
first people I saw probably some other
I'm forgetting too yeah and capill as
well anyway and so I started hunting and
then I get different results from
different breeders yeah and as I you
know got the results I liked I started
go more to those breeders and um and
then the next year also I started to
realize that everybody was kind of on
the hash train I was watching like the
Breeders and people with the brands when
they would meet up with each other
they'd all have these jars in their
pocket and these jars were Rin and that
was when I could that when I was like
okay this is what all the owners of you
know this is the next wave I could see
that the rosin was the next wave because
it's just the way that I just see it and
so I rosin happened real quick I went
home I made that cold room yeah and I
had a partner back when I was doing this
Temple Kix thing he said that rosin
wasn't going to become anything because
that the parchment was going to leave uh
material in the thing and just going to
wait for time until that gets found out
and so I was like oh really I was like
okay and so I kind of believed what he
said for a little bit but then as I went
to spannabis that year I met Matt and
Joel from sasquash at strain Hunter club
and uh they showed me the whole process
and 3 months later I had a new sasquash
in Vancouver and I was one of the first
people when a few people that I knew
that knew how to press didn't have their
own presses mhm and they also didn't
have their own material so what I was do
I just had these guys that knew how to
press come over and do pressing yeah for
basically for us like I would give them
the the oil for pressing I'd give them a
percentage of doing it and I had all
this extra biomass to press flower rosin
so they would just come over and they
would press and they'd get some and I'd
get some and it was just extra biomass
anyway like Smalls or like stuff that I
didn't need right or like just product
that wasn't selling and so from there I
saw the hash rosin being the wave and I
just got into it I then my first thing I
did was enter Masters rosin I built a
cold room in like November and I entered
Masters in March oh wow and I got fourth
place and that was like the the huge
that's where I met like Frosty and
Lorenzo and I already met Lorenzo you
before but that's where like competing
with them and being at the events at
Masters and being at the dinners and
just being part of the whole process
right was where you really build these
relationships that are just like
legendary you know and so now here we
are um six years l
and I'm going to go visit Frosty this
week up in up in Humbolt and and I don't
know it's just so cool like full circle
the whole experience and the whole
journey it's really cool this community
is really amazing and they're exclusive
in some ways inclusive in other ways and
I love the inclusive part where
everybody's part of a bigger community
and then you know there are exclusive
areas of the community as well and with
genetics people with really good flower
and then people without that's very
exclusive still at the very top that
absolutely. 1% not even the 1% but the
0.1% of the flower and the people that
everybody knows each other on that level
too I think pretty much or knows you
through somebody else 100% 100% so and I
like that part I like I like a very good
point smoking the best flour possible
and I feel like most people don't even
get to appreciate the flour that we get
to see on a regular basis and so it's
always something special absolutely no I
feel absolutely blessed to be to have
smoked the flour and gain the experience
that I have like even just this past
mass of rosin in New York you got people
from all over the East Coast um with all
their different pallets and their
different stories and backgrounds and
some of them are from C and some of them
are not and some of them have been there
the whole L and it's just really cool to
see their journey and what they hunt and
why they hunt it and and just the whole
experience is really cool to see all the
different walks of life and that's why
spannabis is so important too you got
all these different passions like a guy
came second place in the organic cup
with some of our genetics he bought off
us the year before and to have a German
guy win a cup in Spain from genetics
from Canada that I got from C just the
whole story the whole thing is like so
cool for me and just like wow just to be
a part of that it's just really special
and uh and extra motivating to just keep
going and and just keep uh you know
trying to elevate this as much as I can
for sure yeah I mean it's a beautiful
time to be alive and the industry is
beautiful we've gone Global you know I
feel like crazy we've lifted the
curtains back and people are showing
each other who they really are and we're
able to do it on a a legal level that
was never possible before and it's so
amazing going it's like spanis where we
got guys from Canada United States
Amsterdam Thailand uh other Asian
countries that I'm not going to say
right now but like we got people from
all over uh coming over South Africa and
Norway and and Finland and Sweden and
all over
and we're all there for the same thing
for good weed or for for cannabis
whether it's the weed the hash uh the
friendships did you see the Brazil wave
this year dude it was wild yeah so South
America I didn't mention that but South
America yeah they're all they're from
every country over there right Chile uh
they're in the other count so we can
mention them because they're in Spain
right it's not like they're doing it in
Brazil yeah so um but yeah and and it's
just that passion that comes from places
of adversity yeah and and struggle and
it's always the the brightest shining
star yeah I mean those guys in the
Caribbean are really passionate about
what they do oh yeah uh yeah I got to go
there with Marlin a while back it was
which which which place in the St
Vincent we went over to St Vincent and
visited with the Cannabis Authority and
we gave a lecture on genetics and pollen
mitigation was part of my like lecture
to them because they're on island and
it's like I want to explain that that
was the first thing I looked at when I
got off the plane is such a small island
that like pollen Jamaica it's a big
problem for sure and so yeah first we we
talked to the Cannabis Authority we said
we're going to be back to get a license
and that still hasn't happen but it's
still something we would love to do in
the future I think I made a bunch of
banana crosses actually to go
specifically to St Vincent that are
regular seeds Okay and feminized seeds
that I wanted to give out to everybody
um so we did legally import seeds into
St Vincent in
2019 okay so and it just hasn't really
evolved in anything much since then or I
think they're doing it they're doing it
it hasn't evolved with me they're still
there pushing forward and I'm they've
gone through their struggles just like
Jamaica and just like are they medically
legal or where they medical right now
yeah it's feel better when it's like
that like as soon as the wreck comes in
you get these corporate people and and
it it becomes a whole different ball
game um at least medical you can have it
for the right reasons for the most part
dude the Canadians keep [ __ ] it up
they go what do we [ __ ] it up this time
they go no it's the LPS that are going
into places and taking over and doing a
bad job you know and I think we bad name
on they're putting a bad name on the
whole industry for taking public money
and and losing people's hard-earned
money and like that's like literally the
bottom line and then these CEOs and
these Executives get a payout after for
tanking these companies and and and
basically lying like I don't understand
corporate business enough maybe but um
that's from my vantage point what I see
time and time and time again and like
they don't care about the plant they
don't care about the end consumer
obviously care about their shareholders
right but they more care about uh trying
to raise shareholders than actually like
maintain the business and which they've
bought into right so it's just pump and
dump is basically what it is in most
Parts yeah and that model is not good
for business it's definitely not good
for small
business the race to the bottom is real
in the United States you know and that's
the other side it's like either pump and
dump or long-term race to the bottom to
gain market share it seems like one of
the other um and both of those models
aren't really good for they hurt small
business more than anything yeah and and
I'm all about small business because I'm
a small business person and that's what
was so dope about Emerald cup and what's
so dopable spannabis is all the
especially Emerald cup I would say more
than spannabis because Emerald cup was
like back in the day not now but like in
20156 it was so cool to see all the
small Ma and PAW businesses and so many
of them got run out in the last 5 to 10
years and it's really sad for I'm sure
everybody around here that knows it more
than me like sad for me just some
Canadian come down and see this but I
don't have to live at first town like a
lot of people here but man it's like I I
can I just empathize as much as possible
it's just crazy the whole dynamic
because it was so awesome before like it
was so the chalice and early Emerald I
think a lot of breeders had distinctly
different seed lines too you know what I
mean like I think they weren't all
breeding the same thing there was a lot
of diversity within the different SE
companies TGA if you wanted some sort of
like fruit or really sweet stuff TGA had
some really crazy sweet stuff who's TGA
the the green Avengers that was subcool
okay right right so subcool and Miss
Jill back in the day it was it was all
the homies dude Heavenly days from
Canada row want to shout him out he was
really really close to subcool nice yeah
so there there was sunny cha there was
was uh Ray Odie okay ray from homegrown
natural wonders and then s Shane from
Sun Chiba there was Pat and there was
all these amazing guys um those are the
guys that I'm pretty good friends with
oh that uh yeah they they were breeding
and dude that they they emerged out of
you know the subcool era where like sub
was they were releasing some bomb [ __ ]
they were releasing some W you know
Cherry Cola type [ __ ] stuff and there
I remember one back pushing the
boundaries on Flavor what you could get
and you know it's like CU we go through
these eras there was Tangi was popular
for a while that was the number one
Tangi for like this weird pH and the
judges yeah Blue Dream had its day I
think blue dream when it was popular was
super popular and people people loved
growing it and then it looked so
beautiful people loved smoking it and it
just it's one of those ones that got
burned out the Clones got blown out
everywhere Lally everywh everyone wanted
to grow it it was easy to grow even if
you're a bad grower you could get two
pounds a light what other strangs did
subcool and them put out other than the
cola one do you remember some like that
was really
orangey you know there was the Doctor
Who that that raided U homeo natural
wonders I don't remember but that was a
good one the Doctor Who and then he made
a purple high-u and it was like a feno
that was like it tasted like grape highw
candy fire and my buddies in Washington
actually had the cut and they grew it
out and gave me some of the flour and
it's like it's so funny when you don't
smoke something for 10 years or
something like that eight years and then
you go back and you smoke it again and
it's just reminiscent it
brings you right back that real and you
know that it's the like you identify
that as exactly what you smoked that
profile and it's like some of those
things are just so nostalgic skunks like
back in the day I still haven't seen
skunk I think uh I'm trying to get
somebody with the skunk that claims that
they have the real skunk on the show and
they're going to bring it and we're
going to smoke it and I'm going to tell
everybody how it's either the real skunk
or it's not the real skunk I mean I'm
super excited about that so the thing is
is with these genetics and these claims
I'm not going to doubt anybody but show
me the flower show me the proof 100% And
I want cat piss I want the real cat piss
I know what the cat piss that's another
one because like cat piss is like a very
distinct Aroma Bubblegum's mine bubble
gum's yours bubble gum was amazing the
real Juicy Fruit the real like flavorful
Juicy Fruit there was a juicy fruit that
was going around and it was Top Shelf it
tasted like Juicy Fruit bubble gun what
it look like um so it was like bat buds
lime green bat buds Li Li green but like
oval oblong buds but they were chunky
like not like small no this one was like
huge buds like a a half PB ziplock is
what we use in Canada yeah a QP would
fit in there you couldn't fit a whole
half pound in there they were just so
big juicy it was so easy to trim they
were just like big fingers of just like
it looked so it was very easy to trim it
was pretty special I'd saved some seeds
and pop seeds of it and even the seeds
kind of gave that juicy fruit this a
Vancouver Island thing Vancouver Island
nice back in the late like 98 was the
probably the early 2000 the last I ever
saw it was 01 yeah that we we lost a lot
of stuff back in the day that was super
special and unique and you know we
didn't we didn't save clones as as long
and sometimes we didn't know I believe
that hop Lon existed back then and we
just didn't know what it was and it was
you and far between but I remember like
some of the genetics where you'd buy it
in the first like year these guys were
putting it out it would be ridiculous
and then all of a sudden it went down in
quality I the bubblegum did the same
thing did the exact same I honestly
think that it's been around a lot longer
than we've thought it was and they just
said it was weak moms is what they
woulded dude we had we we we took weak
clones or we [ __ ] up when they were
moms and passed it down and like I
honestly think coplon could be alive a
lot longer than we had given it credit
for very Val Mak sense super it
decimates gross it makes sense to what
happened in that strain and probably
many others that were just diesel right
yeah so many others right and so many
others where it's like they dut out and
we didn't I didn't even understand
dutting diseases back then we just we
weren't that scientific and now you can
test for it there's so many different
ways there's some really good labs and
there's some not so good lab I'm I'm
really excited to start working with a
lab in Canada called High North and I'm
also working with a hopefully LP moving
forward and uh there's going to be a lot
of data collecting on like the outdoor
indoor LED versus HPS and different
mediums super soil versus uh living soil
and so you're trialing all this stuff
and collecting data yeah and then the
hash and then the hash from all this so
that's like what I'm working towards
hopefully with the group in the next
like one to three years well you're
talking to the right group right now I
know that's a part of why we're going to
talk about after it's so funny because
we use data to track software we're
using phenome one and that's from
phenome networks that are Israel and
basically makes sense this is the
perfect plug for them too uh but yeah so
we basically use it for our inventory
system where we create genetics right
and then so we inventory stuff we create
crosses with it and then we do variety
testing where you put it out in
different regions and different climates
and we collect several data points we're
so we're looking at originally like uh
53 and then it was 63 and now it's about
72 different data points that we'd like
to collect for each plant how often do
you collect those data points so and is
it certain ones at different times
there's yeah in the beginning there's
one that basically you measure growth
and like we're actually getting tape
measure out there doing it like you
would in a yeah um but measuring growth
uh and then weighing the plants whole
weighing the plants dry and wet and so
being able to give that information also
weighing the main Cola what that yields
I think that's a super important piece
of information and we're also doing this
in indoor and two environments with the
same genetics uh that are commercial
environments so we can compare you know
everything with coas at the end as well
so we put get coas we can go okay this
genetic works best here here and here or
it only works best here and other things
are better so you can really start
identifying your lines is kind of what
we're really looking at I got hunts
going on all over the world right now I
probably I don't know if this would
apply with what I got going on but I'm
going to definitely ask you some more
questions after the podcast because yeah
I got probably like had two different
spots in Thailand that are hunting um
and then some spots in Spain and some
spots all over the world right now so
and then a few in BC is obviously as
well so and like some are greenhouse
some are outdoor some are indoor LED
some are HPS so it's kind of all over
the map some are rock wol some are most
Are soil and living soil right um but
yeah I'm I want to to have some sort of
data tool to pull them all into one
thing would be good right now I use a
thing called one note I mostly use that
with my washing though I'm not using
much as much data collecting as I should
be after reading your book yeah um on
the just all the different fenos and
just all the different data points I'm
not doing nearly enough I'm mostly
hunting on profiles personally um
because that's what I've hunted in the
past um but moving forward is I start
crossing the profiles I like with other
profiles I like I'm going to definitely
want to get more into
theu takes years to get to there though
right well yeah the first year you don't
get a ton I mean you get good stuff but
it's really that like the second year
the third year it it count pounds over
time right and what you get into it or
what you put into it you get out of it
makes sense and uh so the more data you
have and the more like dude you start re
seeing Trends and you really see what is
dominant as far as traits once you're
using the same thing over and over
through multiple lines and you pick your
matches better moving forward you waste
less time it you're wasting less time
right and I think the potential for this
software is that they have uh AI
algorithms that they can do uh like
predict type stuff predict predictive
modeling right so like you can do
predictive modeling if you have a
starting point and a finish where you
where you want to see the plant go or
where you you know what kind of traits
you're looking for breeding for specific
traits they can do predictive modeling
now wow crazy my mind is blowing dude
it's it's so amazing because really
breeding for specific goals for you know
regions and climates right once you find
your traits that you want like your
profiles and then you go to the trades
once yeah once you look at where you
want the plant to go and then testing
stuff in those regions and then being
able to push the plant in those
directions I have a question for you um
as a hash maker um washability and like
How likely is when you cross things that
do wash with things that don't wash yeah
what How likely do those traits pass
over and and unlikely what's your
thoughts I'm working on that right now
to be honest uh we have a bunch of
washers that we're going to be testing
and then Crossing them to genetics to
find new varieties but so we have 10
tents right you're in the process of
figuring that out right now dude that's
absolutely one of the things that we're
trying to figure out I'm working with
Jason huto from House of cvar and we're
doing this really freaking cool washer
project that we're going to be testing
this stuff and also breeding Autos that
wash that's a big part of what we're
doing Mak sense yeah I think the time is
now for that all that stuff especially
here in the west coast where we got a
limited especially up north where we
have limited uh summer yeah yeah I mean
great climates over here and then is
definitely on everyone's
radar uh yeah it's a big thing it is it
is the waves coming and with devices
like the puffco it's only going to help
break the stigma moving forward and that
was Franco's main thing and that's what
we're all here to help do is push
Franco's uh agenda moving forward was
help break the stigma yeah and uh it's
helpful for all of us and especially for
the people that uh want to get into it
you know right that's uh how a lot of
people don't want to smoke because
they're afraid of the way they'll be the
light they'll be cast under and uh
torches weren't good for that exactly
exactly so as we break the stigma
there'll be less of this right yeah I
mean all these new ways to smoke is
great consuming is great you know the
the Rosen carts now right I think the
Rosen carts are amazing I think abely
absolutely when you're getting the
flavor and the pull and you know I don't
like the two gam cards it's got to be
like I would I would mind I wouldn't
mind if they had half gram cards
actually they do for sure in Canada they
do for they probably do here yeah yeah I
mean my friends always give me cards you
that's because like there's they last
too long because no because the flavor
isn't good after the first half gram or
gotta gotcha so especially it heats up
over and over oxidization yeah and like
dude like I heard about five gr pens now
it's like why rosin Vape already has to
be heated unlike dla dla doesn't have to
be heated it's already gone through its
process but but rosin has to be heated
to get into that viscous state in most
cultiv cases right so that's probably
also contributing factor as to why the
shelf life wouldn't be as long as
because sure the product's got to be
kind of heated up to even be in a vape
yeah white Thorn Rose is a new one I had
in a rosin cart not too long ago and
it's purple XJ comes out it's purple
rosin okay yeah but it's like flower
petals in silon right in the in the
triome head I just saw a picture today
at this place I was at and they showed
that trop cookies is usually the The
Strain the cultivar that uh is the cause
of the nylin in the triome head for sure
I don't know if you what's your opinion
on that Cho Cherry uh so I got super
sick of it because it's like a harsh
Citrus flavor but that's the same type
of thing that gets people's attention
like if you look back to Mimosa which
was a super popular one for time for
sure um it was a popular one that we had
it's got that same sort of uh flare to
it um for me like I said I was I was
done with chop cookies but like it just
W ego as it's blended with the Z and
also like the trop cookies offensiveness
is kind of dumbed down a little bit and
then the Z
it comes up and so they kind of balance
out a little bit so it gives you that
like wow factor but without like the
super harshness so um I like it for sure
and that's the super boof I'm talking
about the one that Tricom tortoise has
been winning Super boo yeah yeah that's
a weird one for me for me too like At
first I was like well chop cookies but
then as I got into I was like okay I see
why it's getting people attention I see
why it's winning and the purple adds
another visual aspect of it that like
just gives it another Mark you know
people want to buy purple stuff that
super is the super yielder too I don't
know next level as far as yield yeah
like four pounds per oh wow on the
flower side on a 4x4 yeah hell yeah nice
four per light yeah I mean I think could
throw some favin in there you probably
get five there you go is that the under
lighting the under canopy lighting yeah
are are you doing that I'm all about
under canopy I've seen my friends crush
it with the under canopy what's the
percentages you're seen 25% that's like
the average uh even like 15% one of my
friends but like yeah I mean I heard
about 50% I think in green houses is
where it's going to be like really a
game changer there won't because dude
there's so many Smalls you get rid of
your Smalls in the greenhouse now we're
talking about better Urban if you have
good color as well but I'm trying to
understand why the greenh houses does is
that it's because like ppfd and that's
because the sun's moving like this so
it's not getting consistent light all
the time where a breakthrough glass or
plastic or whatever too so like that
you're not getting the full ppfd of the
sun makes sense okay right and then uh I
think because the sun is should better
but well you do get sun plus the under
canopy right okay now you're bumping
your probably your supplementary
Lighting in there will also have a big
factor to how much the percentage gain
is I bet right right
absolutely so I think uh yeah and
they're they're inexpensive the underc
lights are inexpensive I'm going to get
them for
sure from what I've seen from the data
like I know Guin I know a guy yeah there
you go it's not going to be well I guess
it will be good because a lot of times
we wash the Smalls and now the smalls
are going to be too good you're not
going to want to wash them so I don't
know so the thing is is like I haven't
proven this myself but Smalls going down
to 5% or less yeah I mean that's great
cuz you just put them at the base of the
plant right so like you don't have to
thin your canopy out all that stuff
grows out in a nice chunky purple buds
if it's purple wheat normally it's green
with that stuff it gets the the light
spectrum is really good for flower
purple yeah they have the red in there
yeah my LEDs do that it's all about that
red yeah what's the LED company that you
choose uh we're using science right now
we we have the Dragon alpha adjustable
spectrums nice I think they're really
cool they're easy easy to work with the
the app that you use is simple great uh
yeah what about yourself I I had a k
company called Alias they've treated us
very well pretty sure they're just using
the Samsung dials like everybody else
yeah but they're good people and they've
treated us very well good guys got to
love that Samsung yeah exactly it's
pretty much across the board most of the
LEDs that are good have the Samsung
exactly so nice base of it you got any
trips coming up trips coming up yeah a
bunch actually uh got to go back to
Amsterdam see s in a few weeks nice and
then uh I got to tie up some loose ends
from some seeds people in Germany and
then I got to go back for the Berlin
event are you going to Berlin I don't
know yet I'm so busy here dude it's
crazy I really want to I'm planning on a
trip to Thailand Okay uh maybe the
Caribbean cup guys we'll see okay I got
invited to the Caribbean cup uh there
there's two cups over there that are
happening and I'm super excited about
both of them Caribbean's a great place
to go hell yeah of course of course you
can't go wrong in the Caribbean it's
just people are happy there too it's
like so happy yeah I I haven't been in a
while so to go there part of the reason
I don't go to the Caribbean is because
usually they're not very weed friendly
places other than Jamaica but I've been
to Jamaica so many times I need to like
go to other places Jamaica's great
though it's good lot of Americans down
but with Thailand the way legalization
is bro like it's it's unreal the food
there is so good it's cheap it and
there's beaches and it's like yeah and
and the weed's getting better so at
first it was like a lot of import and
super expensive but now there's some
good local grows and if you can in and
you can there's a rosin scene now and
it's all it's all there now um
Thailand's definitely high on my list as
far as places I want to be spending time
unless they like hardcore change the
laws there's nowhere else in the world
where someone like myself can be still
be yourself well yeah because like I
brokered for time and like you know
obviously like I could do that Canada
but I have to do it on like the lp side
of things and it's and that means I got
to work with all these suits that I just
like they're just like so hard to work
with they're just lying every step of
the way like there's no transparency in
what they're talking about at all right
so I like when someone tells me
something them actually being what they
say not some other smoking mirror stuff
so yeah um I guess it's possible at
every level but uh just with the amount
of shops and the amount of grows and the
amount of like just everything that's
going on Thailand there's just for
someone there's just more opportunity
there there really is and I don't I
don't see anywhere else in the world
there's that much opportunity unless
they change the laws yeah just with the
amount of people the amount of tourists
that come through there right and if you
draw I think it's like a 200 mile uh
radius around Thailand has more
population from a 2hour flight than
anywhere else in the world wow and so
that's why they have so many tourists
there it's like it's like easy to fly to
from all these different countries from
Japan from wherever even Russia and and
then India too nice let's not forget
about India it's pretty big population
there huge yeah so I got a bunch of land
race seeds just recently from Fritz you
met Fritz probably I think I did it
sounds really familiar he is the strain
Hunter man he's a he's yeah he goes
around and collecting he collects seeds
from everywhere okay and does his thing
and so we're working on some projects
together where are they from Thailand or
uh they are from Southeast Asia okay
they are from like La India from the
Kush mountains okay he has like some
yeah some like Charis when you going to
start them we popping them as we speak
and did you have to do anything crazy to
pop them did you have to like add that
other what was that solution I was
learning yeah you didn't have to use ga3
for that these ones are these aren't
these are good okay uh but yeah embryo
rescue you can do the embryo rescue
that's the reading on that book if yours
that also thank you problem thank you
thanks for the support man appreciate it
dude yeah the book's been an adventure
uh we just went live on Amazon yesterday
oh there's a ton to learn in there for
every level of everything in the indust
there's a lot to learn in that book we
tried to make it something for everybody
and I feel like it's in depth enough to
where everybody can benefit in some way
and it's a collective effort makes sense
you know so it wasn't just me it was a
bunch of other people as well I like the
case studies too the case studies are
super cool yeah I try to keep it real
with the case studies you know what I
mean and get the real story from the
real people and I I wrote things it's
funny because with the case studies some
of them I wrote a certain way and then I
sent them to the people and they were
like no that's not what happened and I'm
like good to know like okay so this is
what I had heard and this is what the
truth is and so so when you wrote it you
did their version rendition all the each
one well from The Source I got as close
to the source as I could I mean this
Sour Diesel we talk about Sour Diesel
yes there's a lot of like the piff like
for sure I was and then the people when
they talk about it like you they are so
certain like there's no there's no area
of uncertainty when they tell the story
so how do you yeah and I got a version
maybe someone's got a different version
his close to source and
verified um because even with stories
over times stories tend to change I had
a good P story from a from a real New
Yorker a new New Yorker when I was in uh
yeah when I was in New York it was
really I really like the piff like cough
too the piff that I saw was like these
little pinky little like like almost
like turd looking Kix just Kix that are
like exactly and and it was just it was
hazy for sure it was just a haze like a
typical Haze nothing nothing too
so the P that I've had is like a haze
but it's more mellow of a turp and not
more of it doesn't burn your nose sharp
it was like that it was just like that
it was it was was more mellow Haze no
didn't it wasn't like Congo or like one
of no no no it was it was the high is
more chill for it too the CU V was
Stronger but I like the piff I actually
like the flavor on the piff it's another
one you can smoke it down to the roach
if it's really good and it's got
that nice it's it it definitely is
uplifting and I feel like the high is
really clean for me I feel like uh it
opens my eyes up it doesn't [ __ ]
tighten my eyes down I feel like I could
see that like a nice daytime buzz and I
can see that's why New Yorkers like it
too they they got to kind of be alert in
New York you can't just be coach lock
baked and walk around that City you're G
to no it doesn't lock knock you out like
the Durban does e right but you still
want to you know take the edge off a
little so I see why that's popular um
shout out to uh Golden State banana Nick
for for taking me around and introducing
me to the guy with the piff and like
he's been out there for the last couple
years
and um pretty sure his Golden State
Banana's banana OG a cut of banana OG
yeah and uh he's been rocking it out
there doing it coming back with a
vengeance after you know yeah it's
pretty cool to see yeah it's nice to see
people reinvent themselves and and crush
it so it's really cool for sure man
there's there's a bunch of fighters in
this industry you know who aren't going
down no matter what and it's like that's
the best thing and sometimes it's just
putting one foot in front of the other
you know instead of giving up hope no a
lot of I mean there's times where it's
easy to Sprint and it's easy to run
there's other times where you're walking
up the mountain and it seems like the
mountain is so far away the top of the
mountain and you just got to put one
foot in front of the other until you get
over the [ __ ] hump and I think life
is all about that you know what I mean
and just getting up and showing up for
yourself tomorrow is a new day uhhuh and
if it's not a good one today well no try
to see sometimes you just got to show up
for yourself absolutely that's number
one it's number one self-care is is
everything and uh on uh on a spiritual
level and on on a physical level I think
and it's really difficult in this day
and age with the distractions we have on
our social media oh yeah even be any
sort of in touch with your spiritual
level whatsoever getting outside there's
all kinds of important [ __ ] like I think
it's just obvious for me but it's like
going outside you know I've been so busy
I had a hard time mowing the lawn like
because I've been so busy fin I just
went home at 6:30 and went out and M my
lawn it and it felt so good after it
felt really good after like it's funny
cuz uh super blessed to not have a lawn
but also to live in super nature area
nice I I'm just joking cuz I don't have
to mow it but I wouldn't mind a lawn but
kind of the where we live is not really
like lawn territory I guess it could but
it's more like Rocky and like kind of
like trees and Forest but yeah I'm and I
have the beach across the road and
that's where I go around myself and try
to take my shoes off and walk on the
freezing cold sand and toino do you ever
do sungazing have you done sungazing I
do it every morning hly so when I was in
Thailand every morning I wake up and I
and I watch the sun come up over the
horizon cold plunging yeah I do that too
for sure yeah that's what's up I don't
do it enough cuz like when I'm traveling
and like to have it and and honestly
when I'm at home I I have one but I I I
wimp out a lot so I do like a lot of
cold showers and it's kind of like a
process of like it's so much easier than
a cold shower for me I don't like cold
showers there's a part I know you mean I
like the dip boom getting it over like a
bandaid I'm in and then I'm numb right
right and then you think about it for
about 30 seconds and just breathe you're
just breathing through it and then you
get numb and you don't what's your time
that you like to do a cold punch six
minutes six minutes I'm about five so
yeah and well so I don't do as cold as I
used to I used to do 37 degrees and now
I do like 50 okay okay 50 is just fine I
could go I could do 37 but I feel like
50 is good and I get out of there and I
feel super
refreshed um and I don't take forever to
warm if I go 37 de for 5 minutes it
takes me a lot longer to warm up and
it's not that big of a deal but I feel
like I I get the real benefit at 50°
like 50 Dees for 6 minutes I feel
amazing and I get that dopamine kick for
all day love it I love it do you do do
you in conjunction with sauna as well or
do you do separate I do I've been doing
the sauna as much lately but yeah the
sauna pronounced Finnish and I am
Finnish Swedish but SAA is uh the S we
do for I just learned something thank
you yeah I didn't know that
traditionally pronounced s not I didn't
know that can do four days a week 30
minutes uh I I I like it hot I like it
above like 180 MH mhm but you to yeah
it's like after I the saunas a lot and
in Tofino I'm really blessed we have a
couple really nice saunas that are on
the beach Y and then you walk across the
beach and just lay in the ocean and
that's almost torture because the waves
will get you like a bigger wave will hit
you and it go right over your head
sometimes and it's like it's like a
whole different type of like flowy cold
and then we also have a floating sauna
yeah up the inlet where you it's
unbelievably beautiful and you can jump
in the ocean off the floating sauna it's
yeah so that's funny cuz when we're in
Seattle they have uh hot tub boats okay
D it's freezing cold water on Lake Union
Ry yeah and then you go around in the
hot tub boats and HP in same sort of
thing yeah we usually go in the real
boats but the hot tub boats are pretty
cool too you see you know people
partying you co plung in just the
regular boat you can coold plunge off
the side of of the boat but yeah that
that water is super cold up there right
time year yeah um so as far as you do so
how many days do you do cold plunge and
then how many days do you do s a week ah
probably like only two two of each
realistically I would like to do more
I'd like to do them almost every day um
my goal at some our place is a bed and
breakfast in Canada it's called Green
Seed to retreat it was a fishing I did
fishing trips and then I switched it
into like a cannabis thing where we
teach people to make hash and rosin
right on site Y and
so what I'm getting is I'm going to
build a there I'm going to have the Cung
and sauna on site probably by the end of
the summer so so in my backyard I'll be
able to do it and at that point I have
no excuse not to do it four or five
times a week like no excuse yeah it's
the best I I used to talk about it too
much on my show but I I love it and I
love I love heat makes you feel good you
want people to feel
good for sure our whole team does it and
we all everybody feels so good and like
the the morale around the the house
because we all live and work together is
like yeah I've been trying to get my
producer to jump in the coal plunge but
he's not into it but I've had a couple
friends on the show that have stayed at
the house where we got him in the
backyard Kyle that was on the show from
can Organics he jumped in the pool he
was in about he had drank some coffee
first I said you might not want to drink
coffee he drank coffee anyway goes out
to the cold plune I get in and I'm like
yeah I just sit here you know five
minutes and it was 48 degrees that day
or 47 degrees he got in and started
shaking a little bit just dunked down to
his neck and he's like [ __ ] this jumped
out ran in the house and took a hot
shower
uh but yeah your house that was at my
house yeah I have a big 700 gallon above
ground well next time I come we'll go
we'll do it up oh yeah yeah yeah it's
good yeah I'm super down I I love a good
C pun and I haven't done it this trip
and I wanted to do it in New York I was
looking for a spa but I couldn't find
one yeah I didn't find one in time but
yeah totally yeah you guys need to come
uh hang out get some good food there's
so much stuff to do here bring love
California it's dope love it yeah it's
always an adventure here there's like
we're close to the mountains we're close
to the ocean we're close to the we're
close to the Emerald Triangle uh we got
a little bit of everything and you're
going all the way up 101 and into deep
deep territory going in it's it's pretty
this is the time of year too it's it's
great you know the weather's nice right
now uh it's just the start of the nice
weather before the smells in the air are
amazing the different everything was
starting to Blossom and stuff it's
Oakland smells
amazing so if people were interested
finding out more about you where would
they go uh Instagram my personal
Instagram is Gast Town fire uh we got
Gast Town genetics is our genetics page
and Gast Town's Garden is our flower
page nice yeah awesome well I look
forward to seeing you in Thailand maybe
this fall and definitely a span of this
next year thanks me too can't wait for
it on the show man thanks for having me
brother
[Music]
heah