[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James Lab podcast
and today our special guest is JP from
the good pizza podcast how are you doing
today I'm doing good sir how are you
fantastic thanks for coming on the show
you have a great podcast you have a wide
variety of guests uh I feel like when I
was in Barcelona and they nominated me
for podcast the year I felt like you
should have been up there I just I have
a lot of respect for what you do you
have a great podcast hopefully I'll see
you on Barcelona this year you should
come out to span this I am bro as luck
we have it it will be my first year it's
amazing it's amazing and uh you know I
feel like there's a handful of us doing
a good job with podcast there's a lot of
podcast out there you're really you're
really hitting the mark with podcast uh
you release one a week you've you know
you're on what episode number 100 you
say you just filmed your 100th episode
yeah we just filmed 100 we're on 92
right now 92 live yeah yeah yeah but
yeah so we're on number 70
congratulations that's huge bro yeah and
it's a lot of fun we have a good team as
you know it's like so much bigger than
one person like without my team I I
wouldn't be able to do this podcast you
know we have so many people that have
contributed to getting us to the point
we're at our producers amazing yeah um
you know and then just working the
camera angles and getting the stuff all
dialed in it takes a lot of work and
time
absolutely bro yeah man congratulations
for all your success this studio is fire
bro it's a lot of fun
dude I gotta get my uh Studio together
man this is this is nice at least a
fridge [ __ ] well I mean it's one of
those things it's like we've gotten
things over a period of time but we had
an idea coming in and we executed on the
idea and it was actually a little bit
different going into it like we were
like okay well here's where we're going
to go and we went a little bit to the
right yeah and I think it turned out the
best you know we had we started with
different cameras and realized the
cameras we got weren't the cameras we
needed yeah and so these are kind you
know there's learning curves with
everything absolutely absolutely so and
then I did podcasts with the future
cannabis project in the beginning and
that was totally different because
during covid and it was all over the
internet I much prefer the in-person
interviews same bro same I I've yet to
do an internet podcast I really don't
yeah I don't want to do it unless it's
like a legend that there's no way I'm
going to see him right so in Europe or
Antarctica yeah yeah we can run it yeah
yeah yeah totally and those things might
happen but you know and they can be
great too one of our best episodes was
Reggie godino and it wasn't even the
best quality video but the conversation
was really good nice so but there's
something to be said about in person
it's more intimate you can smoke
together absolutely you can hang out you
learn more about the person you know
when you look him in the eye and you're
talking about it yeah for sure F the
energy you know what I'm saying see if
you even like this dude yeah you know
what I mean Just Vibe and build you know
for sure yeah so how did you get into
podcasting so I got into podcasting um
it was you know before I launched good
pizza the brand um I knew I needed to
create media around it and I've always
wanted to do a podcast like I always I
literally had a note in my phone that
was you know it was a podcast note like
if I would ever have a podcast what the
questions would I asked these all high
thoughts while I'm driving and [ __ ] I
put it in my note and then like you know
fast forward a couple years later when
I'm actually about to launch good pizza
in the bre market like really put it out
there um you know I've I've helped I've
helped build Brands I know what it's
like to get on the shelves and come off
them shelves like you can get lost in
the stack easily in California wck so uh
I wanted to introduce myself before
introducing myself so that was why I did
it right and I've I thought podcasts
were cool you know I mean I love Joe
Rogan and I study you know what I'm
saying podcast like and I didn't really
know what podcast what a podcast was
until like two years before I moved out
here I didn't know what that [ __ ]
purple app was on my phone no idea what
that was bro and then I tapped it one
day and I and I fell in love bro so long
story short um I started the podcast um
and I really wasn't taking it too
seriously like it was just really for
the brand but then I you know I started
get some cool guests and then one day my
homeboy Paul from proper doinks told me
while we were smoking he's like yo bro
you know you're you're literally
documenting the end of cannabis
prohibition yeah like when our grandkids
grandkids watch these [ __ ] videos
they're going to know how it went down
who was there who had what strain like
bro you're literally documenting this
[ __ ] for the game bro I'm like and it
[ __ ] me up yeah like it totally
shifted my whole paradig like I'm like
damn I got a civic duty now [ __ ] you
know and yeah we have this duty to tell
a story it's so much bigger than anyone
person and that's the beauty of these
podcasts is like this is the information
100 years 200 or 300 years that
hopefully they'll be able to look back
on and go that's what happened in this
moment exactly exactly and I feel like
this is a big turning point in cannabis
yeah I mean over the last five years
especially it's been pretty wild it's
not very stable you know we're both in
the California market and it's like very
unstable and it's kind of hard to
predict what's going to happen next but
it's great getting all these different
opinions and stories and legends you
know it's like you've had some Legends
on your show definitely bro you know
I've been blessed to have some Legends
on my show and it's just you know
Richard delisi spent 32 years in prison
and that was one of the life-changing
episodes for me and it was like I I got
some great ones with other people too
but that one had a lot of impact on me
and my Outlook why we're doing this you
know absolutely man that one kept me
gring I just interviewed him two weeks
ago so that was my interview last week
and it was incredible bro like you like
you said man like this is that's Uncle
Rick bro he's such a character too he's
the man I'm like bro you're not from C
you're not from Florida bro where are
you from he's like I'm from Brooklyn I
was like I knew he was one of the guys
bro oh yeah I was like there's no way
with this [ __ ] accent this guy's from
Florida then we like we started talking
east coast and all that [ __ ] I'm like
dog you're a legend bro yeah I mean his
stories are legendary you know and it's
like they I can't wait for the
documentary to come out on him and they
need to make a movie about his life
because his life you know he was in a
time where it was way different than it
is now it was way more illegal you had
to have way bigger balls and the the the
punishment was way bigger yeah and then
even with him it's like they threw the
book at him and they didn't even have
any real evidence right you know it's
circumstantial [ __ ] all circumstantial
it's crazy this man 96 years 98 years
yeah 90 some odd years and then he
served 32 years of of almost a 100e
sentence it's like it's kind of
mind-blowing that you could put someone
in prison that long for that yeah for
this plant and I think as cannabis is
becoming normalized people are starting
to realize that [ __ ] that that was a
mistake that kind of stuffff is wrong
yeah bro you know at least I hope I hope
even my parents you know they live in
Texas where it's very conservative but
Texas is changing the landscape's
changing over there yeah bro for as
legal illegal as cannabis is in Texas
them boys got balls of steel how they
moving over there bro you have to you
have to they're moving mean in Texas bro
well they have you know they
circumvented the law and you know and
worked within the loopholes right and so
there's all these CBD shops and so they
don't have dispensaries they got CBD
shops and they're all selling thca yeah
you know and it's they've got big Brands
over there you know crushing it yeah I
love it I love it too and I mean that's
like the loophole for legality and I
think it's also a great way for the
general population people that live in
Texas to get acceptance over it because
everybody's going in there buying it you
know they're selling sh tons of flower
hell yeah so it's yeah it's pretty wild
I mean all these states and how we've
been maneuvered and the the problem with
California is taxation absolutely
absolutely unfortunately Triple Tax bro
to the max Triple Tax Uncle Sam is your
Silent Partner Uncle Sam ain't my uncle
yeah he never came none of my cookouts
right but uh yeah yeah [ __ ] that bro
it's
crazy yeah so what got you into
cannabis well uh I my journey started
pretty early um I was the youngest kid
on my
block single uh single mom situation so
you know she was working nobody was
watching me you know I grew up in the
90s I'm an 80s baby so you know nobody
was watching me youngest kid on the
Block and uh I so like naturally got in
the [ __ ] early yeah and um it's funny I
was just I was just in Jersey for like a
little Friends reunion and uh I was with
the dude that smoked with me the first
time you know what I'm saying right and
I came through with all the weed all the
shrooms and [ __ ] like and he's looking
like you little [ __ ] stop trying
to corrupt us I'm like corrupt me [ __ ]
I was like you you smoked the joint when
I was 11 bro 11 what the [ __ ] you was
like 17 fool what the [ __ ] you talking
about eat those shrooms fool uh I
started smoking weed at 11: I fell in
love with it immediately um I really
started smoking heavy when I was 12 and
I never stopped bro so the first time
you smoked how did you smoke was it out
of a can was it out of a pipe you take a
bong RP what was it it was terrible we
had no we had none of those things no
rolling papers no nothing like yo go to
the store get some napkins so I went to
so get some napkins and they rolled it
up in a napkin and they [ __ ] lit it
and it's all falling apart I didn't even
get [ __ ] I didn't even get high bro
yeah um probably didn't even know how to
inhale you know what I mean totally but
second time a can Coca can Coke can yeah
I don't remember the can but I do
remember it was out of a can yeah and
that got that got me high yeah bro so
the first time I smoked we were smoking
some bammer I I don't I don't think I
got really high I was like running
around like we were high but we weren't
really high and then when I really got
high for the first time I was like oh
that's it yeah so but I tried a bunch of
acid before I takeen acid like 10 times
10 times what and then cuz I was I was
into sports I was at the bay area so I
was I was born in Portland but I grew up
in the bay and so there's this huge
Grateful Dead Community Inay area so
acid is everywhere right and so it was
this little piece of paper and I'm like
well that couldn't be so bad so I tried
the paper and I was scared of smoking
cuz I was running cross country in high
school and I was sucked at running cross
country I was I was a bigger kid and
trying to run and so I was like oh if I
smoke it I'll be even worse and so I
held out and then eventually I smoked
and I was like oh I found my calling you
know it's like nice dude and and all my
friends we all smoked it was like
everybody once we got exposed to the
good stuff especially it was like oh
that's all it was hard to go back yeah
you know we had the bammer we had the
brown weed the Mexican stuff that had
lots of seeds in it uh proto pipes were
big we had those uh pipes that we'd Buy
in Berkeley that had the resin chamber
and put the butt in there and it would
get all resonated you smoke the resin
yeah yeah yeah I remember yeah good
times good times bro you know and it was
super illegal back then people were you
know they were getting in trouble you
know 90s I smoking the first time I
smoked was 91 okay and uh started
growing grew in a closet nice dud um and
evolved from there you know into a
garage closet to a garage garage for the
longest time I was scared to go to like
Warehouse grows yeah and my buddy who
went from growing in my garage with me
went into a bigger space 50 lighter
which was huge for the time this is like
that's big early 2000s he had a
warehouse he got busted at the warehouse
so I'm like oh I don't want to do
Warehouse that's too crazy and this the
the thing is is like you could have a
eight lighter in your garage and be
extremely profitable it was making good
money and uh yeah it was interesting
times we had amazing genetics back then
you know what were you running I started
growing in my garage we had had
blueberry we had this Oregan blueberry
it wasn't the DJ Short it was the spear
blueberry that we grow real tall they I
didn't realize they were going to double
and so we vegged them a little too long
and then they grew up into the lights
you know and then we had uh Trinity we
had chem dog we had Sour Diesel we had
OG uh but even before that there was
like the spaceship the Romulan the
shaman uh Jack herrer there was a Jack
Flash that my friend grew that was
amazing and everybody kind of grew their
own things you know we grew Bubba for a
while I was a huge Bubba fan me too I
still I just got some I got some Bubba
down here actually I got some Bubba on
the way to my crib right now shout trap
Jesus D I love Bubba cush and so we we
had like the master of the Bubba and
then the OG came along and before that
it was like the Hindu Kush I was kushes
in the 90s I remember bro I wish I had
Hindu cush so all the ogs on my show
yeah that their faces just like that
look up into the sky they're like yeah
man that Hindu cush BR it so good like
Fields MOS Skittles uh my old Co co-host
Jamie [ __ ] whoever bro
hind special so Hindu and then we had
cat piss around the same time in the the
mid90s I I got it turned on to cat piss
that's fire and that was what changed
that changed my perspective on ugly weed
too because it was the ugliest yeah it
was the one we used to get was just
shreds in a bag it was like little pules
right so you were getting these little
bracks a lot of times stringy Str but
the smell and it was so strong the whole
room would smell like it you would uh
smoke a joint your hands would smell
like it it had like this ammonia skunk
and it wasn't gas like not gas it sour
ammonia it was yeah it was really really
pissy piss oh yeah like real piss like
literally but one tenth of a gram would
smell the whole room like literally yeah
you could have a tenth of a gram and you
go home and your parents would be like
what's going on you know what crazy like
I know I had it right but like I I got
it on the East Coast um and like this is
before like we had names on bags and
[ __ ] this is probably like
06 that was the first time I ever seen
it and I and looking back to it like
that was cat piss bro like nobody ever
told me it was cat piss right but like
dog I smell like piss it was ammonia it
was I've never seen anything like it
that had to be it yeah $60 a straight up
um and I the thing is is like so cat
piss is the
description of a smell and Aroma right
so I think there's multiple cat pisses
what people think of cat piss there's a
you know SoCal cat piss NorCal cat piss
there's other cat pisses I heard there
was even cat pisses back in the 70s
right there was a cat piss so I feel
like it's a description of an aroma so
there can be multiple copies it's not
like blue dream which is a specific name
right sure uh so I feel like there's a
lot of arguing going on online like oh
yeah I had the real cat piss well you
did have the real cat piss for you but
that doesn't mean it was the only cap is
right so same thing with blueberry it's
like there's there's a Canadian
blueberry a DJ Short blue blueberry and
the Oregon blueberry and they're all
extremely different uh in structure
smell and taste I just got some Canadian
blueberry the other day okay it was
phenomenal it was phenomenal buron it
was really blueberry as much as the DJ
Short or as much as the organ H yeah it
was blueberry turps like blueberry TPS
to the face the last time I seen
blueberry turps was semi- recently um
cam was running some something blueberry
that just brought me back to like the DJ
Short Blueberry if that's what I had I
had it like one time in my life and DJ's
was short and squatty right no no this
before I even seen a weed plant bro like
East Coast days like we didn't see weed
bro it was just finished product you
know I'm say totally yeah so what was
the first stuff you were seeing around
on the East Coast so first stuff is
obviously um you know Mexican brick I'd
say the first cool thing I ever saw was
like Jamaican red hair yeah um you know
I was like [ __ ] 12 13 years old you
know what I'm saying so uh you know that
was like the first time I was like wow
this is different I'm super high and
then like like one homie would have like
a [ __ ] up little shady Graham and a
cigarette cell Fane with California kba
yeah what's that what does that mean
kind bud what it's from California holy
[ __ ] and then we smoke a little ass bowl
of it between like five people yeah you
know what I'm saying and like oh my God
this tastes amazing oh my God I'm so
high how am I so high off one or two
hits this is [ __ ] crazy you know what
I'm saying and I [ __ ] me up and then
it was on from there it was on I was
looking for it like what whatever I
could get like from California like
whatever kba what whatever the [ __ ] that
was or we call it Dro like any good weed
we' call Dro yeah I don't know why this
is what we called it KGB Dr we had we
had a lot of nicknames and beers you
know a lot of beers came through um but
yeah like the first dope weed like I
don't know what it was cuz we didn't
have names for it like that was like
some you know some dope California kind
bud and then uh the hazes came through
you know what I mean the hazes were like
the first thing that stuck like purple
haze cub and black Haze you know I'm we
we would skip school drive to Washington
height so Spanish Harlem bring my boy
Puerto Rock he speaks Spanish you know
what I'm saying he do the deal we get a
bunch of Dimes like 20 dimes and go back
to our town and S for 20 right you know
what I'm saying just a quick bubble up
stupid little kid [ __ ] you know what I'm
saying but uh but I realized really fast
like how quickly you could be the man in
your town if you had something that
nobody had you know for sure and I was a
young boy I was the youngest kid always
the youngest kid in my crew and uh you
know I would see the the tables turned
like some older homies want to hang out
with you now like what the [ __ ] right
this shit's got power bro yeah I was in
Boy Scouts when I was a kid so okay not
say anything bad about the Boy Scouts
but there was a lot of action going on
the Boy Scouts with weed really drugs
and alcohol and everything yeah it
wasn't what people I mean and there was
a good sign you know and I don't think
of cannabis is a bad thing but
definitely there was a lot of weed
getting passed around and that's where I
got exposed to it too and the Boy Scouts
shout out to the Boy Scouts dude the
best stuff came from uh one of my
friends Mr Scott in the Boy Scouts he
was yeah senior patrol leader
heuck baked in the wood had some High
Times him and his brother were going the
most killer weed no [ __ ] back in the day
yeah and I mean unbelievable High Times
winning Cannabis Cup seeds is Le at
least that's what they had told us you
know really good stuff that's right bro
so yeah you reminded me of a storyit me
the first time I went to uh New York on
a trip as an adult was 1999 and I was
going there for work okay and I uh was
kind of by myself and I went to this
restaurant called Nooks that was in uh
by the Empire State Building okay and
this dude named Jimmy the Greek own
owned nooks and we were talking about
weed and next thing you know he's like
oh you want to hang out with me and my
friends I'm like if I can get some good
weed so he takes me out and he gets me
this white bud I never seen white weed
in my life it was the whitest weed I've
ever seen and the story this the BS
story which most likely BS was that it
was grown in the sewers with the
alligators and that's why it was white
because of the lack of you know [ __ ] out
yeah yeah but everyone goty white or
like the weed was white the weed was
white it was the white it was so it was
like light bur but it was so white I I
actually flew back home with it I put it
in a pen cap and flew back home with it
because I had to show all my friends
yeah yeah and so we had to get it out
with you know you had to get a needle to
pull it out and I had this little tiny
piece of it to smoke with my friends
like the whitest weed I've ever seen it
it got me really high okay so it was
probably lightburn looking back at it
you know what I mean but like it was 100
bucks for a gram and yeah and so if
anybody knows where Jimmy the Greek is
man I'd love to talk to him Jimmy the
Greek do you know how many Jimmy the
Greeks are out there yeah but this Jimmy
the Greek own Nooks Cafe oh copy copy
copy so we can find him hopefully you
know and and I think with 911 Nooks was
long gone after 911 I got you yeah
unfortunately wow but yeah good times on
the Coast there was always good weed man
that's the thing about New York right
you you you're guaranteed to see
guaranteed to see something crazy or
something crazy going to happen like if
you just do in New York like weird [ __ ]
happens in New York it's a [ __ ] crazy
City you know what I'm saying the best
city in the world and I remember I
remember my first experience like seeing
something bugged out kind of like that
in New York with my big cousin Denton
and uh I'm like [ __ ] 12 13 he's like
16 17 18 some [ __ ] and uh you know he
wanted to get some shrooms he's like y'
I want to get some shrooms bro we going
back to my mom's crib in Jersey My Boy
Bobby across the street like they were
tight they was the same age I was
younger and uh we're just chilling right
on this on this stoop smoking a
cigarette and this dude comes up to my
cousin this weird ass Shady [ __ ]
white dude he's like goes to my cousin
like yo Jimmy right he's like yeah
what's up fool and I just chopped up
he's like yo what's up I'm trying to
find these shrooms he's like y'all got
some shrooms I'm like what the [ __ ] saw
my cousin shrooms right on the street
thought my cousin was Jimmy whoever the
[ __ ] that was and like I'm like like yo
how the [ __ ] did you manifest that bro
what the [ __ ] dude and uh that was just
like some Rando ass New York [ __ ] like
some 1990s [ __ ] you know what I mean
NYC [ __ ] Bro crazy yeah the 90s were a
special time I mean the genetics were
way different what was popular in the
Box was pretty much everything that was
good it didn't have to be purple didn't
have to be
candy either one no really I mean candy
a little bit but there like Juicy Fruit
there was like some juicy fruit dop yeah
and there was some sweeted do sweet more
sweet fruit AF goey so AF go is kind of
sweet like that was that was you know on
the sweet fru right and uh you there was
a handful of things that were sweet and
as far as like meno perss we used to go
to Menino and get purple weed so yeah
that that was around back then we never
seen that back then we' have lost our
[ __ ] minds if we seen purple weed bro
oh yeah and there was definitely that
was like $4,500 a pound in the '90s like
outdoor was as expensive or more than
indoor you know especially the good
stuff I I just I remember the outdoor
being so amazing back then um and I
think there was a lot L there was there
was a lot less of it than there is now
yeah same thing with indoor and I think
there was a lot of people that were
super passionate about it like you had
to be more passionate about it because
you were taking more risk way more there
was so much on the line and there were
still people that grew mids I mean I had
friends that just grew mediocre yeah and
I feel like there's this ego thing that
when you grow it yourself and you've
been with the plant for that long and
you harvest it that you take pride in
however you did I still have some
friends like that and their stuff is
mid-grade and it's hard to recognize
sometimes when your stuff is mediocre
and I try to be
very subjective you know with and honest
with people too for sure you should be
when I'm growing it's like I constantly
am trying how can I make this better
each time I feel like it's never good
enough I feel like the best Growers out
there they're never fully satisfied with
each run there's always something they
could improve on a little bit and know
what else they want your feedback if
you're like a real curator like myself
and other people like with brands that
give a [ __ ] about equality yeah like
they really do want your opinion like we
set the Eagles aside like you got to set
the ego aside and look at it separately
100% like when we're fena hunting right
for example we're going through you know
700 plants yeah it's a lot of work but
like you're really trying to find the
best of the best and the only way to do
that is be getting getting uh honest
feedback from people yeah so and also I
quit giving people flour I'm done with
giving people flour with pheno hunts
it's like you get joints we're going to
give you pre-rolls you're going to tell
me how does it taste and how does it
make you feel yeah those are the two
most important things and flavors are
especially hard um in a feno hunt in a
feno hunt because a lot of stuff looks
good you want to you want to pick one
that looks good to I mean look is
important yeah don't get me wrong bag
appeal is extremely important unless you
got Skittles unless you got Skittles
unless you got Skittles yeah Skittles
goes a long way because it has like it's
like you know kind of ciss it's like
they doesn't have great bag appeal but
it also fetches high dollar right now
yeah it does it does for sure five in
the street 10 in the bed man it's pretty
wild it's pretty wild and you know and
it's not easy to grow and so I feel like
that's one of those ones that deserves
more money you deserve more money for
growing it you know so for sure so what
do you think about all these Skittles
cross
the diet Skittles there's lots of diet
Skittles have you seen anything that's
as good as Skittles that's across the
Skittles nope have not and I'll tell you
what um I just interviewed Ted from
Alien labs for the second time we did it
round it was my first round two episode
he said it the best and I never even
thought of it like this shout out to Ted
he was like bro why are we chasing all
these [ __ ] Skittles crosses bro
there's nothing better than Skittles
Skittles is there it's at the top how
you how you going to beat the top yeah
you know what I'm saying like why are we
trying to do it like it's if it ain't
broke don't fix it now I know what we're
all thinking and I was chasing it too
and I've I've done pheno hunts with Z
crosses I popped hell of [ __ ] of Z
crosses like bro they just don't do it
bro like well going through Skittles
s1's is silly in my opinion because
you're not going to find anything better
than the original Skittles you might
find some good stuff and Skittles
crosses you you want something that's
completely different or it's not like
moonbo is really good I like moonbo uh
from archive I feel like that is a great
SK awesome yeah
uh and rain shadow runs from can
Organics up in Washington uh we got
those seeds on the website that that was
a little collaboration thing we did with
uh Kyle and Tim from from H
squim they I got cousins in swim bro
that's crazy dude their facility is nice
like yeah their their green houses and
outdoor grows are Barone the best in
Washington flavor-wise dude the stuff
Burns good tastes good nice checks the
boxes it's great seeing people grow
organic um I got a handful of friends
that grow really good flower in uh
metric up in Washington and they're
definitely one of them you're the only
other person in the world I ever heard
heard say the worst squim wow because
like that [ __ ] is like it's the smallest
little town like you got to get across
some body of water to get there type
[ __ ] Che out this one this this is like
what I'm excited about as far as like if
we're going to be in like a skittles
cross kind of situation yeah that shit's
super unique it's called um so that was
a collab a breeding collab project
between third gen and landre Indian yeah
um this was hunted by kadre Verde the
homie Trent from kadre got the seeds
kadre hunted it they selected the number
15 it's really called Superman ice cream
yeah number 15 nice um is blue sh by
Eddie Leo by rainbow Bells 2.0 so
there's like Z in there way the [ __ ]
down in there but it's super complex
belts um I actually was able to give
some of that to Fletcher when I finally
met him in New York for 420 nice I was
happy to give him some of that um hope
you liked it bro and uh it's dope bro
it's different I mean I'm [ __ ] with
it yeah you know I'm I'm we're trying to
bring some light to that flavor you know
and people seem to really like it you
know I just I just feel like I just need
a name change cuz ice cream tripped me
out I didn't want to nobody likes ice
cream what I'm saying bro it's it's sad
cuz I think really good ice cream cake
it's good yeah there's nothing wrong
with really good it got flooded on the
market and so same thing with wedding
cake right really good bready wedding
cake that's gassy and bready yeah I like
it I'll still smoke it I enjoy smoking
same uh and then ice cream cake makes
great extract like the rosin is
phenomenal if you do it right if they
pick it early like I really like that
flavor and then same thing with the
flour if it's done right but also I
think there's a lot of inferior cuts out
there and there's a lot of people
growing shitty versions of it and then
it puts a bad name out there absolutely
absolutely so and then jbz he released
wedding cake seeds so there's all these
phenotypes right there's 30 different
pheno types out there that people are
growing when this all started I'm pretty
sure that went out there okay well
that'd be the only explanation for why
there are so many pheno types unless
they're s1's for sure for sure so yeah I
mean I think that wedding cake is the
best example because there's three or
four decent ones there's one that's just
phenomenal that smokes amazing it
doesn't yield as much as like the ones
my buddy grows he they yield like crazy
they look really really good but it
gives me that purple punch let down
which I I mean I feel like that's the
best way to describe it yeah they go a
little longer too right they do a little
bit longer yeah yeah so what I moved
here cakes were still popping bro cakes
were [ __ ] nice and greasy and just oh
yeah alien Labs had a dope cake yeah
yeah yeah for sure yeah shout out to
alien Labs they've been crushing for a
long time you should get Ted on the show
bro absolutely he's [ __ ] the best
interviewer bro yeah I've seen I've seen
your interview with him it's great yeah
he's good man he's good yeah that in the
Caleb interview was was great one you
just Caleb was phenomenal yeah thank you
bro I really enjoyed that thoroughly I
actually got to get up with bro yeah
good times man it's it's fun being able
to hear different stories from different
people and get a different perspective
it is especially that group yeah yeah
yeah I mean like that was like Turning
Point cannabis World [ __ ] you know what
I mean right and those guys are working
with some of the best genetics out there
I feel like they understand cannabis on
a level that's much different than a lot
of people yeah and also the business
side of it yeah for sure I mean how much
do we learn on our podcast about
business about like I'm I'm there for
you guys but I'm really taking notes
like I'm I'm I'm like really interested
like Ted Caleb burner I just interviewed
yesterday I'm like really asking them
like yo so how'd you do it yeah tell me
about the corporation how do you form a
corporation how do you do this how do
you do that like I'm [ __ ] like dog
you did it bro I want to know yeah he
did it he did I mean he's proof he's
proof that anybody can do it and like
back to what you were saying like these
interesting people like you know let's
talk about like the whole how the cookie
[ __ ] went down like you know I think you
should get interviews from burner I
think you should get [ __ ] I think you
should get shinsky I think you should
get flux uh straight flame um and Caleb
out of all those stories who was off and
Kenny Powers and Kenny Powers especially
like he he don't want to hop on yet you
know what saying get that's cool that's
cool soon or later soon or later but um
you know if and they're all different
versions of the story obviously cuz
you've seen it through your lens but
like you'll get like the the big picture
you know what I'm saying when first
smoke did the all their interviews like
I would tell people like yo you really
want to know the cookie story tapen into
these these podcasts you got to get in
all those guys perspective each story is
a little bit different exactly exactly
so yeah and that's the beauty of this
whole thing is like we're able to get
these different perspectives from
different people and opinions and we all
have a different lens that we've seen
the world through because we've all went
through different things sure and uh
yeah and it we're we're in an amazing
time cuz it's not stabilized yet we're
not sure where it's going genetics is
still we're scratching the surface of it
it's not fully patented yet it's you
know people aren't out of the game
because they don't have money you can
still be an amazing breeder and do it
with a small handful of plants if you
know how to grow really well definitely
and at the end of the day it's all about
like can you grow really well and make
the plant Express so you can tell the
difference between the phenotypes yeah
for
sure so and there's a handful of people
doing it right and there's a bunch of
people doing it so I yeah so and it's
like and it's so subjective too to what
good genetics are but I think we could
probably smoke a handful of joints and
agree that these ones are all great and
these ones are all mediocre and then we
might have a difference of preference at
the top so yeah yeah like uh White Ash
what's your opinion on White Ash White
Ash is the last check box bro um we got
to get off that [ __ ] bro it's so much
easier to sell weed without this white
ass [ __ ] [ __ ] uh can we curse on
the show we can say what the [ __ ] we
want 100% [ __ ] right yeah um so
white ass right so I look for four
things right and um I'll give props to
proper doinks for kind of
like enlightening me to these things
like I always knew they were there but I
never knew what to look for so like I go
by um flavor translation strength of
Flavor Flavor longevity is big for me
cuz I don't like joints that like taste
like [ __ ] halfway through I feel like if
you got a joint that tastes like [ __ ]
halfway through I just sold you half an
ounce for whatever I sold or a half e
cuz you're not going to smoke the whole
thing I'm not smoking that bro um and
then so after flavor flavor longevity is
smoothness yeah you know what I'm saying
I don't want a throat roasting joint you
know what I'm saying it's burning super
hot um and then once when all those it
seems like when all those things check
the boxes holy [ __ ] the white is the ash
is really white yeah you know so and
that's you know combustibility it's not
always the case but a lot of time I have
some some genetics that just do not get
white ass yeah yeah yeah for sure
they'll be salt and pepper Sal pepper
they be though no they will not be
that's a yeah they will not be black
ain't nothing wrong with a little Peppa
no you know what I'm saying but like
look is if it's burn white do I get
excited [ __ ] yeah I can make the video
people get pumped up they want to buy
your weed you know what I'm saying
that's the world we live in right now
yeah well you can add a couple points on
that pound right you [ __ ] can dude I
can't even sell it if it's like that
like I've create i' pigeon hold myself
in this little [ __ ] connoisseur
Corner yeah you know what I'm saying and
like it all has to Che out but like good
pizza is also a standard of weed like
that when it goes through all the that's
my QC process then it's good pizza and I
put it in my bag if it don't it's a work
pack right you know yeah I mean I I
think that's a good place to pigeon hole
yourself in though it's way better than
the other direction yeah the bottom is
rough right now the guys are just dying
off left and right and it's it's really
hard to
maintain uh a product where you're in
competition with these guys that can
produce for $250 a pound exactly $300 a
pound so why would you even want to be
there now is the time where you gota you
got to be on the other end of the
spectrum if you don't have the best
product there's no reason really doing
this anymore no there's not no there's
not and the korur market is the 1% 10%
whatever you want to call it yeah um but
that is a significant amount of people
based on how many people smoke weed you
know what I'm saying yeah and um and you
can still get tickets in that world you
know and uh I did brand at the [ __ ]
perfect time you know thank God bro
thank God I did because you selling bags
bro you chasing 25 cents nowadays bro
yeah you know you get a box play with
your men's y'all split in a quarter or
50 cents maybe maybe nobody's getting
dollars no
more maybe I mean they are so they are
but those are the ones that that aren't
working in volume right the guys that
are you know the boutique guys that are
like okay $4,500
$4,500 right so like those guys are
still making two point like 200 points
I'm making more than I sell [ __ ] box
bro I sell a [ __ ] five pack for sure
you know it's crazy bro yeah I know it's
it's a wild world and it's it's still
the Wild Wild West it's it's it's wild
you know and the thing is the same thing
with genetics if you don't have the best
or something different like you can't
just do the same thing as everybody else
anymore that just going to fly like if
you haven't figured that out as a
breeder that you can't just go make
another gelato don't do it there's no
reason even doing it you're not going to
get a lot of money for your seeds U
unless you're making really really
stable seeds that you can throw acre
worth of seeds out you're not going to
have intersex trades like there is
market for that but there's that's a lot
more different yeah a lot more difficult
than it is to make it make a cross
making something that's super stable
that you can put out in a field it's not
going to Herm out I mean that's that's
challenging uh there's a lot of R&amp;D
involved there's a lot of work and time
and energy and that's why I get money
for my seeds that you know that don't
have interex traits they go you can put
5 Acres out or 10 acres out and reliably
get a good crop absolutely so and we do
have some of those gelato turps you know
and but but that's the difference um and
moving forward it's like you want to
have something that's going to separate
your customer from everybody else yeah
so my main job is to empower my
customers to grow better flour to get
better results and have something
different and so it's exciting to me I
like banana I like banana turps I like
too man yeah happened in banana OG that
[ __ ] was crazy it was so I have I have a
banana that's amazing too so it's a
banana OG times banana punch times times
Skittles it's a banana Skittles ni and
so I got reg seeds of it I got a ton of
them we hunted them up in Washington at
House of coltivar I work with a lot of
Washington Brands TR and so my I'm from
Oregon originally Portland Oregon but I
have friends and family up in Washington
so I love Seattle I love squim I love
that area you've been to squim I've been
to squim many times yeah I got some good
videos yeah I love squim you got to go
can Organics so Kyle he's another one
you got to get on your show yeah is that
where he is that's where he's at he's
[ __ ] s just talking about Jordan's
boy oh yeah yeah yeah bro stop playing
with me bro he's in squim he's in squim
they have like the organic my cousin bro
Hees cousin a grower up there if he he
might even work for Kyle godamn you
never even know but uh you know it's
like and these guys it's like this
banana Skittles is pretty amazing right
this we call Banana Skittles and you
know the banana runs candy it's more
banana runs candy than the banana runs
flour really yeah but like the yeah so
they have this it's a fake banana it
washes really well washes it like 5 and
a half per let's [ __ ] and the the
rosin tastes like banana candy and so I
made a bunch of crosses with this too so
we've got okay cross with Fort Collins
cough Kim 91 apples and bananas oh uh
dude so many different really really I'd
like to buy some of the seeds off you
boss yeah yeah I got some for you yeah
if you want to hunt through those seeds
I got a ton of really good stuff to hunt
through I got two Farms like we're doing
a lot of pretty much 89% rosin
production we got to yeah yeah yeah so
I'm going to St Vincent I originally
made the seeds to take to St Vincent and
the Grenadines which is a Caribbean
Island uh I went there with Marlon aser
he's a reggae singer good friend of mine
yeah yeah I know him I know of him you
got to get him on the show too he's
another he's like one of my best friends
really PL me up bro oh yeah for sure and
so he took me to St Vincent one of the
poorest Islands I've ever been to not
even one it was the it was my exposure
to what real poverty is right sure sure
type [ __ ] and how happy the people are
that are living in poverty yeah you need
to see that as an American you do and it
made me realize that maybe I could do
something to help these people out their
economy revolved around bananas I was
like let's make some banana crosses so
we are going to go give the minister of
Agriculture banana crosses 20 of them in
seed form to give out to the people and
so this was my idea with Marlin years
ago and finally with Co it delayed this
whole process but now we're going out
next month to give these seeds away oh
that's so cool man what a contribution
to the game and Humanity bro I feel like
that's what we all need to do is figure
out ways we can help other people step
up and you know and I think there
there'll be some media coverage but it's
not even about that it's about being
able to give something that can Empower
other people to make their lives better
definitely bro so educ congratulations
on that project man that's cool and it's
a lot of fun I mean when you're giv back
like that whatever you put into stuff
like that it pays you back tenfold
absolutely bro absolutely yeah that's a
that's a nice little check mark on The
Good Karma side of life you know you got
to do stuff like that you know and so
Canadians there was a bunch of Canadian
LPS that went into St Vincent and
Jamaica and all these others and they
were all about making money and so
they're basically trying to take out of
the island off of the island they're
trying to extract money off of this
thing and it's like I don't want to be
that guy I want to go in there to help
the people I don't care about the money
there like I If we don't make a penny
which I assume we probably won't yeah we
we'll get some good publicity and stuff
but we're going to do the right thing
and we're going to help people that need
help hell yeah you know and there's a
lot of people this is only one Island
there's people all over the world that
need help and we We As Americans have
the power to make a difference we do so
what's the weed laws like on St Vincent
can they cultivate cool yeah and they
have medical licenses so yeah they have
dude they have a they have a spiritual
license too like a yeah it's like is
that bro like a religious license
because Canabis is a religious thing
thing yeah and so yeah they have it's
biblical son dude it's amazing that's
how it should be yeah bro for real we
went there and spoke to uh the Cannabis
Authority which is their governing body
for cannabis yeah right so Marlin and I
was It was supposed to be like a 30
minute little lecture who we are
whatever it was a three-hour lecture wow
and they kept raising their hands asking
more questions and I was like can we
just keep going because this is great it
was the first time in my life where the
government was like and this is the
government right there people from the
government that were like we want to
make our people better how can we do
this and I was talking about pollen
mitigation I'm like you don't want
regular seeds on the island necessarily
you want to get rid of males because
such a small island there has to be
pollen mitigation so you don't pollinate
people's crops sure that was one of the
things we talked about and then they
wanted to know about indica and sativa
and THC levels and so I was like THC
isn't the end all be all which I think
is extremely important especially from a
medicinal level right uh but the people
of St Vincent and the government there
is really into the medicinal side of it
and how can they make their people
better how can it benefit their people
in a good way and so even the minister
of Agriculture there amazing guy we get
to meet him and sit down with him last
time and so I'm looking forward to being
able to sit down with him again and
presenting him with some seeds nice dude
that is [ __ ] incredible bro yeah
congratulations thank you yeah no it's
it's a lot of fun and I mean it's just
it's part of why I do this right I feel
like at the end of the day I got my
breeding book too I don't know if you
seen the book but I got I got a book for
you so we we wrote a reading book we
published it and I mean we because it's
a much bigger project just like this
podcast and myself yeah and so 380 pages
I had over 20 contributing writers that
contributed little pieces oh cool photos
we got some piff in there we got some
Cuban black Haze let's go bro hell yeah
we got those in tissue culture as well
so really yeah so we'll have them out
probably I'm thinking within the next
month and a half two months we'll have
plants of piff let me know I guess I'm
might run a couple lights that for me
bro I know that's what you need just a
little smoke right just a little
something for the head bro and I really
like piff I fell in love Cuban black is
okay I like Cuban black is that piff
that's what that's what I'm I'm hearing
is piff so I believe what you think I
think the piff is the S1 of the Cuban
black okay these are two different
plants they're genetically different oh
yeah you got yeah I forget you you got
so we we work with my fla and stuff like
that right and and we're able to do some
testing we can tell that these plants
are different right okay um now how
they're related I'm not sure but I
believe that one of them is an S1 of the
other one I believe that the piff is
probably the one that we have is an S1
of the Cuban black okay and it's really
good and I feel like it's not one of
those sativas that shoots you off like a
space rocket you're not shooting out of
a cannon if SM you get high bro you you
get high but it's more subtle right it's
not like the super silver it's not like
smoking that it's it's got a you know it
doesn't burn it doesn't burn on the P it
burns tasty all the way down to the
roach and it's it's like a little tiny
bit floral a little tiny bit Haze it's
got its own unique thing going on we
talking about super silver I'm talking
about the piff the piff yeah yeah yeah
for sure it's like incense nog Champa
kind of like spicy peppery TPS you know
what I'm saying and if it's grown
correct it right down to that roach
though it tastes good oh yeah and you
can I can smoke the whole thing where is
this super silver if I'm smoking myself
and I smoke a big joint like this yeah
it's like I'm smoking it down to about
here by myself right so whereas if I
smoke Skittles like this I could smoke a
couple of these you know oh yeah just
sitting and hanging out yeah that's why
I was telling you like I smoke Skittles
and fugazi on my show bro that's like I
could smoke them all day I don't get too
high I get right just right could keep
flowing you know what I'm saying for
sure yeah I mean uh my buddy Kyle and I
we did a show and we smoked some of his
strawberry cough and I could tell that
he harvested it extra late you know how
like if you go past the harvest date a
little bit or where you could Harvest it
it's stronger oh yeah right even
Skittles if you go 63 days or 65 days
longer and stronger and that Skittles
especially Skittles you got to take 52
to 54 I'm all about that 53 53 somewhere
anywhere 52 56 even is fine B difference
dude and it's the difference if you want
those melon turps or if you want the gas
cuz that gas comes in a little bit later
we don't need the gas bro I don't I
don't think o o k for if you want that
it doesn't make me feel as good like the
effect if you were talking about the way
it makes you feel I don't like the 63
day Skittles I don't think it makes me
feel as good whereas I like that 50 and
I love that taste where you just want to
keep hitting it you can keep coming back
to it you can fire the roach up the next
day and still smoke it yep you know
that's the beauty of that Skittles too
and uh it's it's something special oh
for sure for sure I mean dog it's it's
still the big dog on the Block gelato
come and go I mean I mean runs is still
here but runs you're not getting tickets
for runs yeah like everybody runs lcg
right like so yeah yeah so let's talk
about that for a second runs LC because
you're familiar with these these sex
tests and like what's what genetically
runs okay gelato 33 lcg go runts lcg
depending on who you get the cut from
they're I mean they're they're slightly
different cut slightly different but I
think they all came originally there was
runs and there was one runs and that
that cut got renamed to lcg and then
they got another cut that they called
runs and then there's the gelato 33 Mis
label so there's a lot of stuff that's
gelato 33 out there like there's a lot
of stuff I mean I've seen the I've seen
the actual test that this and this and
this and this they're on the same side
of the equation the white yeah white
runs yeah and then also so gelato 33 is
the most unstable of anything I've ever
worked with and so when you make s1s of
it in the sense that genetically
unstable so what happens is when you
make s1s you get all these different
Expressions across the board uh SF Cana
has several different ones that are just
s1's of gelato 33 with different names
on them and they're completely different
Expressions no [ __ ] like Cherry guava
completely that that cherry guava is
different but that's special that's
special bro that's so good see that's
something bch that bro holy [ __ ] I was
supposed to have some today but their
grower he uh wasn't a he's busy he's
busy in in the lab yeah yeah yeah but
that's some of my favorite especially
the last batch of it that just came out
is like I seen in a minute bro used to
be it's as good as it was but it drips
you know you got the drip on it got the
white ash it checks all the boxes and
then it tastes like candy you know and
that's special but they have like Mount
Fuji and gelato X and I like bunch of
them I just never liked it it but those
are all gelato 33 s1's oh no [ __ ] those
are just s ones of the to my knowledge
those are all yeah and there's there's
seven of them or something like that
they're out there they if you looked at
them side by side you'd be like oh
they're completely different but really
they're like sisters yeah yeah for sure
yeah that's cool pretty wild yeah so in
Ju like that and I like the 41 A Lot
41's the king bro 41's the king and 41's
a breeder so that's that's the breeder C
right time Skittles makes amazing stuff
that's that's extremely special Yeah
well yeah I know one of our I I can't
really say I don't know if this needs to
be said or supposed to be said but your
boy Kyle yeah bred something that's
super special that was a 41 Z that's
yeah that so that's the rain shadow runs
yeah we sell seeds of that I still have
some of those left F serious so good
I'll give you some I think we're selling
for 500 bucks a pack on the website we
we sell them occasionally I'll give you
some to Fen hunt it's I'm F hunting some
right now I'll tell you where I'm bring
it after the show it is so good tell
exactly where I'm bringing that [ __ ] bro
yeah and it's in that one that rain
shadow runs checks all the box that's so
crazy you said that's really what it's
called I want to say it so bad but I'm
not we'll talk yeah yeah I know exactly
what you're G to say you talk about so
but yeah and there's a bunch there's
there's there's a bunch of them that he
feno hunted the glue Lotto is special
too that's the Gorilla Glue times gelato
41 oh that one's crazy that's that P90
bro yeah and then that that King Lou
times gelato yeah well the gelato 41 it
adds that one super stable and it adds
this amazing flavor where I feel like it
can make if you phenoh hunted correctly
you can find ones that are the the
flavor you're looking for but more
intense sometimes than the original yeah
so yeah man shout out to 41 man shout
out to 41 that's been like yeah that's a
a staple and just the straight 41 is
amazing too you can grow it you can
smoke it I feel like fairly easy to grow
good some of you know some like Skittles
is hard to grow there's a learning curve
with Skittles gelato 41 I think a lot of
people could get that cut and they could
do pretty well with it yeah so just like
blue dream that's another one it's not
my favorite TP but it grows really well
it looks beautiful yeah when I started
growing out here um I crushed a run of
outdoor 41 bro I bet C I was so proud of
myself I mean to bomb the next round but
sure whatever bro I was like had that
run bro I thought I was the man yeah
then you know you learn so what about OG
you seen any good ogs lately no sir yeah
yes yes um tril Kimber that's floating
back around us that's up in sack right
now there's a facility rocking that I
had some really good a good batch of
that um also trip XX OG uh White Ash is
running that to make OG great again yeah
um he's got a little make OG great gang
campaign that's grown by kre Verde and
uh trap Jesus is supposed to have some
[ __ ] crazy ogs I have some on the way
so I'll let you know next week yeah
Brian from vital you ever get him on the
show he'll give you the real OG flower
like he grows it where is he where's he
Valley so he's not too far off he's a
really good friend of mine he grows
really really good OG TV is my second
home BR they crush it they crush it with
the OG his you know vital and then same
thing you need soil he's got really good
soil Okay so yeah he's my go-to him and
Royal gold are my two soil that's where
I get my yeah Royal gold that's where I
rock yeah yeah good people good people
too I never met them but yeah we I do
boosts with them and stuff we reg in the
river with them were you yeah yeah dude
you got to go next year I got to go bro
I went to um Tahoe reggy Fest yeah yeah
yeah that was cool but dude reg on the
river special and so I'm gonna be
working with canif Fest next year and
we're going to have an area and we're
going to be doing podcast so if you want
to come up there to do podcast for show
that'll be tight bro the invite right
now so cool man and that's at regga on
the river or can same thing canest so
canest is actually in a couple weeks
since in September regga is usually the
first weekend in August in August got it
so yeah and I'll be up in a couple weeks
at canest as well that's it's going to
be a cool event tight but yeah reg on
the rivers classic they had the best
sound system I've ever heard for an
outdoor event no way and then just the
most amazing artists Good Vibes Good
Vibes River four days of amazing four
days I went four days so I went cuz I
had a booth we went we went in on th and
then we stay till Monday okay so really
it's kind of like five days but like it
was amazing how long is the actual
Festival though was it three Friday
Saturday Sunday by satday I can do that
yeah and there's amazing artists I'm a
little older now bro I like party we got
VIP camping dude so it's we got the nice
it's under a 10 I'm a chef too so it's
good food yeah yeah yeah I used to be a
chef yeah we always got I mean I make
the best pizza too is that right so I've
been having this little debate with uh
Obsolete and mango and my
who makes the best pizza yo mango looks
like he knows what he's doing bro don't
sleep on in Florida boys bro telling you
right now he makes the best K zones I've
heard cuz because he [ __ ] his pizza up
so he has to flip it
over so yeah no but I'm I'm telling I'm
challenging those guys to a $500 Buy in
bet for who cooks the best pizza I think
I heard about this did I see this on on
Instagram you totally did yeah so I
think Sergio's in on it we're trying to
get Sergio he went to culinary school
he's a chef too so it's like I think
we're going to do some fun either here
here maybe your your spot who knows I
got a portable Pizza Oven too I got know
I got a nice Lounge in my spot bro to
set the pizza up right down outside I
Crush some good pizza I do thin crust
I'm all about the thin crust u i i do
Detroit too but Detroit's like easy
that's in the oven it's it's it's hard
to make a really good Detroit though
like you got to do it in advance there's
a lot of time and effort that goes into
it bread it's lot of bread dude it's a
lot of bread to eat yeah and I don't eat
a lot of carbs myself I try not to bro
yeah it'll [ __ ] you up it's like I've
been good on my diet though I'm down 30
lbs of of weight but I put on over 10
pounds of muscle so I'm down like 40 lbs
of fat nice dude congratulations man
look good man it's exercise dude
exercise is the big thing so for me it's
weight what do you know yeah who would
have thought little exercise yeah I mean
I diet too I mean dieting but when you
exercise and you show up at the gym it
makes you want to diet on top of that
yeah you don't want to eat [ __ ] no and
I'm getting older so now is like I'm
like I don't know how many chances I'm
going to have left to like lose the
weight to be in health you know thing
you in your 40s 47 yeah okay so back
half I'm in the back half and I'm
looking at it like that and I you know
some people look at it like oh we have
all this time left I don't feel like
that at all I feel like no dude time is
very short my time is limited here to
get all the stuff done that I want to do
I mean I I'm pretty ambitious as a
person and I have a lot of goals that I
want to do in my lifetime and it's like
there's no better time than the present
to get on those things because you never
know how much time you got left that's
true true man and you know it's a
beautiful time to do stuff too I feel
like uh you know we a lot of people
think that the world it's getting worse
and worse and worse I don't think that's
true I think it's getting better in a
lot of ways I think the economy's [ __ ]
up yeah I think there's stuff like the
economy but I think other than Oakland
it's a lot safer in most places than it
used to be Oakland's dangerous bro I
don't think there's any laws in Oakland
bro it's so crazy crazy yeah San
Francisco is pretty bad too it's like
but not like Oakland bro no nothing
nothing's like Oakland I won't work
there right now and you know I mean
there are people that can work in
Oakland safely but I'm not one of them I
don't feel I don't care to no no I don't
I don't want to expose myself to that
kind of danger I'm in and out yeah I'll
go visit I'll go visit I'll make day
trips but but yeah it's it's wild but
shout out toak man like dude they still
got amazing Wei coming out it's a
[ __ ] it's a cool like I come from a
[ __ ] up place too you know what I'm
saying and it's like there's Beauty in
that too you know and it creates
beautiful people and like tough people
and like you need tough people to like
people especially yeah I mean I think we
got a lot of snowflakes now I know bro
and I'm from Jersey we break balls as a
sport bro it's like a sign of affection
Right totally until you go [ __ ] yourself
like you're probably my man's yeah you
wouldn't say that to just
anybody it's like I don't know it's
different times man whatever you got to
adapt you know but yeah what is it
saying like uh Hard Times create soft
men soft men create hard times and hard
times create
or whatever it is you know no you got it
you got it and it's a generational thing
it's three generations well so my my
father's generation they were tougher
than Nails you know but but I feel like
my grandfather's generation was even
harder and tougher you know it's like
those guys you know it's like they're
fighting the wars bro The Real World
Wars real world wars the poverty was
different like the depression you could
go hunt for your food too you know I my
father he came from North Dakota right
okay and so they they they hunted for
their food a lot of times my grandfather
could hold a 100 pound Anvil out
straight so when I was younger yeah so
my he was he was like 61 62 probably
didn't weigh more than 185 190 PBS but
he was strong you grew up on a farm or
something fary strength right same thing
with my uncle my Uncle Cory could hold a
100 pound Anvil out and lock his elbow
toss you across the room and toss you
across the like a b yeah you know what
I'm saying and in my father's generation
my father was tough I mean I remember I
saw my my father fight you know I saw a
lot of that growing up yeah my father
was tough really tough and you don't see
that you can't fight like that anymore
people have guns people have knives
before people would get a problem you
could duke it out in the streets that
was just you know that was the way of
life that was cool man should should
stayed like that well people wouldn't
talk as much [ __ ] either you know it's
like they they're hiding behind their
little keyboard and they want to say
some [ __ ] and it's like I was just
saying that way here bro like yo I was I
could tell that dude I ain't been
punched in the mouth in a couple years
you know or if ever if ever you know
what I'm saying a good punch in the
mouth let you slap slap this sound like
a good slap bro come on so getting back
to
cannabis so I need to know your three
favorite cuz you ask everybody their
three favorite yeah yeah for sure so
you're you're modern you're Classic and
your desert island all right for sure
okay so back in the day we're going to
go
sour um desert island we're going to go
Skittles and some
new ah man the one's the tough one cuz
that's where all the you know so much
new [ __ ] right yeah so let's go uh candy
fumes times permanent marker nice Dave
from preferred Gardens uh bred that he
got some good stuff on 50 fenos bro and
um I've picked i've smoked probably 20
20 and change of them yeah I got five
[ __ ] hitters in my notes and he's
going to run one of them for me
hopefully to 49 I think I got I think
I'm locking in the 49 for the
brand tried 11 coffins of the coffin
candy from planta yet literally my
favorite candy coffin candy is literally
my favorite candy that and Warheads but
I think cough and KY cuz just a little
different um and they've been crushing
the batches bro shout out to the homies
shout out to Derek gar der's coming on
you had Dereck on yet yeah yeah yeah I'm
looking forward to have Dereck we had
Freddy I've had Freddy fredd Fred that's
the homie he's actually coming to my
show two weeks he's oh hell yeah hell
yeah I actually you know shout out to
Freddy man I asked him I was like yo bro
I just you on the podcast what's it like
bro you [ __ ] with it like how was it
he's like bro it was the best production
like experience I've ever had um he gets
first place for smoking the most on my
show oh he's bro he's he's one one the
one of the ones that come through with a
Jar full of joints and right after
another do he chilling he's chill he's
chilling bro he's smoking dude yeah I
remember his first episode bro he came
through and [ __ ] just blew it down um
he knows good weed he does bro he does
um does good business he's good dude man
solid dude uh definitely guy better
friend than enemy I'm sure oh yeah he's
he's a big boy he's a fighter you know
yeah he's cool bro
um yeah man what what were we saying
right before that I had something to say
before coffin candy oh yeah no no coffin
candy so you said 11 coffins so I got to
give a shout out to my bro um dirt road
Exotics yeah um my bro Mike um I'm
rocking his 11 coffins in my brand I
actually just finished it up um he
hunted some seeds from Duke of herb yeah
and uh found his cut or his his fenos uh
the number I think it was number one
feno oh bro it's [ __ ] F dude it's
like rs1 on [ __ ] steroids bro it's
everything you missed about the original
rs1 drop so I'm sending you home with
some rs11 from tissue culture please bro
rs11 from tissue culture so different
than rs11 when it first dropped uh so DP
the Clone drop well
not the big clone drop but when they
were growing it when deep east wizard
trees do I think they were all growing
it right originally when the packs first
dropped and they were like 4,500 yeah I
remember remember that uh it was the it
was the wakeup call for me on like I
need to step my game up uh because I got
a bag my friend gave me and it was all
graded this is when they first started
really grading where it was
like and also God you there was no big
buds there was no Smalls it was all even
across the board and they were all
perfectly shaped round buds in the bag
and it was the best graded I've ever
seen all bees sh I like bees honestly I
like bees a lot 4500 and I I had to get
it and it was like oh this and the thing
is the nose hit you like it was like ice
cream on the nose with a little gas on
the back and it it was a little floral
it was like floral ice cream with this
gas on the back and I was like that's
freaking amazing and it's worth every
penny
but whatever happened along the way
whether there was different genetics or
whatever I feel like it changed and it
wasn't like did bro quick yeah quick bro
people think it's the Clone drop people
think it's this and that I think when
they scaled it too I think scaling it
doesn't always work I'm not sure but we
got it from tissue culture uh we tissue
cultured it and I got it for breeding
and I I like that a lot I like rs1 a lot
I like z a lot but there's two Z cuts
too that go around oh really let's talk
about that that bro yeah Z is it's good
two Z cuts for real I I believe there's
two Z cuts and I haven't I I got to get
deepe I get a Rob on the show or
something like that to verify but yeah
there's definitely like a
spear Z and then there's like the more
rounded bud zope and so I've seen both
of them and I think they're both good in
their own ways see I never really got
into Z like everybody bro it doesn't get
me hard like that bro it's it's just a
it's a flavor it's a flavor Chaser you
know you know what's crazy like let's go
to RS 11 for a second right you know
when somebody tells you something that
you never thought of before and just
[ __ ] the whole thing up like a nice
meal or like y I love this dish like yo
you know what's it call it's in it and
you're like [ __ ] really yeah and it just
[ __ ] with you forever it just stains
your memory in your palette right Ted
[ __ ] Ted alien Labs we were talk to
rs1 one day like not too long after a
drop he's like bro that shit's diet
sherbet I'm like oh my God and I haven't
been able to shake it since and that's
kind of like when it kind of started
being whack I'm like man [ __ ] rs11 bro I
hear that a lot but I was exposed to the
best rs11 packs that came out when it
was all small batch right they were rele
handful it was so good same uh but s
smoking it I I have to say I love good
sunet Sherbert the real deal uh I was
getting packs off shinsky in 2012 13ish
[ __ ] go dog so so I was getting him
from shinsky right and uh they got over
to Barcelona and wow they started seed
companies off of bag seeds that were in
that sherbet oh my god there there's
there's some seed companies that built
their brand off
ofc Inc the stuff was so good I mean it
was sticky it never really fully got its
day and there's a lot of people like bro
cuz gelato came right after bro right
after and it kind of just took over yes
right but but sherbet deserved its day
way more bro yeah and I mean it'll never
get it obviously because now people are
kind of hating on it a little bit but
man it is amazing
it is just as amazing as any one of the
gelato cats in my opinion I like it
better than gelato bro to be real I like
the taste of it I like the taste of it I
like the effect of it yeah same bro like
the like the I think the last batch I
went [ __ ] psycho over was um loud THC
yeah and how THC was growing this this
sherb and it was just [ __ ] incredible
bro I got it from Exotics 916 and he his
favorite [ __ ] sherb and like yeah I was
like Jesus Christmas
am I never heard diet sh but I say diet
sour a lot cuz all the sour is like bro
there's no gas diet Skittles that's new
what I've been hearing a lot Skittles
there's so much diet Skittles on the
market and and it's all garbage yeah bro
it's garbage I hate to let anybody down
but it is what it is bro it is what it
is like the truth is is like all the all
the Skittles crosses pretty much there's
a handful of them like moonbow rain
Rainbo 2.0 is okay but moonbo is amazing
like that moonbo that that from Flor and
Flame that's it's so
tasty but uh there's only a handful of
them I remember the first time I smoked
the rs1 though got me so hot it tasted
so good bro tasted so good from Friendly
Farms came through and burned it with me
and I was like bro what the [ __ ] is this
this is it yeah I was like oh my God and
I you know the little [ __ ] weed
nerded me I'm on the hunt now yeah and I
just I can't find this one where is it
at bro these are not right what batch
was that what [ __ ] grow what camp did
that come out of I'm saying yeah bro
well then I think Z there there was some
hand handful of batches that came out of
Z there were phenomenal too and then you
know Z got a little bit of hate but Z
was popular when it first dropped it was
huge like that that brand blew up it's
not getting tickets no more bro no it's
it's [ __ ] flooded bro no super
flooded I got some stuff to show you
look at this Che out there bud that is a
dark nug my friend what the [ __ ] is that
bro that's some purple sand that's the
scariest looking nug I've ever seen that
is the purplest it's the purplest that's
yeah that bro this [ __ ] is
black yeah I mean I used to have a pink
panties that would get like that too
really but yeah the the [ __ ] that's
that's purple sand it should be called
black
sand oh that's
crazy what is what is it I'm not sure
I'm not sure I got the contact for the
guy who uh is The Keeper of the cut wow
and so I'm looking forward to getting
that in rotation I want to do some
breeding with it with my autos
that's crazy looking bro wowzers oh can
I roll up some of this right here
absolutely this [ __ ] triple [ __ ]
quadruple back cross [ __ ] Z 4X so
yeah shout out to lire Farms this smells
amazing smells amazing it really does it
does have a nice smell I like that name
I'm treez this for Z's I like it
creating names is not easy anymore a lot
of people don't understand how hard hard
it is to come it's like I got my gp3
it's my Gary pton cross okay okay yeah
but uh but yeah I mean we've got a lot
of names the nice thing with loud is I
can put it on the front if somebody else
has it and I really like the name I
could just put loud on the front of it
oh that's tight bro but that's tight but
yeah I mean there's so so many names
have been taken and it's like you you
don't want to step on people's toes but
at the same time if they don't have a
big following or if it's not a really
popular genetic if it's old it's kind of
tough uh especially in my opinion
especially if it's something that
describes
the smell or the aroma or the flavor
perfectly I feel like that's the first
goal right when you're when you're
selecting names like that's the first
goal okay can we name it after something
that smells like or tastes like right
but then like sometimes that doesn't
always work and then like okay I can go
into desserts that's [ __ ] dead yeah I
can go into the Italian stuff cuz I'm an
Italian brand right we can go down that
lane but like a lot of the good names
are taken bro I feel like I got a Frank
Rizzo right Frank Rizzo Frank Rizzo
Jerky Boys oh my God Frank Rizzo I don't
even know if anybody else's name did
that but I got a Frank Rizzo and it's
it's yeah man so look that's what we
need bro we need the weird randos that
that's what the game needs cuz the names
back in the day were so much better bro
so much better they were so [ __ ]
random yeah I mean Romulan Alaskan
Thunder [ __ ] like give me a better one
than that train wck come on do people
getting
creative and you know and that was in
the beginning the breaths had a cool
series Hogs breath morning breath breath
peanut butter that was a cool series
meat breath Grandpa's breath Grand yes
bro that was cool man motor breath
[ __ ] motor breath motor breath was a
good one I still like motor breath I
haven't seen it in a while oh kadre got
it motor breath 15 they're still running
they got a couple nights to that I love
the taste of that I love the effect yeah
bro yeah Donnie Burger was one of those
on Donny Burger was fire I don't know
why that didn't get that that was
another one get got Johny Burger live
rosin oh it's fire dude so the [ __ ] I
was never really impressed with the
flower with the Donnie Burger I was like
it's all right I got
some well he' given me a bag of flour
and he's like it's so good you got to
try it and sometimes when people say
that they you're under impressed with it
like I was I was expecting something
else cuz I'm like GMO you got to like
GMO though right I do like GMO okay got
you got you got you but when he gave it
to me I was like eh it's all right it
was cool it's living soil so sometimes
living soil you know I think there's a
learning curve with it with or whatever
no doubt he gave me some rosin Chris
from flora and Flame gave me
some and freaking it is phenomenal it is
some of the best rosin d i was judging
the can ofest rosin entries and I use a
turp uh freaking nectar collector for
entries for feel like I can go side by
side so I do my little I I first taste
them all then I line them up in order
and then I go okay number one versus
number two number two versus number
three and I keep going back and until
it's down to the order that I have and
then I write down all the different
things I like about him but I usually
try to put him in order like that well
his wasn't in the can of Fest entries
and I think he would have won first
place no [ __ ] that Donnie B and there
was another Donnie Burger entry in there
I'm pretty sure one of the other ones
was Donnie Burger but I have some GMO we
went GMO to Donnie burger and you could
totally tell the GMO is in there oh yeah
um but yeah it's it's nice it's got It's
got this
amazing uh lightly floral character with
this heavy gas and I feel like it's one
of those ones that the good rosin just
coats your It Coats your teeth even
you're like flossing and you're like oh
yeah you you tast it in your floss that
night if you take mouth coat man now
when you're doing a nectar collector
like are you checking temps or you just
just sizzling on it I do I or you have a
process second I know I I basically just
heat them up a little bit cuz I'm I'm
all about the cold sh dabs anyway so
normally you know I use my ays I use my
Carta the the focus V Carta 2 okay uh
and then I can set my temps with that I
quit using the rigs I have a ton of rigs
but I'm I don't use rigs anymore and I
got into them a lot this year dude
really I I'll probably get back into it
it's one of those things that goes but I
I do like the convenience of a digital
and electronic device and it's just more
convenient and same thing with dude I
was also training for the hot dabs
podcast so I had to like get my weight
up you feel me you yeah you Dr whole
month you do a whole month training to
get ready for this I can't do the hot
dabs I'd have to train for it like I
would you [ __ ] better if you want to
survive on that show it's a game show I
ain't no podcast it's a [ __ ] game
show bro it's the best those hot dog
yeah the hot dabs will just wreck me
I've never had so much fun on a [ __ ]
podcast bro it was insane
dude yeah there's a bunch of good
podcasts out there Kyle kushman shout
out to Kyle he's got a good one first
smoke of the day we all work with girl
world first smoke of the day you myself
I love feel like we're the guys space
bro yeah first smoke they're doing it
right yeah first smoke did it big bro I
feel like they did it first too you know
what I'm saying a good start on us you
feel they changed the landscape and made
impossible for us to do what we're doing
sure yeah bro for
sure but yeah it's it's interesting and
then you know Kyle kushman he's been
doing the podcast the longest I think
been doing forever [ __ ] man yeah and
he's the Strawberry Cough guy so that's
strawberry coughs for him well I learned
a lot about him on the first smoke
episode I always knew the brother's name
I used to hear his name in Jersey like
yeah yeah yeah Kyle Kush everybody knows
Kyle I was lucky to get him on the
episode I it was a really good we shot
back and forth uh when our guests talk
fast I talk fast and then it like we get
that energy going you know especially
you start smoking and then you just feed
off each other's energy and it's like AB
coffee and Joints it just builds up to
something fun you know oh yeah for sure
bro yeah don't mind me I just roll a
bunch of joints while we talking that's
always good I'll smoke them eventually
yeah this four Z's is good is that what
you smoke right now nice yeah I'm I'm
going light that one up first yeah lire
I I met him he's good friends uh with
black sheep farms who was on my show who
he's an amazing guy yeah tell me about
him bro so he's he's quite the character
he's a cancer survivor [ __ ] he's now a
bounty hunter he's doing bounty hunting
no [ __ ] I mean he's growing and doing
his seeds and everything but the dude's
a bounty hunter and he's just a
character he is the only one that scaled
the fence here to get on the podcast
what you mean his phone died and so he
jumped the fence jumped the [ __ ]
fence he jumped the fence what a Savage
bro I like this guy man yeah he's he
reached out to me man I just I never got
I never got a chance to get back to him
bro yeah Dylan is a he's an interesting
character he has great stories uh you
know he's one of the real Koval guys
like what's that Koval is a area of
Menino kind of by Yukaya oh he's from
Cali yeah he's from C well for sure
California he's Kelly guy sort of I
think he started East Coast too and
moved out here okay with his pops cool
man and uh yeah he's got some great
stories he's just a great person uh you
know he's different than your usual
podcast guest I need that bro I need
that once you get you know how it is bro
yeah yo I started smoking when I was 12
and then I got kicked out of school and
I start growing and I blew up my like
come on bro it's the same [ __ ] Bro
totally it's the same [ __ ] so we've been
fortunate to get a lot of women on the
show my first season I couldn't get
women to save my life and then I think
enough of them saw my podcast and now
can't get enough dude wom on your
podcast right yeah and there's so much
more chill dude like [ __ ] I like the
girl podcast man Maya from om was that
that's maybe my favorite podcast of the
year she's a she smokes hard nice yo you
know who I really enjoyed interviewing
Anna from [ __ ] cam D she has the best
energy I've never been so calm on a
podcast and every time that comes up I
say this like her energy is [ __ ]
awesome bro yeah she's chill she's so
chill and cool and like really about it
bro she's the [ __ ] she used to be in
a delivery service yeah in New York like
as a driver in the 90s bro you know how
[ __ ] shady that was bro I was scared
to even order from them I thought this
is crazy this is crazy I'm not ordering
[ __ ] delivery service you crazy I'm
go to projects and [ __ ] risk getting
robbed and uh to get some weed and do
that bro that was just nuts but she
she's really from it bro like really
from it like I was so impressed by her
story time for sure yeah yeah yeah yeah
for sure shout out
toout yeah dude she's a [ __ ] boss
dude they're cranking out she got a dope
ass team they're all happy as [ __ ] to
work for like I I I really appr respect
and look up to her for in that regard
you know what I'm saying that [ __ ] is
dope bro yeah there's some women out
there that are just crushing it right
now killing it bro killing it I'm about
to drop a podcast with um Jasmine Adam's
wife from uh paper doinks nice yeah you
did one with them together right yeah
yeah a couples like a power couple those
are fun dude you get a cool Power couple
on here so I love the three person
interview I love I love the dynamic not
but I like it now I I learned how to do
it I was the same way at first I was a
little nervous about doing two people
and then I like the dynamic I've had
some really good ones with Steve
D'Angelo and uh Uncle Rick and then
Steve and first Monon from Jamaica and
then we we've had a bunch of good ones
we just had beanock on who's that uh
dude these guys make some killer dry
nutrients uh that are basically pellets
that you time release and so instead of
feeding your plants you pH your water
and you just put them in and they're
good for the cycle what it's really cool
yeah I'll send you where do you put the
pellets you put them in the mix and your
in your uh in youry mix yeah like a top
dress you top dress you mix it in okay
got youx but yeah you can use them right
there beanock
beanock oh [ __ ] shout out to n from
beanock yeah they do the the Dy we're
about to start using them they just came
on the show the other day so they
dropped those off I'm excited to see I
think it has potential I like testing
everything so for sure we had one of
their guests which was from Mother's
Magnolia in Oregon okay and they're in
Eugene and this guy swears by it he
grows amazing flower so I've heard and I
can't wait to actually go up there and
see it really soon but he's doing some
really cool stuff in Oregan and he
swears by it at his facility so you know
there's so many different ways to skin a
cat I'm so over uh being locked into yes
or no on stuff is a good I don't know
sometimes and this is one of those ones
you know it's like sure uh I think the
potential is really there I like the
concept and you know I like Forward
Thinking people that are like thinking
outside the box I mean that's that's how
we got here yeah bro we need Innovation
always bro there's always a tried and
true OG way for show and there always
will be but there's always room for
Innovation man when it's these guys that
are staying in their Lane and they're
perfecting it to the best of their
ability you know like the guys
enlighting you know it's like we got FV
right Bobby bags you know I feel like
Bobby man they're they're [ __ ]
killing it killing it that's what it
looks like and it makes the it makes the
industry better right it makes the
grower better like they've they've come
up with a solution that improves the
industry and so if you can do that if
you can make something that's not just
another copycat of something else you're
making that something that actually
makes a difference That's Where It's At
you're going to be successful absolutely
absolutely so yeah the guys that faving
are crushing and not for nothing bro no
if you're U if you're going to get into
cannabis if you can figure out a PIX and
shovels type of business yeah you're
better off way better off way better off
bro well unless you've been growing for
a long time you better hire somebody
that has because there's such a big
learning curve on quality I mean even
just understanding what quality means
takes a long long time I mean you can't
really explain it and show it to
somebody in a weekend mean Years bro
years ass dude yeah and and devel a
pallet not everybody can even develop a
pallette I feel like yeah true it's
there's you know you got to smoke a lot
and you got to be exposed to a lot of
different flour yeah you can't just be
the guy at the drro that's the buyer and
expect to develop a pallette like that
you'll you'll understand what good weed
smells like looks like maybe even feels
like but you won't understand the taste
and you won't understand the effect
you'll never be able to break it down to
people unless you're a smoker and a real
smoker like you have to live for the
[ __ ] yeah and it's not healthy you know
say like you got to know like yeah like
just like you said there's no other
better way to put it bro like you said
it yeah you got to put in the time you
got to put in the time bro and beat them
lungs up you feel me yeah for sure smoke
proper dinks I love it smoke proper
dinks kid yeah I get to get them on my
show we've been talking bro you got to
get them on the show we've had Chris
professional joint roller to Instagram
on the show who and so his name is Chris
his Instagram handle was professional
joint roller okay yeah I think I know
I'm familiar yeah yeah he does so he
does joint what I like about him is he
he's kind of hated by some of these guys
cuz he'll buy the company joints that
are like at at the dispensary and then
he'll cut them open and you get to look
what's in there oh I love when people do
that that need be done and he's just
sharing how much garbage there is and
[ __ ] gross I would say most of the
pre-rolls are just garbage there's a
handful of people doing it right but
most of them are garbage I'm not a huge
hash hole guy to be honest me Nei bro I
was at first but dog but I'd rather
smoke good weed and good rosin they T
like [ __ ] dude like after a while it
tastes like [ __ ] no well I can't say
that I can't say that if you use good
inputs yeah you can have them both good
and then you can have flavors that
compliment each other Skittles
complement everything yes that so that
there's that's the thing like pairing
the rosin with the flow like when we're
when we're really doing a project like
for my brand like we'll bring the flow
bring a bunch of different rosins we'll
have the RO it's like in my studio right
on the top floor we got proper dinks we
split a studio yeah other side of the
room is proper oh wow you know what I'm
saying if you notice we have the same
bricks yeah say totally so you got us
you got blueprint you got cgo you got
Bruno Rose you got Jake Rose you got
turkey bag Tom you got [ __ ] the whole
gang is up there you know what I'm
saying so so if you need some rolls you
got three [ __ ] the best rollers to
choose from you know what I mean so
they'll roll them up we'll smoke them
and uh what I found was after our last
project We Roll we had some rolls for
hash Island South cgo and his movement
um we did 1.5 G flour half gr Ro
and dog they were little they were
little baseball bats but godamn it
wasn't like the 2.5 with the five it
wasn't the the two with the five it
wasn't the 1.5 with the. three it was a
[ __ ] 1.5 with 0.5 and godamn that was
a good ratio yeah real good ratio and
they [ __ ] slapped then they drip like
crazy that white yeah we did Skittles so
we did half half Skittles and half of
these vanilla bean belts with a
forbidden
Punch or some [ __ ] from a show ganag
Guru you should also get on the show
yeah absolutely um great great dudes man
and great [ __ ] hash holes godamn yeah
I like the the taste of hash holes a lot
of times they're just too strong for me
too sometimes a lot of times they're M
too they they'll give shitts shitty
inputs yeah and if I'm gonna smoke
anything I want it to be good whether
it's flour whatever you know what I mean
at the end of the day I just want bro
we're old dudes man we don't got time to
smoking boo bro exactly so let's talk
about the perfect joint yeah since I
really have never talked about it on the
show but I feel like you'd be a great
person to talk about it talk to me bro
so my perfect is elements paper y i do
uh 10 mm or either professional or the
jumbo organ tips yep shout out to I like
those I like organ tips uh with the
paper filter in the end I do have glass
I have the glass uh tips as well but I
really like these organic tips I've been
I've been loving them since they came
out about a year and a half ago so I
order them by hundred and freaking go
through them and yeah before I didn't
like the you know there's some glass
tips I don't like I remember the first
ones be real be real shout be real he
[ __ ] pioneered that he dropped the
tips funky F tips funky F tips so I was
in Amsterdam in 2014 and uh I saw them
for the first time that was like he was
on tour with serial killers with exhibit
and demich okay which those guys are
amazing and got to hang out with those
guys in Amsterdam no yeah it was crazy
and then I got to see exhibit learning
how to roll a joint he knew how to roll
blunts but B was teaching him how to
roll joints saw yeah I saw that I
witness this whole thing at greenhous
greenhous coffee shop exhibit talking
[ __ ] you know and uh yeah and it's like
those guys were just super cool and they
you know it was really nice to hang out
with them and my friends I'm friends
with Arian and yoa from Greenhouse so
anytime you're in Amsterdam that's the
place to go and those are my boys and
they they've taken care of me forever
you tapped in over there I could tell
have you gone a lot yeah a lot a lot a
lot I spent a lot of time in kids bro of
course you did bro dude I spent a lot of
time in Barcelona and a lot of time in
Amsterdam and I try to spend two weeks a
minimum of two weeks in the spring
usually I try to get in a couple trips
in the fall I haven't been able to
because I'm so focused on the podcast
and this stuff yeah but I usually spend
a lot of time my friend s he's one like
he'd be worth getting a podcast that's
remote that'd be the one guest I would
say for you because he can't come back
to the States but he is a
in amer or if you ever go to amsterd to
go meet him he's one of those guys that
the one thing that you need to do when
you go to Amsterdam is goingon meet s
say l he's legendary so I might pop up
so I'm going to spanis and I feel like
everybody goes to Amsterdam for a couple
days after I'm trying to do that so and
I'm trying to do at least knock out at
least two three podcasts while I'm out
there you feel me so yeah man yeah
there's so many good shops I mean you've
had uh some great guests from Europe you
had Lorenzo shout out to
he's the man I've known Lorenzo
for at least since
2012 so seen Lorenzo grow up and he's
just he's a badass dude kill he's a man
bro's he's very generous he's got a good
spirit good heart very genuine yo his
bro Lorenzo I told you this before bro
your his hip-hop palette is crazy bro I
swear he grew up with me in Jersey bro
he's he's a 80s B he's not I don't think
he's 80s baby maybe late maybe late '
80s but definitely 90s but like dog dogs
New York hipop palet is [ __ ]
impressive yeah like he listens to
underground [ __ ] that i' be like yo what
the [ __ ] I'd be tripping him so I seen
somebody in California listen to that
right you know what I'm saying like I
[ __ ] with bro outside of
that killing it bro his love for
cannabis yeah you know it supersedes him
he's one of those guys I feel like uh
he's he's been in love with the plan
like a lot of us are you know and he he
really loves the CL he loves doing it
he's not here
he loves it dude yeah he's not here just
for the money he's here because he loves
it and he he belongs here and this is
where he you know this is BU like where
he's at in his career it's amazing
because I've known him for 10 years to
see him from when we first met to where
he is now it's so impressive no way that
he's did the the amount of grinding that
he's done and hard work and just
passionate in general and you know it's
like there's a handful of people I could
say I've seen them just really grow up
in the industry where 2012 they're
exploring and now they're crushing it
you know it's pretty amazing no see I
met him now you know the the dude he is
now and what he has established so
that's ill that he's been for a long
time too yeah that's dope bro that's
dope his story was great and we had like
the perfect episode bro like it was like
it was right before 420 like he was
about to leave I I locked in my bro
Sabino in Brooklyn he's got the grown up
Italian podcast there so he lets me use
the podcast St he's Italian nice you
know I'm Italian American Soo is Italian
as [ __ ] you know what I'm saying so I
was like bro this is amazing and they
both had like a best friend in Italy com
in common nice this rapper sere Basta
you know what I'm saying right right
right and like so it was it like how we
all came together and like got to do the
the podcast at the grownup Italian
Studio it it was [ __ ] perfect man
yeah he lost his [ __ ] turps in the
taxi no my cousin my cousin Anthony
[ __ ] hunted the [ __ ] Uber down got
his turps [ __ ] got Lorenzo back it
was perfect bro it was perfect and then
he went home same day nice yeah it was
dope World traveler did the these
Italian Guys I got a handful of Italian
friends all my Italian friends dude I
love you guys these guys crush it dude
crush on
the and yeah I mean weed and hash and
they're just they're the real deal when
it comes to Passion we talk about
passion for the sacred passion those
guys they're they're sweet you dude in
the the hash on the hash scene the
bubble hash my boys in Amsterdam like my
friends in uh Barcelona crushing it
crushing it the bloom room if you're
ever in Barcelona Bloom room they got
some really good stuff TI um herbalist
in the bloom room they got I mean
there's so many places I'm going to tap
in with you before I go maybe you can
give me a little route we all go to
dinners together so there's always
dinner parties I want to go them one of
them Dope ass dinners I see over there
bro like I know they look amazing yeah
the food over there is just next level
and it's like every meal is going to be
a good meal I'm only eating twice a day
right now right like two I try not to
eat out but over in Barcelona I don't
gain weight when I eat out it's
healthier you're walking bro youever
been to Italy yeah I've been to Italy
for sure you can eat as much pizza as
you want imp pasta it doesn't do
anything to walking and exercise but the
quality of the food is just the quality
bro the quality of the wheat it's not
it's natural wheat you know what I'm
saying for sure yeah bro it's not
sprayed with a bunch of chemicals no
it's not genetically modified to produce
bulk bro it's regular ass wheat that we
used to eat glysophates not putting any
of the glysophates on it's B no it's
amazing yeah man I love pizza and I love
pasta I mean you can't go wrong with
good Italian food can't can't I cook too
man maybe I'll whip you a meal sometime
yeah so what's your favorite
pizza man that's a tough one that's a
tough one cuz
like you all right so so I'm I'm Italian
and Sicilian right yeah so like there's
different genres right and on the
Italian side I'm naon you know what I'm
saying so where it originates so Napoli
style pizza I love Sicilian style pizza
I love like spinon youever spinon oh
know so it's like uh it's kind of like a
sicilian slice it's thicker but it just
has tomato sauce yeah um Romano cheese
and breadcrumbs on top nice it's it's
crazy um and then you got uh you know
come on the New York New Jersey slice
can't beat that with a bat and then you
got a New Jersey or New York Sicilian
slice yeah that I love like if I'm going
to a spot I'm like yo let me get a place
slice of plain slice of pepperoni let me
get that Sicilian joint but don't give
me a side piece don't give me that
corner don't give me that middle I'll
take a middle if I have to if the cheese
ratio is right you feel me but that's
that's my three go-to and give me a coke
I don't even drink Coke like that but I
need it with my pizza you know what I
mean I feel you I feel you got to have
something with the pizza yeah we're
already we're already doing dirt let's
just go all the way you know what I mean
seriously you might as well best pizza
me what's your what's your best SLI
what's the favorite slice the last one I
had answer I love pizza right so like I
love making pizza um my friends down in
Huntington Beach shout out to rip
Pizzeria so rip beer and pizza they have
a beer company is my friend Ryan TR um
um they do amazing Next Level Pizza his
Detroit is the best but like he has
classic like New York style as well nice
it's good um I mean I like Tony's in the
city there's a place called kappos
that's my go-to I about to ask you you
got to know about Tony's oh you got to
know about ton put Tony's against some
spots on the East Coast bro wow that's a
I know that's a crazy statement but bro
bro got it but yeah I mean I like I like
Hawaiian pizza too I'm not going to lie
I'm totally down with Hawaiian pizza
California boy you get a pass bro
exactly yeah I mean yeah so when you're
smoking where's your favorite place to
go
eat oh [ __ ] Bro depends on the vibe I
can [ __ ] up some pizza of course I could
[ __ ] up some I like Smash Burgers I've
been on the smash bur cake lately me too
you make them at home too hell no oh so
like next time you come here the kitchen
will be done I am I make legendary smash
BR really and you're a chef yeah dude I
love I love cooking I mean that's
cooking and cannabis go hand in hand I'm
not big on infusions like infusing my
food to C it's just not my thing but I
love eating really good food after I
smok weed like that's just yeah same
same do you like
Edibles uh from time to time the Edibles
hit me way harder than than joints do
yeah bro yeah way harder I get emotional
Edibles I realize bro I usually only
take him on the plane maybe it's because
where I'm traveling to I don't know I
get all [ __ ] goddamn emotional man
[ __ ] and some people can eat like 500
milligram other people are like 10
milligrams is good like I can't sleep on
more than 10 milligrams keeps me awake
really but if I smoke a big fat joint
smoke one of these I go right to sleep
I'm like 30 to 60 grams when I I just
eat cozy cubes that's all I [ __ ] with
they're 30 grams of cube I like the
Rosen gummies from Rosen Tech has these
rosin gummies that were amazing and they
were the white Thorn Rose oh [ __ ] yeah
you seen white Thorn Rose yeah I just
interviewed them yeah yeah John Cali
dude totally had him on my show he's
amazing great and that did he bring
flour for you yeah it's so good right so
it's it's ts are crazy I love it I love
it the turps are great the rosin's fire
too bro the Roos the purple rosin bro
the white Thorn rosin yeah crazy and you
know what's crazy about him we got the
same last name really my grandfather's
name is John casali nice yeah wow crazy
like my you know my mother's last name
yeah he was one of my favorite
interviews too he came on with Jason and
they did a great job so they they've
been making the circuit I think they did
first smoke of the day too are they
doing first smoke yeah I think they've
already done it so that would be [ __ ]
yeah nice did it air I'm not sure okay
for sure I'm not sure I'm not 100% but
maybe it was yours that I saw maybe we
did at his crib yeah we dropped the pre
the promo real yeah yeah we're going up
there yo you got to go up there and do
it up there don't do it here right we
did well we did one here with them they
brought the flower it was really good
yeah it was a great experience having
those guys down here but like it's hot
though it was hot I remember that being
a hot podcast yeah you know we timed it
right so we weren't super bacon but yeah
dog
it was uh yeah and I wear a black
[ __ ] shirt so my my one question that
I always ask all my guests is if you
could talk to your younger self and give
them one piece of advice yeah what would
that one piece of advice
be take more risks buckle up cuz shit's
about to get
real and it doesn't stop don't hey don't
stop don't look don't trust them
[ __ ] man when they show you who
they are believe immediately yeah and
[ __ ] Second Chances yeah you know and
always before you do a business deal
always ask people how they do business
if you've never done business with them
before yeah try to do a little
background check on them small enough
world right our community is a small
enough Community is yeah especially what
we do yeah yeah easy the background
check somebody this cuz somebody did
some [ __ ] they like oh [ __ ] that
[ __ ] you know what I mean yeah
seriously I mean and it's easy to find
people that have worked with people it's
one thing you hear something online it's
another thing you talk to somebody to
work with somebody and get the real
truth you know there's only so many
people you can work with not everybody
sells weed you know what I'm saying and
we all work differently exactly
exactly and there's only a handful of
people with quality remember that so
small handful small handful small
handful coffin candy though that's
that's the one I really like that coffin
candy I think that or the 11 coffins
that's probably the best thing I smoke
this year yeah right off the top of my
head I mean there's definitely the sour
diesel that I got again that that you
got to try some on give some that's
special so my friend Dave from balero
we're gonna do a drop we're talking
about doing a drop with the sour and
then if it works well we're GNA continue
to do drops with old school land race
different stuff he's from Mendo he's
like an unknown dude who's who's really
passionate and he you know I mean I
would say he's known within his
community a lot but he is I think he's
ready to come out and share his story
and share his brand with the world and
he's all he got African black Haze
that's amazing some Nigerian Haze fire
bro I've tried some it's similar to piff
it is a little stronger though man I
think so too and it's one of those ones
I feel like when you smoke it there's
certain it's a creeper some of these
ones are creepers right like you smoke
it and like it slowly lifts you up and
then a lot of times you think you're
only going to be so high and you just
keep getting more High yeah so and I
like that I like that sometimes as long
as I'm not on the podcast doing that
yeah right [ __ ] dude that reminds me of
back in the day bro like when yo it's
creeper weed watch out yeah I remember
like the real good weed would creep on
you sometimes for 15 minutes and then
you're like feeling the full effect
especially we used to take big fat bong
ramps we had like a 4 foot bong and so
we do huge bong RS out of this thing and
like that would get you high right away
but if you smoke some creeper you would
just keep getting more High your eyes
would get more red yeah good times good
[ __ ] times man good times well so if
people are looking to find out more
about you where's the best place to go
uh yeah YouTube uh we got a YouTube
channel good pizza good pizza podcast
good pizza media um it's with an extra Z
with tree Z's uh you want to go to I
mean our current Instagram isore good
pizza uncore the scammer has two
underscores in the front and back so
watch out um good pizza.com if you want
to get some merch good pizza with3
zs.com
um and then the good and just good pizza
podcast yeah with
trees good pizza podcast shout out to
Tera International yeah shout out
supporters of both of our Brands hell
yeah shout out to the homie man yep
United nutrients and kayak Coco man I
love them uh we've been testing him for
the like last few months and I'm super
surprised not even super surprised I'm
super impressed yeah you know it's like
I'm past that whole surprise stage with
my stuff when we're testing stuff it's
like is it good is it bad and we're
doing some trials with different
products I'm doing some uh really good
stuff with Char cor so we're doing Char
cor Kaa and Ka and I feel like I already
know the Char cor performs really well
ka's proven itself and now it's like
okay let's see with Cana we're gonna do
a test nice we'll see how they perform
and they're all slightly different
different consistencies different you
know and I think Ka is doing a 7030 now
charc cor is doing about to have a 7030
hit the market nice uh or either that or
they already have it but I'm I think
that's an interesting approach for it
and then can's like the original ka's
been there forever yeah so I'm big fan
of
Kaa we had Chad come on the show he he's
a character you know that was that was
another great show we've been blessed to
get so many good guests you got a great
show my friend thank you so much and
thanks for coming on the show dude I
look forward to uh doing this again
absolutely man ASAP for sure yeah right
on right on brother hell yeah
[Music]
n