[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James loud
podcast and today our special guest is
Christian from counterculture and
conception how are you doing today great
James good to be here dude I'm glad
you're here we've done this before on
the James loud show back in the day and
we've known each other for quite a while
we met through Jay before he passed over
a finest you guys were doing big things
yeah yeah it was it was a fun time with
him incredible person he was a valuable
contribution to the industry and and
just loved the plant loved weed he he
was yeah he was amazing and it's you he
would be in disbelief on some of the
things in the industry and other things
he'd be excited about so yeah yeah but
yeah and then you grew out some genetics
of mine back back in the day yeah yeah
back in the day at sour I remember
growing that for a while uh you know we
had a lot of in the 215 we had a lot of
sour heads and and not everyone wanted
to wait for you know 10 12 weeks strain
and the 78 sour had the the sour smell
it had the the structure and stuff and
did really well with that for a while
you had that nose burn that yeah you
just don't you don't get stuff like that
anymore I people don't well I think for
a while people didn't appreciate the
sour and then all of a sudden people
just want to purple
I think weed is is starting to become
like a fashion it's starting to become
cyclical yeah you know and to see you
know a lot of old stuff kind of coming
back you know like a lot of the new
generation whether just you know smokers
or or people in the industry haven't
seen a lot of the stuff that we we you
know grew in the past and and and got to
like and it's fun for that in the
industry being on the genetic side like
seeing you know seeing some of the stuff
come back totally I I just it's funny
yeah it's almost this algic some of
these smells that I've been smelled for
20 years and I smell it's like
unmistakable that it has this in it you
know whether it's the real thing or it's
a derivative of it you know it's great
you were talking about Urkel earlier
smelling something with Urkel in it and
it's like I love that where it's like
you smell it you're like [ __ ] that's got
Urkel in it or it is Urkel you know I've
I've seen both KKL Urkel's been going
around again as well yeah yeah that's
one of those ones that'll never
completely go away I hope yeah I mean I
think you know like you hit the nail on
the head that's nostalgic like for me
like when I've smelt some of these like
you know you brought me a super super
silver haze a couple couple weeks ago
and I was like you know like it it kind
of triggers a a memory or emotion you
know um for me A lot of times and like
it'll put me back into a a place and you
know it's it's special it's you know
breeding on the breeding side like with
the Urkel like I smell things and I was
like oo I want to try to pull that back
out deep you know Funk and you know like
purples nowadays like you look at the
color but like purple's like had a smell
too you know 12 15 years agic yeah I
mean before GDP was URL and it had that
very floral what you think of Purple
weed smelling like that's that's it it's
in there yeah and yeah it was it was a
good one didn't yield the best no still
doesn't but yeah I mean for as far as
expression it's it's amazing um I like
GDP too GDP is another one I don't like
grow GDP I I've complained about it on
the show many times about long it takes
to veg but the flower smoking GDP I like
the taste I think it's great heavy
hitter heavy hitter it's got that floral
like overtone almost and then it's
complex yeah it's interesting how it's
changed over the years with genetics
where there was a point where you
couldn't even sell purple to save your
life and then it went green and you know
and then cookies kind of brought the
purple back in the the color back into
it and then it evolves with gelato again
and then they said yeah let's get rid of
all the green stuff I remember some of
the first you know I think we've talked
about this in the past but like some of
the first breeding books I read yeah
like you know that was a recessive trait
wanted to actually select and get that
out of there you know and it's funny to
see because you know in the old days I
think the purples you know probably
weren't as strong you know and you know
nowadays like we you know definitely the
evolution people have you know got it
stronger and and you know frostier and
stuff like that but yeah I mean when I
first started doing selections and
breeding like was a recessive trait you
wanted to yank that out of there yeah
it's it's funny how it's so subjective
and flavor is so subjective and color is
so subjective to the individual and it's
it's funny how there's actually wheight
put on the color of it when it's
something that's supposed to be you're
you're looking for a flavor and effect
but you know people eat with their eyes
yeah whether it's food or whatever but
it's interesting cuz my friend just
passed recently and there's a couple
things I've been reflecting on his
memorial service was last Saturday and
his son and daughter basically made me
the steward of his seed collection and I
was going through the seed collection I
found seeds I gave him 10 years ago you
know so the the value of seeds are in
their use and not in their possession
sure and I'm sure there's tons of people
have given seeds to you that have a
gerum and so many people have given me
seeds that I have in germinated and it's
it's really a trip with that but he was
so heavily focused on Flavor over the
last month since he passed on 420 I've
been you know reflecting on the
importance of effect I've been focused
on Flavor heavily focused on Flavor as a
chef I'm all like Flavor Flavor Flavor
and so effect has kind of gotten
sidelined a little bit I mean of course
I want to feel good when I take it and I
talk about effect but I think it should
be prioritized to a certain degree this
white Thorn Rose that's that's popular
now and if you have a chance to to get
it it's an amazing thing to try it has
an amazing effect even beyond the fact
that it's purple rosin and purple flow I
mean that's cool but the effect is it's
feel-good wheat at the end of the day it
makes you feel great you smoke it you're
like wow I feel good I could take on the
world it's not going to have that
narcotic effect that some people are
looking for it's not going to have that
crazy sativa effect but it has this
calming out almost but like makes me
feel really good yeah enough on my rat
uh what do you breed for a lot of Tarpin
you know the effect as well to like you
know I've always tried to to to look at
it as like something that I want to
smoke yeah you know I grew up in New
York so I I love gas uh I don't think
that's ever going to come out of me but
I do love I love the fruit you know the
last couple rounds I've been breeding
for for hash I have a couple Farms up in
Nevada County and for the last couple
years I've been breeding for hash and
selections for hash and you know like
with the state of the industry it's
tough for some of the smaller Mom and
Pops you know like I know there's always
the the back and forth of is it indoor
better is it outdoor better you know it
but like I think there's a whole
community that has been growing some
amazing stuff under you know light PES
and been doing a lot of selections for
for for things like that to get into
people's hands and and the whole hash
lines and stuff like that so I feel like
a lot of the profiles I've been you know
everyone's kind of playing in this one
little area I've been trying to get out
of that area you know like a lot of the
GMOs a lot of the papayas and stuff like
that like I want to explore and try to
get some bigger yields hash yields and
and just have some new you know new
profiles so I've been kind of focusing
on that for the last couple years not to
say that I'm not you know breeding for
for flower as well too but that's kind
of been yeah you know a little niche
that I've been trying to hit and you're
doing your selection in Greenhouse for
the most part yeah I don't have an
indoor right now so I kind of rely on
you know some indoor Partners prefer
Garden's been working with David for for
years now nice he does a lot of
selections for me and you know like I
always try to get it into multiple
people's hands to see if I'm right or
wrong and you know like I think you know
our pallet sometimes you know for me I
lend towards a gas and you know not
everyone wants the gas right now too so
um you know part of it is also once I do
the selections we put in in tissue
culture and get it out to the masses so
it's you know like I need multiple
validations I also work closely with
Anna from cam you know she's running a
lot of the indoor stuff as as well as
some other smaller indoor Partners in
Sacramento as well really cool yeah yeah
I think the more data you know from the
nursery side of things the more data I
can get to the cultivators and and hand
it over the more successful they're
going to be with with the plants with
the strains that we're putting out so
data on when to harvest data on this
plants never fit in a box and you know
with crop steering and stuff now like i'
I've seen some strains that you know
they like to be pushed a lot harder in
veg and you know like they don't like
the EC stacking as much so it's like you
know the more data I can get on the
specific cultivar you know I'm trying to
kind of package that and give that to
cultivators so that you know they have a
better you know Head Start yeah I think
that's the future is is more data I mean
we're doing data driven breeding we're I
think before it was like we pop a bunch
of stuff and we do our selections now a
lot of us are taking notes and a lot of
us are logging data and trying to
capture as much of that as possible so
that we get better results in the future
yeah and more you know your lines the
better you know it's a yeah I have a a
background in computer science data
collection's always been big for me even
like the old 215 you know like I had
things stored you know encrypted and
secured so you know in case the door
ever got knocked down like I wouldn't
lose that stuff you know so I think it's
now it's more important than ever like
you know the the cultivators really rely
on the nurseries and you know every
Nursery has hurt some of the cultivators
and it's when everyone goes to scale
there's bumps and bruises you know like
there's been no book written to do this
you know so it's just we're all learning
and the more that we can you know give
the cultivators a head start I think you
know that's what I'm really trying to
focus on on the breeding aspect of it
and the data collection totally no
that's awesome and you're working with
Conception 2 you guys are doing big
things over there some World Class
People people you know Kevin had a a
good vision and me and him you know kind
of shared shared the the same idea the
same vision we bring in a lot of
breeders that you know everything on the
menu is actually paid royalties to a
breeder which is unique if the Breeders
are actually getting reimbursed for
their work and and you know they're
they're more driven for Innovation and
you know if they can focus on what they
do great and getting money for that and
keeping them in their Lane you know
there's going to be more and more
Innovation uh in this industry and
hopefully we get out of this this box of
you know purple purple G or candy I
should say and you know like you know I
think the the markets you know like you
look at the other markets that have you
know come and matured and you know it's
more about tpine profiles and effects
and stuff so hopefully the industry
starts catching up and well the spray
tur box is in the right direction let me
tell you that's it's comedy though but
people are buying it unfortunately
people are but people buy Vape carts too
so I mean it it is what it is but I feel
like the breeding is going to go in
other directions I'm already seen it I
see a lot of people talking about sativa
you know we've been talking about how
SAU and OG are making a comeback and
they will they definitely will there's a
lot of people that want them and if it's
not the original sour it'll be a sour
Cross or OG cross there's a lot of good
OG crosses out there yeah and there's
even purple gas that's out there That's
Heavy
Gas so it's just Evolution so it is
exciting I'm always excited to find new
stuff like that we haven't seen before
yeah rhubarb I'm looking for some
rhubarb stuff like that you know I mean
nostalgic things that I think of when I
was a kid you know it's like pancakes is
pretty cool yeah for because it smells
like pancake I remember the first time I
saw chocolate thae yeah it really smelt
like chocolate you know it was on the on
the stick and it was wrapped up for me
like you know I grew up on brick you
know Mexican brick weed yeah we started
getting some of the DC Bud uh the beers
we moved a lot of that remember the
first time I saw purple weed actually
and I was looking at animation jar being
like I didn't know that bud could look
like that you know and then seeing
chocolate Thai stick it was that was
like mind-blowing to me yeah you know so
it never smelted anything like it right
still hav to this day still still
searching still searching for that Mak
it come back yeah I feel like there's
some interesting chocolate crosses out
there the choc L is there was that
chocolate hashberry back in the day that
was kind of chocolatey but that wasn't
super chocy yeah and same thing with
chocol up is it it has a hint of
chocolate so but yeah and these things
will reoccur the Gen genetic
recombination will provide those
genetics again at some point those
unique traits so you do seed production
too and you make seeds you make a bunch
of seeds and crosses and yeah we just I
did a a collaboration with jock at
spannabis this year with turog took the
original Skittle more like half Focus
line cross that to a bunch of stuff
we're finding some amazing penos out of
that yeah found a couple that are
pressing at like over 5% with you know a
Skittle guava kind of like a rotten
Skittle smell um yeah yeah doing seed
production released another line a reg
line with farming Stone another hash
line great line like OG gz cross to
papaya rainbow belts and another whole
line that I was doing Skittles uh Hindu
Skittles papaya CR hind Skittles really
maybe I had a good one that's totally
possible you know I feel like bagging on
strange stuff because maybe it wasn't
grown by the right person or maybe it it
is good and I didn't get the right cut
or even the same cut yeah even the same
cross yeah my experience with Hindu
Skittles I got excited and I was in a
dispenser and I bought two bags of it
because it was like buy one get one free
and it was Hindu Skittles I'm like dude
it's got to be amazing and it just
wasn't skitt
is it flour or rosin okay yeah I've had
a really more in rosin yeah makes it
makes Candy Funk it's got like some
raunchiness like they did the uh Hindu
Skittles papaya it was like rotten fruit
yeah I hit that to a couple I hit it to
the fatso I hit it to the zods I hit it
to a couple different things blueberry
thint which I'm calling blue
Andes um and it's given a lot of depth
of flavor yeah Skittles crosses are
tricky you know breeding with Skittles
is chicky I think there's a lot of
recessive traits then if you breed stuff
and you want Skittles you're looking for
the structure that's not as good it's a
hard turpine to pull out yeah that candy
in there and then we had some Skittles
back crosses that leaned heavy on the
CBG flow Gardens just got some coas done
nice it was like some ridiculous amount
of CVG so I'm excited to try some of
that flower out nice yeah sounds good I
I like Skittles I like yeah I mean I
like candy I like flavor but Skittles is
special yeah I've always you know like
in the old days it was always like the
nose sold the bag so you know I've been
doing a lot of selections based off of
loud Tarpin profiles some of the
breeding that's done now are the
selections like feel like we lost it
becomes you know a little monot turp or
you know a little more it's R
weed sorry for interrupting but yeah
Instagram is run weed it's that that
monot turp and all those thing as far as
why the flour isn't as good I think a
lot of it is social media because you
don't actually have to smell it you
don't actually have to taste it or or
feel the effect of it you look at it and
a lot of people are basing the quality
on and you know some of that stuff looks
amazing and it just doesn't smell yeah
so much of it yeah no I think you're
right that's where the marketing side
comes in um I think that's where
California kind of went wrong too I miss
like opening a jar at a dispensary and
smelling it right you know and and now
it's like I've seen a lot of people with
the push tops and it you know kind of
pushes it to you but like the weed sits
on that jar for for months I'm sure you
lose that you know like some of the
other someone just told me that Oregon
still does the deli you know like you
still pop it open they pull it out and
package it there for you so really cool
that's how it should be I mean I think
there's a freshness involved and if you
use the freshness of the product it's
like just like anything no one likes D
old bread or stale bread no I guess one
bread stays Fresher a lot longer but
sure a lot of preservatives exactly but
yeah it's interesting these different
markets and then New York expanding and
doing their thing and I think it's great
they have their own set of problems yeah
yeah it was funny I I went out there two
420s ago and I grew up there and you
know New York is weed has been in the
culture in New York for for as long as
I've been alive you know and I was
excited you know I was in Washington
Square Park for everybody and and seeing
you know just everyone coming together
and stuff like that but you know they
have the same problem that you know Los
Angeles dealt with with the lacka moles
you know like they take out one you know
legal dispensary and three more pop up
so they're going to have their you know
they're going to have some some Growing
Pains I do think it's going to be one
you know if you look at sales volume I
think it'll be you know one of the top
for sales for for the country like I
said everyone everyone loves it there we
have some seed that are over there now
and they'll be doing some marketing at
the end of the summer flying out there
looking at some some strains we have
working with a group out there that
they're planting like six or seven acres
between a couple different areas cool
one of the one of the Farms is right
where I grew up so um probably 15 20
minutes from where I grew up so wow I'm
excited to see it there yeah I just it's
it's interesting and I can't wait for
interstate commerce yeah I think that's
just I mean for what you guys are doing
in conception and for what we're doing
and it's it's going to be just such a
big game Cher when it opens up and you
know there's all these loopholes now
that you know I think those loopholes
will go away eventually but they they
need to have it done so we can do it the
right way where there will be Interstate
comers where cultivators will be sell
able to sell to other states yeah I mean
that's just silly that you can't go to
New York and buy California weed legally
you should be able to just like any
other Agricultural Product or anything
you buy in the grocery store the
rescheduling is not exactly what we want
but I think it's a step in the right
direction and hopefully like you know we
got to keep pushing and and trying to
make it better but I think it is you
know at least a step in the right
direction I haven't had the chance to
read the the full you know bylaws that
were just passed this morning yeah this
morning I guess they released it I saw
Omar figuroa posted about it but yeah
and then we have a the opportunity to
comment on it for the next few months
yeah 90 days I think it's something
that's got to it's got to happen I mean
it's it's got to happen and schedule 3's
you know people are like man we just any
step is a good step I feel I I really
pref I think I think it should be
descheduled 100% but at the same time we
need to move
forward um you know and I think there's
a there's a lot of people fighting for
what what's right so we'll see what
happens yeah I hope that it really opens
up you know like interstate comence
you know like I think we have an over
Supply issue in in in California and it
needs to be addressed and it's not why
it doesn't get better with age so no
keep the supply coming turn it on into
Raz and then you get freeze
it I mean really extract is the only
thing to do when you have an over supply
of product unfortunately since we can't
sell it to other states yeah but Oregon
has the same thing they produce some
ridiculous amount more than they can
consume I know they were trying to push
an envelope for a while trying to open
up interstate commerce between you know
a couple other states and I think the
whole CBD the whole farm bill has really
pushed the rescheduling or you know
these whole talks because it's it's
really cats out of the bag and and they
need to figure out how to you know
control a little bit better and and you
know create a little bit more of a
thriving economy off of it you know for
sure so what's the new hottest latest
greatest thing in conception there's a
bunch as far as like the candy levers
there's a a Lemon Cherry sherbet nice
it's a collaboration between Tiki madman
and Mario from shinsky nice so it's the
Lemon Cherry gelato cross original
Sunset sherbet I love the sunset sherbet
um it's one of those ones that I feel
like didn't really get like it's day in
the sun it totally didn't it was like
the you know like sherber came out kind
of like the same time I guess the
Skittles came you know and Skittles kind
of blew up for a second and it was like
a real quick rush into the gelados and
then the gelato took over and that was
it yeah yeah I mean sher's special so I
love I love everything about it it grows
it it produces amazing flour it yields
pretty good the purple on it's amazing
yeah it's it's yeah it's a special one
it definitely didn't get its fair fair
share you know it's it's fair day and
yeah I remember that whole thing very
vividly from the from the Bay Area and
it's like sure was was killing still is
it is it is so yeah I'm excited for that
one you know I've been working with
Mario for for years now and i' remember
the original Sunset sherbet I had got 10
years ago or something but I grew it for
a long time and and vended a lot across
California and then started working with
him a couple years after that and then
got to grow the real one I was like oh
man I've never never had the real one
you know like it's so loud and it's I
like that funk that really has yeah
that's that's one of the new ones I have
a blueberry hen Min so it was honestly
it was like two of the original strains
that like I brought through tissue
culture the original thin Min uh I had
gotten from a friend early on it wasn't
even called cookies yet it wasn't even
called you know came to me as a cosmic
or something like that and I remember
growing it at that time I was growing a
lot of sours and ogs and I remember
growing it and like looking at it just
being like freaking out being like this
isn't going to yield anything you know
and it was you know golf balls all the
way up dry it fast forward trimmers are
trim come inside and there's like you
know bags like this big I was like is
this a quter pound is this half pound
like what is this I like no that's a
full pound you know and I think the the
Girl Scout was like such a game changer
you know from what we were growing that
hit the market and everyone was just
like wow at that point I was living in
up in Lake Tahoe in trucky yeah you know
like we were growing in the garage and
there was before like you know AC
systems and stuff like that I used to
drag cold air from from we'd run the
lights at night drag it through the the
garage and suck it out the other end and
and I mean it would it would come out
black yeah and did you have like hoods
that had air flow through yeah we
started six Ines the fours yeah right
those are great hoods like I mean I
actually like looking back now like I
pulled some really great numbers off of
those Hood even going through glass and
and stuff like we had cool tubes that
was
yeah we did vertical growing with the
cool tubes you know I mean interesting
ways of do it back before we had real
before Mini Splits right that Mini
Splits were such a game changer I
remember we started putting Reams I
don't remember who came up with the idea
but we're just like let's just stick a
ream you know like home you know system
into the into the garage and started
cooling that way and that's when you
know you saw the big jump from from the
lights like gab started showing up and
stuff like that and we're like can't
cool this you know like we got to figure
something out yeah Reams came along and
and yeah the rest of History yeah it's
interesting these evolutions and femin
seeds I fought back on a bunch of stuff
like femin seeds I was like n you can't
do femin seeds it's going to ruin the
genan pool right you know and then utof
flowers I was very against autoflowers
in the beginning I was like aut there
were some bad ones at the beginning dude
there were some bad ones 10 years ago 15
years ago it was like I saw them and I'm
like I'm never growing autof flowers
ever yeah then my buddy Nick showed me a
greenhous full of autof flowers and I
couldn't believe that they're autof
flowers yeah like amazing and the blur
the purple LS like I nobody that grew
good ever used those though in in my
opinion I at least the circle of friends
that I had like everybody that wanted to
show me their blurp it was like dude
terrible weed and I'm like never I'm not
using because that's at the time I was
like oh that's LED I don't want to use
LED like HPS or CM I like C MH they used
a checkerboard with C too yeah I think
that's a great way to do it I think you
get amazing flavor but it's funny how
like blue dream grows better under HPS
than CMH I feel like the expression is
better it can handle the heat more too
so that blue dream used to grow like
crazy yeah yeah and I mean you have it
seems now like so many people are are
still talking about the single-ended you
know bulbs like you know like the the
double ender for like the some of the
connoisseurs they they don't want to
still you know they still think that
that was the best you know best weed
that they ever smoked yeah well I heard
OG girls really good in her CMH like
that's the one to grow makes sense I
guess the light intensity is not as not
as you know intense I guess pbfs are
probably lower and C hes right probably
yeah I mean that's probably why does
better yeah I always F like I mean the
ogs always just grew better Outdoors for
me I couldn't I couldn't Jay was great
at growing ogs and in inside I always
always like to put the ogs outside I
love good outdoor and so I forget for
for periods of time and then I get some
good outdoor and like I love really good
outdoor like the effect also the flavor
and I feel like the the rich flavor of a
good outdoor like good OG that's been
grown Outdoors where it's got that gas
that's just down to the roach not that
indoor OG is bad indoor OG is freaking
amazing yeah you know it's like Brian
vital you know his OG's fire that stuff
is amazing and I love I love that stuff
but good OG that's been grown Outdoors
most outdoor flow grown correctly is
good yeah but there's that 1% of stuff
where it's like yeah that white Thorn
Rose is another one it's like sunr the
The Taste is really good it has the nice
it has like a florish
rose like vanilla and almond is in there
like it's it's complex yeah and then the
effect just clean I think my favorite is
the mix light um the addition of some
light you know like sunlight and and
artificial light right there's been a
handful of strains that I've grown
indoors outdoors and then you put it
into a mix light and the expression it
gets is is is just it's night and day I
think it's the future too I honestly
think mix light is the future of of
cannabis in the world you know as far as
if you're talking about the best bang
for your buck if you want for quality
not that outdoor is you know outdoor's
amazing too but as far as if you want an
indoor product I think eventually we're
going to go away from these big
facilities and really focus on mix light
yeah I think it has to you know
especially in California like the cost
of produce is is just astronomical the
power prices that we pay here it's just
it's too much there there's some Growers
as you know preferred Gardens and Lucas
from Emerald kid like T Mansion like
they're light supplemental is you know
we'll go up against anyone's indoor yeah
and I think the only thing you you get
from the Outdoors is like the shelf life
is a little shorter what do you think
that's contributed from I don't know the
oxidation just breaks down quicker like
I don't I I've never really you know was
actually having this conversation with
David the other day like I've never been
able to put my finger on it he hasn't
either just like yeah I don't know the
sun just breaks it down quicker or once
it gets in a bag you have a a shorter
shelf life huh interesting it'd be
interesting to figure out where that
comes from but yeah I'm a big fan of the
mixed light and the just greenhouse and
General and I think it's better for the
planet I think it's as good if not
better of product you have the sun in
there Sunkissed sun-kissed get the sun
kissed yeah and then even in the winter
you can do make slide yeah so yeah the
little cooler temps some under canopy
you it's like well shout out to fav
these guys craft farmer fav these guys
doing under canopies but yeah I like the
favin I've seen really good results
we're running them here yeah it's cool
to see the new you know like I said I
have I have a background in Tech so to
see the new innovations that are
happening you know like and I think
that's one of the good things you know
even with this rescheduling right like
it's it's schedule one the government's
saying there's no medical benefit right
we're getting schedule three if it goes
out you know goes that way like they're
saying okay well there is some benefit
right it's the small steps but again now
it's going to open up more money to
really start doing R&amp;D R&amp;D is expensive
you know like and that's where the
evolution needs to go and it needs to
get pushed a little faster hope the 280e
disappears and and Bank you know real
real Banking and lending starts coming
out of this and it's just going to push
the The Innovation you know quicker
right and we have countries like Israel
that are just so far ahead of us with 40
years ahead of us testing and studies
but we have the opportunity to change at
any moment and so you know I think that
part of it definitely is a good thing
the government's known as been okay for
all this time and now they're finally
like okay well I mean they've held the
patent on you know cannabis as a as a a
medicine right like since the 70s right
and at the same time in schedule one so
you know like once I realize that it's
just you know it's just it was always a
money grab and and you know them just
trying to control with lobbyists and you
know you look at the history and it's
just it's sad I mean strange world we
live in yeah yeah it is unfortunately
but hopefully some of the you know the
old ways are are starting to to die off
and even my grandparents when I told
them you know what I was getting into
you know like it was it took a second
for them to like that's good it helps
helps people but it it's also it's very
addictive and I'm like you know like
reer Madness like probably is one of the
best marketing campaigns of all time
like we're still trying to break those
chains you know like for sure we
recently moved from trucky down to Grass
Valley and like learning new new friends
I mean we have a farm on our property
and it's just like you know having new
friends and having to like disclose that
to you know kids parents and stuff like
that you know most of people have been
open but it's still like you know people
still look at you a little different you
know and it's sure 50 60 years of this
bad information just beat into people's
heads you know I remember in high school
we used to we used to get high and watch
watch reer like but people really
thought that's what it did don't was it
on acid have a bad trip that's a great
way to do it watch it over and over
that's M comedy man yeah it's it's funny
how impactful that was yeah and how many
people still I mean there's a lot of
people you over 50% of America is fine
with it I believe I think like the the
last poll is like pushing 7 like 65 68%
I said the cats out of the bag and and
you know actually it took my grandmother
she had room and tour arthritis and I I
would send her CBD cream yeah and she
was like wow this is actually starting
to work you know so I think the CBD the
whole Farm Bill like really helped
people realize it's not the devil's
lettuce it's not going to right you know
people aren't going to run a muck
jumping out of buildings you know like
it it it you know it helped and you know
push I think where where we're going you
know a lot quicker yeah well it's funny
because like stuff like you hear
thca and you think oh that [ __ ] gets you
high and yes it does but also if you
don't heat it up it does not yeah I
remember the first time I ate a gram of
thca I have uler of colitis and so my
good friend Tim over at can Organics
made a bunch of thca for me and I had
tried eating it for you I was I was a
little nervous eating a gram of it
because I know eating gram of THC like
1,000 milligrams would give me good yeah
oh yeah but yeah did it doesn't get you
high at all but it it did have a good
effect on my gut health so
anti-inflammatory properties and you
know these are the things that we're
going to be researching yeah and you
know exponentially faster than we could
before yeah so I'm I'm excited about
that part Absol schedule three now how
they tax it and how they do other things
people are like they're not going to tax
it no they're Uncle Sam taxes everything
they're GNA tax the [ __ ] out of it
unfortunately you want to know who your
silent partner is is Uncle Sam you know
yeah it's just how it goes but you know
I mean we have to move forward I think
the biggest win here is is that you know
they're now finally saying that not the
devil it's not you know there is some
benefit to it and you know I think a lot
of us got into this understanding the
benefits and wanting to you know I think
one of the problems with 64 is that like
we used to donate to this group of
children um in Nevada county in the 215
uh a lar were trim and a lot of those
avenues like disappeared with 64
unfortunately yeah and we were making
some great strides and working with kids
with epilepsy and all sorts of you know
uh issues and I'm happy to see that kind
of come back now real doctors and real
people like getting involved and trying
to isolate some yeah I mean during the
215 days it was like some of the doctors
were little you know little there were
Dr Frank laso one of the greatest
doctors I've ever known you know and he
was like really about it and there was
doctors that were about the money grab
you know little the 99 plant it's 125
for this script or it's 300 for this or
500 I remember at one point they so some
of the doctors were charging 500 for a
99 script yeah Frank luo was great he's
he just retired last year but he was
writing scripts so he was one of the
first ones so he also wrote my buddy's
younger brother when he was 14 script
yeah he had medical issues and but he
was a Believer and believer in the plant
and all the benefits that that the plan
could give us and I would love to get
him on the show he'd he'd be a great one
yeah yeah I mean i' I've heard you say
it for a long time and it always stuck
with me was you know the sacred plant
and like I said R&amp;D is expensive but
like you know hopefully we can keep
pushing it and and and seeing what we
can do I mean we lost 50 60 years to not
really being able to see see what this
plan can do so I'm excited you know for
for the next yeah iteration of the
industry yeah I mean I'm just happy to
be alive you know we takeing this thing
one day at a time and seeing where the
future I try to live in the present as
much as possible and not get too excited
about the future or too upset about the
past and we're we're in an amazing time
on on some levels we're in the strangest
freaking weird place ever yeah I never
thought there'd be a time where I didn't
understand the younger generation yeah
because I feel like that's that's always
like the case and it's like I just don't
get some of the kids these days and and
you know I feel like how my parents and
my grandparents thought about the work
ethic of my generation is kind of how I
feel about the work ethic of the younger
generation it's like I feel like our
generation has like this work ethic and
you know not all of us there's a lot ofy
friends that I grew up with but a lot of
people do have work ethic and then the
younger generation I think with
technology it's made life easier made
people softer but like
my father's generation and my
grandfather's generation those guys were
way tougher than our generation I feel
like absolutely these guys were made of
leather yeah yeah no I I you know my
parents were both like first generation
my dad's side came from from Norway my
my my mom's side from off the boat from
Italy yeah you know and and some of the
things that I grew up watching your
stories I heard and and like you know
visibility like saw like my my my dad
and my my uncle had to like literally
dig out underneath the house to make a a
basement have like a you know like a den
for everybody you know like at like 10
12 years old you know just digging
things like that and I grew up in a
construction family and and I get
dropped off after kindergarten I get
dropped off to my dad's job site and
have to run around pick up pieces of
wood and clean up you know at the end of
the day and now like we kind of live on
a farm so like my kids are all of a
sudden have a huge CH chor less to do
you know they're not happy about it like
they weren't you know they weren't
around that but now it's like you know
we we live on a big you know piece of
property and everyone has their
responsib everyone has their
responsibilities Mexico that's another
interesting place with cannabis now yeah
I mean I think Mexico uh Colombia
especially being you know around the
equator yeah you know kind of like what
they did to you know like the The Cut
Flower industry and stuff like I've done
a lot of work and over the years and
montere and you know like watching that
you know get moved to to South America
like it's you know wonder how that's
going to affect you know cannabis going
you know I think the breeding's great
you know like being in a 1212 and not
having to to manipulate the lights at
all like I think it could be a great
area to breed but well you're breeding
for different things down there like
high humidity you know and and things
that do well in that 1212 environment
you could take something that performs
really well here and bring it down there
and it might not perform and something
that sucks up here and bring it down
there and it might perform really well
also you could take something here that
you think is going to be a certain way
you bring it down there it's completely
different so that's the beautiful thing
about you know climate and localized
genetics that work well for those local
environments I mean we talk about land
race yeah bringing the race back to land
I guess again going back to Innovation
you know being you know through
regulations getting spurred right like
we're breeding for you know not just the
effects of the tpping but also breeding
for like traits we're looking for you
know like there's you know some that are
you know Bettis resistant or pest
resistant like you know again that's
where I feel like we're going to make
some Leaps and Bounds over the next
couple years if you know if the
rescheduling happens and well and I
think there's a lot of traits that
people don't even think about right you
know when they're doing breed a lot of
breeders aren't even thinking about like
does this plant trigger faster than this
plant yeah because those sort of traits
can be extremely beneficial in places
that have shorter Seasons right
you know and not everything triggers at
the same point yeah you know and it's
and but there's so many traits like that
yeah no I I GRE one this past year that
outside like it won't trigger until it
gets right at 12 12 you know and had it
still still up in in November you know
like getting to Thanksgiving and but you
put it in a depth and manipulate the
light triggers triggers and it finishes
quicker right you know so it's fun like
I love I love I love breeding I love you
know the fale hunting side of things I
think you know like that's often
overlooked right everyone wants to be a
breeder Mash they want to be a breeder
but they all want just want to make
seeds they don't not all of them some
people love it yeah but a lot of people
think the breeding is making the seeds
and that's like the the smallest part of
the whole breeding process is this it's
the part that anybody can do it's the
seed selection and going through and
sometimes just hitting the lottery with
stuff and other times knowing you're
life really well and knowing that you
need to pop 20 seeds and you're going to
find kind of what you're looking for you
know we people argue about big hunts and
little hunts and it's it's different for
everybody in what you're looking for if
you're trying to find unicorns you know
and you're going through big hunts
that's cool and if you're trying to find
specific things in smaller hunts that's
good too how much of your resources you
want to dedicate to one specific Cross
or to tons of different crosses I think
like now now the the whole concept of
cure
you know is is being thrown around a lot
but I think on the feno hunt side like
knowing what you're looking for is you
know and being able to pull pull that
right thing out like for sure it's a
whole new uh trait or you know like that
I think is overlooked a lot and it's a
whole there's a whole art to it too and
also knowing your lines because the more
you work with those lines the more you
know them and you know kind of what it's
going to pass on like depending on what
the parents are and you can easily
identify stuff if you work with it a lot
but if you're working with completely
new stuff all the time it's harder to
get a grasp of really what's
contributing what and and I think that's
unfortunately where the industry is
right it's like everyone wants a new
hottest thing you know like but you know
the people that I grew up around you
know breeding and and stuff like they
worked lines for years and years and
years you know to to to get something
and I think that's one of those Arts
that have kind of been lost right now a
lot of my stuff that worked a lot I
don't even offer because people don't
appreciate it so stuff that we've been
working for the last four years since
2018 especially like I don't share a lot
of I the autoflowers yes but the photo
period stuff not so much because people
just don't appreciate it they want rs1
times permanent marker you know or or
whatever it is the latest greatest cross
with the latest greatest whatever your
latest greatest cross with everybody
else's latest greatest that's kind of
what people are super hyperfocused on
but I think we are going back my banana
cough has been selling like crazy which
is the Fort Collins cough times banana Z
that I made yeah and I wouldn't say that
it has a great bud structure I wouldn't
say that it finishes early it's it's but
it's special because that Fort Collins
cof is like the nl5 haze like the piff
Cuban black Haze you know there's so
many nl5 Haze crosses that are good and
Fort colins cough is special and it
Spears out and it grows tall and you
know short it doesn't it doesn't Bush
out it all it just kind of shoots up
okay you get a little lot of not a
little but a lot of apical growth where
it's just like one main shoot and then
side branches that are all smaller but
it has this crazy funky like nose
burning profile it's not like your
typical sativa which is what I like
which is kind of like piff is like that
too it's not a typical sativa and so you
put some candy on there and you're going
to get some real funky stuff I like
sometimes taking both ends the Spectrum
and putting them together see what you
get like I almost think that's better
you know it's like one thing just
putting all the gelato with another
gelato and that's it's fine yeah but
going real extreme on stuff where it's
like I'm gonna take the shortest plant
that grows the slowest and then put it
with the most vigorous crazy plant that
gets super tall that I need shorter yeah
and seeing what comes off of that we're
doing some wild fenal hunting right now
and we have some stuff that's completely
like the opposite I have stuff that's 6
weeks old that like still only this but
it's like Bush and then we have some
stuff that's like five feet tall the
feminized portion is is you need to like
understanding the lines and then all of
a sudden it's like an onion sometimes
like all a sudden you open you take
another layer off and you're like I
didn't know that was in there you know
like all a sudden something you know
right field you're like where the hell
did that come from what's like the
Skittles s once like you get a lot of
stuff that's most of it's not Skittles
not Skitty not stuff that I and and
there's also tpine like lyine and tpine
in the freaking progeny too when you
cross Skittles to itself yeah first
class Genex my buddy Ray he had some
problems with his Skittles and it was
definitely tpine dominant really after
yeah epigenetics okay which we can still
argue whether epigenetics exist or not
but I definitely think I so my my first
experience with that was the ghost
OG and Josh Doo
where they'd gone through two different
places and growing side by side they're
similar but they're totally different
and so those have taken two different
paths even though at one point they were
a clone off of the same plant uhuh and
they're different do you think that's
like from style or for like I don't want
to say genetic drift because it's
whatever epigenetics it's those those
plants experience bacterial load and who
knows pathogens over the period of time
and maybe they fight off some and maybe
there's good bacteria that changes in
the plant yeah you know so there's these
chemical changes that occur maybe it's
not just genetics but they can be
different expressions and be very
similar and you know I grew them side by
side and saw that so but yeah that's
been the argument lately like is
epigenetics real is you know for sure
all this stuff is real but to what
extent and then what is tissue culture
did say that yeah right yeah I know that
that's kind of a Hot Topic right now I
was just listening to another podcast or
like oh no the hormones change the
change the structure of the plant and
stuff like that and you know definitely
have done like fingerprinting the DNA
and looking at it before and after and
you know there there's no change that's
happening right at the DNA level but I
think if you look at Styles good
bacteria bad bacteria pests all that
stuff plays into it right like even
microclimates too like that's not really
about a lot too you know like in Grass
Valley like I think it's one of the best
microclimates in California and what I
can do there you know what I can pull
out of you know Str and you know we grew
in in the Central Valley for five or six
years so it's like totally different you
know but I think this is all becoming
like fashion it's becoming cyclical and
seeing some of the old stuff come back
honestly like tissue culture we knew we
had to to do it you know at one point
like you know me when me and Jay got
together like it was really we were
trying to do it for for inhouse like for
for what we were developing trying to
clean up the genetics like at that point
like you know coming from the 2115 into
the 64 error yeah I remember Crockett
growing in in montere and that's when
the first time we started learning about
pesticide drift right like and then what
what's in those plans too like you know
we all shared genetics back then you
didn't know what someone's IPM protocols
were you know like they were spraying
some bad stuff you get it and you know
micro buttin all and forbid like that
stuff was in there for Generations yeah
you know and we really went down the
route of tissue culture to remove that
and we were trying to develop our our
our property in in Yolo County was
hitting like a bunch of speed bumps and
all a sudden there's like thousands of
plants you know starting to back up and
you know we became a nursery by by
accident you know like Jay I just
remember like standing in there with Jay
and and Bo and the nursery and were
looking at all these plants like we have
nowhere to put them you know I was like
I guess we start selling them you know
and and even like tissue culture I
remember you know know at the emerald
cup we were sitting there we didn't have
enough plants to sell at this point
we're trying to tell everyone what we
were doing this would have been like 16
17 I think and people at the emerald
crop are like I'd say like 25% got it
and like we we were like showcasing we
had like 10 plans to Showcase you know
and people were looking at us like you
know multiple people oh this is GMO you
know like you and Ron Santo were like
this is a practice that's been used for
40 years in in in trying to explain it
why it's so important emal C though oh
yeah I mean the old days no no no I I
mean I have so many people so many
people like in the old days like all you
need to do is put that that genetic back
outside for a full moon cycle it'll be
totally the same again It'll like reset
everything yeah well you know and so
it's funny because DJ Short he told me
this is a long long time ago when I was
super excited about tissue culture like
I was like this is the bill grah when
Bill grah was the tissue culture guy
back in you know 2009 or 2010 or
something like that I was super excited
and I was sitting next to DJ Short and I
was told him I want to learn tissue
culture and he's like actually all you
need to do is put that plant in the
ground and you do that in the spring and
you're going to take Fresh Cuts every
year off that and you'll get the same
results as tissue culture well depending
on Whose tissue culture you know because
I'm sure you might get better results
than certain people that are doing
tissue culture that don't know what
they're doing and right there's
different types of tissue culture people
don't understand that either they think
all tissue culture is the same and it's
not mirr stem tissue
culture uh when you're using
undifferentiated
cells uh it's a lot harder to do a lot
more time consuming a lot more time
consuming uh and then just being able to
do nodle properly yep you know and I
think there's a lot of these kits and
the kits are great ways for people to
learn and develop an understanding for
tissue culture yeah but I don't think
they are the future of tissue culture
most people are going to have Labs like
you have a lab I have a lab we have Labs
we have technicians to know what they're
doing and you can learn some of it on
your own but to take it to the level
that you guys are at is very very
difficult for most people yeah I think
you know understanding that at scale is
there's very few people that can do it
in the world you guys are at a scale
that no one else is at yeah I mean no
one no one else is even touching it it's
pretty pretty amazing it's cool it's
cool cool to see like I said it's world
class group of people yeah you know
there is pathologist from UC Davis you
know she actually wrote most of the the
primers for for pcrs and stuff like that
you know to see some of the people that
you know again I'm I'm a geek at heart
you know like I I wrote software
developed software developed you know
Hardware too for for 15 years as I was
like also in cannabis you know growing
in my garage so right I'm a geek at
heart so for me like bringing you know a
form of tech biotech in cannabis is is
my dream space yeah and we started it at
finest like when me and Jay and this is
like just the next iteration you know
and conception is also now like getting
ready to open up a lab in Portugal and
you know we've spent to time in Spain
the last couple years together and and
you know trying to get into the Germany
market like it's best iners ever yeah
it's it's just it's it's cool to see
like you know like I think a lot of
people
are looking at California and the
problems we have here but like I think
we're in you know we're all we're all
kind of Treading Water you know but like
there's a it I think the good time is is
still coming you know it's a lot of
people talk about the the good old times
but I think moving forward from you know
genetics and and just the science side
of things like I think we're we're
really starting to you know starting to
push hard so with tissue culture I I
wanted to do this subject justce this in
my book and so we had Matt steer from
apical biotech he wrote the chapter and
I didn't really touch the chapter it was
but but I feel like it's such an
important thing to have an understanding
of moving forward in the future because
if you want clean genetics either you're
going to be growing from seed or you're
going to be going from tissue culture
plants it's not a lot of Clone
propagation unless it was from tissue
culture because there's so many problems
with everything not just hopon and I
think a lot of people focus on hopon
viroid but it's like that's just one of
yeah one of 20 issues that more more
than that one of 50 issues it could
probably have and I think we're still
learning about them too right you know
like you know the whole nodal uh marem
right now like we test right for 40
pathogens right and okay it's clean you
can use Nole or do you use marem you
know like back and forth we do both you
you know like and I think marem is also
a kind of like an insurance policy like
what if we find something new that has
been sitting in that tissue you know
like we're propagating right it's
interesting and and then I don't know if
you read the article Kevin M mcnamer
from medicinal genomics just started
talking a lot about hbd being you know
transmitted now through pollen like we
thought it was you know just through
dirty I haven't read that yet it's
pretty definitely need to read that
because I was always curious whether you
can transmit hoping through pollen I
think we talked about that first time on
the podcast right like totally at that
point like people thought 10 15% you
know like and don't quote me on the
exact number but I think it was 50 60%
like he's saying like 50 60%
transmission rate yeah that's why
because yeah what you're saying purple
City genetics did a study and they found
10% transmission or 10 seven I believe
it was seven to 10 but Kevin mckernin
whatever he says I I would go with a lot
of the stuff that he says he's super
smart they're doing some amazing stuff
over there and you know also resistant
strengths find stuff that's resistant to
H PL and verid well and we've been we
you know everything that we bring into
culture at um a conception actually gets
tested with medicinal genomics yeah so
we're doing the mapping of the The
genome but you know we're also trying to
work super full genome yeah on
everything yeah you know like the whole
the whole mind proposition is you know
like a Nursey like can this is this
right and who's whose word are you
taking you taking my word like where did
I get it like did I get the right one
did they get the wrong you know yeah
we're using my florid DNA same idea but
it's like the fingerprinting technology
is there you might not be able to tell
if it was a sister or if it was 100% if
it was related but at least you could
tell if it's the exact same thing yeah
and it just keeps us keeps us all honest
because there's so much cut fishing
going on the cut fishing game is just
it's so bad and it's like it's been
going on forever because somebody gets
something they're like well they they
want to protect whatever same thing with
crosses down the road it's like I mean I
understand people wanting to rename
stuff to protect their IP because we
can't fully protect IP but like renaming
other people's stuff that's a joke yeah
so taking credit for other people's work
that's a joke yeah it's sad it's it's
sad and it's been happening but but we
can see the future of it not happening
you guys can make sure it doesn't happen
that you know at least to the best of
your ability and that's all we can do
yeah I mean like right now none of this
is enforcable right because like if you
take it to court where is it going to
it's going to go it's going to go
nowhere and any federal judge is going
to look at and like get it out of my
court you know like it's still illegal
we're not allowed to be doing this we
can't sue each other you know no yeah
but I think you know again we're making
baby steps and you know there are
patents getting pushed in well and
selling clones if you're going to sell
clones you might as well fingerprint it
so you know what it is in the bigger
Library you have to put it against you
can find out if it's original if it's
something the same as somebody else's U
but it takes baby steps right it's one
at a time it's one foot in front of the
the other and till you have a big
library and well I think it's important
for the The genome too like I think
unfortunately like a lot of the data
that the genomes like sequenced against
data again like the data who's to say
that this is the real data you know like
exactly who's to say that this OG Kush
is the real OG Kush you you're relying
on the person that gave it to you yeah
and that was the problem with phos right
because there was stuff there was 70 or
100 different things in there that were
named different things other than OG
Kush that were just OG Kush yeah and so
then it just it becomes like where did
you Source it the only way to really do
that and in my mind is from the breeder
and holding holding the breeder
accountable if you know I I think that's
an important thing I think that's where
we're starting right like we're starting
you know like I said everything on the
menu goes back to the breeder you know
like not just the royalty but like the
like mapping in genome you know I'm
saying okay this is you know stamped in
history of what they created yeah we're
protecting them hopefully this is also
opening up a way for patents and stuff
moving forward but it you know like when
we saw what right what happened with
corn and sword and stuff like that with
Monsanto like none of this work was
being done right and then all of a
sudden Monsanto comes out and you know
blankets gets patents on strains and
then starts showing small farmers and
forcing them to use seats hopefully this
is this is that path forward like we've
all put a lot of energy time money into
creating these things and this is a way
to like you know who knows where this
industry is going you know like
hopefully this is one of the ways of
like cementing that you know this is
this is mine I created this and you know
stamping that that portion so and and
again like it's just you know this
regulation's going to just start you
know breeding more Innovation yeah I
mean I think that when you can start
really capturing data and holding people
to be honest accountability is so
important having someone say one thing
as opposed to proving one thing where
you have the data and you know moving
forward it's going to be a great thing
so especially when people like Monsanto
or whoever it is you know I mean I think
there's going to be a lot of people that
want to try to grab a patents and
protect stuff um that's not necessarily
novel but that you can't do that it's
got to be original yeah I think again
going back to the gnoming like the
sequencing like I still a huge portion
of this plant that we have not been able
to really do R&amp;D on yet you know like
the the medicinal the true the true
medicinal side of it yeah and the gening
you know is a step in that direction
it's very difficult too A lot of people
don't understand this this this studying
it is very difficult yeah because you're
talking about a plant that changes from
micro variables it can change extremely
in a period of seven days 70 days of
flower or you know the veg plus the
flower whatever but we're looking at a
chemotype yeah they could be Changed by
influence of you know environment or
nutrition very easily right and so and
sometimes some stress factors could
cause it to change and so it's hard to
fully study something that changes so
much unless you can have a a chemotype
that stays the same or like for
manufacturing drugs yeah I mean how many
times have you saw something on the vine
cut it down put it in the bag and be
like oh that's that's gone it's not
there anymore you know so many times
especially phenoh hunting it's it's like
the winners aren't always the winners
you know when you're when you're
selecting on the plant as opposed to in
the bag it's amazing what a dare two can
do too like walk in and be like wow
that's amazing and then tomorrow's gone
you know it's just what yeah was it
environmental was it you know just one
portion of that you know that that that
makeup showing per a second you know
well then these these flavor molecules
can be deceiving so a lot of people if
you go by just a smell and you don't
actually taste it sometimes the taste
isn't there yeah or vice versa it smells
like mild but then you taste it it's
like wow it's overwhelming it's not
always the case a lot of stuff that's
loud is loud when you smoke it too but
it's it's interesting some of the stuff
that have like softer softer like smell
on the nose and then you you hit it and
it's like wow it's like then you get
softer chps but sometimes they're just
amazing yeah I think Skittles was like a
perfect example of that like yeah I
remember a friend in trucky had a a
mobile dispensary up there and that was
the first time I ever saw Skittles like
I I was dropping off some pounds to him
for the menu and he he was like check
this out and pick up the bag and it's
Depp you know and yeah at this time
Depp's probably going for two grand
$2,200 and he's like this is Skittles
and I was like kind of ugly you know and
think people usually say right when they
and I was like what you pay for this
he's like 3600 bucks I was like what
he's like open it open it smell I was
like that is different you know he's
like now let's go smoke it you know and
yeah I mean it's never judge a book by
its cover and I think a lot of these you
know a lot of these competitions are
done wrong too like I wish everything's
a blind taste test and like I think
that's how it should be done that's how
we do our fenal Huns it's like everybody
gets joints down no one gets flour I
know what the flower looks like let's
just smoke it and then we can talk about
the taste and the effect fortunately it
goes back to the the marketing the
Instagram like you know people want to
want to see it like yeah I mean I'm
excited about the day where they trust
the brand enough to where they don't
have to see the flower they can just buy
the pre-roll and be super happy and pay
premium prices on a premium flour
pre-roll that they're getting Super
Fresh but that also they need to smoke
it fresh especially something like a
joint where it's been ground up and then
put into a piece of paper and smoked you
want to smoke that sooner than later
they don't have as long of a shelf like
once you start [ __ ] with it you know
I I definitely see bran
you know recognition and brand loyalty
yeah like you said like it's tough It's
you know like here in California like
you know consumer package product like
it takes a month to get it to the Shelf
you know like it's impossible like to to
to get any quicker you know and but I
think you know like d Toc is is is come
in California it hasn't really taken off
yet I think right but you know like
hopefully you know with the the market
maturing and stuff people are going to
start like becoming loyal to Brands you
know like you see it with with wine or
beer you know we have a monthly
membership package for seeds and I can't
wait to the day where I can go to all
these yeah all these farmers and all
these guys with facilities that I'm
friends with yeah and get some sort of
monthly membership package in the mail
you know where you get you get the new
stuff that's coming down or maybe you
get to be part of the feno hunt or
whatever I think that monthly membership
package is amazing the the concept of
it's great but we can't do it yet in
California yeah yeah I know County that
I'm in trying to push that that farmers
market model you know there's so many
you know hoops and and things to jump
through but I think it's coming yeah I
mean you can go to Wineries and you can
hear stories about the wine maker and
how they made the wine and then get to
taste the wine there I mean I would love
to see humble and you know Trinity and
mesino and Sonoma especially to be able
to go up there and you go check out the
farm and you can watch them Harvest if
they're harvesting or at least hear the
stories and try the flower and you know
have a chill area and then you can
experience the different Terre from one
region to the next or one yeah one
climate to the next I think that's where
like the hash side too like you know
this is like what we're talking about
it's usually a little more btii you know
and I think you know I remember the
first time cutting down a greenhouse and
freezing it I think it was probably 156
you know like where there was like we're
coming out of the 215 into the it wasn't
we weren't regulated yet but it was just
like prices were crashing but the hash
prices were up and it felt so weird to
freeze a whole house ended up screwing
it up royally like you know my body was
like I'll just vacuum seal it throw it
in the freezer to me vacuum silly pull
all the hair out and crush the flow and
stuff like that so but like I think you
know being able to to put it into a
shelf life a little bit longer and stuff
like that like well rosin in extract is
a a great way it's another one it's like
a joint you don't actually get to see
the flower and you're just basing on the
especially on the taste and the effect
right so at the end of the day rosin you
you can go by what it looks like a
little bit but dude that's where like
the outdoor these guys are do an outdoor
rosin like top shelf stuff that's pretty
amazing colie a lot like yeah they do a
lot of washing for me on the the you
know the type six side um and I think
you know that that group is one of the
best in best in the business you also
work with paper planes like we have a
farm together um a lot of that stuff is
going to live live resin I like live
resin a lot and I was up in Washington
and I smoked a bunch of amazing live
resin up there and uh some people are
just stuck on the rosin there's nothing
wrong with rosin rosin's amazing too but
some good live resin yeah Skittles live
resin nuts it's crazy J like that's I
love that stuff when it's like when it's
on that level yeah I mean I think you
know B hydrocarbon got a bad name
because of the uh the refinement they
were doing for a bit uh all the carbons
and stuff they were you know purifying
it with it just came all monot turp oh
yeah I know exactly what you're talking
about with they're filtering it right
they're using charcoal and some other
stuff to filter it and stuff that wasn't
necessarily healthy and I mean it was
like I remember being up and humble you
know like people saying you know turn
your mold into gold you know and I think
it just goes back to the the product
you're putting in you know whether it's
raw resin whatever it is like if you're
putting quality material in qu right
fire out I mean this market like you
have to have price points you know like
different price price regions like rosin
is a little more higher shelf right and
not everyone can afford it you know but
like live resin a lot of people can
afford that you know and again going
back to you know techniques and and
things like that and and great product I
remember 2013 when the sauce first came
out from water dude that stuff was so
nuts it you know 30% TPS on some of it
which was like TP overload yeah seeing
some of the first shatter and stuff and
smoking it with some friends that was
like cracking and popping and like
totally I don't know about this stuff
again you know regulations spurring
Innovation and getting chemists and
stuff involved now and products are
getting better safer yeah made in the
actual lab environment not just on
someone's porch or her P stoop yeah
interesting times man it's great to be
part of the evolution of something this
big that's going to be this impactful
over the next however many years in the
future that that Humanity exists this is
impacting all of that future yeah I
remember you saying like you know
putting out the book and and doing this
podcast it's like it's solidifying our
our stamp on this history right you know
people coming you know uh in front of us
or you know like I think with ulation
like a lot of people forget about what
we went throughh you know and not just
me but like everybody everybody we so
easily forget about stuff right unless
you document it yeah and I think it's
important because like you know I've
been raid you know like we've been
harassed you know like in the county
like I took a step forward with actually
that that whole group of children that
we were talking about like you know
supplying them tinctures and and all
this stuff like our County decided that
they wanted to ban all commercial
cultivation and they banned all
commercial cultivation they made the
mistake of actually putting it on the
ballot yeah to to ask the county like do
you want to regulate cannabis it funny
you know I think like this industry a
lot of times we have so much like
headbutting you know and you have all
these different layers of people got the
hippies you got the you know all these
all these different people like and for
once it was cool to be a part of because
like everyone came together because
they're like okay okay this is US versus
them you know we ended up getting 75% of
the boote you know like in politics is
insane strategically we had some great
people helping us like Heather Burke
lawyer like she always kept us out of
jail and but you know she really was
like pivotal on like structuring this
and you know like it was it was a cool
thing to be part of because we you know
the county it's kind of funny the County
Nevada County Grass Valley Nevada City
is such a split County from Super crazy
liberals to like super crazy
conservatives yeah totally and it's like
it's this huge opposite end the
spectrums and you know obviously it was
it was pretty easy to like talk to the
Liberals and some of them might not
wanted you know regulation coming but
you know the conservatives like we we
played at different you know different
levels and would talk to them about this
also going back to land rights and stuff
like that and just you know like we came
and came together and was able to like
you know get get it overturned and you
know now regulated and and to me again I
go back it's it's one of the I think
it's one of the best microclimates in in
all California like just it's it's
Unique it's going up up to you know up
to the S Nevadas it's the Foothills so
you're getting like you know some of the
heat coming from the the valley but then
also these great little pockets of super
dry too yeah super dry yeah I I think
it's one of the better microclimates in
in the world it's funny because between
the mid part of California all the way
through Oregon I think for outdoor
cultivation that's the best in the world
absolutely I mean it's one of the seven
Mediterranean climates right like it's
like unfortunately like you know I think
when all this kind of figures itself out
like we're we're Advanced to that
portion where you can take indor and you
can throw it in New York throw in
anywhere in the world the right person
running it with the right genetics like
you're going to get a comparable product
right you know but again it's just like
no one has the sun we have here no one
has the climate we have here you know
and for either hash production or you
know outdoor it can't really be no and
I'm not saying there's not other places
that it can't be grown properly and done
well and I think you know there's places
in New Mexico and places in Arizona I've
seen some great some great hash come out
of New York you know with and I laugh
because like I grew up watching you know
the Thunders storm STS and the hail
storms and even portion of New York it's
you know hurricanes in September so it's
just like you know the the weather and
stuff that this plant gets beat up out
there too but I've seen some great stuff
come out of there so Jean West I don't
know if you know Jee he had kickass
Farms he's from Grass Valley he used to
be a maror man okay amazing guy name
sounds familiar yeah he was always doing
really creative things that were I think
really smart but what one of the things
he did that shocked me was he did this
technique called stock splitting that
you could only do in Grass Valley or in
someplace that was extremely dry because
he would veg the plants out about you
know yay high so and he would instead of
supercropping or topping them to get the
hormones to shoot out uh more branches
he would take and use a buck knife split
the stock down and then tape it at the
bottom and then without that it would do
it would have the same effect as topping
right and he would have these huge
plants with so many Bud sides and he'd
do that so he'd split it Crossways once
down and then he'd split those and so I
mean he would run the buck yeah you know
he had this video that always give me
like the Shivers so I see it like dude
you're killing that plant how can you do
that and I went out and saw his plants
and they were just amazing big huge tall
plants that he had topped like that and
you could only do that because of Bettis
and other fungal pathogens I think in my
opinion you could probably only do that
in a handful of places in the world and
be super successful with it but he also
watered because it's so dry he was able
to water from the top of the plant in
the morning okay and then he would water
from the bottom in the afternoon he cool
the canopy and so yeah he was doing all
kinds of really cool stuff I need to get
him on the show but he's a big Grass
Valley guy amazing he was an amazing
grower I think he's doing other stuff
right now but like so many people in
this industry they've gone kind of into
other occupations yeah some of these
people you know that that definitely you
know scream you know the benefits and
stuff like that unfortunately like some
of them aren't here anymore yeah I mean
we've lost a bunch of friends yeah you
know Jay being one of them but so many
Innovative people too and then also
other people just quitting because it
got so hard yeah and that's why I don't
do cultivation that's why cultivation is
not my jam I'd rather be into the pcks
and shovels and on the genetics much
much prefer because that's where my
passion Is It Anyway is with you know I
feel like I like exploring feel like an
Explorer from you know the like we're
we're going into new territory that
people haven't seen stuff seen these
profiles before and right I'm constantly
looking to be surprised to surprise
myself yeah but it's a lot of fun yeah
it is I I I share that thought with you
on on the breeding side of thing like
sometimes I think I'm like a a Serial
entrepreneur like I always want to like
you know like my whole life you are a
serial I I think you are a Seri like my
whole life is like my whole professional
life has always been like you know
startups in the tech industry and
startups here and yeah you know like
there's something about me that needs to
trying to go forward and be ahead of it
you know like and breeding kind of like
clears you know satisfies that you know
because I'm always getting something new
you know trying to put something new out
there yeah and it's the Long play You're
it's the long game for sure yeah
breeding is not just the the quick money
the quick this or the quick that it's it
takes a lot of time to do it
successfully to do it right I think
that's one of the like picks and shovels
that like I think now more than ever
like genetics are are are worth more
right you know like not having the right
genetic right now some of them some of
them of course of course but but it
proves the point right it's like if you
have the wrong thing even just green
right now and you're playing the
wholesale game it's going to be super
hard to get rid of it you're you know if
you have a purple candy runs Cross or
something you know like yeah and having
the right thing and understanding that
the market and what the Market's asking
for too like it's again it goes back to
the the procurement and that's one of
the things I do love about what I'm
doing right now is being able to curate
a menu of you know a percentage of them
have to be what the industry wants but
trying to find the best ones the newest
ones the unique ones you know and then
having a portion of the menu of you know
people putting things in the jars and
you know cultivators that don't have the
time to breed or fenal hunt and you know
unique strains and and unique Tarpin or
canabo profiles like yeah it's cool to
be part of it yeah it's a great time to
be alive so if people are interested in
finding more out about you where can
they go I'm getting ready to launch my
website but Instagram counterculture I'm
Christian with a K so it's a counter
culture countercore culture Orca pretty
active on on it conception nurseries is
conception nurseries decom same thing
with the Instagram as well too so nice
well one last question so if you had one
piece of advice for your younger self
that was just starting out in the
industry what would that be you know I
feel like you know people use a lot of
the same don't give up and you know I
was actually having a conversation with
a friend on the way here this morning
and and you know I think it's tenacity
you know like I was using the analogy of
of of baseball I love baseball I grew up
a big big Yankee fan my grandfather grew
up in New York watching in the Bronx
watching you know the Yankees play some
of my first memories are are you know
being you know going to to Yankee games
and stuff like that but I use the
analogy of business right it goes back
again to like you know being an
entrepreneur like pivoting and baseball
if you hit three out of 10 you're going
to the Hall of Fame right and I think in
this industry especially right now like
we can get really down on ourselves
because just the the state of it's in
you know it's a it's a [ __ ] roller
coaster for sure and from cultivation to
money being you know like so all the
games that we have to play right you
know the tenacity and I'm still in it
like a year ago like I was questioning
what I was doing you know like cuz I had
a a good you know path on on on the tech
side but it's really just tenacity none
of this was there there was no recipe
there was no book to follow like we've
all made mistakes in this Tre and it was
just like just keep going keep going
like don't don't let certain things pull
you down you know like honestly losing
Jay was a big honestly I didn't have the
time to actually process it um because
like I was literally in the middle of of
building a massive grow I literally left
there went to his funeral for 30 hours
how to come back and go right back to
work you know and it's just you know I I
feel like I've been on this course of
this industry for a reason and it's
almost like a blind faith kind of thing
so like I think what I would tell myself
is just just keep pushing you know like
again like you said can't really can't
really rely on what was in the past or
what's in the future but just being in
the moment i' probably actually i'
probably take that from you enjoying the
moment a little bit more you know being
being more present not trying to worry
like you know things covered or or
worrying about the mistakes we made in
the past it's like just enjoying right
now yeah I mean we're so blessed we are
so yeah so thank you so much for coming
on the show I look forward to doing it
again and I'll see you up in Sacramento
soon sounds good thanks yep have a good
one
[Music]
n