[Music]
oh
[Applause]
[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James loud
podcast and today our special guests are
Jack and Lance from Grove how are you
guys doing today we're awesome thanks
for having good man yeah thank you dude
thank you guys for coming on Lance this
is your second time on the show it is
man and Jack this is your first time on
the show So yeah thank you man this is
going to be a lot of fun thank you for
having me I'm excited to smoke some loud
awesome yeah so you are the co-founder
of Grove and you guys make the most
amazing TPL loock bags that you know I
used I I found out about turls trip
blocks from Lance originally and I was
like well it feels like just another
myar bag right but then Lance is like no
no no this is not just another myar bag
and I'm like okay sure right to test
things you have to test things and and a
big part of what I do is I do a lot of
testing you know at the facility at the
house I'm always testing AB testing one
thing against the other right and so I
basically took a turkey bag I took a
glass jar and I took a turp blck and I
put them on the shelf and I I've
basically evaluated them from week to
week month to month and Lance was right
it's an amazing bag and so you guys sold
me on that now now we got a James loud
TPL loock bag the second one the 2.0 man
dropped it we dropped the first one on
this show so thought it was fitting
especially bringing the man himself you
know to to be able to debut it here but
that's what I love about you you're
you're like me you love testing you you
stick with stuff that you enjoy and you
love but you're always open to trying
new things and that's the same way man
we both grew up in NorCal we both have
that mentality of like the wives tailes
with the glass jars and all the rest so
I was in the same position you were when
I discovered this years ago and it's
like just try it man and you did and the
proof's in the pudding you know the
proof is in the pudding and and you
can't refute the data right at the end
of the day like you can look four months
down the road and you can tell the
difference between the stuff that's in
the turkey bag and the Mason jar and
I've been a mason jar guy my whole life
and I don't use mason jars anymore you
know I'm waiting for you guys to come
out with the Mason jar so the Turlock
mason jar right I feel like that's the
future but uh you guys make a great
product and it's it's easy to use it's
easy to store um and it's not just
another myar bag like a lot of people
think yeah yeah so I want to get down to
where this all started with you and how
you got started with the concept with
the with the tur block and everything
else with
Grove um for me I you gotta kind of go
back to uh kind of my relationship with
cannabis that's what kind of got me
interested and gave me ideas and got me
curious about the the plan the plan sign
so uh my older brother Charlie uh has
pretty severe scal policy and moved out
to to California um and he's actually
the the first person uh who was um
totally disabled to graduate from UCLA
law school so that's a his his claan of
Fame obviously he got all the brains in
the family um but um he was out here and
he got a tremendous amount of relief
from Canabis so seeing the California
medical program you know when he was
home uh you know growing for him um you
know producing uh growing flower for him
before he was in in California full-time
um learning about flower you know is
expensive to grow could couldn't do it
at your parents house was a you totally
different era you know your your family
could lose everything if they found a a
grow in your house then you know talk
you know parents careers over you know
Bank drop them everything so um it was
it was tough and it was expensive so
when lost lost some flour due to you
know not not burping it properly which
you know I really came to understand
that we'll dive into you know that whole
misn what buring burping is anyway but
the flower that just would go bad and
kind of difficulty with the post Harvest
process and a lot of stuff that I found
deep online was really conflicting and
there was a lot of conflicting uh you
know uh UNC opinions about qualitative
seniors Without Really any quantitative
benchmarks and then you know fast
forward and I'm like oh man like I can't
wait to go to you know this dispensary
in Colorado like these guys is going to
this this is going to be the besteller
it's going to blow my mind like I go to
dispens I'm like all right cool this is
a pretty nice flower and you know go and
pop the pop top open the next day and
something we didn't know at the time was
like those DRS lose about 1% of internal
relative humidity for every you know
hour they're exposed to an aent
environment cuz they that bad of barrier
quality but anyway pop this pop up open
and I'm like what the [ __ ] like this is
boof yeah yeah and it was it was harsh
it was unpleasant to smoke Turing
profiles were gone medical value is gone
I was like well there's still still this
problem in cannabis you know even though
we're at this point like you maybe maybe
there's something to really do and add
value here cuz uh looking ahead it's
like all right this industry is going to
be competitive you know cannabis is not
always going to be $6,000 a pound in the
state people are going to jump in it's
going to be a different Market we really
need a professional standard of way of
doing things this industry is going to
you know mature rapidly quality
standards are going to go up rapidly uh
competitive you know um uh the
competitive environment is going to
intensify rapidly the need for
operational superiority and operational
Excellence is going to come rapidly um
so you know we were always confident
that and when we launched Turlock as as
a a
product really we had been through a lot
of different iterations to develop the
the you know the material or turock V1
um and then kind of had to let the
markets catch up to that a little bit
more still not that we didn't need to
grow into the market and grow into the
business and continue to do a lot of you
know research and development and
deepening our understanding but also
cannabis was selling so fast regulated
markets than no one um no one had any
any concern for a post harest process if
you looked at someone and told them that
there was actually intense difference
between drawing and caring they'd look
at you and their eyes would glaze over
right um yeah obviously you know we're
in a very different environment today
very different you know and I still love
a fresh product don't get me wrong I
think Fresh Products are good I certain
genetics you know I think they they're
the best fresh and then other cultivars
seem to be better once they're cured
longer well I think you have to Define
fresh yeah and then I you know so
defining fresh what does fresh mean in
cannabis yeah is fresh and cannabis
means something that has you know
prominent CES Turpin because you know to
me I expect that's a lot of you know
this this broad misleading definition or
term freshness was really a black hole
because I think Z and candy is a great
great example of that you know everybody
says they're sick as e but most of our
fridges are still full of it but you
know that point aside most of suppos are
pulling down Z you know a you know 7 8 n
10 days early right and why are we doing
that it's because of those fragile
profiles of sess with tpin sure so when
we're talking freshness is because cesco
Turpin in most packaging and for most of
us in the the industry um you know
whether you're a prosumer homeg grower
you know a top not Facility have a loose
standard around their free versus bound
water and the life cycle of of product
moving through through their facility
and that's that's what's you know plays
into our concept of freshness I think we
we saw that with you know Z Olympics
recently too where you know a lot of the
people that I I think are the the a lot
of top of game players in the industry
but you know the samples you know take
takes a while to go through and smoke
all the samples if a judge going for two
three four weeks have a you know even
top tier product from Top tier
professionals if it's you know if we're
if the competition's not leveraging the
right supply chain packaging technology
not um not harnessing the right life
cycle so is of the right life cycle
product it's U it's doing a disservice
to to what that cultivator intended to
have reviewed in that competition and I
think we we've seen that you know really
play out and become a Forefront of
conversation as you know sh had time and
an opportunity to really you know get
scientific about about post Harvest and
post Harvest life cycle yeah and post
Harvest life cycle understanding that
well that's that's not just drying and
caring being difference between drying
and caring but that's drying and person
caring that's the life cycle of the
product in in my facility through
packaging sorting you know pre-rolls
whatever and that's also also the life
cycle of the product of the consumer
yeah post Harvest has been overlooked
for so long and it's still being
overlooked by a lot of communities and a
lot of places you know I was just in St
Vincent and I think there's awareness
and there's some people working towards
it but you know especially in places
know California is not as big of a deal
with post Harvest as somewhere like St
Vincent or the Caribbean that is super
humid because the humidity just destroys
turs and that's why they like our
product you know we've been Down To
Jamaica we did a trip uh the team out to
Thailand earlier last year um Hawaii uh
for their annual uh Cannabis Expo in
Jero those high humidity markets they
really love the technology because
they're like I'm not fighting this
ambient anymore you know they they don't
need any active atmospheric modifiers
that's the interesting thing is some
people are using humidity packs or
things like that that's the last thing
you need in those type of environments
you need something that creates that
barrier from that outside higher R
because 70 80 90% relative humidity is
not uncommon to your point in those
environments so having a technology that
can actually preserve that flower as
it's meant to be consumed by the grower
By You By Me by all of us that grow yeah
it's pivotal you know for sure
definitely matters yeah I think there's
there's a lot of a lot of attention
being being paid to um the the the
critical impact of the the postart cycle
cycle particularly on you you know
bottom lines of organizations I think in
you know especially with you know how
intensely competitive California Flower
Market is yeah for example if you're if
you're a grow that
produces let's say 1,000 lounds of of
weight of year that's 44,400 lb of of
flour right or grams of flour if you
have a 3% loss weight from a bad
management of bound versus Unbound
flower it's directly translates to 3% of
your Topline Revenue disappearing
yeah and um it's and not only does you
know are we talk are these metrics that
we're really trying to talk about and
buil ey around directly correlate to
Topline revenue from we perspective it's
actually you know directly correlating
to you know the uh most uh valuable and
fragile parts of the plant yeah and
these days I mean quality is so
important for All Brands but especially
the guys the the middle siiz companies
we're not talking about the Giants right
but for the small businesses quality is
everything quality comes down to your
success or your failure in the in the
wreck Market especially y uh otherwise
it's just a race to the bottom if you're
in the middle so I that could that could
be the difference of keeping your your
business alive or your business failing
and then storage now because there's
this abundance of product available uh
your your product might not get consumed
for two or three or four months that's
when you really have to be concerned
with how is it being stored you know
I've been talking I mean you guys were
in my book I featured yeah your bags in
my book also the refrigerated model I
think everything needs to be store it at
a colder temperature from the time it
leaves your facility where you've
obviously tried to store it and keep it
in a controlled environment the time the
consumer gets it you need to control
that product as much as possible people
don't talk hey well I think you're
you're talking about do points and
stressor the flower there yeah um we've
seen that play out a lot and certainly
you know frustrations in different
markets for for example Ontario work
with a you know some really talented
folks out there um and the um on and you
product and sit in warehouses very poor
climate conditions for months yeah and
what we're we're talking about there
when you're bringing flour from you know
very cold environments let's say below
below 45 degrees Fahrenheit super warm
environments and I would Define that as
above 70 degrees Fahrenheit what you're
doing is you're really stressing flow
you're dramatically increasing
respiration rate for some of those
volatile organic organic compounds and
you know what's going on there is
actually really negative the same way
burping is really negative because you
then have containers and storage
conditions that don't allow those
volatile organic compounds a chance to
settle and re re reattach and stabilize
flow when you're doing any sort of
burping or evacuation or flush or you
have leaky packaging or you have
packaging with Bad Barrier Properties or
you know bad oxygen transmission rates
or moisture VOR transmission rates that
you know and it's really not lined up
with this particularly with the you know
the water activity level of flour and
it's you know unth thoughtful storage
environments you have dramatic
qualitative you know damage happening at
all of those points and then it kind of
comes together particularly when you're
stressing flower outside of those ranges
you really don't have the same product
that you you submitted anymore and
that's it's unfortunate it's unfortunate
uh so let's talk about burping and what
goes on with burping and why tur blocks
have such a huge Advantage if you're
using them as opposed to the traditional
burp burping methods MH just finished a
study on that great question yeah um
just finished a study on that which uh
um Lance will touch on a little bit love
it if you gave a little teaser because
we're com coming out with that we're
we're pretty psyched about what we
studied and who we worked with on and I
think you know one of the things we've
always hoped to do as a business is kind
of further the conversation and curing
and storage and post Harvest life cycle
of flower post harest observational flow
uh but the burping versus you know the
passive G gas exchange that really comes
down to when you have a an agitation
state of flour you have a tremendous
amount of volatile organic compounds
that are within the head space of your
container vessel and by doing a a you
know burp which is really a full evacu
evacuation or flushing you're expelling
those volatile organic compounds out out
of out of the package so once you know
that you know when you open up you know
that pack package you know so depending
on some devices they might say well you
know they might be reinforced the
science of well you have a monolayer of
humidity that's kind of protecting the
product and sure but once that product's
add shade and broken you should really
be hit with an overwhelming you know
smell and that's that's the volatile
organic compounds but when you go into
facility and they're you know burping
and purging containers and you know the
the Cure room and the dry room is being
burped and you you smell that that's
that's not what I want to see in in a in
a in a cure cure and Storage room I want
to you know I want to see that a little
bit under controlled setting in your dry
stage but in your cure stage that to me
that's major qualitative loss points
you're opening that toad you're
agitating that flower you're exposing it
to to Raw air you know you're releasing
it ton oh wow that room smells great
that flowers is going be loud that's
that's a qualitative that's a tangible
qualitative loss Point yep yeah and I
think when we talk about burping as
being an art form that is an art form
when you're having to do it by hand and
you're not able to you know and it comes
out different every time so then it does
when you're doing it to that extent it
is an art form right but it doesn't have
to be it's it's an art form because it's
been a response to the physiological
nature of the plan and our understanding
of how to process it and handle it but
at at this stage in our industry we we
know and have researched and explored
and have quantitative bases that
directly correlate to these these
qualitative metrics right you know and
might say for example what's this guy
talking about well we all have the
classic 90° stem test right where a stem
should bend and then snap at you know
cleanly at 90 well that directly
correlates to about five. 5859 water
activity level in my experience and
there is there is a degree of VAR you
can get into V degrees of variation
nuances A variation for cultivation
style or cultivar uh and by cultivar I
mean dominant turpine profiles which
very interesting stuff get into a little
bit more but that's a that's a pretty
consistent standard so and then saying
well you know what's what's my bound
versus you know free water in the plant
what's what's really ideal what's the
the defini definitive you know litmus
test point when flowers is done drying
and entering curring well you know I
would say very very clearly you know
James has 0.58 to to 0.59 you know all
all day I would say 62 I would say
that's a little too much you you have a
for a little bit more you know Top Line
you know weight the the flower cannot
use that much Unbound water you have a
dramatically higher increase of
microbial you know you could really get
into diving signs there but that that's
that's really where we know we want to
be a flower in terms of both it's
optimized Health State and it's optim
it's optimized you know bound water
content for actually weight at point of
sale nice yeah we focus all that right
for me I'm I'm limited in being outdoor
grower to Mother Nature but for indoor
you know like your operation here the
one we toured earlier you know when
you're God growing as I say and you have
control over that ambient that existing
environment we put so much focus on what
is you walk into a veg State and you
feel the higher humidity you feel how
the air is just heavier and then you
feel how it's a bit lighter as we
transition into flower with indor you
know we put so much emphasis on things
like that that ambient RH and then it
seems to get a bit of lot of loss of
focus post Harvest and the things that
we're finding just statistically you
know there's an average of six touch
points between takeown and consumption
so this chain of custody like to your
pointing what Jack was is mentioning
with our friends up in Canada finding
that there's opportunities for a fail on
what should be that top-notch end
product because of the fact that you
have a variance in your relative
humidity you have a variance in your
ambient temperatures again to his point
not to pick on Canada but Health Canada
did kind of miss the mark on having more
strict regulations around that chain of
custody because something goes to his
point from what might be an ideal
temperature and ideal relative humidity
room or or space for this product it
goes into a truck
that might be out in freezing
temperatures crossing over from you know
wherever Ontario to Quebec and then all
of a sudden that product is brought back
up to a room temperature and you're
really shocking the plant and we try to
educate Growers that you and I talked
about this all the time man growing's
only half the battle any smart grower
and I respect it fullterm weeks on weeks
on weeks on weeks months of of waiting
for this plant to be done but you can
mess it up you can mess it up in the dry
you can mess it up in the cure to Jack's
point you can mess it up in the
processing the packaging and even
putting it on the shelf so that's where
we're trying to get people to focus more
because there is a lot going on and a
lot of people don't realize you chop the
plant from its life force it's not dead
that's a crazy thing man the studies and
going back to the study that we're going
to be releasing next week we did it with
our friends at CRC Dr Alison Justice
who's very focused like us she loves
tping she loves that whole post Harvest
element that's where she focuses the
things that we are finding are
staggering as far as what's going on to
your point in a typical you know
metalizer met pet package a myar package
if you will versus in something like TPL
Block versus something like a glass jar
or a glass jar or um or a Met pet pack
with say a humidity pack like scene
where like certain things that you add
into that environment actually increase
the oxygen which we don't want we don't
want oxid I mean I love CBN but I love
THC over CBN any day you want a little
bit of O that's where we kind of get
back to curated curated gases just the
the same as we know now that a lot of us
lot of lot of guys are focusing on in
their in their Gardens um gas measures
in the rooms you know pump pumping CO2
and what not in the room so actually I
deal gas mixtures you know for for the
plant in terms of pro post Harvest
respiratory environment because you
still have residual enzimatic processes
and biologic processes going down even
if the the plant is no longer in its you
know primary feeding stage of its life
right a good example of that is you know
us monitoring and and through this study
you know the plant as much as it takes
in CO2 and puts puts off oxygen which is
why we live all these bushes and trees
and and living things around us where we
survive and and live the same thing is
going on post Harvest where we're seeing
instead of taking in CO2 and putting out
oxygen it's actually putting out CO2
with a minute amount of oxygen and
that's these gases that we're studying
and going how does this affect the
sugars how does this affect affect the
turpine profile the canabo profile so
it's really eye openening when you do
start kind of pulling back and putting
as much focus on post Harvest as you do
on on harvest itself right growing
itself so pretty it's just important
post harus i' love to yeah yeah yeah
let's Fire Let's fire this up here what
what's the Jame loud podcast without
some loud so this is some I call it dirt
Skittles oh man
this this is some dirt ground Skittles
outdoor for the win yeah so hi from
humbled seedco was on a podcast a while
back and we did the side by side with
the Coco versus the soil that was the
only variable that we changed it was in
the same room plants were grown very
like rose next to each other and you
know it's these These are the Smalls
that's well I like not uncomon I don't
small either there's still quality there
it grind the same you know so they don't
drip as hard as maybe the the bigger
buds but as far as flavor I really enjoy
the flavor from it um it has good Ash
has not that that's like necessar a
quality indicator lot of emphasis on the
ash I'm with you hypothetically speaking
some of the stuff I've seen in Japan in
terms of the living living soil Gardens
yeah yeah is like just the most
unbelievable turb profiles for like very
unique Nuance turbs i' I've never seen
yeah yeah Rock Wall Coco nothing against
these
other yeah yeah Japan does special
things with fruits and vegetables and
I'm sure they can apply that to their
knowledge with cannabis we really praise
and you know kind of the Dutch
agricultural tradition you know as as
you know farmers and Growers especially
out here in the US you know um I we do
not talk enough about um Korean and
Japanese styen of farming and soil
practices yeah you know I you know I I
know some of the best best Growers I
know in the United States I'm talking
very you know small few rooms one room
couple rooms you know stuff's always
sold out to to one guy and no question
like if you don't know anybody good luck
you'll never see the flower type of
stuff we all know this folks right um
the the guy considers just his dirt the
most valuable valuable thing he has has
been working on that dirt and that dirt
profile for 20 years it all starts man
yeah yeah and I think as a craft product
I do enjoy soil there's nothing wrong
with Coco I use coco in my facility
right yeah yeah we use Rock Woolf for
moms and we use for the plugs we use
rock wool as what stonewool stonewool is
what they're calling it now sorry guys
Stone
ambiguous term many many cup winers do
do the same thing yeah yeah yeah and I
think we we well we have a sterile
facility or as sterile as possible we
basically have a closed circuit system
here we're not bringing in new things
that could introduce pests or uh any
sort of viruses so you know it's like we
do everything from tissue culture our
seeds that we pop even we we test those
to make sure we don't have viruses and
viroids uh but as far as smoking best of
the best I do enjoy soil so you know and
there's nothing wrong with rock wool or
coco I think they're both great
substrates and they both have their
purpose um they're are masters of every
medium I mean I've seen oh yeah I've
been smoking a lot of rockwool weed
believe it or not and then I wasn't even
told till after like three months that
oh yeah dude that's all that's all grown
with grodan dude and I was like cool
that's great I like grodan I like them
as a company I like them as people
especially the people that work for the
company yes um which matters yeah for me
that matters right as a small business
owner as someone who builds a a their
work culture with good employees I have
a lot of respect for companies that have
good people that work for them if there
true if let me put some [ __ ] asteris
on that like you know if if the there's
got to be people at that company that
have been there for a while yeah you
know like I I you know I every industry
has EVs and flows and grows and Booms
and Bs but if the only guys that have
been in a business for more than you
know three years are the the owners like
yeah that's that's always red flags red
flags all over yeah that's like a guy
that's like a guy with no old friends
yeah but we spent a lot of time I mean I
see you guys at shows we go to the same
shows there's always Cutting Edge we got
royal gold kpl loock I mean you guys are
Staples I feel like I enjoy going to
events and hanging out with Lance yeah
uh you don't go to as many events but
I'm sure I go to a lot of events I
I we divide and
conquer I'm not in
California much I spend spent a lot of
time in California in 25 but I mean
California I mean you go a California is
a br brutal Market it's a brutal Market
that's for sure yeah and it's tough to
come in and be like I have a new way of
doing things you know a lot of people
like [ __ ] off well the reason Hard Sell
right the reason we have such well the
reason our sale is so consultative be
like I want you to try it you know I
respect what you do I've smoked your
gear I bought your gear like you know
I'm going to give you some bags this is
how I want you to try them out this is
how I want you to use it this is It's
kind of the SOP this is the philosophy
behind the the SOP right um have have to
be consultative you have to get people
able to try it well it's A Hard Sell
because there's so much snake oil and
there's so many people saying I have the
best product and it's not the best
product yeah you know and you guys
actually do have have the best product
that I've seen for for curing for
long-term storage I think you guys are a
great solution I tested you know I was
working with JJ and we tested the the
actual seed storage and I think that's a
game changer we we've got some exciting
work we've made on that they um R&amp;D
team's doing a lot of a lot of cool
stuff yeah right right now um but it's
it's an exciting time I mean with with
groups like CRC really pushing forward I
mean even even some of the stuff that
you know our colleagues industry you
know I I will say you know um canr is
doing a focusing on a lot of the right
stuff in terms of free water and bound
water yeah and kind of their their
philosophies they're really you know I'm
I'm really impressed with you know some
of our colleagues in in the space in
general just even you know in in that
are trying to service this category in
terms of how how much deeper the the
knowledge Bas is is how much more
scientific and you know want the the you
know be best best product to to win yeah
you know well you know hopefully we we
out innovate ourselves versus someone
out out innovating us we we try to do
that but it's it's a very exciting time
in terms of you know we're we're
learning more about the true physiology
of the plant and we're going to learn
more in the next year than we have
collectively learned as industry over
the last 20 I know it's so wild and I
mean just learning about the plant for
for me from a cultivation standpoint
with different cultivars in different
places like St Vincent and the
Grenadines where I've been yep and uh
Washington State and growing outdoors
and comparing the two you know it's it's
a beautiful thing when you can start
comparing and contrasting using
different climates for the same genetics
and being able to compare and I mean
they've been doing it AEG forever and
now we're able to do it really focused
in cannabis we have the software we have
the the manow and and like the amount of
learning that we're able to do in such a
short period of time compared to what's
beenen happening before pretty amazing I
was with the you gentleman today and
we're we're going through his his
facility and we've got you know looking
at five years of hard true data across
every variable for the life cycle of all
the flower that amazing came through the
facility it's you know I I'm talking you
know temperature chain of custody I'm
talking you know um moisture content not
water activity but moisture you know
still doing a lot of moisture content
chain of custody gas gas mixtures in the
room um life cycles all all
variabilities like it's it's really it's
it's fascinating in terms of and this
was in Oakland this Oakland he's cre
Sops and you I think you know I think he
told me to tell you hi so I'll share who
it is off fine but but he's creating
Sops not just for the operation and its
totality but he's creating Sops that are
cultivar specific which is pretty epic
so talking to this gentleman who comes
from the techn techology space which I
respect that was my other life you know
he is looking at it from such an
objective perspective and he's stepping
back and going okay I need to make this
the most efficient it can be and so
thing Jack and I were talking about you
know I I'm like you I'm more of a land
race guy I respect the new stuff which
jack is all into but he's like these are
the cultiv ours at work these are the
Sops I have and he puts them in rotation
he knows what he's growing a year and a
half out from now which is insane that's
how scheduled and how regimen I think
know
yes you know who this is yeah I mean
talk to him like this like next level
he's getting into light spectrums we're
we're we're J in light pigments we're
kind of kind of jumping all over and
yeah I mean that's that's you know
that's a Obsession but what what Lance
is building on there and I think this is
a great philosophy to have in a facility
is you know
removing removing opportunities for
variabilities um
removing opportunities for error
removing opportunities for mistakes just
kind of the SOP workflow processes you
know it's it's you know this was so much
more of a you know um Automotive
production facility than a yeah it
really was widgets that's why I was
referencing he's looking at as a widget
which is not a bad thing like sometimes
I think those of us who are emotionally
attached to this plant and compassionate
for it like we do kind of Miss stepping
back and going let's look at different
objectively it's like a real estate
developer that falls in love with the
building and gets totally underwater on
the building and you know and and let's
then chases the building down you it's
the same same same type of of concept
you know I think you have to have vision
and romance to be a builder of anything
real real estate too but also need to
Tamper that and be like I'm I'm in love
with this building but I'm I'm the world
is not in love with this building
that'll let it go same way same way you
know chasing a strain or new skew or a
new product or
for
me I believe you have to be devoted to
the product for me it's like a
devotional thing but I have a I have a
business partner who's my balance which
is great and we have a whole team of
people that you know I can start chasing
stuff down rabbit holes real quick and
sometimes it's like you got to stay
balanced right and so well you do it's
it's and it's not a yin and yang but
your partner you guys are very well
balanced and it is interesting because
you respect what he brings to the table
he respects what you bring to the table
but you're right you need that just in
general and and that's one thing that
came up again in this conversation was
um I don't know if you've toured any of
the family grows in Hawaii but that's
what I talked about was how you know
those people pass on the genetics from
generation to generation they keep
growing the same plant they're not
chasing the latest candies or dessert
cultivars and that's the interesting
thing too with this individual is he's
doing a rinse and repeat but the thing
is he's got the client he he pre-cells
that's something you mentioned I I know
very few guys that pre-sell very the the
cottage sub Acer guy okay but the guys
that are scaled not so much and this guy
pre- sells a majority of his flower
because they know what they're going to
get the best guys all do I would say the
best guys all see it with guys that are
above a th000 pounds a there's not a lot
of guys at scale that are like yeah
thousand pounds a month surprised me
with this bigger than a large homes
basement footprint no yeah yeah yeah
there's only a handful of guys doing
yeah yeah but it is impressive because
he's proving that you know not to get
into a bigger infil philosophical and
it's a whole tangent but it makes you
step back like we visit our friends up
at cbcb and Berkeley you know shout out
to Jimmy and the crew and you know I was
asking them like what's hot what's not
what's moving what's not and seeing some
of the class like saw Northern Lights I
was surprised to see an L NL I was
surprised to see a um what was the other
one was a Derman poison which I question
it's Purity but I'm like does that sell
compared
to I mean for us like we're we you know
we live world peace through turps like
we we like our team is like we you know
Julian's you know been to Durban you
know and like so we yeah I know real
Duran yeah yeah but it's you know me and
I have not seen a lot of real Durban in
the market n um I love Durban and it was
part of like foundational for the group
that I work with we had Durban Poison it
was one of the things along with Sour
Diesel and a bunch of things back in the
day really distinct Shing profil very
distinct and the thing is is if I
smelled real Durban right now I'd be
like that's it but a lot of this hazy
stuff is not the real Durban that I had
uh it leans towards this this hazy side
and there's nothing wrong with that no
but it's not the Durban that I remember
that was really you know it was really
big and it had bright orange hairs it
was it was almost like yarn growing we
remember as kids it really was for me as
a consumer as an Enthusiast or ahead you
know like I got to tell you James I
don't even know how much I care that
it's like not that authentic of durman
because it's getting it's
getting more people and more consumers
and granted we're talking about a
smoker's dispensary right like you know
there there's casual dispensers and
there's dispensors for the Dr public
there's smoker dispensers absolutely but
you know we're talking about a prodct
here if you're getting people interested
in land races and genetic profiles and
turine profiles that's a good thing that
it is an amazing thing and it's a great
thing you know I think diversity
especially pushing the agenda for
diversity within the plant we keep
bottlenecking ourselves Europe did it
with Haze a long time ago we did it with
gelato from from cookies to gelato to
this candy I'm enjoying this y I'm
enjoying this side it's got like a nice
nice nice soci energy kind of clean Z
proper FL proper cure I'm golden yeah so
I think pushing the agenda on getting
people reintroduced to L race and that's
a lot of the stuff I'm doing is taking
old genetics and mixing them with the
new stuff and trying to reintroduce him
that way that's I always liked about you
because you do very few guys do I I like
sharing that experience with people and
I feel like we had Dave from budalo on
our podcast and he's really pushing the
long flowering variety agenda and trying
to like Cuban pffs that are like running
like late 70s 80 days more he's got some
pearls you know like I mean those things
are amazing and I think they need to be
shared with people because it's about an
experience and if you can get people to
try those things in the right
environment and they get the same
experience that you do they'll fall in
love with it it has to be curated
there's also there's a there's a you
know there's a viability to it too you
know that's kind of one of the cruel
sides of the market is absolutely you
know people people have to you know you
got to grow to pay bills you got to grow
grow for yields if you're growing for
res you got not everybody can grow a
16we variety and be successful most
people can't right but there is a niche
market for the people that do most
people aren't aren't don't have any
business that's that's built for it no
no no and you really need to have a
facility that's geared towards growing
those type of genetics and you need to
have a a model that can sustain you know
a production cycle like that not even at
that even as a home I think I told you
this I got um some first round from Cal
C code
you a friend just asked if could first
it was a zoss with Tai it was a very
land heavy and that thing was the
longest term I ever so even as a homeg
grower to your point like wanting it as
medicine or just being cognizant of the
season and the bandwidth you have and
your spare time those are pain in the
ass man to run it a month or two longer
than I'm accustomed to as a grower you
know the end product was phenomenal
don't get me wrong but it was like geez
man like it's too much I'm going to grow
some soil uh Sour Diesel next year
Outdoors that's my goal is to grow the
real Sour Diesel cut next year outdoor
just for personal because I love it so
much you have the seed because that's
when I do have true seeds from oh no
there's no TR there will you will not
find Sour Diesel real Sour Diesel in my
opinion in seed I I've been searching
finally at reggae I met Dave and he's
got the real cut yeah and so that is the
only real Sour Diesel I remember one
Sour Diesel we can argue about all these
different sour diesels oh my God what I
remember as Sour Diesel is what Dave has
and in my opinion there might be other
sour
derives most excited from just a
consumer head you know perspective like
about what he's working on because to me
that's the most authentic like the you
know like the kind of like like the
throat kind of the I remember the res
and the smoke it had a very distinct tur
like really like like kind of Co coughed
your throat almost like kind of like
Wretch like it's you kind of you had a
film on your throat you know you like
you you you know exactly what I'm about
well it had to be harvested correctly it
had to be dried and cured and stored
correctly otherwise it wouldn't have
that expression that you were looking
for yeah but it had it had a punch to it
a thickness or a not like a not a creamy
smoothness but a cream like they could
play with like milk to the to the
Smoke yeah it was like just like a great
batch was just in intense resin like
resin like that on Most flowers you not
want to smoke you'd be like oh you is
better for washing but it it yeah I i'
um there's a reason so many people are
are chasing it and I think there's
reason so many people are excited that
are you know that are you know that and
there's a lot of people that think
they've seen it because they've seen a
derivative but they've never seen the
real deal just like ciss ciss is another
one it's like those things in their
optimal environment cured dried
correctly grown correctly checking all
those boxes along the way all those
touch points and you get this amazing
thing but that's the beauty of cannabis
is like you could have it and it's very
difficult to grow and difficult to
execute properly and each time is
slightly different on a craft level well
I mean it's it's a qualitative
expression of a you know of a of a of
crop right of a plant you know that's
that's that's the fun that's the joy
that's the that's the passion to it
right I think if you talk like you know
the the heads of the cigar space right
like you talk like you know old man
padron the padron you know cigar compan
is a lot of tobacco vertically
integrated tobacco company from you know
from genetics you know from Cuban seed
that they took when they were refugees
from from Cuba um to you know their
their harvesting and you know it's a
fermented product right it's big big
difference there cannabis is not not
fermented in terms we're talking about
the Aging right but um kind of you know
the admitting the the natural
variability to it being the element to
it you you that that is the the thrill
of like the great you know great bag or
like popping you know that seed like you
know for for people that truly in the
know that can appreciate that like
inexplicably like you know this this
batch of cigars like these these cigars
in this corner of this box they these
were the hitters out of it but that's
where they're similar right because
you're you're we're talking you know the
genetics but genino and feno are a
factor and you talked about the side by
side with soil right and that's John
from raay Cannabis good buddy of mine up
out of soam you know he'd surprise me
every year and he'd bring down I
remember one year when wedding cake was
popping off he didn't tell me he brought
in all his he always would bring in a
dozen jars to Emerald cup and just SL
through the side door and he put three
jars in front of me and he's like which
one of these three are your favorite and
I picked the one which was my favorite
I'm like but they they all have a
similar profile and he's like these are
all wedding cake he's all wedding cake
indoor wedding cake like dep wedding
cake outdoor you chose the outdoor it
was insane how different these three
plants looked at the end of that just
based on how they and all all soil
that's the crazy part it was all soil it
was just it's environmental they're
going through very different light
spectrums right light spectrums and
again you know the appalaches of the I
mean he was 45 minutes Issa Acer so he
doesn't even get much of the fog bank
it's a whole different world there
versus The Rock or versus Fort Bragg you
know it's insane but that does make an
impact and that's where a lot of the
argument was around respecting the
Appalachia like what makes it a true
Appalachia can you replicate that sun
Spectrum indoor and take that soil Indo
and create all the other the fog bank
and all these other factors and it was
decided no you can't it literally it has
to be within these quadrants and it has
to be grown here in order to be
champagne because if it's outside the
Champagne region it's called sparkling
wine for sure a marketing thing too
right I mean there's pros that that hit
and everything else but it's or you know
the same thing in you know scotch versus
whiskey you know you kind of really
start to get into it and then like well
you know in cannabis you know you talk
about with you know we were talking
about some of the the hats you got there
and some of the rods and whatnot you
talk about single Mall versus you know
versus blended right yeah yeah and then
if you talk about single malt some
people would say well you you got a
limited number of flavor profiles in
single malt which is why we blend have
you know the richness of the phone well
that's that's why hash makers blend
right that's an I'm I'm curious I know
I'm not the
interviewer now weting deep now he's
lighting the second one up that's one
thing is interesting I'm curious and not
to it James I I always do this to you
man but I'm curious of your thought
because as much as we've done you know
jessis have done a great job of blending
up and taking the best of the haze and
the best of the gas and the best of the
sour all these things but one thing I'm
starting to come across a little bit
more is people blending which this is
very similar to Wine sure where they're
taking a SAS Mero out of Australia and
making but I'm starting to see people do
that with blending Cult of ours post
Harvest it's so funny uh we talked about
this on my last podcast a little bit
about hash and I think
the has is going to be blending know
whether it's rosin or whatever it's here
it's here already but I see it just
growing and growing and growing I mean I
think it's very easy to do and if you
have somebody who's who loves the plant
who enjoys that process they can come up
with some wild combinations that you
couldn't get from breeding I mean you
can get an interesting look at breeding
if you combine two things and you like
smoke them you're like well maybe this
is what I get it never pencils out quite
like that but it's an interesting way to
do it and I feel like they do it with
wine do it with so many things whis whis
wh I I love that like you know I I got
to sit in on a a Helios uh those guys
are out of main do a killer job you know
a lot of us know who that who they are
um know shout out to homie Mike but but
got the and kind of just kind of
blending and tasting testing but you can
use you know polar opposite tping Tesco
turpine profiles I mean you you you
can't do that with one one you can't
produce a spectrum of of tpin you know
flavors oids whatever you want to go uh
in one plant you know they because
certain turine profiles can cannot exist
in harmony with them one one plant right
that's why I want to find out you know a
good ex I think I brought this up with
you because I don't think you have it in
your collection but Julie from sweet
grass out in Colorado she always ran
sweno and sweno is a literal Cross of
sourd and blue dream the two most
selling strains of the 2000s period
because we had all the access to that
information at weed maps and that's what
I'm curious I want to run both of those
and then consume it and see what the
similarities are to sweno cuz sweno was
a very unique where like if you wanted
to lock and watch Netflix you could but
if you wanted to bust out the vacuum
it's kind of weird you're cool with that
too like it was this really unique
balance of these two extreme worlds that
always were segregated for all those
years you know so that's why I was just
curious in asking you man because I
think Blends are the future so I got a
question for you you tasted this how
many months ago was this harvested
before eating you got to try
so we're going to do a little test here
I know know you're more of a more if you
guys were to guess on the age of that
product what would you
say this is me
one was one of my favorite
questions I'm gonna go all in several
months several months what is several
months that that is some seriously aged
flower in my opinion it does not tastes
fresh to me it tastes like it's
definitely been cured in in age not just
cured so I would say take
down that was last season I mean for
sure that was last season it's super
smooth though man and I and that's where
I argue and the Italians taught me and I
totally believe it and we did a study
out of with a lab in La pooke I could
believe that's six to eight months old
and was
was the smoothness of it and the way
it's burning the flower is so stabilized
the I think that's one thing you can
take from the tobacco industry so this
is some chop Cherry I put this in a turp
blog 10 months ago yeah oh wow I've been
saving this for Lance to come on the
show is so smooth man and uh 10 months
in the tur Block in a 60° room right so
like you kept it in perfect conditions I
mean yeah you know what you're doing
with drying it but like that's like it's
it's so smooth yeah and it's it checks
the boxes right as far as joint we got a
beautiful Ash forming we've got a we got
a nice ring forming it's smooth but uh
but the secret is the the tur block you
and I have talked about this James like
seriously and it I think it was a year
before we did the Epic interview that
that never ended up coming into fruition
out in Barcelona but I met these
Italians sorry guys if I'm repeating the
story but met these Italians and they
started going on to me about not just
curing but aging the butt I'm like where
you they're like it's just like wine
with the Turpin and maturing I in my
opinion you're a phenomenal grower and I
already hype you to to everyone I know
CU I love your flower but that is so
smooth dude like there's no Ting there's
and I mean you flushed it well I'm sure
you cured it well but that is extremely
smooth and that's why I age my stuff and
I have stuff that's two years old and
people like what the [ __ ] do you turn
into because I do love everyone knows
I'm an Edibles guy but no a lot of that
stuff I save it to smoke because it
changes I mean I like fresh flour too
don't get me wrong but I feel like
there's there's some I love testing
stuff too so I'm like well how long can
we keep this and does it still taste
good you know are the turps still there
you know I smoked some 5-year-old stuff
out of my freezer the other day it was
it was okay it wasn't the best but it
wasn't completely bad it was better than
what most people smoke it's better than
the dime bags we getting as kids right
yeah it's better than the the average
stuff that you buy at the dispenser even
like it still had enough TPS so how are
you bringing it back to temperature so
defitely talking about D points so
before we go too far one of the things
we're talking about in terms of curing
wine again Gus is not a faned product
but in terms of curing wine wine cures
differently in different bottle sizes it
does totally because it has different
interior interior D points right same
thing with cannabis right you know
people like well I'd rather rather have
a batch you know I'd rather have you
know this great year this great vintage
yeah you know the the James loud you
know you know Cherry from early 2024 you
get a j botm size volume so it's
actually whole you know optimal bad
sizes for the curing and storage of
cannabis yeah I agree and I mean I have
my own very rustic way of doing it it's
a nice way to put it but I do a sandwich
bag with an ounce and I wrap that in the
sandwich bag then I vacuum seal it
Loosely I label it and I put it in the
freezer I've been doing this for a long
time so we definitely got to get you our
saac like you will love it man if if
you're get saac for sure yeah but you
know I wanted to surprise you guys with
something since you guys surprised me
with something I I didn't know you guys
were bringing new bags I'm glad you did
that's really cool well the official
launch for your well this will be
perfect timing but the official launch
will be at tpami we're going to excit
yeah tpami will be there together I'm
not sure if this will air before tpami
or not if not you guys is a great event
in fact it it will yeah dude TP well I
mean the on a tangent really quick with
turami I mean the amount you obviously
man some great friends but the genetics
like this is something that you know and
I'm going to go a little bit of a
parallel and love Tim and Taylor all the
but the emerald cup that I remember and
that I love and the reason why it was
such a pivotal part for me was because
I'd get to go up there and taste the
latest flavors off the hill and
depending on what flavors I liked or
what flavors w we would go queue up at
those booths and purchase those seeds
and that's kind of gone away and so the
cool thing of tpami is bringing it back
and inviting dozens of geneticists James
loud Ridgeline humbled Etc you know
having these guys come out bring their
best seed to the table but then have a
thousand Growers show up that want this
limited edition stuff too oh scared
people with the amount of cultivars we
brought out you we got this big feno
hunt that that's ongoing so we're
constantly pheno hunting new stuff and
and then also testing it again and
testing it again y we we go through
redundancies and also multiple rounds of
testing uh with everything that we do to
make sure that we're providing people
with the best thing we don't just settle
on one thing right away because as the
plant grows it changes and as you take
different clonal Generations it changes
yep uh there's the sexual maturity that
goes on within the the plant from the
initial seed run to the second or third
clonal generation where it starts to
stabilize a little bit more interesting
so yeah lots of fun yeah I mean I think
that's you know fun made old adage you
know moms get tired that's why tissue
culture such an interesting thing so
many people that's why we got a lab that
does tissue culture right there it's
pretty sick it's it's super important I
think tissue culture for banking typical
you know I think most companies don't
have tissue culture right now but I
think we're moving towards having tissue
culture in most facilities like large
facilities it's necessary you have to
bring house we're we're becoming more
aware of viruses and viroids and the
impact that they're bringing into the
industry as a whole like as a percentage
even yeah I think having clean genetics
is super important especially if you
have a nursery being able to say that
you have clean genetics and that you're
selling clean genetics that's super
important whether it's seed or whether
it's clone it's so difficult though it's
it's fluid you know you're talking about
you know you're talking about you know
kite dancing and you know a storm right
yeah I mean that that's it's you know
it's undeniably the future it's it's
just it's difficult right but it's it's
all how mature how all mature
agricultural Industries operate for the
most part right not for the most part in
tality yeah exactly but the Clone game
that that goes back into your point and
you see it over in Europe because you're
out there dang near as much as we are
doesn't mean it has to be like bananas
or everything is a cavish banana because
it's grown for you know it's resistance
since you know it's a let's hope it
doesn't turn Banas well yeah cuz bananas
already went through one Extinction so
yeah but it is a good point and again
like I said you see it out there with
Austria being the capital of clones
because they're doing it right and
they're keeping them sterile and clean
because in my opinion this is why I'm a
gen seed grower and again why we get
along so well is because I'm not in for
I don't want someone else's problems
that that's the thing I have with an
issue with a lot of the Clone producers
and I love how sterile and producers
these days you have careful enough that
is very true with that because hot PL
and verid transmits through seed
production and a lot of people were like
well what if it's just the donor that
has it then will they get it through the
pollen and the answer I believe is yes
yeah you can get it from both parents
you if they both have it you're going to
get more like a a basically higher viral
load and a larger population of your
seeds getting it uh there's a lot we
don't know about it still but there's
quite a bit that we do yeah that's I
respect Sharon that's why I respect
getting stopped in secondary coming back
from spannabis the other year was
because unfortunately a GU with but we
had seeds and you know they brought over
you know obviously the the egg guy
thankfully he was Pro cannabis his his
mom and dad both grew of course he is
from Northern California this a guy at
LAX and you know so he's definitely
supportive but he's like you know these
these seeds aren't sterile like we don't
know if these seeds are safe so
unfortunately we can't let you bring and
I totally respected it going to a school
like calply with a bunch of Aggies like
I understand it because to your point a
lot of people don't realize that the
seeds are but I think you see more of
the white the widespread coming from the
Clones because it's just it's the whole
lot you know for sure so and I think the
viral load is really small when it's
from seed initially too and so as you
take clonal Generations from that plant
and that plant gets stressed out and and
develops other things like systemic
bacteria exactly and fungal pathogens
then the Hop latent virus it's it's
latent because it doesn't Express then
it goes up so there's a lot of people
that don't think they have it and they
do have it 100% um and if you're in
denial you probably definitely have it
yeah um it's just another one of those
problems within our industry it is but
this is where again and you lead with
education it's a full circle here we
lead with education but the people are
doing it right you know the lead with
education help like your viewers
understand why you do the things you do
and how you do the things you do because
you're wanting that end result to be a
better finished product which is going
back to why Jack so passionate about
great this product like how can I make
that M product better if not for my
older brother who's a medical patient
right for every user and every consumer
of flower no matter where you are in
what Market wherever flower is present
like there's a way to optimize and make
it better and lean into technology you
know lean into technology 100% I mean
that's really what we're doing it's like
trying to do data driven breing and
trying to improve everything that we do
every time you know it's like sometimes
we have to make gradual improvements
over time but the idea is not to just
just rest on our Laurels and you know we
we figured it all out cuz it's just not
like that there's so many things to be
Innovative with in cannabis within this
space Innovation is here but Innovation
needs to continue on I think I'm seeing
it like MJ biz for a couple years there
wasn't much Innovation and we started
seeing stuff with LED lights yep and now
the LED Innovation is kind of taking
over and we haven't stopped then they
got under canopy right oh my God side
canopy under canopy this is inner canopy
under can canopy
I think in every category of the
ancillary side of the industry you seen
that kind of play out yeah you know but
I you know the rate of innovation slows
the rate of consolidation accelerates
you know it's not a lot of new ideas and
lighting but you know they everyone
agrees on what the you know the best
ideas are there's intense competition
driving you know those particular areas
forward right like I think there is you
know pretty cohes a lot of cohesion now
LEDs LEDs forward I I think there's a
lot of conversation about W observation
and obviously just balancing red and
blue red and blue spectrums right and I
mean Spectrum tuning is a thing now uh
it's not done right by everybody but I
think people are understanding light
spectrum a lot more you know now that
you're able to tune the lights and it's
like uh that's changing the game a
little bit yeah and it's all these small
Minor Adjustments that can make the
product better what's the next one
that's going to be hot the next
Innovation that's going to be hot next
area that everybody really nerds out on
because I I think kind of the Innovation
waves go based off category based off
what people's talk you know focus on
there's defin there's been a couple new
way nutrient waves right uh there's been
couple couple genetics and you know uh
tissue culture and kind of w waves
around on production it's been one wave
around you know kind of post Harvest
storage and post Harvest management yeah
been a couple waves around facility
Automation and and and management
genetics has made their waves and
constantly is making their
waves gentics always will it's always
going to be yeah and I think because
that uh people are chasing flavors and
they're they also there's these Trends
and these trends go
through show oh totally extractions you
know I think we we're not fully there
yet with extraction because they're
still trying new things and coming out
with new stuff I mean this Rosen wave is
amazing what they've been doing with it
but I mean also I think we can go back
to hydrocarbon I have no problem with
that really uh I've loved the evolution
away from away from that as a natural
thing yeah it's kind of weird I don't
know like there's certain not that a
huge concentrate again definitely lover
of edibles but you know they are derived
from concentrat so I found stuff that's
like like your bhos and and CO2
extractions for some reason just is
different like I get hangovers it's
different but I think being able to
separate the cannaboids and for drug
Discovery and other like that I think
there's still like this wave that we
haven't really got to yet now with
Federal legalization on the on the
horizon that's cuz you're a sungrown old
head though s scient scientifically
speaking brother like and you know I
love you SCI scientifically speaking um
there are tpping profiles and um
cannaboids better captured
um uh better captured with hydrocarbon
extraction there there are certain
profiles that are lost and more
extraction there's certainly different
processes that are more ideal for you
know digestion versus topicals you know
versus whatnot I mean I see sift coming
so dry the dry sift in the static hash
is now a thing I seeings coming back it
is you know they're like they're making
it out to be like a new process it's
like no this is like one of the original
processes we're just making it more
advanced that's like hydrol man why
doesn't everyone the guys up on the hill
used to with you know just the trim
stuff they' put through a hydrol and use
his topicals and Stu like that stuff
you'd love to see back I think the
Innovation which is a good segue to go
back to the question yeah the Innovation
is going to be around how people view
what they want to consume like I think
it really is going to get to a point
where people are finally going to get
over this freaking hey with the highest
THC wins [ __ ] and finally move into
what is the profile for me which again
goes back to why I love your genetics
this is the future and I think part of
it is convenience we live in this world
that's very convenient so pens Rosen
carts are great by the way AG I think
that's been a great Innovation pushed
forward and and done some really amazing
things but hand rolls I call them hand
rolls some people call them pre-rolls
when you say handroll it it defines it
as something that's more of a high-end
product that hands actually touched it
PR we think of the popcorn and the r
people up in a blender and then make it
that's not
this I like I like the hand roll I mean
I think it plays well into the culinary
I side of things I think I think um
Canabis is
incly linked to to the culinary arts
culinary business and I think a lot of
our most successful colleagues in the
space have very strong culinary
background agreed um and I I think
there's a lot of axum of thinking and
values that transition very well between
the two spaces and I think hand roll
hand rolls app and it's it's a good name
but we have to remember you know is you
know there's uh whole whole industry um
or whole whole vast swast of the
industry that are not for people that
are enthusiasts you know it's difficult
to remember but we have to remember that
right I I been talking a lot about you
know beer beer analogies lately and I
think there's definitely some nuances
between our our culture and you know
cannabis and being a you know yeah being
being a beerhead but uh there's 7,000
crap Ries in the United States right and
awesome they're people having fun and
they're creating new category and
they're doing good business and you know
it's it's awesome it's fun but that's
only about 10% of the beer consumption
in the United States there's 16
companies doing for that account for
approximately the other 90% right even
more than that I think it's it's six
companies that are 60% of that must be C
in cores
[Laughter]
twice I'm that study but I yeah I don't
think we're crazy far away from that
cannabis cannabis is Consolidated far
more rapidly than I well it's like the
pre-rolls that make the most money as
far as like take up the largest part of
the market share are the one gr y dollar
joints dude it's crazy you saw in Canada
not just us quar too yeah
half their time what gets sold mostly is
those cheap cheap whether it's one1 or2
joints people love those you know
because you get high and it's cheap and
a lot of people are okay with not having
the best of the best I try to chase the
best because I want to be the craft guy
right at the end of the day think that's
my identity right we all have identities
on who we are and what type of Market
we're trying to capture I mean I want
something for everybody too so if you
look on my site for seeds like we have
stuff that's priced where it's priced
for everybody I have stuff that's $500 a
pack right for for five seeds or 10
seeds five seeds I think for 500 is the
most expensive thing but we have some
stuff where for 45 bucks you can get a
pack of seeds right and so there
business school models for for this crap
right you know that the the Brads and
Chads and thads you know brought us
right and Kens
yeah can't exclude the
Kens definitely the k k Ken yeah yeah
and not that you know Brads and thads
and Chads aren't aren't diverse and
aren't really just a you know a you know
broad broad term I think you know you
got your fundamental you know your you
know value proposition your you know
middle of the road and then your your
highend I think where a lot of us in
this space really have thought about is
is a very linear very polar thing where
you're either you know w l you're either
Louis Vuitton or your Walmart or you
know where where you're at this
different thing and there's actually a
you know you could say it's a it's a big
Grid or it's even a three-dimensional
cube of you know where where you're at
in terms of the G value chain and what
you're doing and depending on who you
are what your business is you know it
could be perfectly okay that you make
something that only you know one out of
100 cannabis people like but if those
one out of 100 cannabis people [ __ ]
love it and they're they're about it and
they're they're nuts for it well there
you there you go you have a home if if
you if you're doing something that
people love you have a home and you have
a space for the product so you know who
I want to be and I identify with mostly
is being the Bob Weir of cannabis oh wow
man I want to support all those Jerry
Garcia out there all those cultivators
that do amazing that that are providing
this experience for the people I'm
trying to be the Vel and the gortex for
the people in the industry that's what
I'm trying to do with genetics you know
I love Bob we best rhythm guitar player
of all time one of the best musicians in
my opinion I mean just an amazing guy
with no ego and that's who I strive to
be I don't want to be Louis Vuitton I
don't want to be Gucci not there's
anything wrong with those I I don't want
to be Robert PL but I definitely want to
work with Robert Plant I want to work
with Jimmy Hendrick and Guy the best of
the best you know it's I feel like
that's my position in this world yeah
yeah you're you know you know guitar
maker offender I mean for
for us and you know we we've certainly
talked about it and kind of sou
searching and trying to you know build
and you know when you you came on board
you know you were the first person to
ever be like all right well how do we we
Market this and create a brand and try
to you know get more people to try this
more quickly yeah right you know I you
that's it's marketing right that's what
you're trying to do but I education you
let me do we we've always hoped that the
you know the you know the for for our
brand like we just want to be your your
favorite Growers like you know product
they use yeah like you know all the all
the best you know Hunters you use use
you know hops you know number nine you
know yeah uh for for for their you know
their deer rifle like you know that's
you that not not a bad analogy right
yeah we we we want to just be your your
favorite Growers want to be their
favorite favorite favorite tool yeah you
hears me say it all the time you know we
want to be a noun and a verb like I want
to be Uber which is a ride share program
which is live right like want to be that
want to be without the har
lawsuits yeah but want to be the kleenex
a facial tissue want to be the Coca-Cola
of sodas like you know and I with you
again you know we're friends but
objectively speaking man how you've
grown your brand because again you've
LED with education but you've LED with
passion and putting this community over
that corporate mentality that so many
people like you said there's plenty of
Walmarts of weed out there and stuff I
think you have to you have to create
value you have to you have to you
stimulate some sort of conversation then
you have to be willing to move with it
you know particularly with the the
recent election and everything you know
I I know you Elon Musk and Tesla and all
that's a a very hot button topic right
but absolutely in terms of just having
the you know the the you know passion
for something as a holistically as an
organization you know to founder aside
right let's put that aside yeah to try
to open source things and and do thought
leadership and push the space forward
and you know being transparent well at
first off you know one of our biggest
accomplish you know their accomplish
business they've dramatically pushed you
know electric vehicle and that that
conversation for it and everything else
right I think that that kind of and then
they're keeping up with it of course
they're electric car you know rival
businesses yeah right you know who who
cares this is you know this is a great
thing for the world I think that kind of
that abundance that growth that that
attitude of you know you're not going to
out innovate us we're we're telling you
this we're not we're not telling you
we're working on right now
that stuff we've already worked on well
and it's there's a Solutions based
company right so are you and so am I I
feel like that's one thing that
separates Great companies from the rest
of the world right this if you have a
problem that you're a solution to that's
how you're going to be successful
exactly true and you find too you know
for us there's you know imitated never
replicated it's interesting because not
all bags are created equal that will
probably be our next marketing campaign
because absolutely you know I've explain
to these guys having been in a few
rodeos you know when you're the leader
the biggest Targets on your back you
know and so that's something we're
starting to realize you know the ankle
biters are are biting because they're
seeing what we're doing but the one
thing that we know and no matter if it's
people who think they're direct
competitors or people are trying to
replicate you know we're in a totally
different position because unlike them
we're actually a part of this community
we're actually people who know
experience and use this product and
believe in it you know and it came from
from those that grow from the start so
definitely you know a big factor in it
as well yeah and I think you know for
awesome you know account and
formulations we talk about you know
something that's patented right you know
it's very easy to move an inert
hydrocarbon from here to here yeah um
you know it's it's a brutal space you
know being being in you know chemical
formulations which is essentially you
know what dirt block is so we have to
you know obviously the way we make it
thankfully is bed we have we have some
some advantages there you know with with
our partners with our our supply chain
but it's it's constantly have to be at
innovating if if you know somebody you
know completely eliminates you know
passive you know map packaging is like
the best solution to this like it's
going to be us yeah yeah yeah you know
maybe we've been lucky for that maybe
we're in The Perfect Storm for that
being in canis which is so fluid that
having that that you know the fluid
attitude and the attitude of oh we've
got to build stuff where the space is
headed instead of where the space is at
you know maybe we've just been very
lucky with that but you have a good team
too you're the Innovation you guys have
done I mean the bin liner for instance a
lot of people don't even know you have a
bin liner you have a bin liner you know
it's a lot of people don't know
different things
like lot of back sizes like Ry like Ryan
carnavali and Jang were like you know
filling filling different bags and you
know hand making bags with the hair
straightener standardize the bag sizes
for this industry that have you know
probably a billion billions of bags been
made for for the space now yeah or or
case packs you know um my father was in
in a way you packaging distribution and
you know did all sorts of Jans and stuff
he was like guys case back pounds are so
interesting like why why is that you
know I can't believe the soon us his
case packs like well I will tell you why
you know it's actually it's because we
couldn't afford boxes yeah yeah like
that's why the case packs were huge but
we're constantly trying to stay ahead to
your point for specifically the tot
liner we just widen that by two inches
because all of a sudden there's more
than just HDX or or what we grew up
calling black and yellows yeah out there
you're starting to see black and reds
black and greens not all of them are
uniform in size so we had a few friends
that were like hey dude I'm kind of
having to stretch this what's
up adjust custom stuff that we do for
facilities that are running you know
some of the the call factory farms huge
facilities have very different the theop
once you're getting over you know 60,000
Square ft of cannabis space and you know
the tools and processes really changed
dramatically that's where those guys the
thing that I you know I or I should say
the the they don't change that
dramatically the scale but changed
dramatically it's still turog and it's
still still a still the same container
but it's it's an agricultural container
that the guys are using in the avocado
space yeah wow it's an sop that and you
see that here you know we just turn a
facility where they're running our pound
bags but then going over to Europe where
they're running our 5 kilo bags I mean
that's a that's a 10 pound bag yeah
that's
full so to to Jack's point but those are
licensed producers you know that are on
the medical side into his point it is
more of an objective a perspective
versus a passionate guy who got opened
up an opportunity to start being a
master grower at this big operation you
know it's quite interesting yeah and
like man shout out to Austria that's the
that's the triangle of Europe right
there I've learned yeah there's so many
guys I meet like all over Europe and
it's like where's your own shirt or like
where's your plug or like you know it's
Austria yeah yeah I guess the
legislative environment and um just made
it a right place yeah yeah right place
right time yeah exactly so I got a
question for you for sealing your bags
CU a lot of people have bags and they
want to seal them what is the best way I
know they have some conveyor sealers
yeah the the one I recommend I mean it's
literally like 15 20 bucks on Amazon as
an example but you've got the
traditional kind of press heat sealers
um that's what I use at home like I said
was an inexpensive first time buy you
can use a ceramic hair straightener if
you just do a couple presses on and
basically the way you seal bags is a
combination of heat andw time 12 times
essentially how long you're spending on
each part you don't want to melt it but
you do it it is the the material
structuring way where it's supposed to
heat seal quickly so you know I often
times will use my fiance's hair
straightener to stra yeah I've used like
the V seal
yeah you can use any number of heat
sealers you you know I you don't need
because of the nature of this material
and the nature of cannabis we would
contend that you don't need do vacuum
flush um cannabis but the heat sealer
set to a a low temperature and a quicker
D time is ideal you know um given the
structure that we run you material
structure you want to use a lower
temperature it's a non-metal it's a
non-metalized structure right it's
definitely one that I always take some
of these I've obviously had a few of
your new ones in my bag I always travel
in my backpack and then for me at hotels
I just take a an iron literally just
bust the iron out and do it on the
countertop and you're doing it in
delicate any way or you know and just to
his point just let it dwell for like 5
10 seconds perfect seal yeah set and go
no not even I'm like two
Mississippi and then you can always
another two Mississippi yeah yeah the
worse is like you're traveling around
Europe and like you damaged the back
yeah yeah so I got some questions for
you about the business and about
building the business what are some of
the things you learned along the way
with building a business you'd like to
share you learn a lot by doing so many
things wrong so yeah that's a whole
another that's a whole another podcast
yeah
gosh I don't know uh it's all about
people I think the by far the most
important thing I I do is is who who is
on the team and and how I support them
and try to keep them you know what what
they need I think you know I think it's
a it's a Kaizen thing right I'm talking
about you know it's it's a it's a daily
aspiration right I think you know a a
business Journey or entrepreneurial
Journey you know it's lot you know I've
grown up in this business right I
started this company you know um with
with you know uh Ryan um gosh you know
nine years ago March yeah and so I've
you know very much grown up in in in
this industry and you know my my
worldview is shaped by this industry so
to speak in certain ways but I think um
who you have and how you how you you
take care of them and you know try to
you know have what they need you know I
think people people can't do great
creative work if they don't feel safe
you know I've always strived to have an
environment where people feel safe and
they feel secure and they have an
opportunity to experiment right I think
um Warren Buffett said it best you know
he was God what was he what was he
trying to fix um at the time I forget it
was the bank he took over um and uh he
was talking about you know tell one if
you lose the firm a little bit of money
you know I'll be understanding if if you
damage the firm's reputation if you
take advantage of a customer if you know
if you you know if you do something
unethical I'll be ruthless and that's
the the balance the environment you want
to ideally strive for but a lot of is
you have to have a product people love I
think for for us we were very lucky to
develop something that people found a
lot of value in um I think you know that
and not getting too over your skis you
know not getting too much of nicker
syndrome you know not getting to the
point like a made we made some money
this month let me let me look at these
ports calculate payments during the work
day I think and work for that yeah I
think people people sense that you got
to be you got to got to
know who you are what you're good at
what you're not good at I you know I'm
not the the best manager I'm not leading
and I'm not organizing you know MJ
biscon in every sense you know for for a
lot of the sense like you know Lance and
or had to sells Haley and certainly CFO
Dan or tell me where to be and mhm what
but not to to a large degree right but
you know I'm still on the floor every
morning for like a couple hours I'm out
there with the team like I'm getting up
when they are like I'm out there with a
couple hours like I want you know want
them to you know see me working in every
sense I I think you know you can't ask
people to do [ __ ] you're not willing to
do
like you can't you can't not clean the
toilets you know what I mean like yeah
as a boss you become the janitor too
degree you know and yeah I've accepted
that and I enjoy some of that stuff
maybe cleaning the toilets but you know
doing anything and everything whatever I
have to do to support my team somebody
misses a day I can come in and feel you
got [ __ ] love the sock too like part
of owning a business is yeah loving the
shitty days as well yeah i' go for a
shitty day doing this and you know and
I've had some really lucky days than the
best days I've had doing other things
yeah so yeah not the easiest but
definitely the most rewarding that's a
lot of people I'm sure in your travels
too James you're like you know because I
never push on people to ask what what I
do or what I'm in town for and tell them
and Serv as the Canabis community and
tell the history and like man you must
love I'm like I do love it but it's some
of the hardest work I've ever done you
know and it's crazy but that's what
makes it so rewarding and a lot of
people like a question these are cliche
podcast questions like oh what would you
recommend or what would you tell someone
wants to get in the business a lot of
people in this industry tell them to run
and I'm like no if you're passionate if
you're just a passionate person you
don't have to be passionate we we did an
internal audit when I was at weed map we
had about 400 employees at the time and
just did a fun survey just an internal
survey 34% of those individuals did not
consume which is totally fine but they
were passionate people they were
passionate about customer service
they're passionate about webdev we're
passionate about branding whatever the
case may be now we're fortunate we do
have a bunch of consumers and several
Growers we have lot of people that
aren't unique culture you know yeah I
think culture is a just like cannabis
that's a a fluid you know living thing
that's something we're always know
aspiring for you know I you know I I
wish I you know uh when I
was what 24 I wish I knew everything I
knew now or had the perspective I
thought I knew everything when I was 24
you stop Lear you stop living back about
some stuff and I'm just like man how did
my like you know I had some good people
around me how did no one hit me in the
mouth yeah it's like [ __ ] yeah I did I I
definitely did my jaw's still
crooked but uh
yeah it's it's interesting growing up
and then evolving and getting older yeah
you know and then this space but if
you're passionate and you want to be in
cannabis there's a space for you it's
not like Tech it's not winter Tech all
you can you can create something people
love and create a sustainable business
there are great companies in the space
that have eight employees there are
great companies in the space that have
800 employees yeah yeah you know a lot
of the guys on the eight range you feel
a lot more fulfilled than some of the
guys in the 800 range yeah and you know
I'm sure vice versa to a certain degree
but there's a there's so much growth and
you know we talked about you know some
Heavy Hitters in the space and some red
names there's people like that in every
Market whose names we don't know yet
there are people putting out world class
gold tier product in every Market I mean
certainly we're in one of the epicenters
and the heartbeat you know being being
here and the James La facility and also
being in the [ __ ] Bay right but you
know they're they're hitters you know
everywhere oh yeah but there's a lot of
opport a lot of like the there's so much
opportunity pass and cannabis consumers
are [ __ ] ruthless man you got it's
like the restaurant business you got to
you got to come
correct your last meal exactly you're
only good as your last seed or your last
jar or your your last bag your last bag
you know I think that there's so much
truth to that and if you can have that
hard work ethic with a bunch of passion
you can do anything and you can't again
it's a story I tell this is phenomenal
this guy he was um in the military
active had definitely some top level
clearance at the Pentagon told me his
whole story reached out on LinkedIn he
said he's passionate about the plant he
can't consume because of obviously his
career and the choices he made uh but he
said as soon as he got his honorable
discharge he's going to get into it he
reached out to me a couple years later
and he's managing an operation down in
Miami and I'm like I'm so happy for you
he was passionate he never consumed the
plant because of his career at the time
and he made the successful transition
and people had asked to your point like
there's OPP I've never worked in an
industry where there's so much
opportunity when you look HR sales
marketing pharmaceutical Logistics
Securities
geneticists scientists I mean there's so
much need in this space it's almost
trivial so for someone to go like I'm
passionate about the plant but I don't
know how to get in I'm like there's
plenty of options for you to get in you
got to and you got to start small I
think a lot of people like I want to be
a breeder and it's like dude learn how
to grow the plant first right like there
there's there's levels to this stuff and
there's it's just like in in The
Culinary world and that's why I think
there's a good you can start out as a
dishwasher or a water boy in cannabis
and end up being a big big time seed
breeder or being a big time cultivator
or have a product where along the way
you're like dude I I want to make a bag
that's better than all the other bags
yeah you know I think exactly true you
know we live in America and it's the you
know I think we there still is the
American dream it still is alive I think
that a lot of people are like oh it's
gone no the American dream's still there
you got to fight for and you got to want
it and I think persistence pays off so
huge especially in the market that we're
at and maybe it it's not as easy as it
was in the 50s for the American dream no
or even for the California Dream but
you're right it does still exist and the
thing is and it's unfortunate is with
the younger Generations because they've
almost kind of been brainwashed on it's
easy and it fingers length and oh I can
DJ because I've got this kit or or I can
be an influencer I can be an influencer
CU I know how to break dance like hey we
all break dance when we were kids but
the thing is like nothing's easy and all
these shortcuts and all these hacks that
everyone's putting focus on the most
successful still it's hard work there's
very few people that handed their first
million and Warren Buffett's a
phenomenal example you know there's
Steve Jobs is a great example Bill Gates
is a great example like there's enough
individuals that are in our lifetime not
from the Industrial
Revolution just like just show up like
genuinely try that's half the job
genuinely try to be genuinely genuinely
try to do the right thing like try to
create with the way you do business and
don't be a [ __ ] douchebag that's like
90% of it right there that's 90% I agree
no or Karens yeah yeah well and those
people get weeded out you know what I
mean like they may have they have some
of them have and some of them still need
to get weeded out but but do you
remember back in 2018 man there's a lot
like when the Funny Money started moving
out of it like a lot of those guys that
I'm a master grower wait you're LinkedIn
says you're a yoga instructor last year
help me understand how you're a master
grower in Industry well I've been
consuming since iist St I I I sit it on
stage one time I'm like I've been going
to a bathroom since I'm a kid that
doesn't make me a urologist that doesn't
mean I know everything going on man just
because I'm associated with it yeah and
I mean these things you know we have
this un instability in the market which
I think over time changes we be we
develop a more stable Market more stable
with genetics less companies for for the
better in some ways you know and some
some ways it can be sad but I think you
know we weed out the the bad Growers
those guys aren't going to be around
correct um I don't think those guys most
of those guys aren't around anymore yeah
most of those guys are not around I
don't realize the base level operator of
a lot of Growers right now like is much
higher than it used to be the average is
very high three years ago yeah the
average is much higher and I'm talking
globally yeah and then beyond that oh my
God like nobody wants to talk about this
msos are hiring you know the right
people yeah are hiring the right chefs
and they're figuring out how to put a
put together rep replicatable you know
good menus across across Geographic
Footprints yeah you know same way Dart
and Restaurant Group has I mean nobody
wants to talk about that there's some
stuff coming out of some of these MSO
facilities that they're put together a
good playbook some of these msos are you
know starting to be cash FL POS and pay
down debt I mean I'm seeing guys grow at
scale you guys are seeing guys that grow
at scale that are creating a better
product with a thousand lights than some
of these guys with 100 lights it's
insane or then then you know something
nobody wants to talk about is how much
of it is going to be like you know
nicotine industry where you know you've
got really vast bastardized you know
infused flavored products I mean we're
seeing a lot of you know Botanical
Turpin you know a Canabis cannabis
tpes see lot see seeing a lot seeing a
lot of infusion seeing a lot of stuff
you know coated dusted you know mixed
and people like it you know that's going
to it's going to be a big part of the
market infused infused flour it's like
confused flow is what I call confused
they they do a you know Vapor infusion
yeah same way same way they do in
tobacco I mean people are familiar with
the some of the Drew Estate cigars you
know uh Acid cigars they even have even
around their marketing thing they they
in their marketing thing they have
explicitly talked about Jonathan Drew is
a great entrepreneur and veryan brand
Builder and value value Creator dude
makes some good [ __ ] cigars you know
people who like cigars like his cigars
right you know he's making money he's
selling cigars
something they have a good company right
there's something something to it like
but they're talking about well they
don't refer to the Drew State brand as
flavored they don't use the f word it's
not flavored it's infused right right
that's and like we're doing you know
with these these hemp packs and
infusions and stuff and I think I think
that's they're doing they're doing stuff
in wreck that's infused they're doing
you know I think there's some of these
brands that are really pushing that and
to smoke it through a backwoods where it
still tastes good yep you know oh
absolutely but you know you can you know
this this bubblegum cannabis it's just
you know it's just like that's like I
that is that like that is a there's no
way that's a naturally occurring tpine
like I know too much about flavorings
just T like I I know wait watermelon
there's not there's not a tpine
watermelon bub gum I've seen bubblegum
TPS that are bubble gum Expressions that
are very bu like the real bubble gum if
you get to
the Indiana or wherever you want to say
it's from I mean there's a big argument
over that been going forever but that
bubblegum it definitely smells bubble
gum on the plant but when you go to
smoke it you don't get the translation
of as the bubble gum y but I have smoked
bubble gum flavored cannabis it's very
in fact we have one right now
billionaire bubble gum it's coming up
it's pretty bubble gum I'll have to get
some for you so you can go bubble gums
like this is this is a turbine this is a
a expressional plan I feel qualified in
you know I'm not going to go out here
and say I have you know like you know
Ryan from Doge as you know pal or
anything that that's someone we all
agree inside and out yeah you know no
smoke but I I know that turp at least
and telling you it's had an artificial
character to it yeah I don't I don't I
hope there's not a future for it I'm too
much purist but then again I don't spool
with tobacco so that's I don't hate on
anybody for anything you know I mean so
if you want to do it and there's a
market for it good for you I mean
whatever like I'm too busy to worry
about what other people doing really
yeah it's just it's true and as a
breeder I want to be breeding those new
cultivars and those new varieties where
you're like wow that's something
different that that checks the boxes for
me or I introduce some something new
that nobody's ever tried before or
bringing the old with the new which is
what I love that you you you know you're
doing more of how's how's the
conversation going to switch from from Z
turps and Z crosses I'm as guilty as
anybody I've been smoking a lot of uh
candy camer right now and candy candy
fumes really of it right so so how it
goes is now we're leaning more towards
the gas right so it's still is candy but
they're like I want gas with my candy
and now it doesn't have to be dark
purple we're okay with like a little bit
of purple in there but we still want
that purple for whatever reason I think
that people think it gives it's the the
bag appeal it it's the bag appeal right
all it is it's it's Instagram and social
media that's kind of shifted
our like get the real purple you know so
Instagram has shifted our perception of
what good cannabis is it's got to fit on
the the jar right has three to five NS
yeah yeah right there's all little and I
grew up where the the worst looking weed
was the very best weed like literally it
did not look good but it smoked amazing
tasted crazy and the effect was amazing
like we we had that was our focus in the
90s it was like man it looked like swag
in a bag I mean there was we had some
purple stuff that that came from up
North that was like pretend right where
you smoked it it looked amaz like it
would check the boxes for bag appeal now
but when you smoked it it was like man
this is like [ __ ] CBD like before CBD
was a thing this was it I didn't like
that stuff but in today's market that
stuff would probably sell because the
way it looked y but there is there is a
market for the effect and there you know
it has to be a certain yeah it has to
give you a certain effect if it doesn't
give you any effect it's kind of like I
think I think the consumers today are
kind of spoiled to be candid I know it
might be a little again a little
provocative to say but like to your
point we had to sacrifice a lot in the
80s and 90s and you talked to someone
like Kevin jodry you know who talks
about how the War on Drugs Daryl Gates
perpetuated by Nancy Reagan War on Drugs
that we grew up with in the 80s that
100% took a lot of the turps out of the
equation because all of a sudden the
guys weren't just having to hide under
canopy but they were having to hide the
the smell the scent up on the hill too
so that's something that all of a sudden
just drove this PIV shift into more
conservative cultivars that weren't
nearly as gassy or as as spicy as what
we're accustomed to and that did affect
the bag appeal I mean to your point I
remember northern lights in my opinion
looked gorgeous looked fabulous but
there was a lot of people that didn't
have the same opinion they thought it
was too green they thought it was too
funky it's too round too fluffy a bud
compared to again your Durban or your AK
whatever it was that was popping up at
the time so it's really interesting how
to your point IG is person and in the
over manicuring that's another I think
you and I both rough cut man the amount
of over manicuring that still happens
and I do kind of blame that more on the
SoCal indoor scene yeah it's excessive
man sugar leaves need love too like they
they've got Turpin they've got tricomes
you know yeah so it's it's crazy I grew
up and all my personal when I would grow
would go in jars and basically we would
leave the the sugar leaves on you know
what I mean and then finger trim them
off
yep in fact I was still doing that in
2018 yeah so you and I both I know I've
seen yours and some people question I'm
like I love rough cutting man there's no
need like what am I to do turn it into
Edibles which I
do but I don't need to it's still
smokable the stuff we're seeing today
was so super Frosty I don't even know is
some sort of some sort of cookies cross
and this stuff was super Frosty funny
I've been seen a lot of cookies crosses
coming back I'm kind of hoping that we
get more cookies coming back I think
cookies is cool I mean other than the
fact that it has a bunch it's not
herming the [ __ ] out in your gr well
that's that's the that's the main
problem that's why so many things Herm
now is because they all have a lot of
cookies in them and Inter I think it's
been stabilized a lot more it has it has
been totally stabilized more but you
there is still a whole bunch of stuff to
Herms even some of the good stuff and
it's like Mike from exotic basically
changed my opinion on the whole Herm in
sex expression and he's like he he had
told me because I was complaining about
it and I'm like well dude like and then
I was complaining because some people
complain about my stuff having interx
Expressions yeah and I tried that used
to be my main thing is I don't want any
interex Expressions any of my seeds if
it has interex I'm but then you miss in
what Mike to his point was that then
you're going to miss out on TPS
potentially and he's absolutely correct
some of the stuff that I have I I
definitely put it on the packaging and
we actually we put it on the like if you
look in the description on our website
there's stuff that I will tell people
you it has intersex traits but I'm not
going to prevent people from germinating
those seeds and trying those things
because it has I mean if you want to try
them I think there's some amazing TPS
that you get out of some stuff that has
intersex trades yeah and over time we
can get rid of the intersex trades I
mean now with with some of the data that
we have and with the sequencing they've
already identified uh potential markers
to be able to get rid of intersects
powdery mildew resistance all these
things so more into the technology see
naturally in different land races right
the reason land races are prevalent in
different areas is you know often you
know you have you know Turing profiles
and Bud structures that are more adapt
to the realized the environment there a
a Durban is very uh very good for an aid
you know South African environment
whereas you know Golden Buddha is very
moldes in you know the way it the way
those you know bigger colas are they're
more humidity resistant right yeah or
I'm sorry those those less tense colas
are less spy yeah well and it it leads
to that open bud structure the stuff
with the really open bud structure does
a lot better typically in humid
environments that's why these equat oral
varieties and these tropical varieties
with open bud structure yep do so well
like a pineapple chunk yeah yeah yeah
that's Co a lot of the old stuff's
comeing back man a lot of sour getting
bred back in Blue Diamond like you're
hearing some stuff they D so like when
they started going with the extraction
you know I mean they were doing the GMO
and it was dumping and then the Donnie
burgers and all why they so hard I like
GMO a flower I I I I was a little baffel
why they went so hard towards cuz you
can really stress
get it get it to dump you can get it to
dump heavy right so it's a heavy dumper
and then like the Donnie Burger I don't
like the Donnie Burger flower so much
it's not my choice like when I I won't
smoke the rest of a bag if somebody
gives me some Flor and Flame shout out
but uh when he turned it into extract
and I got to try the Donnie B he gave me
two grams or three grams of it and I
brought him it was a reggae we were at
reg on the river together and I had the
Don Burger that's that's yeah we were
smoking we were smoking with a little
dipper yeah and we were trying that Flor
of flame and that is amazing I love the
effect and it's super smooth it has this
little floral hint and it has this
sweetness to it and it's it's special it
is you know and it's different than GMO
but I could taste the GMO in it I love
GMO man that's when I'm surprised didn't
have more time in the Limelight I have
to tell you like there's a there was a
few over the years and everyone beats up
runs and Skittles you know because they
definitely got played but like there's
some like GMO where I'm like what's up
or even like skitt keeps coming back
Skittles that kind of that like garlic
funk rank dank you know GMO TP
it's but it's such an overwhelming
tpping profile it's not as easy to play
with as a skittles that kind of say with
tping it's much easier to mix and match
that yeah yeah yeah and I mean I love
the papayas they're doing with extract
now and some of these these Wild Ones
it's like uh you know but I still love
Skittles so like you give me a good
Skittles rosin I'm like I'm all about it
it's sweet to the nose man it is tough
to your point it's it's an all-around
winter and you know again I think it got
played a little bit on flower there's
there again there was just there were
such great man the 2010s especially like
I respect the 2000 but the 2010 so much
stuff that really got some serious play
versus just I feel like it's been cycled
so quick in and out but I bet you we'll
be back here in five years and like I'll
be talking about like man like what I
would pay for like a Primo tops you know
a [ __ ] you know pack of you know like
I think liol I've been loving his
Skittles flower yeah it's really
interesting the trends and the
directions they go in and kind of
Skittles keeps coming back though which
i' I've seen where it goes away for a
little bit then comes back and then
we're talking about the pack prices
being super high for Skittles you know
again where which was like a meme dude
it was a joke just like run people don't
want to grow it right people don't want
to grow Skittles I like Skittles and so
my friends grow it we smoke it I enjoy
smoking it but how about GDP let's let's
bring GDP back let's let's bring Urkle
back like GDP is a tough one to bring
back just cuz pain in the ass to grow so
a lot of people don't want to SW I want
to grow sweno but I don't have the
patience for it I'm like I just I don't
I don't yeah I mean we got some Cub so
out of TC that's coming down really soon
we got some chem 91 we yeah the 91 chem
dog we've got some chem D we've got Star
Killer we've got I've heard good about
star Cuban black hay we've got the piff
we've got the blue
[Music]
dream it is it's from rare dankness and
I did some reading with it I love it
it's super it's got this gassy amazing
yeah that's a that's a Southern Ohio you
know right there yeah yeah it's special
that one is super special and like if
you if you know it you know it and when
you smell it again you're like that's
Star Killer right it's one of those ones
it's so distinct if you an intense
powerful medical indicia yeah it's a
powerful medical IND that's a great way
to put it I I I have not I have not seen
a great execution of it I feel like
in over 10 years up in Washington can
organic
ni shop reserving it yeah yeah yeah yeah
they got the cut from me and uh we
didn't tell anybody it was Star Killer I
didn't even tell them it was Star Killer
for the longest time there's stuff where
I'm like well we got to come up with
another name because I can't tell you
the name of it because I can't give it
out because I promis the person I gave
it to that I wouldn't give it out and so
those guys K Organics and I have a
really good relationship long they're
really good guys they're really good
guys heard do some cool stuff
I I've done breeding work for the
community yeah they are they get it they
have an organic product I mean I love a
handful of brands in Washington but they
are one of them and you know Tim is the
one who I get silver from for my
reversals oh nice um but yeah I work
real closely with them we've done
breeding projects together for other
companies yeah Pro pnw man that's again
not to but like just like Jamaica and
Hawaii like I see these guys growing
outdoor and I'm like props do you guys
like man for dealing with this what
Mother Nature has given you we're about
to do some seed production in eastern
Washington some exciting stuff cool uh
yeah that's where all the good grows are
it's crazy it's all the it's really wild
yeah my my buddy Andrew Jones he's doing
some amazing stuff out there and so he
did it this year and I got fomo and I'm
like let's work let's do this dude let's
work yeah and I mean I think we're gonna
be bringing loud seeds and partnering
with uh with Andrew out there and doing
some really cool stuff and he's a good
friend we've done he's another guy so
and I met him and he introduced me to
Tim from can Organics Okay so Andrew and
I have been really tight and and done
some really cool stuff in Fallbrook we
were working down at Fallbrook together
yeah they he had a farm a hemp farm and
so yeah it's it's funny how small the
world is and how the guy everybody works
together at the top I think there's a
lot of collaboration going on and not
not as much hate no for sure because
most of the Smart Ones what we talked
about earlier a lot of the bad apples
got we you know kind of pushed out of
the bunch you know especially I think in
the mid late te up till now yeah like
it's kind strongest they'll search back
in well you know
yeah I mean I've seen that happen too
like how did you get back in the IND
like dude you're like a bad Penny yeah
what exactly do you say that you do for
this
community I feel like I've seen people
make mistakes and I've seen people come
back a better person yes so I've seen
that I've seen people make some silly
mistakes and come back in the industry
you know like yeah and apologize about
it which I've been very there's a few
that have been like sorry it was a
douche I'm like you know you figured it
out
how you're coming to Jesus I think we're
talking about the same
person but you know it's small world
small small it's funny how that works
out you know and but this is such a
community and we're very tight-knit and
everybody kind of knows everybody so
everyone knows all the [ __ ] Y and
when you burn people especially it gets
passed around real quick like nobody's
business man and that's why I tell
people again speaking up on stage I'm
like this is very unique because every
industry start out as a community rather
be real estate Automotive banking
whatever it doesn't matter all start out
as a community of individuals are trying
to solve a problem like like you guys
like we can bring a solution right and
that's the thing is this is still being
led by the community this is not a
corporate one industry if you will
especially not on the global scale
surprisingly I mean there's 53 legal
countries around the world and a lot of
Americans don't know that so when we go
to places like Thailand or Australia or
or Argentina or wherever we're going
around the world like it's interesting
because they take a different approach
Ro towards it and a lot of them can
balance that Community incorporate they
can we're here for the right reasons we
have our heart in the right place but we
want to do it very professionally and
very structured and it goes back to the
Sops and all these other standards you
know right so but it's definitely we've
seen a lot in our time I'd say you know
it's for sure a lot of change it's only
thing constant so I got one question
that I ask all my guests you have one
piece of advice for your younger self or
your younger colleagues what would that
one piece of advice be man everybody's
in such a
rush and people are in in such rush and
like the the the Beauty and the the best
stuff is not at you know DS companies
you know mansion party or something like
that it's you know it's done it's done
in the lab it's done in the grow it's
done in the done in the done the shop
it's done in the warehouse it's done
it's done late at night you know it's
done with you know it's done your core
people like you know don't don't rush
that don't don't rush the people are so
Keen to rush the magic and Rush the
process and they're F so focused on like
you know like the the the the fruits of
it you know and the the benefits of the
journey no I think the the people make
it and do stuff they're they're
interested in the journey they're
interested in their relationships
they're going to make during the journey
they're what they're going to learn
about themselves during the the journey
what they're going learn about the the
world you know I I think you know you
you got to you got to be able to like
you know pick up that pick up your phone
like you know in the lab you know or
whatever you're doing you know in the
warehouse you know it could be you know
your your shitty little building you
know in Cleveland you know you know
across the street from the from the
biggest men's shelter in this St but you
got to be able to pick up your phone and
like look at you know people going out
or you know doing this or fronting or
all that Instagram [ __ ] you got you
get and you got to be able to put your
phone put and just put slide that phone
back in your pocket or put it back down
your desk and like keep doing you know
it's it's the flow you know people
people try to rush and avoid the the
flow process the flow process is when
you're flowing in there with your guys
it's a unique time on life and your team
and your colleagues you know and it's
that's that's such a unique beautiful
thing and you can do such incredible
things there and that can Propel you for
so long creat so much momentum and
people try to try to rush that or skip
that stupid that's an original answer
and I love it that's that's great well
if guys are trying to find out more
about you guys and girls they're trying
to find out more about you guys and
they're interested in TPL block they're
interested in Grove bags yeah where can
they go Grove bags.com it's Grove
bags.com you can find us on the handles
uh social Grove bags on IG FB LinkedIn
um we really lead with education so
that's one thing again just to stress
like come hang out our site it's it's
not so much yes you can purchase product
there you know we are a company you got
we got bags we got bags you can order
seeds from me and you get triplock bags
sh our we're going to be doing more
stuff in 25 not to give too much away
and that hasn't happened yet so I can
say we're we're doing a lot in 25
together with you but again it's because
we're on a similar trajectory and we
have similar ideologies and culture and
core values amongst our companies it's
it's a it's it's peanut butter and
chocolate in my opinion but yeah man
definitely reaching out to us and check
out our site we have a lot of
educational information peanut butter
and
ladies so thank you guys so much for
coming on the show today on that note
definitely man I look forward to having
you again for a third time and you for a
second time sometime in the near future
we'll have to do one of these events
whether it's span abis or Mary Jane yeah
we love man let's do that Mary Jane lot
of fun yep thank you guys thanks for
having
us thank you guys for watching please
like And subscribe down below