[Music]
Heat up here.
[Applause]
[Music]
How's it going everybody? Welcome to
another episode of the James Lab podcast
and today our special guest is Lem from
Lampire Seeds. How you doing? Great to
have you on the show. All right. Good to
see you, man. We've been hanging out at
shows on and off for quite a while, you
know, and uh you've got a shop up north.
You bought some of our books. Um and
yeah, so thank you for that. Thank you
for the support. Thank you for the kind
words with the book. Yeah, man. The book
is great. I just wanted to start off
just blessing the energy of the cannabis
plant that we all get to share in.
giving thanks to the elders that have
basically paved the road we're all
walking on and uh we're carrying the
torch and hopefully, you know, we we can
keep the next generation well lit.
Absolutely. Well said. So, yeah, it's
amazing because I think a lot of people
think of breeding as something modern
with cannabis, but breeding has been
going on since the dawn of time, right?
Since Well, not since the dawn of time,
but since agriculture has been a thing
and since men started breeding before.
Yeah. I mean, we're talking two ice ages
millions and millions and millions of
years ago. Absolutely. Long time. And
yeah, naturally occurring. And they may
just be starting to show our work,
right? But it's been happening naturally
forever, right? And they were, you know,
they were breeding for resin. They were
breeding for plant fiber. They were
breeding for so many different things
for for millennia, right? And and right
now we're breeding for different things
maybe, but the breeding work has been
done for years. To get us to this point,
there was a lot of work that went on.
It's just like humans, you know. It's
just like humans from the beginning of
time. A lot of stuff happened, you know,
nature takes its own course, but yeah,
they're really showing the work this
tonight. Like now, like down to the
actual locust on the alil, like really
being able to break it down, especially
with that human genome project. Well,
it's interesting because if you take
something like wild mustard 2500 years
ago, basically cabbage, Brussels
sprouts, kale, kale, all those things,
kale, Yeah. broccoli, they were all wild
mustard. And because of human
interaction with the the plant the with
wild mustard uh we now have all these
amazing things and they were bred
specifically for different things like
land race genetics how right apples and
wine and cannabis basically. Yeah it's
pretty amazing as far as the path that
these things have gone on with human
interaction to get us to this point and
how we've grown alongside them as well.
It's as if you know we want to survive
and the plant wants to survive as well.
You know, one of those things like the
Ethiopian land raises with the absic
acid or whatever, right? You're
wondering like is this thing responding
to the human like humans are starving in
Ethiopia. Is the plant learning how to
like live in drought? Is it a response
to what's going on? Is it an interaction
like an electromagnetic currency that
connect or is it just surviving learning
how to deal with drought because
otherwise it won't survive? It's almost
as if the plant has just as much of a
need to survive as we do. For sure. And
there's adaptation that occurs with
cannabis and with humans that you don't
see with a lot of other plants, you
know. Yep. Exactly. We're both making
each other better. And like the like
your book was saying, you know, we're
40% similar genetically, which is
amazing. You think about it. I mean, we
could have evolved from cannabis. Yep.
That's totally possible. Mushrooms,
cannabis. I've always thought the
cannabis is in control. At least for me
in my life. People are always like,
"Yeah, we're in control of cannabis."
It's like, "No, man. The cannabis
chooses you." Yeah. and and like it's in
control. It tells you what to do. Yeah.
And at the end of the day, we're just
stewards. We're just moving the plant
along, you know? We're we're uh one
component of this plant's long life
cycle. And it's one of ours. It's one of
ours. It's a magical cosmic connection.
Like I was telling you, I was up late
and I was thinking about reading your
book there, the cannabis breeding book,
and I just cracked it open on the first
page and it opened to the Methusela
seed, the 2,000-year-old, like the
oldest plant, the oldest seed that got
to germinate. in Israel, right, where I
was born. And I was like, "Wow, that's
fascinating." I called my buddy up, Dan,
and he's like, "Oh, yeah. My cousin was
on that project. I visited that plant
recently." And like, "Man, this is such
a small world." And this is exactly what
I was thinking about. I was thinking
about old seeds, and it just opened to
that page. Yeah. It's just cosmic. It's
beyond cosmic. It's amazing, you know,
serendipity. And it occurs so often uh
not within just this industry but within
life, you know, as you move through
life. It's like there there's intention
and then there's some things that are
just meant to be, you know, cosmic
forces that line up and Exactly. things
happen. Tell me how you got started with
the plant. I had seen it growing up and
one day I was walking to school. I was a
little kid and I had I found a little
gold case. Somebody must have thrown it
out the window when they got pulled over
or something. I brought it into school
not knowing what it was and it was maybe
second or third grade. They made me
write a report on cannabis. So that was
like my first exposure to it. I hadn't
used it yet, but then I'm like 10 years
old at summer camp and some of the kids
from Florida brought joints and we
started getting high. But it wasn't like
till I was 12, 13. I was having grandma
seizures and they were, you know, three
days horrible seizures. And I realized I
could score some weed, dime bag in the
hood, smoke a joint, and just not have
seizures. you know, really cut down,
have maybe a half a second or 10 second
seizure compared to like a 3-day seizure
or like a 2 and 1/2 minute grand mile or
just something that was damaging. So, it
really wasn't a question of legality or
morality for me. It was just like I had
found the way. And from that point on,
that was it. I was writing letters to
Carl from the Super Sativa Seed Lover
Club and getting seeds sent in the mail,
growing the M19. We had like a an
amazing triple cross of Pakistani citron
hashplant, Afghani hashplant and Durban
hashplant that I had written a letter
and he had sent me skunk one and then he
sent me skunk one again and myself as a
12-year-old kid I'm like hey man I
already have that I need something you
know more zah just and they're like
listen we're not releasing a lot of this
but I'm going to send it to you and the
cool thing is I'm back in span of in
2019 and I run into Carl and he's like
dude you're on the original mailing list
and we want to see what you've done. And
I was like, "Dude, I F-150 like like
we're deep into crossing that strain
five, six times a year into itself over
30 years." Yeah. And it's just amazing.
It's like the backbone to our genetics,
the limb. Nice. And uh it's just
awesome. I love seeing those old hazes
come to life, you know, and what you can
do just cross them and cross them and
cross them. You know, I went to an event
that we were both at, which was the
Turpami in December. David DS. Yeah,
David D. Big shout out David. Really
good event. I mean, I think it was well
attended. It wasn't the biggest, but it
was well attended by the people that
matter. It was great for a first year
turnout, I thought. Lots of potential,
great vibes. The talent the talent
there, the the talent was there. And the
thing is is we had guys coming out of
the hills with sativas, you know, like
true sativa structure, if we're talking
about morphology, that that leaning with
amazing profiles that weren't just the
standard gelatoes that everybody's
consuming these days. We're talking
about I mean we had farms. You got me
and Jean Ari. You got everybody there.
Everybody. I had Super Silver there. The
only thing missing was maybe like a
business forum to just kind of help
everybody. Like each one of us maybe has
an edge or a tip that we could share
with each other. Yeah. It's like Von
Benjamin, one of my favorite musicians
from Midnight says, "When together we
realize our actual strength and size,
evil will be trembling." And that's one
thing that people are missing. like we
don't people overlook what we have here
and what we've made and the potential of
what will happen if we just come
together and and not like worry about
the ego or yourself and it can be
challenging because times can get rough
and all of a sudden you're like whoa
what happened you know cannabis man you
know I have to think a little harder to
keep it going but that keeps you on the
cutting edge and uh it's one of the
challenges especially people are facing
in Northern California right now as the
number goes low and we're fighting
people like glass house trying
bring the number down to 100 or 200
bucks when raising the taxes in June.
The best thing you can do is tell people
no, you know, tell that person no, I'm
not going to sell you a box for 20
grand, you know? Yeah. kick rocks and
you know and just force yourself to to
get a plan. Enter the white market, set
your brand, build your brand, lock in
contracts that come back forever instead
of waiting for somebody to come down the
driveway who may or may not ever come
back, but that's not a building block to
your empire, right? You know, on top of
just having a pie chart, like what I
tell growers all the time is know where
your cannabis is going. know what
percent is going to go for whole plant
fresh frozen or edibles or maybe that
your smalls are going to go towards
joints or pre-rolls or an edible
product. Know what you're doing before
you get after it. Contract your stuff
and have it sold and uh that'll help you
get ahead of it instead of trying to
grow a,000 or 2,000 lbs or get to the
point where you've grown more than you
thought you were going to, which is
everybody's goal, but then processing
it. You know, like if you're trying to
sell your cannabis in eights, no,
there's 128s in a pound. And if you're
going to grow 1,000 or 2,000 lbs, you're
probably not going to be able to sell it
all in eighs in a year. So make an
edible product, which has been, you
know,
at least convert it into concentrate so
it doesn't go bad. Exactly. Cuz I mean,
I see that happening a lot where people
are like, "Oh yeah, I got last year's
outdoor." And it's like, dude, like
we're a year and a half, right? If
you're not cryogen or freezing that, and
who's got room to do that with a,000
pounds? But you can take it and turn it
into a rosin. You can turn it into any
form of hash and you can preserve it for
an extended amount of time. Even civ or
dry civ right now static. People are
getting really into that. Oh, I love
static. I love static. I love all those
forms of hash. And I think they all have
so much potential, but also the shelf
life lasts a lot longer. A lot of them
get better with age. Well, all the hash
we were smoking, let's say, 20, 30 years
ago, right? I'm 50. So, you'd score some
hash and not realizing because we didn't
know about CBN's as much, right? This
hash is probably 2, three years old.
it's been smuggled from like Afghanistan
or like Morocco or even longer. So, we
were getting ruined on that stuff, you
know? So, a lot of this fresh rosin and
like when I smoke it, I'm not a big
rosin smoker, but it just wakes me up.
It's the opposite cuz it's so fresh. The
whole plant fresh frozen glands are just
they almost have a chi to them. Yeah.
They just have like a high like a wiry
energy when I smoke them. Totally. And
people can continuously smoke it. You
could never smoke like a half ounce of
hash. It would just put you to sleep.
It' be like no like hash oil or butter.
Half ounce of hash is equivalent to x
amount of depending on the strength. But
that's that's a lot of flour. It is. And
you got to remember too like you know
Bob Marley like all these people that
were smoking they were smoking cannabis
o five or 10% and getting really high.
You know you remember being a kid in
high school scoring dime bags and
smoking weed and just laughing your ass
off. You know if you would have put that
weed to the lab it probably wouldn't hit
15 20%. But it was great cannabis. Yeah.
And that's something that people miss is
that the turpps decide they help your
brain accept and decide how much THC
you're going to get.
And it's just dangerous chasing the
percentards or or you know in the white
market especially it's so prevalent that
you see people we see two 300 people a
day and most of them just ask us how
they can get the most for their money
and their value in their mind is like
over 30% THC. It's just what they've
been taught. They just don't understand.
and they come in like, "How much THC can
I get for 40 bucks?" As if like the
higher the number is more medicine.
Yeah. But would you go buy 151 and drink
that? You know what I mean? Like it's it
that's a great comparison. And education
is lacking. And once you teach people,
they they know, but it's there's a gap.
You know, not everybody's in the bubble
or a chrono or like a lifetime cannabis
enthusiast, right? So, a lot of the
older folks, they're not going to want
to smoke. They're coming in and no one
wants to start smoking when they're 60
or 70. They probably just want most of
them just want to get to bed, you know.
That's why you're seeing edibles in my
mind being so prevalent. Yeah. And I
love edibles, you know, and I love the
direction edibles have gone in with the
rosin gummies. I love rosin gummies. I
love these companies that are actually
just using the flavor from the actual
flour to the flour. All the integrity is
kept because like that's the problem,
man. Once they start using distillate
and a lot of these companies once they
just start having to meet a financial
model they end up using distillate and
they have their brand but it's not the
same integrity anymore and that's a
shame as you see like these giant farms
take over. Integrity farms brother. Yep.
Absolutely. And I think integrity is
just so important in the industry and
you're only as good as your last batch
to a degree you know. So shout out to
Michael Omaha man great elder who always
told us man the three most important
things are integrity integrity.
integrity. Absolutely. Literally, man.
You cannot go wrong. I tell people all
the time, kill them with kind blood. You
know, just be nice, right? You know,
like we're we're in Yukaya and we've
been there since ' 09. We're the first
dispensary and and nowadays there's, you
know, 10 15 more spots within a square
mile. Yeah. And I don't worry about it
even though it is worrisome. You see
cookies up there and they're for sale
and there's just so many spots. And what
I tell people and I welcome them every
time they come is just be nice, you
know? Just be nice, right? Right? Be
nice to your people and they'll come
back. It doesn't matter what kind of
competition you have cuz pretty soon
it's going to be like that everywhere.
Everyone's going to feel that. It's not
a thing to be afraid of because it's
America. Yeah. You can't just tell
someone not to open, right? Totally. So
New York's going to feel that.
Everyone's going to feel it. And it's
nothing to fear as long as you have
integrity. Absolutely.
You know, I'm getting excited for
interstate commerce. I don't know how
far away we're from from having
interstate commerce, but I would love I
feel like we're close. You're seeing
Snoop and a lot of these people really
start stepping it up and you're seeing
like the THCA. They're they're building
like the train tracks for the railroad
to run on. I feel like and they're
close. Um they have to have some kind of
interior knowledge having invested in
the European medical market and
somebody's telling them what to do and
helping them guide their decisions. So I
feel like they have at least a little
bit of an edge. Anything's positive in
the right direction. Honestly, we've
waited so long. If you think about
California, we we've been doing this
since 96. And so if they were to let us
have interstate commerce, that would be
amazing. You know, if somebody bought
the USPS, which is going bankrupt, and
let us use it to ship, that would be
great. Yeah. If we had a cannabis bank,
if somebody put 15 mil into a federal
credit union for cannabis, it would be
amazing.
Totally. And these are the things that
force like farmers the permitting and
all the rules force us to take another
look at our labor. Like how can we
reduce labor? One of the biggest ways to
do it and what's happening is whole
plant fresh frozen because you don't
have to harvest your cannabis in the
same way. You don't have to spend time
curing it, drying it, trimming it,
paying a trim crew. You just freeze it,
done, right? We have a manufacturing
facility at our dispensary in Ukaya. And
we can process a farm in a couple days,
just be done. And then you have a
product that's the the quantity is
reduced. It's much smaller. It's higher
grade. It'll keep for longer. You can
decide if you want to put it into an
edible or just sell it as hash, right?
Or turn it into rosin. What are your
thoughts on trimming machines? I don't
like trimming machines personally. It's
funny. I just had a friend of mine
complaining today about how all the
dispensary herb or a lot of that he was
buying is trimmed. And you know, we
we've used them. Sometimes you grow so
many thousands of pounds that you just
have to use them or your weed will like
rot before you have it trimmed. And it
makes it like the comparison to me is it
makes it look like your weed is like a
year old outdoor. Like you can take a
piece of fresh greenhouse that just
looks better than any indoor. It's just
glistening in the sun with so many
trikes and compare it to something that
you tumbled on a machine and it just
doesn't even compare. Plus, you have to
pick the right strain. Like you want a
strain that's kind of chunky. You don't
want a strain that has like a lot of
smaller buds or it has a lot of shape to
it. It just depends on the trim machine,
too. Cuz I hated trim machines up until
last month and then I saw the resonator
work. No, they're amazing. I've been
building them since I was a little kid.
like beef tumblers and machines. Yeah.
Well, this liquid CO2 with the resonator
where it has the the net like the the
thing's amazing. It's amazing for what
it is, right? And the yield it goes way
up. You're talking like 20 to 40% versus
like chasing 5 to 10% on whole plane
fresh frozen. Yeah. And now 10 to 15
when you're just say like you're
freezing your trim and running it $20 to
trim a pound, right? $25, $15 depending
on way less even. We would have trim
crews like there's still you still need
people to operate those machines, right?
You need an operator and someone to like
a clipboard. Oh, no. I'm talking
specifically the resonator because you
do use the liquid CO2 and so there's the
cost of that plus and and but I really
like TJ and the kind of stuff he's
doing. I think it's actually pretty
impressive. Yeah, it's awesome to see
people just moving forward and not, you
know, staying on the cutting edge, but
also just making things better. Yeah, I
like it when people try to be creative
and they're able to do stuff that
benefits the industry, right? And so
I've also learned not to say, "Fuck,
that sucks." You know, because maybe
this version does suck, but down the
road it's not going to be that blural
LED light anymore. Now we're going to
have a LED that's amazing. Yep. Exactly.
Or feminiz seeds. Everyone hated
feminized seeds when we were younger. I
mean hated hated
especially people had negative
experiences or something, you know, like
sure they either came across a herm or
they weren't educated enough about it.
Um we don't run feminized seeds yet, but
something I'd be into I'd be into doing
a collab or getting that 4Z feminized.
um just because many people want it and
even just selling seeds and breeding.
People have been asking me for feminiz
seeds forever. I mean the last 20 years
especially. Well, if you start with
stable genetics and you make feminiz
seeds from stable genetics, it's a trait
that can be bred in or bred out, right?
You can breed it into regular seeds just
as easy as you can with feminiz seeds.
Certain strains have a harder time doing
it, but it doesn't mean that you should
run from the challenge. You just upreed
it and go for it again, right? Yeah.
There definitely is a demand and you
have to listen to demand. That's a
really important thing in the industry.
If you have people asking you for
something, you have to listen. Whether
you have a dispensary and people want a
certain product, you may not like that
product. People may be like, "Ah, why do
you have cheaters or why are you
carrying steey or but if you have
customers asking you for it, you have to
run it, you know?" Absolutely. I
remember starting and we we had only
organic products and we had like 50 jars
of flour and people would come in. We
had four gram ace and you could pick it
out of the jar yourself. People were in
heaven, you know. And then slowly like
rosin and pens started coming in and all
these regulations and you really see
like a lot less quality herb honestly as
it's commercialized. They're still
around. You can get grape flour. Well,
we can get grape flour, but I think the
average person get grape flour. If they
know where to look, they can. It's hard
too if you're the average person. Yeah.
And you're going to a dispensary,
whatever state you're in, you're trying
to figure out which medicine is good for
you and you try all the different ones,
which isn't cheap, and you finally find
one you like. I hear this story a lot.
and then they're out of it and then you
got to try the whole gambit again. Yeah.
And you know people want the same thing
every time. They want the same response.
So it's hard for them to chase it. Like
we haven't smoke in 40 years, right? And
so you know what you like. You know what
you liked when you were a kid. You know
when you see it again. It's almost like
you have a photographic memory. I do
anyway for any strain I've ever seen
since the beginning of my life with
cannabis. I I like register it. I know
what it smelled like. Yeah. even like
wet moldy batches of crypto that came in
from Florida and mail order in the 80s
or I'll remember that even you know but
I definitely remember the good ones you
know that one that just you're in the
deadlock and you score some Afghany or
even before all these strains like in
the 80s you could get some tie stick or
Colombian or just you know just tie that
was just amazing man mindblowing you
know one hit and you're just done yeah
it's funny cuz I remember all the
different genetics and we didn't even
have names on stuff it wasn't
necessarily I named it a lot of times a
good green or kind. Yeah, we had kind
bud, green bud, sexy, maxi or pretend to
go. We had Mexican brown weed. Yeah, we
had the brown a lot of brown weed that
was seated. Definitely, you know, and
even even some of that stuff was
actually really good though. There was
like the the more the higherend Mexican
that was actually really it was still
pressed. It still had seeds in it. Yeah.
Like Ces or Bus Head or many names. We'd
get blocks of it in the hood, man, from
the Jamaicans growing up back east. That
was basically our staple. But the bad
stuff would give you a headache. You'd
have the worst headache afterwards. Yep.
Or give you cramps or like you could
tell something had been sprayed or
something was wrong. Pesticides. But
man, I smoked so many good dime bags out
of the hood that just made me laugh for
hours. It give you just giggle juice.
You know, it'd be creeper. You you feel
like nothing was going on and then all
of a sudden you're just permagrin and
just laughing your ass off for hours.
And totally I rarely see that cuz it's
not the shiniest. It's more like an old
school sativa that you know people
aren't really wanting to grow indoors or
outdoors. Yeah. But when you get it,
it's awesome. Just the creeper, you
know, that that effect. People want such
an instant gratification high now. They
want to exhale and just feel the weight
of the world going off their shoulders,
you know, and you can get that. But
there's something about good creeper
weed that kicks in after 15 minutes, you
know. I I still I got some of that last
year from Johnny from Huckleberry Hill
Farms and that stuff literally it was a
batch of his mother's weed and it
literally I took a bong and it didn't do
anything. So I took another one and I
think I took a couple more and like
literally 15 minutes later I was on the
couch and I'm like man freaking eyes got
tight and it was one of those slow
creepers. Not like okay after I took a
couple bong hits I feel good. It was
like man that [__] didn't do anything
and then literally 5 minutes I'm like oh
I feel a little bit high. 10 minutes
later, I'm like, I feel great. And then
15 minutes later, I was like, wow. Like
borderline too high. Yeah, I like that
kind of effect, man. I love cannabis in
general, man. I mean, I like any kind of
land race or as long as it's organically
grown. I mean, I have a hard time even
judging some of these events where they
throw 40 different kinds of hydroponic
cannabis like in Europe or Michigan. I
mean, anywhere where you're judging
sometimes, you know, you really start
paying attention because you're like,
man, I smoke organic weed everywhere I
go. Right. What are your thoughts on
Bilero? You try the pearls. Oh, I love
the pearls. They're upbeat. They're
really nice. Yeah, I like what he's
doing. I like like a rare stuff. I was
trying to help him market that. It's
just hard. Like I said, it's hard to
educate people and get people in the
consumer point to respect tiny little
pebbles like that. It's like Dr.
Greenspoon. But I love that stuff. Like
I'm a hyper guy and I that stuff makes
me more hyper and I still love smoking
it. You know, every time I see that dude
I'm like what can I do to get a little
bit of those just little pebbles, you
know? I love those. Yeah. His Bubba Kush
is really good, too. He's got a couple
good Bubba Kush crosses. They're
amazing. I liked what he said on the
show about, and I agree with him about
how it's just a beautiful thing to just
give someone cannabis. You know, many
times I've given someone my last nug,
and I'm talking like really nice indoor
organic head stash from seed grown in
only water with no chems or nudes, like
just really head stash. And it's just,
you know, I always knew another bud
would come my way, but there's something
to be said about just giving someone a
nug, you know, especially when it's like
the best nug they're ever going to get
and a nug that you respect and you just
kick it down and that's like a beautiful
thing, right? Yeah. He's local. I like
what he's done with the sour. His sour
was dead on. Everyone's kind of chasing
the sour. It's so good. I I have some in
the drawer right here. The thing with
the sour is like that. Not not that he's
fighting it, but you know, the nose is
slowly fading from the sour you saw in
like the late 90s, early 2000s. It's the
same like popcorny lime green with the
pinkish hairs. It's what everybody's
wanting. But the nose is slowly
delineating. The first person I've had
express it correctly in a long time.
Right. Definitely. Whereas actually the
actual expression I'm looking for and it
might not be genetically different than
a lot of the other ones, but because
they're going I think it's different. I
just think like they might be drifting a
little on the nose. There might be, but
I feel like his is dead on. Right. So
his like his is the one. When I smoke
it, I get the same effect that I'm
looking for. Same smell, same smell. The
nostalgia is just there, you know. I
mean, it makes me smile even just
thinking about it now. Yep. Me, too.
It's like, it's like the sour. Yeah. And
that was, you know, it was so big when
it was big. People don't even understand
that if you weren't there, it's hard
from New York City diesel to sour. And
we have the original New York City
diesel cut. We crossed with it and it
has that loud sour nose, you know, but
it's, you know, the sour is the sour.
Nothing, you know, that's a cut. So you
can chase it all you want, but you're
always going to get something that's a
little bit different. Well, so you know
what's funny is with cookies, uh we
haven't seen good cookies for a long
time. And so I've been getting asked by
people and so we phen hunted some from
seed, the best ones, my friend. No, it
was uh Loud Scout. It was platinum
platinum cookies. Platinum, which is
loud. It Loud Scout. Platinum cookies.
Same thing, right? And frigin. We got a
dead ringer for the original original
cookies. Like dead ringer. Like you
smell it, you're like, man, this smells
like 2012. It doesn't smell like the
cookies you see today. Because I feel
like they're all either watered down
versions, crosses. When people try to
breed it up because of the low yield,
but there was this strain in Yukaya in
the 70s and ' 80s called the Brand Y
Kush. And people swore that that was
like sometimes called the black mamba,
but many people said that was like the
backbone to the cherry pie that went
into some of the cookies. It was those
small little pounds that looked like a
football that after you grow it, you're
like, "Oh man, these are hard to sell or
I don't want to grow these again." Some
of that cherry pie, too, some of the
lower branches would seed or like it was
a difficult strain. Sure. But so tasty.
Just mind-blowing. Like a pound of
cherry pie. Yeah. People you could smoke
the whole thing to your dome. It's just
delicious. Yeah. Um Yeah. I haven't seen
a lot of the cookies in the beginning
when the form cut was raging. You'd grow
it and it was it was weird. It was an
odd phenomenon. You'd get bigger yields
off a 600 watt than you would off a,000.
If you backed the sun off of it outside
in the shade, you'd get 5 lbs versus
like 2 or 3 lb in full sun. It would
have these massive leaves the size of
your torso and it'd be kicking out tiny
little popcorn nugs, you know? Remind me
of like an old schooling G13 or just
some old school hash plant that grows
like a foot of stem and then gives you a
half gram nug, but it's just hands down
the best smoke, you know? But I think
the cookies faded out just partly
because it's so low yield. And when you
when you're growing it, like when I'm
growing it next to some of my stuff, you
just want to break it off and throw it
away. It's just too finicky. Yeah. And
it doesn't yield, you know. Well, and
that's why we bred with it, right, was
to improve the yield because the yield
was so bad, you know. And then we I
often do that. I use my lamb because
it's so bright and so big. I can take
anything from anybody's catalog and just
they have a dead-on genetic that I like,
but I just want to boost the yield a
little bit. Yeah. It's amazing people
back cross then too or you just I always
do that like I have that original male
that I made the dirty skittle with just
because that lem is just the backbone
man that that's what made the sk the
dirty skittle is like 37% THC you know
that's a big jump on an F1. Yeah. And
then just every time I cross it back
like when we made the 4Zs it's just
still right there. The four Z's is
really good. You gave me some flour at
Turpami. You gave me a sativa too. That
was a heart raiser. That was that was a
heart race. Like that's those killer
hazes. Yeah, that was that's like when I
think of original haze. That's the only
haze I've seen in years that smells like
a skunk. A lot of the hazes have that
African land race or like a Duran or
Jack or a fruity, you know, nose to it.
But that that that haze just put me
down, man. Yeah. Big up to J Trees on
that one cuz uh yeah, that's just
perfect cannabis. Well, and you don't
see hazes like that often. And then we
were in an event where there was 50
different bags of and you're smoking all
that weed and that still we couldn't
finish the joint, right? Even Arian was
like, "Whoa." And that's what I was
like, "Yeah, honestly, Arian was blown
away by the amount of haze, you know,
coming from Europe where Hayes is
European. People think of Hazes being
European even though it's Californian,
but he knows what he's doing." And he
was right. You know what I'm saying? For
years, let's say the last five years,
even I've been like me just because the
downfall of Jack and Durban, people
weren't into it, right? But having a
dispensary and paying attention to the
market in the last year or two, people
love it. It's at the top of the order
list. People love a fruity sativa that
they can relate to like old factorywise,
not just like looking at it, right? You
open the jar, it does something to you.
It's aroma therapy. It's more than just
loud, right? Yeah. And there's a time
and a place for everything. Like it's
good sativa. You I like strong. I like
candy gas. I like it all. History
repeats itself, too. So those oldie but
goodies are never going to go out of
style. Those ain't never going away. I
guarantee you that. Same thing with
these hazes. They will never go away.
They're going to keep coming back. You
know, I think cat piss is one where I
hope it comes back. Everybody wants that
skunky cat pissy. Just that odor where
like something sprayed you. Yeah. I want
that nose burning skunky ammonia, right?
That's what this lamoj is like mint
Windex and that's kind of nice. But
yeah, we're still just chasing the like
I got sprayed by a skunk, you know, like
we got some old seeds to open recently,
some 87 new old stock using this that
C-section, the seed section technique
where what happens with an older seed is
there's something, you know, there's,
you know, the outer shell and there's a
kodaliden, but there's what I call it,
it's almost like a subfascia. And what
it does is it recedes over time and it
makes it so that kodaliden can't open.
So if you if you have old seeds and you
you smush them after they don't open for
a little bit and you see that there was
nothing wrong with them inside, you're
wondering why it wouldn't crack. And I'm
talking about after scarification and
gillic acid. So what you can do is you
can actually cut the seed open with a
razor blade. And you'll see that the
kodaliden is held shut by almost like an
acorn which was that subfasia and it has
receded to a little point and hardened
and made it so those old seeds can't
open. So if you cut those with a razor
blade and you'll be missing a little bit
off those first two coat of lightens
when they finally come up, but they'll
come up even with like a 40 or 50 year
old seed. I've done this really and you
just keep it wet and all of a sudden you
know they're good because you put them
into a cup and they sink, right? So
they're not floaters. No matter what age
they are, you're like, "Okay, this is
like this can work." There's potential.
Yeah, there's potential. So what I found
is with really old seeds is they'll turn
like to male or like the males have a
better survival rate. Something about
the males are a little bit stronger with
age. And I don't know if it's time or
heat or something that makes more males
of the older seeds, but I know that with
this seed section tech, I can get
anything to open and it opens up and
those first two leaves are missing what
I cut out of it. And then we're going to
put this to the test. Oh yeah, man. I
got some seeds to send you that we've
struggled, you know, and I just got
these ones to open from 87. That's
great. So yeah, I mean we use G3, we do
scarification, we do all that stuff.
Yep. But yeah, hormones and uh and then
try to do them in vitro, right? In
tissue culture. But yeah, I mean I'm
always interested in trying new tech.
You use like hydrogen peroxide or what
kind of water? I do hydrogen. Yeah, we
clean our So we do a six to one with
water and hydrogen peroxide. Yep. So
yeah, and we soak it in that sterilizes
the outside seed. Uh you know, and
everyone has their own way of doing
that's in my book, too. That's a cool
one of the coolest part in there is, you
know, I mean, you're reading it and
you're seeing they got besides the
genome project, but you're seeing they
got a 2,000-y old seed to come back.
Now, that's just amazing. So, that means
like we can find we can get Civil War
era seeds or seeds that are in medical
kits that are dug up, you know, to pop
now. And that's just amazing. Yeah. It's
like they they found that frozen lady in
a log like in Russia with some super old
jar of nugs. And I just think that it
all goes back a lot farther than anybody
thinks. I think we've been here a lot
longer than people think. I think Herb's
been here a lot longer than people
think. It's just we use like these
certain finds to base the whole creation
theory on, right? Like Richard Leaky or
Homohabilis or But let's say it's a lot
older than that. Like let's say maybe
during one of the ice ages, you know, we
didn't get totally like wiped out. Maybe
a couple people survived or maybe
there's just it goes back a lot older
than we thought. Yeah. Just like
cannabis, I feel like people have been
cultivating it for a lot longer than we
think. for sure. You know, there it it
does grow wild everywhere, but it it
very well could be that people planted
those fields. Well, and it has the
ability to adapt to an environment,
right? Pretty much every environment.
Cannabis can adapt just like we can
adapt. It's a pretty amazing and it's
here to stay. Like you take it back
before the Bible, biblical times,
whatever. You take it back to the root
to the dinosaurs and it's here. Yeah.
You know, you're reading there's goats,
there's herb, there's humans. So, it's
like part of the story here. Well, and
it has a survival mechanism where the
plant will produce a seed for offspring.
Even the stable genetics, you can take a
a plant if you let them go long enough.
Exactly. It'll produce a seed, right? As
a survival mechanism. Yeah. So, this
plant is going to probably be here long
after we're gone. And, you know, very
possible. Something on that note, being
from the east coast, we've always just
been chasing fast seeds. So, I'm looking
for the codal and roots under a
microscope like and some of the strains
we've had are like 30 days. So, there's
two benefits of that. like you have a
super fast strain, but in nature, why is
that happening? Because that strain will
be done in 30 days and by 45 or 50 days,
it'll be pollinating so that it can
continue and like seed the rest of the
crop. So that's why it was like that's
the purpose of it. But when you get it
and breed it, that's what we started
like we have that four Z's is 40 to 45
days. And people have a hard time
believing it's not an autoflower, has
high THC, but I tell people be ready,
man. Because if you have a new cycle, I
mean, that thing just gets huge
instantly and deals with heat, it deals
with cold. Like, we've not only bred it
for bug resistance and temperature out
in potter where it's 130 all summer
long. And then in the winter where it's
like 20, 30, so you have just
unbelievable temperature change, right?
And you can tell like the year the
Russitmites ravaged us, there was plants
that just didn't get touched at all. So
you look for that and even though you
haven't done the work and you can't
prove it on the, you know, genetically
what the work you've done, you know, you
have a strain that is bugp proof. You
know, it's like a citroronella candle
out there. Everything's getting eaten
alive and this thing's just thriving.
Yeah. So I tell people, not only pay
attention to your climate and like where
you're going to grow it, but pay
attention to the plant that's saying,
"Hey, man, I'm taking care of myself or
I'm doing good." You know, if
something's thriving in your climate,
don't try to force it. Don't try to grow
like pers or something that takes
forever in a zone where you have to have
a quick crop. Like if you're on the
coast, bust a quicker crop. Yeah. You
know, with four Z's, we're getting, you
know, five to six rounds where people
get two or three. You learn real quick
because that is one of the best places
for stress testing for the tritis,
powdery milk. Oh, man. Those things, you
know, I got to give it up to the farmers
that are coastal, you know, and and
there's so many advantages to breeding
coastal and genetic testing coastal.
like as far as if you're testing your
and paying attention to where you are,
you know, like you could be coastal,
you're not going to be able to grow most
OGs. You can want it all you want, you
know, and you're also not going to want
a late flowering harvest because unless
it's bulletproof, you know, you're just
going to end up having so much loss. But
when you're feno
hunting, the coast is great because
especially for resistance to certain
things, right? That's amazing. You can
see what happens. And it's a necessary
thing. You know, you can do it to a
degree indoors, but it's not the same. I
bred for, you know, 20, 30 years
indoors. And the one advantage to it is
you can, you know, I'd be getting seeds
at Emerald Cup and I'd already have run
it two times before people are like
growing it outside. So, like I'm already
giving you your feedback without having
to wait the whole season. And it's a
good control group like you know, you
have your I had a seed mom room in my
bedroom and then you're budding it and
when you're flowering it and you can do
two or three cycles or you know, five or
six a year and you can really see with a
control group because the environment is
exactly the same. Yeah. outside, even in
your greenhouse, there's different
sections, different heights, different
wings, like it's too it spreads it out
so much that it's not as much of a
control group, right? When you have just
like direct indoor breeding setup, I I
feel like you can get so far ahead. You
can Well, I'm I'm big on pheno hunting
for where the seeds are going to go. If
you're going to be selling clones to
people that are growing indoors, you
should probably feno hunt indoors,
right? If you're going to be growing and
putting the seeds out in fields, you
need to test them out in fields.
Definitely. So, I feel like really
depending on what the final use is and
now it's like we can go into like is it
a hash strain? Is it going to be used
for flour? Is it going to be used for
pre-roll where people don't care what it
looks like? You know, we're going in
that direction of the cruciferous. So,
where it's like wild mustard turning
into all these things, right? I always
go 24/7, right? And people are like,
"Dude, what do you mean? No, no, no."
Right? I always veg 24 hours. I have for
like 40 years. Wow. Right. And people
are like, "No, dude. No." Right? I
always have this conversation with my
farm, my crew, and it it just grows so
much faster, man. Like it's mostly
indoor, you know? It's not as from a
High Times article that you read when
you were a teenager. I remember reading
that in High Times, the 24/7 model. Oh,
man. It could be, you know, like we're I
was in High Times best of in like 95.
You know, I I was an avid high times
reader, but I don't know. Oh, it's just
when I moved to Boulder and I lived in
Boulder from like, you know, 92 to like
99. Yeah. Everybody was just there
growing and that's where I learned most
of my indoor techniques, you know, and
just like we were using rockwool and
taking clones like I'm still using that
same clone technique and it works
amazing. I could clone something in like
six to 10 days. Yeah. Um Yeah. I don't
know. I don't know where where it
originated. So, let's talk about your
secrets for cloning. What do you do for
cloning? You don't have to give away all
There's a lot of No, you know what? I
give away my best stuff every year. I
give my best genetics out there and
force myself to make better stuff. And I
tell people like, don't hoard it because
then you're not sharing it and it
doesn't help anyone. You know, if if
you're only taking a few clones, I have
fun with it and I'll put tape and let it
marble out before I'm going to cut it
and cut it on a wider surface. So, you
just get a big knob. Um, you know, also
if you have space, take a big old clone.
You know, take the big one. Save
yourself like 2 or 3 weeks. You'd be
amazed at how quick it'll root and how
much healthier and stronger it'll root.
But the most important thing to me is
that you take it off of a a 7 9 11 or 13
bladed leaf. Like veg your plant out.
Even if you have to do it 6 to 8 ft,
even if you lose time, take healthy
clones because you're taking unhealthy
clones or like substandard stock. That's
how all these viruses and all these
things occur and it's just not worth it.
Also, I only take topical merist stems.
You know, I know it's easier to take
from the bottom if you're hedging and
you want to trim the unders and not
throw them out, but those are usually
like the sicker or more viral or have
bugs or not that they have bugs
necessarily, but even with the hop
latent tests, sometimes the lower plant
has it and the top doesn't, right? It's
as if the plant's trying to grow out of
it if you would just give it a chance.
So, if you just veg it out and get it
just healthy and luscious and take those
clones, all of a sudden it's like you
have a different strain. you're growing
that and your friends are taking other
co cuts or clones and they're wondering
what you grew. You're like, "No, man. I
just took a healthy clone and it's so
important to take healthy clones." I I
couldn't agree more. I think healthy
clones and depending on where you cut
the clone and how old your mom is, you
don't want an old mom either. And what
you just fed it and good in, good out.
Yeah, we're put we're replenishing our
mom stock every four months, right? At
most, like no more old moms at the very
Yeah. So, we have uh we have four tables
and every month a table gets replaced,
right? So we go through that and we go
from tissue culture moms right so we
want as healthy as possible you know
even in a sterile environment we try to
prevent crosscontamination the problem I
mean not a problem but one one thing
I've noticed when we grew we grew tissue
culture out at the farm and we got the
highest yields we've ever gotten some of
the ones that we let go a little bit
seated lightly I thought that was odd
and I noticed had very smooth stem like
none of the stem there was never a
cambium layer on the stem as it grew it
was like it was almost like just a
smooth stemmed
plant, you know. Yeah. But the thing
about taking a tissue culture and
putting it outside is if outside is
where the viral area is and if you think
about the cannabis crop as one big crop,
right? Even from like the the up up in
Oregon and Seattle and California, if
you look at it as one big crop, it's
hard to fight, you know, what's outside,
it's almost vector. You know what I'm
saying? we have like chemtrails and
neighbors or if you're, you know, in
northern Cali, you're near vineyards,
there's fires and all the bugs are
hopping on the birds which are hopping
out and over your crop. So, there's a
lot to handle. So, there's there's an
argument for if you're taking a tissue
culture, which is almost like less
strong, you know, and you're just
putting it out in that a lot of times it
has a better start cuz it's cleaner
vyroid wise, but it won't have as good
resistance to what's actually happening
outside. Plus, what's happening outside
just happens to it. So, you can start
with it fresh and all of a sudden it
just goes out and gets diseased. It's
hard, right? So, for me, it's like you
just got to keep a good eye and not be
afraid to throw out a percentage of your
veg. Like, even if it's five or 10%. If
you have enough plants so that if you
notice something that you don't like,
don't be holding on to that cuz you're
short on plants. Don't go take that to
fruition. Just
keep afraid to get rid of it. You know,
cull. It's hard to do sometimes if you
love cannabis and you're attached to it.
But no, but the best the best growers
out there grow more than as far as they
veg more than what they need. They take
more clones than what they need and they
select the best ones. I feel like that's
just across the board with the best.
That's just pretty standard. Yep. I line
them up on a paper slicer and I put it
underwater under a big a shallow
Tupperware full of water. I'll put a
paper slicer in there. I can take a
thousand at a time and just you know,
right? I started doing like, you know,
10,000 a day, just really clone it out.
And my mind is like, "Oh, how can I just
like line this up better?" But I don't f
or cut any leaves. Like you're asking
how I clone. I don't cut any of the fan
leaf cuz I feel like that like disturbs
it or it's like having an open cut. So
instead of like, you know, that's the
first time I saw that was when I moved
out here in 2010. I see people just
jamming domes and cutting leaves and
cutting half leaves just to make 50 on a
on a tray. Are you doing like a 50 cell
count? We do 72 but only plug half,
right? Yeah. I do the 50s just work so
much better. But when you start doing
thousands and thousands and thousands,
you're buying the 70s and spreading them
out just because it's financials like
Yeah. The 50s though root amazing. We
used to get 20 bucks a clone and we get
a,000 bucks a dome for those 50s. Yeah.
We were just slicing them all day, you
know, of the limo G. Yeah. I mean, we've
been doing trials and we've been
noticing that the one and a half inch
cubes get better results than the twos.
Like as far as we get faster rooting, we
get wider, thicker, healthier roots,
right? Because it's imagine a plant,
right, that's like VP like you're you're
just it's drying out. It's able to feed
more. It's almost like aeroponics or
something. You're getting more oxygen to
the roots. There's it's just bubbling
all the time. You know, I I noticed I
grew hydroponics for like 20 plus years
and we would make our own setups with
tubes. It was like an aeroponic with the
nutrient film. And at first we were
spraying the bubbles onto the roots and
then the roots were just clogging the
whole tube. So we would have to put the
holes where the roots weren't just to
airate the water, right? But you notice
you could get the thing that you know
those plants would eat 24/7. We would
leave the CO2 on accidentally sometimes
in the dark. And you know, contrary to
popular belief, like I believe plants
can digest CO2 in the dark, you know,
because we we accidentally leave a tank
on and it would just empty and we'd turn
on the lights and it'd already be just
perking and growing almost like it was
digesting the CO2 or like slowly
releasing it like a late release
nitrogen keeping it and not digesting
it. That's why I was going to ask you
what you think about like
photosynthesis as effect to like
anthsyanins beating like the virus cuz
like we have plants sometimes that the
top will be green and the bottom will be
purple or the part that gets like less
sun will turn purple like on one piece
of cannabis and I think that's very
genetic specific right to the cultivar
because I see a lot of the stuff and I
can use an example from indoor
cultivation where everybody's using
these LEDs and their stuff is kind of
purple. It's not that purple, but it has
that purple hue. And then it's like the
purple that trims off the Well, then
they get the favven under canopies,
right? And they have a lot of that far
red. And now all of a sudden the bottoms
are more purple than the tops. Right.
Right. And so I think a lot of it has to
do with the light spectrum. I would say
they're also saying like the nutrients
like what you feed it can
count. Absolutely. And then you know
obviously air temperature like you're
but in respect to it you know beating
the hop latent you know why it beats hop
lat and like that Indian study that
study out of India over there I saw that
there's been a few of them and I'm not
sure exactly why I think we're still all
trying to figure that out right but uh
it's really interesting the direction
they're going in and the fact that
they've identified that anthocyanins and
the relationship to hop late and you
know it's it's amazing because I feel
like we're one step away from being able
to breed it out as opposed to, you know,
you can you can treat it with you can do
mirror stem tissue culture and you can
basically you're basically outgrowing it
at that point anyway alals like some of
the Israeli studies where they're like
blocking the ability to mold, right? But
at at some point it's borderline GMO.
Like there is a line in my mind for me
anyway. Yeah. Like whether you're going
to use crisper or like I'm an organic
gardener, organal, whatever you want to
call it. Like I would rather grow
organic food than grow chemical
cannabis. Yeah. And I mean the thing is
for me I'm not opposed to crisper and
I'm not opposed to other people doing I
don't do it. It's not my thing. We do
data driven breeding. We collect as much
data as possible and that gives us the
you know the best opportunity to breed
in the directions that we're trying to
go. Yeah. The most important thing is
data man because if you don't have that
you have nothing. So like whatever
you're doing wherever you're growing
record it. If you're monocropping, like
see the difference so that you know your
area. One of the best things you can do
on a large scale commercial farm is just
get yourself a set of flags. Yeah. You
know, and if you have a bugged area,
mark a red flag. If you have an area
that's not getting good water or is
overwater, mark a little blue flag just
to set a little flag so that you won't
lose sight or control. Get yourself a
clipboard. Be organized, of course, but
yeah, know the areas, flag them out, and
then when they're better, remove the
flag. And that helps you like be able to
handle a large area. Like if you're just
one guy running a 10,000 foot farm as a
lot of Northern Californians are doing
right now, you're getting your ass
handed to you, you know, and and you
know what you're doing. You've been
doing it your whole life, but it is
still challenging. So, anything that
helps, which I really recommend we have
more forums and people sit down, not
just on a business attribute, but really
like helping each other instead of
shutting each other out or saying, "Oh,
I found a secret. I'm going to use it to
get ahead." Think about everyone
benefiting so that we can all work
together. Because when we shut each
other out, man, we're really just
handcuffing ourselves and we've
perpetuated this situation, which is
like a bad domino effect of negativity
when no matter what, you know, whatever
drama you have, whatever cannabis enemy
you think you have, it's much worse than
someone outside our cannabis community.
So, getting over it and
just working together is the most
important thing we can do. Not just now
when things are rough, but remembering
that when things get better because
they're gonna get better. Of course,
cannabis always provides. They're gonna
get better and they're gonna get worse
again. Then they're gonna get better and
she wants us to remember that we have to
work. It's not just easy, you know. So,
tell me about this cup. You brought this
awesome Chem Dog cup. Oh, yeah. Yeah. My
friend Greg G from the Chem Dog. Oh,
yeah. He's one of the ones that
remembers the Lem from the Dead Lot from
back in the 80s, which my wife is always
like, "Get people to remember that
you've had that limb going forever."
Nice. And that's why I was so psyched
we've got some 87 seeds to pop, man. And
it's not just that you were younger and
had better taste buds, man. Like
literally, the bud was amazing back
then. And we were trying to see if some
of these older seeds and some of the
fascinating thing about using that
method to open older seeds. And what we
found to be successful is that those
older seeds don't have the virus. Now,
I'm not saying if you introduce it to
the crops, they're not going to get the
virus, but that older stuff just wasn't
around, which is amazing. Totally. And
the fact that it's skunky and neon,
glows in the dark, and you were right,
like when you were a kid, you had weed
that stands up with the weed today,
which is amazing because we didn't have
labs. We were just breeding by look,
smell, taste, you know. Well, and I
mean, you don't have to over complicate
cultivation, you know what I mean? We
kept it simple a lot of times back in
the day. And then, you know, I started
in the 90s, the mid 90s, and then by the
late 90s, it started getting really
complex with recipes where people were
really putting a bunch of inputs in. You
know, we kept it simple. Even the guys
that were growing three-part, a lot of
guys just did three-part and got really
good results. Oh, yeah. That's just GH
three-part for for like 20, 30 years.
That's what we got. We grew up on that.
We were bred on that. Dude, there are so
many It's not viscous and it can flow
through any hydroponic system and at
most you're adding pH up a gallon every
few years. and it was affordable, you
know, and it worked. And a lot of times,
you know, you're growing, you're you're
not realizing what you're missing,
right? You don't know if it's you're
like maybe short. People think cal mag,
you know, but in reality, you might be
like a tiny bit short on copper or
something that when you just add that
three-part mix, it just takes care of it
and it just whatever whatever problem
there was just goes away. Yeah. A lot of
people used to grow it in soil. Yeah.
with three-part with the soil mix. But
it's hard cuz you're not flushing those
heavy metals out. And as you become like
a chrono or really into cannabis, you're
going to taste that. It doesn't matter.
There is no getting it out. No. And
that's, you know, the living soil
movement, you know, can living soil is
great, but it doesn't have as much of a
flush like the organic farmers that
actually flush just Roro for the last
two or three weeks, which people are
like, you know, some people are against.
the the thing with the the K andF in the
living soil, like I think it's better if
the whole crop is one crop. But when
they're mixing it up and they have like
10 different phenos in one room, it's
hard because like the turpps digest and
off gas, so you're just like it ends up
all tasting the same. You ever have
that? You ever see that where like one
farm's all the different
strains exactly the same cure? Man,
there's so many guys up north or that,
you know, you could tell the gu they're
using seagull [__] or back. I can almost
smell the n when I'm tasting just from
judging all these years when I'm smoking
I'm like gh you know mills you know
you're like you know house and garden
you you just know by the look and the
smell and Athena has a very distinct
flavor you know and it's regardless of
what you think of it or not think of it
you know everyone has their own opinions
but it's Athena has a distinct it's it's
the best looking stuff out there it
looks amazing but you can like you said
and and people should know don't buy
like liquid nudes you know in a and in
bulk especially if you have a long range
plan, buy the powder, mix your own or
copies, you know, you can just just like
when we were kids and we used to go,
they didn't have grow stores and you
you'd see something and instead of
buying it, you just build it. You just
reproduce it. So, like look at the
formula they're using source the
nutrients that you need and just buy
them. Hey, and a lot of it's the grower,
too, cuz you know, it's like you can
have the worst grower in the world and
it doesn't matter what he's using, it's
probably going to be bad. But then,
yeah, you have to hear the plants, man.
if you can't like if you're not hearing
them like you you don't have to listen
like the plants will just talk to you if
if you're not hearing them you know then
it's not well I was bagging on rockwool
a while not really bagging on it but
like about the flavor and then my
buddy's like dude you know the weed that
I've been giving you for the last four
months is all rockwool grown with Athena
Proline and I'm like [__] well it's not
always just looks amazing and it's
always nice to have fresh this stuff was
absolutely amazing and you know it's
like I'm a big fan of United I got the
hat on today I've been using United for
the last six, seven months. We've been
doing trials and working with them and
I'm super happy with their nutrient
line. Was he cleaning it out or what was
he flush at all or like what does he
just feed it right till the end or? No,
no, you you got to flush it cuz you feed
to the end like it can give you heart
palpitations. Like when we were first
starting to grow hydro as as kids like
you could take the biggest dreadlock
down from the dead lot with with some of
this unflushed cannabis, you know? Oh
yeah. It was just like it was beyond
expandable. You got to flush all this
stuff in. I mean, not not with straight
water, but there's, you know, you use
molasses and other stuff in there. And I
think molasses is amazing, man. The
powdered molasses from uh from the last
couple crops that we were using. I was
amazed. Like, I've never seen anything
like work that well. Like before you're
doing your final deleafing of your big
and you're going to lose a lot of sugar.
Give it to a little bit of a heads up
though so that it has time to digest it.
So, it hits exactly so when you remove
it, it's already in there. But I've seen
just amazing like not just the tarp
difference of crystals. I also think it
helps just with the yield because you're
just helping with a little sugar boost
right at the end. Yeah. Um yeah, that
powdered molasses definitely good stuff.
Amazing.
So, do you do synganic or you organic?
We're organic, man. We're almost living
soil. Like our our soils out there since
2015. So, we're looking at almost like
10 year old living soil. And wow. Just
from like lack of funds when times have
been tough the last couple years, we we
haven't bought a whole bunch of nudes.
We're just like either mixing local soil
into it and just using what we have and
we've gotten amazing results. It's when
we realize you remember when you're a
kid there's no new companies. You go to
your local hardware shop and try to
source some lime or get some wood ash or
some cow manure like and it would work.
So a lot of times people don't realize
if you're on this regimented hydroponic
schedule, you can almost just feed once
or twice. You don't have to just feed it
every day and just pound it. You know,
that's almost more for like a commercial
setup. You know, if you have just like
some plants at home in some soil,
beating it like hydronoots every day is
not that necessary, right? And that's
the thing Arian was saying. You know, if
you have some plants at home or a
smaller grow room, sure, grow organic,
but on a big scale, it's really hard.
And we've been doing it and it is hard.
It's hard to have a giant organic to
scale without spraying. And you know,
you definitely get less, but it's all
about integrity or what you want to do,
like what you want to provide. To me, I
want to make a medicine that's actually
helping because that's what we're all
about. So, it's been more challenging,
you know, for all the farmers in
Northern Cali that, you know, big up to
the organic farmers. Every single one of
us that works with cannabis has this
opportunity to make the world a better
place, right? So, now some people will
pick money over making the world a
better place. But we all have that
opportunity to get you're chasing money
and what are you going to get from that?
You know what I'm saying? That's like
we're here whether your mom told you
this or not, but you're here to make the
world a better place. You know, so the
sooner you get to it, it's just like
getting comfortable in your own skin.
You know, the sooner you get
comfortable, the better off you are,
right? Cuz you're here to stay and might
as well make the place better. You know,
we've only have Yeah. We only have short
moments left. So, it's like, you know,
as far as we're here to stay, but we're
it's our time here is so short.
It flies, man. I turned 50 this year and
you you know, you know, do I got a
couple years I got a couple years before
I turn 50, but I feel you. It's like,
you know, it's it's funny cuz uh when I
was a kid, I thought 50 was so old. And
now that I'm like that age, it's like I
don't feel that old. I still feel young.
I feel 18. Every once in a while, I get
a look at myself and I'm like, whoa, who
buddies, you know? But like, yeah, it's
just But that's what's nice about
cannabis. You can stay young at heart.
And that's one of the beautiful things
about like resurrecting these old
strains. It's almost like time travel.
Like all of a sudden, you got a strain
you're smoking on when you were 12. And
when I had that limb when I was 12,
there weren't a lot of people that had
cannabis that were at that level. I
could get anything I wanted with it.
Free backstage passes. You know, I could
just own the dead lot with that quality
cannabis. People were moving pounds. And
even when we were moving outdoor pounds
in Boulder, we saw hundreds of pounds,
but not at that quality, man. That
quality was always, you could even give
it to a farmer when you were buying
wheat off them and they'd be like,
"Whoa, what is that?" Cuz people didn't
have time. A lot of the outdoor farmers
didn't also have indoor setups. I'd go
down to work big grow trim crews in New
Mexico and Colorado and I'd bring some
indoor that I'd grown in Boulder and
people were just blown away. Like who's
this kid in the trim tent with like a
pound of indoor, right? Yeah. I mean,
good weed can get you places. It always
has been able to get you places. You
know, it's funny because there's the
thing is what people don't understand is
there's lots of flour out there. There's
always been a good amount of flour
except for when there was droughts. But
the quality, the good stuff, the the
amazing that 1% stuff. Now, now you're
looking at the 0.1%, but back in the day
it was like 1% of the stuff was really
what I thought was amazing. And then you
get people forget it's a very small
circle of people that have like that
heightened respect or level of knowledge
for cannabis. Like I remember calling
into the High Times Cup a couple times
saying, "Well, how do you guys know that
something's 65% and 35% and they're
like, well, we have a deep pool of
internal knowledge." That was kind of
got me laughing because it's kind of
like when you look at Gregor Mendel or
some of these geneticists where they're
saying you're 25% your mom, 25% your
dad, 50% a mix of all these different
things. It's like kind of you know it's
not exactly 25%. You know, you don't
know if it's 21% or 26% but it's not
always exactly that number. Then it's
the same with breeding like you know
people are looking for these like
homozygote or to homogenize things kind
of and really like I think you're
looking for the hetero like you're
looking for that the outlier. So I used
to throw 2,000 seeds in these little
Dixie cups and just go for it and I got
to see so much genetic expression over
the years. I cross so many different
things to see what was dominant. Like
blue dream is 90% dominant with anything
you cross it with, you know. Well, it's
so stable, right? And we did a lot of
good Yeah. banana tps will literally
take over any tarping profile if you
cross except for mean jeans black lime
like literally like you'll cross it with
something and you're going to get those
banana turpps shining through it's it's
a dominant turpp crosser right um so
it's cool you get to find out like the
results what's happening if you cross
something into something else and the
thing I'm most into now is getting those
old school land races with the THCV with
the alals for that right hand throw for
sports figures and Parkinson's and just
just making real medicine that can get
somewhere quicker than people who are
doing five or 10 year studies to get
there, right? You know, they may not be
shown all the work, but you actually
have something that's more, you know, a
better medicine, let's say, not better,
but more usable than Doug's variant or
like some of those strains that came
through to the market, but either were a
little seated or not stable and just
didn't make it. You know, they're not
still around really. You don't see like
THCV or CBD dominating the the uh the
white market space or the retail space
people ask for. It's around, but not
like it was when when like the rage of
CBD, you know, Mhm. was uh like when the
gift when the gift came out, Ringo's
Gift and the Sour Sue and some of those
crosses people I grew a whole crop that
summer of just CBD and I was sour.
We still have those. They're dominant.
You can just get those. You just toss a
seed and there it is. You know, you're
like, "Whoa, sour sue." So dominant.
Totally. Um, and there's something to be
said. I remember growing those and we
have like a blackberry and a blue dream
and we saw many strains that were super
high CBD. And dude, the blackberry kush
was the pretenda though. That was Yeah,
it was Bud Light for sure. It looked
amazing. Done in 5 weeks. Dude, the
outdoor plants I went and saw this farm
that had outdoor plants. It was just It
looks so amazing, you know, walking up
there. These black plants and I'm like a
the shiny diamond, you know, that does
nothing. And I got so excited because
I'm like, I'm coming back to buy some of
that weed. And then when I got back, we
smoked it and I was just totally let
down. Yep. That happened a couple times
going up north. If you have a tolerance
at all, it does nothing. You know, it
was a rage though. All the rage. It was
one of the strains that really started
PMing pretty hard like right before the
green crack. And when it's tested 8%
THC, right? So like that was like super
low THC. That's another problem. Yeah.
Some of the really high turpp strains,
man, can have like really low THC, you
That's why people have to we have to
re-educate or just unlearn this whole
thing about THC because there's only so
much room in a molecule anyway, man. So
if you're if you go for the highest THC,
it's so rare that you're going to get
the highest turpp. Yeah. It almost never
happens. There's a there's a handful of
things that test really high in
canabonoids and also really high in
tarpen, but it's few and far between.
It's like the banana. the banana when
you know it's it's so THC high THCA high
when you when you make whole plant fresh
frozen out of it it's almost like a
malleable white clay as opposed to a
strain that has like liquid turpps and
like that one has that banana turpp and
it can hit super high THC but a lot of
times you know people just get confused
and they need to remember you just smoke
a bowl and see how it is it's more
important to see how it's grown you know
like that it's grown with integrity or
or you know that it's good medicine sure
and that's a problem that's a problem
with a lot of the edibles too, man. If
you're using like distillate or like
low-grade boof, it's not really medicine
and people are going to get sick. So,
you have like older people coming in or
someone who's already sick who can't
afford to get sicker and they're getting
a product that's making them sicker and
that that's really not what it's about,
you know? So, we have to avoid that or
else we're going to end up in lawsuits
and all these things that will hamper us
from bringing the medicine forward.
Yeah. You know, that that's important,
too, just to have integrity. as the DCC
is like banning all these products, um
it's obvious that like people are just
not keeping it clean. Well, and it's
really unfortunate that they're, you
know, the whole delta 8 problem that we
had guys that decided we're just going
to convert all this hemp into delta 8
because in my opinion, there's no bad
molecules now. There's bad people out
there that that are doing things that
Well, just trying to regulate growing a
plant is ridiculous. They don't tell us
what kind of tomatoes to grow. I mean,
just, you know, not the whole thing is
just ludicrous and and then they just
raise the tax and raise the tax and I I
don't know. You start wondering like
what's the plan? Is the plan to just
make everyone bankrupt and corporate
comes in and buys everyone out because
they couldn't have built it and they
can't make it. That's what you got to
reme remind everybody we made this. You
know, they can't make it. They can just
come in and buy us out. And they can
only do that if they force us all to do
that. If we remember that we're the
asset or our passion is the asset like
Sherb says, remember that and like light
it up, keep it in your heart chakra and
just use it, you know, cuz if you get
tired or you let them beat you down or
you say to yourself, man, how am I going
to do it? You know, they'll end up
winning. You have to just turn it around
even at your lowest points and just be
like the cannabis plant will provide.
You know, that's what it's all about,
right? But we are fighting hard out here
in California for sure. You're looking
at cannabis is, you know, that used to
be 6,000 a pound. Let's say for 30 years
of my life, every pound I sold was six
grand. And all of a sudden, cannabis is
much less and everything else is up. You
know, not just the cost of food, gas,
cost of living out here. So, it's a real
challenge. That's why you have to get
really smart. Make a pie chart. Know
what your percentages are. Know where
your cannabis is going before you grow
it. Well, you better have good quality
flour. Otherwise, you will not survive.
Oh, man. If you're not at the top, then
yeah, don't even you can't even make it
to step two or three. It's not even
worth doing it anymore. Unless you have
the the best genetics, the best flower,
whatever you're doing. Like, if you
don't love it, don't even try. It's not
even worth it. It's just not If you
don't wake up thinking cannabis, don't
even bother, man. Well, if you're here
just for the money, there's way better
ways to make money these days, right?
There's way something else. There's
there's so much more out there. our two
rules on our farm, you know, may they be
rough or not or just smoke weed and
don't be a [__] Yeah, we just stick to
that. We keep it simple. It works. But
it's hard, you know, I I don't mind when
people don't smoke cannabis, you know,
if they need that to focus. But yeah,
for me to really understand it and part
of the disconnect with the DCC and these
other groups is that they're not
cannabis people. That's why they haven't
helped us move forward. And I really
like recommend to people, get involved
in your local government before you're
forced to do it on the ground level. Get
in there, talk at your board of
supervisors meeting, know that you can
unseat a mayor with 50 votes. Like, get
in there and make yourself a voice and
activate with your community so that
later on, 5 10 years, like what we
learned down in line in California is
they're overt taxing us. And we could
have avoided this by telling them from
the beginning, we can't keep the tax
model that we had 10 years ago when we
were thriving for what's going on today.
It's not appropriate. It doesn't work.
It's like a failed government. So, we
have to like keep it fresh and new, like
have representatives in your board of
supervisors, have a relationship that
you can talk to the mayor and say, "Hey,
listen. We need to keep this lucrative
for everybody, not just a one-way where
we're just getting taxed and we're not
benefiting." Yeah. So, like that's
really important, man. The whole tax
thing with the excise tax going up 25%
is crazy in my And the reasoning behind
that, not that, you know, Newsome just
does this every time. is just he's just
said we didn't come up with the revenue
because basically we're chasing people
out of here with the the permit fees and
the taxes anyway. So that you know
they're just going to raise it and it's
going to go up to like 19 or 20%. It's
going up 25% of what it is now and they
may even raise it to 25% eventually
because have you ever seen them lower a
tax? They don't lower taxes in America.
Sometimes they abolish them and I hope
we do more of that but you know they
don't lower the taxes and that's that's
another one of the problem. Yeah. They
they removed the cultivation tax which
was basically unconstitutional taxing a
crop before it's sold. So, and not that
I'm a federalist, but that's just not
constitutional. So, wherever the the
thin line of the laws are, it it's just
frustrating because really everyone who
paid cultivation tax for all those years
should be able to have a class action
suit and get all that money back. They
should. I agree 100%.
Spanabis Europe, what are your thoughts
on uh Oh, I love it, man. It's great. I
love the culture, the vibe. I really
like how they run it. I like how they
give you the first booth you were in for
the rest of your life so people know
where to come back. Yeah. It used to be
Amsterdam for me, like the melting pot
or this the the gathering point in
Europe, but it really just kind of
transitioned into Barcelona, right? And
you got to love it. It's just amazing.
For anyone who hasn't been there, it's
just mind-blowing. So, Spannabus was
amazing. I'm glad I went. We had a great
time. We sold a lot of seeds. We sold a
lot of books. It was just fantastic.
Today, Similas, they like the threeacks
over there. Oh, yeah. They well they
like the three-packs here now like the
biggest seller. Yeah, exactly. Because
it's more affordable. It actually you're
bringing something like a lot of people
don't have more than 20 or 30 bucks but
they want a part of it. That's the first
time I started seeing that in Spain.
People are just like can I buy one seed?
You're just like whoa this dude actually
wants one seed. He's not joking. He
wants one seed. Okay. So he just wants
to do what he can. You know I always
give more seeds in my packs. Like I'll
give 20 seeds per pack and I'll even
give like buy one get one just because
bottom line I want people growing the
seeds. So, I want them to have more. You
know, I'm not going to give them a
hundred, let's say, but I don't mind
giving extra because if they're not
growing them, you know, if you're just
hoarding them and people aren't growing
your strain, then where is your strain
really? Yeah. You know, if you're not
sharing it and putting it out there,
like, how's it ever going to be known?
Yeah. I mean, I feel like that was we're
we're at fault for hoarding genetics
back in the day, you know, and then I
saw guys like it came from keep it
secret or keep it
quiet, but we didn't want to share it
with everybody and let our stuff out.
And I saw us winning cannabis cups with
genetics and and other things and us not
letting the good stuff out. And then we
got these guys with Gorilla Glue, right?
They changed the game. They won the cup
and at the same cup that they won, they
gave the seed, not the seed, that they
gave the clone out to literally
everybody that wanted a a clone. I think
they they might have sold them, but my I
got one for free. Oh, man. And like
2014, we sold like 2400 seed packs at
the Emerald Cup of Gorilla Glue. Just we
were the only ones that had the Gorilla
Glue seed. And Oh, you had the Gorilla
Glue seed back at the 2014. We made We
had And we just had them for sale and
they were just went viral. Like the
people just ate it alive. They just
disappeared. So, did you do you cross
the Gorilla Glue with something else or
you guys? Yeah, we crossed the Gorilla
Glue and and you know when we started
seeding the Gorilla Glue, it started
like having auto flowers like it just
there was so much cracked out of that
that you got to see like where it came
from. It looked like some Colombian.
Some of it smelled like like hot licks
or fireball. Oh, it it's gassy
chocolaty. Like it it's really complex.
I feel like and it's just so dang
crystally, you know? There was like two
versions. One was quick and one took a
little bit longer, but it would like
hang from like so much resin. Yeah. And
it just took over. It kind of like made
everybody stop growing the sour for a
second. People were growing just sour
and it transitioned into Gorilla Glue.
That is
exactly that is why the sour is gone is
we trim nightmare. You know that when
the plant you're trimming sour and the
plant's actually talking to you, it's
actually telling you I don't want to be
trimmed. It's actually telling you stop.
And you don't know cuz you're a trimmer
or you're working or your boss is
saying, you know, but in reality the
plant just doesn't want to be trimmed,
you know, especially that West Coast
sour D that was just, you know, so much
harder to get into and and trim. So I
never got good West Coast
sourdies and that was it right in the
beginning. And then there was like an
AJ's and there was the West Coast we saw
from the West Coast was smaller yielding
but way louder. So they were selling it
at dispensaries and there was a west
coast but I feel like it had hop late
and it was like and then my buddy even
tested I feel like all the diesels carry
it and all the older strains like you
know blue dream it won't test for it a
lot but blue dream is so old and it's
it's amazing like it I haven't seen it
get sick I grow some every year I always
have a little patch of 100 pounds on the
side it sells in a second it it has like
amazing resistance just cuz obviously
someone put the work into it and that's
a problem a lot of these these guys who
are out there pollen chucking and it's
awesome when you take two things and I
love breeding. I love when people take
things and mix them and try to get
something better or something they like,
but you got to remember like, you know,
do the work. Like Blue Dream is is so
good because somebody put a lot of work
into it first and that's why it has the
longevity it has. You know, you have to
really do the work. Yeah, definitely.
It's cool to mix some someone's work
with someone's work, but you know, a lot
of times grow that stuff indoors first.
Grow it indoors. greenhouse and outdoors
and do your research on it before you
just release it because otherwise you're
just trying to profit off something and
giving someone you don't even know what
you're giving them. Yeah. You know.
Yeah. So, if you had one piece of
advice for your younger self coming in
the
industry, what would that one piece of
advice be? Oh, man. I don't know if I
would take it, but I'd give it to myself
just like not to be so trusting and to
remember that, you know, sometimes you
think someone's amazing or or you're
really just projecting what your own
beliefs or core values are into the
person. So, just have a better filter.
Uh, not to sound harsh. Yeah.
Cuz you can waste a lot of time just
like having a lot of heart and diving
into something. Um, but cannabis is
difficult cuz it's all brand new. You
never know. Like some of the permitting,
some of the initial processes that we
got into, you know, we lost. Yeah.
Initially, we didn't know where was
going to get permitted first. So, we we
set up permitting in Menescino and
Sonoma. Mendo was rough. People have no
idea. Still having a hard time. They're
trying to shut the permitting down right
now. Instead of like Humble, they're
somewhere where they're accepting it and
just realizing this is what we have.
They're just there's a real dichotomy.
There's the richer land owners that are
trying to shut it down. And I
understand, you know, they're part of
the conversation. and they think it
increases crime, which it doesn't. They
just need to be educated. Everyone has
to remember to just join the
conversation. Cuz if you can't talk to
people, it just forms separation. And if
you educate them, you tell them they
don't want people driving around in
their neighborhoods. You tell them this
is farming, this is agriculture. When
you're harvesting wine and you're
harvesting pears and grapes, you have
people in the neighborhood. They're not
creating crime. They're here to work.
They're they're working, you know. But
you it's it's a hard argument especially
Menescino where they give the cannabis
tax 5% of gross from us to the crystal
meth task force and it's just a problem
they can't solve and we shouldn't be
responsible for honestly. Yeah. Like any
cannabis tax is it just makes it so
difficult. You almost wonder what is the
purpose because nothing else gets taxed
like us, you know, and here we are.
We're a medicine like we're essential
during COVID, right? But this is the
price we pay for having legal cannabis,
right? So
unfort lobby groups and we're working
together. That's why if you're out there
in one of these burgeoning states or
just starting off, form alliances early.
Get in there with your local lawyers and
activists and, you know, don't pay them
necessarily. Offer them a percentage,
but get on an initiative where you're
moving in a direction that you won't,
you know, get into a jam one year, 5
year, 10 years down the line. Have your
plan and project. Look ahead. Cuz if
you're in it and you love it and you
know you're in it forever, see ahead and
try to project like out here for us,
PG&amp;E has all these rate hikes. So get
solar and get solar quick cuz seriously
know that if you want longevity and
you're a solar farmer or or a cannabis
farmer at all, get solar with it because
they're going to increase your cost of
production by so much eventually that
it's going to start hurting on top of
your labor. Like know that you you may
not want to trim your whole harvest, put
some of it towards an edible cuz edibles
are the only thing that's gone in an
increase in value in the last 10 years
while flour and everything else is
depreciated. you see a candy bar, let's
say a kea bar that was five, six bucks
is like four or five times that now. So,
I think edibles are a big part of it.
And if you can keep it organic, that
that's amazing. Like get your product,
let's say, on Whole Foods shelf in five
or 10 years or just have a projection or
a vision of where you want to take what
you're doing. Yeah. And uh just stick to
that cuz everybody knows just what to
do, just not everybody does it. You
know, people know what's good and what's
right. They just get sidetracked. So if
people are looking to find out more
about Lem from Lampire
Farms, where would they go? We have, you
know, the dispensary in Ukaya,
Compassionate Heart. We've been there
since 09. And the IG Lampire Pharmacyed
and the O Genius is this the OG line. So
contact us on IG. Just DM me and you can
get right to me. I'm available 24/7. I'm
into it. If it's like 2 in the morning
and you want seed somewhere, just hit me
up and I'm there. I'm always available
for tips or like any kind of questions
or feedback. I'm into it. So, like I
enjoy it. It's not like bothering me.
I'm up at 2 three in the morning anyway.
I get after it. I don't sleep a lot. And
so, uh, yeah, hit me up. We got a lot of
FourZs coming. I'm hoping to do a collab
even with you or we want to boost it and
get it into some nurseries so that we
can make it more available. We get a lot
of orders for like 10,000 and 20,000.
And our nursery is small. We're only
producing like 5 6,000 per season. And
that's why we've been successful without
having like Vyroids. And you know, I
don't know how good it would be, but I
know there's some good spots out there.
Radio Ridge and we've had them run our
stuff before. Solid people. Solid people
out there. Ryan, Eva. Yep. Jordan, Ryan,
and Ava doing it. They got really nice,
healthy stock. And it's really hard. You
know, you got to be careful. Yeah. It's
I recommend just getting them from one
spot and not getting clones from a bunch
of different spots cuz you never know
what you're getting, what you don't see.
Yeah. Yeah, you know, you see someone in
the street, you don't know if they have
a cold or not. It's the same thing with
plants. Like plant could look amazing,
you know, and then you put it with your
other plants and you don't even know
what it has cuz they haven't even found
out. Those eggs don't hatch, you know.
Yeah. It's like you got to be so careful
when you're introducing new stuff.
That's why seeds are so great. You just
start fresh with your own seeds. You
don't need clones from anymore that you
can get hopen from seed. So you really
have to know your source. That's why we
went that's why we opened those 87 like
yeah super sativa seed lover seeds and
some centy seed bankank skunk one seeds.
We opened a bunch of different ones and
I was betting or just praying on the
skunk one and that's the one that did
well and man it is just the stank of
dank just you know it's so fun showing
friends of mine that haven't seen it in
like 20 or 30 years. Rest in peace Sam
the skunk man for all your contributions
to our industry. You know, we're talking
about we're talking about so many of the
legends out there, man. Franco, like
there's so many people that like, you
know, they they basically paved the road
that we're walking and driving on today,
you know, and some of them are still
around like Chichin Chong and some of
these guys are still out there doing it
and just leading the way with integrity,
doing it right. Oh, yeah. Ed Jorge,
Robert Connell, Clark. Yep. All these
guys that stood up for the plant on so
many different levels, too. You know,
it's guys standing up in court for the
plant, guys writing books, guys writing
books before it was okay to write books
where you, you know, education George
Van Patton or Jorge Cervantes or and
Edank putting out Frank big time putting
out the education. Education is the key,
man. Even in in the industry or in
retail, if you can just take a minute,
like when these dispensaries first
opened, it was more of a medical
approach and you'd spend 20, 30 minutes
with somebody trying to see what they
needed or putting them in the right
direction. And that can go so far in
establishing a relationship with a
customer that's more than just an
in-n-out. You know, if you treat
somebody like they're going to be there
for the next 5 or 10 years, you can go a
lot further with them if you just listen
to them. Um, yeah, a lot of these
people, believe it or not, are coming
into the dispensaries, like a third of
them, they've never been in one before.
They're a brand new customer. They've
probably never even been exposed to
cannabis. So, they need more than an
initial like introduction or education.
They just they need to know like they're
there for a reason. The plant energy
brought them there. Like whether it's
the fact that they're putting their
pharmaceuticals down or whatever it is
the cosmic energy has brought them to
where they are now and they just have to
come in and just learn, you know,
totally. That's why it's up to us as
stewards of the planet to keep it
organic and keep it medicine because
people don't understand the destruction
or damage you're doing when you're
putting something on the shelf that's
actually like destructive. Well, you're
putting something in your body that's
poison and people are doing it every day
with if you're already sick, man. You
know, I mean, it's like Yeah. That's
like what's happening with us with just
health food with the food in general
health from eating poisons on top of all
the chemtrails and graphite in the air
that we have to just like fight to
survive. But you have to be so conscious
not just of the cannabis you smoke but
of the food you eat, the way you treat
your body, your mind, right? Keeping an
open, you know, it's challenging, man.
As a cannabis farmer, you have to know
it all. It's not just like knowing
plumbing, electric. It's it's deeper
than that. It delves into like HR and
emotional IQ and I mean, you know, I I
have 15 20 people working for me and and
I I never knew I was going to be dealing
with like their relations and their
inter relations. And it's just a broader
scope as you upscale. You have to be
ready for things that you weren't
planning for. Like it's part of the
American dream, right? You take a big
bite out of the cheeseburger and and
sometimes you choke on it a little bit,
but eventually you get there. It's not
exactly what you plan, but you get what
you wish for. So remember that. You
know, people say be careful what you
wish for. I say just dream big. You
know, go for it. Attack it and it'll
come to you. Like to people who want to
get into the cannabis space, even though
it's crowded or it may seem challenging,
if it's where your heart is, dive in,
man, cuz people, we need you. You know,
any kind of love energy is lasting and
you'll be in it. It's here. It'll be
here for your whole life. Well, dude,
thank you so much for coming on the show
today. Thanks for the amazing cup.
Thanks for the flower. You got some
rosin here for me, too. I love I got
that 4Z rosin. So, thank you very much.
And man, let's do this again sometime.
All right, we'll do a farm tour one of
these days. Yeah, man.
Thank you guys for watching. Please like
and subscribe down below.