foreign
[Music]
how's it going everybody thank you for
tuning in today today is the big day
where we announced the winner of the
loud Loops grow contest
I learned a lot of things over the past
six months uh especially over the last
two weeks since I got the entries back
uh about fairness and everything else I
feel like giving people seeds and
expecting them to grow them
is almost unfair I think a clone would
give every Everything an even playing
field uh because then everybody starts
with the same thing giving people seeds
you're going to get some winners you're
going to get some losers uh especially
with five seeds it doesn't give you a
lot of things to pick from if you're a
great cultivator I don't necessarily
think the best cultivator came in first
place I think the guy with the best
genetics who grew really well came in
first place everything was really
impressive I mean the top 10 we narrowed
it down from 18 to 10 and then from 10 I
put them in order I smoked joints
competing them against each other but I
I gave each one a fair chance and some
people turned in five phenotypes so it
was first I had a narrow phenotypes down
for people and then moving from there I
had to go on and
uh pair them against each other and what
I did was like smoke in the morning and
then give it a couple hours uh this is a
really strong Indica leaning variety uh
and so the cultivars that you guys
selected to turn in some of them were
really strong and I also feel some
people went a little bit long with their
harvest date they probably could have
gone a little sooner and that definitely
affects the strength of the and the
effect of the uh the high
okay guys so how I made it more of an
even playing field or attempted to make
it more of an even playing field was
when I did the intake I took everybody's
product and I stored them in these Grove
turf block bags
uh what I really like doing is taking my
jars if I'm worried about my flower
getting damaged I mean if you're talking
about pounds and ounces and whatever
they make different sizes but you just
take the flower right here
and you can put them in with the lid off
and put them at 60 degrees
the great way to store your flour long
term
I think it's an amazing solution I'm
glad they came up with these
and then the entries
I basically divided them up into these
chirp lock bags for storage and for ease
of use I smoked a lot of joints I rolled
big joints I feel like you get the most
flavor from larger joints so two gram
joints was my go-to choice although I
smoked some smaller ones
um you know and it's really interesting
because
I feel like after storing these in five
days before I actually smoked them a lot
of the Terps came out that weren't there
initially when I looked at some of the
stuff I was like it looks a little you
know premature or some of the stuff I
was like well it's not cured out yet and
it definitely did the trick
so appreciate uh Grove and turblock
donating for the contest so
uh without further Ado we're gonna go
down through 10 to first place so the
first place is ten thousand dollars
and then ten thousand a charity second
place is a two thousand dollar gift
certificate and a gift box third place
is a one thousand dollar gift
certificate and a gift box and then
fourth through 10th Place
they get a 200 gift certificate and a
gift box mailed to them that includes
t-shirts and some cool stuff uh and the
gift certificate is good for anything on
the James loud genetics website so uh
we're gonna do this contest again with
clones tissue culture clones uh later on
this year so I'm really looking forward
to that but uh let's go down so 10th
place we got the Big Green Wave
um you know the the 11th to 18th I
appreciate you guys thank you guys for
turning in entries uh top 10 you guys
get uh prizes so big green wave at 10th
Place
uh Ninth Place we got God's Garden
and uh you know I I can't speak highly
enough of all these entries it was
really difficult based on looks some of
them were actually sleepers that you
know in the sense that they didn't look
great they smelled pretty good but those
were definitely the ones that leaned
towards like the Skittles Side of
Everything
uh so and what we had was zerio's which
is uh zerbert times uh cereal milk and
that that times the zbx which is a
skittles back cross with gelato 41 and
so you get some cereal stuff a lot of
the stuff leaned towards the cereal milk
I have to say but you got some cereal
milk sherbet you know and then there's
Skittles in there so there was some
sweet stuff those ones didn't look
nearly as good as the cereal milk
so uh God's garden and Ninth Place we've
got a relaxed atmosphere that turned in
uh some really amazing stuff that I
don't I wouldn't necessarily look the
best but smoked absolutely amazing
definitely soil grown
um as a lot of the entries were soil
grown
budget grower77 at uh Seventh Place
uh really good stuff uh NorCal cannabis
we got sixth place for NorCal cannabis
really appreciate the entries love your
Instagram uh keep up the good work uh
fifth place we got cannabinoid wolf my
friend uh Michael Myers great job
I feel like he might have kept the best
injury to smoke and turned in the second
best one to me but you know
whatever whatever goes it was really
good I feel like his structure wasn't
there his room was probably a little bit
hot but his Bud although kind of loose
was super sticky and smoked really
really really good uh long finish
amazing uh 420 Bomb Pops he turned in
colas from each of his five phenotypes
and wow good stuff good stuff and I mean
the top five is it's really so
subjective when you get into these top
five uh with contests especially with
people that are so passionate yeah all
these the top 10 especially you know not
that there was anything wrong with the
11 through 18 they just weren't up to
par with the top ten uh some people
turned in some really interesting things
um and now we're going to get into third
place
which is a happy Fields Farms
and I feel like the Expressions that he
got out of these plants were amazing uh
you know there there's a lot of unique
Expressions which is really what you
want as a cultivator
when you're growing all these you know
these seeds out if you can't grow them
exceptionally well it's going to be
really hard to differentiate between the
best and the worst uh Happy Fields Farms
his Expressions really amazing I mean I
got a good idea of what to expect when
you buy five seeds out of that and I was
pleasantly surprised so second place
we got wsdj
uh really good stuff gave me five
samples as well
and they were all really phenomenal
smoked really well uh burned really well
tasted really well the effect was
phenomenal
uh you know I think
you know these guys all in the top five
could could be testers for me anytime I
feel like they did a great job the guys
six through ten you guys did phenomenal
as well
uh and without a do
the first place winner
SoCal tree Smith
uh congratulations uh hopefully we'll
get you on an interview sometime in the
near future
really appreciate your entry you turned
in one entry it was a little over 40
grams phenomenal flower sticky and lots
of candy and I think that's what I was
looking for is candy somewhere that has
a good structure but still has that
skiddly candy that you know that really
lingers on the back your palette that
has that long finish
phenomenal stuff
um you know it's it's really interesting
doing these contests and this is my
first one we're gonna do more we're
gonna do more with clones specifically
and uh
yeah I think you know so I guess let's
talk a little bit about the Expressions
uh that we got you know that went from
uh very like various candy we got candy
necklace we got Skittles sweet uh we
we've got all kinds of different candy
in there and then there was some really
earthy pungent gas uh from like the
cereal milk side and the sherbet side
where it's like that earthy gassy kind
of nose burn even gassy in some of the
females and I really like those as well
I think the market is kind of pivoting
for for some of those as well the candy
is always going to be popular dessert
strains are always going to be popular
we will constantly be going back to
those but uh trying to switch it up with
the earthy pungent ones
uh you know
I would say that the ones that were
gassy that had that cereal milk kind of
complexion those ones are the ones that
stacked harder the ones that probably
yield more uh there was a lot of
interesting stuff there but I really
liked the sweet nose uh that probably
doesn't yield quite as much doesn't look
necessarily quite as nice
uh really interesting though and then so
big shout out to SF Canna I gave them 72
seeds I germinated them and give them so
I could have a baseline for kind of what
we're looking for genetically and so as
far as Rec grows SF Canna popped and
found some amazing stuff they grow in
cocoa and I would say that it stands up
to a lot of the soil entries believe it
or not some people hate on Cocoa some
people hate on rock well I'm not a huge
fan of rockwool but Coco definitely you
can crush and these guys crushed with
the 72 there's at least 10 that I think
should be grown out again that were
phenomenal so big shout out to SF Canada
those guys are crushing I really
appreciate you guys for tuning in and I
look forward to talking with you more
about the contest thank you very much
you guys have a great day
[Music]
cruising