foreign
[Music]
how's it going everybody my name is
James loud and we are going to review
some of the entries that were turned in
for the contest these are the top 10.
we've eliminated eight out of the
entries and we have 10 to go on for the
next week I'm actually going to spend
time going with each one individually
smoking tasting comparing what I think
is the best against the other ones some
people entered five phenotypes some
people entered one phenotype and they
they hand selected and you know I'm
happy trying all of them I think there's
a good amount of phenotypical variation
between all these entries
um
it's really interesting because we have
different densities so some of this
stuff is denser some of this stuff is
obviously uh Tighter and some of the
stuff is bigger we have some real chunky
nugs here uh like this one and I mean
some amazing Terps across the board we
got really really really good Terps uh
but yeah I mean just color if you if you
look at the color there's a wide amount
of color and I think that has a lot to
do with nutrition and environment as
well and some of this stuff is a little
premature uh at least the other entries
that were eliminated
a lot of them were on the premature side
uh but some of these are totally done
done and amazing I'm not disqualifying
people for seeds uh
so if the butt is seated as long as it
smokes and smells good I'm okay with it
at the end of the day the most important
thing for me is not structure is not
yield is not THC content but is flavor
and effect so we'll be doing a lot of
blind tasting with these entries and
we're going to go against each other I'm
going to be doing this I'm going to have
some friends I'm making some judges kits
that are going out so yeah these in in
no order
uh I can I can talk a little bit about
these so this was a little premature
actually this number one but I kept it
because of the Terps even though it has
a little hay smell to it the structure
is amazing and I'm sure it's gonna smoke
it it has a real underlying candy smell
to it which I really like some of these
came across real creamy
uh like this one right here
it has Heavy Gas and heavy cream we get
a lot of big buds like this in there
which is amazing uh medium density we
got a good amount of color
uh and we're talking about zerios times
zbx zerios is Shield milk times zerbert
and zbx is a skittles back cross and
like this right here this is nice and
dense
this is everything that everybody wants
it checks the boxes
we'll smoke it and make sure it checks
those boxes as well but as far as from a
visual aspect I mean the the size of
these nugs these are fat the trimming
it's great I mean the Sugar Leaf
dude there's some leaves that are just
coated and caked now we got some of the
people that entered smaller buds
I don't mind smaller buds smaller buds
are okay
especially when they're frosted like
this stuff I mean this is like super
Frosty
and this has a freaking awesome candy
terp to it like I mean it's kind of
skiddly it's kind of lemon lime it kind
of you know goes in and kind of burns
your nostrils a little bit too
now this was one of the
softer buds on this number five right
here I really like this number five in
the it's frosty
but this leans towards the cereal milk a
lot of a lot more than some of the other
Expressions uh really nice though as far
as
you get candy on the back end
it reminds me of Twizzlers
uh it definitely has a Twizzlers smell
to it you could tell it was soil grown I
would say this is living soil I don't
know firsthand who is what I'm doing all
this stuff blind
um this fat Bud right here
it Knuckles out the calyx kind of Stack
and uh
it was trimmed really well
um as far as the smell
this one has like almost a candy
necklace I don't know if you guys
remember the candy necklace it has like
a Kenny necklace terp in there along
with some gas and some cream
something I would definitely enjoy
trying if if that comes across in the
smoke man that's a great
great flavor
we're announcing the winners next week
on the show
on the 15th ten thousand dollar grand
prize ten thousand dollars goes to
charity
as well charity of your choice
really good stuff another definitely
like living soil cured out perfectly
uh this one right here has
a muskiness to it almost
an underlying candy Terps has like a
nice skiddly kind of finish to it that I
really like
now this one is a sleeper I feel like
this entry right here number eight
is a little bit of a sleeper
it doesn't look like it's that good
it honestly looks mediocre compared to
the other ones but it has a really good
chirp it kind of reminds me of Skittles
as far as the structure
uh it doesn't have a lot of trichomes
this one is actually sticky but as far
as like it's not nearly as frosted up as
some of the other ones and a lot of
times when you're breeding with
something like Skittles the actual
terpene profile is associated with the
structure so if you're breathing stuff
together with Skittles you're gonna get
stuff that looks amazing if you breed it
with something like Oreos but if you
want the skiddly side of it you're gonna
have to deal with stuff that's not
necessary as Frosty that doesn't have as
nice of a structure sometimes to get the
terpene profile that you're looking for
we got number nine here
I mean rock hard
there's not a lot of Terps
this one kind of reminds me of Oreos but
the thing is is when you're Fino hunting
and you're going through these different
buds this is basically a final hunt
although I'm growing in different
environments normally you want a pheno
hunt in the same room so you give each
each different seed each one in the
progeny its own chance each one of the
plants its own chance
um but we're doing a Fino hunt with
several different environments basically
and it's not on an even playing field
because someone might get lucky with the
lottery
they're going to hit the lottery and
they're going to get the winner and
they're going to have the Terps but
you just never know this is great
this number 10 beautiful structure every
I like everything about it
it kind of reminds me of old school
Bubba Kush structure it's number 10
where uh the calyx swell up at the end
where they absorb almost all the
the uh
pistols
so they almost the little orange hairs
basically go away and so they get eaten
up OG is classic and Infamous for that
it definitely comes from that afghanika
side somewhere over there like like the
Hindu Kush that's a great example of
another one where as it swells you don't
see a lot of hair you see a lot more
trichome
and this one is freaking small little
bud
packs a punch
we get candy we get gas I'm getting that
almost like a Flintstone vitamin candy
out of it
but really nice really approachable I
feel like this one will smell great in a
joint all these ones have a really good
chance we're going to be testing some
stuff and I'll be reporting back next
week we will be giving prizes to all the
top 10 contestants the winner gets ten
thousand and ten thousand goes to
charity and then second place they're
gonna get a
Focus V Carta 2 they're gonna get one of
those along with a dab applicator we've
got Grinders we've got t-shirts for all
the top ten so all these people that are
right in front of me they're going to be
getting prizes I really appreciate all
these amazing entries you know this this
uh
is on the level of something I haven't
seen even with High Times the best stuff
I mean we're up there with the High
Times cup competition good luck to the
winner thank you guys very much
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]