[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James loud
podcast and today our special guest is
Maya Elizabeth from M how are you doing
today I'm doing fine thank you how are
you I'm fantastic thank you so much for
coming on the show you were actually on
the hit list of the people I really
wanted to get on my show since the show
started well thank you I'm honored to be
here and thanks for having me absolutely
so let's dive into some history how did
you get started in the industry cannabis
and I have had a love affair since I was
like probably about 14 it's when I've
been started smoking every day um by the
time it was you know the early 2000s
prop 215 had just passed in San
Francisco and there were clubs popping
up and in Berkeley and Oakland and so I
got my medical card when I was like just
when I turned 18 third floor went to the
third floor that's exactly right me too
and the patient ID center on like San
Pablo that whole time and um yeah just
by the time it was starting to become an
option I was just kind of flowed right
into it so I was already making Truffles
and hard candies I've made like
everything infused over the years and
servicing the clubs and started a a all
female Collective called the omgrown
collective in 2008 and um yeah and then
went on to somehow get the first permit
for manufacturing in California in 2017
and yeah yeah here we are the rest is
history the rest is history yeah so the
edible game has changed so much in the
last 2530 years that I mean since since
91 I mean I've been smoking since 91 but
since since I would say 96 97 it was the
same in 91 as it was in 96 and then it
kind of started with prop 215 it's
started changing and people started
getting creative and I think there was
always like the hippies that got
creative you know on the lot at the Dead
shows and stuff like that you stuff but
like the it's it's next level now it's
everything's milligram dosed uh you're
getting stuff that's safe and sanitary
and
consistent and we never talked about
milligrams before it was like oh here
here's a brownie and you never knew I
mean oh it's a strong brownie or oh it's
a weak Brownie and I think weak back
then was probably 100 milligrams
absolutely yeah everything has um really
gotten refined if if that word fits you
know yeah and um it's it's wild because
we measure these invisible cannabinoids
that turn from an acid you know get
converted and activated at a certain
temperature and we measure these
invisible things and um you're allowed
to be 10% over or 10% under in
California like in Canada you can only
be 5% under yeah which I thought how
Canadian yeah how Canadian right yeah uh
and it's just this
wild like Wormhole of granular cannabis
science it's all changed so much I mean
the flowers changed yeah uh to a degree
the flowers changed I mean it's
Everything's changed and everything will
always change it's it's all constantly
evolving I mean we're all constantly
evolving it's true and it's it's
absolutely amazing I mean I think that
there's a lot of people hating on the
way it is right now and I think it's
still just as amazing amazing uh in a
different way so and it's a struggle for
some people I get it so but I think we
got to count our blessings I think that
less people in prison is a good thing
yeah it's interesting I think everyone's
had their like expectations and reality
shattered of where we're at with legal
cannabis by this point so you know it's
kind of like six in one half a dozen in
the other where you know the cards are a
little stacked against you with all
those taxes and all the things that you
have to do so right the beginning of
legal ization as far as recreational
there was like the first people that had
the most amount of money got their
licenses right and especially with flow
that didn't necessarily mean that they
had good flour that mean that they could
get their license and they had something
on the market but that and so that was
disappointing for me seeing all the
flower that was not very good and it was
like at the bottom it could only get
better and it has it has gradually
gotten better and you know with extract
2 I I know like uh absolute extract
canic craft those guys you're working
with them I believe uhhuh those guys
have been pushing the envelope Dennis
has been pushing the envelope for years
absolutely it's true yeah both Dennis
and Ned are for sure pioneers and you
know Trailblazers yeah Trailblazers
Pioneers uh amazing people and they have
great stories it's true and I mean
there's not a lot of people like like
the the law was changed uh in Santa Rosa
because of Dennis so awesome yeah legend
legend yeah yeah he's he's legendary and
it's amazing having so many people that
are pioneers and revolutionaries in the
industry and they're constantly you know
evolving and showing up and making
change and it's pretty amazing it is
amazing so yeah so tell us about om so m
is um is my company I started om in 2008
uh and we started as om edibles but
we've made everything over the years
we've done like the holy anointing oil
from the Bible all kinds of topicals a
lot of different tinctures multi- herb
tinctures um now we mostly focus on
Epsom salts and bath bombs hydrotherapy
and we also just re-released our gummies
non-solvent gummy pectin gummy wow yeah
uh but we've we've done everything over
the years we also have a CBD side to our
company and we do like bulk CBD Epsom
salts but you know buckets five and 10
pound buckets wow yeah some body oils
and a couple other balms I'm a huge fan
of bath salts the kind you smoke but but
epom salt I do uh I we have a jacuzzi
tub at the house and I'm getting older
and I get aches and pains yeah and epsom
salt is absolutely one of the best ways
to help with
inflammation uh it you know it's high in
magnesium it is magnesium basic it's
magnesium salt but uh it it's just
amazing and then adding something
like cannabis exactly full spectrum
exactly I think that's just a big game
changer and a lot of people I think a
lot of people are unaware of the
benefits but as you get older it's like
there's little secrets that's one of
them it's true I feel like uh you know
magnesium could alleviate 90% of
people's ailments and woes yeah um and
it's best absorbed topically yeah so
Epsom salts are an affordable effective
way to relieve pain and do literally a
million other things Epsom salt does
like a million things it even
strengthens your hair it strips away
shampoo buildup it stops spasms it takes
away eczema and psoriasis makes you feel
good makes you feel good it makes your
dark circles go out from your eyes it
makes you sleep like a baby it makes you
have regularity in your system um you
wake up like charged up with like not
puffy and dehydrated unlike alcohol
which I love like a glass of wine here
and there I don't need to demonize
alcohol but like after a cannabis bath
you sleep like a baby and you you wake
up actually moisturized and nourished
yeah and rested and like completely like
depuffed yeah and hydrated it's amazing
yeah and so
um we take pharmaceutic salt
pharmaceutic grade salt Epsom salt and
we um we Infuse that with apricot oil
avocado seed hoba and argon which are
like basically the headiest of the
headyy oils like yeah so like sebum is
what our skin secretes to make scars go
away and it's found only other place in
nature is hoba oil so these things are
really good for your face for your skin
um moisturizing oils that are all
plant-based and of course full spectrum
cannabis yeah yeah and then therapeutic
grade essential oils yeah it's amazing
um I blush when I say this of course I'm
literally five minutes in and I'm about
to drop my little bomb but it's so worth
it because I watch People's Light Bulbs
go off so there's actually a a
concentration of receptors in the womb
space for women wow yeah and also the
colon is like a sponge so you know
unlike eating an edible or taking a hit
of weed there's really no chance of a
bad trip but it's like very sedating
they do everything a topical does but so
much more wow yeah so um like couples
love them um they really like can just
shift your mood and take your worries
away like even in the witchy World salts
pull negative energies and they cut
energy so like a lot of people who are
healers take salt bath every night to
cut everyone's energy from them yeah
yeah even salt was like a preservative
in history or like secretly that's why
you know what I'm saying you got haters
be gone and so um in like many you know
psychic people's place you'll see a bowl
of salt in the corner CU it's absorbing
negative energy right um also you know
cannabis the government patent is for
neuroprotectant properties as well as
antioxidative effects right so the
antioxidants cancel free radicals which
is what makes all wrinkles and illness
so it's like on top of that it just
leaves your skin like shining and
nourished and supple it's like a beauty
benefit and it's also great for your
hair so I'm like there's not really
anything these these cannabis baths
don't do yeah yeah it's pretty amazing
it's it's my favorite consumption form
besides inhalation yeah yeah they go
together really well that's awesome yeah
yeah so where did you come up with it so
we were on the garden um out on the all
female Collective literally back in like
2008 and my girl was super sore and she
was taking like whole bags of magnesium
salt like 10 pounds at a time and
dumping it in the tub because actually
when you go to one of those fancy
soaking pools it's really just 2,000 lbs
of Epsom salt yeah yeah so you can in
cheap so you can like take a whole huge
amount of it and dump it in and it's
like amazing so I had just made a fresh
batch of olive oil and she said I'm
going to go take an Epsom salt bath I'm
like so sore and I said can I put some
cannabis olive oil in there and she's
like yeah and she came out she's like
dude I'm effed up my body feels like a
noodle I got to like lay down wow and I
was like I'm taking one I need to see
what this is all about and I tried one I
was like wow this is really a powerful
effect it's so relaxing yeah it's
interesting cuz like you hang out with a
lot of you know couples and maybe the
guy or the girl is a really heavy
consumer and the other person is not the
one who's the heavy consumer gets in is
super relaxed has this wonderful time
the one who has you know is cannaboid
deficient their body like sucks it up
and they and they turn into a noodle so
it's just so interesting kind of like by
soaking in it your body will take what
it needs right yeah that's the beauty of
it yeah totally yeah have you experiment
with strain specific using different
genetics or do you feel that pretty much
across the board with the cannaboids
you're going to get the same results I
think that so THC definitely makes a
difference um but you know we have 10
pounds of arnica salt and we have some
people that buy six of them at a time
and I think to myself wow this person is
dealing with chronic pain and these
baths really must help right so um the
CBD ones are very effective as well it
does like translate well but the THC
hits really different if you're into
feeling sedated and relaxing or maybe
you're dealing with anxiety or severe
pain sure yeah really cool yeah so yeah
and then with om you guys have done all
kinds of other stuff as well Edibles and
yeah you've won awards we have you're
working with whoopy for a while yeah we
we were so we did let's see I mean I've
done everything over the years um
hundreds of thousands of hard candies
you know probably a couple hundred
thousand peanut butter puffed rice
truffles throughout prop 215 those we
were really famous for those they were
like I don't know if you remember
Rainbow Grocery in San Francisco but I
used to go get the 5 pounds of organic
peanut butter there and then the go to
get the puff brown rice and hand dip
them in Belgium milk chocolate they were
just so heady and strong it was like two
for five bucks wholesale you can't beat
that yeah it was a total different era
um $40 now exactly I know isn't that
wild um so so yeah now now we do mostly
bath stuff but we did like I said bring
back our gummies so out of all the
things you've made what's your favorite
besides the bath salt or besides the
Epsom salt
so well it would be a draw uh would be
the love bomb which is like this all
over topical SL Lube that we make that's
like five natural ingredients wow yeah
um the love bomb or our gummies I went
really far down the gummy Wormhole yeah
I wanted to get into it cuz I saw the
potential because I I I love gummies I
love the you know and gummies as far as
with cannabis them I think that's just a
game changer and it's so appealing to
everybody that people that wouldn't
normally smoke they see a gummy and
they're like ah you know like my mom I
could be like Mom try this gummy whereas
I'm not going to pass my mother a joint
right that would never happen and
there's so many different ways you can
make a gummy there's so many different
recipes you can make them vegan you
don't have to make them vegan you can
you know there's there's a million
different ways to make them and there's
some really good ways and some really
bad ways it's so true and so um you know
when was the last time you put a gummy
that you didn't like in your mouth like
you might try another brand or flavor of
gummy but you're not going to put that
exact one back in your mouth yeah most
likely right you know if you really
didn't like it so you know you start
with your kind of pad diffu texture more
like a galet yeah uh you can get nice
and firm and bouncy that's something I'm
really into I want her to like talk back
to me so my gummy talks back but she's
pecked in right so she won't melt you
know won't melt
it form and I'm not opposed to a gelatin
gummy like I enjoy them I'm really not
opposed I
just I don't like the Haribo really
necessarily the hard ones where it's
like a lot of che where they get stuck
in your tee like Swedish fish like this
I actually like Swedish fish but I don't
like like if like I like Swedish fish
for whatever reason they're nostalgic I
like Swedish fish but that doesn't talk
back it doesn't bounce back to you right
I know yeah yeah so I can go so granular
down these gummy wormholes one the
potential for flavors that you put with
gummies I mean you can do teas you can
do all kind Earl Gray C meal with sugar
and and you can also blend those with
berries and all kinds of I mean it it's
endless it's like a Choose Your Own
Adventure and I mean that's I used to be
a chef so like I get really excited
about talking about flavor combinations
and there's so many different flavor
combinations that work really well
together and then you take something
like a gummy and you can do a million
different flavor coms it's so true it's
like a Frozen little bite yeah
experience totally so cannabis wise yeah
what's your favorite thing to
smoke so so I love dabs um I do a lot of
non-solvents I'm like I judge the
non-solvent um category for the emerald
Cup every year so rosin and bubble has
rosin and hash yeah so good yeah it's
the most lovely time of year for me it's
like having a little extra part-time job
it like it's you got to little you know
carve out a little time for that cuz
it's couple hour meetings and we just
wrapped that up actually and that was
fun yeah I think it's maybe my eighth
year doing that wow so who won I'm
kidding I know right I could tell you
the number but I don't know the company
cuz it's actually blind that's really
cool yeah so flower and hash are blind
but like topicals and Edibles are not
sure um so I find myself smoking a lot
of hash uh out of I do the puff Co it's
honestly it's going to sound terrible
but it's kind of like a little out of
laziness not okay laziness maybe isn't
the right word I'm busy I'm doing stuff
all the time like you know my hands are
always in something and so th that works
for me cuz I don't have to sit down and
commit a lot of time of heating my torch
and right all the acutron that goes with
it you know sure um other than that I
love good flour I brought you I brought
some really nice flow today nice um I
brought some um some outdoor like East
Coast Diesel and I brought some indoor
cereal milk um from I'm I'm a huge ecsd
are you AB absolutely one of my
favorites and I have yet to see any ecsd
that's as good as it was back in the day
okay tell me I hope maybe I can be the
person who who can bring that to you so
disappointed okay tell
me I'm
nervous I mean I get the smell for sure
on the inside it's just in these plastic
bags they eat up these plastic bags eat
up the smell they eat up the the tur
basically look this turns into all one
bud look at that indoor cereal milk this
is from the people who made it nice look
at that turnning all one bud it's so
nice that's indoor obviously yeah bar
you barely have to trim it it's like
such a beautiful strain good nose on it
yeah they're both so fire yeah yeah I'm
a huge fan twist one for us if you want
want to try any yeah look see sticky
test check you could even like drop it
and it barely even yeah yeah the sour is
I love sour me too yeah when you were
talking about your flavor track there I
was like okay we're we're on the same
track yeah I love Kim dog Sour
Diesel a lot of the old school stuff I
mean you give me some GDP I'd be happy
so one of the entries this year yeah was
a straight up like six-star hash made
out of a nostalgic purple really I was
freaking out over it I was I was
freaking out the most over it I was like
house was purple I was like you guys are
you like white thn well not no no there
was that for sure there was white I me
too it's really special this was actual
like purple Urkle hash and I this was my
comment in the section I gave it almost
a perfect score it was like glistening
purple diamonds like the color of this
and I said um when we had weed like this
we didn't have hash like this which
makes me a very lucky girl that's
amazing because I got to go in a time
machine I was like oh my God like
someone went to the p last picked up
that nostalgic purple Urkle little
silver tiny balls and washed it into the
nicest hash right that was really
special experience for me totally
awesome yeah especially like those old
school purples you know it's like I have
not seen GDP in a long time that's like
the purple GDP yeah no one grows it
anymore well you know the reason yeah
because it Veges I used to so I used to
grow it and it would veg for 31 days and
I don't want to it also tests around 12%
so this Market is so percentage based
you know but but you have a tummy ache
you're going to reach for that purple if
you have access to it it's the best
medicine yeah it'll make you hungry also
so good take your pain make you hungry
yeah it was good stuff and good flavor
and it was gassy it was like you know we
talk about purple candy gas and it was
purple it was purple floral gas oh
creamy maybe not candy but it was floral
yeah it was like lavender yeah you you
take the tiniest pole you get huge Cloud
that doesn't make you cough I call that
expando y look for that quality a lot
you know I love that yeah me too so it's
like you know when you're judging hash
you smell this when I that I just broke
open it's so rubber tire in the sun oh
yeah oh so yum yum that's creamy too so
yummy yeah yeah this is burnt tire and
cream totally this is like this one's
got the code for my brain that I want
well we're gonna start off by smoking
some some Z okay yeah I mean we live in
an amazing time we got to experience
really good flower back in the day I
mean it sounds like we're from the same
era where yeah prop two 15 third floor
Harbor Side BPG yeah uh PCC in in
Berkeley off Telegraph and all the all
the traditional guys I mean everybody
was traditional back then even the guys
that sold it to dispensaries it wasn't
like the license gross right and amazing
flower uh amazing genetics and just as
good as today in my opinion and more
variety of genetics I feel like there
was more diversity right so like yeah
there was way less
strain names but there was the diversity
was as far as genetic diversity there
was the ha a lot more Haze back then uh
a lot more hybrids too that were
distinct hybrids it's funny someone gave
me um you know a jack Herrera cross duie
the other day and I you know I'll be
honest with you I can appreciate Jack
herrer but I know that's not like going
to give me the effect I want I know
that's not my medicine of choice you
know so I was like oh let me just try it
for like old time sake this is nostalgic
and it was you know kind of early and
everybody's always saying Jack herrer or
sativa it actually was a super flat down
or high for me I was like o opposite so
there was so many back in the day there
was lots of different Jacks yeah I like
the Jack Flash yeah that was my favorite
my friend CJ from high school his
parents used to grow it and it was they
brought I believe they brought the seeds
back from Sensei seeds in Amsterdam and
it was amazing but there was Jack like
the Jack Herrera is different than the
Jack that I see today it's very linear
and very
like uh lyine and not a lot of
complexity to it and I remember the Jack
back in the day having a lot of
complexity and also would get you ripped
did you ever go to um kenam Medcare at
pken Suter with the Giant Buddha
downstairs I don't think so anyways I
used to work there for a period of time
as a bud tender also and that was
definitely an era we were I mean we were
paying 42 for purple yeah 4200
to times were different back
then missed those things yeah I know so
and I mean I think that just just the
guys you know when you're growing in a
garage as opposed to growing in a
warehouse you're putting more attention
into those plants people are getting
more per pound for it but uh pretty
amazing some of the stuff that we got to
see the cat piss back in the day was
like my favorite yeah uh but sour and OG
it's like dude the the OG was it would
you smoke it down to the roach it's Pine
yep it's lemon it's Pine it's it's got
that little hint to Citrus but it was
like gassy and not like chem do gassy it
was like OG gassy which is very
different to me I'll forever and always
be an OG girl myself I just love love
those gases more than anything in the
world yeah oh yeah and actually to be
honest with you the first thing to kind
of like make a wave I think since like
cookies and the gassy stuff has really
been um white Thorn Rose to tell you the
truth there hasn't been a unique new
profile in town so white Thorn Rose and
I've I think I've talked about on my
podcast before but uh as far as what I
love the effect of it and it's Feelgood
weed it makes you feel great and then so
my friend Dave has this blue 13 cross
that was like uh Louis the 13th for he
got it from
JRE uh at Wonderland Nursery back in the
day uhhuh and from Kevin jrey and then
he crossed it to his blueberry Haze and
it is incredible it tastes very
different than white Thorn Rose but it
has the same effect like literally
interesting has that same like you smoke
it and you just feel really good and
that white Thorn Rose if you smoke it in
extract I got some from Bella Heritage
yeah yeah and some of her rosin and that
stuff just it's purple freaking tastes
ABS so pretty and then the Rosen pens
I've I've got Rosen pens of it that are
just just like I don't want to share
them with anybody because it tastes so
good and it makes me feel great um but
yeah that's a fun and you can smoke that
day afternoon evening whenever and it
just makes you feel good yeah and so
that is what changed my ethos in
breeding in the last two months because
I've been so fixated on Flavor right how
does it taste how does it taste how does
it I'm I'm constantly asking people how
it tastes instead of how it feels and I
realize that I'm on the wrong track
around 420 when my friend passed and so
now what we're doing is we're going back
to like how does it make you feel and I
think we're going to prioritize that a
little bit more and flavor is going to
come along with that too but I think
that's a it's a valid question like how
does it make you feel we're talking
about medicine even though you're using
it recreationally how does it make you
feel oh 100% yeah even when we use it
recreationally I would just point out
that I think it's still rooted in some
type of wellness and healing yeah
totally when we pick our winners you
know for judging the emerald cup I I
just noticed at least Within Myself you
know there's never um a hash that blows
my mind for flavor yeah that didn't also
blow my mind on nose yeah so sometimes
there's a great nose and not a good
flavor but there's never an amazing
flavor without a great nose yeah that's
one thing I have been able to I've seen
so so with Pho hunting yeah Sometimes
the best ones are not the loudest ones
they have a good nose but I what what
I've seen across the board is sometimes
the best ones aren't quite the loudest
because sometimes the loudest ones are
the best ones Skittles is like that you
squeeze it you smell it it's amazing
it's loud but some of them are like more
subtle on the nose where you're like ah
it smells pretty good um like purple
punch is the opposite purple punch has a
great nose like I think when you squeeze
the butt it smells pretty good but then
you smoke it and it's a big let down and
it tastes like cardboard tur yeah you
get one hit that might taste okay and
then the rest of it just tastes kind of
bland yeah charcoal charcoal yeah like
you're just smoking a plant yeah um and
so I'm not a huge fan of that I want I
want it to taste down all the way to
taste good all the way to the roach or
when you fire it back up the next day
you're like whoa that tastes amazing
yeah and then after you hit it if the
flavor sits in your mouth uninterrupted
until you interrupt it you'll be tasting
like whatever it is exactly yeah and if
well with dabs too like where it's in
your teeth right so like you could uh it
could be half an hour later and you kind
of just move your mouth around you're
like whoa I still taste it still taste
it this is what I've been smoking on
this is so yummy is actually from from
last year um yeah my girl from feeling
Frosty hash washed it it's really nice
yeah so nice so yummy it's like kosher
Skittles and a bunch of OG and Skittles
that's awesome yeah Skittles is great
yeah absolutely do you have this new
thing I do not
I have to say it like it really did make
a huge difference it was a game changer
so yeah I got the new ays from uh Focus
V do you like it and I like it it's it's
like an upgrade to a pen I feel like you
get more of a real hit from it um and
it's portable and it can fit in my
pocket so I could like load it up and
take it around and oh it's little it's
yeah it's uh it's about that tall and it
has kind of like a round top right okay
I know yeah yeah and it works good and
it's just like it's like a big fat p oh
that's
awesome but yeah I mean dabs have come
so far from having to use hot knives
yeah and and or charcoal yeah so yeah ex
chase the dragon yeah one of our mutual
friends uh Micah back in the day we used
to smoke on charcoal and you'd light the
hookah charcoal up yeah and then drop it
on there and tube and you'd hit it yeah
chase the dragon we used to do that I
used to set that up at the club for
people oh yeah and so that was like the
pre that was before we had dab rigs
that's how we used to smoke it we had
BHO and that's how we used to smoke the
BHO and we had butter you know yeah
really good stuff this is amazing that
yummy so good so yummy right she's so
talented they're both so talented her
and Madison yeah and that flavor just
sits in your mouth it totally coats your
mouth yeah yeah I love that and it's
complex I like complexity I feel like
stuff that's just very linear like if
it's just blueberries or it's just lemon
or it's just orange it doesn't do it for
me yeah uh Agent Orange
for the most part I've I've tried a
couple different fenos of Agent Orange
over the years but agent orange you know
from subcool now that was very linear to
me and then I went to House of coltivar
in Washington and they had some agent
orange that was like the most amazing
complex like hits on all these levels
and it was amazing so sometimes
phenotypes have a huge play in that but
uh yeah it's like and I'm not a huge
orange turp guy but like I like
everything I like everything in in the
right moment I like everything I even
like blue dreams from time to time oh
yeah I mean BL dream yeah oh yeah
absolutely and if you're around 15 years
ago you got to see really amazing Blue
Dream yeah yeah exactly lots of it it
was everywhere when there was like that
little like Trend going around where
people were trying to put down blue
dream I was like first of all it's weed
oh they still hate on it and second of
all I guess you weren't in prop 215 when
it was really cracking then cuz we were
making lots of progress and success with
blue dream and before everybody had it
it was the thing to have and it was in
high demand and then we can blame Ed
renthal and a couple other people
releasing they bashed it down no they
released the cleanser oh man maybe it
was Ed maybe it wasn't I'm not sure but
but Ed did sell clones back in the day
and uh he sold a lot of clones but yeah
Blue Dream as soon as it got out
everybody shared it with everybody did
so much yeah and everybody wanted to
grow and it made you look like a good
grower so yeah it's it's like one of
those ones like if you want and I would
used to tell people beginner Growers you
should grow that if you're growing for
the first time don't grow OG Kush even
though you love smoking OG grow Blue
Dream see how you do with blue dream
first exctly and uh I mean I used to
love growing and it was the first thing
I got over two pounds that and sour I
used to get two pounds of light now
that's like nothing people are like I
get four pounds but uh back in the day
two pounds like if you hit two pounds
everyone else was getting one and a half
pounds uh you were doing really good
exactly yeah Blue Dream does make people
look like good Growers because it's like
kind of blue and silver yeah not that
not too many hairs right and you feel
really good about yourself it finishes
and it's chunky and it's yeah you know
the cut that used to go around and
there's I think there's a lot of s1s
that have floated around since and I
think a lot of the people that have Cuts
now have s1's I mean there's a handful
of people that still have the real deal
but I don't see a lot of the flower
that's like the same stuff that we had
that was like super sticky absolutely
and I mean it was it was a it's as far
as like structure and Vigor and and a
lot of the the boxes that are to be
checked it was the apical of all of them
back in you know I agree it looks so
beautiful and you would open a pound bag
a turkey bag you open that back in the
day and it was like wow what is this
especially if it was the first time you
ever saw it absolutely so I know it so
that in AFU I don't know if you remember
AFU oh I remember afang go for sure yeah
so we used to get I mean the sweet AFU
was so amazing the first time I saw it I
was like this is fake there's no way way
that there could be this much sugar on a
plant yeah I always saw that I I've
always smell a almost like a bread dough
a yeasty bread dough on Afghan goo that
was a good medicine strain too it was
good IND heavy yeah it was Heavy it was
heavy and it looked just crazy like my
friends used to grow it it looked like
they had sprinkled tricomes on it and I
was like there's no way this is real
like absolutely so remember the old
school like hash plant that was all
garlicky smell like onions oh yeah that
wasn't turpy
necessarily uh it was kind of bland as
far as turpins go but it did smell
Savory it was like Savory and it was
like super mild not an exp on the no but
it was almost GMO harsh you know how
flat GMO can be like almost like
[Music]
harshyne Burger GMO and how that's
evolved into the extract scene like yeah
heavy I like garlic hash yeah that's a
really good high yeah really strong the
flower GMO my friend Marlin went through
this phase after like he was a OG head
and that's all he wanted to smoke only
OG I had a lawyer back in the day and I
had Marlin and those two people all they
wanted to smoke was OG Kush like
literally Marlin was like where's the OG
I used to be the OG guy and I love OG
that's how I met Marlon Asher back in
the day was from OG so and then he went
on this GMO kick and that GMO kick
lasted a little bit but it's so strong
and so I was like gmo's cool I prefer
sour yeah yeah but G more stimulating
more stimulating and that stuff would
you know you would be high yeah super in
the extract too dabs of GMO done yeah I
love sour I love a good Sour Diesel
myself yeah yeah and it's funny because
I feel like some people it gives them
like the couch lock for whatever reason
productive it makes me productive but it
makes me it's another one that makes me
feel right absolutely so yeah all those
chems I feel like the chems the gassy
chems were always good I you know OG's
too absolutely so let's talk about the
state of the industry all right what do
you think about everything that's going
on right now with cannabis in California
when I look at the Cannabis space right
now I see opportunity yeah yeah it took
me a minute to come back to this MH I
had my little you know moment in the
corner yeah I had my timeout right
totally even though it wasn't ever
really a timeout but you know what I'm
saying like well there was a time where
it was like what's going on here like
and I feel like we're so new to the
whole industry is new yeah and so
there's there's no balance there's no
solid foundation with everything that's
going on we it's it's this time where
it's like what's happening next right
and and we didn't know I think that's
scary that can be very scary so we you
know we're here in California watching
New York at their wave and yeah you know
it's so interesting so um
gosh there were you know remember when
all that Canadian money was around and
all the LPS coming down by and
everything yeah like it was so fun so it
was like I kind of feel like the way M
played it was like we didn't take on you
know too much money yeah um that's the
best you know what I mean and so here we
are these years later like still totally
like chugging along you know but it's
we've switched distributions a bunch of
times we've switched manufacturers a few
times I mean it's been rough out there
and if I if wasn't completely in love
with weed I definitely would have given
up yeah um but it's one of those things
where it's like you can't see yourself
giving up you know so right you just got
to keep fighting I'm just totally still
here and I've just shifted my
perspective and it feels really good to
kind of like shift my expectations a
little bit cuz when I step back and take
take what I thought I was going to get
out of there yeah I'm actually really
blessed you know and lucky like people
use our products you know we people
every month people use our bath products
and they bring people relief and I came
for that juice you know I came for that
juice and that nectar gratitude living
in gratitude I am Greatful you know and
so you know cannabis is a female Spirit
like water is a female Spirit like can
you find anywhere in nature where
there's a 90 degree angle in a body of
water no river or lake has a COR a
corner you know so we take water and we
put it in these 90 angle pipes right
and we're kind of like changing the
programming of this like energy you know
so so I kind of feel like that's what we
did with cannabis we took it from like
the feminine the open the free cuz like
cannabis is this forever giving generous
plant like yeah you use the scraps and
then you can like use the scraps again
and then you can use the roots and the
seeds and it's just this everg giving
non-discriminatory like compassionate
everg giving thing you know that she
doesn't want you to weigh her before you
throw her away and block your flow
because you have to track every bit she
says there's more than enough of me just
take me you know so in the spirit of
that plant kind of shoving it into this
90 Dee compliant right for me there was
always this disharmony you know and I
can feel that because I'm on the super
feminine side of it right so I as as
crazy as it sounds I there was a part of
me that had to disassociate a long time
ago like seven years ago and
um and now I just see it for what it is
so like we do CBD like we do all kinds
of things I Always Forever make medicine
I make Rick Simpson Oil like I always
forever be a medicine maker doing it my
own way as well as as well as this like
compliant Market because we've come so
far like why would I give up now you
know absolutely I can't see that you
know so so I get it and once my reality
came to reality I understood that you
know there's no one coming to save us
right this industry is challenged and
most other people probably would have
given up you know cuz like sometimes if
I feel like I'm going backwards it's
like no actually you're still going
forward it's not a circle it's a spiral
because you know what looks like success
today is very different from what I
thought I would have been getting five
years ago right right so all all that to
say this I feel grateful I'm fine I I
understand it now I understand
everything now um we actually let our
permit go we got the first one in
California we decided to let ours go um
maybe two years ago now we were at a
crossroad it was like okay we're good at
manufacturing we've scored 100 on our
tests like we did all the things you
know we had the Standalone building in
Berkeley it was like beautiful you know
that's how we got the first one is
Berkeley let us through right and um but
you have to realize with that comes
managing employees workers comp right a
lot of robberies started happening you
know you might be following the rules
with security but it could be easy to
still break in you know we're a bunch of
girls yeah so I I kind of found myself
at a crossroad like I could pick up
other brands to manufacture for and like
really be a manufacturer you know or I
can just focus on being a brand and work
with a manufacturer so we decided to
actually do that nice and yeah and it's
I actually I I don't feel like I made
the wrong decision I really feel good
about it um everything still takes work
it's not like when you choose that route
your work is done as an entrepreneur
it's really not like that at all you
know some of some of it it's the work
just starts to begin you know what I'm
saying it's like you're still doing all
the things so like um I will say that a
lot of people think people in cannabis
are just like living some sloppy easy
life you know and it's a grind we need
to break more than anyone like all my
poor cannabis friends I'm like we bro
you need a vacation like we need to
we've been saying it's not boss girl
it's Moss girl summer and like really
time to kick it back you know these
hamster wheels go on forever their
wheels they they're made to spin forever
and so like sometimes you need to jump
out yeah well you grind is Relentless
and yeah and like want to I want to get
more for doing less at this point and
when you hop into these vibrational
hacks right where all the money in the
world is already out there and it's a
frequency so like how do I tap into that
station and like just divert it over
here for like really doing less or like
right or like what would I do with my
time for free right now how can I figure
out a way to like make abundance out of
that you know so right just a lot a lot
of Shifting um a lot of Shifting in
terms of you know like every bu we've
been going through Rapid growth these
last 10 years for sure yeah so much
shifting it's been wild and it's not
stable by any means it still has a long
ways to go before the market stabilizes
but we're seeing I mean the light of the
tunnel is there I know it's there and I
can see it I'm still gon to just put one
foot in front of the next I feel like uh
what you said really resonates with me
that nobody's going to come save you you
really got to do it yourself if you
don't like the way the laws are written
change them right make effort towards
that if you feel like your business is
failing do whatever it takes you know
you sometimes you just got to suck it up
and do you know wake up the next day and
do the best you can do and go one more
day and live one day at a time if you
have to or another good example like
everyone's talking about this recent law
that they're talking about passing you
know this Federal legalization or
decriminalization whatever you know and
and it's like okay I get it okay you can
choose the Fear Factor timeline or you
can understand that like this plant has
a gravitational p and like when you're
with her and in alignment like the doors
just seem to open so like trust your
flow there's going to be a place for you
you know not everybody that's going to
come here is going to be monsters
there's going to be good people
everywhere just like everywhere in life
so we just got to trust that we'll get
in where we fit in well yeah and if you
take away your ego and allow you
yourself to be driven by Passion I think
that's where you're going to win
especially with the plant 100% you know
and if you love The Plant like I love
the plant like you love the plant you're
going to be successful and you're going
to Pivot or you're going to do whatever
it takes to be successful and totally
and it's just I I'm just so grateful
that I'm here I'm so grateful that I get
to have this podcast that I get to
interview people like yourself and we
get to talk about cannabis and we're
recording the oral history of cannabis
and it's just so amazing
2024 like 2024 and it's just amazing
that we're able to be in this industry
that's growing and evolving so fast and
it's like surfing a really really really
big wave and I love surfing that's
awesome yeah I know totally um I think
for the right people this is a a time of
opportunity and excitement there's lots
of opportunity out there and and it can
be scary yeah but there's plenty of
opportunity and and you know whether
it's genetics I mean there's the Fear
Factor you were talking about though
there's a lot of people with that Fear
Factor like oh you know I'm this is only
going to happen for another couple years
we don't know we don't if you're still
here now just keep going seriously at
this point just keep going and keep on
fighting yeah U and I feel bad I'm glad
that I'm not into flower production yeah
I'm so glad I'm on the genetic side of
it because I think those people have it
worse than anybody the price keeps
dropping and then we've got guys that
are able to get their cost lower so
they're charging less and it's just
charging less for better quality product
and every year the product gets cheaper
and better quality for cheaper and so
it's real tough being a cultivator right
now and I feel for those guys out there
absolutely on the commercial level and
people that have invested their whole
life into that and they're like well
what do I do now well there's other
things in the industry uh but yeah I
mean I love the genetics I think it's
amazing being able to cross breed so
many different things and now s you know
taking a step back and looking at what
my goals are and what do we want for the
future what do I want to leave is my
legacy for especially for cannabis what
is my legacy I mean I wrote a book that
that's great but it's more than that
it's the genetic side and I feel like
now that I'm older I can really kind of
focus on like okay well what am I
leaving behind for everybody absolutely
and the plant is beautiful like that
whatever you put in it gives back to you
absolutely I I'm got like a really
awesome veggie garden you know every
year I try to have a veggie garden now I
can't imagine my life without one and
this year it's just knock on wood just
so homegrown vegetables it's so much
better you know and it's like whether
it's tomato you just can't get that kind
of stuff from the store and it's also
that you put the love into that plant
and you put the time and energy and so
it has your energy so you're eating a
byproduct of your energy and that's just
so amazing also like you know there's
cannabis Laden throughout the garden
like there's just it's all interwoven
exactly where it should be amongst the
lavender and the chamomile and the chard
and the kale and the Watermelons and the
pumpkins and the zucchinis like they're
all together you know and um and I love
having my son Witness of it you know I
have a
three-year-old and you know he's
learning where his food comes from and
we get to go out there and we're lucky
enough to pull something from the garden
pretty much every day um and just you
know having cannabis plants around just
raises the vibration like feels so good
to be around those plants it's the most
iconic leaf in the world yeah you can go
anywhere in the world and draw that leaf
and most likely make a friend yeah
absolutely you know they're going to get
you some weed you're going to get high
together and you're going to have a
lifelong friend even if you don't speak
the same language tot it's such a
friendship herb yeah I mean food and
cannabis are the two things that really
bring people together it's it's like an
unspoken language it's so true yeah
someone was like so what do you like do
for fun I was like weed in restaurants
yeah I was like and make money I love
make I think making money is fun yeah
cuz I'm kind of an an abundance like um
manifestation type of Junkie A little
bit totally just like love it um always
playing with the energies in the world
cuz you know we're doing this and it's
whatever you make it and so um well yeah
those are my fun activities basically
yeah and around those right yeah totally
like going to cannabis events eating
good food at the Cannabis events you
know it's like yeah I yeah I love
spannabis for that oh yeah I I love the
European events and oh yeah I'm going to
Mexico City in
October first part of October and
cannabis people in all these countries
they're so amazing and the quality is
getting like Mexico City blew my mind
last time I was there the quality and
the people are so passionate about weed
and it's very much like it was in
California in 2008 do they have little
some little social clubs there in Mexico
City so they have groups they have like
Association type groups where like
they're Growers and they all share their
weed and they you know they have
meetings and they talk about their stuff
and they smoke and they share the weed
and share genetics and they're super
passionate about California genetics and
US genetics that's awesome and they're
doing breeding some of these guys are
doing breeding fat bustard he's a he's a
breeder down there and he does some
really cool stuff uh Santa Rosa green
seeds they're in Santa Rosa as well in
Mexico oh that's awesome and uh that's
what's up yeah and I mean the people are
just so passionate and even extract
they're into like making good extract
and they love talking about it as much
as I do and I'm one of those people I
can talk for hours and hours and hours
yeah around food and weed and everything
else and it's so amazing absolutely I'm
um speaking of food I'm like I'm
actually doing a women's uh event coming
up and I'm cooking all the food myself
that's
great yeah I'm not a classically trained
chef but I'm definitely a kitchen witchy
mama and I I definitely feed people you
know is my love language so for years
I've been like playing with this event
in my mind and it's like it's an
honoring of women in cannabis nice yeah
and it's an
intentional uh like clever menu with
with a hash pairing oh nice yeah for
each course nice where you smoke yeah so
so like yeah we're going to smoke our
weed and eat our food instead of eating
the weed I'm not I'm not really into the
whole eating the weed thing I think that
that's great save that for at home I
save that for at home and maybe once in
a while like someone has an infusion
dinner whatever that's cool for them me
I want to smoke my weed and then eat my
food and I love amazing food and I love
amazing weed and paired together they
can be absolutely amazing but just the
whole thing where you want some turps
and some you know 10 milligrams but I
feel like if you eat it with the course
I want to feel it now I don't want to
feel it after I'm done eating and then
I'm like oh I feel great wor about
getting home yeah exactly and I love the
two things and I also like wine I mean
me too I like good wine good alcohol I
like cocktails but but I'm not really
drinking very much right now but I
really I love the social aspect of all
of them right like yeah especially
cannabis with people that like food like
that's a great one where you can talk
about good food because there's so many
good restaurants out there and
there's restaurants everywhere in the
whole world like doesn't matter where
you go there's good restaurants and I
feel like there's good restaurants
everywhere if you know where to look I
agree 100% And you know anyone who wants
to have a restaurant should find a way
to let people smoke weed because we'll
order like three times as much totally
you know tip better yeah treat the
servers better everything everything
better we got a joint what are we
smoking here so this is um some cereal
milk oh yeah yeah perfect
mhm really yummy I really like cereal
milk me too and that one there's some
different fenos of it too for me it's
got to be expando it's got to be smooth
if it's not smooth I don't want to smoke
it well the thing I like about really
good cereal milk is it's creamy and it's
gassy and it's got a little candy Floral
in it and it's like it's so it checks it
really checks all the boxes it's
everything you want it's everything you
want it's like every so so with all the
modern cannabis these gelato
crosses uh I think they're all trying to
be really good cereal milk honestly uh
but I mean I like a good gelato 33 I
like a good runs you know all these
things that are what whatever you want
to call them white runs pink runs all
these things when they're done proper
and they burn white and they just taste
good down to the roach I love those I
like I like Haze too though so super
silver I got some W hawen I'll show you
these plants when you leave but we got W
hawen Times maloi oh and these things
smell great when you do the stem rub on
them and they're veg about 5 feet tall
they're about to go outdoor and I'm
going make some seeds with them wow but
uh the stem rub on them is like this
amazing it's not quite candy but it's
sweet like citrusy sweet and it smells
hazy where you get with the haze but
like funky okay I have to check it out
sound sativa like malao that's one of
those ones that makes me feel good like
red Congo in Malawi yeah really good is
really strong red Congo makes me feel
good and happy and laugh and then deran
just KCK kicks my head in the dirt where
I can't talk yeah I'm so high it's like
and it doesn't have a ceiling all those
all those stengths all those different
African genetics I feel like they don't
have a ceiling to where you can keep
smoking them and you get higher and
higher Skittles there's like a a line
here and it just doesn't get me higher
than this it'll get me high but it
doesn't get me higher than this where
some of those equatorial longer
flowering ones you smoke them and they
just keep getting you more High more
high you can smoke them for hours and
you're still going to get more high that
sounds awesome I haven't gone like super
deep on
those but I'd like
to yeah there's not a lot of people here
growing up yeah it's mostly take so long
because they take so long and and
they're so tall and they're so tall you
need a specific type of room to and
genetics are rare and the people don't
share the genetics yeah like those kind
of things I mean I think you could
probably get seeds of them fairly easy
on the internet right and you know hunt
your own but people are lazy they want
clones so because the seeds are out
there the ace genetics they sell some
good stuff you can search all over the
Internet and find pretty good stuff um
Aladdin from Khalifa genetics he sells
really amazing stuff okay land race
riols you know who says
hi Josh and Kelly Dragonfly oh nice
they're amazing people they're my dear
friends they're they're absolutely
amazing so we were together on the
connect Community event in Barcelona
yeah and she has an opinion and she's
very well spoken yeah and I'd love to
get her on my podcast talked about yeah
she's amazing and so like we hit it off
there and then she's I mean I have no
problem in debating stuff and some
people don't like debating right but I'm
willing to debate stuff how I feel about
stuff and I'm okay that you have a
different difference of opinion and I
think that's great when we can have two
differences of opinion talk about it and
maybe I'll see your side a little and
you'll see a little bit of my side and
then we're like okay well this is how it
is now right and so I mean I'm okay with
trying to change people's minds and also
having people try to change my mind and
so not a lot of people these days are
like that I feel like in the last 10
years people have become so soft they
don't want to hear another opinion
they're like no that's wrong right and
uh we missed the good old debate so did
you have a debate with
her we well we were talking about sativa
a
genetics and
uh yeah yeah I mean it and it was just
good it was good I feel like no bad
vibes you were able to just speak like
civilized people and say each other's
side and yeah and I think she gets the
whole passion for the sacred plant thing
and I think not everybody does
yeah some people it's it's either over
head or they're not into that or
whatever but like I'm always about the
sacred plant and I feel like the plant
has given so much to me uh the reason
I'm here is because of the plant
absolutely you know and I've put a lot
into it but I've got a lot I've got more
I feel like I've got more out of it than
I've put into it a lot of times and I'm
just so grateful it's crazy that you
know we could do the things that we've
done and end up here now in the present
and the present's pretty cool absolutely
so still cool cannabis events High Times
you know it's like the High Times went
away and people people like oh cannabis
events are done and it's like no they
just started so the emerald cup Emerald
Cup's amazing yeah it's about to happen
I love the emerald cup August 18th so
yeah it's like Emerald cup and uh Boston
Freedom rall is coming up in September
I'd like to go to that that's a pretty
cool event I've heard I haven't been but
I'd like to check it out someday too
yeah me too and then you know Hempfest
has always been amazing up in Seattle
but they haven't been doing him right I
know events got hit really hard you know
with the whole yeah and funding for
events and like it's just and just
people low turnout after everyone
getting so scared right yeah I was going
to say um you know Kelly and I have been
working uh doing some really special
work uh with um a plant medicine
actually like blessing up people's lives
MH um and um it's so new it doesn't
really have a name wow yeah H single
ingredient plant medicine comes from
cloves nice yeah really cool Beyond cool
like bring me back to the juice I came
for with cannabis you know right wow
Miracles nice yeah so she gave me some
hash that was like super super amazing
yeah uh some of the best hash I smoked
this year yeah gu span is so good and
and just amazing and the effect right so
talking about effect and going back to
effect right you feel that energy just
feel that energy and it's like those are
the kind of things that have brought me
back to what am I doing breeding for
flavor even that's great it's great and
I love the way weed tastes but like
let's make some feel good weed again
well theirs doesn't lack flavor no not
at all but but it has a noticeable
feeling I feel like that some of the
stuff that I you know it's like they all
have different effects everything has a
slightly different but the Feelgood weed
from White Thorn Rose and Blue 13 is
like it's different it's different it's
not a it's you couldn't categorize it as
a stimulant or as a narcotic right
somewhere in the middle but it makes you
feel great slightly
sedative slightly but like I say
stimulating and sedating it is it's both
that's what I like about Kush it's
stimul and my brain's going but my
body's kicked back yeah so you've seen a
lot of different OG kushes over the
years I'm sure oh yeah yeah yeah lot
there was that Diablo OG that was coming
from Petaluma there was like syoma OG
from those
areas sfv oh I love SF I also like you
know Khalifa Kush the Flow Rider OG yeah
yeah so what's so so that Flow Rider the
the the original the triangle cush right
yeah it's like that was like the lime
green bigger buds really good stuff had
a little bit different of a high had a
little bit different of they all some of
the kushes can be heavier some of the
kushes can definitely be heavier some of
those highs can be a little flat for me
yeah I don't appreciate a flat high
right I I do want a stimulating aspect
to it or else I'm just going to get tiee
I just love pine needles when you can
smoking you taste the forest oh yeah
it's like there's something to be said
about smoking the forest oh yeah I could
I could talk about Kush literally all
day every day yeah so special yeah and
it's funny those OG's had different
levels of Earth and so basically Earth
Citrus and pine needles and you could
get some that were really piny and some
that were like just a little piny and
then some that were super earthy and
some that were mild in the earth and
then some that were real heavy in that
Citrus when that Citrus like sativa is
uh uplifting I like those ones kind of
getting more into the sour diesel Vibe
exactly I like those stimulating sour
stimulating sours yep yeah I like
those so yeah this weed's good isn't
that nice yeah yeah that's um that's
from the guy that made it nice yeah who
was the guy that made um you know um
Kenny Powers Yeah Yeah him totally yeah
that's from him and his one of his work
Partners day yeah they do good work oh
yeah so beautiful it's pretty a weed so
pretty yeah the flower looks amazing and
chunky have you tried the Pluto no what
is the cross um that's to be debated but
it's definitely a gelato times a cake
okay I believe all right I wasn't there
and so we've heard we've heard different
iterations uh sticky Farms up in Menino
I'm familiar uh and then Casey and those
guys were doing it back in the day and
that Pluto was something special and it
got real big and it was really like it
checked all the boxes it was like
floral uh floral candy purple yum smoked
good down to the roach and the bag
appeal was amazing it was dark purple
yeah you're saying all my little trigger
words yeah yeah special I like gassy
floral candy yeah and this is one where
it's like you smoke one you're like ah I
might smoke another you do bong rips you
wouldn't do just one one of the things I
really appreciate about you know a lot
of the hashes are they're a lot of them
are Li you know live most of them are
live mhm and some of those like tuar
rose Hawaiian
flow really refined floral notes can
kind of only be captured when the
plant's alive yeah so they come in late
at night it's all swelled up they chop
it out of element of surprise put it
right on ice and a lot of those jars can
capture you know stuff that you don't
get any other way very volatile easy to
disrupt flal not that only can be found
in fresh Frozen the first to go when you
dry your weed right you know it's
beautiful so what's your opinion on like
a BHO like live resin verus rosin yeah
so so I it's funny when you were talking
it was you were basically saying exactly
what I say which is if it's like really
good I'll I'll enjoy it like I I'll
smoke a BHO if it's done right and
purged properly you know oh yeah yeah um
so so yeah it's it's um I can appreciate
good work anywhere yeah uh if I were
like this is always my filter of like
desert island five strains you know what
are you going to bring on a desert
island for the rest of your life yeah
for me it's not going to be a vho right
it's GNA be ice water hash rosin yeah
flower so what are your five for as far
as flavors strains yeah oh man okay well
in no particular order Skittles you know
some Skittles variant for sure yeah
probably white Thorn Rose variant mhm
something really up and gassy that's
like dies you know for sure that I'm at
three I definitely want a nostalgic old
school purple if I can get one yeah yeah
and then um for my fifth one um I'll
probably just go with honestly like a
straight up cookies yeah I love cookies
cookies is stimulating and sedating you
know I think people have for it's funny
how fast we forget but there's people
that are like eh cookies and it's like
no cookies in 2010 it's in everything
for one thing right and in 2010 that was
one to have like if you had cookies it
was Top Shelf yeah absolutely bready it
was like bready and gas expando and and
he barely had to trim it it was just
silver little silver balls yeah it
didn't the the one that we had never
like the the first one that we had
didn't yield had terrible node spacing
it with like spaghetti over just like OG
like back in the day that we had but the
smoke of it was like your smoking
something that's special yeah it was
like definitely like uh little bit of
musk and a little bit of bread and a
little bit of gas and it was it was
layer multi layer that top pissy top
lingering pissy note that's so distinct
like you're in a hotbox concert and
somebody lights up a joint of cookies
and it like literally grabs your nose CU
it has one top note of Durban piss above
all the others yeah and you goer smoking
that smoking that cherry that is what
you find in everything and that's what
people love it's what brings the
smoothness right you know the gassiness
that top note so distinct yeah so like
yeah for all that stuff it's like the
the bread that's in wedding cake is like
yeah people people are quick to forget
but I don't forget I I cookies has a
special place in my heart because I I
was like there for all that and like
yeah I was growing cookies and pink
panties I was at you know the little
pink panties was cool though when you
grow so I used to I used to grow pink
panties too and it would get black the
plant was black the Clones were purple
stem same thing Sunset sherbo but the
the you know as a parent to Sunset
sherbo or whatever the the cut that we
had of uh pink panties I have jars of
just purple stemmed clones yeah pictures
of them yeah really cool before cookies
there was really just OG was the queen
of the mountain you know and cookies was
the first cannabis strain to really
changed the whole game yeah it was like
there was so so for me I remember the
Bubba and the master and the OG right so
there was the Bubba cush and that was
the top shelf that was like we didn't
call it pre98 it was just Bubba cush
right and and then there was the master
cush and it grew really strange it grew
like fingery and it grew like side
probably my lesser favorite of the two
yeah to tell you the truth and the Hindu
the Hindu from back wait that was that
was first actually Bubba was so
soapy Irish Springs in your mouth it
totally was so you ever have a senen
candy it's like it's like a a Chinese
candy that like literally tastes like
soap it was like so senen Vibes that's
yeah bubble was that was the thing it
was like straight soap and that's how
you could recognize it in the thing is
it grew I like the way it grows but if
you show me showed me a picture I could
be like yeah that's it's so distinct the
way that it grows and it was like
shorter and the way that the the the
leaves actually the pointed leaves they
don't have serration on them and they
kind of fold up so I would still put I
would still put Girl Scout cookies above
all those but neck a tie and same level
as straight OG for me for me yeah like I
like all those variants but they weren't
you know I love the sfv and the Josh dog
yeah and those two are like my jam yeah
I like s sfv for sure yeah the the r
whatever you Pine yeah sfv sfv is the
pinest it's the pine yeah it is the it's
like P other than that I want diesels
but you know what I love about that pine
needle is like you you smoke it and
you're smoking it down to the roach and
every time you blow it out you just
taste the forest the pine needles like
literally it's yeah and and so Josh
Freeman he's from Sebastapol he taught
me that you can eat pine needles I
didn't know that they're really high in
vitamin C and if you eat the baby pine
needles as they're freshly growing they
taste amazing and I'm like [__] that
tastes just like OG Kush the first thing
I thought of when I had it I have to
give that a try sometimes yeah so the
fresh growth from the pine needles it's
like Redwood or whatever I have to give
that a try yeah really good all right
tastes like OG Kush if you want to it's
a reminder of OG Kush day I like that
yeah if I could drink and eat OG Kush
actually so well back in the day we used
to make this um I learned a lot like
over these years being taught and like
one of the things was that that actually
glycerin is really not a good solvent
for cannaboids but it's an excellent
solvent for Tarpin wow yeah so um you
know making tinctures the old school way
through
glycerin uh with all these different you
know strain specific
batches really left you with like
essentially a liquid flow you know like
a liquid version of of the flower it was
such a good capture of chirpin but but
not a good capture of cannaboids
interesting very and not healthy for you
to smoke in your pants yeah we we were
making like spritzers and stuff like
cush sodas and stuff it was so
interesting because it wouldn't really
get you high but it would make your face
start to sweat like there was something
going on yeah like have you ever had a
high turpine experience where your face
kind of gets a little flushed abut it
was doing that it's so weird CU it all
lines up I was like oh my God I get it
this was truly a capture of tpin yeah
very interesting yeah it was really you
know I guess kind of an accident I was
trying to make something very strong wow
but it was only strong in tpin
interesting yeah really cool yeah I
remember the ver the version 1.0 pens
all had they Ed glycerin and they
combine it and it was just so bad yeah
blisterin just not meant to be smoked
like that really yeah but yeah the
industry's just come so far look at pens
and now we have right now we have puff
Co and we have a all these cool things
so um so my girl
Frosty she like hooked it up with this
like special attachment or whatever and
I didn't realize I like wasn't even
living my best life without it wow and
so she had to like put it in the app and
all this stuff and so there's like a
counter so like this is like the new
color I've had it maybe like two months
and ni anyways I had taken over 2,000
dabs with it so far wow that's amazing
yeah and I was like if I had this piece
I would probably like have taken a lot
less because it makes it so much more
dab like like I've wasting my money
totally that's really cool interesting
huh yeah I mean the future we used to
have the volcanoes Volcan I love volcano
me too yum but once I figured out that
you need one bag per flavor and it's
better if you just keep reusing it for
that same flavor it's better than mixing
them all and they all end up tasting the
same yum yum cat piss back in the day
was my favorite the champagne was good
too it's another oh I remember the
champagne yep I I remember the cat piss
for sure yeah skunk I love skunk right
speaking of volcano bags we used to run
a volcano bag across this whole thing at
the dispensary that's amazing big 20
foot long volcano bags you us to
everyone would just be sharing them oh
that's awesome it was you know pre-o
yeah we didn't weren't afraid to share
and you You' do it for a hit of weed
people weren't afraid of yeah you would
do it for it was worth it for the hit of
weed right yeah we didn't even think
about that kind of stuff though yeah I
know we were like really living life now
everyone's like oh I need hand s ier I
know wild it is wild I know it's so wild
cuz like I'm up in like I said sebasti
now and I just just literally like today
saw two people biking like on a country
road wearing masks like just no one
around I've seen I've seen people by
themselves in a car with the windows
rolled up wearing a mask and I'm like
okay well maybe they have Co want to be
seen that's what I always think too I'm
like I guess they must have it but I
just don't think it's true they wouldn't
be biking in a hot summer day it's like
100 out no it's just can you imagine
you're biking with a all your hot breath
just pressing on your face yeah I mean
you're getting your lungs stronger I
guess yeah exactly that's wild yeah yeah
I mean we live in a strange world it is
a really strange World well there's just
so many different realities going on at
once yeah well everyone's got their own
reality right so totally all these
different perceptions of what reality is
coming from different people and yeah
and trying to understand
people uh from an outside perspective
instead of looking at just them straight
on that's the best way right so and I
love that about cannabis I feel like it
makes me able to think of stuff from a
different perspective sometimes totally
well I think that's why some people have
like really can't smoke cannabis is
maybe they're not ready to look at thems
yeah like my favorite Bob Marley quote
is when you smoke the herb you reveal
yourself to yourself you know and we've
all been in the situation where you get
in a little tiff with your friend you
smoke a little weed you're like wow I
was like out a line back there it really
does show you the opposite side right
you know it's a perspective shifter and
like that's why you know I personally
for me that's one of my tools but I
always know I'm going to like Flip Flip
my mind after I smoke on something you
know um so yeah uh you know the Matrix
is just these like tightly bundled
belief systems you know like an example
is we we all agree that we stop at red
lights you know and if you break that
belief you can go to jail yeah or even
worse hurt someone but like everyone's
going to think you're crazy yeah because
you run a red light because it's a very
tight bundle of beliefs around traffic
rules and safety in our
society so we all agree to
that well I there was a point where a
lot of people more than half the
population agreed that cannabis was bad
for us right and it's like it's so
strange you know and that but that was
the reality back then they were like
cannabis is bad you know reer Badness
all this stuff and misinformation and
miseducation and it's like it was it's
so strange that we went that Direction
with canis like if you think we've
probably been using it not even probably
we've been using it for thousands of
years as medicine and then just in the
last you know since the well since like
the 30s and 40s they started you know
making it look bad to everybody well
such a cur all yeah they demonized
yeah they grows like a weed in our
backyard so like cannabis can
do what white willow bark does yeah and
chamomile and lavender and colula but
they can't all do what cannabis does
right plant medicine Canabis does what a
100 plants do exactly and it grows like
a weed mhm it's their nightmare right
there's no profit in it for them that's
why they tax it so high yeah it's it's
pretty wild
and now but now we have the we have the
majority at least agreeing that it
should be legalized yeah I think big
steps Little Steps over time that have
turned into big steps so I feel like um
two two things that really help people
change their mind is either personally
experiencing a cannabis Miracle or
witnessing someone they care about yeah
receiving a cannabis Miracle you know or
benefit from Cannabis and at this time
it's seated out enough that I think you
know with Six Degrees of Separation
people have been in touch with these
cannabis Miracles and seen what these
plants what this plant can do for
totally straight edged people that were
really even opposed to trying it
themselves you know so yeah it's like
you know we don't have a right I feel
that we don't have the right to tell
people as long as they're not hurting
other people right what sort of plant
medicine is good or bad for them they
should be allowed to do as long as
you're not hurting anybody else that's
how I feel so you know um we have more
than 200 cannaboid receptors in our body
you only have eight opioid receptors
yeah so they start under your tongue
sublingual tincture right if I was God
forbid on my deathbed I would hope that
I might have a receptor for the medicine
you may place in my mouth under my
tongue it's not saying put this here
yeah you know so uh for in my in my
personal opinion I think it's our our
Birthright mhm yeah and pretty clearly
uh clear to see that it's a tool that's
been given to
us uh to use to be well you know for
sure I mean it's every it should be
everybody's option whether you want to
do it or not I'm not you know I'm not
one to judge like that but like it's one
of those things that it only makes the
world a better place in my opinion me
too yeah uh hungry happy rested side
effects of cannabis right yeah yeah it's
it's it's so fun it's it's pretty wild
yeah so yeah and I mean alcohol it's a
lot you it's funny thing with alcohol
and tobacco they're both legal but they
do a lot more bad than they do good in
my opinion yeah so everyone has their
own opinion on it but my opinion is that
they do worse than or they do they do
more bad than good I've definitely seen
many people destroy them their lives
from alcohol you know I've had my own
little dances with drinking too much and
all kinds of things
and you know they call it a spirit for a
reason and um and and trust me I love a
little glass of wine here and there junk
get me wrong I don't have to put it down
to bring cannabis up but um but it's a
really different vibration as far of a
as far on the other side of the
vibration Spectrum as possible totally
and so I was talking about this at a at
a dead and Company show a while back
though and it was because you could see
the vibration that people were on the
people that were smoking weed or or
whatever tripping yeah and then the
people that were drinking had a
completely different vibration what it
does is alcohol Tunes you out right
whereas cannabis it's true and
psychedelics they tune you in so they
hyper you're able to hyper Focus or
focus more and I think we all need to be
tuned in a little bit more especially
with music and sometimes tuned out of
this Norm that we have and into the you
know on the right frequency so I'm like
really that's speaking my language so
you know with the this time 2024 yeah
you know it's not like a time we've ever
seen before and it's never going to go
back to whatever it was you know and
it's this time where you know if you
don't have a little bit of a meditation
process where any way that you're going
in and connecting with your own soul
yeah it's going to feel rougher and
rougher you know for me I'm a spiritual
person I believe in great spirit you
know and if I didn't have that
connection to great spirit and the faith
that you know the things that I believe
that the Universe has my back and
frequencies and vibrations matter and
all the things I really my my little web
of beliefs you know then I would feel
way more lost than I do already when
everybody's feeling lost on some measure
you know so um the thing is we spend so
much time in technology that like you're
kind of tuning yourself into the
vibration of AI by being on your phone
all the time like I do it all the time
they do way too much they we use them
for cameras calendars like everything we
do you start getting highminded yeah and
so you know you're tuning into to your
to your cell phone over and over again
you're getting on that AI Vibe but the
truth is we're actually nature Spirits
you know we're people we're humans of
Nature and so people need to ground
themselves more and I think that's one
right so if you go and lay on the ground
like find a nice spot that feels good to
you in the grass take your shoes off
flip yourself like a pancake at least 20
minutes on each side get your phone as
far away from you as possible it doesn't
matter if it's sun or shade wherever
you're comfortable yeah when I do that I
can feel the problems pulling off of me
it just like gravity pulls it off of me
right away and it's it's like a spa day
and like some really effective therapy
yeah and a whole bunch of other good
things all wrapped into one and I get up
just feeling like you know a new person
yeah go do gardening with your shoes off
yeah exactly that's when you're able to
spend time in nature I I do cold
plunging too and that's good I love cold
plunging I love the idea of cold
plunging yeah I think that everybody
should try it I got to try that yeah
it's it's so I'm sure the part of my
brain is very small yeah I think like
that I heard how it works like there's a
part of your brain that you know grows
when you make yourself do things you
don't want to do so the cold plunging
literally grows this part of your brain
and apparently undisciplined people have
like this very small part of this brain
I'm like I bet mine is like so Pinner
because I'm a lady I like to be Comfort
yeah getting into a cold pool sounds
like so awful to me to force yourself to
get in freezing cold water yeah and so I
went to the extremes where I went down
to like 37 now I'm fine it anything
below 55 you get really good results so
I'm like in the high 40s low
whatever I enjoy doing it I feel like
it's a great replacement for coffee in
the morning it's a great way to also
just get a different perspective and
it's it's hard to be upset after you get
out of coold plunge sure because you're
so focused on in the it really other
thing is it brings you into the moment
and I think we need to do that a lot
more than what we typically do we're
thinking about the future we're thinking
about the past and if you can once a day
just get in some cold water or meditate
or do whatever it is right and then go
into the present you start realizing
that the reality is different than you
probably had the perspective for before
right and uh it's it's really wild but
yeah cold plunging meditation all that
exercise self-care it's my spiritual
practice when I started having like an
energetic hygiene y practice wow my life
really started changing prioritizing
yourself sometimes yeah it's funny yeah
I got to change the order sometimes
sometimes I'm like no actually I can't
start work until I take my walk
yeah you know my mind is too busy it's
pulling me in so many directions if I
just take my walk I come back I find
that I'm really able to focus you're
more productive totally yeah it's so
much yeah you really need to prioritize
your people need to prioritize
themselves more for sure right now right
now especially you know so yeah taking
something out just for you whether
whether it's a walk or whether it's C
plunging or going to the gym or what or
a combination of all those things
there's so many things you can really do
that that are good for you totally
besides your diet cuz that's important
too so good but the the weed's good and
then these dabs are some of my genetics
really yummy um they were made by my
buddy up in Washington so yummy so
smooth yeah Gary pton times grape soda
yum can't go wrong Gary Payton's another
good one yeah I like Gary Payton a lot I
I like a lot of the strains that Ken
made like um snowman yeah the why the Y
is really interesting cuz in
2014 I have yet to see the why life like
it was in 2014 there's been some awesome
crosses that have been made with it and
whatever but like the wildlife we used
to get the wildlife uh my friend Stevie
my friend Gold Member he used to get the
wildli from San Francisco 60 bucks an
eighth whatever like that was like the
high price back then and he get some
ounces yeah he get some ounces of it and
it was it was amazing yeah it was but I
haven't seen that since since since yeah
that's 10 years ago and it was like
floral candy it was like smoking candy
it was like Skittle is Skittles as
Skittles yeah it was that with floral
and you would smoke it and it was like I
couldn't get enough of it yeah and those
are the things where I get like an ounce
of it and I just smoke that first even
if I have 20 different things I'm gonna
smoke all that because I just I just
keep going back to it CU like that was
so winners yeah I keep going back to
them he also made cherry pie yeah the
wise pie times cookies yeah pie times
cookies was good yeah yeah awesome stuff
yeah so good so if you had one thing
that you could tell yourself to your
younger self that was first started out
in the industry you could have if you
could tell them one thing what would
that thing be don't pay attention to the
smoke and
mirrors nice yeah there's so many little
fear factors and like distractions and
noise houses of cards that came tumbling
down and you know just not nothing was
really as it seemed so just like get
really passionate about whatever it is
you're into and put your nose to the
grindstone and just keep going it's so
funny that you say that because I feel
like most of the things I thought when I
was younger are not completely the
opposite right but they're never as they
seem perspective and perception are just
these amazing things and you get
perspective over time and then you
realize wow like I think that suffering
is not that bad like I think people
should suffer to a degree so they can
appreciate the good times right and like
you I think that a lot of parents they
don't want their kids to suffer or have
a hard life and I think hard lives make
some of the best people and appreciation
for what they have and being grateful
you get that from having tough times
yeah it's true the pressure makes the
diamonds absolutely and you really are
just grateful for all that you have and
and you also know what you have and what
you had and the experiences really put
life into perspective so every day you
know I feel like as we get older years
go by faster every year goes by a little
bit faster because you figure a year
when you're five years old is 20% of
your life but right but a year when
you're 20 is a 20th percent of your life
you know 5 per. yeah so like you look at
it like that it's as you're 40 that five
becomes two and a half and so each year
goes by so much faster it's all
perspective and we think you know time
we got so much time and really we don't
I don't think this is the end as far as
like existence but we have a finite
amount of time to do all the things we
want to do and there's no better time to
do them than the present that's so true
yeah oh yeah they say um so uh if you
had the luxury of knowing that you were
dying tomorrow yeah what would you do in
your last 24 hours and then like now
that's how you should live each day
that's always an amazing question and
you should ask yourself that every day
yeah I know I would I would go make
amends with
like one or two people who make it's not
that we're on bad terms but maybe we
haven't talked but they're important to
me you know family I would make sure
we're all good you know knowing I would
never see them again yeah I mean I'd
definitely go see my parents right I
think that'd be the first thing I'd do
yeah so I'm lucky I was raised by really
good parents that's awesome great
parents yeah me too you know we had our
ups and downs and arguments and stuff
for my parents were amazing still are
amazing are they here I'm I'm blessed to
have both parents still around that's
great you know my dad passed in January
sorry to hear that yeah that's tough and
it's like I know that that's coming and
that's as you get older like I
experienced the loss of my dog which was
one of the toughest things if you've
never had that you probably wouldn't
understand it but as we get older we
start experience loss yeah and then I
just I imagine you know that my parents
are going to pass one day which they
will everything passes right and so it's
it's a trip when you think of those
things and like what you would do with
your last day right so yeah I have to
say you know I'm grateful I spent so
much time with him on his last you know
on his last days on his last months nice
so much time blessing it was a blessing
I'm grateful because you can never ever
get that time back no yeah yeah you
don't that's the one thing is you don't
get time back yeah you can go have new
experiences but you don't get the old
ones back it's very true yeah but it's
all about bid memories anyway it is and
it's also about like recognizing what
are the moments from your past that are
robbing you from your present right cuz
those are the moments that should go
yeah cuz they're just taking up real
estate real estate in your own mind you
know yeah that's what I love about
psychedelics because I feel like we have
these filters and I I call them filters
but really some a lot of them are
traumas but traumas create filters and
all these experiences for the moment
we're born we see the world as we see it
now because of all these experiences
yeah our lenses these lenses right so we
see this world in a specific our reality
is this lens right and so when we take
psychedelics we smoke cannabis I think
sometimes it pulls those lenses or those
filters off and so then you start seeing
the world maybe not how as how it really
is to everybody else but how it really
is and how it should be right and I
think like trauma is just such a bad
thing and we've all experienced with
each one of those lenses comes like a
whole different belief system right yeah
and so a lot of them are limiting
beliefs and those are what you have to
let go of you once you see them you can
let them go right in all kinds of ways
that I'll tell you later but like you
know I mean I can go into it now but
I've just been doing this practice where
you basically bring it into your heart
yeah bring it into your heart yeah which
is the tool of 5D you know used to be
the mind and the mind wants all your
attention right but it's really all
about the heart so it it the heart is
such a high vibratory tool that anything
you bring into your heart gets
neutralized wow yeah so yeah so anytime
you notice a limiting belief you know
and one way you can find out this all
came from this woman I've been doing a
coaching thing with one way you can find
out what they are is you start
describing yourself to like a best a
friend like pretend there's someone here
and start describing yourself and you'll
start to notice these beliefs come up
you know you might say something like oh
yeah sorry I smoke a lot of weed I
always forget stuff like that's a
limiting belief that cannabis makes you
forget things right you know and you
pull it into your heart and then it
leaves your life and it's not it's not
holding you anymore it's like it
neutralizes the contract wow and you're
not in agreeance with those words
anymore nice 5D tool pretty cool where
we're at right now it's so cool all that
earthing and just there so so many hacks
like you don't have to do things the way
you used to right you know that's the
beauty of today and the now yeah totally
really cool super cool you are the Maya
in Whoopi and Maya and you guys are
doing some big things yeah so whoopy and
Maya is whoopy Goldberg's vision
for a product line for the moon cycle
moon cycle Rel all medicated so um it's
everything a woman wants on her moon
cycle it's like a bath yeah uh a herbal
rub that has a lot of different herbs in
it um a tincture that's also multi- herb
and a rock AOW wow yeah so we started
the company I think seven or eight years
ago and like everyone else we had our
you know set of challenges which
everybody in the cannabis has and we
decided to kind of pause it for just a
little bit and then we restructured and
now we're we're back wow really cool
it's so cool it's so interesting because
it's like wow you know sometimes
Opportunity Knocks twice you know and
not everybody gets that opportunity it's
so cool and like and and everybody loved
the products and everybody loved the
company and like to this day we're still
getting requests for our products you
know and like serious people like
endometriosis patients and stuff that
we're actually finding true relief from
from our products so so I'm excited and
grateful to like be able to do this
again um on July 20th which is Friday
Saturday whoopie's getting her keys to
the city for Hollywood yeah and and then
we're having a party that night and
she's going to be releasing re-releasing
whoy and Maya there and also Emma and
Clyde which is her flower line yeah
that's great yeah super sweet so
so it's exciting the brand will probably
mostly be licensed um to out ofate
Partners like I know she's from New
Jersey that's like an important place
for us to be definitely East Coast you
know
um of course California too but everyone
who's been in California understands
that there are some challenges with lots
of challenges you know yeah so sad you
know yeah that was um one thing I did
want to say when we were talking about
Spain and all the Social Clubs is like
you know not to get political but I
really feel like Gavin Nome like dropped
the ball when he didn't let us have live
music and food and wine events and
espressos with like our weed you know so
there's just no we're not able to have
that culture yet we have the best
cannabis and the best wine and produce
in the whole entire world yeah
heartbreak literally the best heartbreak
you know we had the most potential to
have such great cannabis tourism and
farm totable Boutique Vibes and I think
he said that he's against it it just
wasn't written correctly was his cop out
for it but it's like come on like
whatever it is dude you dropped the ball
like we could have been flowing by now
you know could have brought a lot of
money to San Francisco yeah and having
Place places where people could consume
and enjoy and enjoy other things along
with it 100% and not be treated like a
criminal right when you have to spend
top dollar for some boofed out weed yeah
that had to be like robbed of its Tarpin
just to make it to market the compliant
way mhm it's a heartbreak it's a
heartbreak and I think we're solving
those problems as we speak like with
refrigerated distribution and delivery
and trying to get the product to the
consumer sooner because I think that's a
huge problem right is the consumer and
some of these guys have amazing flow I
was talking about this on my last
episode but there's amazing flow but
then you got to wait one or two months
to get it and then it's not amazing yeah
it's a boof process the boof process and
they're boof aying The Weave I know you
know Alec has a really good breakdown of
that you know Alec from SC Labs you can
explain that whole process so well it's
very that's awesome I need to get him on
the show yeah you do um you know I just
feel like it would have been such a Vibe
if you could like roll up to a farm and
actually see un unmanicured weed in jars
and then they bring out the little
wooden tongs and like handic cure it for
you and then weigh it up for you and you
know that real nice Vibe where you're
getting something fresh and farmed to
table like it should have been more like
that right considering like a couple
flakes of trim isn't anything anyways
right you know to mic manage it like
that just like blocked all the flow well
I love the micro Brewery Winery model
that would be great for you know with
the Terre yes in in Humble you know
Menino Sonoma Trinity like all those
places and and you you know then you put
the farmers back uh you empower the
farmers to do what they've been doing
long before most the people that are
doing it now and then you can experience
it with them and hear the stories of how
their grandparents were Outlaws and
bootleg basically like bootleggers and
had to fight for the plant and do stuff
that they believed in even though it was
illegal and now it's legal and those
people are the ones that should be
growing It Anyway totally 100% so if
somebody is trying to find Maya and
they're looking to get a hold of you
where they want to know more about you
where can they go well we're on
Instagram we're at um get om living on
Instagram we also have a CBD website
which is om dwell.com and then our THC
website which which is um om living.com
nice and you can find us in retails you
can buy our products online um and then
yeah whoopy and Maya will be back on the
shelves shortly as well really cool yeah
we need to collaborate on some stuff in
the future I would love that awesome any
formulation needs I got you oh yeah oh
yeah we're ready I you know it's like
there's so many cool things that I have
the ideas for that I can't execute
myself but that's what I love about the
you know not to go on and on on the show
but I love that about the recreational
world and the Bel legalization of
cannabis is that we can be Specialists
and I don't want to do everything
anymore I don't want to do tissue
culture I have a partner that does that
um I want to focus on genetics I don't
have to grow flower or be the guy who
changes you know the AC's out like we
used to do everything back in the day
right exactly beautiful we can really be
Specialists and really dial those things
in and now with technology it's just
amazing you don't have to be the Swiss
army knife anymore right yeah I mean
those were fun days too don't get me
wrong sure sure but we did that CU we
had to be private so we couldn't just
bring bring anyone in anywhere yeah it
was much different yeah so like you know
a lot of you know cannabis people who
were Founders like came from a time
where we only hired friends and family
because that was the only safe way to do
it so to like step into these situations
where all of a sudden you have HR you're
like whoa but I only know how to connect
with people by like rolling up a doobie
yeah talking story no they they need one
lunch 30 minute lunch a day you got to
have a break in the morning
afternoon right well thank you very much
for coming on the show thank you so so
much for having me
[Music]