[Music]
you
[Applause]
[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James loud
podcast and today our special guest is
Michael Klein for bio365 how are you
doing today Michael doing great James
thanks and thank you so much for coming
on the show the last time I saw
you was it a dead show I think it was a
shoreline at the dead company Shoreline
in 2023 maybe that's probably probably
likely yeah with Shane and Tim and uh
with then those guys yeah seen quite a
few shows over the days yeah how many
shows I can't remember no I I I I toured
full-time with them from 85 to 95 nice
and and I've seen most of the the
following bands most of most of the show
so it's a couple thousand I'm sure wow
it's amazing yeah it's never too late to
have a happy childhood that's for sure
that's the beauty of it so what do you
think of the sphere I was I I was really
impressed I have to admit what was a
little disappointing for me was they
didn't have enough time to develop the
graphics and the limited amount number
of Graphics that they had worked up
limited the set list so that you were
seeing the same three shows pretty much
each week well there's always time to
change and I guess they're coming back
in a couple months here they sure are
and uh you know Bob Bobby you know wants
to go out on stage he he's never going
to stop no he's like my father my father
will never quit working my father loves
working yeah and bobb's the same way and
he's one of the hardest workers out
there he is he is he's definitely uh
he's doing better than ever physically
mentally it's really impressive it's
pretty mind-blowing it's people Aging in
Reverse uh Mila the hash Queen Mila
Jansen she's another one that I feel
like she's aging in Reverse it's like
it's great when you see people that are
getting up there in years and they look
younger than they did the year before or
even the year before that sometimes even
10 years before I'm up there now and
appreciating you know my health and and
it went through a couple actually three
years I just had a full hip replacement
and uh I was at Barton Hall with 20
guests the the the heads of at least
three of the top 10 msos yeah and I
couldn't attend cuz I was in so much
pain
on crutches I missed the show but I had
all my guests there amazing yeah that's
how it goes yeah so tell us about bio365
and how you got bio365 off the ground
sure um and I I'll I'll try and give a
really brief thumbnail on how I got the
bio 365 so you can understand how
twisted I am um so I basically uh had
had a great life growing up in Cleveland
Ohio my father was very successful and
he was a bit of a twisted old guy and he
he he tried to guilt me into achievement
he would like when I was 12 14 years old
he'd say I hope you forgive me someday
you don't have to worry about feeding
your children or keeping a roof over
your head and frankly I don't see you
have any reason to achieve and without
achieving I don't know how you can feel
good about yourself without feeling good
about yourself I I don't know how you
can ever be happy so I I hope you
forgive me and I'm going where's the
money dad you know but I go off to
college everybody's smarter than I am
everybody's hard working than I am and I
go sh I I've got to get an edge and I
just said
microprocessors I drove down to the
electronic store and I bought a
soldering iron and a and a mitz 8080
alair kit and I started building
microcomputers and eventually started a
microcomputer video game software
company that did a lot of atari's early
wall and tank type of games yeah um and
uh and and was off into Data
Communications and and software and uh
got really lucky um sold sold my My
First Data Communications
company and spun off the software from
it and sold that again at 30 I I retired
and I went all right I think I feel okay
about myself who the [ __ ] am I and what
am I supposed to do the rest of my life
I mean I was literally lost so I did
what I think any rational human being
would do um I I went on tour with the
grateful Dad for 10 years social
director amazing yeah it was a it was
complete Serendipity I I moved out to
the mil Valley and one of my best
friends from Cleveland moved out there
the same time and he calls me up on day
and says you want you like to play in a
flag football league I said sure says
okay come on and this first week we're
gonna play against Bobby we's team oh I
just went into to shock so I I met Bob
through that and and became a you know
more or less a an adviser business
adviser I partner with with with Bob and
modulus
guitars we're we're Partners in
Sweetwater and TR Studios and and um I
had the time and and I was such a fan
that the idea of spending 120 days a
year on the road with them was was
Heaven I bet and and what I can remember
was yeah so I I I you know I did that
for 10 years you know I I got into
things that that were were really
important to me not necessarily great
opportunities I I I had become a vegan
and and a and then a raw fooder and
opened up a raw food restaurant in lsor
in around
2000 um and but the let me get back to
the to the Dad we had about I'm gonna
say 10 guys from somoma and mesino who
they would give us these wonderful bags
and we would give them laminates and and
then eventually when you know after
after 96 or whenever the the collective
started up the they taught me how to
grow and and introduced me to the plant
and and uh and and I ended up starting a
collective in in somoma level Valley
somoma in probably around 2012 nice and
and uh anyway that that's that was my
introduction to the plant I mean other
than it had been my medicine of
preference from the age of about 12 yeah
um and I I'm constantly surprised by how
many Ohioans are have such a strong
background with the plant right you know
so Farming Farming yeah farming yeah um
and and interesting that's how I also
got into farming and soil which is a
good segue um at the raw food restaurant
um imagine a restaurant where everything
you served came in the the door that
morning as a raw fruit nut or vegetable
yeah no cans no bottles we had to
dehydrate things for two three days to
create texture but we grew a lot of the
of our of our produce for the restaurant
in in our garden in in corter Madera and
I I learned about living soil then I
learned then I we we were using compost
um but uh that's when I first really
started getting interested in in what
made a plant what made a plant taste
good you what made it what why were
these giant tomatoes from from the
supermarket why did they y'all have no
flavor at all you know but this ugly
thing that came out of you know my
backyard is just bursting with flavor
and it's so amazing I worked at
shapanese I interned there 20 years ago
uhhuh and that was my experience was
like how could this tomato taste so
amazing compared to the stuff that I'm
used to tasting and my parents grew
tomatoes and they were good but this was
even another level well it it it's
really it's amazing and it's also really
identical for can
yeah um and you know I'm sure a lot of
your audience has heard the living soil
story and and that but you know just
real quickly you know plants spend a
quarter or a third of their energy
making specific food for specific
biology that lives in their root Zone
that Cycles specific nutrients a plant
needs magnesium it makes up the food for
the microbe in the soil that Cycles
magnesium and it sweats it out through
its roots and the microb brings the
Magnesium to the plant and exchanges it
for the food that the plant makes for it
and that way the plant's feeding on
demand getting all the specific
nutrients it needs to build the building
blocks that it its DNA is wanting to
express yeah um and and you know I I I
would say bad things about salts or
anything because most of our customers
use salts and and and some of them go
grow some pretty good cannabis but
you're you're basically filling up a
bucket and hoping that it's going to
meet the needs of the plant right and
the plant's needs are always real time
you know if if if a an aphid lands on a
leaf um the plant senses it actually
makes up a a food for microbes that
float in the air and it sweats it out
through the leaf and the microbes will
come down and create a layer of slime
over the leaf and that's the plant's
defense that leaf eaing
aphid now if 12 more aphids land on 12
other leaves it's got to make 12 times
that specific molecule yeah and
eventually you know the bucket's going
to run out of one and and that's that
giant that tastes like cardboard yeah so
um it's really important to me that that
you know cannabis become more of an
organic organically grown product I know
the quality is better I I used to say
that salts were were Force feeding a
goose but really it's water boarding the
plant um and that that's just not a way
to Good Health yeah um so hopefully
we're moving in that direction there's
some people growing some organic fire
out there organic and Sanic I feel like
organic is a great approach too where
they're using synthetic with Organics to
try to achieve a a great product I think
at least it's a great Direction yeah
I'll tell you something really
interesting so um we were doing an early
test when when we we started the soil
company we're running our nutrient Den
soils against competitors and right we
threw in one of our our nutrient light
soils and so basically what our soil is
really all about is is biomimicry MHM
and the first leg of biomimicry is is bi
ology in the root Zone it's not just a
way of of selective feeding so that the
plant expresses itself better it's also
a big part of its defenses in the root
zone so the problem is a lot of good
gardeners add biology and then it drains
out drains the waste with the rest of
their stuff and and and so I think I I I
started to tell you earlier my wife in
2007 started a biochar research company
and created Five patents around creating
optimal optimally temperatured and
carbon content
uh and inoculating the Char with with
Biology and and with nutrients and when
you when you create biochar you create a
ton of synthetic natural gas and right
in the middle of their they're creating
this this
capability fracking came along and
destroyed the the business model so that
they couldn't really go forward they
wanted to give the Char away as a way of
sequestering carbon and uh so the the
the soil scientist from Cornell who is
her partner said well I'm just going to
take the stuff and make a soil but he
wanted to make a living soil and he
patented a biological activation and
aging process that we do in a HEPA
filtered indoor clean space we don't use
any unpasteurized manures in any of our
nutrient packages yeah and we're and
we're able to create a a living base
that we mix into all of our our
different media um that's as clean and
consistent as as anything in in any in
any substrate out there yeah um but it's
a whole Community we we take our wide
spectrum biology biochar and organic
nutrients and we put them through a 30
to 45 day activation and aging process
um and the plants love it so so number
one biomimicry is does the plant have
the biology it expects to see one of the
interesting things is if you don't have
the biology the plant is smart enough to
stop wasting the energy of making the
food and it puts it into biomass and
that's why that tomato is bigger
okay um so the second leg of biomimicry
um is air and water paracity okay
because plants need space for their
roots to grow our soils are remarkable
in that our our cocoa is 14% solid 24%
air and 62% water MH um and so what we
find is we we we'll have a customer
growing in a in in a five gallon
container and we can grow a bigger plant
in a two gallon container yeah you know
because it's all about root space and
and air and then Sops that that support
those roots filling up the container um
so so that's really important and the
third thing and this is something that
is almost absent in in in in most Hydro
operations is it when it rains in when
it plants get water from excuse me from
the soil with tension mhm when it rains
there's plenty of water plant doesn't
have to pull at all water is just there
for it every day it dries out every day
the plant has to pull a little harder to
get water from the soil right that dry
stressing is is probably if not the
number one trigger of secondary
metabolites it's up there and you can't
dry down plant in in in rock wool or or
in a straight cocoa um they don't water
long enough or even in a Pete um so
having a water release curve that mimics
nature turns out to be really important
for the plant to express itself in its
best yeah um so that's really that
that's what our soils are about we
actually manufacture them in a in not
just completely indoors meaning all
inputs all finished product are stored
indoors we sallyport the building yeah
so that there's no way the internal
Factory can be open to the outside um
and we like I said we use IPM in our
production we were using hypo aism mites
and neemat toads for fungal control it's
as clean as your grow rooms hopefully um
and and that that shows off in its
consistency and and its performance
excellent we've been obviously going
with the ups and downs of or I should
say mostly Downs of the Cannabis
industry um we've actually grown pretty
pretty successfully I mean we have more
than half of the top 10 msos um GTI
Verano um pharmacan columb be care of
cannabis um but but more importantly for
me we have the greatest group of of
foundational ogs breeders Growers um who
really understand our soil and are are
are growing great great fire with it
yeah um and and that that to me is more
rewarding I I I'm very disappointed in
what's happened to the to the Cannabis
industry it it it doesn't honor the
plant it it's run by Finance people
getrich quick entrepreneurs that um that
don't understand the plant or the values
that created our our community and uh
you know I'm I'm trying to figure out
how we can get get back to to where we
started yeah I don't think there's any
one solution it's a bunch of small steps
yeah yeah well it's interesting so you
know I had a a very interesting Final in
in business strategy at Harvard Business
School and and it was about a a lobster
boat company that was very high-tech
they had designed their whole Fleet of
of lobster boats um they had a big R&amp;D
facility they they they went out of
business in about two years and the
thing was the economics of the lobster
business are determined by the economics
of a boat with three guys on it um and
that's their cost and that's what
they're going to sell at and there's no
advantage to scale there's actually
disadvantages of scale because you're
paying for all of that R&amp;D you're paying
to manage all these people right um I
think cannabis is exactly the same the
the functional unit in cannabis is the
room whether it's a th000 or 4,000
square fet if you have 20 of them you
have more than 20 times the cost of one
single 4,000 foot room right um and I
don't understand if cultivators are
willing to
ferate I I don't understand why you
can't be competitive in in most States
you know depending on on Power and and
you know what what what the indoor
prices you know bottom out at it's it's
just it's become a race to the bottom
and I I I just believe that cannabis can
be grown less expensively than it is
there's too many people have too many
magic things they're throwing in there
they're they're not doing any real
evaluation of side by side of what
they're putting in and whether it's
benefiting them right um they the they
aren't really looking at system costs um
and and there's a there's a lot of
cultural practices that have come from
the old day when we didn't have room
to cultivate the way we were trying to
cultivate so you up pooted and you shove
things this way and that way and you
know there's really no reason to to
plant your clone anywhere and Transplant
it again I mean there's no reason to
transplant at all after you plant your
your rooted your rooted
right um and and and you can grow in
much smaller containers like I said than
people are
growing I think yeah I think there's big
benefit to growing in smaller containers
um you know for us is dryb backs getting
oxygen to the roots and but but you know
I think it's all we're learning and we
go through these Trends whether it's
using
18 uh inputs you know as opposed to
using three which I think is more common
now than ever uh so we go through these
wild trends of well this has to be
better or this is better because this
person does it and maybe they're getting
good results but the the flowers changed
a lot over the last 10 years
especially um I got some really sticky
sticky flow that I I'll show you later
and we're not seeing that anymore we're
not seeing the really really sticky
stuff that just you could push it onto
anything and it'll stick and there's
there's a lot of reasons for that but
also the genetics of preference you know
we've also bottlenecked ourselves into
this corner l
yeah into this stuff that's much
different that doesn't necessarily taste
like the Cannabis that we grew up with
or that I grew up with and I'm sure
you've seen it's like uh it's
interesting the way people think and the
way people work and you know how we get
so excited about one thing that we lose
all these other great things along the
way yeah and that's really happened
since the 90s and and in and in the
whole industry you don't really know
what you're getting anyway I mean that's
the biggest misconception ever well I I
I should take that back I mean it used
to be I I I heard this story that there
was a group there was like 50 Elders in
humbold and and people could present
things to them and they would go yeah
that's that's the real Sour Diesel you
know but but unless you get the from the
original breeder yeah it's it's really
kind of it's kind of tough to know and
especially these the new strands the
candy brunch stuff all tastes the same
it's all renamed a lot of it's not all
of it but a lot of it's renamed um and
then Sour Diesel is the best example
because for the longest time I I almost
thought my mind was playing tricks on me
that I didn't remember it right but then
a guy named Dave I talk about this on my
podcast all the time he pres I I was at
reg on the river and he comes up to me
gives me a bud and it was the sour
diesel I remember from my childhood and
there was one Sour Diesel that we had it
wasn't all these different we had one I
mean maybe there was more for other
people but back uh 2000 and before there
was one Sour Diesel and I you know I
have some of it in my freezer yeah but a
lot of the sour that's going around now
is this gassy version of Sour Diesel so
that's what people think Sour Diesel is
right right and it it happens over and
over and over again OG Kush there's a
lot of OG cush around but it's not the
OG cush I remember from 10 years AG
right right um yeah it's it's funny to
hear uh to hear guys like Josh D and
ghost talk about it that they they talk
about having a cut of TK that nobody
else has yeah and they don't Rel it you
know and I I haven't smoked it but they
they like swear about it I got some TK I
got some TK here today but it's but but
is it the real TK I mean that's the
thing yeah and so and it's so subjective
because the name doesn't mean anything
and if fingerprinting technology is
going to help with that I feel like
that's the beauty my Florida DNA and a
couple other companies where you can
fingerprint the genetics they have
basically uh 2,000 Snips they can
compare more right and so it's actually
more accurate than a human fingerprint
and they can tell you yes it's that
exact thing or no it's not right and so
the more of us they on board with
getting our stuff fingerprinted the
easier it's going to be down the road
right I I agree and I I think
blockchain's going to be involved in it
I think that there's there's a lot of
technology that that that is coming at
the plant and I think in in in mostly
positive ways yeah exception of your IR
radiation and a few things but um sure I
think that yeah there there's so little
sence we were talking about that earlier
that you
know very few of my customers really
know know what what you know the impact
of their their inputs are or or are
willing to actually push push the the
parameters on on dryback or use
tensiometers to actually take the plant
to where you know it's not going to go
into Wilt but is really going to have to
suck yeah um and and again there's just
going to be a lot more science I think
improving the practices yeah there has
to be a lot more AB testing people need
to do a lot of testing and the thing is
is testing testing it with most people
is just like okay well this was better
they're not they're not documenting it
they're not doing it properly I mean
there are people I take that back there
are people that are doing it correctly
we just need more of them yeah yeah
there I mean there I find it really
funny I I was in Florida up until
2021 and the C the product was just
terrible there was there were there were
17 licenses maybe 12 of them were
operating no competition you know it and
uh and now it looked like such an
attractive State especially with wck
coming MH that there's some real players
down there growing some great great
cannabis nice like IDE I don't know if
you know ideal out of Oregon yeah the
name for sure they're growing 100%
organic just beautiful flower
um there's real competition coming to
Florida and so I I think it's really
cool that's awesome yeah I mean I I hope
everyone has access to good flower at
the end of the day these guys at
flowery okay they they've got a whole
feno hunting setup they're they're doing
a lot of breeding I think they're yeah
sunburn cannabis uh we got
peik doing his thing that's one of the
great great stories you
know at a 1991 Grateful Dead show at
Deer Creek Indiana you know Kem dog
bought a bag off a peab bud mik and that
was the start was the start that changed
the game I have uh somebody gifted me
tickets I traded them for some seeds but
tickets from both the the shows so for
the 91 shows oh really
yeah good stuff yeah yeah but yeah and
that uh serendipitous day
changed the Cannabis that we've seen
it's changed the what we see now yeah
without that it would be different I
believe I firmly believe it would be
different and they brought gas to the
market I think
absolutely gas and you know the funky
stuff I I think that and and and OG Kush
you know is just those are my true
foundational yeah I love both of those a
lot yeah I have both you and I also do
like some of the sweet stuff and I like
the you know we we have the gdps and I
get excited that's nostalgic for me too
but I like the skunks I like stuff
that's really skunky we had cat piss
when I grew up you know that that was
the big thing was that really nose
burning cat piss it wasn't gas like OG
it was skunky like a dead skunk or like
a sprayed skunk yeah uh yeah with
ammonia that burned your nose yeah and
that to me is what you know that got me
excited I I saw that the that that Kevin
and skunk VA are putting together
something where they're they're uh
they're going to do tissue culture and
and run Nursery apps I guess grateful
heads grateful heads Heads yeah yeah
they're doing some cool stuff and I I
think we're doing a breeding project
trying to bring back back the old ciss
genetics I mean I think we're doing on
the so so what ciss is though ciss is a
description of an aroma what a lot of
people don't get is like well they want
to lay a flag in the ground say that was
my cat piss well maybe you had a cat
piss and maybe this other guy did
because it smelled like ammonia you know
or whatever it is but that's a
description of a smell it's not like
blue dream where it's like a strain name
or cultivar name m um so I'm looking for
that one that smells like
sprayed skunk with ammonia that burns
your nose so and there over the years
I've smelled ammonia and stuff we had
the A5 Haze and that was ammonia right
that was really good but that was
straight ammonia that that would burn
your nose I didn't I didn't have that
broad access you know until the 2000s
yeah you know and a lot a lot of stuff
was just wasn't around I by uh one of my
mentors guy named jaaya and uh he had he
had a strain which was a blue dream uh
New York sour diesel cross wow it was
alpha blue is what he called it it
sounds amazing and it it was wonderful
but you know you couldn't get anybody to
grow it cuz it's 12 weeks you know and
it's like it's rough even now I mean I
have so I have a blue dream times a
double Lemon Cherry that that's that's
like a nine weer and so but it has
everything that I love about blue dream
and so we're calling it dream candy
we're launching that this year oh nice
so we feno hunted that we got three
different ones one's a dead ringer for
blue dream that takes a little bit
longer and then we have the one that
somewh in the Middle where I feel like
it it can reintroduce Blue Dream to the
world in a way where some of these kids
that want that Lemon Cherry gelato
runs uh they'll be excited about it yeah
yeah that's great so sometimes you got
to sneak it in the back door I'm I'm
building my uh my home on orcus island
now and putting in a room so I nice I
look forward to yeah genetics I got
genetics I got lots of genetics I going
to read your book I I hadn't uh yeah I
got a book for you as well
I'm excited to hear more about bio365
and telling everybody about your product
because I feel like you have a special
substrate it's not like other cocoa
products uh you have one that we did
some trials side by side and we got much
bigger plants and it wasn't even the one
that was extremely
hot it's interesting um the the nutrient
light soils um they still have that um
base of biochar in biology they they
just have a smaller quantity of
nutrients right and every time you feed
your salts to the plant our biology is
going to consume maybe five or
10% and it's going to allow the plant to
signal in between your feedings and
balance itself off right you know so we
we did this trial where we had our
nutrient Den soils going against some
competitors and we had one of our
nutrient light cells in there and it
actually
outperformed the the the the nutrient
dense ones which we've never seen before
and we we we went back to the lab and
actually measured the the respiration of
the biology and saw that the biology was
growing yeah from the
salts and and and so you know most
people say oh no salts kill biology yeah
no no lack of water kills biology sure
you know if your if your substrate holds
enough water yeah the biology is fine MH
you know and and so that that surprised
us but you know some of some of our best
uh scale cult cators are are are really
pushing the plant with with the nutrient
light soils where they're they're
getting The Best of Both Worlds yeah
we're seeing a lot more utof flowers out
there yeah I think autoflow is slowly
growing what happened is it took this
huge leap and everybody decided they're
going to plant acres and acres and Acres
of it and then they didn't get the
results they were looking for so but but
then a ton of people were making seeds
everyone got excited about Autoflower
seeds there's there's a couple companies
that make really good autoflow seeds I
feel like I make great Autoflower seeds
seeds and there's a handful of other
ones um that are actually putting in the
work one of the largest uh msos thought
that they' go they do two cycles yeah
right and just use it for molecules
right and the flower turned out so
beautiful they ended up selling it as
flower yeah and they're and they're and
they're doubling up this year and and
cutting back actually indoor I've seen
it I've seen it happened yeah and it's
funny uh you can get a lot faster return
if you know what you're doing and you
use large enough plant numbers you can
actually get higher yield and larger
yields per acre right uh you know it's
it's incredible and you can get more
Harvest per year yeah so I love light
deprivation I love the quality of
products you can get and I love
Greenhouse too I feel like Greenhouse is
the future I feel like you can get an
indoor looking product for those people
that need their flow to look good right
I'm not one of those guys but I'm an
outdoor believer but you know I also
early on I spent a lot of time in in
Colorado um maybe like
201 18 19 yeah and uh and in Colorado
every year one of two things would
happen Okay uh there'd be hail and snow
and freeze and you lose 60 70% of the
crop if not all of it yeah or the
weather would be good and they turn out
so much that the prices would drop $
three $400 a pound wow I mean it was it
was a feast or famine and and there's
just not enough visibility on Supply in
this business to not see it tilt into
over Supply unfortunately you know
especially with with all the this get
rich quick wow you know it's it's sad
for me it's really sad for me that the
guys who really you know built those
foundational strains who who who built
the industry plant as we know it um
they' mostly been screwed yeah you know
um being a head cultivator at the
biggest cultivator in California you
make the same as the the uh Chief
Executives
assistant you know and in California
it's it's not a great living and anybody
went into business with their own
Capital got killed like everybody else
and it's just uh it's it's been hard to
see well that's why I don't do
cultivation you know it's I love
cultivating I I have a lot of respect
for the guys that do it they're doing
the Lord's work mhm uh because the price
per pound is so low right now it's very
difficult to be successful yeah and I
would much rather work on the genetic
side where I can work with everybody and
I can be the the velcro today I I think
genetics you know for for the wreck
operations that we that we work with
genetics are the only way to
differentiate themselves yeah you know
and and that they need to yeah we we try
to do everything in house so literally
we're doing the seed production we're
doing the pheno hunting we're then
licensing genetics selling clones
we're trying to stick with that Nursery
model but I think the future is
licensing genetics for us yeah I I agree
the there's a loophole now I guess that
under the farm bill where you can you
can ship clones and seeds anywhere seeds
anywhere yeah it's well as long as it's
below 3% THC you can ship it anywhere
and thca right so like you could have
thca the ti whatever but like they're
selling some people are selling flour
thca flour that tested 23% thca but test
below 3% Delta 9 THC I'd like to know
who who bred that one yeah well I think
almost all of it is like that and at the
end it tests higher for for Delta 9 THC
ah okay so yeah it's a big loophole
right now that that that will change
people are you know people are in denial
but they're going to change I would I
would think so so but I do love the fact
that you can ship seeds freely around
the world basically um you know
definitely in the United States you can
go state to state without getting
arrested or put in jail for a seed which
wasn't always the case right um but it
is just a seed they've misregulated
everything yeah I I I don't know if you
can bet on them fixing it or screwing it
up worse you know it's well I think it's
GNA get fixed and it's GNA get SC again
the Delta H stuff really bothers me yeah
you know that's the ultimate get rich
quick you know I don't care about the
quality of the high it's no and as a
molecule it's not a bad molecule there
are no bad molecules in opinion you know
but as far as like the get-rich quick
side of it it's just kind of disgusting
because they're taking the worst of the
worst product processing it worst of the
worst hemp and turning it and processing
it and turning it into a product that
will get you high it will have some
effect on yeah but it's but but what is
it do into your body what else is in
there again it's it's it's you know
anybody's willing to jump through a
loophole just to make a few Buck is not
the Cannabis industry I remember want to
no
unfortunately but uh you know and then
we go through waves with everything so
it's going to get better and then it's
going to get worse and then it's going
to get better and you know to which
degree we'll we'll see I mean I think
basically going from schedule one to a
or yeah schedule one down to
rescheduling to schedule three I think
that's a good thing I I think there's
it's good and
bad I think the big deal for the
industry is the 280 MH because no no
one's making money there's one or two
companies really actually turning a real
profit yeah um and and and they're going
to have to refinance at much higher
rates than their first round of
financing it's just been a horror show
yeah so two 280 I think is the most
important for the the economics of the
industry that has no impact on the
structure or the quality of the industry
yeah um but it'll make it viable I think
um I'm concerned that in in bringing it
down to schedule three they they might
put other Hoops around it that make it
more difficult or or more challenging
for The Operators to I mean the schedule
3 is supposed to have all sorts of
facility rules and and right it's
supposed to we'll see what happens we
don't know nobody knows we don't know we
don't know and I I yeah I mean the truth
is we don't know and we can hope for the
best and you know I mean we've we've
done that in the past and it hasn't
always worked out for us but you know
we'll see we have an opportunity to do
something great right and and I think
you're right we are I think we are
improving I I'm I'm you know I know we
are but there's just that overall
frustration and you know we did blow a
great opportunity I don't know how many
more we'll get yeah you know
it's but it's also you know for for Bio
we're not we're not you know looking at
at food crops expanding I mean we we
developed our Salesforce with you know
kind of expertise in one plant yeah um
that that that were broadening now um we
we we have always had a a good micro
greens customer base in in in in the
East and um we we're doing something
that um we're really excited about is
we're certifying our soil is is pathogen
free salmonella leria
ecoi and and that's that's really it's
important in in for controlled
environment Agriculture and in the food
side that's really going to be important
I agree I mean I think same thing with
clones I think clones should be
certified Pest and pathogen free I think
people should put that stamp on their
genetics pathogens are such a big deal
and for the longest time we were
ignoring it pretending it didn't exist
and then once they had to agree because
it was devastating people it was
devastating States like California I
mean I think we were so heavily infected
with hopl and viroid yeah and ferium and
I mean people aren't even talking about
ferium right now but ferium is a huge
problem
in East too the humidity levels are
everybody overw Waters it's just and
everyone wants to blame hop Lon too then
and it's like well maybe it's h maybe
it's ferium I mean there's there's other
pathogens too you know we're looking at
I think over 50 registered pathogens in
cannabis that they know of so I used to
have a a data Communications business
and and um we arbitraged in
international rates whether they were
Telex or fax or or or phone um and
what what we would do is we'd go into
the customer and would sayl it doesn't
matter what you're paying per Telex
minute or fax minute
or killer characters for of email yeah
your real costs are are in your your
business process that creates and uses
those messages for running your business
and storing them and retrieving them and
and confirming they were delivered and
that's where all your costs are yeah let
us paint a picture of a better world and
if you like it we'll implement it for
you and then you'll have much better
total system costs and we would El we
would eliminate the paper and the People
by doing things like taking an
application system that would print out
an airway bill and then the person would
take it off the printer to a fax machine
and shove it in a fax machine on the
other side of the world in in the
freight forwarders other office that
take that fax machine paper and then'
stick it into they' key it into an
application system on the other side so
so we would hook a PC up to the
application system looking like a
printer it would take that printed
message turn it into an EDI message send
it through our Network Force deliver it
to a PC on the other end of the world
where our our PC would keyboard emulate
the transaction into their application
system amazing okay and so eliminating
the people eliminating the paper um they
saved so much more money than didn't
matter what they paid and they were
locked in Forever with us yeah which was
a nice side um in in in terms of system
cost and cannabis you know I was sitting
there one day with with a with a
customer going over their their
cultivation costs and they were paying
$220 for couple gallons of my
soil the pot they put in cost
$4 every time they touched the pot they
had to fill it empty it wash it
sterilize it was 50 cents mhm they were
paying much more for the pot than they
were for my media which was the whole
basis of their successful cultivation
and I said that sucks um so the first
thing we tried to do is eliminate the
pot and so most of our soil we deliver
today in sealed grow bags anywhere from
one and a qu gallons up to 20 gallons
yeah um and uh and you know you want to
talk about you know hoo Lon vroid the
number one vector is probably the path I
would agree and and I would agree 100%
you know and you can go through all the
work of sterilizing everything you
should um but you might as well get rid
of the pot and save the money and the
labor and and
and you know we can engine we can
actually engineer a bag with with micro
parations in it that let it dry back
beautifully much better than like a
smart pot which is all over the place
right um so that you know we're looking
at system cost and trying to get people
understand where they're where they're
spending their time when you know where
they're spending their
touch points yeah understanding all that
well and there's so many little details
that you need to be aware of when the
profit isn't what it used to be right so
every little scent counts yeah and you
know and the the more you scale the more
that's noticeable
too but uh yeah I mean it's a different
world we live in a completely different
world from the Coco that I hated in the
year 2000 when my buddy brought over
these bricks of cocoa that were like
this and a kidy pool and a shovel said
you got to break all these
up you know I I I really admire the the
regenerative Farmers out there who are
making their own soil and and really
loving it and seeing the benefits I mean
there there's no question um whether
you're talking Korean or or biodynamic
biodynamic biodynamic yeah versus
kfal but but if you ever had to price
the labor in the time into it you know
you obviously can't scale it and and and
it's it's is really hard to very
difficult to SC so I heard Wrigley in
Nevada is scaling they do they do living
soil 40,000 sare F feet or something but
I think it's very difficult to scale and
maintain quality with anything so when I
when I was growing um for my my raw food
restaurant yeah um we in order to to
really trust my my compost we had to buy
a chicken CP and get chickens and
generate our own chick can manure and
and you know making sure you could get
clean inputs was was constantly The
Challenge and um controll environment
you know you're you're monocropping
incredible density right um it's a giant
Buffet so
um most people won't bring compost into
into an indoor or uh unless they're
doing it themselves and they really know
right and then then that just becomes
again really expensive
so hey guys you're doing a great job
there's living soil that you can get
right out of the bag yeah and uh and and
the plants will love it
yeah yeah so where do you see the
industry and substrates going in the
next five to 10
years so again I because I do believe
that we're we're moving forward and
we're making progress I I believe that
the the industry is going to go towards
organic cultivation I think it's going
to go towards um
towards better honoring the plant and
again that comes back to to to
biomimicry yeah it comes down to um you
know we just need you know literally
four five years of the of the research
that's going on now yeah and for it to
really solidify and we'll we'll just
understand better I I'm really confident
of that um but I I I do I do see that
that it has to be that has to be a
priority on on the corporate level um
and and these guys are all getting
hammered throwing you know really
mediocre [ __ ] on the market and not not
able to differentiate themselves and and
you know it's not it's not that hard
yeah you know like I said I don't I I
don't see any cost advantage to to to to
the scale there um but you just need
really clean techniques and and clear
clear clear Sops that that you know
don't just take cultural practices and
yeah I mean I think that that even
carries over into genetics with the Sops
and you know sop specific for genetics
with companies it's like
uh that's the future and and empowering
your customers with information that's
going to get them better results because
at the end of the day quality is
everything I think quality we we can
agree that quality is what's going to
make the difference in the future market
and you know having unique genetics but
also
quality uh qual you know it doesn't
matter how good the genetics are if
they're not grown well unfortunately
yeah and and again I think that those
values will will naturally reemerge as a
as a matter of of competition actually
yeah you know and that that's obiously
what's happening down in Florida is um
nit and kaana figured out how to bring
an effect Brands down to Florida and and
tuck them under his license right but
they they operate as
independent cultivations but they're in
his building and he's technically paying
the salaries of the of the employees
interesting but you know like I said
that's how ideal went in down there and
you
know there's some there's some real
Growers down there I'm I'm impressed I'm
excited yeah because I feel a little bit
of Floy as as a home state you know I I
was embarrassed you know you live in
Florida yeah yeah it's interesting uh
the Dynamics and then once interstate
commerce comes into play how do you see
that yeah you know so when I grew up in
Ohio um you couldn't buy California wies
really you couldn't buy K's beer this is
this is
60s it it took 20 years plus for states
to negotiate out the alcohol yeah um
restrictions that are very similar to
cannabis I I don't
know what you know why Colorado is going
to want to give up their cultivation
taxes to California yeah um so I don't
see it happening
quickly um even with Federal if Federal
was go completely legal still I I I
still think the states would would would
want to retain control from from the
taxation standpoint yeah no I'm not
optimistic about it happening in in the
next 10 years yeah um but at the same
time I'd be the first one to tell you
that I have an interest in a remaining
state by state totally you know yeah I
mean I would love to go to Texas and be
be able to smoke this stuff from
California yeah but also if Texas could
produce their own I would just also be
happy and they will and they will I mean
you know what I would say is that the
the the progress of the industry is very
much been stunted by the economics of
the industry yeah you know people are
just trying to survive it's rough right
now it's really rough for cultivators
yeah we lost several years in a row 40%
of our customers yeah stopped
operating yeah I mean it affects
everybody so not just the cultivator
suffer the nutrient company right the
substrate companies uh the lighting
companies and then there's an
overabundance of some of these um
markets with within like even lighting
and other stuff like that where there's
so many you know and I think there's
there's some good products just like
everything else there's good products
and bad products out there you know and
and it's it's funny the the technology
really is I mean I I see things every
month you know not you know they've now
now got lights that are killing you know
killing pathogens and in in in the rooms
and and under canopy lights and yeah and
also the strains
are they're very finicky and you know o
OG's just don't like LEDs you know no
they don't like they like C yeah exactly
so I mean and and and and there's also I
mean again strains
uh there's so much drift yeah you know
and and and we're probably I don't know
I don't know much about this stuff but
you know some of the things I'm reading
is that you know we're seeing a steady
weakening of of of the genes from when
we had real land race strains and and
the plants just less less able to adapt
um and I don't know if that's true but
um the person said it with so much
confidence I had to believe him yeah
well I think land race varieties
are grown in specific climates and
specific environments that serve a
purpose and you know I think a lot of
those there there wasn't the inbreeding
that we've done now to where we're
bottlenecking ourselves like with these
gelato and stuff like that they're you
know I would say that that's potentially
one of the contributions why we have
things like hop PL and viid that's such
a problem is because our genetics aren't
as strong as they used to be yeah that's
that's a really good point and I I don't
know I remember getting getting really
stoned on what was probably 12 or 14%
you know not that long ago I mean in the
90s even totally Sour Diesel even when
we first started testing it was like the
outdoor that was 12 to 14% was really
strong and good it was really good I
mean we didn't care about percentages
right right exactly and now it's it's
it's become a price marker and you know
in the market
it's really sad to me that's it's really
sad and it just is a sign of a
uneducated Market because if people are
buying for the THC percentage first of
all that doesn't tell you the whole
story it doesn't even tell you really
part of the story other than it's going
to get you maybe more High than
something else but really I'm all about
effect like i' I'd love if they put a
description of how it made you feel
although that's subjective it's you know
it's very subjective at least we could
get an idea um or the flavor Prof FES
whether it's lemon or whether it's
berries or fruit or gas you know I think
there's so many other ways we could
Define I think that's that's evolving
I've heard that you know the the the gas
candy yeah
sour yeah you know designation is five
of them whatever I me that's the way we
need to go and then in Humble we need
terar we need to identify it like wine
we yeah I would love that my partner and
I've
really keenly interested as to the role
of Terre um in uh in cultivation of
cannabis versus wine the um the
interesting thing though is that the
biology you get ends up pretty much
reflecting the nutrients you're feeding
um you can start with anything but it's
it's going to change based on on what
you're feeding it and and the plant
itself
so we're trying to nail down what that
what that really means we go out and
Sample you know humble Coastline you
know biology and culture it and see how
it it it worked with some you know
plants that were you know that was a
Terre you know we're trying to figure
out how to to do it and measure it and
determine whether it's sustainable or
valid you know it's it's it's
interesting areas beyond my pay grade
for sure that's exciting to me though I
mean because you can go up and I think I
talked about humble but really it's all
around the world like terroir is you can
go from one region to the next and you
could taste Sour Diesel and maybe it's
the same cut and it tastes completely
different well any any any cultivar is
is both it's environment and genetics
you can't there's no two you can take
the same exact genetics and grow it two
different places it's never going to be
the same that's what gives you the
phenotype is nutrition and environment
so that's what you give you the
expression that you see at the end right
and uh you know and all these things
with environment you could have
different levels of humidity you can
have different amount of sun you know
it's like the minerality all these
things as far as uh it's pretty amazing
getting into this and then I also see
this as something where we can open this
up to the whole world where you can get
a tasting experience going driving up
the 101 and you can stop at these farms
and maybe get a tasting experience and
then that puts the money back into the
farmers which is really what we need to
do I was I was really hopeful that uh
that the Farmers Market
legislation would pass I don't know if
it even came up for a vote but um I
thought that was really a beautiful way
to to to support the the northern
Farmers yeah well we did get approved
tasting lounges lounges cannabis lounges
got approved so that you know Gavin
Newsome love him or ha him me proved
that yeah um but can you purchase at
them now I believe you can purchase at
them now they they changed that yeah so
I I believe I'm not 100% but but I
believe you can purchase at them but you
obviously can't consume alcohol and it's
going to be one or and I believe they
can do cannabis
cafes so and I love the concept of a
Cannabis Cafe I'm not big on putting the
Cannabis in the food from for myself
just personal preference I'd rather
smoke a amazing flour in a joint and
then go eat some delicious food I'm with
you but I'm sure somebody's going to
change that opinion you know I mean it's
yeah a lot of creative people out there
and and um
you know I I when when I was in the raw
food business you know what heat does is
it melds flavors together and it
intensifies them right um and and it
gets rid of water um so you can you can
take a cultural flavor model and
disassemble it and reassemble it with
raw components and and you just have to
adjust for those that flavor intensity
and and and um what what what I was
really intrigued with I I was talking
with the population geneticist just the
other day and he was talking about
really understanding how to to
sequence the specific expressions of
specific
trines and and then go ahead and and
breed from there yeah bre breed from the
ability to to take these you know
subexpressions and and and put them
together and and and and and also to
vary the intensity
yeah of the expression I don't
understand it I would love to talk to
that guy yeah I get a bunch of questions
he's he he's um he was at ancestry nice
he was leading their they had a they had
a division which I think they closed
which was was linking um sequencing to
specific Health outcomes yeah um and you
know with all the population genetics
type of math I get excited you know we
talk about the white papers from from
abstracts Tech that just came out on
flavorants and you know sulfur based
compounds that are smaller than they
smaller molecules than tpin uhhuh um you
know THS and stuff like that right right
yeah I know yeah that gets me excited
like breeding for those type of things
those type of expressions and I feel
like there is the relation to the effect
in the flavor oh for sure and uh you
know I love the flavor of cannabis
though I love smoking good stuff I love
the way it makes me
feel um and there's something great for
every type of occasion too so that's the
beauty of it we have all the different
things in our Arsenal and we can pick
and choose between them it's like okay
I'm going to go do this I'm going to go
to a dead company but you know what
takes a long time yeah takes years it
does it takes all this stuff is very
it's it's the Slow Race we're we're
doing the marathon and not the Sprint
but people want the Sprint you we're
we're Americans and a lot of Americans
no they want instant gratification and I
think that's part of the problem with
the Cannabis industry is it's not
instant gratification we didn't get here
over overnight it took us a long time
that's a great Point
yeah so yeah I mean it's it's still
beautiful it's you know I mean the fact
that we're here right now talking about
cannabis legally no one's going to come
arrest us for talking about I think
that's great yeah they will close down
my bank account
yeah um but yeah you're you're right and
I'm I'm an eternal optimist I you know I
don't know I don't know what other
choice exists I'm the same you know um I
I I I've once heard this philosophy that
um the guy basically said whatever
happens to you has to benefit you right
you know and he had this whole big
scheme that you know the universe is
perfect and if it wasn't it would have
collapsed by now and so everything that
happens must be good to happen and but I
just look at it from a practical
standpoint um is is that's where you
learn you know I mean that's that's the
opportunity um and and uh the the only
thing that makes any sense to do is to
say hey I'm going to learn from this and
we're going to fix it yeah I mean you
have to go through enough bad stuff to
really really understand it
unfortunately and I mean I think that's
part of getting older I'm 47 now and so
I've learned I'm almost 48 next month
but I've learned a lot in my 48 years
about what to do and what not to do and
learning from my mistakes learning from
my friends mistakes but I feel like you
have to make a certain amount of
mistakes and you know certain amount of
suffer in has to go on in your life for
you to appreciate how wonderful this
place really is even in the bad times I
think both both those points that you
know the appreciation but also the you
know the learning um the the getting it
right yeah you know and
and I my father used to say to me
businesses don't fail because they don't
have a reason for being they fail
because they run out of money before
they figure it out yeah you know and and
and so I I just I have to believe we we
we can do this we we can do it much
better than we're doing it now and we
will yeah know that's and I think
striving for that perfection even though
I feel like the needle constantly is
moving I think striving for Perfection
is what life's all about too because I I
think that it's never going to be
perfect but it could always be better
agreed agreed to go and I hate I hate to
fall back on my my father had all these
say he call the saying sayings of
chairman Sam you know nice yeah all
these really wise things he say we would
say nobody is as good or as bad as you
think they are you know and and and he
would say business is about getting
people to do what you need them to do
whether you're working for them or
they're working for you whether you're
selling to them or they're selling to
you right um is listening and and and
finding out what it's going to take to
make it work for the other person and he
he was pretty insightful while he was
twisting me up
nice I love them mentors life is all
about having good mentors and people
that we
can uh learn from right you know Elders
mentors even younger even younger
mentors I'm learning from people that
are younger than me yeah uh but I
learned in working in the restaurant
industry I learned amazing things from
my dishwashers if you're willing to
learn there's amazing places you can
find information and right you know
especially cooking you know it's like we
had a guy I learned how to
make uh amazing food from one of my
dishwashers so if you had one piece of
information for your younger self going
into the the industry with bio
365 what would that piece be my dilemma
with bio 65 bio 365 excuse me is that
I'm too old yeah uh and I wanted it to
happen too fast I didn't want to wait 10
years and I couldn't force it especially
with the way the industry was you know
we were doubling every year even though
40% of our customers were going out of
business but you couldn't you couldn't
sustain it and and so I think that was
my my biggest uh take on on the trise we
we actually went through a real so
there's something called Klein's coraly
to Murphy's Law you know Murphy's Law is
whatever can go wrong will go wrong
right Klein's corer is whatever hasn't
gone wrong yet is just waiting for an in
opportune
time so you know we open by 365 with two
pilot lines in New York and California
and reading and
uh when we validated that that that we
had something and we wanted to invest in
it built a scaled plant in courland New
York yeah and that plant had a $40 a
yard
better uh direct labor cost than than
the plant and breing
and at the time which was the end of
2019 um the shipping from New York to
California was $40 a yard so it looked
like a wash the intelligent thing to do
was to close down the reading plant um
get rid of the the the the overhead of
the the plant rent and the manager the
stuff that wasn't direct labor um and
build a new one in California you know
and we did that Clos it in January 2020
and Co hit and the freight rate
tripled all of a sudden we were losing
$200,000 a month in Freight penalty for
not having the West Coast
Factory and then we it's covid so try
couldn't go out couldn't go out looking
to find a place till the lockups ended
couldn't find a place because Logistics
warehouse space was so in demand for for
the logistics um ordered all the
equipment which took two years to arrive
because the the control boxes were they
couldn't get the semiconductors for
right so I mean we lost a phenomenal
amount of money during that period just
in Freight penalty and and that that was
just bad bad luck because I it wasn't
the wrong
decision um and retrospect it might have
been but um that that was the toughest
thing for us to overcome um and and
finally we did and and so it's
I I think that you know it was hard to
get the market to understand that we
weren't just a commodity substrate right
that we weren't just like a charar or
you know real coco or what whatever and
and you know so that that's been our
biggest challenge but I think we're
getting to the point where people
understand who we are and they see all
the people growing in it and they go
something must be going on there and so
that's that's that's gotten us over the
top and we're now you know profitable
and growing and and and and hope to
continue um as I said in in in other
food crops as well as
Canabis yeah if people are looking to
find out more about
you where can they
go talk to my wife um no uh yeah in
Instagram LinkedIn bio 365 at Instagram
you have a website uh bio 365.com yep
bio 365.com and um and msk bio is is my
Instagram yeah excellent but really
enjoyed it thank you so much for uh for
allowing me to come and and discuss our
stuff so you've been on the list since
the beginning of my show of people that
I wanted as guests so I'm glad you
finally came in I'm I'm getting that
list is getting narrowed down slowly but
surely so thank you for coming on the
show and uh yeah really appreciate it my
pleasure thank you you're
welome thank you guys for watching
please like And subscribe down below