[Music]
you
[Applause]
[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James loud
podcast and today our special guest is
male from turps how are you doing today
what shaking oh man it's been an
adventurous week man we've had a lot of
fun it's been a little crazy this is the
second podcast we're doing today so yeah
thank you so much for coming on the show
yeah I remember when I saw you in Alam
and you were I think building or getting
this place into action or oh yeah
something like that it's funny how long
it takes to get there CU that was like
three years ago I think that we were
together in Al it had to be over three
years ago but yeah we've known each
other for a long time we actually were
part of the same circle of friends and
didn't hang out but kind of knew of each
other you know for for the last 15 20
years yeah uh all the same mutual
friends and then we hung out in
Amsterdam I don't know 5 years ago
something like that that was that was
Amsterdam and I saw you also in Spain at
spannabis the past two years totally
yeah just been chilling dude just trying
to take it easy relax not really like um
overwork myself which you know we've all
been used to but now it's like you might
not be successful unless you overwork
yourself so I think working hard is part
of the process you know if you believe
in yourself and you believe in your
product uh you know I think that goes a
long ways and then it gives you
something to strive for every day when
you can be devoted to something yeah I
think that's part of like part of what
we do is we we become devotional and
when when you can be devoted to your
craft that's when it can really take off
and almost have a mind of its own yeah
100% I mean it's also your heart's got
to be there now yeah you know it has to
be there because the amount of effort
that you're putting to get to where
you're trying to go it's like if your
heart's not there it's going to be a
struggle for sure yeah I mean you really
have to love what you do to a degree and
believe in yourself uh because there's a
lot of these days people don't believe
anything yeah you know and it's hard to
believe stuff when PE you know I think
when people are struggling so much it's
hard for them to believe anything
believe in anything too you know it's
like the industry has had its ups and
downs and this is just it's a roller
coaster right so there's going to be bad
times and good times it's going to be
good and it's going to be bad and then
it's going to be good again and then
it's probably going to be little bad
again but like I feel like I'm on this
upward trajectory and I'm excited about
the stuff that you're doing I mean the
stuff you're doing in Portugal with our
good friend Paulie Paulie love Paulie
man he's like one of my best friends in
the whole world uh he was my sous chef
for a while when we did cooking stuff
together and you know it's like he's
just a amazing human and you guys are
working together over you brought him
over to Portugal in the project you were
doing and I think that's great you also
uh I was speaking to red on the way down
here and he he sends his hellos nice
he's doing some mushroom stuff back in
Chicago and yeah he's been doing that
for a while with Tony and they they've
been doing some interesting stuff and uh
they're going to clinical trials now in
South Africa so really cool I mean he's
been pushing the the bar ever since I've
known him and then with mushrooms like
him and Tony have really kind of been
doing Wild Things I mean uh you know
when people were just first starting to
talk about it they were talking about
taking it to that next level yeah and
he's yeah I'm a big fan it's like we
we're lucky we have so many friends that
are really interesting that really are
outside the box thinkers that kind of
are innovators yeah uh and then when
Paulie was telling me about your your
Vape cart that you're coming out with I
was like man I don't really have Vape
cart guys on the show but you're doing
something super Innovative and I feel
like we have so many other great stories
to talk about yeah that it would make
for a great podcast I just I love
Innovation whether it's with genetics or
whatever it is in this space Innovation
is so necessary so why don't you tell
everybody about your device well so it
date back to like I think it was 2016
2017 we were growing up in
lonville we brought all the the flower
down and we dried it and froze it and we
processed it into sauce and diamonds uh
at the lab in Oakland and and when you
really got in front of HTE and saw what
you could do with the full turp spectrum
it's kind of like holy [ __ ] because you
know most of the Vape cards back then on
the market were all hot dog water with
Botanical turps and there's a monetary
play there and not a not something
that's like grade A for the consumer
it's like you know when you're looking
at the elite cultivators the elite
manufacturers these guys are trying to
keep a top tier product at a a market
competitive cost because you know price
and it's quality right but like there
was that Heyday of just like okay all
these trash 510 threads are all going
you know to wherever and people who
knows what they're ingesting and right A
lot of times you get a market
segment that doesn't they're not
educated in it because nobody's taken
the time to educate them like okay so
this is how they make that like I
remember walking into warehouses that
only sold d8 yeah I'm kind of like
nobody knows what they have to do to get
this you know and I'm not going to tell
them but I'm just going to kind of
listen and leave yeah so that that year
on that hill we came down we did all
that and I just sparked in my head I'm
like why isn't there a cartridge for
specifically the the diamonds and the
sauce and then you fast forward you know
now six years later people are decarbing
the diamonds they're putting you know
the HT back in they're separating it
reformulating it or they're taking live
resin and decarbing that yeah there's
there's definitely a higher level of
quality coming out from an extraction
formulation
standpoint but if you really break it
down into the active
compounds your thca or your THC is going
to need a certain level of temperature
to vaporize and if you bring the
flavonoid and the turpine in there with
it you're cooking it because that
doesn't need those
temperatures you can get into the the
deeper science about the volatiles and
like the heating curve to actually
vaporize the volatiles instead of
evaporate them etc etc so what we what I
did six years ago is I started down a
path of creating what essentially is a
dual chamber cartridge yeah with a
battery that is uh
rechargeable and you know I was thinking
to myself you
know how do we make this even more
preferable besides splitting the active
compounds because it's
like supposing you wake up tomorrow and
you don't want to
to smoke the certain strain of that Vape
cart that you have so what do you do you
buy 13 Vape carts so when you wake up
you can appease yourself and it's like H
yes and my engineer like unfortunately
yeah right my engineer's like listen I
can make that turp tank swappable and
I'm like really and then it kind of went
from here to here in my mind and I'm
like Okay cool so it's like with our
with our pod based system you'd go to a
um a dispensary and you would get the
thca pod which contains the diamonds non
decarbed they sit in crystalline form
yeah you can't essentially fool a
customer and say it's liquid diamonds
but it's really just hot dog water which
you know that's that's a lot of the does
the industry standard almost
unfortunately you know distillate
distillate it got a lot of people
through some hard times but at the end
of the day is it like is it full
spectrum off of the plant and everything
now because you're cooking everything
off in the Roto and then now you've got
to bring the flavonoid back in and I I
met with some other companies which I
won't name but and this was back in 2017
but everybody wanted to use HT they
wanted to use the the tarpine that was
native to the plant but cost
Effectiveness and then amount that you
need to formulate with times that price
per gram to get the same pungency the
same taste that you were getting by
adding the Botanicals at whatever 7%
yeah right those Botanicals go a long
way
they it just wasn't took them out of a
market of compet Market competitive
price point so now you can be Market
competitive with it because obviously
the industry you know what I mean so we
started working on the UI for the
battery and uh we have a chip
inside that essentially it's an oem chip
that we had designed specifically for
our device in which you're throwing a
certain temperature at the the diamonds
and a certain temperature at the saw
and we're able to create a he a heat
curve for the sauce which will ramp it
up so you actually vaporize the
volatiles that are left there especially
if you're using fresh frozen sauce which
is what we have in here right you the
point of the Frozen is the the stuff you
that goes missing during the drying and
curing process and right those volatile
compounds that just
disappear if you're going to if you're
going to harvest in that manner and
process in that manner you might well
want to taste it you know you don't just
want to cook them like you could throw
fresh frozen in distill it in a single
chamber and well you want to taste as
much as possible exactly exactly and you
want it to taste different right that's
that's the thing that that it was like
in my head I'm like okay this is going
to get you high yeah now the thca is
very potent it's isolated but the thing
is the the turps everybody chases the
turps like people chase turpion in life
oh I love this sushi spot it tastes
great or this this Mexican moonshine is
amazing you know what I mean like so
people chase turps and don't even
realize it and with cannabis it's like
oh what's the new Candy strain yeah
what's this what you're chasing the
turps it could have 100% you know THC
potency to it yeah that doesn't change
anything in terms of a quality
standpoint as a nostalgic standpoint you
don't crack a turkey and just look to
see how icy it is you crack a turkey and
and you're trying to get the the smell
trying to okay this this smells like
cotton candy Skittles you know and
that's what they say it is oh wow this
is new so I'm like how do we bring that
to the consumer yeah cuz all my friends
on the East Coast everybody that has
shops and everybody that's kind of like
in that you know upand cominging Market
it's kind of like you get the same
response for people that go from like
flower to Vapes and stuff where it's
kind of like yeah it tastes good but
it's like not like I couldn't it says uh
Skittles on it but I can't really
pinpoint it you know you can't taste the
Skittles bad trim turps you know again
you know it's just kind of like instead
of going the the quick and fast and easy
route like how do you make this like top
tier but still keep it Market
competitive from a price point you know
so we're able to introduce the ability
for the user on the screen to highlight
either the diamond or the sauce icon and
change the intensity of either side to
your desired preference you know if you
want it to be more intense on your THC
you can up that if you want it to be
more flavorful and less intense you can
balance it to to your preference and
again with a simple turn and a pull you
can just drop in whatever TP tank you
want for that day so it's very
userfriendly it's very uh advantageous
to somebody who you know I when I see
this sometimes I think of
like uh like a
of three kids that can't just like step
out and roll a joint and like sit there
and come back in and it's kind of like
okay this is something she and she's
done you know she's high and nobody's
like you wreak like weed Mom that's the
biggest advantage of carts you don't
smell like flour like burnt flour in my
opinion you know with with the market
maturing Across America and you know to
some degree you know Europe and other
places the world you're going to get
this type of necessity you know you're
going to have people that are going to
look at this and be like okay that's
awesome because I work in some company
and I have to go to the bathroom and I
want to take a [ __ ] head of this
while I'm sitting on the bathroom toilet
and I go back to work you know you can't
really go out front of the building and
pull out of Backwoods and start rolling
up and then go back and your boss is
like what are you doing so and this is
just the the truth of life like people
look for things to escape or make their
real world easier sure and they don't
necessarily want to risk what they have
by doing it you know I'm a flower guy
like for sure I love flower but you had
to bring if you're going to come to
Market in my mind with
something why not it be something novel
something that pushes the envelope a
little bit something that takes the
science of the plant and actually uses
that science to benefit the customer and
the overall experience on it there's
just not much these days like I showed
it to a few guys few operators that are
like within the extract space and The
Vape space and they were like finally
something that's different yeah
something that makes a change in in the
experience and then it was everything
besides that it was you know making sure
we're with the right manufacturers in
China yeah making sure that coming to
Market we have full quality control of
what's going out in the field from a
strain
standpoint making sure that the
extraction lab and it's the same guys
that I you know and I mean was working
with back in the day so we have a very
good relationship the guys at A1 you met
Jordan and Mike before yeah yeah good
good guys you know so it's like I'm
comfortable with who's in the supply
chain from that end right at that point
you know it's just money and and and and
heart like we said like if your heart's
behind it and you think that this is a
better product you know go for it and
you got some sort of work ethic yeah you
got to have a little something you got
to have a little something little
something so let's talk about turpins
for a minute because I feel like we can
educate everybody on Turpin because not
all tpin are created equal you have
native tpin which are basically native
to that distillate or to those diamonds
right if we're talking about Native and
then there's cannabis derived tpes right
which are cannabis as opposed to
Botanical or plant derived tpin and then
there's the the artificial tpin yeah
right which are made in a lab so we have
these three or four categories of
tpin uh that people are using and
they're definitely not all created equal
the Cannabis derived or native tpin
depending on what you're doing are
typically a lot more expensive they're
harder to extract typically they're
separated with cold extraction yep how
do they do it from a hydrocarbon stance
you are pushing solvent through the
material very cold and then you're
crashing at a low temp to purge the
solvent and create the crystalline
formulations and then you're fractioning
them separating them and then you're
again fining finalizing the purge and
then you're you're filling and supplying
I've been
obviously looking at the solventless
methods yeah with the right genetics
obviously because rosin and the solvent
list thing is is super genetic based for
being profitable or not right I think
with the right genetics and the right
mechanical separations which I've seen
them do you know like the the roll oh
yeah wands of the the a that come from
rosin I kind of think I have a method
that you can do your initial squeeze
your 24-hour your whip and your cure
yeah and then I think that there's a way
mechanically with head pressure and
vacuum through a filtration C
yeah that you could separate the
two and then from there you have your a
maybe you got a cent fuge it just to get
any remaining leftover turp off and then
you can reformulate that into micro
diamonds with silicone molds and low
temps in back ovens right so now
essentially here's your solventless
diamond and here's your solventless
sauce I know the guy for that actually
okay his name is Kenny from triome
Technologies if there's anybody that can
figure it's him or he's probably already
figured it out to be honest yeah I I sit
around and I I think about that because
there's a a bigger Market segment
there's a bigger vantage point of people
and you know the way that information
transfers Across America like there was
a time where the other coast had no clue
right they didn't know what passers were
now they know what passers are now they
know what rosin is now you start to see
the education roll downhill to them yeah
and then it's like you know I don't want
to be that company that didn't do their
due diligence to be able to supply this
to them in a solventless fashion right
if that's what the buyer wants you make
the customer we spent all this time and
energy and effort to make something to
make the customer happy right you got to
do that you got to see that all the way
through well it's a fully customizable
experience so you can take it in any
direction you want you want higher tpin
and what kind of tpin and you know I
think that the Poss possibilities are
pretty much endless with which direction
you can go as a consumer which is nice
because as a company you can offer all
these great packages and great Concepts
yeah for people yeah I mean going in
going into a dispensary you know you buy
the diamonds and then you get an array
of turp Tanks to choose from and you
know it's like okay I'll take these
three and then well technically TPS can
be shipped in the mail so you could even
have them on your
website do a little farm bill action for
sure but the thing is what's nice about
TPS too and having you know jars of them
sitting yeah is that you can it's like
there's it's like a cheat code to
breeding to a degree because it's like
let's say we're like okay let's just
play around and make some cocktails 10%
of this 10% of this 80% of this
essentially you know you you obviously
know like when you're doing your your
breeding like you're looking for the the
turs of this is check salad joints you
know to get an idea it doesn't always
work out like that a lot of you know
that's the funny thing with breeding
though you pencil it out and it doesn't
look the same on paper as it does in
reality a lot of times I think the
future of rosin is blending just like
they blend
wine uh you know and I think also
blending turps together in the future
why not yeah right I think you can get
some really cool stuff I do a lot of you
know I think hash holes is a great
example people are trying to combine a
certain type of rosin with a certain
type of flower to get a certain type of
flavor and effect yeah and so it's the
same thing with the pen I think
that uh it's great we're exploring these
areas because I feel like we got to
leave no stone left unturned to a degree
especially in this space and there's so
many different directions you can go
right when you think you've got it all
figured out something new emerges yeah
right that's with like V Vape cartridges
and you know I got
my ays from Focus V and this is my dab
rig that I carry around in my pocket and
I love this but I'm all about Innovation
and I'm all about switching stuff up and
I think there's so many different
possibilities and I love it all because
I'm all about the experience too and
it's like and the experiences we can
have in life and all these different
experiences and where we can go with a
pen where I don't want to get super
baked but I definitely feel like smoking
having some turps in my mouth yeah you
know I mean that's great to be able to
choose you know in the morning you're
going to the gym you don't want to get
that ripped but you want to get just
right you want to get comfortable you
want to get comfortable and that's the
thing is like the industry is is still
full of our Our Generation and age right
so it's like if we gave up if we threw
the towel in like you know we're burnt
we've been at this a long time someone
else is going to figure it out I don't
know about this younger generation
though I have my doubts and fears you
know but I still see people emerging
that are creative and Innovative so much
the younger guys it's it's more the
corporations and the guys that you know
money solves problems you know so to a
degree you see science scientists now
come on and the guy may have never
smoked weed before but he might be like
well why are we doing it like this cuz
the boiling points here are lower than
here so there's you need that too you
need that too but for it to push the
ball forward yeah if it comes from us
we're still doing our job right you get
what I'm saying like to hand the
Accolade to them to me yeah we're not
doing our job right you nobody nobody
wants to hear the opinion of some brand
new fresh out of the gate guy on his
podcast people come here because you're
a very well respected long-term in this
industry guy people come here because
you are you like I'm talking to James
you know I'm not talking to John from
Super scien tech.com that just got their
permit two years ago and you know they
still think Gorilla Glue is the best
thing in the world and I love Gorilla
Glue but you understand what I'm saying
you get the dated I got a love hate
relationship with that Gorilla Glue
feel when red grew it in Orville like I
just remember being like what the [ __ ]
is this I remember when he just replaced
s diesel almost completely overnight you
know I think there there was like the
sour craze and all my friends that were
growing sour all our friends that were
growing sour and all of a sudden
everybody's growing Gorilla Glue and the
Gorilla Glue was amazing don't get me
wrong but I feel like it kind of just
stepped on sour right at the end there
finished faster it was gassy it checks
the basically it checks the boxes for
the the same boxes that Sour Diesel
checks
and so a lot of people were like well
I'm just going to grow this it finishes
faster I don't have to worry about the
rain at the end of the year uh the the
yields are good the buds dense the bag
appeal was
amazing had better structure than sour
definitely and it wasn't such a pain in
the ass to grow like s it sour and you'd
have you'd look at sour wrong and all of
a sudden it fingers out completely and
you got Fox tailes those were good times
though but I mean sour kind of built our
group of friends dud like sour and our
relationship with sour and
dog and you know Menino Sonoma humble
yeah like within our circle of friends
that kind of built our group and then
Gorilla Glue comes in and freaking
basically Gorilla Glue kind of took over
for a little bit absolutely it did and
it was kind of like it would it had that
trajectory that dream had you know cuz
it was like people like this [ __ ]
thing yields it's got a wonderful turp
content you know what I mean it's like
let's dream was good too at one point
some people don't remember it but dream
was the one like literally blue dream
when it peaked it it peaked people were
like tripping on how good it was too and
it was sticky and it had the bag appeal
there were so many good things about it
the effect maybe wasn't there for
everybody but as far as bag appeal yeah
it was was where it was at you know it
was some of the best it was definitely
wonderful um you know just back to like
the importance of the tpine and like you
know if you think about it from an
industry standard where they're like oh
sprayed packs the sprayed packs I what
the [ __ ] are they spraying it with tpin
whether they're native or not or
artificial or whatever I'm not
justifying the actions no I'm not saying
that this is right but I'm just saying
this is what they're doing from a
mechanical level like they are trying to
increase yeah the tpine content so it
pops it jumps because when you're
rolling yeah and it's
loud this is going to get me lit like
this it's just the whole thing you're
smoking it through a a backwoods it
still tastes all turpy yeah you know I
think that's part of the appeal of the
tped Ted flour yeah U and you know what
I don't I'm not judging I don't care if
you like it you like it and if you don't
you don't I'm it's not my thing really
but I also understand its value for
certain demographics you know if you
look at it from that perspective and
yeah it is people chase flavor right at
the end of there's flavor Chasers all
over with everything in life 100% 100%
And with ours it's like I've met with a
few people that kind of like they didn't
nudge me but they kind of like laid out
a portfolio of companies that they could
feed the hardware to just solely the
hardware yeah and the problem in my mind
with just giving this out as Hardware or
doing that sort of thing is like you
lose
control over the QC yeah of what inputs
end up in there yeah do I want to come
out to market with the brand right now
is it is it uh you know a heavy load to
bear on like like just life like you
know like we talk about a lot of work
right yeah but if I were to just go that
route and just like okay we'll sell
Hardware to a thousand different
companies a thousand times over and
they're putting bgrade [ __ ] tpps in
and it's just not like this Tech cannot
be an experience that a single chamber
trimmed Ted hot dog water cart would
give you because it doesn't make sense
why all the this and this right why are
you going to jump through these
hoops if at the end of the day the
experience is the same right so our
thing is like get the couple acres grab
these
Frozen or dry cured immediately Frozen
MH that's another thing we'll talk about
next
but bring the quality of the technology
and match it to the quality of the
experience yeah so it's like then you
take it from our standpoint where it's
like guys love Frozen yeah because of
those volatiles and it's like you know
we know what wet sour smells like yeah
but if you have a 100,000 cartridges on
wreck to Consumers that have never
walked through a field an indoor or
anything before in their life never
grown a Canabis plant yeah that wet may
not be that nostalgic reminder of that
strain
so if you were to dry the flow freeze it
process it those TPS are going to be eye
to eye with the dried flow
cryocure yeah or or any I mean just
cryotechnology
I've heard about that where they're like
where they're changing that but in my
opinion it's like and I had this
discussion with somebody today like is
it smarter to appeal to the to the guys
like us or is it harder to appeal for
the common person that may have
experienced these same strains and
flower so that when they hit it they
realize that oh my God that tastes like
I stuck my face in a bag of Blue Dream
you know like you're you're you're
smoking the
SM smell so you know at the end of the
day it's like that's you have to
sometimes not think about you or your
peers or or the industry and you have to
just solely base your trajectory and
your road map and how you're formulating
your inputs on the buyer on the consumer
on the person that's going to leave that
Yelp review you know like well yeah I
mean I think there's that Ultimate
Experience too that you can provide that
that's unique and that's what'll set you
apart from everybody else if you can
provide an experience that's different
that's better that sticks with people if
you can get people's head and they're
like wow that's the best thing I've ever
tasted yeah then you're on to something
it's just that's what it's all about
with whether you're a breeder whether
you're making extract whether you're
making extract equipment it's all about
chasing flavor and giving people and
chasing experiences right yeah so yeah
if you can give this I mean same thing
with breeding if you can create a new
variety that's different from everything
else everybody has that's not just a
derivative of all this other stuff but
that's actual a new thing then you win
then you're on to something special and
you think of it from an environmental
standpoint like you know you see these
States California cracking down on how
you're disposing of the lithium and then
you see them cracking down on the
flavors people are using like yeah you
can't really use all this artificial
[ __ ] here anymore like it's not good for
people none of this has been clinically
Tri yeah you can't see what's happening
to somebody more menthol cigarettes guys
yeah but I mean shout out all shout out
all my Newport smokers but you know what
I mean like at the end of the day it's
you know if you can buy a
battery yeah and recharge the battery
and not be you know a waste on the
environment for lithium like why not if
the tech is there why not just use it
because at the end of the day waste is
waste and you know lithium's a you can't
just like throw it in the landfill and
things can happen in in Mass right so
the T and the same thing with the tpin
it's like at least you and I know we've
been smoking flour forever and all this
comes from that same flower smoking so
we don't have to be like just is this
mysterious to my body or not like this
is
what this is what cannabis is like
you're legalizing everybody's pushing
for the the motion of the legalization
of cannabis right everybody's looking at
it from a Countrywide scale now you know
it's like businesses or companies are
putting their
projections in front of them like if
this were to happen this is where we
would be so why would you need to do
anything else there's so many people
that haven't even just experienced the
plant right why do you need to
substitute that with weirdo [ __ ] just
because it lowers your bottom line like
and that's the thing it's like you know
some people are super [ __ ] greedy
some people don't care about whether or
not they're doing this or that to the to
their consumer because it meets their
bottom line they meet their p&amp;l sheet
looks good their performer my this my
that sure you and I both know like the
essence of this
starting off sure there's money to be
made there was always money to be made
but there was a Brotherhood yeah there
was a I'm selling this and doing this
well our friends are kind of different
because we were all about quality we
wanted the best [ __ ] possible and we
didn't give a [ __ ] about price it was
always about having the very best of the
very best I feel like we always fought
for that it was always that strive to
for greatness you know I mean with
everything that we've always done with
happiness it brought normal people that
like had access in 2002 to a bag of good
weed and it's like yeah they had a
stressful day at work yeah they want to
go home and smoke a bowl here's an eth
for 60 bucks here's this Durban Poison
from [ __ ] honeydo you know what I
mean like totally some top shelf some
top shelf and it's like that
happiness was a motivator yeah and you
almost can't put an a price on an
experience you I mean you can but you
almost can't put a price on an
experience it's like cuz those are like
especially some of this stuff it's like
batch to batch craft flow that we had
back in the day yeah that was just like
some of the stuff coming out was so
amazing some of the stuff where people
were like oh Durban Poison for instance
people like oh Durban Poison no the
Durban Poison that was going around back
in the day completely different
completely different than it is today
completely it wasn't it wasn't very hazy
it was super funky uh in sensey ha Haze
was maybe there was a little bit of haze
but it was more so the the Cherry anise
and Funk and also the structure of it
back then it was like appeeling from a
structural like a color structure to me
it was bright orange hairs you know what
I mean and like some people don't like
the hairs because they cover up the
tricomes but it's like that stuff it
didn't matter like I love good Durban
some of those African land race
varieties that we got that were closer
to the land race of what it really was
than these watered down versions I see a
lot of times today MH uh you know the
red congales the Malo and the Durban
those were the three special things that
we kind of saw in the Bay Area I love
all them for different reasons the
Durban was super strong 100% dick in the
dirt but like having having that impact
on someone's life to
like let them reset for the next day or
let them help them get through their day
or that was a motivating factor for me
because like if you ran the gamut back
then the money was
guaranteed yeah you know it's like
theory of doing art or music is like you
do it for the passion you do what you
love yeah and the money will come you
know money's not the first yeah it's a
devotional thing and we talk about on
the show about devotional arts and
cannabis now it's turned into a
devotional thing too like art where you
basically do the best you can you put it
out in the world and if the world loves
it you know you win but either way you
loved creating it right exctly it's it's
a different world now with cannabis
before before it was like pretty much
you could grow mids and you could be
successful now you cannot do that you
cannot grow middle-grade cannabis as a
small producer and expect to be
successful you will fail very difficult
you'll fail extremely hard you know
coming online you think cannabis is
going to be easy money it's not it's
devotional and it's like it takes eating
sleeping and breathing what you're doing
to be successful these days and it's
it's the Beauty and the curse of it
because it's beautiful in some ways some
of these people and and how they're
devoted and some of our friends and how
they're devoted to what they do you know
even Paulie for instance when he was
growing flower in California his flower
was amazing his his Greenhouse flower
that he was doing was as good as a lot
of indoor it was topshelf greenhouse and
it was the genetics it was the way he
grew it the way he harvested it trimmed
it dried it cured it and stored it it's
all those components adding up to this
amazing beautiful product you know and
it's it's great when we have people like
that and it's more motivating for me
being around people that are like that
yeah 100% And you know now it is what it
is and it it has its goods and its bads
and you know we could sit here and
probably complain more now than we could
Applause but you know we're still going
to stay here and we're still going to
push the ball forward and you know at
the end of the day this is this is what
we came here to do so you just got to
see it through yeah you know you just
have to see it through but unfortunately
like life's getting strangely expensive
everywhere and well I don't think it's
actually more expensive I just think the
dollar is worth less than it used to be
yeah either way it goes deeper in your
pocket way price of flour has definitely
gone down and the value of it has gone
down compared to where wood was back in
the day because if you look at the
$4,000 pound for 20 years ago yeah that
would actually you you go 10x on that
that's $40,000 for that same pound yep
maybe not 10x maybe it's five but
$20,000 a pound let's keep it at 10x
let's just crazy right when we when we
start talking like that where they got
$4,000 a pound not only do they get
$4,000 a pound but the dollar was so
much stronger yeah that now that $4,000
a pound is 10 20 30 40 whatever you want
number you want to put it doesn't really
matter it's not even hypothetical we
could probably do the math and come up
with some real factual numbers where
it's like [ __ ] that's crazy because now
that pound that's $300 for that outdoor
if you look at it from years ago that's
only worth like $50 yep yeah $50 from
the '90s or early 2000s right no one was
no one would take $50 for a pound there
was no one selling $50 pounds back in
the day no I mean we live in Wild times
three and a half grams was 50 bucks you
know like they but even for the Mexican
it was like you might get an ounce for
50 bucks if you were lucky it was
typically 100 an ounce for Mexican weed
back 100% cuz the pounds would be like
anywhere from 5 to 8 depending where you
were at on the supply chain so it's like
if you're paying that or maybe it was
cheaper in bulk and SoCal yeah but like
I wasn't trapping when I was 14 sending
Mexican around so I just remember seeing
it on the east coast and in high school
like 160 bucks an ounce you know yeah so
it was like it's never been this low if
you chop it down into numbers price per
gram never been price per gram at
inflation what's so funny though is when
you're deal dealing with real estate
agents and these corporate Jack offs
like out east and you're trying to let's
say secure a facility to build a grow
because for example I got the social
Equity permits in Washington DC I got
the whole vertical integration permits
from the FED case that I went through
right and they're like yeah if you had a
can of charge and you live in DC you
know you can apply so was in town
ironically [ __ ] it let me do it I had a
buddy that had some real estate signed
my name and yeah change the driver's
license filled out the apps next thing
you know I have these permits I'm like
okay let's knock on some doors and see
from a real estate perspective what's
out there and then it'll be like oh yeah
online it says 1750 a square foot what
are you doing in there and I'm like you
we have a cultivation license so we'd
like to build a medical cannabis grow
oh that's fine but the price per square
foot is now 2750 so it's like yeah all
these
people from a corporate standpoint that
are detached from the industry they hear
it and they automatically think that
these guys are printing money you know
we can squeeze them well it's the
Cannabis tax and it's you get taxed on
every level from everybody all over with
you know cannabis hemp whatever all of
it there's always that cannabis plus tax
where it's ridiculous dude it's
ridiculous and it it's lack of knowledge
and again like nobody has released a
documentary or something that at least
shows the world where it started up here
yeah and where it's you know ended at in
today's you know footprint like I think
that there needs to be some sort of
mainstream whether Netflix or whatever
yeah there needs to be something that
shows the truth from Camp all the way
down to now you know
McDonald's documentary what was it not
super high me but the what super me
super siiz me super high me was the good
one though yeah super siiz me yeah
that's funny there's got to be some sort
of of documentation that's shown because
like you can't just let them tell it you
you let them tell it they're never going
to show the guys that really became
Martyrs or or well no but this is the
beauty of podcast we have the
opportunity to hear from so many
different people and get so many
perspectives it's not like it used to be
where one person is telling the history
of the world right or or not even one
person but let's say 20 people have
history books now we have a 100,000
podcasts of different experience right
and
so history is changing in the sense that
we have more history told by more people
so we're getting more perspective on
reality the opportunity is there now to
have all these different stories that
are told from the mouths of people not
second or third or fourth hand stories
yeah
and so that's the beauty of technology I
mean there's a lot of the curse side of
it but I think that's the beauty side of
it and the beauty side of History moving
forward is now we have all the
opportunity to tell our own story in our
own and our own version of the story
yeah and I think that's a beautiful part
before it gets weird and skewed by
somebody else yeah and I mean it's going
to get weird in anyway history's
becoming weird with technology and all
these things and yeah you know I never
thought in my life that I wouldn't be
able to relate to the younger
Generations like the you know the
teenagers because I was I always felt as
I've gotten older that I could relate
and then in the last couple years it's
been interesting because I feel like I
don't relate to the younger kids quite
as much I don't understand you know I
think my parents same thing was like
they didn't understand the work ethic of
Our Generation and my grandparents
didn't understand that because I come
from hardworking people yeah my parents
my grandparents everybody they're
hardworking people and so I heard them
talking about the work ethic well I see
the younger got kids and it's like their
work ethic is much different uh their
focus on stuff is much different yeah I
try not to judge too much you know I try
to just focus on myself but I'm also
observant of what's going on in the
world yeah and I agree you know it's
like they might be able to code you a
whole scenario for an idea that you have
but they couldn't change at Tire to save
the death of them so and not everybody's
like that I mean we're kind of putting
them all in a box but coding is going to
be a thing in the past anyway with AI
you don't have to learn how to code
you'll be able to use AI to code
anything that you want yeah which is
another scary step in the future that
you know it's a little weary like the
thought of removing the human element
from things yeah you know like there's
AI music
like I've seen some sort of inputs and
prompts lead to some sort of output yeah
but it's like dude you're taking away
the idea of the musician like some of
the most artistic influence IAL people
that will be in your life that we grew
up like oh I love the boom you know like
now you be able to make better music
than human music I don't think so but I
don't know but I think that we all have
influence and for AI to have influence
from our influences I mean that there's
a natural progression there it's a
really strange thing there's no AI hris
you know there's no AI Le Zeppelin
there's no a you know but but yet yet
but the brain will get smarter yeah you
know but there's easily
AI dance music AI hip-hop beats AI that
from the way that artistic side of the
world is going it's very easy to be
like okay now go in there and rap on
that and well then where does cannabis
go with AI you know it's like because so
I I can tell you I can tell you with
breeding where it goes where AI does
predictive modeling and so we're to be
able to use predictive modeling from AI
to actually speed up the process of
breeding when we're trying to reach
specific goals and the more data we have
to give it the easier it's going to be
to tell us a path and give us a
successful path for going in the
directions we want to go because what it
can analyze DNA at such a data at such a
fast rate way faster than we could and
you know it's like it can take the
things that we're doing and it
accelerated a lot faster I mean like I
said there's probably good things and
bad things with it in general at point
in my life I hang with my dogs that
don't turn on the TV and I try not to
look at my [ __ ] phone too much so
it's like you know I don't need the
anxiety you know for so many years
living and
working anxiety as the US and in Europe
too right so you've been on it off you
and your wife live out there a little
bit yeah I I met my wife in California
and it was I'd gotten home from the feds
in
2010 and then was back on the hill in
2014 after probation was done and um you
know thanks to Red he brought me right
back on the hill and was like I met my
wife that year and then ended up still
staying in California working until 2018
yeah and at the end of 2018 after that
Harvest I was like all right let's just
go like I'm burnt out
again same [ __ ] different year so I was
just like I I need a break I need like a
a Moment of clarity in my life where
like I can just focus on the things I
love and not you know lose a toe trying
so I did that and in in the back I'm
working on Portugal I'm working on the
cartridge you know still doing some work
out here but popping in popping out you
know and and sleeping standing up on
flights and it was a little gnarly the
first two years to Ping ponging because
it you got to still have it and you
don't want to live like that and it's
rough that yeah it was easy for me to
get visas in Europe cuz it's like
reunification of family and my wife is
there so it wasn't like it's not very
difficult for me to V I had a Visa in
Austria I lived in Austria the
Netherlands Berlin and now I'm outside
of Barcelona nice so now that all this
is coming back and this is done excuse
all this is getting done and I might be
coming back you know and now I'm kind of
driving around here like do I really
want to come back here because like
Spain is so peaceful it's so peaceful
beautiful yeah I love Barcelona
especially the outskirts of Barcelona
it's just so mellow it's it's like a
slower pace of life right even in
Barcelona even though there is like the
faster paced Barcelona life the party
life you know staying out late hanging
out eating good food food's wonderful
yeah I mean but it is a slower pace of
life like the machine doesn't move like
that out there you know so if you're
expecting turnover times of next day
it's not if you want to get [ __ ] done it
just it doesn't move at the same speed
so going there as an American or a
Californian from the bay are and then
going expecting people to do stuff on
your schedule it just doesn't happen no
it's not happening you want to set up a
business it takes a long time to set up
a business in Barcelona it's not easy
and the difference is is if you have
money you can move the needle a lot
faster right so that's one advantage of
going to places like Spain where I feel
like you go in there and you just want
to do stuff like everybody else and but
no if you want to pay a good lawyer that
knows how to maneuver through the system
it's more it's way more expensive but
you can set up business in 6 weeks
whereas it might take you 6 months to a
year or longer if you're just trying to
go through the regular channels and do
stuff like everybody else 100% so
sometimes you know your money is your
shovel as they say they dig your tunnel
you know so in certain places and it's
not like American like leave $100,000 on
my back doorstep it's kind of like a
little bit of money goes a long way
because right if you look at the the
average income and how people live there
and you compare it to here and the
ability to make money yeah it's it's a
completely different animal than America
and you know I'm hearing a lot of talk
about Americans that's the promised land
yeah we're done here well the side
hustle was invented in Spain I feel like
everybody I know from Spain has a side
hustle of some form you know what I mean
everybody does some alternative form of
work to to make money and yeah you know
so they they do know how to work they
just work at a different pace and a
different speed and they're way more
relaxed they also value different things
in life more than we value so and I'm
not saying like us personally me and you
but it's it's like you know there's the
money is your god and then there's the
money is cool but life is cooler yeah
there's that whole social life that
everybody has out there that I think is
missing from a lot of people and I think
that's something that we probably
absorbed from our friends that spent
time in Europe originally and then
spending time in Europe ourselves we
really kind of fell uh you know we felt
aligned to that kind of Lifestyle yeah
and I mean I still am a workaholic I
still work my ass off but I also have
that need need for a social life need
for friends I still go hang out at
friends on the weekends and we cook and
we do fun stuff you know keep a life
Balanced Life you know it is a there I
mean I I wouldn't say I have a balanced
life even close but I still treasure
those experiences with my friends where
we can do stuff I mean I I would say
that there is no work life balance for
me but I still enjoy I have great
friends and my friends have we have
great experiences we still eat great
food we don't drink nearly as much as we
used to so we remember stuff more yeah
we don't do as much stupid [ __ ] as we
used to I feel like that's always good
but all that stupid drinking [ __ ] crazy
left right up down yeah all that's what
creates the memories that you know well
it was great when we were younger to do
that kind of stuff and you know it's
like I think you're right that it does
create the memories we had some really
good times you know 100% now it's just
you know it's I talked to to Paulie
about it and and a couple other guys
about like how just that that October
November uh I guess what did the kids
say now the vibe that was in the air in
California back in the day it was like
just that energy yeah it was it was
something that you looked forward to
every year it's like it was great and
then now it's kind of like October
November's here but that energy is not
the same we're also not the same as we
were when we were younger we don't have
the energy you know we got gray hair now
my gray hair I don't grow a beard out
because I talk me in at 10 p.m. dude you
know what I mean like I'm tired so I
like my sleep now and I used to think it
was great to not get sleep I thought you
know I was tough for for being able to
suck it up and get a five hour night of
sleep and then back at it in the morning
yeah back at it and just work through
you know power through the day and you
know and there is some value to that
when the time is right and you need to
do that but I think we need a value
sleep and rest and exercise and those
things are super important there's
they're just as important as making
money and success I feel like it is
health is wealth so I feel like there is
that level of success where you can be
uh exercising you can afford to eat
right and all those things I mean that's
success in my opinion too yeah and um
just back to uh this thing for a second
so what we were thinking about doing to
kind of bring this to Market not
necessarily is just our brand yeah so it
makes a collaboration we thinking about
a lot of collaborations genetics guys
right guys that specifically focus on
genetics okay cool throw this out throw
your name on The Box profit share with
you simple right then you've got other
extractors yeah if they're using our sop
Etc you partner with that you partner
with guys that are like-minded
individuals that look at this as a value
ad to their
portfolio and you bring it to Market I
remember meeting uh I was in I was in
Barcelona and you know one guy that I
think uh is like definitely a Bay Area
uh Oldtimer like us is p and Shan Pell
transplant yeah yeah but for sure P's
like San Francisco now but he was
originally San Francisco he's done
Europe he's done Mexico yeah he's the
man so it's like me and him started
talking and and I had never spoken to
him before but it was comfortable
talking to a guy that had lived that
same eras that we lived and he he'd been
out here so it's like you know the The
Nostalgia was the same and I brought it
to him and once it was done and I was
you know a little skeptical about what
he was going to say because I know that
he's he's got a pretty high filter yeah
and he tried it out and was just like
whoa so let me try it out speaking of
which huh you want to try it out fire it
out let's go load tpine first or no high
turpine first low thca okay and then
we'll we'll slowly uh get it stronger I
want to taste the turps though I want to
see what straight turps basically or low
uh low canabo high turps taste like that
was the holy water back in the day that
we used to get
was uh super super high
turps I've been smelling it a little bit
too and I'm like smells good all right
so part of the tech that we have the
brain cools the coil down yeah and
forces the user to wait and locks them
out so you're not overcooking everything
and now you just hold this button down
yeah hold on so you're not destroying
volatile
compound and
so what are we smoking what flavor is
that blue dream that's a blue dream
tastes like blue dream yeah it's frozen
Frozen Turf Blue Dream Live resin or
live excuse me Blue Dream fresh
frozen too hot so I just got to wait you
just wait and then as that diamond fills
up the coils cool down to a to a
temperature where and so what
concentration are we smoking right now
is this like about
50/50 EMP for you guys that's really
good yeah that's really good I feel like
uh the flavor is there
good job on the Blue Dream you really
captured the the essence of Blue Dream I
feel
like I was looking at my frozan options
um from one of my buddy's farms and I
was like you know
what I'm going to go with trusty dream
nice and like back to that whole T
mixing thing there's a scenario in which
you might do extractions where you're
getting the candy you're getting the
fruits you're getting you're getting the
the orange the lemon the Cherry the
grape but you want to you know you want
it to have a little bit of gas okay you
blow 10% of OG in there or sour or glue
yeah and now you have a gasier version
of that
turp nice so that's that's the beauty in
that cocktail turp sort of thing yeah I
mean I like the wine maker model where
you can add a little bit of gas to it
you could add a little bit of candy to
it you can change it and if you like
then you can get real creative like the
wine maker would for their brand you
know it's like I see that happening with
rosin a little bit and I think that it's
only going to get bigger and bigger the
the cocktail the blending of the stuff
uh but also blending of cannabinoids and
you could totally blend isolates too
yeah 100% And like you could in theory
throw CBD CBG diamonds in there and CB
question mark diamonds in there whatever
you wanted to to do from an isolation
standpoint right and can Turin so you
see like what was that one company they
used to do a lot of those formul Papas
and Barkley or something like that so
it's like you can kind of do that same
formulation with this if you wanted to
have a CBD to THC sort of because the
the tpine always is roughly around 45 to
50% thca in it because once you
start moving more of that thca and
getting higher concentration of Tarpin
it's a little too floral it's a little
too much can you do that with the pen
what do you mean like so let's say I
want to do 10% thca and 100%
tpin or 90% tpin because I guess it
would be a blend right so we're looking
at that ratio if I wanted to do super
low to where it doesn't get you high but
I wanted that floral crazy Co covers
your mouth with turps or does it not t
it doesn't hit right if you add
10% that's a little low I don't think
you're going to make it to a to a a
ratio of that even at its lowest but
you're just smoking turps or you you
won't even hit at 10% I don't know how
to override the system to even get that
low I don't I don't there's not like a
the UI is the UI so it's like you can't
lower it past the point of a failure
point oh okay so basically there's a
window of of Watts you're throwing at
each side and that's the difference in
the intensity you're not changing
temperatures right you're not you're
only changing power so can you smoke
just pure thca out of that with no
turps or is that like let's say you
didn't want to smell you're going to
work you don't want to smell like
anything you definitely don't if you're
smoking pure thca you're a [ __ ]
Soldier cuz that ain't going to T this
is going to be rough dude it should be
really harsh going be rough dude like
you know you you drink your [ __ ]
whiskey warm and in a [ __ ] porta
potty you know I mean like you're a
tough dude sign this guy up but
unfiltered cigarettes
yeah remember the camel ones the no
filter camel like those guys those guys
were the Renegades yeah but yeah I mean
we'll see how it goes you know maybe the
hopefully the industry will accept it
and adapt to it and I mean I think it's
a great direction to go in if nothing
else it's a great Direction and it's
it's Innovative I think that the
potential is cool and you know so you
said something that kind of resonated
with me a little bit was like so do you
want to have 13 pens just sitting in
home and it's like yeah if you look in
my I have a pen holder for my pens I
probably have 13 or 14 pens in there
with all different flavors and I don't
smoke them all and a lot of them are
Rosen carts so Rosen carts have a shelf
life I'm probably not smoking them all
before they aren't at their peak level
yeah and so this would be an interesting
thing uh I mean I see it as something
that has a lot of value potentially and
I love Innovation my man so yeah so uh
as far as Portugal let's talk a little
bit about Portugal we've kind of been
talking about Portugal ever since you
were first starting to get your license
over there how is the scene over in
Portugal Portugal is pretty quiet you
know it it's just desirable because of
where it's at on the a map yeah and the
cost to operate very cheap there in
comparison to here was good soil good
water good summers in the South Long
Summers in the south South yeah good
surfing good surfing um you can kind of
grow 11 weers there comfortably in the
South yeah they'll finish out wow that's
awesome yeah I mean with climate change
or whatever the [ __ ] is happening in
this world like that's starting to to
maybe change a little bit like some
years there it didn't rain at all so was
like come November it's normally like
end of November it should be fairly
rainy yeah it wasn't raining and this
year rained a little bit earlier than
you'd expect so I'm watching I'm like
what the [ __ ] they allow for the
medicinal cultivation for the EU right
and so they're a big Hub too for other
countries importing I've heard yeah I
mean Germany does a lot of damage if you
look at you know the numbers Germany
does a lot of medicinal importing and
then now with the social club scenario
and the the barrier to entry in Europe
being GMP facilities and all the rules
that go on with flower and stability
testing and yeah it's set up from a
pharmaceutical standpoint as a
filtration point to keep a specific
Financial class out of it yeah and if
you look at it a lot of it seems asinine
and like why would you [ __ ] need to
do this and it's like why are they doing
this because this 100 lighter is going
to cost you $4 million yeah you know so
let's make this a little bit more
difficult of a club to get into and they
did it but now seeing Germany go the way
it's going I mean we both know where
Spain's at you know yeah I get sometimes
when like people see what's going on in
some of the wck weed States and they're
like what every block here smells like
weed now everyone's just [ __ ]
flooding the city smoking yeah and I
could see like that in Europe would
probably get push back the Europe
government well look at Spain in 2014 it
was kind of wide open you rolling joints
in front [ __ ] restaurants and now you
do not do that stuff in Barcelona you
know and it's it's changed so much
because I remember rolling my joint up
that I was going to smoke after dinner
at the dinner table at a restaurant and
you know I think people got kind of sick
of it to a degree and the government
definitely pushed back and was like no
this ain't gonna happen here guys yeah
especially you Americans 100% I think
Europe has legs yeah I think Europe is
definitely a place where the industry
will will eventually expand to um from a
Rec standpoint yeah not necessarily the
gray area social club stuff yeah but
again it's
like everybody is looking for the new
America and I think after living there
for so long and you and I both know it's
like they just don't consume cannabis
the way Americans
do no they consume hash Bingo but it's
from a concentrated form right right and
they still want American genetics they
still want a lot of the
American principles when it comes to
weed they want the West Coast genetics
and the West Coast what the Cali weed
right or whatever the Cali weed the Cali
genetics all that stuff but they smoke a
lot more hash than anything there's
thaton of super market for sure all
around the world there's this
connoisseur Market that wants that West
Coast
style product but a lot of Europeans
still smoke hash 100% And just I think
from a volume play if you're just
looking at just gross volume in flour to
consumption levels per person spread
across the EU and you compared it to
America it'd be a scary number because
there's guys out there that smoke five
four gram blunts a day you know
and it's do I think it's overc
consumed um when you see the popular
aspect being the the cannaboid content
the potency yeah as being as what makes
all these people hype this shit's 34% T
yeah we're going to get [ __ ] high
most New Yorkers I
know they don't want it if it doesn't
get them [ __ ] Stone stoned that's why
Sour Diesel was popular that's why the
first time my friend from New York had
glue he called me and he was like this
is it this is it and when I smoke glue I
was like this shit's too Stony like I
can't operate my day under this [ __ ]
strain it ain't going to happen but he's
like n this is the one he man we're this
is what they want so I was surprised the
piff got so popular out there be because
it's not as strong as some of the other
things piff is cool though I like piff I
love piff yeah I love piff and I I like
I like the hazes because they're rare
now and there's some guys trying to you
know bring them back and I I've seen
some stuff but it's like you know
everything's been thrown to the Wolves
it's hard to get some of the old strains
that that we grew up on and stuff that
really moved the needle for us like
let's talk about those for a minute I'm
sure people are excited to hear about
the old genetics that we used to have
around uh and some of them didn't even
have names I mean you go far back enough
it wasn't all
about the specific genetics it was all
about you know it was green butter it
was you know especially if you're were
buying stuff it was like oh you want
this [ __ ] it it was top shelf or
brown butt a lot of times and it was
never called top shelf really it was it
was uh we had all kinds of names [ __ ] y
[ __ ] oh God the [ __ ] yeah the crippler
we had the [ __ ] the crippler there was
always funny names for stuff but also I
mean there was some strain names but
like it wasn't always associated with
the
genetics first time I saw [ __ ] my buddy
came back from Florida and he was
visiting his sister and she was in
college there and he came back with 2
ounces yeah we were taking the nugs and
we threw it at the wall and it just
stuck so sticky and we were like oh God
and then my first introduction into
California you know the I never ever
ended up with anything from Canada at
that though during those years yeah that
like I even have a a memory of right so
it's
like my graduation to Northern
California in 2000ish like I have a
broad memory mhm of coming here and
like whoa yeah the Honeydew hay the
Madusa Mist lavender pers granddaddy
yeah the real Cali Mist I real
C I really missed that one yeah you know
it was bright it was like a cute it made
me it feel like drinking one of these
[ __ ] cucumber drinks in the
summertime on a boat was like smoking
the Mist
nice it's all gone now so I I'm just
glad still there we just don't see it as
often and I think there's no one growing
it in bulk that I know of I know seeds
are still available Simon still sells C
Miss seeds okay and so I know it's still
available I don't see a lot of people
growing it and maybe the appeal isn't
maybe people don't understand the appeal
until they try it and maybe it needs to
make its rounds again you know you know
the original cat piss that was weird
that was the one that was the one there
was nothing better than cat piss in its
day it's like whatever you think the
best thing is now cat piss was that and
then some yeah and it was just so much
different than everything else that was
around and one little small piece would
make your whole car your
clothes your whole room would smell like
it and the smoke was distinct catpiss
smell you could smell it you be like
[ __ ] they're smoking cat
piss um yeah that was that was the best
I mean that was really the Exotic of its
day and it was 60 bucks an a straight up
didn't matter how many you bought it was
top top top yeah price
and AF was good yeah you know super
silver goo we had the afo
yeah AF guy that was a good one uh the
aota was all of the above that aota
coming down was aota had hella red hair
right I think the aota that I smoke
didn't have it was it was bright and
green and and super it was pretty Frosty
not as Frosty as like the AFU I remember
seeing a jar of aota that was just
like insane red hair nice again that was
a that was a drunken night in Humble
those years were like semi a blur you
know but yeah there was the Hassan that
was like uh yeah there was the Hassan
that was a good one from my boy Josh
Freeman pink cream Jasmine soda was
another one I if you remember that not a
lot of people do I got that cut from
Josh and that was like the it was the
early finisher of its day it never got
to be big tall plants but it finished
early and in the Bay Area you wanted
something Lally along with all the other
stuff you grew because of all the damage
that you would get from caterpillars
yeah and it never got caterpillars on it
it was one of those was like resistant
to caterpillars I wonder if the turps
just kept them off of it I think it
finished so early the caterpillars just
didn't have time to do any damage ah
gotcha the season yeah yeah you know
those are the days when you know
hopefully the stuff that's coming up for
the future is as
remarkable it has the potential there's
still dude humble is filled with
passionate people still yeah that will
just grow weed for themselves if nothing
else still right that they don't care I
mean obviously care about money but they
care more about the flour and the weed
and yeah there's companies doing it too
I feel like there's some good companies
doing it up there that are pushing the
limits you know it's like we got
Ridgeline Farms we got Johnny from
Huckleberry Hill yeah uh you know Jason
and Johnny those guys are a pair they
but they do some good stuff some of
their breeding stuff is good that white
Thorn Rose Johnny kind of got on the map
for that but I feel like that's just
that's just the beginning of all the
stuff that he can really bring to the
table yeah yeah and then Ridgeline has
the Lance or something like that the
Lance yeah that's a good one Ridgeline
runs Jason's doing some good stuff and
he's just a good person I they were on
the show yeah they're they're good guys
and you know it's like uh they're
devoted to the plant too we talk about
devotion those guys are devoted to the
plant there's a Dave from budalo he's up
in Menin up in Yukaya he's the sour
diesel guy now I found the new Sour
Diesel guy he is the sour diesel guy but
he's also the long flowering variety guy
so he does those long flowering ones
that just have amazing effect right he
breeds specifically for effect they're
growing specifically for effect uh and
there's so many other guys that I'm not
even naming right now but there's guys
that are still just so passionate and
still trying to move the needle trying
to bring back genetics trying to create
new new genetics you know and we need
all that the industry needs all that we
need all that passion infused into the
genetics uh and you know I think the
future is bright in a lot of ways I
think a lot of people look down on the
future they're worried about the future
but I think in a lot of ways the
future's still bright we still have a
lot of potential there's still plenty to
be uh innovated you know there's a lot
of innovation still uh that can can be
had in this industry whether it's lights
whether it's extract whether it's you
know genetics substrate it doesn't
matter there's so many things that still
need to be explored and I'm just excited
for the future you know constantly being
exciting constantly being Amazed by the
stuff people around me are doing it's
happy to be here yeah I mean and I'm
just exactly I'm just H I'm along for
the ride in some ways I'm super happy
it's
like with the breeding book it was like
this big Challenge and once I've
finished it it's like okay what's next
for me what are we going to do next with
the book so every couple years every you
know probably every few years we're
going to do a new release on the
breeding book and update the information
and the beauty of Technology we can put
the supplemental stuff in there uh
online and then as we create this stuff
online we can Infuse it into a new book
that's cool that's cool so just kind of
keeping a Tim stamp and moving it
forward you know yeah and and constantly
trying to move the needle forward with
everything that we do so I mean this
facility we're we're trying to do the
best we can do and uh make a difference
and I'm out there working in St Vincent
the gred with some farmers and with the
government the MCA out there the medical
cannabis Authority uh so I'm excited
about the future I'm excited about other
people's podcast too there's a lot of
good podcasts out there yeah um but yeah
so if you had one piece of advice for
your younger self or how about we're
gonna switch this up today all right you
had one piece of advice for our group of
friends and their younger selves what
would that one piece of advice be the
big
fault I've seen from a lot of successful
guys from our era they never save their
money because they felt that this would
never go away yeah and it's painful the
war stories when you get the phone calls
and stuff like it sucks because again
their hearts in it but you saw
in call
it 10 years things from 14 to now yeah
when I was back on that Hill from that
Harvest to
now if you calculate the cost drop like
you're saying like that's substantial
it's almost not sustainable for a farmer
right so okay you're Frugal farmer
you've been saving your
money you understood that there was you
know a possibility of this happening
happening because of Agriculture you
it's walking a path that has been walked
before yeah
you can pivot you can do something else
people build families and people have
children yeah you know there there's
real human beings behind this so the
stories are are painful to hear because
they've been doing this for so long and
we respect them and then now it's kind
of like I don't know what to do yeah and
my thing is like not going to change the
devotion that people have because that's
always been there yeah but if you could
change the essentially the Financial
structure of how they spent and what
they save for because like if you knew
if a little bird flew down and told you
hey 2024 this is going to be the ticket
for a
unit you approach it a little bit
differently but sometimes people just
have Blind Faith in things and I get it
like yeah it's a it's a trait know but
that would be it because you know I I
still think the industry is in decent
hands you know I still think for sure
hands but it's like it would be in
more decent hands
if the finances were different yeah
that's just my take on it because I
don't think that there was a whole lot
of fuckups in the you know where we're
at in flower now where we're at in Tech
now and where we're at in the [ __ ]
pushed the plant forward if anything and
pushed us forward you know it's like I
think we all [ __ ] up to a degree we
all had our fuckups and you know it's
like a lot of them were good learning
experiences for all of us you know it's
like we didn't lose too many
friends from violence luckily yeah you
know I think we we may have lost some
friends getting locked up and we may
have caught cases and stuff like that
but a lot of those were good learning
experiences on what not to [ __ ] do
yeah so yeah I think you know we're
we're probably pretty blessed to have
the friends we have and to have the
experiences that we were blessed to have
um you know and that's made us who we
are I wouldn't take any of those
experiences back the good ones the bad
ones I mean unfortunately you know I
think they're all good learning
experiences if nothing else 100% wild
wild stories you know stories that I
can't even talk about on yeah camera but
it's like they've made me who I am today
and made me appreciate what we have
which is pretty special yeah 100% and
and
you know we kept doing it before yeah we
got locked up and then we came back and
just did it legally yeah when we got out
whether it was the medical the 215 days
up until now so it's like when we were
back in this and it was like okay well
we can be above ground
now we don't really got to worry too
much about them so we we had friends
that got kicked out of the country for
for uh yeah for for cases that you know
serving sentences and then getting
kicked out of the country and never
allowed back in the United States you
know it's wild yeah my my S got deported
back to Haiti after I think 18 years you
know so well one of our mutual friends
uh got deported to Italy oh yeah which
he was born in Italy had never really
lived in Italy you know his parents had
passed and everything else and uh you
know wandered Europe for and figured it
out you he's the man love that guy but
uh yeah over a case a non-violent drug
offense so yeah I mean this world is
kind of
crazy but I think we're also starting to
recognize to a degree that that cannabis
especially isn't bad cannabis isn't the
enemy it makes the world a better place
100 per. so yeah so if people are
looking to find more about male where
would they go oh man um
for the company yeah uh we've got
everything coming online now there'll be
the website which is
www.ts T pz. comom
the Instagram is rare turps at rare
turps
tpz and I don't think we have a Twitter
set up yet we're just like really at the
point of like we've got all these story
boards from an animator that I work with
and it kind of explains all the aspects
of the cart there's a tutorial for it
you know when you um when you purchase
it you'll scan a QR code and that will
lead you to how to use it yeah so
everything's kind of getting finalized
and brought to life now taking meetings
just figuring out distribution making
sure that you know the stakes are high
these days like yeah it costs a lot of
money to come bring your your little toy
into the market you know so it's like
you got to you got to you got to do this
more calculated and less Cavalier nice
so everything's getting buttoned up to a
point that we're going to push forward
correctly and make sure that there's no
like loose ends or or open knots when we
do come to Market I would think could I
push to come to Market within like the
next 90 to 120 days yeah and that could
still happen because obviously there's a
lot of Frozen coming down now yeah
there's going to be a lot of Frozen and
freezers but I think our big hello how
are you um is going to be at the end of
next year when we're pulling down our
acreage and really nice got things in
line so let I'm G to definitely take
some of your genetics and put that out
in that field absolutely and get the
James Jungle Juice oh yeah I'm down I
think that's a you know I'd love to
collaborate on some level and that
sounds great bring more of this Mexican
moonshine when you do that was amazing
it's pretty good right special 100% you
know when we're chasing flavors that's
one of flavors I chase I love that
flavor and it's like so smooth thing is
it's Hunter prooof right and so like
Hunter prooof and smooth and people
don't understand what that means it
means you start drinking it with your
friends you're sitting around a table
drinking it next thing you know the
bottle's gone with four people and you
don't feel like you're you've had a
great time talking to your friends but
then you stand up you're like I got to
sit back down that's 100 Proof yeah it's
100 proof and it's super
smooth but uh yeah and that's just
amazing it didn't taste like 100 Proof
that's how smooth that's yeah it's it
was special right well next time 100%
fantastic well thank you so much for
coming on the show thank you for I look
forward to seeing you over in Europe I
know you'll be at spannabis you'll be at
hopefully at Mary
janein that's in Berlin yeah yeah yeah I
if I'm not here I'll be there but if I'm
not there then I'll be here so you know
I might have to come back to get this
thing into traffic so for sure well
thank you for having me absolutely have
a good one
thank you guys for watching please like
And subscribe down below