[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James loud
podcast today our special guest is
Freddy big from planta and SF Cana how
are you doing today I'm doing well man I
appreciate you having me on you thank
you so much for coming on the show we
had Chris uh couple episodes ago he got
me too lit he got too lit we were so
high typical typical Canabis Chris
typical canis Chris for sure tell us how
you get started in the industry smoked a
lot of weed no I think an avid smoker I
was an avid Avid smoker that's uh yeah
how I got into the industry and I will
say that like I am pretty passionate
about cannabis I I do love it and I am
and it has been a large portion of my
life for a very long time so when did
you start smoking I feel like I started
smoking very young very young but I
started smoking like
consistently like around 20 I started
being I feel like a real smoker you know
I feel like I kind of [ __ ] with it in
my younger ages but like by the time I
was 20 we were smoking we were smoking
you were't to martial arts wrestling you
fought MMA I heard yeah I fought 71 as a
pro uh so yeah I competed in mixed
martial arts I wrestled in high school I
was high school American so yeah I did
play spend a lot of time playing sports
and with in athletics and smoking in uh
training you know what when I was
training I well when I trained for
wrestling I didn't really smoke that
much I don't know if it was the stigma
but I didn't even though I knew did know
some people that did smoke and have good
success but when I was fighting I was
smoking a lot for sure
for sure yeah that's the way to do it
the Diaz brothers kind of showed us all
the way they smoke a lot they smoke a
lot they smoke a lot bro I will say Nick
and Nate those are those are some
certified smokers and yes I love I love
training with nateas I know some gyms
don't really care for you smoking like
the Diaz Academy you know put out your
joint before you get on the mat you know
what I mean it's pretty chill about it
so yeah I did dig that yeah I train with
CJ laque right now yo CJ he's East I
know bro yeah for sure
heavyweight he's a super heavyweight now
he's 315 what I think he went to Liberty
maybe something like that yeah I know
bro for sure yeah he's a good guy so
yeah we train really good dude he
knock he knocked people out he knocked a
couple decent people out yeah for sure
and and he hits hard so big big de pass
for that guy yeah he's a big guy he's a
big guy he's he's fun to train with
though I bet I bet so yeah he does a lot
of GJ like the fight Community is a
small community small Titan community
somebody fight you know I got a lot of
respect for anybody who has the audacity
to put it all on the line and get in
there you know so totally yeah I mean I
trained Dragon House 20 years ago Dragon
House Frisco what Zang what his
name yeah okay zong is a character zong
is a character indeed Dragon House
they've been putting on cool events in
the city Keys our Pavilion y yeah I've
been to a couple in there for sure yeah
his school back in the day was uh a lot
different than it is now it wasn't M it
was kung fu but Mar was about a lot
different back then a lot different a
lot different back then for sure but
yeah San Francisco smoking weed you
always used to be able to smoke in San
Francisco on the street it was never an
issue San Francisco I feel like you know
I lived in San Francisco in my early 20s
and I feel like as far as like embracing
cannabis no City embraced cannabis as
early and as much as San Francisco you
know what I mean it was one of the first
places where it was accepted to walk
down the street smoking weed I feel like
a lot of other places you know people
were worried about going to jail for
smoking weed in San Francisco walking
past cop smoking no problem no problem
so I feel like San Francisco has been
brace cannabis for such a long time yeah
for such a long time yeah I remember
Blowfish Sushi back day we used to drive
out to Blowfish and smoke on the on the
Stoops and then wait wait for a our
reservation no big deal no big deal no
big deal you know just smoking peace
yeah totally are peaceful totally
they're not killing people they're
killing cheeseburgers exactly I feel
like there's no harm no bad Intent no
problem yeah so tell me your earliest
memory of uh good weed you know I feel
like one of my really good childhood
friends my brother was was the weed
dealer uh when I was younger in high
school and he was the guy who had it you
know what I mean um so I was around some
really good weed and I feel like yeah as
far as like my friend Circle my peer
group uh one of my best friends had the
had had the best weed and was was the
guy you know what I mean was the was the
weed guy for a long time yeah and that
was a different era you know what I mean
yeah that dude went to prison for 6
ounces like that uh that was a different
era completely different world back
right I feel like you know these new age
Trappers got a little soft like it was
it was big penalty of going to jail
before when we were doing it it was a
lot riskier it was a lot RIS scary times
for
sure we had pagers we didn't have all
the access that's hella funny someone
was just talking about pagers I'm like I
don't think I ever trapped off a pagro
I'm like I'm old but not that old I I
never trapped off the pagers yeah I'm 47
so I mean there was codes you didn't
even you know it it was a wild wild for
sure so you grew up in the Bay Area then
I did I grew up uh I grew up in
Fairfield California oh nice yeah you
ever see ciss I did of course of course
the legendary ciss for sure it's a big
topic on this show really it's my
favorite super dense it was like that
super dense yeah had a like almost a
yellowish tone to it definitely wreaked
like ammonia yeah ammonia you know and I
think there's multiple cat pisses we
talk about it all the time but right I
feel like there was anything with amonia
was ciss the Bay Area ciss was like I
feel like that was the East Bay thing
too I feel like cat piss was very very
East Bish you know what I mean in San
Francisco we didn't we didn't get the we
didn't get the piss as tough but I I go
to the town and Oakland everybody had
the piss that was like one of the first
real zah you know I mean that was exotic
you had the piss that was the [ __ ] oh
yeah the champelli and the piss the P
like that was that yeah that was that
old school Z well and that's the one
that
really made me fall in love with weed
was the cap his because you could smoke
it down to the roach you could fire it
up the next day $60 an e back then was a
lot of money that'd be like over 100 a
day for sure right but uh it was totally
it was that Stony indicia it was that
stare at your shoe Aces type Indica
Strong high and it could get you high if
you smoked it any time of the day and
night didn't matter didn't matter what
your tolerance was it was strong strong
strong what do you think the lineage on
that was uh Northern Lights times Super
Silver times skunk interesting but it's
it's long gone so remaking it you know
that's gonna be we're doing a
documentary this year on it and uh we're
working on versions of cat piss and
stuff like that right a lot of those
versions are lost they're lost you're
not getting those back you're not
getting those back but along the way you
might find something better and that's
kind of what we're trying to explain I
would say you might find something
better for sure yeah or different or
different it's hard to say something's
better than something it's hard to say
something's better CU at the end of the
day it's a matter of opinion it's like a
zetopia better than Skittles or Skittles
better than zetopia depends who Mark
markets it better who grew it depends
who grew it who grew it has a large
portion of the conversation I think some
some really legendary strains have uh
lost their Allure because they've been
grown by poor Growers well Skittles is
one of those ones that people struggle
to grow good Skittles there's a handful
of people that can grow good Skittles
and that's
it it's not even the one% of it I
wouldn't even say yeah it's such a it's
such a Fickle plant and the Skittles
Market is such a Fickle Market Market
it's such a unique such a unique odity
you know so I think that it still sells
in its green I mean it's not gelato it's
not the bud structure is not there it
doesn't have color it's it doesn't uh
it's not along the lines of any other
contemporary strains it's it's totally
unique it's totally unique and I was
like I was blessed to have Skittles 2017
I think is when I started getting
skittles from a a grower from humbold
who had the who had the real yeah the
real Candy tardy Skittles cut so yeah I
tried it around June 10th of I I don't
remember exactly of 2014 was the first
time I tried it to the cup it's super
distinct super distinct you know
obviously like you know it's crazy I
remember I see the the grower was really
proud of the weed I was like I don't
know I looked at it it smelled great I
was like maybe a B+ and the grower was
very
offended and I was like he's like you
got smoke it and I'm
like well we's smoke it right and I will
say this I hit the joint and it had
intense flavor it was super unique and I
was like wow this is really unique the
flavor on this is really really special
really special and the high was intense
and I was like okay this might be
something the bag appeal was definitely
not there though bag no it doesn't have
the bag ofel does not have the bag ofel
a lot of everybody you know you guys
have Skittles is sticky a lot of people
don't have SK Skittles is sticky it's
dry it has like a dry talking about the
SF can group we do a lot of things not
other people are able to do yeah for
sure I will say those dudes the SF Cana
cultivation team is a really talented
team that uh has a lot of diverse skills
yes they can grow Skittles they can grow
candies they can grow cookies I feel
like and they can grow in different
mediums they can grow in different
lighting I feel like those dudes are are
are really great at their craft really
great at their craft they do a lot of
things that most people can't do and the
yield on they're getting on the Skittles
is crazy the yield it's crazy crazy the
yield the quality like that's a [ __ ]
people don't believe I'm like I don't
know I seen it yeah you know so getting
three pounds plus a liers on Skittles is
is unheard of but it's like and doing it
at scale and doing it at scale it's rare
we don't do it little we don't do a
little no and it's like the quality most
people when they grow a small scale they
can get quality like that but once you
scale up past 100 lights or press 500 or
a, lights it's really it's level to the
[ __ ] man it's definitely it definitely
level to the [ __ ] and I feel like that's
why I was on a past thing I was talking
about you know there's small Growers
with with big egos there's small Growers
who have under you know smaller canopies
and they have it dialed in and then they
feel like they're great at their craft
but then there's other teams that are
doing it over a large scale which makes
it a totally uh it's a different level
it's a different level and to be able to
be able to uh get quality at larger
scales is is is you know a skill not
many many groups are capable of right so
what's your favorite uh thing to smoke
right now what are we smoking we're
smoking 11 coffins right now nice that's
good um this was a 400 seed hunt um
planted cannabis company La based
cannabis company that I'm uh partnered
with uh I think the cultivator is
amazing and I think that uh he's
dedicated a lot of space to finding new
flavors and new fenos um we've been
popping around 200 seeds a month this SE
this was a 500 seed SE hunt 400 of which
was this uh rs11 Cross of coffin County
um it was bred by Duke of verb Duke of
DOA um really close friend of mine Rusty
uh so it was a large seat hunt and you
know it's hard to feno hunt you know I'm
the pallet and I get to you know help
select so it's hard to select that many
I I can't remember what the total was
but I know it
was man it might have been 70 70 to to
assess you know I feel like the
cultivator grows out 400 seeds x amount
are going to be male x amount of plants
aren't like are going to get crossed out
and then you get uh a sample of the ones
that are viable viable you know Keepers
right so I don't remember how many it
was but it was a lot it's a lot and I
feel like you have to do it in a time we
pass fashion because you know the
cultivator is is devoting space to
keeping all these plants alive so you
know the 70 or whatever fenos you have
so you have to get through them in a
timely manner I feel like you can only
smoke and fairly assess so many before
your pallet gets burnt out you know so
it was uh pallet fatigue say like I
would like to say it's a rough job but
like smoking like a ton of new flavors
all week long isn't isn't the worst job
ever you know what I mean so but and and
this was actually number 178 you know
you see a lot of uh strains are like
number four or number seven so this is
uh this is we call it 11 coffins and
this is number 178 out of 400 wow and
this one right here it's really dope
when you see all the fenos cuz you see
different representations you see
different characteristics get to come
out this one right here had the the rs11
that ozk gas it had an even balance of
the gas and the candy from the coffin
candy because coffin candy is another
strain that's unique to us but it's like
a complex candy um the 11 coffins yet
had an even balance of the you could
taste the rs11 type gas you could taste
the candy and I think that like strains
that do well blend things people are
familiar with you know so and I think
people want candy gas and I think this
is really a true candy gas it's sweet
it's gassy it's uh it's really complex
it's got some different texture and
layers um so I like this one a lot I
like this one a lot we also have a uh
Skittles back cross but it's it's
Skittles backcross the Skittles back
cross to a strain called strawberry
scholato which is a Skol which is
Skittles by gelato by a strawberry
diesel coffin cut I don't know if you're
familiar with coffin cut but uh tast so
it's like a triple layer Z it's like a
triple Z that we've uh that's probably
the new strain that I'm most excited
about we also did an afternoon pineapple
which is a a sativa dominant that had
actual pineapple flavor cross that to
run so it's a candy gas but it's like a
hazy like it's like a hazy gas I would
like to say a more sativa I would to say
it tastes like pineapple but it has a
hazy sativa gas mixed with candy I think
I'm really excited for that one as well
nice what do you think about
sativas wouldn't be my first choice I
wouldn't say it be my first choice I
think that uh and I don't think that
it's really hard to see a true
representation of any of the you know
the sativa Indica labels it's hard to
see like real true definitions that
aren't hybrids so I would say that
there's like sativa leaning plants that
I would
say probably not my favorite probably
not my favorite but I haven't seen like
a really true ah maybe a little bit I've
seen some Nim snacks is a new strain
that's like that's like has a hazy type
Vibe I think
that that is definitely sativa leaning
that I that I really enjoyed it was
grown by Humble harvest in Sacramento um
they uh yeah they were growing this
nimma snacks and it had like a hazy
sativ gas but it was burning super clean
Super flavorful that I mean but I don't
think it would it would be my first
choice yeah you remember the super
silver back in the back in the day in
San Francisco I'm very familiar with
super silver I was working with a group
I was getting a bunch of super Silvers
from from a group that's like a 13
weeker or something huh that's like a
really really a longer flower it's a
longer flowering there shorter flowering
versions of it but the yeah the one that
was going around uh I think the dudes I
was working with a group out of Pacifica
a long time ago and they were growing
Super Silver and I think it was 13 weeks
yeah that [ __ ] takes forever when you're
waiting for it so that's like 15 weeks
before batch to batch you know what I
mean 16 weeks back batch to batch out of
like a house grow that [ __ ] yeah I did
work with a group that had the super
silver I I I I like that strain I like
that strain would it be but I don't
think it would like be
tops as far as what my pette prefers
yeah and customers these days I mean I
guess if you had good super silver
anything will sell you know if it's good
if it's premum I feel like anything that
is grown to really good quality will
sell except for Jacka rare right now so
I feel
like I feel like some of the he kids
showed me the new cool [ __ ] and I'm like
this is Jack and I feel like some groups
I think uh lumpies has an apple strain
but it it it's Jack Vibes to me and I
see and will say that like yeah a couple
people was like this is the new hot [ __ ]
and I'm like this is Jack bro this is
Jack so it's interesting to see because
I feel like a lot you know I feel like
the truth of the matter that that
strains that are marketed well do well
strains that are marketed really well do
well so so uh some of those strains and
I feel like some some really good
strains that aren't marketed well don't
do well you know so I think that uh
marketing has a lot to do with the with
the success of uh a lot of products yeah
especially like
if you're comparing on an even playing
field if we have like you know 1010
flour compared to 1010 flour whichever
one has marketed better is going to do
the best I mean the grass is greener
where you water it so you know I think
when you put the marketing attention on
top of it um it gets a lot of presents
it gets a lot of presents I think that
just kind of is what it is for sure
right I mean McDonald's and Nike they're
not making better product they're
they're doing more Innovative marketing
yeah how big of a role do you feel
social media plays
how big of a role I feel like social
media plays a large
part I feel like that the social media
platforms have made it hard to Market
cannabis but um they're so normally used
regularly used and I feel like that it's
a large tool to Market on I feel like
it's the very uh difficult tool to
Market on um I feel like I've been able
to navigate it relatively well but it's
definitely a Nuance space you have to
know how to tiptoe around Instagram
without getting deleted and I feel like
we've been deleted enough times to kind
of figure out what works and what
doesn't so I think that uh social media
does play a large part but I don't think
that that's going to be the future of
cannabis marketing no and I think
um the relationship with the customer is
the biggest thing and customer you know
having their trust to where they come
back and they shop and they want SF can
every time or they that's that's the
definition of a brand really that's the
definition of a brand your brand is your
promise you know like if if I have like
initially the definition of a brand is
your brand is your promise like SF can
you know we only I mean I get to QC it
we only put our name on on x amount of
quality so that that's our promise that
every time you smoke our weed you're
going to get something that's beautiful
potent and burning clean so yes for sure
yeah we got a bunch of SF can of photos
in my book so that's dope yeah we went
toward and we've done we've been done a
bunch work together so with the
collaboration stuff and yeah you went
through some of the canal Loops fenos
there was like 90 some odd fetas it was
kind of all over the place with that one
so I feel
like they do an amazing job as far as
cultivation is concerned yeah as far as
labeling the cuts and knowing which
flavor is which that's I'm not going to
say they mastered that yet so I
definitely and I am blessed to test all
these and a lot of times I'm like what
is this yeah they're like number 647 I'm
like what are the genetics I you know I
want to know all the stuff and I feel
like people want to know they want the
story you know people want the story so
so a lot of times I feel like the
cultivat cultivation team that's not
really on the radar you know they're
looking for how how the weed grows how
the plant you know structure how to make
it taste better how to make it burn how
to make it taste better so sometimes
they don't know the genetics and I'm
like we got to know the genetics guys
guys we got to know the genetics you're
like I don't know James gave it to me
I'm like yeah but that's not the
genetics brother we can't Market this as
got this from James you know what I mean
right it's it's funny because uh I feel
like the the line keeps moving and the
bar keeps moving up oh the the
cultivation space is evolving at such a
fast pace and I think they're like the
Innovations and quality and the yields
and it's just you know it's evolving
super fast it's evolving super fast and
you see
people two years behind and they just
get further and further behind as as
everything starts to advance and then
you see like some of the more
technologically advanced growth and and
it's amazing what people are doing
people that focus on White Ash getting
you know that's a whole another animal
too so it wasn't something that was
really in the conversation three or four
years ago so I feel like clean burning
weed has has been a lot part of the
conversation for a long time like you
didn't want your weed to burn black and
you wanted it to smoke well whether you
identified that as the white ash by Ash
color I don't think the ash color was a
box that needed to be checked but for
the for the weed to be flavorful and
burning clean was was a box to be
checked and for it not to be burning
black has been has been has been a thing
for a long time for sure um I don't
think that uh the science of White Ash
has uh totally been been mastered I feel
like there's definitely some other uh
nuances that uh that affect the color of
the Ash and I won't say that uh and I
feel like you know but as Baseline
typically if it's burning white it's
it's clean whether you know it's
interesting to see because I've seen
some of these more uh potent strains
that don't burn as clean and I wonder if
that has anything to do with it because
I will say some a lot of these some of
these strains that are burning super
white necess not aren't necessarily the
most potent FL flavorful strains they're
just burning white and people like them
because they're burning white and I've
got flour that people were really proud
of and I'm like this is burning really
clean mhm I don't think it got me high I
didn't I'm not really tasting a lot of
flavor out it so the overall
experience I would rate it lower you
know I would rate it lower even though
it does have the white Dash yeah I feel
you it's really interesting and then the
struggle to get it white all the time
and I mean there's recipes that guys
have come up with where I feel like it's
pretty consistent but not everything is
the same so you have Skittles versus and
you know I'll say that I like to say
maybe I'll take an unpopular stance
there's guys that have mastered curating
white ash but I still don't think that
their flower is at the top of the top of
the Heap you know there it always Burns
clean but in my opinion it's not the
best flower yeah well at the end of the
day I'm all about flavor and I'm all
about effect those are the two most
flavor and potency are really important
flavor and potency are real important
for sure we used to get C piss back in
the day it was the ugliest of ugly like
we get shreds in the bag sometimes and
it was s $60 for an eth and so that made
me realize how important the other
things are bag appeel wasn't as
important but you know the brick weed
was nasty back in the day so I didn't
get good brick weed oh yeah I didn't do
a lot of brick weed bless than I really
do a lot headaches no headaches for me
smoking out of cans with seeds
popping definitely hit out of a few cans
here and there definitely smoked in some
survival situations totally so yeah
where do you think the future of the
industry is going global yep that's why
I was in Spain I think that the Market's
going to improve globally I think
Germany just did some type of
decriminalization
legalization I think that uh you know so
now you got Thailand Germany and a host
of other countries that are starting to
become legal and I think that uh are
able to trade with each other yeah so I
think that uh Global's the future I
think that having a global footprint is
like essential and that's why I was uh
that's why I was in Spain because I
would like wanted to Market my Brands
globally have you been out to Thailand
and seen the scene out there I have not
been out to Thailand man I I know that
uh you know what it is when I was in
Spain everybody was in Thailand for the
full moon SES oh wow uh I do I know a
lot of people that went out there um
I've heard I've heard mixed mixed
stories of the market but I think it's
really interesting and and and
Thailand's been high on my list of
countries to visit for a long time you
know as a fighter I would like to go
there for the MU Thai and act really
they have amazing food amazing uh fruit
yeah I mean this fruit I like fruit and
they have high you know some of the
highest quality uh they don't even call
it organic it's just how they're growing
the food is is in Thailand so Tan's
super high into this yeah I have a ton
of friends out there I've been waiting
to go to I mean looking forward to it
and it's crazy cuz you know I based my
travel whether we can smoke or not since
I like to smoke can we smoke there or
not so Thailand was high on the list but
I was like man you can't before you
couldn't smoke there so now it's no more
appeal I'm hearing the weed's Uber
expensive I was hearing $45 a gram for
good weed out there wow I was like
that's crazy I feel like you know the
price for weed in Barcelona was was
really high I didn't bring any I I
dropped a bag on weed in Barcelona you
know I was buying $100 Ace every day
yeah sometimes twice sometimes twice a
day yeah but they have good flower out
there they have good extract out there
they got passionate people the industry
is booming out in Barcelona and I mean
still in my opinion it had amazing Vibes
man it had amazing Vibes and I I did
feel very welcomed and I did like the
culture of how they chilled at the shops
and smoked and you chilled there they'll
bring you you know smoking accessories
they got papers and bongs that's how it
should be whatever you need man I love
it and some of them you know you can
order a latte some of them you can order
a beer like uh food snacks
I yeah I definitely I definitely like
that
Vibe yeah I think it's great where you
can smoke and you can hang out and chill
in a public place where you know there's
other people I would take cannabis over
alcohol every single time so like I feel
like sometimes you know you get pulled
into the bar because that's a social
Norm in America so but I think there
there was establishments where we could
chill and smoke and have music and the
same type Vibes I would take that 10
times out of 10 you know over alcohol
and that's what I did like some of the
cafes in in in Span are open till
midnight 1:00 and you can you know catch
a Vibe chill smoke yeah it was pretty
dope and I like the flavors so I wanted
to see the menus I was hitting different
shops seeing different menus smoking the
SP the the CI genetic Spanish grown weed
yeah that's a lot of it a lot of the
good stuff for sure uh you tried any of
the Spanish stuff yeah I tried a lot of
gokal weed and I feel like I I feel very
blessed like uh yeah the power of social
media one I touch down some local
Growers yeah knew um hit me up and I was
able and I was gifted a bunch of weed so
how about Spanish genetics uh it's
mostly Cali Amnesia ha I feel like well
that's the broad that's like what's
broadly grown there's lots of Amnesia
and then it's a lot of California
strains but they definitely want
genetics and they're like I love that
they're interested in popping seeds I
feel like yeah yeah cuz you know popping
seeds is for everyone it's not like the
most profitable way to go if you're like
trying to make money popping seeds is
not the way to make the most money but
like but it's essential for like the
future and and I think it has its own
value it's inherent value not everybody
can cash in on that value but it has
definitely has a lot of value well and
guys over there are now growing better
to where they can actually do good
selections because you have to grow a
certain level to do sele to really
assess you got to yeah to really have a
good representation of the plan if it's
not grown well you get a poor
representation of the plan you don't
know how about hash holes what's your
opinion on that I love hash holes I'm
not a I'm not a hash hole all day guy
right and it's
interesting I'm not really the guy I I
feel like I enjoy smoking really good
rosin really you know I don't mind
paying for really good rosin but I don't
know if it's worth it to throw that $100
a gram rosin into the hash all I don't
know that I get I feel I get that that
uh pleasure out of it but some people do
some people do I would rather take a
second wash I I feel like I'd rather
roll a hash hole in a second wash then
like some people are busting open these
you know these jars that are 200 bucks a
jar and throwing them in a hash hole I'm
like that's crazy I feel like it's like
beer bonging champag you know what I
mean I don't know there's definitely
people that do that I've seen yeah I'm
like I don't know if that's the way that
I want to enjoy my1 Grand rosin I mean I
used to have a friend that would drink a
kkin jerk the IJ pints of it he put them
in the freezer the same not highend but
he the cat piss guy
actually that's funny I had my irk and
jerks t
yeah you put in the freezer oh no no I
didn't put it in the freezer uhuh I HD
it in my backpack I feel like I was a
little bit younger when we were doing
before I graduated Tennessee yeah we did
the Jack and cokes with the 7eleven big
big uh big gulps huh yeah all bad all
bad yeah it's all bad so but I mean
that's better than the the 40s in my
opinion you the malul liquor I think
malul liquor just man these people were
crazy M Liquor is crazy it's crazy that
like s Ides is the huge uh cannabis
infused drink like and I feel like the
younger generation isn't aware of like
the sa he Snoop Dog M licker 40
generation because that's what I
identify St Ides as you know what I mean
the Crooked Eye type type drink so it's
interesting to see that uh there's say
eyes infused cannabis drinks that that
are really popular right now totally
good for S eyeses though for sure they
definitely cleaned up their image yeah
it's interesting all these compan
that are going to be jumping towards
cannabis though too in the future to
yeah the big companies are are coming
you know that's like that's just an
indication like St I they're a large
model liquor company now they're huge in
the Cannabis space there's going to be
more of that for sure especially as like
federalization clears up things become
legal things become clearer then yeah
the large money is definitely going to
come in yeah it's already coming in
sneaking in it's already dripping in
yeah for sure but like just trickling in
not like you know well I mean there's
there's it's a big industry and there's
several sides of the industry there's
the boutique highend side of the
industry and then there's large IND and
there's everything else yeah know for
sure for sure I'm on the top I
mean for sure and the boutique yeah I
mean the highend you know it's so small
everybody knows every very small segment
of the market everybody knows everybody
and that's like it's not for everybody
like it's not it's not for everybody and
that's not that's not there's nothing
wrong with that most people aren't going
to enjoy you know the best of the best
when you look at alcohol most people
aren't enjoying the finest wines you
know they're getting somewhere middle to
bottom and that's what most most
cannabis consumers are consuming you
know like so but there are those people
that really really you know search for
the search for the best and and seek
that out and enjoy it and it's funny
because it's always you know what's
funny in cannabis it's not necessarily
like the uh the financial levels like I
don't know how you say it but like I
feel like some people with meager means
smoke smoke the best weed smoke the best
weed you know what I mean Sacramento I
feel like it's a median income City
Sacramento they're smoking amazing weed
in Sacramento so I feel like and there's
some people I know with a bunch of money
and they just smoke the the worst
cheaters the wor rich people smoke the
worst weed ever for sure so I think I
mean I guess it just shows what some
people are passionate about and what's
important to them but yeah totally well
yeah it's great when passion drives it
and you know I think the other thing is
is collecting data points over time
really determines how much you like we
or don't like weed I think right you
smoke a lot then you realize what's good
and bad if you smoke very rarely then
it's kind of all the same and it's hard
to really assess it after 20 years or 15
years or whatever you really get a good
idea if if you tried a bunch of stuff
you can really have a more broad broader
pette yeah a broader pette for sure well
with cannabis you can go in any
direction it's like there's so many
different flavors out there now uh as
far as like whatever Direction you want
to go berries strawberries blueberries
raspberries assai berries right there
there's so many variants there's so many
variants it's definitely infinite when
there's a lot of subtleties the plant
I'm all about the subtleties there's a
lot of nuances in the plant there's a
lot of reasons yeah why things can't be
I feel like people are always like if we
can mix this strain and that strain
we're going to get and it's never like
that and it's never and it's never like
that people like you know we cross this
with that it's almost never like that
it's it's mostly never like that and
every once in a while you get lucky
every 400 fenos later you find one that
matches what you were looking for
totally but there's a lot of recessive
traits in the genetics so when you're
trying to breed for specific stuff
unless you're reinforcing those traits
if you're just creating f1s you don't
know what you're going to get um and if
you don't know your lines you don't know
what you're going to get right so the
more you breed the more you work with
the plants you kind of know what the
possibilities
are what what what characteristics are
going to come out and how heavily each
one's going to come out is just
different right yeah I think that's when
you see large when you see a bunch of
different fenos yes there's like common
characteristics in all of them and some
are you know I think it's just like kids
like you know you have five kids they
all look similar they all got the same
eyes but they're all some are tall some
are small you know I think it's it's
similar with uh when you do AR pheno
hunts there's Char certain base
characteristics that you can see in in a
large portion of the strains that come
out and it's just different how how much
of that comes out is is is a is
different I think that's really that's
really one of the most interesting
things from feno hunting that I found is
like is that yes there's base
characteristics that you can see in all
these strains that like come out and
then you look for the one that where the
characteristics that you're looking for
comes out the most yeah and then there's
the unicorns you know that's and then
there's the what the [ __ ] is this right
exactly and then yes all these look the
same about the same about the same about
the same and then you're like oh what
the [ __ ] is this there's definitely some
of those what the [ __ ] are this for sure
those are the fun ones too
the funky ones there's like okay you
know and I think that when yeah when
you're selecting Keepers you're like
okay I like this one cuz this character
stand out I like this one because these
characteristics stand out we're going to
rerun this one because it grew so well
you know and like but some of them are
like this one's funky this one's
different and like it's hard to assess
whether that's good or bad you know it's
hard to hard to it's hard to forecast
what people are going to like for sure
well until you smoke it you don't really
know if it's a winner and I think some
people Miss on that that note when
they're going through the process really
at the end of the day it's all about
smoking and finding out the effect and
The Taste because sometimes it just
doesn't translate on the plant it's the
most amazing beautiful smelly thing and
then you grow it out and smoke it or you
dry it out and smoke it and it's just
not totally different experience hard I
think that you know I think that's why
it's important to have a team or like
people with diverse skill sets I think
that like my planta cultivation partner
is an amazing cultivator and he knows a
lot of the characteristics of the the
plant but then yes he dries the flower I
get to smoke the flour and assess it and
see like from a a smoker's perspective
like what I feel is about the plan and I
think that we come together and find
some really special things so you're in
Sacramento Too part time I'm all over
place I don't know where I don't even
know where I'm at that's the new Emerald
Triangle beta LA to Sacramento so I just
be running the triangle the new triangle
that's the new triangle yeah so since we
played a game with Chris we're going to
do this little game where I got three
joints
two of them are SF Cana and one of them
is not SF Cana and you get to guess
which one I get to guess which one so
you can go ahead and dry hit them all
and then uh we'll fire them up
interesting interesting challenging no
we like to have
fun I'm all four fun I'm all four
fun I feel like this is most likely
something that we
feel like this is a maybe this is a
maybe this is just from the dry H though
we got to fire it up just from the dry
head
yep no but I feel like okay this one's
not we didn't grow this one I don't know
you know what it is I I'm GNA say this
we grow a lot of [ __ ] people don't get
to see and I feel very blessed to see it
all like so this feels this one seems
like a strain that we're not known for
this feels like like a glitter bomb e
different e yeah that has something
different in it but I feel like so my
vote would be this one but I will say
this we I feel like we SF Canon we have
access to most of the great contemporary
genetics out there and we've grown them
whether they worked out for us is is you
know not
always not always the case but we have
access and grown some things cuz this
tastes like a glitter bomb SF can we're
not grown from glitter bomb but we grew
some glitter bomb you guys did grow some
glitter bomb two F yeah so we grew some
glitter bomb we've grown some so but I
think that but I would take didn't I
have to smoke them I feel like if I
smoked them I would definitely yeah
definitely definitely know because it's
the thing not everything smokes like SF
can weed right but I would say this we
this would fire first this would be my
vote and this would one be the one that
I'd want to smoke the least yeah not
saying that it's a bad thing I think
that like you know it's just just a
matter of preference it's a matter of
preference so I would smoke the sweet
one first
nice yeah I would smoke the sweet one
first it's funny CU When you say that
cand is really popular people get mad
like I feel like I'm just going to say
it candy is the most in demand flavor
right now and some people will get mad
when you say that and I'm like I don't
control the market the market controls
the market yeah the Demand controls the
market so if people like dessert
flavored strains then and that's just
what it is that's just what it is I
enjoy a really good gassy biscotti
carbon fiber type weed as well but I
feel like the market right now they want
color and then they want a candy candy
yeah and then something else with it you
could put candy gas you could put you
know just got to be a little different
just got to be a little different that's
a hit
yeah yeah the gelato the we're in the
age of gelato
still we are in the age of gelato c yeah
I would say some people say runs you
know but yeah I mean gelato still the
from the Gelato I feel like it's you
know the elbows connected to the to the
wrist is connected to the finger type
thing you know like right if you look at
it that way if you look at it as
everything's gelato crosses and you
could also say everything's cookie
crosses cuz gelato came from cookies
which was the biggest wave or impact in
the bay it was yeah I mean 2010 20 to
2012 it was the biggest thing out there
in the at least coming from the bay
there was still a lot of ogs La just
loved their ogs you know yeah like that
2010 era I think that kushes had a a
nice little wave in the bay where people
wanted to grow I was growing like a
classic Bubba cush that had like the
really cushy structure at that the
classic OG Kush was really in favor a
little bit in that 2010 2012 Range but
then the cookies rained dominant for a
very long time for for a really long
time yeah cookies didn't catch on in
other places quite like it did the bay
you know La had cookies you can get
cookies I feel like it was that's what
kind of made it the exclusivity of it
like a lot of people were interested in
it but not everybody could get real
cookies right you had to come to the
city you got to come to the city for the
cookies yeah it was the first thing I
smoked that tasted
Brey it's got that that bready character
that this it's also in like wedding cake
and stuff like that yeah that's what I
was going to say yeah all those
contemporary strains kind of come back
to some kind of cookie right the
doughiness of it yeah I mean a lot of
that stuff is out there for sure cookies
is in a lot of
stuff so I feel like this tastes like SF
can of cherry guava I could be wrong but
this is something you're correct in that
range and it's smoking like that it's
smoking clean got the ring I feel
like yeah you are correct it's a good
one I love the TPS on
that one of my top three all favorite
stains probably Cherry guava it's
phenomenal strain candy has some gas to
it bag super potent bag appeal color
super potent yeah super potent super
potent yeah it checks the boxes I really
like that
one so you got any big projects coming
up I mean we got a bunch of big breeding
projects is coming I think I got uh a
lot of uh travel coming I'm going to
Houston I love Houston shout out to
Texas uh so and I feel like the Cannabis
scene is emerging super fast right in
Houston so I [ __ ] with Houston so I'll
be back out in Houston and so yeah it's
a bunch of travel there's we got a bunch
of new uh seed projects and development
so we got a lot of new things coming
yeah Houston my brother lives in Houston
my parents live in Texas as well I feel
like it's funny I go to these I go to
these City's on some cannabis related
stuff and I'm not really uh as familiar
with the city as as I as I would prefer
to be so yeah I got to Houston and I was
like and I didn't realize it was a
really cool City I didn't I didn't uh it
exceeded my expectations as well I
didn't know what to expect I didn't know
what to expect you know what I mean I
had never been out there I thought it
was going to be a little country but n
it's like real modern big city for sure
crawfish when I think of Houston I think
a good crawfish VI craw crawfish too
yeah it's really good that sounds like a
Vibe it sounds like a Vibe sounds like
something I'd like I didn't know Houston
was see I didn't know Houston was known
for that and they had I mean they have
really good food there really good food
they had amazing food the cost of living
is a lot less than California for sure
it's amazing the cost of living yeah
it's amazing what you can get out there
relatively it's crazy how much stuff
costs out here well now with the thca
it's like they have thca all over Texas
and uh you know it's like they tax that
we we yeah the
DCC you know and the taxes that we have
to deal with in California way different
than like what you know they're dealing
with in Texas where they have it in a
CBD shop yeah it's crazy it's crazy the
tax the taxes has has had the largest
impact on the I mean if we're talking
about the might as well call it the
failure of the recreational Market where
I mean it hasn't been a whole lot of
winners in the recreational market and
and a lot of that is just due to due to
taxation due to Taxation and it's really
hard for a consumer to pay $80 for eth
that Bobby down the street has for 40
you know it's really difficult and
that's like and and that's from the
taxation I think it's overly taxed it's
not tax like it's not tax similar to
other things that would be similar you
know it's not taxed like alcohol would
be it's tax at such a high rate that
it's made it almost impossible for a lot
of recreational companies to succeed
almost like it that was the plan
H yeah it's interesting because the
price has gone down
of the flour and then the price price of
everything else has gone up has so now
there's not as much profit and it's a
big struggle it's a big struggle for a
lot of companies it's it's a big
struggle for a lot of country companies
I would say the industry as a whole has
had a difficult past you know 36 months
36 months postco I feel like there's a
lot of nuances as to why that happened
obviously a lot of people made a lot of
money during during covid and invested
that in infrastructure which made a made
a larger Supply you know the influx in
Supply is going to always defect the
demand yeah I mean a lot of people are
regretting their investments in
infrastructure I see it over and over
and over again 2021 everybody was going
bigger everybody was going bigger
they're like I got 200 lights I'm going
build out to 900 like all right yeah I
think a lot of us thought it was never
going to end you know and it was so good
during Co for so many people especially
in this industry I feel like yeah man
the price of the price of cannabis went
up 300% in like three months I mean
that's unheard of I don't know why
people thought that was gonna last but
but yeah it was such a
it was such a huge jump in the market it
affected the market so much and then I
mean I think that that influx of cash
affected a lot of the world so and we
see the effects that it had on cannabis
and a lot of those a lot of those
Ventures sadly enough are failing at a
at a at a high rate yeah it's
interesting and then now I mean we're
talking about going global and then
we've got all these countries opening up
and eventually there's going to be
Commerce we're going to do not just
domestic but it'll be International
domestic and uh import export it's going
to be amazing we're still in the first
quarter I feel like we're definitely
like in the first quarter you know we're
in the first half of the first quarter
as far as how the industry is going to
develop in the next 10 years you know
yeah just scratching the surface of it
just scratching the surface and all the
infrastructures that have to be built
out in between no there's definitely uh
going to be a lot of opportunities in
cannabis in in the in the upcoming
future yeah I'm looking forward to some
of it I'm looking forward to the new
genetics too it's like uh people are
there's a lot of people breeding right
now there's more people growing than
ever before you know I think that and
that's globally everybody's a breeder
globally if you didn't touch no poen
you're not a breeder right I don't know
what the rules are I don't know what the
rules are but that's what I you know so
I've heard I don't know so you yeah
that's that's supposed to be the deal
you know it's a lot of people coming up
with new strains but I'm like you're not
a breeder though how you come up with a
new strain like I rename game is real
it's the rck game yeah there's 75
different uh Lemon Cherry gelados with
different names that yes Rich off recked
runs that's a new thing recked runs
recked runs yeah that's a new thing
definitely yeah there's a lot of every
week There's a new strain but no breeder
attached like I don't know how you got
that one right but most of these Brands
aren't cultivators so it's like just
marketing just marketing yep so it's
funny because Lemon Cherry gelato is
really still I would say the most
popular thing on the market I mean
there's there's a lot of other popular
things
lemon gelato is just dominant right now
in the highest demand is in the highest
demand yes and I feel like what it it
actually is is is Up For Debate it's
really up for debate right yeah no for
sure but it's probably the largest in
demand definit yeah as far as as a whole
as a whole solid lcg that's what the
wholesale people want yeah it checks the
boxes for most people it checks the
boxes for most people man it looks good
smell good tastes good get you High yeah
that's enough for most people totally
I'm good with that you know Skittles
doesn't have a big ceiling but it it as
far as effect it doesn't get you that
high it doesn't get you high blam you
like this one not at all y it's a
daytime smoke more ativa leing yeah that
yeah for sure but it's a it's
approachable to everybody like that's
one thing with Skittles it's like it t
pretty much it tastes so good and
anybody can ever and everybody can
appreciate that flavor so distinct yep
for sure we got to get on a joint number
two I'll take that one when you fire up
you like it so much you're not sharing
to the bottom no that's good I'll write
the second
one yeah this one's got a nice ring it's
got some drip to it that one was smoking
what's funny CU not that one at all
really good flow I feel like from the
time you light it up it changes and the
flavor intensifies as it goes down if
it's really good down into the roach for
sure and that's rare you know what that
is if the last 40% of your joint is
enjoyable that's really good rare flower
yep that tastes aming top
10% feel like you're 30% there's 30% of
the joint left and it's still flavorful
that's top tier flour I mean I would say
on average stuff the first hit might
taste good and then the flavor goes away
right and then there's like typical yeah
that's typical that's most things you
know and some stuff that looks so good
you go to smoke it and it's a
disappointment some of it smells so good
and the smell doesn't transfer into the
taste of the smoke no yeah purple punch
is one that I am not a huge fan of
straight purple punch but I think it's a
good breeder I think it breeds well into
stuff uh but it just has kind of bland
turps like you you might get a little
flavor when you light it up and that's
it all the way down there's nothing else
I like the flavor that it does have
though yeah that had a nice sweet candy
flavor it's like a predecessor to good I
think the extract on that's really good
but I'm not a huge yeah just not my
thing not most people's thing yeah
doesn't have the potency no has the bag
appe pill though I feel like it's a lot
of Growers had success growing it as
well yeah for
sure forbidden fruit was another one
it's like forbidden fruit had its 15
minutes of fame literally that's one of
those this is unique this is different
but so I feel like it was unque it was
different everybody was
interested the appeal went went bad fast
overnight overnight night people were
like I don't want this people were
interested and then they decided that
they didn't like it right I remember the
first bag of forbidden fruit I smelled I
was like this is different this is crazy
yeah then I smoked it I was like ah not
my
favorite yeah it's funny because Tangi
really had its day for a long time Tangi
was you know it was winning all the cups
I think it's one of the most awarded
uh strains in history and you don't see
Tangi anymore really I mean I don't see
Tangi anymore you know what you see
Tangi that's grown to get washed cuz you
see a lot of Tangi rosin you see that
like there's some Tangi strains that are
grown just to get washed yeah and I like
orange turps I like I mean I like every
kind of turp pretty much I'm not a
citrus turp guy I mean that'd be like my
least favorite probably is like some
Citrus turps but yeah I won't go by it
or go out of my way I interesting enough
like some of the yeah some of the hot
[ __ ] is like some orangey citrusy turps
that I've seen lately that people were
like hey this is the hot [ __ ] and I was
like the orange Citrus turps huh dude
that orange Zer Bird's
good the orange Z's unique like I said
orange wouldn't be my you know yeah I I
feel like that one is not super popular
on the market as far as for me you know
never seen a blacked out strain that
tastes sisterly like that and that
orange zerbert was like full Co
dark dark as [ __ ] orangey Zerby yeah
that but not my favorite she's like
Sunkissed oranges but yeah you have to
really like that orange it's kind of
like how Jack is kind of disliked orange
I don't know if you heard of Orange
Julius it was like a chain of like this
orange drink that's what the orange Z
tastes like yeah I never seen a I never
seen a citrusy orangey like pered out
super dark strain like that one but same
[ __ ] wasn't my favorite I I voted
against it Different Strokes for
different folks right for sure there's
definitely some people that appreciate
that yeah it's amazing uh super boof you
smoke super
boo I don't believe I have I don't
believe I have it sounds familiar but I
don't believe I have no yeah how about
Dante's
Inferno no not that one either I'm not
those are some more smaller batch grow
yeah yeah yeah Mile High Dave has that
Dante's Inferno yeah I've heard of that
as well no I haven't smoked any of that
yeah yeah I haven't touched a lot of the
smaller batch I have and I but like I
haven't been dug into a lot of the
smaller bad stuff how about
Z I feel like if lcg is number one Z
might be as might be the two or the
three might be the two or the three it
might be one of those trains that people
still have interest in might still have
like similar value and the real zope is
amazing it's good I I think it's great
and the real Z is a really amazing
strain SF canana and planta both of my
cultivation Partners have grown it and
they both came with some really amazing
representations of soap representations
of soap so I definitely soap is a
definitely a pretty dope strain so are
you going to go with sfk on that one yes
for sure I would say can you guess what
what it
is uh no let me see hold this is the
that's what I was going to say I feel
like I was like this could lean either
way it is more
of it's got a nice
Ash it's burning
clean I don't know I'm like I could tell
you which ones it's not yeah it's
uh guava gas it's guava gas interesting
number four number four and I have gg4
on the bag so everyone's like Gorilla
Glue number four no it's quava gas
I like the five better no I'm just kid
yeah out of the uh that was a really I
think
that I think that we found some really
dope guava gas fenos yeah same thing I
don't think it's going to be hit though
but I think the potency on the [ __ ] is
crazy it's crazy potency on the [ __ ] is
really crazy but I don't know that it's
going to be like I don't know that it's
it's going to be a wave maybe hit yeah
maybe I it might it might it did for
Nemo that's a very you know that's a
very unique that's a very unique uh
brand that's a very unique brand that's
been around for 18 years yeah you know
that's been around 18 years they they've
been able to make a lot of [ __ ] jump
that uh most people can't make jump and
the man the Skittles and the the number
they're getting for their units is
astronomical it's pretty wild much
respect to them man much respect to them
they're definitely uh
feel like there's so many yeah there's
so many segments of the market you know
what I mean and they have their segment
of the market that's willing to pay an
astronomical amount of money for their
product I ain't mad at them like I feel
like a lot of people hate on them a lot
of people love them but I'm not mad at
them they've been they've they've done
an amazing job I think they've done an
amazing job it's good for everybody
that's what people that don't like them
they their own issues but uh it's good
for everybody you know and there's
levels to all this and there's price
points for everybody so no matter you
you go to buy a car there's price points
that go on up forever and ever exactly
no yeah for sure and whether it's worth
it or not that's like yeah that's a
matter of opinion the people that are
paying it think it's worth that they
must and they're paying it and I know
for actual factual that they're paying
it it's not like yeah got a friend that
P yeah I got a more yeah I got a friend
that just got a QP at an astronomical
rate and I was like oh it's real people
are paying that okay for sure and he's
saying that yes he could get X out for
it and I was like that's absurd but it's
wild the Market's there for it the
Market's there you know what I mean I'm
like not mad at it not mad at it yep and
I've had some really good uh
representations of their work so I I
respect their work I mean so yeah it's
good it smokes good I respect what
they've done as a brand as well they've
curated Their audience and they've been
able to get the highest dollar for their
product I'm not mad at them by any means
yeah if if we weed would have gone up as
much uh with inflation that's what we
all would be paying compared to like the
80s and 90s if you look at the price of
wead yes it it hasn't gone up with
inflation but I think that's
because I mean when it was illegal it
was being produced at a lower rate now
that it's legal you know there's there's
there's less risk so there's less reward
you know what I mean there's less risk
so there's definitely less reward that's
a big part of why the price is cheaper
right I mean 50 pounds are probably
you're probably going home you get
pulled over 50 pounds you're mother in
California you're probably going home
today smile on a handshake yeah I
remember I remember when 50 grams you're
probably not going home no I think 50
pounds now is they're not even going to
bring you in they're going to site you
and release you probably I think you're
right man I think you're right I don't
want to test the theory out I'm not
trying to test the theory out but that's
the rumor rumor has it you know what I
mean yeah
so so it's a way different age so yeah
way less risk so it's got to be less
reward even though it's still rewarding
well it's a misdemeanor now so
misdemeanor yeah as it should be as it
should be for the
best so yeah we had Luke scarmazzo on
the show he did 14 years Luke scarmazzo
was the guy I feel like he's uh when he
went down he was he was the dude he was
the dude he was the flex king of his era
he was definitely the flex king of his
era I think that he has a uh he has a
great a better image now but L car Mo
was the guy before he was like yeah I
know that I know of his legacy he has a
he he's a feel like he has his own he's
like a living legend to a certain degree
yeah and he's young still he's young
still but there that he was like the
story was he was like Sky balling off
cannabis like in a long time ago and
then he got busted by the feds and did a
lot of time behind it but yeah I heard
he was the flex King I dude he wrote a
good book too he his stories but yeah I
would love to hear his whole story I
would definitely read that whole book
but yeah I know he was he was like
getting money the generation before me
and I think it was a lot I think he was
doing his thing getting a lot of bread
and then got hit with by the feds but
yeah I mean yeah St wild that's the
story that I heard yeah that I heard you
know like it was like one of the people
that people were getting behind trying
to help support to get out of cannabis
or get out of prison and I was like I'm
like I definitely heard a bro like he's
definitely living legend yeah in the
streets he's a legend for
sure feel like not everybody knows that
a lot of people know that he was in jail
for cannabis they don't know the whole
story they don't know that he was a
legend in these
streets yeah he was doing big [ __ ] in
the streets yeah pushing boundaries he
push pushing boundaries he was pushing
boundaries he was pushing them over he
was pushing them over that was a thing
for sure and a different and it was a
different era it was a different era so
how long do you think gelato is going to
be you know that not not even gelato but
that flavor profile is going to be on
top you think it's going to lo you know
10 12 years you think it's going to go
sooner man if I had the answer to that
one I'd be rich crystall because I feel
like everybody wants to know what's next
yeah and I feel like you know there's
been large marketing efforts to push
what's next but I don't think anything's
really caught the traction caught the
traction of like the broader market yet
so yeah how long that's going to last I
I don't know I feel
like I mean I think that as it develops
there's just going to be there's so many
there's so much infinite variety of
flavors that there's going to be Savory
gassy sweet different categories of
flavors and it just in the Market's
going to determine what's going to be
the most popular it's interesting
because back in the day it was like it
was very Regional what was popular you
know La was OG we had cookies in the bay
they had Sour Diesel in New York right
down in Florida they had their own thing
and I feel like because of accessibility
and because of social media everybody
knows who's popular and so it's all all
over the place I feel like we're we're a
lot more Global world at this point
we're a lot yes with the with the
internet and social media were a lot
more Global worlded I feel like slang
and fashion used to be like more uh more
Regional but as far as like how the
access to information and access to
people I feel like we're more a global
Society so yeah there the trends seem to
be more Global yeah food slowly become
that extremely Global Food I mean it's a
glob Global Society you know we can talk
to people Nationwide yeah so easily now
there's so much access to information
now so much so much too much too much
sometimes for sure well I feel like
there's a lot of information and there's
like just as much misinformation so it
just depends who you ask yeah so if you
could go back in time to your younger
yourself that had just been in the
industry for one or two years what would
be your biggest piece of advice trust
your hustle trust your hustle yeah I
feel like that's a thing
yes uh I don't think I ever looked at
cannabis as a career so maybe if I would
have had thought it was a career and I
had invested more time in it might have
could have got further but more or less
I'm happy with how things worked out
well it's great that you're driven by
Passion I mean I think that's the
biggest thing is that's one of the
biggest blessings like well and really
to start off smoking it's one thing I I
have a lot of friends who start off
growing I was like a Avid smoker I love
smoking weed right I love everything
about the plant but uh that's that's
what made me fall in love with it was
the smoking not just the growing or
anything else it's interesting to see
because there's a lot of Growers that
are really passionate about the growing
aspect not so much the smoking aspect
and it's like I'm definitely I'm
definitely the smoking aspect of it so
it's interesting to see that like people
value my palette cuz I never it wasn't
like a skill that I set out to have you
know what I mean yeah so well you're
blessed by being in the right Circles of
people to have exposure to the good
stuff and really you know that's once
you get the good stuff you can never go
back in my opinion it's just it's really
tough man it's real tough to go back
like I mean you can go back financially
you can you know that might be the
circumstances but yeah once you once you
smoked and enjoyed really good good good
flow it's hard to go back yeah no I
can't smoke no mids NOP it's hard even
go on vacation when you have such good
flower unless you have flower with you
or you know it's like any more we're
talking about global so there's places
like Spain where you can really get good
flower but that's not
everywhere that is not everywhere and I
feel like yeah that that that dictates
some of my travel I don't want to go
anywhere where we can't smoke good cuz
how good could it be if we can't smoke
right that's definitely a thing but in
the future that would be really cool
like if you had a brand and you could
have insert the same quality globally
like I could you know pop a ath planta
open in California and get the same
quality in Spain get the same quality in
the UK that would be that'd be pretty
dope yeah freshness it's com I feel it's
coming it is how fast who knows how fast
who knows yeah I feel like a lot of
times we take two steps forward and one
step back as long as we're still going
in the right direction that's okay it's
coming yeah yeah I feel like I feel the
same I agree I agree it's like the
progress is slow I feel like progress is
slow but we're heading in the right
direction making huge strides yeah I
don't think any of us Enis envisioned
legalization being like this when we
were younger but not at all not at all I
didn't think this no might have invested
more time into it had I thought it was
going to it was going to develop the way
it did but yeah yeah same I'm happy how
it worked out yeah it's a great time to
be alive I mean just in general with
technology and the the emerging
technology and now we got the the new
virtual reality glasses that just came
as wild
it's a great time to be alive and I
think that the evolution of cannabis is
is is crazy it's evolved it's evolved
just as fast and I feel like the culture
of of cannabis Enthusiast has evolved
you know just as fast so there's like a
lot of culture and events that are
starting to develop like super fast that
we'll see like on a global scale in our
lifetime probably yeah so you got to try
that one last
joint the you might want to go back to
one the mystery joint the mystery joint
you don't think is SF hopefully it
smokes well it's not it's different and
that's what I was going to say that like
I feel like a lot of these brands are
known for especially like cultivation
brands that uh are known for certain
strains but I think they all grow a
bunch of different strains so I was
going to say you know I know you're
friends with the grower you get some of
the ones that not everybody gets me too
yeah so cuz it tastes like something we
could have grown but definitely
something that we're not known for be
growing yeah you you guys stay away from
long who these are well these are very
well rolled who rolled these
professional joint roller at Instagram
he's our joint guy I I roll joints too I
just don't have time he gets the band on
them he gets it down perfect I mean I
write I roll good joints myself but I
enjoy I enjoy these a
lot so these are so these are the
collaboration with SF Canon we got
pre-rolls coming out we've been r&amp; ding
them for a while we still have to r&amp; DM
for longer but this is the pre-roll that
we're going to be releasing in in
California this is a nice size this is a
good size joint yeah I like that three
gram to three and a half gram those are
I feel like you get the best flavor out
of them especially when it's good and
you can smoke I like that as a share
size if I'm smoking it by myself I would
probably want it a little bit smaller
but for a share size this is perfect
well I feel like with the SF can of weed
for example you can put it back in the
tube and you can pull it out of the tube
and it still tastes good you can do that
four or five times so for sure I really
and then same thing with feno hunting
I'm big on giving people joints for feno
hunting rather than giving them the
flower so it's all kind of on the same
even playing field interesting that's
dope I think man I wish people did that
for me yeah and just hand me roll
pre-rolled joints of all the all the
fenos and be like hey just smoke these
I'm like no I want to see the flower too
though but I want to like both though
right well someone like you you I would
share the FL Two Joints yeah I'd share
the flower with you and then I want to
know the feedback on the joints right
right but not everybody for the most
part I know what the good flow looks
like I know it has bag appeel it's the
really The Taste in the effect that I
want to know right feedback from and and
like how how did it taste to the Joint
when you smoked it halfway was the
flavor gone was the flavor even better
down when you fired the road trip the
next day some of the weed the flavor
changes as you smoke
it so it doesn't stay consistent it's a
big thing right they're like this is the
one that gets put out I don't think that
this was not your cup of tea this didn't
really taste
right like this one might have and
spicy spice it's actually not even THC
it's
spice that's interesting it's spicy it
is spicy that's
funny I'm like which one do I really
likee tell me a little bit more about
your MMA career MMA is a tough way to
make a living yeah my MMA career I felt
like I was very blessed to uh be around
some of the best people in the sport so
I was blessed to be around some of the
best people in the sport and I think
that I was blessed to see like
how people at a high level perform
because I was I was around some of the
some of the best fighters in the world
so it's interesting to see how like the
best
people perform and handle things at a
high level so uh so my fighting career
was dope I think that it was it was
really dope it was something that I
enjoyed as well
um uh yeah that I was passionate about
that I was able to make some money doing
so it was cool I think that uh it's a I
really fighter pay is the most [ __ ] up
[ __ ] in like sports I feel like like uh
the amount of Revenue that the largest
mmaa promotions are paying their
Fighters is like very small amount like
uh most professional sports I think the
revenue sharing is like closer to 50% to
where like the league makes 50% the
players make 50% somewhere in that range
and I think that like professional
fighting it's like the largest company
gets 85% of the profits and they pay out
there people 15% so I think that there's
a lot of uh that the fighter pay is
really [ __ ] up like if we're speaking
all that the fighter pay is [ __ ] up if
the fight if the fighter pay was better
I might have fought more uh but it
wasn't like and I feel like the fame in
clouded is high but the pay is low you
know what I mean so and I feel like yeah
the opening pay for some of these larger
promotions isn't that high and I feel
like there is some people making making
a really good living but it's a very
small amount most people that are
fighting are definitely in it for the
love of the fight game not not not for
the B yeah if you look at the I think
only like a real real sliver of the
people are making a good living doing it
yeah there's a handful of people
crushing there's a handful of people
getting their bag but not that many they
not that many shout out to Nate Diaz he
did his thing he's he got paid he
showing everyone thing he's been showing
everybody how it's done for a long time
yeah so as far as fighting goes I was
definitely blessed to be around uh some
of the best fight camps uh I was a part
of euriah favers Team Alpha Mill we were
MMA team of the of the world three years
in a row and then I did I trained a lot
with Diaz brothers I trained a lot with
Nate Diaz so I did get to train with the
some of the best people it was really I
mean I enjoyed the lifestyle for sure if
I could have made better money probably
still be doing it how's their cardio
those guys smoke a lot of weed when I
was training with Nate I I feel like
obviously their cardio phenomenal I feel
like my cardio was on a high level and
we were smoking a lot I'm like we were
smoking a lot and I feel like cardio was
on a on a on a very high level I mean my
last fight for Bellator the dude I
fought was supposed to have like
incredible cardio feel like he was more
tired than I was and I was smoking a lot
I'm like yeah so I don't know that how
much of a negative effect smoking has on
has on athletic performance definitely
not much but the Diaz brothers is oh man
dudes can go forever those dudes can go
forever for sure well then Nick's ban
for cannabis I feel like it was really
unfortunate and that he was definitely
competed in the wrong era because you
know the bul of the bulk of his career
he was suspended for smoking but uh
that's a dude who's definitely going to
do what he wants to do so I think it was
an injustice to sport that we didn't get
to see that dude perform more cuz he's
uh it's a tragedy that was a special
athlete that was a special Nick Diaz
he's a special athlete I think that he's
a he's a unique and special martial
artist and I think that we didn't get to
see him in his prime because of uh he
was uh sideline because of of cannabis
uh so yeah it is unfortunate so who's
your favorite MMA fighter of all time
it's funny that you say that because
Nick Diaz might be my favorite MMA
fighter of all time I got good
relationships with some really amazing
Fighters like like Gilbert Melendez one
of the local ones and uh it's crazy
because as far as like skill set that I
respect of how they do it that's
probably my favorite fighter of all time
me too I got to get him on the show
shout out to Nick Diaz yeah that's a
tough one man that's a tough that's a
tough one y but he'll do it for sure for
sure that's probably the that's probably
I mean he might be the goat in my
opinion he was a really really talented
mixed martial artist yeah CJ used to
train with him as well he was in CJ's
corner back in the day nice that's dope
so yeah you know Northern California I
feel like it's a Titan near fight group
so yep for sure cannabis is the same way
cannabis is the same way and fighting I
feel like a lot of it's interesting
there's a lot of uh fighting people who
have transitioned into cannabis and
make a living on the side in cannabis so
it's it's cannabis is like pretty
prevalent in in fight culture it's
interesting yeah a lot of these u- jits
guys smoke a lot of weed lot of
Jiu-Jitsu Guys Smoke we it's a Vibe and
grow it and grow the [ __ ] too
yeah for
sure well so people are trying to get a
hold of you where where can they go to
find
you uh I feel like I'm pretty accessible
but I'm you know you can find me online
at Freddy
big uh I feel like I'm yeah pretty
readily accessible online so tell me
about your products oh I brought some um
some flour so um planta cannabis company
is a Los Angeles based cultivation
company um I think that my cultivation
partner does an amazing job J that's
what I was saying we've been feno
hunting um new flavors and we' we we've
uh put some new flavors into rotation um
and we're running some Classics too so
this Cleopatra right here is a candy gas
11 coffins is also a candy gas these are
both bred by Duke of Verve and I think
there are some um really different
unique turps we have biscotti as well
which is a really dope representation of
a really popular classic strain I think
my cultivation partner does a really
amazing job uh I think that were
available all the best stores in
Southern California at the moment um
backpack Boys Go Global Atrium so uh
yeah so that's what I brought out today
and I think that we've had a we just did
our first recck drop less than a year
ago so uh we're making a press into the
recreational market and nice I think
that my cultivation partner does an
amazing job and I think that the quality
and flavors are pretty exceptional
awesome well thank you so much for
coming on the show today I look forward
to having you on the show again
yeah man appreciate you have me on
[Music]