[Music]
you
[Applause]
[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James Lab podcast
and today our special guest is Nat
Pennington from Humble Seed Company how
are you doing today pretty good pretty
good it was a wild ride getting down
here uh with this crazy bomb Cyclone
that we're having and it's been a while
that we've been trying to get together
like this hasn't it we've been yeah yeah
it's been a minute uh yeah we had hie on
a episode I think five episodes ago four
episodes something like that yeah
amazing time we got really lit a lot of
fun she told me she told me yeah alie's
Allie's my daughter and um I was really
great that you guys got her in there
because she's really grown up in the
Cannabis space you know like she's seen
it all it's great to have the second or
third generation people come on the show
I feel like they have a different story
especially growing up when you're you're
fully immersed into it from the time
you're a little kid yeah and then
growing up and evolving and seeing the
world as it's it's changed so much you
know in the last 20 years especially I
know it I know it it really has yeah I
mean that we could go over the stories
but I'm sure that you guys probably
covered them so totally a lot of good
stuff yeah so let's dive into your story
so I know a little bit about your story
especially with salmon uh you know in
genetics the Cannabis breeding was out
of necessity for me and that was in the
late 990s when I was growing in the
woods gorilla style and it was like you
know we didn't have nurseries we didn't
have there was like the Amsterdam Seed
scene going on but it wasn't as
accessible you know and and so basically
for me I was like well I should just
probably figure out how to make sure I
have my own starting material for the
next season and so that just seeds made
sense and uh never once thought that it
would end with being a career and and a
you know something that we've been able
to sort of share with so many different
cannabis enthusiasts and uh I think a
lot of us are that way you know like I
mean you're a chef right right so you
know whether it's like inspiration from
being a taste maker or when High Times
magazine was my thing you know some guys
like play boy magazine when we were
teenagers whatever my thing was High
Times magazine that was the thing that
got me the most excited was reading
about cannabis and seeing cannabis and
seeing these people from around the
world Arian Ross cam uh and all these
other guys that were very inspirational
to me from a very young age I was like
those those were the people I looked up
to when I was a kid yeah yeah
so you asked about the whole salmon
thing you know back then I mean I was in
love with the fixing the rivers and the
S and helping restore salmon as well so
there were
passions uh with the breed in passions
with doing salmon stuff and and but you
certainly weren't in at least not in
California and humble or whatever
making careers and shouting from a
Mountaintop we're selling cannabis seeds
here you know so it was a different time
and uh my job that I chose to have you
know as
my uh front-end job um was the salmon
restoration work and which did like it
we started with undam the clamo where
that was 20 plus year project that just
we just finished off world's largest dam
removal and and uh world's largest like
really river river restoration
absolutely amazing by the way that's
really amazing well I I am not at all
like saying that it took so many people
it was like and really like tribes um
were so essential that our Native
American tribes up there in Humble count
well in Humble and all the all the way
up the river really Warren Buffett ended
up owning the the dams because it went
from a one power company to another kind
of Midway through our our fight against
the reler of the dam so it would have
been like another 50 years and that was
the impetus to really you know kick into
gear and then Burkshire hathway AKA
Warren Buffett ended up owning Pacific
War or Pacific Power um which like
provides Oregon Idaho
Montana a lot of the power up there and
the dams are on the border of California
and Oregon but the Utility Commission
line is literally at Humble County and
cisq County so the county north of us is
powered by the group we were fighting uh
owned by Warren Buffett and then um I
think we're all on uh pg&amp; of course
which has is their own horrific story of
corate greed that we've all been dealing
with um abely so like my house you know
I'd pay a power build a PG but you go
you know not very far up that River and
and it's um Pacific Power and so um yeah
just battling those guys and it was
really grass rootsy um at the time I did
a lot of the Grassroots stuff but I also
got really involved with uh doing some
genomics work around salmon and worked
at the Salmon her restoration Council as
their Fisheries program coordinator for
like 10 years and did um just general
salmon biology work doing that and but
one of the highlights
was uh getting a grant to do genetic
research and determining the difference
between two different runs of salmon
that are of the same species but you
could call them subspecies because they
acted so differently um one being a my
Springtime migrator and and then the
Fall Run shinook which is sort of like a
little bit more common place across you
know even across the Pacific Northwest
it's uh it's a neat area up there
because the tribes are really intact so
you have this like cool culture that is
um you know actually still a living
growing
culture
to anybody who lives there of course
tribes in particular a salmon that that
navigates the waterways in April May and
June is just such like an amazing
blessing
because you know I I am always like well
I I'm restoring salmon so I can eat more
of them really and I mean I I hate to
sound like you know some people might
not appreciate that how that sounds but
if you ask me like the very best way to
take care of Earth is to like live with
her and or whatever and um you know
eating what
was I kind of feel like meant to be our
sustenance as much as you can is kind of
cool actually and so that Spring Run
Salmon oh my God it's the best it's like
absolutely yeah yeah I'm finishing
Swedish so I I couldn't agree more I
think having respect for our food is so
important yeah just like respect for the
plant yes so we did that genomics
study um and ended up being worked at UC
Davis um where I just had this crash
course I mean I'm not a geneticist by
training but it's something that it
really you ended up looking into a a lot
and the study was published in Science
magazine which is kind of the
crowning publication that you can
publish your your research
uh and then another one a followup one
where we had discovered some salmon
bones that were in caves you know likely
or more than likely
from uh indigenous peoples that were in
the upper upper clamo above where those
dams were uh because of our first
research we were now able to Sequin you
know salmon remains that were like 5,000
years old and and be able to tell what
type they were whether they were like
running up the river in spring or
running up in fall and and a lot of that
might just sound like minutia or
whatever but it it's really important
stuff when it comes down to like
managing uh a river system and trying to
bring back an intact salmon run but the
similarities to now what's also
interesting to me you know just as an
example like Autoflower and photo period
cannabis yeah Cornell just published a
paper that is so so similar to like what
we did to find the the marker for and
I'm sure you're very familiar with like
this uh what we call Marker assisted
breeding right and so I think a lot of
people are like oh my gosh this all of a
sudden they think you're Gene editing
you're doing editing totally different
which there's a huge difference
between you know running around
willy-nilly and and slapping spider DNA
into other species and
doing learning looking a genome is like
a book and if I want to read a book you
know like more power too you know like
and that's always what I'm like you know
basically if if you you can think what
you want about GMO crisper Gene editing
and all that anyone who who looks at you
sideways when you say you're you're
trying to understand more about the
genetic background of an organism it's
just like well why would you not want
more knowledge you know simply just
knowledge and some of it can be so
incredibly useful and and what Cornell
did they P they found that one spot in
the genome where Autoflower and photo
period are differentiated and so it it
it makes it so basically like you know
as you very well know if you make a
cross of an auto and a photo you're G to
have progyny that
inherits all auto of you know kind of
took all that and then some that took
all the photo well when that F1
generation a lot of people are confused
because the F1 generation is not an
Autoflower it's a fast flowering variety
and so you get traits that are you know
passed from the Autoflower which make it
trigger faster make it finish faster but
it's not a true flower you need two of
the recessive genes together to make it
Express Auto that is true and then but
it also as you well know goes to how
pure bread or how homozygous are your
two parental lines because yeah when you
have not like parental lines like so
many of the Cannabis genetic lines that
we see in the space these days that are
not at all homozygous or stable or pure
bread whatever you want to call them um
which is like 99.9% of everything yeah
then you you're right you can get the
quick but you can also sort you can
actually end up with more full
inheritance on one end and full
inheritance on the other end and uh
that's why it's so I think it's so much
more useful to be able I always
say you know if you don't have stable
lines and
uniform then it's not as scientific
because the core of science is being
able to do an experiment and repeat it
again and have the same outcome so um
the only way to really do that is to
have some some uniformity in the genetic
well now we're getting deep though I
think now we're getting into the well
and the best way to do that is with data
driven breeding and the more you know
the more power you have to be successful
and then even tools like Ai and their
potential
in our space is just huge I think people
don't fully understand it so they're
scared of it but it's like AI with data
driven breeding and then predictive
modeling where you can take all your
genetic material uh have a database with
all of it and you can tell the AI
program exactly what you're trying to do
and they can help you get to that path
faster yeah
yeah at the same time I'm always like
well this ain't you know I because I
know we probably get pitched by the same
we do and our jeans and this that and
the other and and I love those guys but
I'm always reminding them like you know
cannabis is not soybeans like we're not
trying to breed something that is gonna
make our cows grow the fastest or you
know highest protein content highest oil
content most disease resistant there are
variables that are consistent like it
seems like people care about
TFC and as much as that is frustrating
sometimes to see you know we can breed
for those
individual uh sort of data points but I
know that folks like you and I aren't
aren't in it for that we're like it's
it's an art and I believe you know it's
also something like you know here we are
I'm trying this amazing whiskey that
you're sharing with me and by the way
it's I got these glasses because I had
issues with the corne scratch in my eye
so it's the first time I'm having a sip
of alcohol in about three weeks since I
scratched my cornea but um this is
amazing and it's not it's very
subjective that you and I enjoy this and
I think you know as much
as you know we can get help and we
should be getting help from AI models
and we should be getting help from
genetic sequences sure like this isn't
something that I would encourage uh the
Bayers of the world to just jump right
into because they're going to find out
real quick that the Cannabis consumer is
a like a subjective to the indivual
subjective to the individual and
absolutely and like you know I think
that this is amazing whiskey but you
know very well could be some whis
whiskey afficianado you could walk in
right behind me and tell me that's swill
garbage exactly I like my Jack Daniels
you know or or whatever it is you know
and that's that's the difference between
drug Discovery and the recreational
model or you know the model that we're
in which is somewhere in between you
know I think uh it's so subjective to
the individual and our unique body
chemistry is very different and and so
how the plant responds to us can be
completely different from one person to
the next and it's it's an art form we're
in a great space right now because I
feel like we're still the infancy of it
to a degree yeah you know we're only
going to improve on stuff uh but there's
you know there's a lot of snake oil out
there there's a lot of bad breeding out
there there's a lot of stuff going on
that's going to change over the next 10
years I think I agree I agree and for
those of us that have been in this for
long enough we've like learned a lot
from all the hype and trends that that
come and go and learned about all the
snake oil I like how that and I'm sure
that you've also come to the
conclusion after a time of potentially
like chasing the some of those dead ends
that like James
knows what to do yeah you know you
you're an expert you are an absolute
efficient Auto expert of this plant I
would you know hope to think that I have
some
expertise and you know it's it's folks
like us that I think honestly our best
you know what people will discover
eventually that like you know just have
faith in some of these you know Season
vets that have been loving this thing
for since 91 for me since 91 yeah since'
91 I started smoking in ' 91 and fell in
love with it I I think that's probably I
was 12 years old a skater
kid and like in the Gully you know with
the other skater kids that were much
older had my first toes and that would
have been probably like 91 literally 991
so we're right on bar and then you know
I moved to humbled in 95 and then it
wasn't on like just a pilgrimage to to
go to this weed Mecca of the world at
the time or at least the US I'll say it
just happened to be that I ended up
there traveling the
country with my my girlfriend at the
time and I just
stayed fell in love with the that place
in general and weed but but that place
you know like yeah I can't go to Humble
too often because I might end up moving
there to be 100% honest yeah I mean I I
got we have a lot of good mutual friends
yeah and I go up there and visit like
the guys from Royal gold oh yeah and
it's like it's you Rick oh yeahi they've
been on the show when I moved to humbled
um Rick was one of the first people that
I ended up being really you know tight
buddies with we lived together actually
on a hippie commune together for a time
it was a very very relaxed like not
culty kind of a thing but you know yeah
right right after the summer of love and
all that you know some of those hippies
like they call them the diggers and they
were sort of the hippies that were like
more let's get back to the land let's
get roots of what this counterculture
movement is which is to like make our
own way and and not be so conventionally
tied and an anti-war and all that good
stuff but um yeah then they Janus Joplin
people contributed money to buy this
piece of land up there and uh it's
called Black Bear and it still exists
actually so Rick and I landed there um I
did like a brief stint uh chasing around
the grateful Dad and then Jerry Garcia
of course died 95 was a rough
year yeah but that was the year that I
just you know didn't I mean my
girlfriend and I we had gone to many
Dead shows yeah Rick and I both landed
there at the same time and so I've known
Rick and uh and Rob Gail a humble turp
Council we all lived at that place in in
the 95 996 kind of time frame and and
then of course that was when the
proposition 215
yeah came to pass 1996 we hitchhiked
from that commune to go get registered
to vote I wasn't inspired by like
[ __ ] Bill Clinton running for
president for his second term I was
inspired to go register to vote to vote
Yes on proposition
215 which the first legalization of of
cannabis in any way shape or form kind
of I don't know I guess maybe that's not
there's been some things but it was the
major one it was the major one that
really put us on the path to where we
are now yes yes without prop 15 I don't
know if we would be where we're at today
I would say definitely not I always like
to shout out you know the Dennis Peron
yeah types of and Dennis I think was the
big push but there was other people
people in humbal even like Ken Miller uh
was an co-author on there there was
totally people helped Dennis in writing
that and um but we owe a great service
to him as in you know the Cannabis world
and and that was too good of a law it
was too well perfected for us to be able
to really get to know the plan and enjoy
it
and many of us I think respected the um
true intention of the law which was
to you
know clear a path for people to a have
access in particular people that were in
great need with you know any medical
issue that they could have um
right uh obviously there was it came
Dennis was in the Castro area of San
Francisco and HIV was a major issue at
the time they hadn't developed a lot of
the medic medications that they have now
and so people were really suffering and
also you know we're still dealing with
cancer everywhere you look people have
cancer and that was another more now
more now it feels like maybe more yeah
maybe it's because we're older but it
sure feels like more to me yeah so for
that to be compassionate use you know
was the the how we everybody it was
framed at the time it's like and and I
mean I think it was more than just
compassionate use it was it still is
always has been a medicine
and um but that was the The Cry for
common sense was like you know we got
people that are going to pass away if
they they want to ease their pain with
cannabis instead of opiates instead of
like you know all this other
mind-numbing stuff and you know who in
the world is to tell them that they
shouldn't be able to use it and then and
and but it really was the way he wrote
that the initiative the voter initiative
was that you know any doctor can
recommend that cannabis is probably not
not a bad thing to use for you you know
and and I had mine for any number of
things I mean half the time I would just
wait for the doctor to prompt something
I was like what do you want to write it
for this year you know but and and I
certainly did have back pain I mean I
had tons of back pain yeah I mean most
of it was from hauling heavy bags of
soil into my gorilla grows but yeah
miles miles down into the gorilla grows
yeah that'll do it it's like I was
taking cannabis for my
cannabis but um that that was an amazing
time to be alive in California uh and as
anything you know every amazing
thing does tend to get spoiled wants it
you know everything yeah everything
changes the the only thing constant is
change that's correct yeah but it was an
amazing time I mean it still is an
amazing time it's just different right I
think it's amazing there's a lot of
jaded people unfortunately and I mean I
think there's been a lot of suffering
that have happened in the industry
especially up in Humble yeah um but yeah
n late 990s were a special time I mean
even in genetics right when we talk
about the diversity that we had yeah uh
you know stuff that was in Humble was
different mesina was different than the
bay there was more genetics and more
diversity but you know I feel like each
Place had their own thing Europe was
completely different and now we've got
uh we've got this this uh internet and
social media that is kind of like made
cannabis a certain way or the way we
look at it is a certain way whereas back
in the day it wasn't about how it looks
so much it was like how did it make you
feel how did it taste look was kind of
secondary I mean obviously people you
eat with your eyes but I feel like some
of the best stuff wasn't the most
beautiful stuff 100% the the first
impression came from opening the bag and
smelling you know and that was how I
sold every pound I've I sold in the late
90s early 2000s it's just all that and
yeah look matters of course well when we
were kids everything was less
homogenized you could go to Oregan and
get different soda and different candy
and you know I mean I'm I'm from
Portland Oregon originally and coming in
the Bay Area I grew up in the Bay Area
but we would go up there and I'd be look
looking forward to get the different
candy when I was a little kid you know
six seven eight years old we would go on
road trips and there'd be different
things and cannabis was the same way
you'd go up to Oregon and You' get
different varieties than you would in
humbled and and then Mendo had their own
thing going for sure and but there was a
lot of breeding going on back then I
mean I think people were breeding for
like yourself for seed stock to keep the
stock alive for the next year the best
stuff yeah I mean there hasn't been a
year since
998 where I didn't make a batch of seeds
to have for the next year and it in
9798 it
was cross two or three things with one
male even by like
200123 it started to dawn on me that I
probably should have separate places is
for separate males and and you know yeah
when I one of my gorillas got
camped uh for those that don't know that
means
helicopters come in and they take all
your all your stuff yeah Camp was an
interesting organization yeah to say the
least well what it was always humble
State University the big school in
Humble now cowply humble is doing a oral
history study so a lot of the time when
things are so storied that that and and
like back to like our whole genetics
thing like remember the the evil company
phos right oh
yeah I'll go I'll come out and say it
that you know all of us I think probably
you know I spotted that a mile away
though absolutely did smarter man than
me I mean I went to dinner with Ellen
from you from phos multiple times they
were interested in working with me yeah
um and I just knew something wasn't
right there was just no way it didn't
make sense to me yeah and I ended up
being right you know but Rob Clark he
was on their board of directors I have a
lot of respect for Rob yeah and what he
does and I think maybe Ellen you know
Ellen's still my my friend and and even
she's a good person what's her name is
still Alicia right yeah um and I don't
even hold anything against you know mle
either it was that it was a lot of
speculation about what cannabis was
going to be and I think that they had
taken a ton of really close investment
money like getting money from your
buddies and then all of a sudden like
you know no one was not as many people
were interested in paying for just that
genotyping service so then it was like
they didn't have I mean it was either
like screw over their friends or screw
over the Cannabis space as a whole and I
think they chose the ladder you know
what I mean which who knows like if if
we got in that situation what we I don't
know but they were too big too fast and
it was kind of like a with great power
comes great
responsibility you know and so like and
but you know what I don't even believe
that they ever really had great power
and still to this day the the anecdotal
list and this was kind of where my point
was was like this anecdotal list of
submissions that didn't even really have
phenotypic full genome sequencing either
and they they were
we can look at 8,000 Snips for 40s I
mean exactly like my florid DNA they do
2,000 and it's 80 bucks or whatever 60
80 bucks and so what they were doing was
I mean we came to find that out pretty
quickly because like and and Rob and
Mojave Robert Clark and Mojave they it
was so wild they called me up one day
and I was so honored I'm like oh my God
you know like move Richmond and Robert
Clark to talk and and they're mad at me
and I'm like wait a second what in the
world I've never even met you what what
could I have possibly done they're like
how did you get that submission that
just you just called it train wreck seed
number I don't know it's still online
people can look this up it was like
train wreck seed number 13 and it was
like we submitted it and I don't
remember
20187 or something like that 2016
probably and um yeah and we weren't like
super in deep with those guys I mean at
some point they were cording us just
like they were recording you we
submitted some things into the
library you know and to me I I always
knew it was anecdotal you know like of
course like and and and people would be
like why would you submit their genetics
they can they could take them and use
them I was like they can take them and
use them tomorrow by going to the
dispensary in Arcada that has all of my
seeds and spending
$500 and just buying one each of
everything then they have them alive
like I'm sending them dead leaf tissue
like that's a lot less dangerous than me
putting my seeds in a dispensary and
they can go get them right so I'm like I
don't understand what you're telling me
to be scared about you're right they
were obviously there was nefariousness
involved eventually what Robert Clark
and Mojave were interested in is how I
got the exact duplicate of their very
best thing their sage and and I said I
didn't have your very best Tuple I
submitted a uh seedling that well we had
phenotyped it out so it was like from
seed and it was um a beautiful we were
creating a line that was
most reminiscent or Mo we were copying
train wck and Seed form is what we were
trying to do which um you did a lot of
that too by the way that you had a OG G
Kush and a blue dream and well you know
to me it just made sense I like I had
people in Humble that were had been
growing for 20 years that were like we
love growing from seed we love growing
your seed but now all of a sudden all
the buyers only want OG Kush and they're
like why can't you just make a seed that
is OG Kush and I'm like well there's no
reason why you can't it just takes some
time and you know back when tomatoes
were the early days of
tomatoes you couldn't get a seed and
know it was going to be a cherry tomato
or know it was going to be a slicer or
know it was going to be Aroma you had to
make had to work that out and that's
making home is likea seed lines right or
stable or uniform whatever you want to
call it and so when they said you
know people that have been growing in
the hills of humble for
30 years and way older than me and they
were my heroes and mentors and they said
like oh man we hate growing
from these clones that we have to get
now if we want to stay competitive
because the only thing people would buy
is this one strain can you just make
that and so I that was the thing that
triggered humble Seed Company to start
working on doing pure breed lines and
yeah and having uniform warm outcomes on
seed the irony of course and this is
like once again back to my warning to uh
Bayer and senta out there like it took
me about eight years to make an OG cush
strain and and don't you're right I I
put probably put the name OG Kush on
that seed pack probably before I should
have but um now I know better but it
really it did take like six to eight
generations to have the the line to
where like 100% you know like we were
over at Soma Hills and they're like this
is this is all like the entire 80 plants
that we planted is OG Kush from clone
like 100% And it's all from seed but it
is 100% that it's very difficult to do
and I a lot of people don't understand
they're like well I just put OG Kush
with OG Kush I S1 it it's like we're
talking about recessive traits oh no and
we're talking about a lot of difficult
traits to make Express right
one having a clone of it and it's one
thing maybe you pop a bunch of seeds and
you have one or two or 10 or 20 but to
make the whole progyny Express OG cush
is why there was you know DNA did a good
job with having stuff that was very
gassy and cushy but like as far as a
real OG Kush in seed form it's it's like
you can't just S1 it and expect to get
the results you're looking for it's same
thing why there's no real Sour Diesel
seeds that are the real real Sour Diesel
I don't care there's some good bx1
there's some good bx4 some guys have
some really good inbred sour that
they've been working on Karma genetics
JJ from Top Dog Leo from efficient Auto
yeah but it's very difficult to do yeah
and to get it express to express across
the board is so much more difficult than
people want to give it credit for yeah
and you're basically like you're selling
someone a feno hunt where hopefully they
find sour in it you know and that was
not what I wanted to do with making the
OG of course by the time not making the
strain OG don't yeah but making seeds
that were uh mimicked OG as as closely
as possible and I I would like actually
if Josh G's out there listening like I
would love to hear if you think that we
did okay because I feel like we did
eventually but the ironic part of it was
that it was we were finished way past OG
Kush being cool and it was just like so
now I've got but now it's coming back
back now it's coming back I think OG is
make it comeback in the next year I mean
it's already I'm seeing it already again
in flour I see people getting excited
about it I hope it does same with sour I
hope it does yeah and I hope sour comes
back but that one proved to be a lot
more difficult in my opinion it's very
very the nose on the original Sour
Diesel is something that like I don't
even think there's many many of us old
farts out there that even remember what
that smell was you know and it's like
you find it in you're like oh my God
this is it God takes me back to like
1993 you know I was hoping to have some
today Dave from budalo and he's up in
Yukaya I don't know if you know Dave
Dave is the steward of the sour he's the
he came to me reg on the river it was
like hey I got this basically wanted to
know what I thought of it and I was like
this is the real Sour and that was when
in that moment I realized that all these
sour I'd seen the stuff I'd seen you
know a lot of people have given me sour
the last couple years yeah this is gassy
sour well the real Sour had a very
distinct nose that wasn't it was gassy
and it was loud but it was so complex
and so Citrus and so you know funky and
it would burn your nostrils and he has
that yeah and you know there's not a lot
of people that are willing to grow it or
could even grow it to that level yeah
it's it's difficult on so and that's the
thing is it's not like a really
commercially viable thing this in this
day and age because unfortunately it's
rare that people are willing to pay
double to get to smoke like me I would
in a heartbeat because it would just
take me back to like even high school
you know but definitely like the early
mid 90s is well it's hard to put a price
on an experience I know for me it's like
for especially for sour it's like I just
want I want to smoke it yeah it's great
that he has put it on and then you know
it has a shelf life and all these other
things but it's hard for to get it to
express every time like that too yeah
and it's like you know you're looking at
10 plus weeks yeah uh you know and the
structure isn't the best it's a very
finicky plant but same thing with OG and
I've heard OG actually expresses better
under CMH and HPS that it does under all
the new LEDs which makes perfect sense
why a lot of people yeah if they do grow
it they're probably not getting the
results that we're looking for with OG
kush yeah and and that you touched on
with all sour thing like if it's real
Sour it also just doesn't look the way
that people expect buds to look these
days yeah which is like you know to be
honest I got to shout out to Mario
shinsky for I always loved the way that
like those you know kind of like cookie
crosses that came out of um gelato and
sunset sherbet yeah yeah and and like I
was
really taken by how beautiful that
cannabis looked yeah um and and the
smells are great too but that set a kind
of a difficult standard for like you
know when people are used to seeing the
Cannabis that looks that kind of cool in
a dispensary than if they were to see
sour and not have the background of of
us of being like smelling it and knowing
like whoa this is going to have a a
really different if effect than what
you're used to um and and Trigger like a
whole different set of cannaboid
receptors in your mind which you know
like uh my business partner Ben and and
hie and everybody a bunch of us went to
Morocco and now I'm Tang I'm tanging but
uh like cannabis is a Pandora box of
capability and uh you know we got over
there and seeing what they are growing
over there the plants that they're
growing just such a different animal but
but you know they want to make a hash
only no such thing as trimmed buds at
all ever no you got to wash it they not
not wash it but they process it so the
static machines are what's going to blow
up over there because it automates their
process you know I think yeah it's it's
a different world over there and what
genetics work over there and compared to
here is completely just different yeah
it's completely
different it wasn't a conventional I got
high from smoking it it was like just a
totally different feeling than what I
get when I smoke cannabis yeah you know
we're going to spark up right oh yeah
yeah I'm not sure what we're about to
smoke yeah but for those folks out there
that think that like THC is what you
should be shopping for or even like what
the lab said the Turpin profile was or
anything it's just our science and in in
the Cannabis space yeah and don't get me
wrong like I have so much respect for
the folks that are out there doing the
lab work and pushing the right you know
understanding of what cannabis does but
you have to have to have to try it
before you pass any judgment or anything
like that because I mean I know a
million people that would have looked at
that what they call belda out there
which is like the local uh Moroccan type
cannabis and they probably would have
just been like I'm not even GNA bother
smoking that I'm not whatever and and
and would have totally missed out on
just a completely different experience
yeah from Cannabis so Dave from budalo
in Yukaya he's dude he's great cuz he
does long flyering varieties right so
he's all about long fllying varieties an
effect and I think we need to go back in
that direction to like how does it make
you feel yeah you know it's like with
fenal hunts like I smoke joints with
people and I'm like well how does it
taste how does it make you feel yeah I
feel like the future for us especially
for some of this magic is to share it
with people in pre-rolls or hand rolls
to where they get to experience it with
the you know as far as like everyone
wants convenience so having a a pen
that's great having a a joint is even
better in my opinion and then you get to
experience it for what it should be you
should be able to overlook the way it
looks on social media I mean whatever
like people like the way stuff looks but
I feel like effect is just so much more
important and there's stuff like white
Thorn roses kind of taking over you know
Johnny Johnny's great you know he's been
on the podcast and really like every
single podcast somebody brings a white
Thorn Rose yeah and it's Feelgood weed
it's stuff that makes you feel great you
know it's like it's not you can't
categorize it as an indicia or TAA it's
not your typical run-of-the-mill thing
but it's one of those things that makes
you feel amazing yeah and it's like
that's a lot like our blueberry muffin
strain which is always been just like to
me the most comforting cannabis high
that that you I've ever you know and and
Johnny's White thn Rose I like it's
amazing and and a lot of these things
what I try to remind people is like look
when you're swimming in different weed
all around you all the time and you have
a mill jars of strains and things that
you can try from and you don't you're
not just after getting as high as you
can quickly and and I think like what we
see with people going after like you
know just walking into a dispensary and
being like what's your highest CHC thing
it's kind of like I I don't know this
for sure but I could easily imagine when
PE when they stopped prohibiting alcohol
in the US that people probably were like
I mean during prob for example people
for sure only were drinking hard stuff
you know or only moving hard stuff
around the heart of the better because
you know you're hiding it um and even
I'm sure you know in the first time
during legalization of of alcohol that
people probably it probably took a long
time for fine wine to really make a
comeback you know the government made it
difficult too I think they made it
extremely difficult but but bardi 151 is
not the number one sell are in the
liquor store God thank God and I don't
think the strongest cannabis is going to
be like that either year from now it
might be the strongest selling thing
in I don't know I mean I don't know
anybody that drinks 151 or ever clear
but it's just it seems like if you're if
you're like you know only if you're just
trying to achieve one goal which is to
just INE inebriate yourself and forget
about your suround young young people
maybe they like Long Island Ice teas you
know that kind of thing but but yeah I
think most of us the more sophisticated
the more your pallette becomes educated
the less you're worried about the THC
percentage blueberry muffin's a great
one I did some crosses with it I was
hoping to have samples for you today uh
because I feel like those clones are
kind of special and so the finished
flower yeah I mean I love that I I got
it I think I told the story on the
podcast with hie but I got blueberry
muffin on axent I was trying toy by a
clone of DJ shorts blueberry oh yeah I
grew it out and I'm like this isn't it
but this is pretty freaking special
smells like blueberry muffins and turns
out it was blueberry muffin yeah
everybody always assumes that we made it
out of TJ schs blueberry no there's no
and we didn't have anything to do with
that one and as much as you know like
it's funny because my wife who just
dropped me off was very very close with
DJ Short and she was just like he's
gonna want to kick your butt if you name
a stram blueberry muffin hun and I'm
like and and then we actually met up
with DJ short and he was just like what
no [ __ ] do it man like what are you
talking about you can't name that
anything else though cuz it's it smells
exactly it smells exactly like that's
what frustrates me with names now when
somebody takes a name and then you have
something that's that fits that
description better because all the names
are kind of taken from pling things you
know you can't name something apple
crisp or apple pie because there's
probably five apple pies out there even
if yours smells more like apple pie I
know Kung chicken that's that I don't
know if that's taking but I've seen some
kungpow chicken turps heck yeah man oh
my God hie found this bizarre TP we were
doing a big big hunt and she finds this
one and she's just like what the heck
this smells like a Sal like salami like
spoton and you know who in the world
like would even want cannabis that
smells like salami I mean we did try to
get we got a qu Itali Italians they
probably should that's true but um the
this plant is amazing and just a little
like factoid that you know you probably
know I mean you wrote the book on the
topic I always reiterate this one though
because I I think it's special cannabis
is like one of
six% of the plant kingdom that does not
screw itself on the regular or or is
unlikely to screw itself so it's like
because it has a male and a female on
two SE separate plants that's really
pretty rare it's like 94% of plants just
like us for the most part just well
humans dasis versus monious though yeah
for sure yeah so it's ious versus manous
and you know genetically that leads to
the potential for a lot more you know
genetic paths to you know diverence or
whatever you want to call it and with
cannabis is like connection to humanity
which I feel like is really really deep
um it makes sense that we have all of
these different Turpin profiles and and
yeah you know all these other amazing
things that we're discovering beyond
turpens that are just as important or
more important and and then even the
most important thing is just at the end
of the day what it does to you when you
consume it or and how you know it's Med
medicinal for us as people and
therapeutic for us as people and and
freaking you know
salami smelling cannabis you know I
wouldn't want it to go away I want all
the options we can get you know I agree
yeah yeah all these different colors you
know if you're a painter the more colors
the better yes soami mother's Magnolia
out of organ they have beef stew you
know they really do and there was like
that meat breath strain there's meat
breath there's there's been some
interesting ones but I'm ready to smoke
how about you let's do it and then oh I
got we're talking about breeding let's
take a break but when we come back we've
been experimenting with some pepper
breeding and making a little hobby hot
sauce too nice yeah that's great I love
hot sauce too we goofing around with it
it's not you know I make it with my kids
because I can't go and and like do as
much cannabis stuff with my kids nice
it's yeah I I love I just made some uh
some Jam
not selling it we're giving it away
giving it man let's tap into these
joints I got some uh the dirt Skittles I
smoke with hi so I think it's only fair
to smoke it with you as well man and
this stuff is really special I heard it
got you guys you guys are lit on the the
podcast huh yeah Skittles normally
doesn't I mean Skittles gets me feeling
great sure but as far as like I smoke
some stronger stuff typically if I want
to get that effect and this stuff for
whatever
reason we did this soil versus cocoa my
my buddies SF Cana did a trial in a room
the only variable they changed which is
the way you do a real trial is to tra
yeah change one variable and they uh use
soil versus cocoa uhuh and I really
enjoy the soil so this is dirty Skittles
huh dirty Skittles I like the name yeah
and you know it's like I love Coco too I
have no no problem with I use rockwool
for my moms and we do for for clones we
use Rock Wool ston Wool
grodan shout out to my friends over at
grodan but yeah there's something
special about soil and especially for
flavor I don't think soil always looks
necessarily the best but as far as
effect and flavor you get different
Expressions regardless of what you use
for substrate it's different soil versus
cocoa versus Rock you're getting
different effect different Expressions
so
true it's the beauty of the plant man I
mean and and it's like not just genetics
too it's environment a lot of things
come into it environment nutrition ter
they would say environment nutrition
dictate phenotypes right it's like if
we're talking about chemotypes that can
be a whole another thing right you can
you can have I think those things play
into that a little bit too for sure for
sure whereas the genotypes they stay the
genotypes yes true that I mean there
what epigenetic changes can
occur yeah we started talking about
genetic drift that we go down that
rabbit hole U and then epigenetic
changes and then how tissue culture can
play a part in that I used to be really
good at that you knock the Rings through
the Rings I could knock the Rings
through the Rings and all that stuff and
then it like then all the The Vape
people were like experts Wizards at it
and then I then I was kind of like oh
man they start ruined it for us lead
heads Mak drawings in the air with stuff
it's wild it's wild yeah I mean how
things evolve I mean back when like uh
Texas holdom was really big you know and
and all my friends would always and I
liked playing it I I wasn't like super
into it but I like going for the social
aspect of sitting around with a bunch of
buddies and and playing a game to hold
them and or turny or whatever and uh
that was the thing we be like so thick
the room would be so thick you could cut
the smoke you know and and just all of
us just playing around blowing smoke
rings across the table we got good at it
for sure and then the vaporizers ruined
it dabs vaporizing you know they it's
just it's gone in an interesting
Direction and it keeps getting uh more
interesting and evolves further and
further and further like the enails and
then all of a sudden we've got these
yeah uh electric you know dab devices
yeah really cool stuff I Vape I mean I'm
not like against it but uh it just
wasn't the same as it was well I'm happy
that joint I love I'll never stop
smoking weed through a a joint no I feel
like that's the best way to identify the
flaws yeah are are you know whether it's
in the genetics or whether it's with the
cultivation of it that's true drawing in
the keing it's easier to have it's like
simple to have flavors Express well yeah
in uh you know rosin or live resin
or Vapes maybe it's not as easy cuz I've
had some terrible Vapes too but um yeah
no you're right joints is like the test
true good point I never thought of it
that way yeah I mean I enjoy smoking a
good joint and also like uh how far down
does it still taste good when you
relight it does it taste good when you
light it up the next day totally all
those things and and how does the flavor
change because some stuff it smells
great and then or it smells good and
then you go to light it and sometimes
even off the first hit purple punch is
my you know I talk about a lot on the
show but it's a big let down for me as
far as like it it's a beautiful looking
plant so from a cultivator perspective
yeah dud purple punches where it's at
it's like looks beautiful yeah it smells
pretty good in fact the rosin and the
extract is decent but the joint when you
have a joint and a lot of stuff that's
breed with it has this too where you
light it up and then all of a sudden
you're like where's the chirps chirps
are missing so true and so you know and
that's that goes to like what we've been
talking about you know as far as beay
and all these companies that want to
look at stuff I think a lot of people
are like well let's just breed with the
data it doesn't work like that you
cannot just breed with the data because
it's so subjective and on paper a lot of
stuff looks great I mean even on on
Instagram a lot of stuff looks great
that's not you know so we get we get all
this variation that is very subjective
to the individual and it takes somebody
who knows what they're talking about to
go through knows what they're looking at
smoking smelling tasting experiencing
true yeah I me imagine that two seasoned
cannabis veterans sitting here talking
about how important it is to be seasoned
cannabis no but there's it's like
undeniable that it's true and and when
some of these kids learn real quick i'
I've see some of these younger guys like
they're like oh well I like this stuff I
like this stuff and I don't like this
stuff and they they develop a palet
really quickly but it's also data points
like uh you know you come from a science
background I'm a chef but have a lot of
experience in science and it's like the
more data points you have the better
and so experiencing it's the same way
the more times you tried it you have a
better idea of what you like and what
you don't like yeah um you know it's
like if you have you know a year of
experience it doesn't really add up to
having a complete pallet yeah and then
with outdoor it's like every year is a
little bit different you know so if you
grow the same thing Outdoors every year
it's slightly different you really need
to experience it multiple years to fully
understand that plant well that's the
truth and people ask us a lot you as
well I'm sure about you know what can I
grow this year that will finish at this
certain time or has a resistance to PM
be Petrus whatever it is you know that
that got him the year before now you
know the the septoria was never really a
thing for anybody that in California at
least like not traditionally it's coming
out here I've been really surprised to
see it so often lately and I feel like
it's almost like a more d ous monster
than the Hop Leon like yeah septoria is
gnarly but um that's a whole another
topic I guess what we were talking about
was uh the reactionary
overcorrect that happens so often in
cannabis and it's nobody's fault I don't
ever fault a grower but how many years
did I have it just dump rain in you know
on October 10 and then like two days
later it was 85 again outside and
everything just molded yeah and then the
next year I just was like I'm not
growing anything that finishes later
than this certain day when the stuff
molded or whatever it happened last year
and then the next year it dumps
September 20th and yeah all the stuff
that you
Knowle Auto
flowers there's that well it was like
you'd always have a still a couple ones
that were the the late ones because you
had to grow them and uh those ones would
just be beautiful and totally clean even
though they got rained on yeah they
might get get crushed by rain but they
don't get any metritis they don't get
any PM it like did them good you're like
oh man they did it so that's exactly
what you were saying was sort of like uh
having not all your eggs in one basket
or not all your turps in one genre and
and all of those things data driven
breeding towards some of these goals
like we want but the beautiful thing
about Coastal environments like up in
Humble you can really test for petritis
and PM resistant plants yeah but from
one Ridge to the next as we had Johnny
and Jason talk about from Huckleberry
and ridg line it's like the plant will
Express differently so there's all these
different variables and with
microclimates you don't know exactly how
the plant's going to perform and then
that gets us into another interesting
conversation which is land race
preservation I know you're doing some
land race preservation working with land
race my business friend Ben has been
doing um really cool stuff down you know
cuz you just mentioned I think we were
off camera but uh same been and all that
and you guys donated 10,000 seeds I
donated 30,000 yeah you guys did great I
mean props to you guys and you know Big
Mike's donated some seeds as well from
love it love it from Advanced and I
think there's people that are willing to
give back and people to share and you
know and not expecting anything in
return like that's the culture that's
real can anabis culture right there is
and and I know I'm sure my daughter
talked all about you know the $1,700
pies auctions for the elementary school
and absolutely you know paying $1,700
for a blackberry pie so that the school
gets to have a field trip again this
year that's paying taxes I don't care
how you look at it and so you know there
was a time when people grumbled a lot
about the prop 215 and and you know all
those dope Growers just they don't pay
taxes on it and all that this that and
the other well there was a lot of taxing
happening self taxing excuse me and um
it changed so much in Humble um the
economy you know I appreciate actually
what you said about um one of the
hardest hit places because it really was
um you know as a county whatever you
want to call whole Emeral triangle as a
community as a county whatever however
you want to put it however you want to
put it we were so because of humble in a
lot of ways in some ways yeah and and we
were
so uh dependent on it and I don't know
how much some of like our County
officials and and these aren't even
people that are like far removed from
from the culture and everything like
there's we have
definitely uh County Supervisors for
example who you know are full total
supporters if not partakers in cannabis
and um they didn't even I think have any
idea how much a town like Garberville
was dependent on the economy of the
Cannabis economy the Cannabis economy
whether it was pre pro pre you know
recreational legalization or or post
that there was those taxes self taxes
were staying right there and helping the
schools helping fire departments helping
all of these you know sort of Public
Services then not to mention you know
tons of money spent at small business
that thrived in Humble we actually had
the highest concentration of nonprofit
groups in the entire United States in
Humble County for a time I'm not sure if
it's still that way probably
is so there was a lot of that and now
there's just no way that folks like
Jason and and Johnny and and for that
matter people that are even like a lot
less well-known right uh cultivators out
in the hills of humble could ever even
be asked like I mean we've had to cancel
our County you know acreage or square
foot tax for the last like five years
for four or five years which a lot of us
Growers like wanted to pay it we were
more than willing and there wasn't a lot
of argument from the Cannabis Community
uh like my wife is on a long lived
Environmental Group and worked there for
close to 20 years now and uh put they
put um all the tree sits and Woody
harelson up locking himself to the
Golden Gate Bridge to protect redwoods
and and um you know Bonnie R playing the
concert every single summer her her
great story is that you know how many
times someone would just come into the
to the office where that was a lot of
that was coordinated from and just drop
off a
non-descript brown paper bag and you
open it up and they they no names no
nothing out the door but it was like big
sacks of of cash to help you know do
this like pro bono from the thriving
cannabis economy from the thriving
cannabis County and I'm not saying it
has to go back to that I believe in
taxes and I believe in you know the
local government and the way that things
have worked up but but no one knew how
difficult it was going to be made by
onerous regulation and there were also a
lot of promises that weren't kept like
namely one of the biggest arguments for
the prop 64 that was within the space
that we were in which was the growing
Community yeah which we had the most to
gain or lose probably because we could
lose like the way that we interacted for
many years with the plant and then for
probably if you were like me for the
most part the way that we interacted
economically although you know like I
always had a job with the you know doing
salmon biology stuff but that wasn't
really just to be honest paying all the
bills right uh so I was a music teacher
for a short while at a school a local
school not like a real accredited but
that was just another way to put some
money in the pocket but cannabis put
cannabis put the food on the table put
the food on the table but yeah it it
allowed you know I look at the
generation that's coming up right now
and I can understand why people are
there's a lot of like feels like a lot
of unrest in in their country because I
just don't feel like there's equity and
like being able to own land or or own a
home is just so Out Of Reach I think it
feels that way at least for so many
people that are young that you know if I
was young right now that might be you
know a passion that I would follow would
be trying to create more more Equity at
the time when I came out west and and
even before I moved out west I had I was
sort of imp passionate about nature and
yeah and and I still am of course but um
people got to live too so got on another
tangent boy that that's some good stuff
I like the dirty Skittles it's good it's
dirty yeah it's good it's got good TPS
it's yeah I mean you can't go wrong with
people that say they don't like Skittles
have not tasted this because it's it's
hard if you like cannabis and you like
candy it's pretty candy oh it's candy I
mean I think people that say they don't
like Skittles probably have tried to
grow it because it's not it's a pain in
the neck to grow it's a pain in the ass
the plant is a pain in the ass I know if
anybody would argue with me on that one
when breeding breeding with Skittles you
can find the Skittles Expressions real
easily because they're the ones that
grow the shittiest they're the ones that
that look ugly you I can spot them
typically with my crosses and I've done
a bunch of work with Skittles trying to
tease out the Skittles turbs totally
it's like the ones that are real Skittle
they all look like Skittles yeah so
wimpy and harded can't I can't take it
it's too bright it's too dark I'm gonna
get milde right I'm not trying to beat
up any strain though and we have we've
definitely got like we have a strain we
call hibiscus that's half Skittles half
blueberry muffin and they're not that
different really but but blueberry
muffin is one of the easiest things
there is that I it's like beginner bud
you know and I don't want to say that
but it's it's great if if you've never
tried any to grow before because it
doesn't get and have a lot of those
problems yeah blueberry muffin is an
interesting one so let's talk about that
for a little bit because I really like
it and I think I think the genetic
lineage is important it doesn't
blueberry muffin do have Skittle but no
it but we cross it with it and blueberry
muffin really came from a day that I
know a time that I know that you
remember as well where strains that had
names on them were a lot more rare than
just seeds that you got from the
community that were just like and and
there were certainly plenty of things
that that had names and came to us in
that form with like you know this is
granddaddy perss or something like that
was an old one you know I don't know
like just but more often than not the
our source material for breeding at that
time in the early 90s was not like
anything that had a name especially you
know in a place like humble where there
was so much
genetics kind of yeah ended up go coming
there because so many people were
growing and uh yeah blue ray muffin was
was really like a strain that there were
seeds that were M new skin supposedly
that I had gotten there were a good
batch of seed that's from Oregon that we
called the Oregon grape that was yeah we
had the Oregon blueberry it was an
interesting it was a spear-like plant it
wasn't anything related to DJ shorts
short Inda plant uhhuh but uh yeah organ
had some good genetics too yeah the or
blackberry kush from Humble now that was
an interesting one that was like a CBD
variety before we had CBD varieties yeah
I wasn't ever a huge fan of that one one
but some of them were just and then um
and then there was that uh the Raz and
and so the blueberry muffin did have all
of those things in it like the first
thing that I ever
actually had ended up creating a moniker
strain name for um out of the
encouraging people over at um purple
heart uh which is right up the road yeah
literally of thead and they were so
sweet there was this one buyer in there
and and remember you'd go down in that
basement kind of space and if you you
know that was where you were allowed to
go if you were either selling or a part
of the the management or something like
that and I just thought it was so cool
get down there and and she said you know
this is just so unique and special and I
really just think you ought to name this
and she was like it's beautiful it's per
purple and and why don't you you should
just start calling the strain Purple
Passion and so I was like that's amazing
I love it and I do have the seeds like
somewhat uniform
stable so called it purple passion and
and it led to me writing a little bit
for Oaker Dam news remember that little
news newspaper that and when Oaker dam
was at its sort of um I mean that was
like the beginning of Harborside and
right dude I can't believe that they
just now they're like getting shut down
or receivers they like they basically
receivership well they went to State
Line and right Steve and Andrew were
long gone you know they did on my
podcast we just were at their
anniversary Reunion yeah which was great
in Oakland it rooted in the 510 yeah but
yeah interesting story uh about the
original name because Jimmy Myers from
GDP the the GDP the guy oh how GDP got
his name was uh at the third floor they
he didn't care what it was called and
they said they wanted to call it
Granddaddy perss and so that's where the
name Granddaddy Purple came from
originally regardless of all the other
stories from all the other people that
that was the original name from his
stuff that he had gotten the cut from he
was just a steward like a lot of us um
with special Cuts you know it's like
over the years so then she she said that
I wrote about it under the pseudonym uh
because back then man you was not people
don't don't realize like even though it
was medically legal you were still
taking a big risk and I mean you know I
talked a little bit about my days as a
gorilla grower what was your pseudonym
my pseudonym was uh there was a
president of humble State University and
I always thought his name was just kind
of super sort of snoody sound and his
name was Rand Richmond and it was just
like I'm sir Rolland Richmond and a lot
better than GW kush or something like
that no no no so I call myself uh Rin
like looked like Rolland right and so I
just went with a Roland a and then the
last name was big old Bud big big old
rolling a bigle rolling rolling a bigle
bud yeah so you can I think even like
Google find some of the articles but
nice purple passion and that was
probably like
200 you know two or three or something
either right I don't know when the
oaksterdam news was in circulation yeah
that sounds about right then the purple
passion turned into a strain that is now
an acronym on on our catalog there was a
strain and it just so it happened that
there was a party at the farm long story
short the next morning right by the one
of the offshoot of the purple passion
that was like just beautiful dark purple
there was some panties at the base
because somebody had had a really great
night that night and uh turned into
purple panties and then so that's why I
called it the purple panty dropper
because I was like you know imagine that
I knew exactly who it was I remember
seeing a string called The Flower purple
panty dropper if that was the same one
oh yeah no I think that was that was it
and uh
and then I don't know I haven't actually
talked to Mario about but the shinsky
has that pink panties pink panties yeah
I believe his pink
panties um that
was sunset sh oh no that that's what
made the sunset Sherbert and I believe I
can't even remember what the cross from
that I mean who knows like because I I
you know we were all that in that day
you just didn't even like want to talk
about you know if you said where you got
something from it was like you we talk
about Tomatoes at The Grow shops you
know it was wild time exactly we did I
remember that yeah yeah you didn't say
you were growing weed you were like if I
want to get bigger yields for my
tomatoes yep totally you know wild times
the the first humbled Seed Company seed
packs were little business cards uh the
local place up in Humble were like yeah
we'll print business cards no problem
I'm like well you print weed pictures
and stream names on them and they're
like screw it yeah and um then I would
just like put the little seed vial
ironically the same vial that we have
today and then just a little bit of
shrink wrap you know and that was it was
not fancy but it for the time it was way
fancy you know and so I would bring
those down from LA to um back to Humble
just dropping off tons and tons of seed
pack those little seed packs everywhere
and never getting paid a dime um up
front always like you know they were
they were like well this is something
new to us and and a lot of the time too
it was great because it would help me
get at least get the 25 flower that I
was growing sold because more often than
not it was like how do you get in the
door to get down into the special buyer
room you know because there were you
know a lot of people were jumped on that
and even though lots of vendors yeah
lots of vendors and even though a lot of
it didn't stay here in California you
were pumped if it did you know like you
wanted it like that was the target was
to be able to service the legitimate
medicinal cannabis community and uh if
you were doing it that way it felt like
a little bit like it was more stable and
and like you had done a good job or
whatever so that was like always
something that I enjoyed getting to go
into those
places but then yeah Consignment seed
packs and come back
oh yeah six months later and just see if
they'll honor you know like see if they
had it there's no seeds and you guys
don't know what happened yeah pretty
much usually that was the story and then
the blueberry muffin came out of the PPD
which is what we call the purple panty
rapper now with the Raz the razzleberry
but then
um and the razzleberry was a cut that I
got from up in
Oregon um so let's Circle back to the
Caribbean Ian and kind of some of the
stuff you guys are doing because I think
you're working with other islands in the
Caribbean besides just St Vincent I've
heard you got get B on here too um
because he's been doing a lot of that
stuff I had another kid not too long ago
um and so I've been a little bit more
the let's hold it down at at home which
is also you know like I always say too
you gotta just keep your head down and
and breed breed breed breed breed you
know I mean there were so many people
that said well you'll never be able to
survive as like a seed company what are
you thinking you know the people that
laughed at me back in the day it's like
no no I did it I did I I had the vision
I believed in it oh yeah and I wasn't
taking No for answer I was just going to
do it and I believed in this for a long
time and I literally had people laugh
you're right lit some of my friends
thought it was so funny that that you
know it's like there was there's guys in
High Times doing it why couldn't I be
that guy or why couldn't I do that stuff
and it's crazy and guys are working I
know I don't want to be a jerk yeah but
a lot of them are but they didn't follow
their dreams you know whatever they did
most of most people don't yeah you know
and I feel like I'm fortunate enough to
have followed my dreams that led me here
and people are always like oh my God you
get the dream job and all this that and
the other it is TI it's unbelievably
difficult doing what we do I work my ass
off all the time yeah PE people want the
it's hard on relationships you know what
I mean yeah it's hard on everything uh
but but I feel like people they see it
and they're like well they want the
Glamorous side of it but they don't
realize the hard work that it took to
get there in all the yeah sleepless
nights and people laughing that [ __ ] too
you know I got one great question for
you if you could have one piece of
advice to share with your younger self
or your younger
colleagues what would that be dude
that's a really tough question because
what we were just talking about was like
how we our passions turned
into you know hopefully successful
business currently successful let's just
say but um some sort of Legacy yeah
exactly and and so I'd love to be able
to just be like you know do what you
love and the money will come yeah I'm
not so sure that we live in that world
as much as we used to but but I still
think it's definitely worth a try and
you can devote you know even if it makes
you four or five years before you really
think that it was even if you're not
making money I think that you said the
word devote and I think devotional is
the key to all this if you can devote
yourself to the whatever it is that you
want to do whether you want to be a
musician it doesn't matter you want to
be a priest if you can be devotional and
devote yourself to that thing like I
have with cannabis and you have with
cannabis I think anything is possible
yes right and you have to just eat sleep
and breathe it live it yeah and
whatever you do you get back in return
usually yes I I totally agree so that to
answer your question yeah with like
utmost caution because I don't want to
steer anybody the wrong way but you have
to you have to try and otherwise you'll
probably there was a turning point where
I was like if I don't give this my all
for a little while I will always wonder
whether it could have worked and and I
am so thankful that for that
like willingness but I also wasn't you
know like living like I had a little bit
of a savings and stuff like that not not
a ton I've never had like an economic
cushion in my world at
all but maybe enough to get through you
know a few three two three so months I
and also like once getting the little
first piece of land that I got in in
Humble County mmhm just like well hey
I've got a daughter you
know she probably told you she like went
was on my back in a back baby backpack
going to build out the first of my
gorilla grows and I never brought her
after the plants were there but I was
risk adverse at that time because of
that precious little you know person
that now was I felt very responsible to
and so like yeah with the utmost caution
depending on your life circumstances try
your best to get a little cushion
whether that's working at [ __ ]
McDonald's uh and then going home and
hustling seeds online or whatever you
know I always had two jobs me too I was
the same way I always had a legit job
and then my job that I would dream job
and I was fortunate enough to be able to
have a dream job and then another Les
dream job with the salmon stuff but that
was only just cuz where it was where I
was right being in the kind of in the
mountains of humble but I mean you're
living the dream here like this is an
amazing
facility I love the fact that you're
bringing you know like all of these
people together on the podcast as well I
mean and then the book man I mean I got
a I'm I'm buying a copy putting it right
in our offices I know you gave hie one
already but I feel like I got one for
you too I got one for you too for sure
well I I'd love the I want to help cuz
it you know all of us small business
folks we know you know we gota we're
like always looking out for each other
right I try to work with other small
businesses yeah you know we should talk
about some collaboration on some level
I'd love to do that the beauty of this
community and the beauty of doing
podcasts like this is that I get to know
people better yeah and just like how I
talk about how LEDs sucked back in the
day with the blurps and then
somebody figures out how to improve them
and make them better femin seeds suck
back in the day and it's pretty much the
standard now well I used to say fed
sucked we're all guilty of it yeah yeah
and then I learned and I also said autof
suck but also like me too humble Seed
Company you guys are doing cool things
I've met a lot of people that work with
you and you know it's like so it's great
connecting with you on this level and
interviewing you and yeah um if people
are looking to find out more about you
and your company where can they go so
they can go to our website of course um
we're have we have like this
relationship with the local Native
American tribe um and it has given us in
one way or another the ability to just
sort of kind of spread our wings more as
far as people being able to like order
our seeds and stuff and I mean I think
it's totally seeds are hemp seed seeds
when they are seeds are hemp because the
definition of hemp is anything so
anything below 3% THD in the United
States is considered hemp and seeds are
hemp until they changed the farm bill
saying otherwise which I doubt they're
going to do because you know back in the
day there was like the source where you
grew but it's not like that anymore yeah
that Shane Pennington right he was he
was all of our hero and it's funny
because we have the same last name and
everybody always asks me is Shane
Pennington but I'll tell you what I
called him the day after that after he
published the response from the DEA and
I was like you are my hero because webs
too you know of course yep and uh yeah
we're watching the plant become just
more accessible and and like and
normalized and normalized which I think
is a great thing I mean not just for our
businesses but I think it's a great
thing because the plant does more good
than bad in fact I think it makes the
world a better place yes and and like as
a chef I'm sure that you also got to
understand that like there's no better
way to really know
um what you like when it comes to an
eggs benedict then than to cooking eggs
benedict five or six times and screw up
a little bit and try it with Paprika or
no paprika or Canadian bacon or real
bacon whatever you want to put on it
yeah and so like that I feel that is the
same with cannabis like we talked a lot
during this conversation about what
makes cannabis good cannabis and I just
feel like you know having more options
of cannabis at your fingertips makes for
good cannabis situational we bottleneck
ourselves into gelato or into these
things and then we lose a bunch of the
other colors along the way I think Kevin
jar talked about it recently yeah I saw
on that yeah and I think he has a really
good point with that like we breed
towards these certain goals where we
think this is what we want but then we
lose all these other things along the
way and it's like the diversity is what
makes it so special also how you
introduce hybrid figger back into the
planet is diversity right exactly and
you know Kev is like a hero my he's
always been a little bit of like guy
that I've looked up to and a mentor me
too me too absolutely but I'll tell you
this like someone like Kevin as who is a
mentor to Guys Like Us who were probably
mentors to other people out there that
are watching he wouldn't have said that
as in in as articulately as he said it
when I watched that recent thing he did
about 10 years ago it was more like we
all just got to grow these commercial
things because we all got to make sure
that we
survive through this which he was right
about that too but like it takes so much
seasoning of being in the space to start
for all this stuff to really like Dawn
on you where you're like diversity
is unbelievably important and it is in
important to your seed business is
important to my seed business and it's
important to every grower out there and
people just don't even know
how critical it is to having both like
really good cannabis available and
really effective cannabis and then also
to like having a good business model for
this plant that is like resistant to
singena and resistant to Bear because
there's subjectivity in the consumer
there's
people want that uh
diversity desperately and need it too
and and I am so glad that that's the
case because I think it's a bright
future for folks like us that have spent
decades and yeah
lifetimes really diving into the beauty
that the plant the you know the wealth
of diversity and what it has to offer
well thank you so much for your time
today I really appreciate it it's been
fun we'll have to do this again up at
your farm I'd love to get a tour I'll
bring some clones up I made some crosses
that I think you'll like love it that's
so great that you're working with the
the muffin and and let's do something
this spring uh we'll float down the UN
freshly undamned clamo River too that's
going to be a hot thing this summer
that's going to be amazing so I would
absolutely be honored have you come
through but yeah thanks again for coming
on the show I look it's always a
pleasure man I felt like we connected
right away like over the years it's been
Easy E easy to hang out with yeah a lot
of fun awesome thank you very much yeah
oh hot sauce I know it's not a product
don't plan on it but it's a fun hobby
we've I'm selling the bottles for $1,000
a piece there you go I love it thank you
so
[Music]
much thank you guys for watching please
like And subscribe down below