[Music]
you
[Applause]
[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James Lab podcast
and today our special guest is Nate
Hammer how are you doing today Nate I'm
doing great cheers James it's good to be
here again man man this is great you
coming on the show so uh what is the
deal with the Nate and Matt and the
confusion with your name yeah that's
right who you CAU I was speaking to
Derek Gilman gania the other day yeah
because we were doing MJ Biz and I
wanted him to come on the show again
nice and uh he called my phone rings and
I'm like oh how you doing Derek he's
like oh you already know who I am is
this is this Matt I'm like yeah he's
like oh well can I speak to Nate I I
know we're the same person mate he's
like you are I'm like yeah so what
happened is um as you can you can tell
by my naty accent I'm not from here
totally and for a long time I wasn't
supposed to be here so and working in
cannabis you know I could have got
deported pretty easily MH so they just
came up with a bit of a pseudonym for me
I love it Nate Hammer so that's what I
sort of got recognized by throughout the
years on social media when I was working
with all of these people and then when I
finally got my green card and my name
was okay to use which is Mater yeah
um it had already stuck yeah so call me
what you want mate you can call me
little [ __ ] if you want to call you
crazy yeah for sure so we originally met
when you came here with DNA we did a
podcast we filmed some stuff at the
facility cleaning their seeds they they
had brought seeds we cleaned their
genetics and so I got to see your skills
firsthand uh really cool stuff you met
our producer you guys have become
friends so how did you get into the
Cannabis industry so when I when I first
moved out here there was I was pretty
limited to what I could do I started
like you know working on the Queen Mary
and Long Beach I literally sat outside
Home Depot with all the other illegals
looking for work right but you know I
had a degree in film CU that's what I'd
got before I came here but um I've had a
love affair with America for a long time
uh visiting since I was a kid my uncle
moved here uh in the 80s he's from the
same town as me in the UK yeah and um
yeah so I just uh I was doing all of
these jobs that I hated to do till one
day someone offered me an opportunity up
there you know in the Emerald Triangle
area trimming weed trimmigrants right
yeah that's why I was a trimmigrant for
a long time nice so yeah I I was working
on a farm up there just trimming weed
making way better money than I was
making sucking up [ __ ] on the the Queen
Mary right and um the the owner of one
of the ranches I was working on we ended
up becoming friends and he said hey you
know I think I could teach you how to
grow weed uh instead of just sitting
there with some fiskers all day why
don't you come and um learn how to you
know do the business
so that's what I spent you know a long
time after that doing and um long story
short is I merged the two eventually
yeah you know a bit of cannabis
knowledge and uh film knowledge making
cannabis content the price of cannabis
dropped and then you win in fil yeah
yeah yeah exactly yeah yeah $300 a pound
or something it's wild now you know it's
it's really it's sad it's really sad I
mean I I was talking to guys at TP
namami recently talking in Vegas but
also TP namami was an event that we just
had recently and you know it's like when
outdoor I mean topshelf outdoor goes for
$500 a pound now and that's really
disheartening in a lot of ways I feel
like it's way undervalued I feel like on
the streets the stuff is still going for
a lot more yeah in dispensaries the
stuff is still going for a lot more yet
the farmers suffer yeah I mean the cost
of growing you know has gone down
especially with the LED Revolution but
still $500 a pound isn't going to meet
is it nutrients have gone up power has
gone up yeah the lights have actually
you know gone down U I think there are
some efficiencies to be had for sure I
mean people are doing double Stacks but
man it's like I think there's a lot of
mids going on right now too and there's
still that small like 1% so
transitioning from I mean you obviously
started with with a film degree and then
you grew cannabis and then at some point
you transitioned into film we take it
way back I you know I grew up in the UK
um you picture me with Cobble shoes and
uh you know dirty face cleaning a
chimney like the stereotypes I'm FY
joking no I grew up in the UK and um
yeah my in my early days believe it or
not um I I worked in the fashion
industry I lived between London and New
York as a fashion model wow yeah wow are
you sure W I was thinking
morean going to football games getting
in fights but yeah another fashion model
actually yeah let me explain the shaved
head first um you know I wanted to you
know want to look my best for this show
so I went to The Barbers yesterday I was
ended up getting it [ __ ] Britney
Spears for some reason so I've showed up
looking like a sperm whale but sorry
about that a that's all right yeah so
yeah I worked in the fashion industry
for a lot of years um which is what
inspired me to uh learn how to make
films I was always way more interested
in how you know how it was done I was
like oh [ __ ] so I see what we're doing
is we're repeating this in this angle
and then doing it again in this angle so
you can somehow cut it up cuz up until
that time I always thought there was
some hidden cameras or something like
how do they do this so you know back in
the day I I was working with all of
these uh big names Hype Williams was one
of them yeah we shot this commercial in
Grand Central Station in New York and
when I saw Hype Williams sat there with
his director's canz on and you know
telling people what shots he wanted I
was like man that's what I want to do
nice so I decided to you know finally go
to film school and I got my degree and
then uh when I graduated that just so to
be the year I broke up with my long-term
girlfriend and I came to New York to cry
sorry to America to cry about it yeah
and then I just [ __ ] never left right
overstayed my Visa and then uh ended up
in you know the the trimming world the
trimmigrant world try to make a buck and
um yeah that's how I merged the two but
the story you know it goes deeper than
that I have friends in uh in Europe that
I you know I come from the same town as
and they they had their own seed game
yeah in in Europe but they wanted to a
lot of things were going on with the the
Postal Service in Europe that was making
it really hard to sell seeds so
especially the UK yeah especially the UK
the EU which the UK was part of the EU
till you know like a year and a half
years break it I think it's I think it's
even longer than that but yeah yeah it's
it time flies like that yeah it does
it's wild because it feels like it was
two years but it probably five years
because it was right around covid time
yeah yeah I think it was like 2019 2020
yeah yeah yeah so my um because I've
always been coming to America you know
since I was a little boy and a friend of
mine he's the guy who had the seed
company in in England yeah you know and
it was doing all right um but he's
always ACC costing me like I used to he
used to come to my gigs and he be like
Matt like you know I'm doing this
cannabis thing and the word cannabis in
the UK back then and even now I'm
assuming I mean I've been here for a
decade yeah was you know really like no
I'm not getting into cannabis are you
crazy like I'm not going to jail right
so I always turned him down
so um you know cutter 2017 after I've
been working on this farm for a long
time and he was following my Instagram
and I was just unabashedly and
unashamedly posting weed stuff on some
on my Instagram yeah you know and people
from school would be like hey man like
what are you doing that's crazy but I'm
like no I'm in America this is you know
this is cool fine it's all good here so
um yeah something went down at that farm
that I worked at something you know that
I'm actually traumatized over yeah um so
I worked for this guy the guy who picked
me up when I was
trimming and um you know I I thought he
was pretty cool um there was always
something a bit sketchy about him I
think it was the way that he treated his
girl um I didn't it didn't sit well with
me the way that he treated his girl he
didn't treat her very well yeah um
anyway so over you know the months that
I was working there I was guaranteed
like you know a certain paycheck yeah
for growing the crop because I was I was
out there on my own living in this
little 20 foot shitty um RV oh wow
that's a very normal situation yeah
exactly I grew a big beard you know
what's what's crazy I have this weird
hair pulling condition which is why
you'll rarely see me with facial hair
cuz I I pull it out right and I've had
it since I was like really young I
started on my hair wow and uh but I had
the biggest beard when I worked up there
and I I equated that to like I think I'm
actually really happy I was just on my
own no one was bothering me no stress
and I was I was growing we we had two
hoop houses yeah uh 40 ft wide 240 ft
long we grew 600 plants in there amazing
we had a valley with another 20 plants
but they were like you know 100 gallon
pots yeah and we had an indoor two so
there was so much work to do so with the
Hoops they were light dip yeah yeah and
I had to pull the top on my own it was
freaking crazy yeah it gives you good uh
workout every day yeah yeah yeah not
that I didn't already have it but yeah
it was that was a lot of work so going
back to my feelings about this guy he
and I mention his name I won't give him
the the credit yeah but um yeah I didn't
like the way he treated his girl and uh
this one night we went to the uh the
Midstate fair I think it was the
Midstate Fair it's like pass the robo's
area so it's got to be and John Mayor
was playing oh boy yeah it was a good
show it was a really good show anyway uh
so he he was living down in that area
and I and I obviously had to make my way
back up to the the ranch to get the
plants you know faed and water the next
day and he said he'd be there to help me
and I had a couple of friends with me
helping me from the UK yeah and um next
morning it's like 11 I've already
watered like half of the plants and he's
still not here um gets like 2 o00 still
not I'm like you know what [ __ ] this guy
man um
so his girlfriend finally calls me he's
like oh he's not going to show up today
he got a DUI last night I was like oh my
gosh like not you know not that having a
DUI is like you know a big sin but that
was just like the last STW for me cuz I
was sick and tired of always doing all
the work myself right so I was like um
all right no worries so that was just
like you know what ticked me off um so
anyway couple of weeks later this one
night he gets into it with me because uh
he locked himself out of his indoor
grow right yeah yeah I know I mean you
know I can imagine how upset you could
to be like oh my plants but it wasn't me
I was down in the greenhouse but he uh
you know he's like tried to push it on
me and I was like you know what [ __ ] you
yeah I said [ __ ] you I didn't do that
this guy takes his shirt off yeah gets
in my face so I just spark him and then
when he comes to he disappears and comes
back with his gun oh boy right and I'm
like what the [ __ ] like oh my gosh he
puts his gun to my head and he says like
say your last words cuz this is it like
so you know like you know they say your
life flashes before your eyes like for
me I just like froze and then his
girlfriend like runs and moves the gun
away gives me just enough time cuz I'm
sat in my Tacoma or his Tacoma at this
time because I got into the truck and I
just put it in neutral because I can't
find the keys but I'm on a very Steep
Hill yeah and the the truck just rolls
back and I'm rolling away from him yeah
and then I get to my little shitty 20
foot Trader that I was telling you about
jump out I'm I'm only wearing my
sweatpants cuz it was like real hot day
that day yeah uh I run into my trailer
grab my shotgun and then I just scarper
off into the woods and then this guy's
like looking for me and I spent that
entire night and this is like the the
Central Coast in the woods all
night little English guy you know I I
know how to use a gun because I'd spent
a lot of time shooting so you know but I
hid in the woods for probably like eight
hours until it started to get light yeah
but I could see him you know in his
truck looking for me oh wow yeah I was
tripping ball man it was crazy and at
one point I could see some
houses so I uh I was like I'm going to
head to those houses and I'm going to
knock on the door not with a shotgun I'm
going to get rid of that and then uh I
climbed over this fence and I just woke
up like I don't know how long later but
I guess the fence I tried to climb over
was an electrified deer fence oh [ __ ]
yeah still got the zip across my my
nipple right here wow so anyway that was
my experience growing weed on the
Central Coast and that's why I say I
have PTSD I left the farm never went
back yeah and um but you know for a long
time after that like I'd wake up and I'd
be looking around my house for him even
though it's unrealistic like he's not
going to be there someone that's still
in the industry I don't know if he's in
the industry or not I've cut ties with
him um you know I will say I hope he's
doing all right because he was obviously
like there's something going on with him
but yeah yeah we're not friends trauma
is one of those things man and I'm sure
that caused a lot of trauma a lot of
people say why don't you smoke some weed
but for me it just doesn't work yeah
it's so funny I feel like uh we all have
our own body chemistries and you know we
all respond to trauma differently and
one thing works for one person
especially with can canabo and with
Tarpin and all these different things I
mean it's you know these combinations
were good and maybe CBD yeah well I I
you know that's exactly what I do i'
I've tried CBD I still use it to this
day I do believe did you smoke before
that
no no I mean yeah I'd say yeah I've
smoked but I've never had a good
reaction huh and I'll tell you I'll tell
you for why so I use CBD yeah and they
have CBD RSO now yeah so I like to lift
in the gym and I have the crazy
inflammation especially in my elbows
yeah so someone recommended this CBD RSO
yeah so it's non psychoactive or it is
to a degree because it's like it's RSO
so that you know at the very base level
it's like 2.2 milligrams per right it's
it's psychoactive like how ibuprofen is
Psy exactly I I definitely felt some
sort of buzz from taking it whereas if I
just had like a a CBD isolate or
whatever I wouldn't so right so I was
taking a CBD RSO for for months and I
felt like it was definitely definitely
helping where the inflammation was
concerned sure like the anxiety and
stuff I don't know about that but
definitely with the inflammation and the
packaging between the
THC the RSO and the CBD RSO was
identical the only difference was the
fact that it said CBD and the fact that
it said CHC and I got to such a comfort
level of walking into our March and Ash
I think it was to grab it right that you
know one day after work I just grabbed
it went home and I remember exactly what
I ate that night I cooked freaking
salmon uh with Holland days and um some
mashed potatoes and some asparagus right
for me my daughter and my wife and I had
a couple of
beers and uh had by this point I was
having half a gram so it come in a gram
pen yeah or syringe and I was having
half a gram of CBD RSO I'd put it under
my tongue right and you know I work out
like pretty competitively and I live
pretty heavily yeah so I so it was
really helping it was great for me nice
so I um this one night took half a gram
of CBD as what I thought it was yeah and
then had a couple of drinks and went to
bed and then at 4 in the morning I woke
up and I never I've never felt so
strange in my life I was like what's
going on like what did I do do and like
why do I feel this way I could hear my
heart like in my head in my chest but
then I I sat up and it was like time was
really slow it's like being high right
but for me don't forget like I don't
smoke weed I do use the plant and when
this is like an extreme amount you're
talking about 500 milligrams right so
you know especially for someone who has
no tolerance like it's a psychedelic
experience and also yeah I mean
traumatized yeah yeah sure yeah so I
mean don't get me wrong we'll move on to
the psychedelics because I actually do
enjoy psychedelics but this one time I I
woke up I said to my wife there's
something wrong like there's something
wrong yeah and then I could hear my own
voice in my head and it was saying it
was it was like a psycho a psychotic
episode it was saying Matt not that you
would but you're capable of harming your
family oh wow that's what my own voice
was saying yeah so I said to my wife
like call the ambulance now and she was
like why what's the matter I said just
just please call the ambulance so then I
go in the kitchen I'm sat there waiting
and uh this fir truck shows up I've got
a ring camera too so it it caught the
whole thing oh yeah and I'm wearing a
t-shirt that says homegrown cannabis oh
boy right so these [ __ ] these [ __ ] uh
am EMTs show up and I I say to them like
guys this is going to sound crazy I know
exactly what's happened like and I say
I've been taking CBD RSO expecting them
to know what I'm talking about yeah and
I could tell like they're just sort of
laughing off like this is just the guy
who's had too much cookie or like you
know he's ate too many edibles but I
know exactly what's happened and I'm
trying to explain to them I've had I've
had too much THC it's like it's Rick
Simpson Oil it's for cancer patients
it's extremely strong and I've had the
wrong one yeah uh so I try to tell them
like I just want to be away from my
family just until this wears off yeah So
eventually like they are you sure you
want to you know go to the hospital so
they put me in the uh the fir truck take
me to the hospital and all they end up
doing is just putting me in a chair and
it had some restraints in it they
strapped you down yeah God it seems like
that would make it worse they they left
me in the freaking Lobby they didn't
even give me ma own room so I'm sat
there for 12 hours like Nicholas Cage in
[ __ ] one FL of the cook cuz they gave
me a sedative it could have been Xanax I
don't know what it was but they gave it
to me and did help so I'm sat there and
then you know as the time goes by I'm
like okay I think I'm ready to leave but
yeah my eyes were like super uh red for
a couple of days after I bet but what
Parker Curtis good friend of mine who's
going to be on the show told me was um
you should have had some CBD isolate
right because that will CBD will drop
you down yeah exactly and he he he
actually happened to have some and
competes for The receptors actually is
that what happens yeah well I think that
these EMTs they need to be educated
because you know they just gave me a z
or something if they had some CBD
isolate maybe the situation would have
been better for me a lot quicker yeah
but they don't have CBD isolate yeah CBD
is the Nan for THC exact right that's
the slogan right there it should be they
should they should make a Naran like
cannabis C Ann
Naran but uh that's actually a good
marketing tool right there well that's
what happened to me so not that I did
indulge in you know THC anyway but I
accidentally overdosed on a RSO ended up
in a hospital walk outside with a I grow
weed t-shirt which is crazy all these
EMTs are laughing at me most
embarrassing experience of my life and
then I was literally I I was high for a
couple of days I bet yeah crazy wild
yeah I remember I ate too much I was I
had people trimming in my house right
because I used to grow plants in the
house we used to trim in the house in
the front room and I was making Edibles
for trco from Green Day He was going on
tour and wanted these really strong
edibles but he didn't want them to smell
like weat right so I kept on adding more
to make them as strong as possible kept
tasting them making sure that it was
right next thing you know I'm curled up
in the bed I'd eaten way too much I was
tripping and I thought everybody knew I
thought my neighbors knew that I was
high and my I thought I was going to
die so I called my wife and I'm like I
need to go to the hospital I need you to
take me to the hospital and she's like
what what what happened she's like
freaking out
like and I'm I'm like yeah I ate too
much uh we I was making those it was
Rice Krispie not rice krispy it was
Fruity Pebble Treats at the time right
and I told her I was making the Fruity
Pebble treats for tcole and I need to go
to the hospital because I'm dying and
she's like hangs up the phone yeah and
I'm like oh [ __ ] you got to ride this
[ __ ] out on your own I call her back and
she's like you need a man up and like
figure it out I'm not coming home she
was working at the time and she was
working right down the street but she's
like yeah I'm not coming home you ate
weed you're you're going to be fine and
I'm like like [ __ ] and then when she
said that at the end though it kind of
clicked it like oh yeah I'll be okay
yeah and then I'm looking out the window
like [ __ ] my neighbors know I'm high but
that that paranoia that you get from
Cannabis is real and I feel like there's
a large group of people out there that
heaven had the experience of trying a
smaller dose of cannabis where they
would enjoy it but because of this
traumatic experience where they either
ate way too much took a dab or consumed
way too much now they never want
cannabis again yeah or experience it my
first experience and I'm not you know I
think I spend all my life with people
who love cannabis I mean I think
cannabis is a freaking glorious plant
provided by Mother Nature and it's not
just for getting high but if that's you
know what you use it for great but
there's so many beneficial factors to it
but when I was I think I was about 10
that's the first time I got high yeah
because my brother who's older than me
he started smoking um brick hash yeah um
and he used to make these things called
uh bottle bags have you heard of a
bottle bag No it's like very sort of
thing yeah [ __ ] have a bottle bag you
know what I mean so you'd get like a you
get a bottle of coke like a plastic
bottle of coke and you probably do have
it you just call it something different
here sure cut it in half yeah get a
plastic bag like the corner of a plastic
bag tape that to the bag yeah and then
push the bag into the ball get a foil
cap put some holes into it sure uh this
isn't a lesson for uh what's it called
paraphernalia by the way this great
though yeah so you've got your you've
got your bottle you've cut it in half
you've taped a bag around it you've
stuffed the bag up up into it you've got
a foil cap you stab it a few times with
a pin you sprinkle your hash on there
yeah you burn it and you draw it with
the bag so you pull the bag down once
it's full you take the thing off I mean
we used to use cook cans but I like that
I like and I fully understand how it
works it makes perfect sense I've never
done that but yeah I mean that smoke I
was 10 yeah and I I never like it was
the worst experience in my life so and
you know that was under the influence of
my brother the crazy bastard sure so
that was my first experience so how much
older was your brother four years two
years older than yeah two years older
than me and I might get that I might
have gotten that wrong maybe I was 12
and he was 14 or I was 10 and he was 12
either way that was a long time ago yeah
and it was it's no you know it's no uh
activity for a 10 or a 12 year old in my
opinion yeah I mean I think think I
started I started smoking when I was 14
right so I feel like that's a I'm not
going to say it's a good age but it was
the age where I started smoking I mean I
think high school high school a lot of
kids are introduced you know I was one
of those kids at chewing
tobacco I tried chac when I was seven
threw up all over the place yeah you got
the spins immediately it was so good
though to experience it when I was seven
CU When I was like 14 and everyone's
like let's try chewing tobacco I was
like you guys try chewing tobacco I'm
going to watch
and I saw all my friends get sick lying
on the ground throwing up drooling and
you know spitting and so I was never in
a chew like because of that experience
when I was seven right and cannabis I'm
sure part of it was from that
10-year-old or 12-year-old experience
that basically turned you away from it
yeah possibly maybe I should just start
small on the zins or something and my
wife back into I'm telling you there's
probably something that's right for you
and I feel like white Thorn Rose is feel
good weed so something like white Thorn
Rose you need to look for it I mean I I
don't have any right now but I could
probably get you some but like it's
about starting small and just you know I
think that there's a can canabo for
everybody I think there's some some
profile that works if CBD works for you
that means that there's probably
something else that works for you and I
think it's also about like exploring
plant medicine Kyle's always saying to
me you know exactly what you're said
you're saying right now he says it's
just that you haven't found the right
cultivar or you know you know you're
smoking too much you I'm I'm totally
open to it but you know I I've been
around I've been around the block and
you know I've had I've struggled with
addiction uh just not cannabis you know
um alcohol you're English so it's
definitely alcohol you got another beer
yeah right no seriously drink drinking's
yeah that's part of my Heritage but War
you drink warm beer too no that's not
that's a freaking typ dude no actually
warm beer in the Caribbean is they they
drink Guinness warm and they have extra
bitter Guinness yeah I I used to work at
a pub in London
yeah um and we used to pour the it was
like um there are some beers that you
drink warm it comes right out of the
barrel and you just pump it a couple of
times it's ale sure it's ale right
that's why you drink warm you know
that's like an old man's drink isn't it
for sure yeah I wouldn't you wouldn't
catch me dead drinking a warm beer
Stella you how about ipas ipas are like
the Cannabis of beer yeah IPA is an
interesting one I [ __ ] hate the taste
of it but I I keep drinking it yeah yeah
I don't know what that is well they're
strong yeah for sure and they're turpy
yeah definitely yeah I think the story
behind ipas is they were shipping it
across from the U Europe or the UK yeah
to America but they used to load it full
of hops right right to keep it I don't
know fresh or to keep it from spoiling
yeah and that's how it originated but
it's by no means yeah exactly there you
go but it's by no means like a it's an
American Beverage for sure well I think
it it originated going from England to
India or or vice versa and then we've
evolved it into something completely
different than what it was originally
that's what I'm saying yeah like you've
you've done so much with ipas that it's
just it's an American drink it's like in
the in the 90s ipas evolved into so much
more and then these
specific hops that they use and the
combinations of hops that are really
dank and very much like cannabis there's
definitely ties to the the beer world
and the Cannabis industry there's
similarities with beer and cannabis
especially with the recreational going
online yeah and these big companies and
then we have in alcohol there's you know
the big four or whatever and then we
have the craft breweries and the craft
Brewers have kind of taken over wordss
the almost the exact opposite with
cannabis it was all craft and now we
have these big companies coming online
and I think there's the fear of The
Craft going away and I I think that
people that have the best flower are
always going to be successful yeah um
but I also am big fans of people that
make their own beer and grow their own
weed Kyle kushman great example of
somebody who is a homeg grower who loves
weed and will grow plants no matter what
that's what we yeah that's what we've
been pushing for you know since I met
Kyle like eight years ago we've been
pushing out grow your own content well
you guys have your own channel and it's
very successful yeah I mean we've you
know we've curated over the years and
you know collaborated with I think more
recently the podcast I think we're in a
podcast boom aren't we like people just
freaking love podcasts and I think uh
yeah I think that's something that we've
been able to utilize yeah whereas you
know we'd spend you know a lot of time
and money and making a cinematic piece
of content yeah that would get barely
any engagement if you compared it to
just two people sitting across a table
talking about you know breeding or uh
synthetic versus organic or Whatever It
Is Well I think the best podcast in my
opinion are the conversations that
people have between each other that are
just really casual conversations where
you get to know somebody like we're
doing today yeah like I think that's our
our you know in Joe Rogan kind started
it you know in in that form Kyle was
doing it he's been doing it forever yeah
I watched a I watched a clip the other
day uh about how Joe Rogan got the
inspiration for his podcast and it was
from Tom Green yeah Tom Green was you
know just had his little show did you
see that he's a wild man yeah he's I
love Tom Green FR got finger D would you
like some sausage right yeah that's a
great movie totally um yeah so Tom Green
had uh you know a really young Fear
Factor Joe Rogan on the show yeah and
Joe Rogan's like what the [ __ ] is this
like what are we doing he's like people
like this you we're just here we're
talking and Joe Rogan's like huh and
then before you know it Joe Rogan's got
his own show yeah and his evolved
relatively quickly and he loves doing
podcast cuz he does these long podcasts
you know and I like that I mean our
format you know it's an hour hour and a
half two hours what is this guy called
uh you know is it's like Jamie pull that
up is it Jamie yeah yeah yeah because
you've got one he's called Ryan he's got
Ryan I [ __ ] love Ryan yeah Ryan's
behind the scenes Ryan's you you know
this is a good point to Pivot so um I'm
here with Rick the Lei right and um
because of Ryan yeah I was I was working
on um like producing or yeah I was in
very early stages of pre-production on
an idea for a film that I wanted to do
yeah um I sent it to Ryan because you
know I like I like uh you know he's he's
very well versed he's very passionate in
what he does and I met him on your show
when I came here with da and Aaron
totally so I was like hey yeah and you
know I'm I'm trying to produce this film
and I've got this person involved that
person involved he's like you know who
should make a movie about and I'm like
who he goes Richard thei oh yeah he's
the best and I'm like Richard delisser
so I watched the episode that rich did
with with Rick on and I was like like
the anecdotes and stuff and it screamed
like blow you know with Johnny it's yeah
I mean it's very his story is very
authentic and very much like blow you
know it's it's wild so so because of
riot who produces this show yeah because
he said I should do a film about Richard
thei I was like all right let me let me
do some deep diving did some deep diving
and I was just fascinated by you know
his story also very aligned with the
social justice aspect of it totally
because I've been in the canopis
industry for so long and you know we
watch we watch Uncle Sam with tax
revenues your your Silent Partner Uncle
Sam yeah right exactly every every year
so many billions and there's still
people rotting in jail for you know
certain some states yeah we even have
some presidents that are partnering
their sons well we have all these people
in prison and I just I just don't
understand that so um yeah I did a deep
dive and I was just fascinated and even
the project that I was already working
on and I you know I've one of my mentors
in film school is called Terry McDonna
yeah and he's a big director in TV and
film Breaking Bad directed a bunch of
episodes of that he directed uh better
call Soul the expand
he's a big big director and he was one
of the people that I was I was producing
this project but you know under the um
the watchful eye of Terry you know any
idea I had he would give me feedback
yeah so I I said to Terry hey uh what do
you think of this like showed him who
Richard delisi was and he said this is a
you know it's got all the Hallmarks of
something really great yeah but I'd
never met Rick I'd never met Richard
yeah but I did have a podcast and you
know up until that point our podcast was
doing pretty good um that that reminds
me of something quite funny that
happened with you in Barcelona when we
had you on the podcast oh yeah and
you've got this massive [ __ ] trophy
on the table and Kyle goes oh so what's
this trophy for and you're like best
podcast Kyle's like I'm coming for you
next year [ __ ] yeah we'll see
we'll see luck love a bit of healthy
competition good luck to everybody you
know I mean I that event was great the
international cannabis Awards where we
got first place got that that trophy
right there it's this trophy is it
that's it yeah it's it looks bigger in
real in real life but
yeah so it's funny so Sergio the guy who
um it's the very first one right yeah so
yeah I used to work for Sergio many
years ago he's a really good friend of
mine yeah and um we just saw him in
Vegas as well he's um he's he's one of
the guys that I used to work for back in
the day yeah nice um so I think we will
be answering the I best podcast uh yeah
we'll see how it goes we'll see how it
goes I mean I'm excited for everybody
and I'm one of those people I mean I
don't have a big eagle with this kind of
stuff I just I got that I got that when
we interviewed you for sure you're
you're about keeping Legends alive you
know before they I'm about Community you
know they give me this award I wasn't
expecting an award at all and I'm happy
that we got it but I'm just so happy to
be part of a bigger community and you
know have a good team and you know it's
like I come from a world where it's all
about loyalty and about friendship and
about winning and losing together so
it's it's so good when you have a team
that when you suffer we all suffer when
we win we all win and it's like we've
had good times this year we've had bad
times this year but we got a solid team
and I mean and not just the podcast team
because these guys have had to suffer
with me too or we've suffered and but
like my cultivation Partners we have
amazing cultivation partners and
partners all over and uh you know this
this group a lot of us started in the
black market even you started in you
know
yeah and and so coming and transitioning
to this it's a beautiful thing I love
the fact that people aren't going to
prison as much for cannabis yeah that's
the big thing I love having Rick Deli
and luk
scarmazzo and you know both Uncle Rick
and his son who I met 15 years ago one
of the first things he told me is my
pops is in prison and we're going to get
him out yeah right and then to see him
out you know he he had a 96e prison
sentence 96 serve 32 that's 98 serve 328
and serve 32 and so you know there's a
lot of blessings that we've been able to
experience in our life and yeah you know
and just I feel like it's a blessing
every day to be able to wake up and get
to do this kind of stuff yeah yeah yeah
so you know when you asked me earlier so
how did you transition from um you know
making films and being in cannabis or
vice versa so that's where it started
with my friend in the UK who had a seed
company and I finally was like you know
after what happened to me on the farm
with the gun and the night in the woods
and getting shocked by the electric deer
fence that's wild I it was really crazy
dude and um yeah you know not divulging
too much I I was already predisposed to
uh freaking uh drugs like yeah um and I
spent the last year being so happy
growing a beard like I told you right
and then I fell right back off that
wagon and I was I was in a bad way for
quite a while mhm um until I decided you
know what [ __ ] this I I got to do
something or I'm going back to England
yeah so I I took the phone call I had my
boys come over from the UK yeah um
actually Sergio ended up being part of
that wow and uh I used all of the
connections that I'd made as a grower on
the Central Coast introduced him to
whoever I knew and then that company
turned into homegrown cannabis Co which
is what what it is today what I do for
homegrown cannabis Co is I curate the
education yeah but
the irony is the guy who put the gun to
my head he used to you know tell me
about all of his idols and all of his
idols were like DNA genetics and burner
who I'm going to be interviewing
tomorrow for our film with Richard Deli
all of these people that he idolized and
at that time I really had little
knowledge of I've worked with I've
literally worked with every single one
of them whether it's hge santis yeah or
Ed Rosen Thor so there's a little bit of
shod and Freud there too I'm like you
know sure [ __ ] you dude so that's pretty
cool so yeah drinks to that one
nice yeah good stuff so DNA Dawn and
Aaron great people really good friends
of both of ours yeah you know and we
probably wouldn't be here sitting today
if you hadn't come in the door then I
mean it's hard to say right hard to say
know but you're you're probably right
yeah but yeah some of the best guys in
the industry I love those guys uh
they're they're old school I've known
them for a long time you know when I was
just trying to break break into the
industry those guys were already a huge
success you know and then Kyle kushman
you've been working with Kyle and he's
you know he's he's an eccentric
character I love him he's he's a wild
man loves that Strawberry Cough part of
our business model when we started the
company was how do we separate
ourselves from just a seed bank yeah to
you know something that offers more than
just seeds so that's where Kyle came
into play Sergio yeah he had his own
channel at the time I think it was
called 420 TV mhm and um so he knew he
knows everybody like he introduced me to
Steve DeAngelo that's I made my f first
film with him um so Kyle was integral in
that business model because what we
wanted to do is we wanted to create
cannabis growing content that wasn't
just your average grower but someone who
was dedicated a certain amount of time
and had a certain reputar in cannabis
right uh teaching you how to grow but we
wanted to give that away to our
customers for free
you know in order to invite them into
our ecosystem and our family right so
that's what Kyle and I have been doing
for all those years and you know we've
ended up making content with pretty much
I mean there's a lot of people still out
there that I'd love to work with yeah
but at this point yeah it's like if you
go to our channel on homegrown uh
youtube.com homegrown cannabis Co and
that's where the content that we've
cated for the last decade is all
available there all really well well
laid out and ready to go I don't know
there's this preconceived notion in
cannabis that if you don't if you don't
get high you shouldn't be in the
industry or I I don't know what it is oh
yeah I agree with that 100% yeah you
agree with it
right no you know I I do have feelings
about it though uh you know and I do
have some of the best girls I know don't
smoke but I also I'm the one who tests
their flower for them they give me
samples and I'm like oh yeah this is
amazing it's it's a really tough thing
and I think everyone has their place I'm
not going to hate on people that don't
smoke It's just tough doing business
with people that don't have that
experience um and they look at it just
just money A lot of times it's it's a
devotional thing for me yeah you know
yeah yeah the full the full embodiment
yeah but as a as a camera person or
somebody like uh our producer Ryan has
gone through periods where he doesn't
smoke and I don't have any negative
feelings about that at all because I I I
respect him because he's found his Place
uh with us in this industry and and so
that's okay for me but as a cultivator
I'm like it's tough I know a couple
cultivators who don't smoke and they do
fine but it's a tough one I guess what
I'm saying is um it's like are you too
much of a [ __ ] to smoke weed right and
it's like I almost feel compelled to
rebuttal which but I shouldn't but it's
like I've tried drugs that you probably
haven't even [ __ ] heard of and you
know we're all we're all human and yeah
I don't I don't smoke weed because I
just don't like how it makes me react I
don't not smoke it because I'm afraid of
it uh and I also do use the plant for
what it's there for right and it's there
for many things you know like at my
story earlier which you know
unfortunately was one of the most
embarrassing things that's happened to
me in my life but I still use CBD RSO
right um I still use C full spectrum CBD
tinctures um and I do feel like they
help you know I've got a lot of anx
you're still consuming the plant yeah
exactly you're absolutely still
consuming the plant whether it's CBD or
th C or any other canab there's CBN that
people take for sleep yeah and it's it's
not all I mean the plant has so many
uses whether you know some people build
houses with it you know I mean it has so
much potential there's rope and clothes
and all these things yeah if you spoke
to a friend of mine Jacko you might even
know um Steve
D'Angelo's um I used to work with Steve
I don't know what his position was but
yeah he he used to speak to me a lot
about hemp and how it can save the world
because there's so you can have hemp
plastic like any hemp can but you know
hemp would beat big a sorry big farmer
and it just beat so many uh
conglomerates textiles the whole textile
industry could get taken over with h
which I would I would think would make a
lot of sense it's a better material
better matal it's a lot stronger lasts a
lot longer but that's also the problem
if you're trying to make money and you
only have to sell someone a handful of
t-shirts to last the rest of their life
there goes capitalism exactly bunch of
hemp yeah so um yeah like like like we
were talking about I uh you know I
started out back in the day uh working
as a fashion model between London New
York do like catwalks and stuff all that
stuff no yeah I did I did catwalks you
know I've walked Kelvin Klein things
like that um my best friend grown up was
a fashion model and he flew all over
Italy Europe you know was very
successful and yeah so those are the
days you know when uh I think that was
my Gateway into hardcore [ __ ] drugs
you know I mean real drugs man drugs so
yeah I mean I'm not making light of it
or maybe I am but that was an Affliction
for many years of my life and I actually
only stopped really [ __ ] around with
uh hardcore drugs when my do my daughter
was born yeah and that was that was what
it took for me to you know take a step
back and now I just basically uh drink
all the time I just drink you know uh
recreationally um but yeah like the the
psychoactive nature of cannabis not for
me right um not saying that it's not for
everyone um it seems to be for most
people but well at least you're going in
the Psychedelic route so you like
mushrooms and stuff like that love
mushrooms hillbilly is my favorite
cultivar um it's less of the from my
experience you know I've had penis enves
before I don't like I don't like pees
yeah they they're way too psychoactive
for me they're a different kind of
psychoactive different kind of energy
it's not you know I'm still I like
golden teachers gold teachers are great
hilles are great the Magnolia they have
blue magnolia what's your experience
from Hillbillies I want to know if it's
it's similar to mine um I feel like it's
uplifting and energetic and I feel very
good on them and that's what I like
about uh golden teachers as well they I
mean golden teachers are like the entry
level right but I
like that they're not super
introspective and I'm not going and I
like introspective too don't give me WR
I think that's the problem with uh any
psychedelic that's introspective for me
is I got a lot of demons and I don't
like being in my own head I think it's
good to go in your head sometimes and I
think there's a purge right there's a
purge as and there there's a necessary
Purge that you need to do every once in
a while because we have all these
filters and I
think who you are now and how you see
the world is from all the experiences
each one of those experiences puts
filter over your eyes right over your
mind and so that's how you see the world
and it's not necessarily the world
really is that's your perception of the
world and we all have different lenses
based on these experiences and sometimes
it takes a deep dive into psychedelics
or you know cannabis and they they tune
you in and make you see how the world
really is and sometimes you need to get
out of that perspective to understand
that you're an [ __ ] because you do
this this and this and psychedelics
isn't the perfect cure for everybody but
for me I'm able to look at the world
through a different lens and I'm able to
kind of see the world I mean I guess
it's all perception anyway so it's all
you know your own personal experience
but I feel like I'm less of an [ __ ]
when I do psychedelics I want to make
the world a better place I see how we're
all tied in together once you start
seeing that there's this
interconnected uh balance between
everything every living thing that
exists you start realizing that uh you
know you shouldn't be hating so much all
these things and I really like that side
of this the Psychedelic experience
whereas like you get so much more tuned
in with cannabis tuned in with
psychedelics whereas alcohol and some of
these other drugs tune you out Sor
exactly you know and I feel like you you
know you go to a Grateful Dead show back
in the day now now dead in company and
there's a lot of people with alcohol and
you can tell which ones are tuned in and
which ones are tuned out yeah yeah and
uh it just kind of grows goes across the
board but I feel like they they can both
exist in in the world in a good way I
mean alcohol can be something where you
relax a little bit and and that works
for you but really I think alcohol does
a lot more damage to people than more I
mean I'll still keep drinking alcohol
but you know in spite of knowing that
and in spite of knowing that you know
there's things out there that's that's
way better but well us humans are doing
our damages to try to kill kill
ourselves every day you know so so and I
feel like cannabis will it helps a
little bit going in the other direction
I feel like yeah we might be smoking and
all these things but we become more
conscious of the things around us you
know like cheeseburgers so yeah yeah I'm
a sucker for a cheese B I guess I make
the best cheeseburgers like literally I
do Smash Burgers I mean I do I do big
half pound the heck is that is that do
they just like pound a piece of meat
until it's just dust and no no no what
you do is you have a griddle right you
have a hot griddle planta that you heat
up and you get it really hot and then
you take your Patty that has to be 70%
lean or less and you smash it with a
with basically iron I have a cast iron
uh basically it's round it's cast iron I
smash the burger with a piece of
parchment paper it makes it real thin
and what that does is it
adheres to the PLA and then you actually
scrape it off until you get this thick
crust and what you do is you put some
onions and salt and pepper before you
flip it over and the onions start to
cook then when you flip it over it
grills the onions a little bit you put
your cheese on there and it's done in
like two minutes I think at this point
in the show when you look at the
analytics this is when the drop off is
cuz all the Stoners are going into their
kitchen to make a burger totally with
the munchies well it's funny because
like I think a lot of there's a trans a
lot of people transition from cooking to
cannabis disc really easy to transition
because it's a lot of hard work and
you're creating an amazing product the
ones that are creating amazing products
you know they understand that it takes a
lot of hard work and it's all the
components it's not just one it's not
like we can have amazing meat but if the
Buns [ __ ] the [ __ ] Burger sucks right
so you have to have I like Brio but
there's like good potato buns and other
buns right but like it's also trial and
error R&amp;D like but yeah as far as the
tie-in with you know cooking and
cannabis they really marry well together
and I feel like breeding if you look at
some of the top breeders in the world
guys in the industry a lot of them have
experience either cooking they they
either love cooking or they were
actually a chef talk about Arian rosam
sh Brooks I can name a million other
ones but like a lot of good friends of
mine that are in the industry definitely
transitioned from cooking at some point
in their life and understanding flavor
and flavor profiles and combining
flavors man that's just such a great way
to transition into cannabis because you
understand on a different level where
it's not like oh it's just good weed
it's like no it's good weed and it has
these layers of flavor and then there's
these these notes on the front and notes
on the back end and it has this long
finish and when you can start talking
about cannabis like that you know you
start understanding not only cannabis
but everything like that you know and it
transitions to everything we should
start having uh you know the Growers
wearing Chef's hats now sure yeah
instead of just the L cloaks they're
pretty sanitary too you know yeah could
you imagine guys with those big tall
hats you can barely get through the door
you know but yeah that's pretty cool man
yeah I like that you know it's a
transferable skill no doubt well and
these are lifelong skills right farming
if you understand farming in agriculture
you can go anywhere in the world with
that same thing with cooking same thing
with nursing there's a handful of
careers out there it and I think you can
transition if it doesn't matter where
you go in the world if you know how to
to grow you can probably get a job
growing somewhere yeah same thing with
cooking if you can cook really well you
can go do that anywhere nursing
obviously you can go to make money
pretty much anywhere doing that yeah
yeah they I I think um I remember Swami
when we did a series with him he said
something along the lines of uh once you
learn how to grow cannabis you learn how
to grow which is like you know it's
that's just suggesting that you know
it's not just cannabis you've learn how
to grow so in a world where you need to
grow your own fruits and veggies all of
the the principles of grow the
fundamentals they're they're there yeah
yeah for sure well and there's a lot of
places that are importing produce from
the United States and other countries
and like they could be more
self-sufficient I'm I'm working down the
Caribbean St Vincent with the government
down there uh we imported 30,000 seeds
and came up with a a breeding plan and
an economic plan to help out the the
community and you know I mean the actual
local community that's a big deal yeah
it's a big deal and I think it's it it
has a lot of potential you know all
these things look great on paper but
seeing them executed over time that's
really what I would like and you know
I'm interested in the data too on like
what varieties of mine grow well in the
Caribbean you know so like from a
breeding perspective then we can really
start yeah changing the world you know I
think with genetics you have um last
time I was here a couple of months ago
um you showed me I mean I don't know how
much you can talk about it because it
might still be under wraps but you were
talking about some real like analytical
uh data research stuff that you're doing
to learn how each cultiva responds to
each yeah I thought it was really
fascinating well yeah and so basically
we're we're a hub here and we're
collecting all this data right on these
cultivars but collecting it
indoors you can get some really
important information for other people
that are growing indoors with your
cultivars but then we can go take that
same thing and we can have germ plasm
sent all around the the world to these
different climates and actually start
collecting data from how they perform in
different environments and after you
have enough of them you can compare and
get really useful information especially
for breeding especially longterm and
then creating you know cultivars that
perform optimally in those different
climates and really that's what we're
chasing after that's what land race
genetics typically are uh I think
there's a confusion on what land race
genetics are too I think a lot of people
think land race are something that grow
in the wild they're they're feral and
that's just not the case land race are
genetics that have been bred for a
specific purpose in certain places in
the world and they don't necessarily
have to be indigenous to that region but
they're bred for a specific reason and
typically they're optimal for that that
purpose or re reason and so I want to
get on that bandwagon and so start
optimizing genetics for certain places
and I think that that's what the world
needs is more optimization with
cultivars and and there's so many
different uses there's that's the beauty
of this plant is there's so many
different uses not just the drug side of
it but we can look at the you know the
hemp side of it as far as Industrial
hemp uh manufacturing for textiles uh
seeds you know there's so you hemp seeds
are extremely valuable can you so
elaborate on the the land race aspect
with what you talked about yeah um I
remember Ed Rosenthal was telling me
that he wants to go to Jamaica yeah to
find a certain land race and the way I
interpreted that was a a cultivar that
was innate to Jamaica but is that not
the case well it is it's so it's
multiple Generations land race they've
they've basically bred that through
multip generations for specific use and
it's the thing is these genetics these
varieties are dictated by climate
environment they're they're manipulated
from over time by the climate by the
nutrition by the basically by the
environment and nutrition right so
that's what the phenotype that that
expresses we have a genotype and that's
basically the genotype is the DNA that's
locked within the plant that doesn't
change but phenotypical expression gets
changed by environment and nutrition
yeah yeah like you can have um the same
cultivar and um I mean I might sound
real novice right now which I shouldn't
do I've been doing this for 10 years but
I've only been you know making the films
but I do try and educate myself a lot
but I've seen the same cultivar MH but
one of them is so purple yeah and the
other one is not sure and it could be
that same exact plant the same genotype
right right that's grown in Costa Rica
right and grown in Alaska and it doesn't
even look like the same thing it doesn't
smoke the same taste the same have the
same structure because it's influenced
by its environment around it and so how
about temperature cuz um I've heard like
temperature is huge yeah so like it's
growing in a c yeah you see the purples
when it's uh you know cold yeah these
anthocyanins in the plant uh that make
the plant purple especially in colder
climates some plants are just naturally
purple and no matter how hot it is or
cold it is they will they will be purple
but a lot of things are influenced by
their environment so cold nighttime
temperatures or cold temperatures in
general they'll purple out um and then
that can also change the flavor right
and so there's specific flavors when
people say it tastes purple you know
they're talking about the floral
characteristics a lot of times uh that
you get with that but like yeah there's
people that talk about it tasting like a
color and there is a color association
with a flavor with cannabis and it's
pretty wild so if this um you know if
anyone was tuning into to this episode
to learn anything about weed that was
your five minutes right there the rest
of it's just anecdotal [ __ ] but um yeah
we were talking about transferable
skills Chef to breeder um and you know
filmmaker to cannabis content creator
and there's a certain aspect of
knowledge that's required well you've
learned a lot about cannabis from
learned a lot yeah I I met Eric nug
shots for the first time oh nice I'm big
I'm a big fan of his he is a badass yeah
and you can tell you know you can tell
that that guy is very well versed in you
know uh can in cannabis and cultivation
yeah for sure well in in there's a whole
side of it to like there's guys I mean
we've experienced it with guys coming in
with photography skills where it's like
okay I need you to shoot this and it's
like dude those seeds look like garbage
but you have to educate somebody on same
thing with a plant and and what I love
about cannabis photography so much is as
as a breeder and as a cultivator someone
who's been working with the plant for so
long when these guys pick the plants
they've done some amazing stuff with DNA
too yeah but uh yeah the spinning photos
and this stuff it has to be perfect and
the thing is is if you have tips of your
leaves that are burnt or if you have
flaws it's there forever it shows up
it's very especially with these high
definition photos like everything stands
out so you have to pick the perfect Cola
at the perfect time and have it still
alive and happy when you shoot the photo
it was Todd McCormack who taught me all
about I was completely nous about
layering about photo stacking photo
stack I went to his house uh we went to
stay with him for a couple of days and I
was like so Todd why is your camera on
this
it seems to be moving forward why do you
have to go out of the room when you
start yeah it's like yeah I've been over
there and seen his yeah yeah he taught
me that so he was doing that 10 more
than 10 years 12 this was 2015 yeah so
yeah he's been doing it for a long time
yeah and I think I I remember him doing
some photos for us a long 2012 or
something like that know wild but yeah
technology has gotten so Advanced now I
mean even the new iPhones for for
photography for cannabis is like the
phones are better than the cameras that
we used to have yeah yeah man even the
video CER I've been implementing my
phone into you know my workflow a lot
like I remember um we filmed this show
on iPhones you do no but you could you
you would never know you would never
know yeah I'm like we do I wouldn't tell
you if you did but yeah yeah I wanted to
um there was an anecdotal story I wanted
to talk about just because it was um
pretty funny might be incriminating for
Ricky Williams so I will um disclaim it
first
but one of my favorite um memories of
making a piece of content was with Ricky
Williams um at the time being a Brit
didn't know who he was um my colleagues
did as oh my gosh this is a big deal
like Rick's going to come and do some
stuff for home he's a stoner too and oh
yeah yeah he's totally into astrology
and um smoking weed learning about you
know uh all of that stuff yeah um so he
came to my house in San Diego um but you
know as hospitable as you know I am
that's that's all I could offer Ricky
Williams I couldn't do the whole thing
because I don't know who Ricky was yeah
but what a really nice guy um so yeah we
spent the day interviewing him at my
house and um I wanted some props I was
like we need you know something to
contextualize this video so let's pull
some plants from the garden and Parker
he's our head grower over at homegrown
yeah um he had a garden full of uh
plants that they weren't flowering at
that time so but they were you know
pretty tall I said Parker like we need
we need a few plants for the set so we
rented a U-Haul and we filled it with
probably like 15 plants yeah I think
they're in um 25 gallon pots maybe wow
um big ones yeah they were going to be
big ones yeah for sure they' just been
transplanted big Parts though yeah big
pots that's what I'm saying so um we
filled up the U-Haul with it and then we
dressed my we went into my yard and we
dressed the set with these plants and it
looked pretty nice um and then we
interviewed Ricky and I was like right
we've done the interview but I really
want to get some b-roll yeah you know
contextualize the interview get some of
you smoking where can we do that and
Ricky was like well you know I grew up
here in San Diego yeah so oh no I
actually didn't know that I also didn't
know that you played football until like
20 minutes ago oh
wow I've you know I mean I wouldn't say
Ricky and I were like Chums but you know
if we bumped into each other we'd know
who one another are sure um so he said I
went to Patrick Henry High School which
is in San Diego and they've got a field
there um I was like well why don't we go
there and we'll um we'll film you just
throwing some balls and walking up and
down and carrying on so he said yeah no
problem I'll meet you there so he he off
he went on his own and um I thought I'd
kill two birds with one stone I was like
so what we'll do is we'll load all these
plants into the U-Haul yeah we'll drive
to Patrick Henry High which is a [ __ ]
high school yeah and we'll do the bit
with Ricky and then we'll get back in
U-Haul and we'll take them back to the
garden and put them where they were nice
and that's what we did uh the school was
closed too but Ricky was like ah we'll
just hop the fence and you know of
course we went we went and did all of
the cool [ __ ] with Ricky filmed and it
was a great day and then um breaking the
law with Ricky William yeah well he he
wasn't breaking the law that's why I
have to disclaim it he had no knowledge
that and I showed up to the school with
a truck filled with weed plants like a
high school like he had absolutely no
knowledge of this and I neither did I I
didn't even think about it to be honest
with you think about it like that in
that context yeah but then when I got
back I was like dude did we go to a high
school with a truck filled with weed
yeah like and Parker was like yeah we
did one of my Fondest Memories of you
know making some content nice yeah sorry
that's like not incriminated to Ricky
all he had no idea no that's a great
story that's a great story so
out of all the adventures that you've
had what was the best one um wow or just
tell us one of the top ones it could be
it could be going to bogatar with uh DNA
with Don Aon and Rez nice um we stayed
in this Farmhouse which was like
honestly when we got there I don't think
it had been touched since like know the
narcos were running the place yeah it
was like they said it was a stash house
that Don and Aaron and res didn't the
the guy the guide did yeah I was like
yeah it feels like it you know so I
spent all night like playing poker with
Don and Aaron and then we went to all of
these Farms the next day and we made
this really cool video and um that was a
really good memory of mine and I didn't
know what to think of of Don and Aaron
because we hadn't spent a lot of time
together but you know those guys are
just the most humble like him Don Rez
yeah guys ever and I'm going to Colombia
do these guys do Coke do they not do
Coke turns out that they don't so I was
in safe hands so um uh yeah you know we
went to Colombia we didn't do any
cocaine and we did a really good uh job
of the video that's probably one of my
best memories yeah I love Columbia same
thing I didn't I didn't partake down
there but you know my younger self may
have been disappointed a little bit but
you know it's like I'm an adult I was
there for business um I was speaking to
MJ Biz too and uh I did have an amazing
adventure Bogota is one of the most
beautiful cities it's also huge like
that's the biggest did you see did you
see that hospital there's a hospital
that's just half built uh and it's been
there since like the 80s and it was
actually being built by the Naros as a
narco Hospital wow but then the
government obviously infiltrated the
Naros ended that era so the hospital's
still there half built off the side of
the freeway wow no I did not see that
I've got some videos of it it's pretty
cool man but it was the cheapest Uber
I've ever taken for the distance that
I've gone it was so wild how cheap Uber
is over there but then you have to sit
in the front seat I don't even know if
it's still like that I was there in
2019 and uh yeah you have to sit in the
front seat with the driver and if they
pull you over you have to tell them
we're friends you can't tell that's all
you had to do yeah I had to sit in the
front seat but I also had to give the
driver a hand job oh yeah
nice I didn't know you had to do that I
did not yeah yeah good times and I was
in Cali as well and C is I mean it's
just so beautiful and the food is so
good and I feel like I was taking care
of you know they just really took care
of me and all over I did have a
bodyguard when I was there in Cali Cali
Columbia Cali Columbia you must have
watched like narcos right before you
went you're like yeah I definitely need
a body gu no they they told me that you
know this everywhere I went he was with
me and then you know there's in Cali
there's you know there's there's
basically uh checkpoints and so you got
to stop at the checkpoints and they show
them the information and you get sent
through but I was yeah they took really
good care of me amazing food like really
really really really good food oh yeah I
definitely remember the food too which
is also what rutes to one of it you know
being one of my favorite memories of you
know making content and there's been a
lot of them I've been out here to
Oakland a bunch of times too I'm really
excited tomorrow um to go it's more
dangerous in Oakland than it is in
Colombia in my opinion so yeah I would
have to agree yeah I mean not that I've
experienced danger in either but yeah if
I had to feel safe in either of them I'd
say uh Colombia but yeah tomorrow uh as
per the movie that we're producing Sansa
Mar of gold yeah um for Richard thei and
in light of all the social justice um
issues that are going on in cannabis and
the time served by Richard yeah which
symbolizes so many other uh things that
are going on um we're going to go and be
graced by burner he's going to do a
little spot for us talk about his
opinion on the whole situation nice um
really excited about that and if anybody
wants to follow what's going on follow
Santa Mar uh film on Instagram where you
can go on Santa mar. gold which is the
website and and you can follow us on
homegrown cannabis Co when when's your
expected time of release for that it's
really like it's almost like preliminary
still what we're doing right now is
we're sort of cultivating um the
interviews because we have all of the
resources already because you know at
homegrown we have our own production arm
yeah so we have the cameras we have the
lights so when it's convenient to
anybody to that you know that wants to
participate in the film yeah we'll work
around their schedule we'll go and
interview them then when it does come to
time to tie the whole thing together and
we've got the budget for that then um
we'll have more of an idea on when it's
ready to be released we have actually uh
Uncle Rick is in one of our
documentaries that we've been working on
with Steve D'Angelo for the last six
months and so we've just filmed when we
can and we've taken long breaks in
between yeah I think I was actually
right I was lucky enough to you know
review some of it already for Ryan yeah
and it's coming along really nicely yeah
it's a fun one and I feel like there's a
lot of good content and and uh these
these projects are just so fun it's like
this is why I'm here you know this you
know I really enjoy the podcast and
being able to tell the stories but it's
guys like Rick and Luke scarmazzo and
Steve
D'Angelo uh who's you know it's funny
because Steve has gotten a little bit of
hate lately and Steve is just a great
guy and he's a Pioneer in his own right
and we'll be with him tomorrow too he's
amazing yeah I love him Andrew and Steve
it's like I've become really good
friends with them over the past few
years
especially um but yeah they're guys I
looked up to when I was younger Andrew
has the most fascinating hemp shoes that
have this weird mushroom trippy like
aesthetic to him he's the most amazing
ex yeah he's mushrooms in Sarah Andre I
mean I've so as far as energy and
learning how to talk on camera Andrew
has given me the best pointers it's like
his experience with film as an actor
yeah it's like when I have questions
about stuff about film or opinions he's
always got an opinion and it's always
something positive so yeah it's a good a
good people yeah yeah well that's been
the beauty of this podcast we filmed
over 90 episodes now and it's like I've
learned so much from my guests yeah and
gotten so much Insight on different
things that I never would have thought
in the beginning that I you know because
I I did a podcast during covid so that's
when it all started I did 43 episodes on
the future cannabis project it was
called the James Loud Show and I got a
lot of insight from people had
scientists on there but it was really
breeding focused and now so it's more
about the Cannabis industry and all the
different aspects yeah and I'm able to
get these I feel like almost puzzle
pieces like you're another piece of the
puzzle right you get to get added to the
big puzzle yeah we should have uh we
should have put James your producer on
this H sorry James your Ryan your
producer on this show too like you know
we've had our escapades together too um
but you know that guy's super passionate
about what he does oh yeah no and we've
done podcasts together he's done a few
lives with us and you know he's he's
great and he's a lot of fun and you know
but there are all these pieces to the
puzzle we're telling this bigger story
and and Kyle is you know his he's doing
his part I'm doing my part we've got the
good pizza podcast you know and there's
a lot there's a lot of good ones out
there for sure first smoke of the day
they've been doing their thing good
pizza hot dabs has their own thing you
know it's like and everybody has their
own side of the story and I feel like
looking back 50 years from now I'm not
going to be around in 50 years more than
likely you never know but more than
likely I'm not going to be around in 50
years but you'll be able to see the
stories of all these great people
and I feel like we're just contributing
to the the bigger community and I think
people are going to need to hear stories
about why the world was so [ __ ] up
right now you know and how Canabis saved
it and how cannabis saved it or directly
from the mouths of the people that lived
those stories rather than saying this
person did this in a history book yeah
that we've had forever you know I feel
like now we have a real inter and
detailed timeline of the things that
went on directly from the people's
mouths that's what I love you know and I
love that too especially about your
podcast I remember you saying out on
mine you know yeah keeping the Legends
alive they're not going to be around
forever they've contributed so much and
yeah we got to get that documented for
sure and and cannabis you know it's been
it's been turned into for the longest
time it was demonized right is this bad
thing and I think being able to share
these stories how it actually makes the
world a better place that's a beautiful
thing to be part of something like that
you know I'm proud to be part of that
too for sure and in the most unlikely of
circumstances yeah coming from a country
where it's completely Contraband where
the word would be like hey well you know
you could be in jail for you know just I
can't even explain how you know the
contrast between how it is in America to
how it is in in Europe and the UK and
even how it still is right and it's it's
ways yeah slowly but surely changing I
mean they have medical there yet or not
yet but in the UK they will yeah maybe I
think I've heard in some circumstances
you know maybe like in a charlott web
sort of like dire circumstance it's
possible yeah but but otherwise no but
yeah in the most unlikeliest of
circumstances I did not see my career
unfolding down this Avenue but I'm very
very happy it did and I'm really happy
to be a part of this community and
create content and to have it received
by the people that watch it and um those
people are extremely grateful and yeah
it's very fulfilling so now looking back
if you had one piece of advice for your
younger self before this whole thing
where you got involved with cannabis
where he was coming into this industry
what would you tell him um it' probably
be don't do drugs and stick with the
plant medicine nice for sure I love that
so if people are interested in finding
out more about Nate or Matt Hammer right
where can they go let me make a
disclaimer real quick to everything I
said under the guys Nate hammer and Matt
hmer was uh not factual it was false
just in case immigration are here um
yeah so um yeah sorry what was the
question where can people find me where
can people find you um what's your home
address so yeah exactly uh
331 my uh my Instagram is Nate Hammer
420 um a propo 420 uh we've had our
Instagram on homegrown shut down so many
times we've wanted to start up but
that's homegrown seed our website's
homegrown
cannabis.com and
uh YouTube is youtube.com/ homegrown
cannabis Co and that's where the content
that we've cated for the last decade is
all available there all really well laid
out and ready to go well thank you so
much for coming on the show I really
appreciate it and let's do this again
soon thanks man it's really good to to
be on the show I appreciate you having
me thank you guys for watching please
like And subscribe down below