[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James loud
podcast and today our special guest we
have two of them net from beanock and we
have Tom from mother Magnolia cannabis
and Eugene Oregon how are you guys doing
today doing great man thanks for having
us yeah thank you thank you so much for
having us doing well man really excited
to be here absolutely man I'm glad you
guys were able to make it out here uh we
got Emerald Cup this weekend so it's
going to be a busy weekend I'm excited
to see what they do with it in Oakland
you know that's new right it's totally
new it's totally mind-blowing that they
went from Santa Rosa to Oakland we went
from the hippie to the hip hop right and
and so we'll see how that works out uh
you know I mean I've had so many things
going on in my life that I'm like oh
that's not going to work and then it
works out so maybe it'll be fantastic
maybe it won't maybe it's going to be
somewhere in the middle maybe they need
to work on it you know yeah I mean I
think the 510 has a quite the big
history with with cannabis to begin with
it's not yeah I mean Oakland especially
I mean yeah as far as legalization and
the dispensaries and the movement yeah a
lot of it started here this this is kind
of the epicenter the Bay Area is the
epicenter but I feel like the emerald
cup was more geared towards hippie
hippie culture humbled Harvest time
especially especially like in December
when we were judging it was like fr
fresh off the mountain right yeah I I
remember the emerald cup is really being
a celebration of the outdoor grower yeah
right and that really being the kind of
the Pinnacle of like the best outdoor
flower you know you're going to find it
all at the emerald cup totally I mean
and back in the day the judges they
would have a handful of entries now it's
like 150 flower entries and I it's
pretty wild the amount of people
entering um and exciting I mean all
these things evolve everything evolves
we evolve as companies event evolve or
they die off so you either have to
evolve or you know that's it yeah I mean
I've always been curious at the judging
process when you have so many strains
you know I I can't imagine the task of
having to judge say a hundred strains
yeah you've got to have a decent amount
of time in order just like fena hunting
right so it's the same process that that
we do when we're going through different
genetics where we have a hundred
different plants that we have to test
out I'm sure I mean that's how I would
do it yeah and so first you got to
organize them you know you organize them
by smell look however you want to do it
and then you kind of go in and
especially if you're tasting them you
want to judge them for Taste and effect
because one thing is smelling and you
can do the visual and all that stuff but
when it comes down to it you really have
to consume it you really have to try it
but as far as like an effect you don't
have a 100 days to where you can get a
fresh start every day with one to be
like oh yeah this one makes me feel like
this you can tell the strength of
something if it's stronger but there's
subtleties that you're going to miss
when you have to judge that many yeah
yeah I think it's almost like there's a
bias to the first one that you try that
day for sure you that's going to be the
one that's probably going to have the
most lingering impact on your psyche is
the first one that you gravitate towards
that day yeah but then there's going to
be the ones that are super strong where
you smoke it you're like that's the one
that that one got yeah my B that one
made me feel tired or that one man I
feel like my heart's racing a little bit
after that one hit you know and I feel
like rosin judging rosin it's like
there's those subtleties are a little
more intense
right so with flour it's like not as
intense sometimes and it's more subtle
whereas rosin it's all concentrated yeah
yeah yeah so this there's a lot more I
would say uh congruity between the smell
and the taste in rosin when flour
sometimes you can have that flour that
smells and looks incredible purple punch
right yeah and then burn it it tastes
like paper well we were talking about
our good friend Chris Castle and he does
a Donnie burger right and so his flour
is not anything that I'd be like Chris I
need some of that but the Donny Burger
rosin I'm like dude it's such an amazing
product you know we shared it on on the
reggy on the river podcast I made
everybody try it I was like literally
going around with the Little Dipper
making people try it right out of the
jar and everybody's like wow this stuff
is ridiculous and it's just it's a
concentration but it's different than
the flour like the taste is different
even though it's a concentration it's
when you concentrate things they don't
all concentrate the same that's true
yeah some flavors
can concentrated can provide almost an
unpleasant flavor experience yeah where
some of them it's so faint that when you
concentrate it you get just the right
amount yeah and I mean I think something
like Skittles right you concentrate it
and it's concentrated in the right way
where it's like wow you conc doesn't
matter whether it's rosin whether it's
BHO or whatever it is yeah all that
stuff it Skittles is amazing and I think
Skittles derivatives like moonbow yeah
you know you get any of those moonbows
and I think they're pretty amazing and
they lean heavy especially the ones that
lean heavy on the Skittles where it's
like candy it's got the but but it like
checks the boxes because Skittles really
doesn't yeah I think when it comes to
effect I think that's where a lot of
people are left Desiring more with
Skittles certainly as a flavor
experience yeah it's 10 out of 10 11 out
of 10 uhhuh um and yeah we I actually
hunted a uh I actually hunted a feno of
moonbo from the archive pack that he
released from the exx and uh buddy of
mine in Atlanta actually he found an
incredible keeper yeah um and it is like
you said it's it's very Zing but it's
got a little bit more complexity
underneath it's got a little bit of that
OG Funk probably getting it from its its
dosy roots right and it's got a lot more
potency when people talk about Z forward
that is Z forward all the way like that
is very Z for but it's very complex it
has an amazing structure it checks the
boxes I got to try it yesterday Chris
gave me some when he drew it out and I
was like Wow uh very exciting and I love
stuff that's not diet Skittles it's the
Skittles cross cuz some people like oh
everything you pull with Skittles is
better that's not true especially the
stuff that like where you're like ooh
because I can pick out a room where I'm
like okay that's Skittles that's not
Skittles that leans towards the other
parent you know what I mean because it's
usually the shitty structure you look at
the weakest plants with the shitty
structure and those lean heavy on the
skitt so it takes a lot of work and I
think archive has done a really good
job with that and they I've I've smoked
three or four different moonbo cuts that
are all like really special in different
ways you know that was the hardest hunt
we've ever done and also the easiest
hunt we've ever done yeah hardest
because there wasn't a lot of like bad
fenos they were all pretty good easiest
because the one that we ended up
selecting was just head and shoulders
yeah it was just it was that limey mouth
coating along with like the cushy
aftertaste and the strong effect I mean
it was really a well then it comes down
to the jar test when you have so many
good ones it's like which one did I
finish first
which one did you reach for which one
did you finish first which one was empty
first literally that is the gauge that
my crew uses which are emptied first
yeah every time I think that's uh I
think that's perfect because it's just
speaks to what you want to go back to
again authenticity right and you want
obviously you want product out there
that the customer feels the same way
about yeah like man I finished that if I
go back today you think they'll still
have more I hope so totally and then
there's a no it's like well there might
be more but we're not sharing it that's
the really good stuff yeah I find myself
holding back stuff at the end because I
like sharing it with my friends but
there's a certain amount I want to just
save for myself yeah right especially
with really good stuff and it doesn't
have to be new stuff sometimes it's
weird stuff I like strange you I I love
Super Silver Haze you know I think I got
some real Sour Diesel at re on the river
and you guys are very familiar with that
cut I'm sure and I love it I love it and
then like I I got some buds I gave a
little bit out to a couple different
friends and I saved the last for myself
hoping to get more this weekend at
Emerald cup okay because it's the real
cut and I haven't had real Sour Diesel
in forever yeah that's not common you
don't see that a lot in I see so I see a
lot of people give me flour say Sour
Diesel because I talk about on my
podcast so much that and cat piss I've
gotten a couple different cat pisses
that I haven't been super impressed with
lot of Sour Diesel that I'm like it
leans it's more of a chem 91 or a chmd
than a real Sour even though it looks
like sour it leans towards that really
burnt Tire Gas and even when you squeeze
it you don't get a lot of citrus and I I
want a a flower that punches me in the
face where like the real Sour when you
opened a bag of it it would like
literally pop you in the nose and you'd
be like wow that's amazing yeah I think
look I think there's a couple things
going on with sour one with a cut that's
as old and as popular of course it's
going to have so many derivatives
s1's I think it was an S1 we can debate
it but yeah I believe I believe it was a
bag seed from the Chev 91 I think a lot
of the old strains probably were you
know before there was a lot of actual
breeders that were you know deliberately
breeding you know you got some Bag seed
hey hell yeah let's pop this and I think
the other issue that sour presents that
it is such a difficult strain to
cultivate it is I mean it is one of
Skittles another one but I think sour is
more difficult than Skittles due to how
long it has to run I agree and you need
you need to maintain a perfect course
for over days yeah I mean it's not a lot
of there's not a lot of systems not
going to find that in commercial
production people are just aren't going
to have the time or Pati there's not a
lot of people that'll want to do it and
then because you start looking at
numbers right so the second you start
looking at numbers and you know you you
know that's it it's like it doesn't
pencil out and unfortunately yeah you
need that cycle to turn at 63 days I
mean most of our selections are for that
so we can get five Cycles here Skittles
is a 53 to 56 in my opinion it pulls the
best that you finishing a little bit
early got that going but if you look at
an extra month for sour that's wild yeah
you know 77 days or whatever or plus 77
plus I think to get personally I I
believe 11 or 11 to 12 weeks when I used
to go it was 11 to finish proper to let
it yeah to let it finish properly and it
still doesn't look like it's done at the
end you to keep going it still wants to
keep going you still getting white hairs
on the top a little bit and yeah and
then they finish pink a little bit you
know that's when you you've done it
right oh I don't think I've ever seen
that you get a little pink hairs on the
pistols well what happens is it dries it
has almost a it's their their the way
the the white ones dry is they'll dry
almost pinkish so when you're looking in
the back it's not like pink like bright
pink or anything it's like a a d red a
dull red yeah you get that with certain
genetics uh yeah and even the crosses
some of the crosses we made back in the
day with sour definitely had the they
did have pink pistols so really cool
pink pistols especially like when it was
like three in flower and you got a whole
bunch of pink pistols on the crosses
yeah those would always make the High
Times covers they look amazing and then
they go away right but they're really
cool yeah I mean I don't I can't say
I've had a good batch of sour since so I
went to college at humble State
University yeah um and yeah I think my
last batch of sour that made me go wow
was actually in 2013 yeah you know it's
and since then a lot of the stuff that's
come my way just like you've expressed
is a lot of like that burnt rubber and I
just remember the sour diesel having
such a citral citrus kind of brightness
to it along with the gas and it's got it
has to have that Citrus and it's it's
you don't get the nose burn from the gas
you get the nose burn from the Citrus
right it does have that file it's that
citrusy nose bur where it's not Haze but
it is Citrus you know because like that
Haze is a different thing Al together
it's completely different s's grapefruit
which is a New York City Diesel which is
completely different from Sour Diesel
also has like a citrus but it's a
grapefruit Citrus as opposed to like uh
lemony lime like I would say Haze Haze
goes in the more lime category and then
that sour was like a sweet lemon like
amazing like and and I remember for the
longest time there was only one sour
there wasn't multiple types there wasn't
a bunch of derivatives there wasn't a
bunch of ecsd it was just Sour Diesel
you know and then you know and I'm sure
over in New York and other places yeah
they like different names and stuff like
that and you know then we got the
weasel's diesel and the AJ's Diesel and
the you know all these different yeah
and humbled sours was all like sour
that's that's that's everyone just
called it sour you know we need sours
old guys we need sour old guys well yeah
and I think the name they came up with
the name sour because it soured
relationships not because it was Sour
smelling right so that's in my breeding
book yeah I I wanted to get to the
bottom of it get as much information as
possible from my breeding book and get
the information as correct as possible
you know because no matter what there's
always going to be something sure
there's there's 115,000 words so we
didn't get it all perfect and I'm okay
with that but I feel like we did our due
diligence to try to get everything
correct you know I have where did that
where did that uh history come from in
terms of it souring relationships where
did where did you where did you find
that so I i' I actually talked to Greg
Kem dog so Greg who who is chem dog and
I talked to him and that I talked to
Mike peab and a couple other guys and
Mojave Richmond and started getting
stories from everybody and then I got on
a conference call and we kind of sorted
out what I had written and what should
be written also about the chemdog right
so like there's a case study my book has
case study so we went through got a good
case study on the sour uh Mac one which
is extremely special I'm not the biggest
fan of the Mac one for smoke but I
absolutely think it is an important
genetic as far as Legacy and everything
else like not legacy Market but Legacy
for cap and I feel like it's a special
one it it hit when it hit and it's it's
really special it's a partial triploid
right so it's really hard to breed with
it you know natural partial natural
triploid yeah and so really cool I mean
I get excited about these genetic things
and it's like as much of that stuff as
we could include in the book we did yeah
next version is going to have even more
stuff incred that explains why one has
always been hard to breed
with making phos did the study on that
and so yeah it's it's pretty cool yeah
making and then it's also an anomaly
because it's a lot of recessive stuff
going on with it if you look at the we I
got a Mac 69 from first class genetics
and from my buddy Ray and that was Haze
that was like Colombian tasted like
smoking old school Colombian it was
really that's the dad in it right uhuh
yeah that's the miracle right so yeah
completely the opposite um you know you
don't get that Haze in the Mac one it's
very soft a little bit of floral it's
nice it's it's it's nice it's not my
favorite thing in the world but it's
still really cool yeah I mean when that
one took off I mean that you want to
talk about a wave like a new wave that
was a wave you know what I mean almost I
remember seeing capulator at Emerald cup
and there was like a line like over 100
feet just like Santa yep with 100 foot
long line for people and he spends time
with everybody and you know it's great
that's beautiful yeah I love seeing guys
in the industry that care about the
people that buy their product and you
that show love to the people that show
love to them yeah 100% yeah I've been uh
lucky enough to have a conversation with
Fletcher and yeah I felt like most of
the time we were actually I grow a lot
of other stuff in my backyard a lot of
citrus avocados nice and when I realized
that we spent most of the time talking
about Citrus yeah I was like I you know
there's a there's a certain love that
you need to have for plants in general
cultivation that I think you know really
uh makes you the best cannabis grower
period right when you can go a little
bit outside of just this plant that we
all really do love so much and when I
see like such a deep love for plants and
other breeders I'm like I think that's
that's probably why I've always
gravitated to his work so much because
for sure appreciation for flavor that
goes beyond cannabis and the magic of
what plants can do well and I think
there's you got to have a drive to keep
on improving right because I I think a
lot of people they they let learn how to
grow and then they just stop at a
certain point and like that's that's
what they do they found their way and
that's that's the end of it's the guys
who are like how can I make this better
and they've been doing it for 20 years
still like how can I make it better
those are the best guys out there you
know and same thing with breeders it's
like the guys who haven't figured it all
out and are willing to experiment and
and still have passion about it because
you know you get beat up a lot in this
industry so you got to have passion that
goes beyond money you know it's like cuz
there's other things you can do to make
money out there but a lot of us this is
what we meant to do you know nothing
more than this and it's it's what we
love doing it's what we love talking
about it we love love everything about
it we eat sleep and breathe it and you
know it's like I have random
conversations with people at airports
about cannabis and you know we start
talking about stuff and next thing we're
talking about flower we're talking about
this or we're talking about rosin and
it's like you can tell kind of Who's Who
and you know who's who's doing what I
mean absolutely not everybody has the
look but you can kind of tell yeah I
mean I look or the smell I was in I was
actually in nursing school before I
jumped into the industry oh wow and I
had so much guilt about just this wealth
of cannabis knowledge that I had you
know um I've been smoking since I was 15
16 yeah um I started growing when I
moved up to humbal um and I just I just
loved it you know I loved it I was
talking to Tom a little about earlier
The Strain made me fall in love with
cannabis was blueberry I remember my
first batch I I got a blue was Oregon
blue R was it DJ show it was it was
coming up from Humble I don't know what
the name was I mean I was only 16 17 at
the time um and it was like the first
non-generic smelling cannabis that I had
gotten and I just remember being like
why does it smell like this what did
they do to make it smell like this and
that was like the moment where I was
like I want to know everything yeah
about this plant and you know such a
magical smell you know it's a strain
that will always have a special place in
my heart for that reason so what was the
guilt what's what's the guilt so the
guilt was that like I was in nursing
school man and I was just like I like
you can do so much more with your life
it wasn't no it wasn't that it was that
like I have all this knowledge about
strains where they came from who bred
them like I cared so much yeah but I was
like I'm holding on to all this
information that's not going to do
anything for me not being the torch
Bearer for all that information is not
just like why do I care so much about
something that's not not part of the
career that I'm going into you know what
I mean and it was just like it was just
I just carried all this like guilt for
all this like I couldn't talk about this
to the people in my program like you
know what I mean like this was still
very
much a place where yeah I wouldn't talk
about smoking I wouldn't talk about can
it's all I wanted to talk about right
but you know I was around these people
where I was like I can't talk about it
ever you know what I mean and there
might even come a day where I I'm going
to get tested and all this stuff so it
was a really that part was really tricky
and then I just kind of slipped into the
industry and I just I dropped out it was
actually right during Co when I Dro it
was in in March I finished that semester
and I said you know Co was really good
for cannabis it was really I mean I was
this every time someone says Co I'm like
Co was actually really good yeah it was
great if you weren't making money drink
Co you were doing something wrong
something was like you shouldn't be
doing cannabis because I feel like all
my friends really killed it durink co we
had our biggest year yet yeah I had my
biggest year of my life yeah
100% out smoking weed I thought it was
going to be one of the worst years but
was one of the best years and and it's
funny that's another one where it's like
it looks bad and then you get through it
and you're like wow that was amazing
well I mean look at how many people
absolutely lost everything during Co and
you know dispensaries were essential
businesses you had liquor stores Canabis
Shops and and grocery stores that were
open during during Co yeah and
everyone's at home everyone's at home to
do they smoking drinking you know hang
col their checks you know doing that
remote work and uh yeah Co was great so
it's interesting that you would have
made that switch during Co yeah I mean
it just it was it was you know I kind of
I had a little I had a little Instagram
page where I was I started growing at
home again and that's always been my
love right my love has always been um so
I have a minor in chemistry and the lab
work right the the importance of doing a
small experiment with highly
controllable um inputs in order to
expand that to a larger thing was
something that I always loved and so I I
like to keep my growing small scale for
that reason you know easy to manage easy
to turn uh easy to know what's changing
and what isn't and that's when beanock
had reached out to me and they were like
hey we love your page you know do you
want to grow with a granular style
fertilizer and I was like
no a word no I have a minor in chemistry
I'm pretty sure I can mix nutrients fine
like I don't I don't need a granular
style fertilizer it's another one of
those things that I think is
counterintuitive to a lot of people
right it is especially in this industry
in this industry people are like no I
need to do all these things and
sometimes it's a lot more simple yeah so
as you well know you've been working
with beanock for a while right yeah I
think that uh we I think we got turned
on you guys through Nelson I think he
was the the gateway drug there um he
said first Hits free and that was it um
so yeah it was about 5 years ago um that
and you know my team looked at me like
are you [ __ ] crazy nobody was uh on
Bard with the idea at all but you know I
you know you were mentioning a moment
ago you know the idea of just sort of
that Relentless pursuit of refining
things and testing and and and you know
that's good but we can do it better
right that works but maybe we can do it
cheaper that works but maybe we can you
know create a hybrid model and that's
that's essentially what we did I mean we
uh we start you know we were we've grown
in soil forever soil has been you know
our our medium and it's it's what we're
you know it's what we it's the hill
we'll die on yeah but it's all you know
organic inputs um top dresses compost
teas and and when I looked at my you
know lead grower and I was like Hey
we're going to try some beanock he's
like what I was like yeah let's just do
some experiments we'll start small and
we'll just see where it goes yeah so
we're all about just you know testing
retesting testing retesting and seeing
what works and uh and beanock um it was
it was a big surprise to everybody big
surprise to everybody and you know we've
we've tried about every configuration
with bean stock with our organic inputs
and we've you know we've landed on a
hybrid model that um that just works
yeah it's amazing when you find
something that works especially
something that like people like how the
heck did that happen yeah maybe we
should rewind and talk a little bit
about what the product is for those
who've never heard of it maybe I think
that' be great so yeah so so what
beanock is it's a it's a granular style
fertilizer um that was specifically
formulated to be used with cannabis and
the idea came from a very simple premise
you look at horiculture outside of
cannabis and granular style fertilizers
are dominant yeah not by a little but by
a lot right they the majority of uh
large Horticultural applications are
using like a grainless especially in the
cut flow industry yeah and so from
inception our Founders were you know
like okay well if this can work for
other plants how can we make it work for
cannabis um and so we use a cating that
was initially developed by NASA to be
used on the ISS
um but what is special about the coating
and that makes our product different to
other granular style fertilizers is that
it is activated by irrigation events so
the coating is composed of a bunch of
micro micropores that open up when the
plant is watered um it seems like a
simple change but in actuality in
practice it actually makes a big
difference you're growing Outdoors
you're having hot days that means that
your plants are going to be drinking
more our fertilizer is going to be
releasing more a lot of traditional
granular style fertilizers on the market
they offer a like a polyurethane coating
or a polyethylene microplastic coating
and it dissolves you're kind of locked
into a daily payload and then when the
heat gets to a certain point it'll just
break down right fertility dump and
roast all your plants um so we needed
something a little bit more high-tech
that's how we found the coating
eventually we had to play with
formulations it started out as an
all-in-one when we realized that that
wasn't going to work we separate ated
our product into four lines or four
products two lines we have our Bloom
line which is composed of three products
it's our absolute flower that's the
flagship product has all your Macros and
micros and we have a k boost which is
pretty simple it's just potassium
magnesium and sulfur and we have our
calcium fortify which is just calcium
nitrate nice those three together make
up our Bloom mix um it's really easy to
use that's what you'll see here in these
little pouches is those three products
premixed this is for this is a product
that we made for the hom grower someone
who's just growing a couple plants you
take one of those rip it open throw it
in a 5 gallon pot it'll give you two
weeks of Edge and up to 10 weeks of
flour with one dose nice and simple and
then our other product is an all-in-one
product but it's only for mothers and
Nursery stock just for your veg plants
really easy to use 25 grams per gallon
um and it's meant to be used with that
dosage the 25 gam per gallon dosage is
mainly for Cocoa core or Pete Moss
something that's very lightly amended
Amed Tom he our in a way that's
very not married to synthetics he's not
married to Organics yeah um and he has a
really unique use case where he's not
using it at full strength or even close
to full strength but that's fine right
because as a grower myself you know the
biggest my thing I care about the most
is am I helping other Growers am I
helping other people be successful you
know the fact that people's livelihood
are going to be staked on you know the
product that I'm selling isn't lost on
me sure that's actually something means
a lot to me and so to have the
opportunity if someone like Tom whose
team has been so creative in their
application of the product and share
that with other people I think is is
really exciting for me yeah it's really
cool yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah so
how long has beanock been around oh man
so it's been around for it's been around
for a while I think we're going on 7
years now it originally had a different
name and had a completely different set
of owners initially um and that's where
the current owner and they pitched it to
the current owner and they said hey you
know this is a product you want to be
involved um he's not a cannabis guy yeah
but he seemed interesting enough um yeah
this looks interesting you know like saw
the potential saw the potential worked
with a couple consultants in the
industry um and the Consultants kind of
help reformulate the product and get it
into the state that it's now um and that
was the Inception was I believe seven
years ago um and the new team has been
running with it for about five years and
I jumped on board in 2022 was when I
jumped on board nice like I said they
reached out to me via Instagram yeah I
initially was pretty stuck up you know
like I don't need I don't need granules
to grow my cannabis I know what I'm
doing they kept kind of bugging me uh
Nelson actually offered me some flour I
went up to Santa Rosa got some of the
flower and I was like hey this is this
is better than I was expecting yeah um
and then's pretty convincing he you know
he I think if you if you'll talk to him
about his conversations with me yeah
he's never had an easy time convincing
me right I think that's that's part of
our relationship is that I've never I
look I'm a very data driven person sure
um my formal education has led me to be
just like a very very evidence-driven
person that's how I like to make my
decisions
um and when I tried the flower you know
to be totally honest it was a lot
harsher than anything that I would call
acceptable right but he was like Hey Hey
I pulled this at 56 days like I didn't
like I didn't even attempt to like flush
it this was like a quick and dirty feno
hunt and I was like well that checks out
it definitely just tastes like it's very
high in nitrogen you know what I mean um
but it was enough to be like I wonder
what I could do with this so I did it
and my first batch you know my regular
clients hey did you do something
different this time it's really good and
my ego was so shot you know what I mean
to think my first time growing with
these granules was the least work I had
ever done and my customers were stoked
you know and I was just like oh my God
like what you know I really was
expecting to hear something else I
really wasn't expecting right to get all
this praise and then the wheel started
turning and I said yeah you know what I
think I'm I'm I'm going to keep rocking
with this product I want to see how far
I can push it and that turned into a job
opportunity and that's when I dropped
out of nursing school and I was like you
know I'd be I'd be silly to not take the
opportunity to go work for we're still
very much a smartup startup we're still
pretty small company yeah and I'm from
the bay area right company too right we
are we are um in a sense that a lot of a
lot of our R&amp;D was in Santa Rosa but
everything is stored in Florida like our
major Warehouse is in Florida all of our
operations are in Florida but um you
know a lot of our research and
development did happen right here in in
the Bay Area so or Santa Rose is close
enough to the Bay Area but yeah yeah it
feels like the Bay Area to me even
though it's a little North but yeah yeah
yeah yeah for sure so yeah it's been
it's been a great run with them so far I
mean it's a product that I really
believe in um you know Tom and I were
talking earlier about you know a lot of
individuals approach to cannabis and how
dogmatic some individuals can be but we
really feel that there's there's so many
ways you know to cultivate and to
cultivate highquality product sure I
just want to have a solution that works
for some people and works well right I
don't believe that there is one
fertilizer that solves everyone's
problem no if there was everyone would
produce the same exact thing or there
would only be one company and and it's
not that it's not the case and I think
there's also different demands right as
far far as what customers want 100% and
what people are willing to pay and
there's so yeah there's different price
points for everybody and there's
different quality products and what one
person considers quality is different
than what another person and different
markets too like Oregon as opposed to
Los Angeles I mean I think those are two
different markets um Instagram has a
huge oh my go impact unfortunately I
think some of it's bad too like people
want it to look a certain way and
sometimes they're like well that's not
good CU it doesn't look right and
sometimes the ugly weed is the best weed
100% magazine weed and all of a sudden
it's like where's that
flavor some of those ugly ducklings can
just be absolutely packed yeah so for
sure wild I feel like the best batches
of cannabis I've ever had have never
been the ultra dense it's always like a
little bit spaced out a little bit you
know nothing that would indicate an
unhealthy plant sure um but yeah it's
definitely but not hard ball never the
hard ball has never for flavor
especially yeah yeah yeah
well everything those bracks get pushed
together and everything's so tight and
then you know I I just feel like it
takes away from the turps yeah takes
away from the flavor profile yeah you
know I think there's even you know
speaking of flavor I think there's a lot
to be looked at in that regard right how
the physical structure of the plant um
leads to a better combustion and
therefore a better flavor experience
right I mean how much lipids are present
in a strain and how the combustion of
those lipids can create an unpleasant or
a pleasant exper like there's still so
much there's so much that we need to Fig
we all talk about TPS where's the talk
about Esters oh yeah you know what I
mean well we can talk about THS we can
talk about I mean I guess the new term
is flavorant yes so yeah the abstracts
tech they they released a bunch of white
papers on that you know I think it's
really cool and they're breaking down
the different flavorant and and files
and how they break break down and it's
like it's great when companies start
going after that information is
flavorant a technical term now that's
being used it is now yeah not that I've
heard I've never heard that term yeah so
so abstract Tech yeah I mean I think uh
I reposted some stuff that they've
they've had but I think this falls under
the category of THS right which are
smaller molecules than tur sufur based
compound compound y exactly sulfur based
compounds right and so and that's what
gives the skunk its skunky smell and the
gas it's gas smell and you know some of
the like ammonia I'm sure that's where
the ammonia comes from y that's going be
nitrate based but but yeah even the
Citrus not all of it comes from tpin
right so like they have there's a good
explanation much better than I can
explain right now but like uh yeah we'll
post it up on the screen so everybody
can check it out but it's really
interesting and I love when companies
are just trying to take it to that next
level and you know it's with with
research and development you go in a
direction and you hope to get a result
and sometimes you don't get the result
you're looking for and you have to take
a step back and that's okay I mean
that's the beauty ofar you know I was
seeing the thing on Dyson uh he he made
I think 5,000 inferior copies before he
made his first vacuum right his real the
real one that that everybody he was
hanging from a nail just before he broke
through yeah like mortgage's house like
then all of a sudden he he cracked the
Cod right and and that's sometimes
that's what it takes it just takes not
giving up falling down getting back up
uh you know as many times as it takes
and it's like it's a mindset too yeah I
mean I think part of the mindset is
knowing that just because your
experiment didn't prove what it's set
out to prove doesn't mean that it was a
failure right that's the mindset right
as did you learn something 100% then
it's not a failure right then now you
just have more Direction on where to go
next time well yeah and I think a lot of
data collection is data points that you
can compare so like the more data points
you have the more you can understand
something whether it's a cult of our and
you want to know how it performs under
this type of circumstance uh in this
environment you know the the more
information you have the better you can
make decisions yeah your educated guest
becomes that much more educated for sure
I think a lot of this hinges on data
collection disciplined data collection
organized data collection yeah and being
able to make an observation off of that
because at the end of the day as a
scientist what you're trying to do is
make observation in the most calculated
informed way possible right um and so
like seeing what you're doing out you
know out here with 57 data points per
seedling James that's so cool yeah but I
think that's what's necessary to move
everything forward and to get as much
data as possible you know and then as
far as for breeding the more data you
have the better you can make decisions
um and then over multiple Generations
when we're doing inbreeding right and
then we know we're looking for right and
it's stuff that I I guess I I I'm going
to be able to Train everybody to to
understand everything that's that's the
Hope right right now I'm doing a lot of
it but uh you know we're working with
phenome one uh from phenome networks
it's a software program and they have
photop which you'll be able to take your
iPad out in the field and you'll be able
to go through those 50 data points not
all of them but like because some of
them are like we're measuring the plant
how fast it grows at week one and
measuring it you know stuff like that is
that sof is that the software that's
going to be available or is available it
is available now it's not cheap but it
is amazing especially for breeding and
then you us field that's what we use
here yeah and also we're a hub so we
have other locations and we're going to
be taking those locations collecting
data how it performs in one cultivar so
then we look at how it performs in
different places also one seed crop so
we look at the whole seed crop rather
than just one phenotype so you can do a
whole bunch of really interesting stuff
you know especially I I do flower so
you're not keeping any of those alive in
Clone form or tissue culture as of yet
so we need to get the data on the whole
field right or the whole room right and
then we can we can look at it and then
we can get averages oh man for your
typical feno hunts what how many
cultivars are you working and or how
many you know different fenos you you
doing at any given time it really
depends uh on on what we're doing
whether it's you know I mean I think
I like to go through a hundred sometimes
but I if I know the line really well I
don't need a 100 I know that I if I find
20 I'm going to find what I'm looking
for in some of the lines that I work and
some of the things that we do I don't
know and so in those instances you know
and is is it going to be for a field
application am I trying to sell seeds of
this or am I trying to sell a a
phenotype right because if I'm trying to
sell a clone of it I don't keep that
seed start alive I don't even feno hunt
that I get rid of it completely it's
like if it's stuff that we plan on
licensing what we do is we get rid of
that clone start completely right and I
clone it and then we grow the Clone out
and we start our pheno hunt from that
point because there's no point in
looking at something that you're not
going to get in my opinion you know it's
like let's just get away we save time we
save money and now we're starting with
something that gives us an actual
picture of what the end product is going
to look like I think that's so important
those little steps but now if I was
going to take and sell 30,000 seeds to a
farmer of that right I femin seeds that
I really like I need to know what
happens in the field we can't just throw
out those seed starts we need to grow
them out and see what they do outside
right and so growing it indoors doesn't
really matter right because we want to
know inner sex expression what that's
the big one right like it does doesn't
cause a much Herm if I sell 30,000 seeds
how many Herms do we get what what is
the percentage or you know what I mean
or if you you know we can't hunt that
big let's say we do 100 do we get one
out of 100 do we get two out of 100 do
we get zero you know but the more more
you work with especially at scale the
better picture you get of what's going
to happen but from climate to climate
you can have two completely different
results what what is there a a certain
percentage of Herms that you feel is
acceptable when you're talking about
that large a denominator absolutely so
like with autof flowers I feel like one
in a thousand is very acceptable um you
know and then one one in a 2,000 or
3,000 you might find a full-blown male
in there right but it also depends on
the envir if you have like if you have
soil that's not properly amended and
that that we have or area that's
extremely hot or extremely cold outdoor
cultivation specifically specifically
you know but like and that that's where
you the Herm is I mean obviously people
aren't growing a thousand seeds indoors
typically they're going to do clone yeah
right but outdoor where people do grow
from seed I think especially with
Autoflower like one in a thousand's very
acceptable uh but then the more stress
type scenarios are going to cause more
Herms so you're going to get more inner
sex expression the you know you stress
the plant out and you're going to cause
whe whether it's heat whether it's
fluctuations uh whether it's nutrition
you know there's so many variables that
can cause it uh and then same thing with
photo periods I mean the thing is is
like feminized people think a lot of
times like well feminized have more of a
chance of inner sex expressions for
hermaphrodites and I find that not to be
the case Cas in most situations I think
they it can be bred in or bred out uh
it's it's patience and sometimes I will
release stuff in seed form that has
interex traits I talk about it all the
time uh Mike from exotic because I was
very ad a lot of exotic gear yeah and so
I was very adamant about not selling
anything that had any INX Expressions
tell I talked to Mike and Mike convinced
me otherwise he's like well out of all
the stuff you've popped yeah have you
kept anything that some of
Express and he's like some of the best
stuff out there has interex expression
Herms absolutely and if you have 10
seeds and two of them Herm but eight of
them don't yeah and you find the winner
in that eight who cares as long as you
let you know I feel like for me it's
like awareness letting people know sure
absolutely absolutely we run uh a bunch
of his stuff and some of our favorite
cuts of his they they do Herm
periodically and we just accept it
because it's so fire dude there's some
stuff his especially oh yeah rainbow
cakes is one of our favorites and it
just a Herms so his his red runs I
haven't had any problems with Herms but
his red runs is something special so I
really like the red pop right like I
like the red pop that then the smoke was
a little bit of a let down just like a
purple punch M purple punch is a little
disappointing to me like I I love the
way it grows I love the way it smells
smells extract is fine it's it's not bad
it's not amazing but it's not it's not
bad yeah but then you go to smoke a
joint of it and you light it up it just
it doesn't taste like anything tast like
paper yeah exactly you get like the hay
taste and it's like might as well smoke
tobacco something like that you know I
mean that's how I feel about I'm like I
just I get more enjoyment out of tobacco
than I do out of smoking purple punch um
but that red pop it has the all the
beauty that you need it gets that runs
in there with so so the red pop is sorry
the red pop is like a so it tastes like
Cherry Cola is that the one that the
popping bottles is from is that or is
that different I'm not sure bottles is
one that we're just you know hunting
right now just I I don't it I don't keep
all the crosses in my brain like you do
like I don't have that encyclopedia but
popping bottles is one of the new ones I
was wondering if that's one of yeah he
has some really good stuff and I yeah
code red so we're running we've got
we're harvesting code red got to be
really it's got be right's got to be in
that red pop was good but it was it's
like it's like I say like all these
things whether it's purple punch or
Oreos or whatever it is these are all
one like apple fritters is another one
for me but they're all one step away
from amazing you know or or two steps or
whatever and it doesn't flavor component
it could be it's just missing one thing
right staining kind of you might need to
cross it to something and then go
through the selection process and find a
winner and sometimes it's that easy
sometimes it's not that's what's so
frustrating about feno hunting is you
got the boxes that you need to have
checked yield potency flavor you know
how do they grow all those boxes need to
be checked if you're going to fold it
into a program and it's so frustrating
when you get to that Finish Line it's
like all the Box are checked but
one yeah or you go to the end and you're
like the one you're like this is the one
and then everybody goes to smoke it and
they're like that's not the
one and it happens all the I would say
it happens more than it doesn't happen
where like the ones that on the plant
you're like oh we got the winner we got
the new new latest and greatest height
this is going to be the one and it's and
once you cure it up you're like wait
what happened where was all that flavor
that we had there where did it go what
happened or sometimes the look even
you're like how does it look like this
when it look like that on the plant
seriously seriously yeah yeah I mean
there genetic math right it's like it's
like trying to predict the Plinko right
it's seriously it's like it's well it
just takes time and patience and I mean
the the breeding at it's the long game
right it's the long game and it's it's
all patience especially the feno hunting
because anybody can make seeds right
that's not the hard part the hard part
It's a Grind it's a year at least Forum
of year do right to do it right to get
to get something into production us it's
a year that's what we always think about
when we get something going about a year
yeah yeah yeah for sure well then we get
everything in TC so we have it backed up
in TC so that our n impressive out
that's just so impressive yeah I got a
good partner he's really solid with TC
and he does mirror stem TC which is
different than most companies do Nole
and I feel like when we're pulling it
out of mirr stem I'm very confident that
it's clean and we're not going to have
something come back when we look when
you look at at at tissue culture as a a
great solution for that one of the the
you know we haven't moved into that you
know yet and and and I feel like we're
late to the party on that what's the
what what are we looking at in terms of
cost when it comes to actually making
that part of your sop at a farm a
commercial scale I mean I think you can
build a lab for less than
$100,000 right and then you're looking
at an employee skilled employee you need
a skilled employee depending on where
you live is what's going to dictate that
if you have somebody like Justin we can
hire a tech that's
an hour in the area maybe less up there
but if you if you have a a Justin or
someone that's on that level you know
those guys can can range anywhere from
100 to whatever so so let me understand
sort of the two levels here one is what
you're talking about is actually
building out a a room at your facility
that ultimately is a designated TC room
correct you need a lot of specialized
equipment right so and then what about
subbing that out is there is there a
concept there where we clean genetics we
we take like let's say you have stuff
coming in and and let's say you pop it
from seed here's the beauty of that
where you're feno hunting it yourself
yeah you pop it from seed you keep it
clean you keep it in a pretty sterile
environment as sterile as you can uh we
can do nodle on that right and then we
can put it in Mir stem as well so you
can get it back right away in Nole uh
and then it goes through marem and then
Banking and that costs any you know I
mean we Char 5500 for genetic typically
per genetic yeah per genetic that's
that's the thing is is like you build up
your library of your proprietary stuff
yeah and then anytime you need it out
you get a clean copy you don't have to
worry about it and that's and so that's
the main upside is that you've got a
clean copy that's banked that ultimately
you can call on whenever you need it I
mean is that really it and then it takes
a few months to get out of culture if
it's in mistem you know I mean we're
we're storing stuff um but you can also
just have like a small lab that doesn't
cost $100,000 you could have a small
place where you can basically have your
own stuff coming out of culture where
you can do a lot of that stuff
yourself um you know I think the mirem
part is hard because I don't know
anybody else that Does it Like We Do It
um you know we're blessed to to have
this as a you know a solution there's a
lot of people that say they do that's
the thing is like there's other people
in the industry that are like I do this
this and this show me your coas show me
your test results from before with
hoplon and hop Lon clean after a number
of years yeah every three months let me
see it after cleaned it every 3 months
for for let me show yeah I can show you
guys ours it's like Justin can show you
3 months 6 months 9 months 12 months 18
months after with clean results you know
is that something that is part of your
Sops is it a testing every three months
he is costing yeah he's testing every
three months and so that part and then
just to clean I mean the cleaning cost
you know our cost to actually do it is
is expensive you know you figure all the
man hours that it takes you know the
media all the all the time and effort
that goes into it it's not cheap to do
it and there's nobody else really doing
the the solution correct that I know of
yeah that doesn't mean they don't exist
I just don't know yeah yeah no one of
the tricky Parts as I understand it is
you can do a good enough job where the
viral load is so low that it won't test
right for a while but but a after a
given amount of time that viral load is
going to come back up right and so from
my understanding the way that Justin
does it like there is no viral load no
he's taking UND different iated cells
right so he's taking cluster like on
syst yeah it's not the vascular right
it's beyond the vascular system he's
taking that undifferentiated cells
growing the plant from on a cellular
level right and then it's not coming
back and the thing is is like conception
I really like I'm friends with those
guys over conception I I got a lot I'm
friends with everybody I like everybody
there's nobody maybe people don't like
me but I like everybody pretty much and
conception I think they're doing a
really good job but they don't they
don't [ __ ] with h you know it's like if
it has hop PL they don't want to mess
with it right it's just not they wantan
theyve seen they they've done RNG they
don't even try to clean it if has hop
Lon they don't want it right so they
basically won't put in the system
because I believe they've had it come
back right and and that's problem like
why would we waste their time why would
they waste their time and energy and you
know I think they're they're they're a
good company yeah so I think right now
in the TC space there's still uh just a
general lack of Education as to what's
actually happening and that's why a lot
of people don't understand the
differentiation between the different
levels of TC a lot of people don't
really understand how much skill is
involved in doing it appropriately how
much actual physical skill if you think
you can do mirror stem at home you're
wrong that that doesn't happen right but
a lot of people do a lot of people are
like I'm going to go take this class
over this weekend or this week and I'm G
to pay whatever the amount of money is
and I'm going to learn how to do Miron
and it's just not the case it's a lot
harder I think I I'm one of those guys
who's like if he can do it I can do it I
I typically I'm like that and so Justin
we were in Seattle at House of cvar he
was doing some stuff up there with my
partners up there and uh they have a TC
lab and they're amazing and uh Justin's
like well you want to learn how to do
mirror stem I'm like yeah let's do it
I'd love to learn and so they got me
under the hood and I realize for one
thing that I'm my hands are too shaky
right for one thing I drink a lot of
coffee I don't have as steady of a hand
as I would like especially for stuff
like that cuz looking under a microscope
it doesn't look like my hands are
shaking at all but like you get it under
a microscope and there's just a little
bit and and it's a lot more complex and
I mean wow these guys surgical surgical
right surgical on a molecular level
right so not only is it surgical but
it's on the smallest of scale right so
it's real interesting because that
sounds like we're just around the corner
from the robot arm going in there and
doing that automating that process where
a ton of money in we have a Rob we have
a robot arm here yeah called J no no no
we actually have a robot arm wait
awesome but uh but yeah so wow but yeah
but it's not for that but it's for TC
it's for TC but it's not for the mirror
stem it's it helps mirror stem excisions
you still have to do it all yourself but
it transfers right so it'll transfer the
vessels so you're not contaminating so
and it speeds up productivity because
you're not touching the actual vessels
that they're going in gotcha wow wow wow
but yeah I mean tissue culture and then
a lot of people just they don't fully
understand tissue culture and what it is
and they're like well I could do that
and I thought the same thing and I you
know most people don't know what sterile
means no even working under a the
differentiation between disinfecting and
sterile I don't think most people could
talk through that no and another one is
like people don't even know they think
91% alcohol is better than 70 and that's
the biggest you know confus most people
are like oh I want that because it's
probably it's going to clean better the
truth is it's great for your bongs the
90% is great for your bongs it's great
for soaking scissors like if you're
cleaning your scissors off but for
sterilizing
surfaces uh 70% is better because the
contact time so you put it on there you
want a longer contact time because
that's going to kill more things except
for hop plon you don't want to use it
for alcohol alcohol or alcohol for hop L
it doesn't work it actually stabilizes
the Vero what yeah so it's the exact
opposite makes it easier to transfer
because of how it interacts with the
coating of the of the actual virus right
kind of coagulates them and makes it
easier it's completely you think alcohol
and then you're just broke my brain yeah
all right you need specialized wow yeah
bleach
oers yeah so it's it's pretty wild and I
think so much of this stuff is
counterintuitive whether it's breeding
or whether it's like viruses and viroids
like we think we understand it and it's
like you know you know enough to make
yourself dangerous but then you're
dangerous and you're spreading the virus
right like that that happens all the
time with companies it's like oh we
figured out we're just going to soak all
the scissors in alcohol in between cuts
and everything and it's like no that
doesn't that doesn't do it but it sounds
like it would but it doesn't I mean yeah
I think there's a lot of Dunning Krueger
still in this kind of where you know a
lot of people don't know how much they
don't know right um and they they learn
a tiny little bit and they're like oh
easy it's just a little pathogen I just
got to soak my I just got to soak my
scissors I mean it wasn't even that it
was like a a year ago at an event I'm
not going to name the company
oh yeah we have our new um cloning gel
cool thing about this gel it's got
alcohol in it so you don't have to clean
your
scissors you can just go ahead and dip
all the cups all the cuts right in this
one bottle you don't have to worry
because the alcohol is going to make
sure that it's perfect and I'm like
please please don't ever say that to any
customer you know yeah so I mean there's
still a just a giant lapse in education
yeah um you know I've always kind of
felt in a weird place in this industry
because I do have a formal education and
I know a lot of people don't and I've
never been one to hold that against
someone right I'm firm believer there's
a lot of different types of intelligence
right and that books smarts is only one
small part of being like an intelligent
human being right there's emotional
intelligence kinesthetic intelligence
Street intelligence Street intelligence
absolutely yeah know Common Sense born
with like a natural common sense but um
I do look forward to this industry
becoming a little bit more data driven
and making decisions based on evidence
so when I see individuals like yourself
like taking actual steps to make that a
reality like I'm so grateful because I
know that a lot of people are going to
take that information run with it and
make this industry better for everyone
involved well I think we're all Pig
piggybacking on each other like we're
standing on the shoulders of giants
especially in the breeding world like
this stuff was done in this the the
early stuff was done in 60s and 70s for
modern cannabis you know I mean land
raise stuff has been done for hundreds
of years all over the world and then we
hybridized this stuff in California in
the 60s and 70s and we're really
piggybacking on those guys that were
like let's take this cross it with this
we got this and then you know I feel
like real breeding was done back then to
a degree and I think it's starting to be
done again there's people out there that
are doing a really good job at it and
then there's a lot of people that are
just like let's just cross this with
this a lot of time
this and it's like that's just the same
thing you're just in breeding and you
don't understand you're in breeding who
are some of your current uh favorite
breeders that are doing it out there
that doing it the way you know Jackson
is probably one of my favorites uh mean
jeene um you know uh my my buddy Nick
Nick stomberg I think he's doing some
really cool stuff yeah yeah he's great
he's what's it what's the the he's
people don't even know who he is right
and he's one of those guys who's just
doing and doing it right and doing a lot
of testing he's one of the guys I look
up to I think at one point he might have
looked up to me and now I'm the guy
looking up to him like dude this guy's
doing it uh Fletch I think he's doing a
great job Mike is doing a great job um
you know I think there's there's a bunch
of people doing it right and then
there's kind of everybody else and I
mean I just I think going back to some
of the land race is not a bad way to go
I'm doing some experiments with land
race genetics um taking a step back but
also just thoroughly testing everything
I think that's super important and pheno
really doing phenoh Huns you know I mean
it's not just about making seeds and
about hype um although understanding
what's in that pack in that cross yeah
and understanding your L one way to
understand it yeah I mean I think you
need to have like a six-month plan a
oneyear plan a fiveyear plan you know
and and mine a lot of what I'm doing is
kind of Legacy stuff now I see like the
end in the distant future I mean I don't
see it tomorrow but I know that like I
only have so much time left to do all
this stuff I got my book out and so I
think that was a step in the right
direction and some of the breeding stuff
I want to do is you know it's a 10year
project this stuff is like literally
it's a 10-year project to do some of the
exciting stuff that I want to do and I
don't share all of that with everybody I
think there's some stuff that I keep for
myself but uh yeah and it's
like I I like you know so fire he's
doing some really good stuff too I think
you know him and Mike are pretty tight
mhm uh but I like a lot of their work
are you familiar with the guys over
you're talking about land race the guys
that were at a seeds that doing the okay
a seeds I love those guys those guys
were I featured them some of their
photos in my book I'm stoked so we're
just about to start feno hunting a
zamalia some Cali China I can't remember
exactly but the whole idea is right so
land race great but for for commercial
cultivation we can't wait 11 12 weeks we
need something that's it so they've got
so their whole gag is we've got land
race for you guys to run we've crossed
it with these things they're going to
help it finish in N9 weeks so we're just
about to embark on that so I'm I'm I'm
hyped to hear that you're you're I like
Ace I I like Khalifa you know it's like
my my book was written by myself and 22
other people contributed information
right so like it wasn't just me it's a a
group effort and yeah I always like
group efforts I like it I feel like
winning with a group of people is so
much more fun than just standing there
winning by yourself I don't eating alone
I'm not like one of those guys who
enjoys going to some fancy dinner by
myself I'd rather be with my friends and
celebrating with my friends it um you
know and the book is a testament to that
it's like I could have never written
some of that stuff that's in my book on
tissue culture there's a whole chapter
uh
Justin's uh partner Matt from apical
biotech he wrote the chapter on tissue
culture Dale Hunt wrote the chapter on
IP and protecting your plant you know I
think that's super important
intellectual property and plant
protection is so important people need
to at least understand it you might not
need to do it as a breeder but it's
great to understand what intellectual
property actually is or whether you're
creating something that's novel you know
or whether you're just trying to steal
somebody's because that's that's
happened too you know it's like M
Richmond he's one of my friends with his
sage like someone else tried to patent
his Sage you know and it's like that
kind of stuff is going to happen with
companies but you know what do you do in
that type of a situation M I don't think
that there's a lot
of protections right now you know with
it no but there will be because it's
it's already in a right so like we are
going to become another a commodity just
like everything else I think we're at
the stage where it's pretty normalized
you look at Oregon cannabis is pretty
normalized up there I think 100% more so
than it is here and it's only going to
grow bigger bigger bigger the the
movement's gotten stronger and stronger
to the point where it's not going away
we have our two presid presidential
candidates that are both kind of you
know leading on to believe that they're
going to decriminalize it completely on
a federal level uh so I feel like if
they're talking about it it's really you
know it's gaining you you got the whole
rescheduling you know we but baby steps
baby exactly I'm okay with that we're
not going backwards we're not that's the
thing it is going to take some we might
we might but I don't see us going
backwards in that I mean I see other
countries maybe going backwards like
Thailand oh which is silly but it's it's
like they went too crazy and then now
they're like take it back a little bit
but I see it on a global scale you look
at Portugal you look at Germany you look
at Uruguay columia Canada Mexico is even
making Leaps and Bounds um St Vincent
which is Medical in the Caribbean
Trinidad which is fully decriminalized
there's so many places Australia is
medical you know we just get enough
people to understand that it's not bad
that it makes the world a better place
that's it and then we get everybody on
board and that's where the magic happens
right yeah well there's still a lot of
deprogramming that we are and it might
take Generations right it took
generations to get here yes
unfortunately yeah yeah there's yeah
like I said the Deep the deprogramming
that needs to occur in the general
population when it comes to cannabis
well an acceptance an acceptance of
allowing people to do what they want to
do that's not hurting other people
that's not a bad thing right like the
end of the day it's not causing lung
cancer like cigarettes it's not causing
liver cancer like alcohol we might have
some psychosis that goes along with it
there might be some things but it's not
as bad as either one of those two things
yeah I mean when you compare to alcohol
it's just it's not even in the same
galaxy in terms of the harm right yeah I
mean I I would compare it to I mean
compared to almost any recreational drug
I mean it's it's safety in comparison is
yeah well the the only thing that's
safer I think that's illegal is
mushrooms psychedelics right so they're
saying that it's safer the for
pis for overd I think well no I mean you
could moments that I wouldn't get behind
the wheel after taking some mushrooms
but I have no problem driving on for
sure you shouldn't be driving on it but
I think as far as like safy I'm
just long term yeah yeah I he sure but
yeah this they need to decriminalize
psychedelics too I think that's just
silly I think they they actually are
beneficial and can make the world a
better place
with their whole psychedelic program I
think that there's a lot that's
happening I think that was John Hopkins
that I was actually referencing that
you're right absolutely but with MDMA
and with psilocybin I think both of
those are starting to actually become
more widely accepted for their
therapeutic effects helping people get
over traumas andely they just they just
announced a ban on therapeutic MDMA I
don't know if you heard about that did
they they said more studies need to be
done that's good that's good so they
didn't yeah
they that was yeah they didn't complet
Kash they just said more studies need to
be that's good that's good that's
understandable and respectable yeah yeah
yeah for sure I mean I never thought I'd
see this push in my lifetime you know um
I agree with you I I I do think
psychedelics can make the world a better
place uh I have had such a crazy
attitude shift Within Myself right from
looking at myself in my younger days
always blaming the world nothing was
ever my fault always angry sore loser
you just had an experience that made me
you know know feel the love of the earth
and realize hey man there's there's a
better way to approach life there's a
more positive way to approach life and
seeing like what kind of impact that had
on myself made me really want to have
other people have like a
similar I I guess it's not for everyone
you it's not for everybody but I got to
experience it from a young age but I I
believe that like sometimes we go
through life and all these things that
we experience put a filter over us true
right so we see the world a certain way
with all these filters stacked on us to
lift those filters back and kind of see
the world how it really
is um you know it's a beautiful amazing
thing and I think stress stress is just
such a killer and sometimes if you can
do you use some form of a psychedelic or
even cannabis to get over these
stressful things and realize that
they're not as bad as we want to make
them it's a perspective sh it's a
perspective what's always amazed me
right is the power that it has to impart
empathy on people right and I think you
know as three consumers of cannabis I
think we all probably feel that if the
world was a more empathetic place it
would be a better place no there's no
question and I think that that for me is
something that I I can't wait to learn
more about why does that happen yeah you
know I have my theory which is I think
that like naturally when you consume a
psychedelic you have such a deeper
appreciation for the natural world in
your life and I think that's just where
it comes from I think we are all so
disconnected right you know from what
makes being alive so special
you know that being forced to kind of
appreciate just pretty colors or how
many people empathy right empathy also
CU because we look at the world from our
perspective and we don't realize that
everybody has their own view of the
world they're looking at their own lens
right they've experienced things
differently so everybody has a different
perspective and that's where empathy
comes in when you realize that there's
other perspectives than your own that's
yeah that's a good point and uh yeah I
I'm excited to see more research coming
out the stigma being broken I mean
that's one we're still I mean the stigma
on hallucina genics is still I think
pretty strong because even amongst my
contemporaries there's still a lot of
there's a lot of people that I've been
able to convince you know but there's
still a lot of people that are just like
deathly scared you know and like I don't
I don't I don't want to jump off a hotel
balcony it's like that's not that's not
necessarily what's going to happen I
think fear is a good thing it absolutely
you should go
all willy-nilly for sure yeah yeah but I
think we're moving in a good direction
absolutely so let's talk about Oregon
because you're from Eugene I love Eugene
my friend Sunny's from Eugene OR he
lives up in Eugene right now I've gone
to been going to Eugene for a long time
I love the the food scene up in Eugene
uh the breweries up in Eugene food
trucks too yeah yeah I mean you guys yep
I think Portland has us beat on the food
scene but they do but you guys have some
really cool stuff I've had some really
good experiences up there yeah Portland
definitely I mean I was born in Portland
I love yeah same thing with the beer
scene it's good in Portland you guys
have your own thing down in Eugene
though and I it's it's a slower way of
life the people that live in Eugene
pretty much love living in eug like I
was in SoCal for almost 30 years I went
down to UCLA and and when we moved up to
Oregon to the to the farm you know 32
Acres out in the middle of Farmland it
was just like I literally felt like I
had landed in Paradise like just it's
just it's beautiful up there it's magic
nice yeah yeah organ's beautiful so how
did you get your start in the Cannabis
industry well so I was down in LA and uh
you know I mean I I started growing at
UCLA in in closet like a lot of a lot of
guys in college did and U lot of people
on the show did actually yeah so
two-bedroom apartment we had two closets
you know veg and flower it was perfect
um but my buddy's dad had uh started a
hydrarm and uh so he you know he hooked
us up with some gear and and from that
moment I was kind of hooked in terms of
that magic of taking something you know
like a little clone and then turning it
into finished flower it was just it was
incredible but I've I've been you know
involved in in cultivation my whole life
my parents always had like vegetable
gardens and and Orchards and it was
always something that I just LED doing
so i' had been down at in in La running
a landscape construction company for
almost 20 years and so again involved
with plants nurseries cultivation
and um the opportunity came for us to
move up to Oregon in 2015 and that
summer that we moved up there measur 91
had just passed and so it was you know
it was now a a legal Prospect to
actually you know really develop a solid
business so my wife's an attorney and
she thought well you know if we can
actually do this legal beagle then let's
let's push into this let's take all of
your background let's take all of your
experience and let's actually let's
let's do it and the farm was was kind of
falling apart I mean you know the the
farm was was you know it had been in the
family for a number of years and was not
doing well it was not a sustainable
model financially so at the end of the
day you know all my years in running
businesses like you have a great
business but if it doesn't pencil it
doesn't pencil it's not sustainable so
we wanted first and foremost to create a
sustainable model and save the farm and
create something that felt like we could
actually build something meaningful
there so 2015 we started doing the build
build out um and it was just me and and
and one other guy my my my best buddy
from from NorCal um who came up and and
helped me get everything
going and we started with one veg room
and one flower room and that was it it
was just very humble beginnings and we
started with one cut we had one Cult of
our that we launched the entire farm
with and that was alpha blue so one of
so his his good buddy in NorCal had had
uh uh been breeding and had uh alpha
blue which is New York City Diesel cross
with blue dream and we started and so we
say that the farm is the you know sort
of the house at Alpha built so alpha
blue is our longest running cultivar
it's our you know still to this day one
of our most popular
cultivars um it's funny I've never
smoked it but I can imagine exactly what
it tastes like yeah it it it is just
that Berry forward flavor that's just
yeah yeah it's it's fantastic you get
the you well so blue dream has an
amazing structure it's like the apical
of structures right as far as grows
really well it's super vigorous the root
system is just amazing with it we always
talked about putting OG Kush plants and
grafting them onto Blue Dream right so
this conversation from 15 years ago or
something like that because OG was so
finicky but like the so basically the
New York City Diesel that's a great
fruit great fruit like citrusy it's got
a nose bur to it too yeah and but it
grows really big it might be a little
less dense than blue dream but those two
profiles seem like they would marry
really was killer so then he ended up
Crossing alpha blue with a bunch of
other crosses that we launched uh we we
folded into the program he crossed it
with Granddaddy Purple he crossed it
with the DJ Short Blueberry so we had
you know we had our you know our whole
lineup was sort of founded on alpha blue
in in the early days um and then from
there it was just literally just one
room at a time each Harvest paid for the
next upgrade paid for the next paid for
the next and we just iterated from there
so um I I feel like
a little bit of the competitive
Advantage early days was just that I was
focused on developing a sustainable
business not just growing great weed and
I you know and sort of for me like
cultivation if you look at the at
the the definition of cultivation right
the first definition you find is of
course around plants and cultivating
things but the second definition is
skill acquisition or acquiring knowledge
or qualities right and so the fusion for
me for my entire life is been
cultivating right whether it's been
music or sports or you know whatever
it's cultivating and it's cultivating
something at the highest possible level
that you can right so for me a lot of
the driver was just like if we're going
to do this we're going to run cultivars
that nobody else has we're going to do
it in a way that nobody else is doing it
and nobody had LEDs at the time in 2015
fluence was just emerging with their
LEDs so I hated the purples right the
blur PES terrible right fluence came out
with amazing light people were scared to
use it for sure so so Jerry one of the
founders of fluence flew out to Oregon
he was making a few stops trying to get
people on board for this Tech and he
showed up plugged in the first light and
it blew me away it was not the the
purple party lights it was an actual
legit like powerful fixture yeah and at
the time you know I I I I talked to a
few people about it they're like you're
[ __ ] crazy like Ells are not ready
for prime time you're going to be you
know like are you going to get three lbs
of light like you know was that
so far ahead of their time because
everybody was scared to go there I was I
was like done with LEDs at that point
yeah I'd seen so many my friends yeah so
many of my friends grew with those and
would you know have always really proud
of what they've grown right or what
they're growing and they want to bring
you over their spot and it's like you
got to be kidding me this looks like
[ __ ] it it's ter like just the yield and
may 500 ppfd like it was like nothing
density it was like yeah it's so so that
was it I mean we really were just like
focused on on really trying to do
something different and I felt like with
the LEDs we were going to Define
ourselves in a different way and we
weren't going to be running hydro which
is again totally fine I have nothing
against coco or Hydro but I was a focus
on soil and LEDs and that was that was
how I wanted to to run the program yeah
um and that's what we've been doing for
almost 10 years now um have you tried
under canopy yet so so there's there's
two things that that uh you know you can
sort of never have enough of in life
well there's I guess several things but
but one of them are in in indoor
cultivation are amps yeah right so you
you run out of amps it turns out like
you just like no matter how many amps
you think you need double it right and
so we have you know multiple multiple
600 amp drops and we just ended up you
know going through it as just quick as
you possibly could y so under canopy
lighting from a from an amp perspective
and from a logistical perspective to
outfit every one of our seven flowers
rooms with under canopy lighting it's
just like I literally don't have the
power to run that wow um but the idea of
actually setting up under canopy
lighting I I know people are having
great success with that um it's just not
something that we have have embarked on
um I feel like you know maybe the return
is there I don't know what the I don't
know what the numbers say in terms of
the return on inv get one and see what
happens you know I feel like and and the
only and and the only reason we haven't
it's sort of like you just need to try
heroin one time to see what happens like
I don't actually want to try it one time
to
see so so that's been the mindset with a
lot of the stuff that we've done is like
if it works yeah like let's run biob Biz
right well great that's going to cost $8
million a month to run a commercial
facility on bobiz I don't even want to
see what the results are going to be
because I just it's just not going to
pencil right so it's it's been tough for
me to get on the under canopy lighting
train just because I don't have the amps
uh or the appetite to try to to to to
manage that but I'm sure that there are
cats that are using it and it's working
well and it probably does pencil yeah um
we have such we've got six different
pre-roll lines in our lineup and so uh
we love bbds like so so a lot of that
lower stuff that just doesn't develop
because I don't have the under canopy
lighting or the the the ppfd down
there's just too low for those lower
nugs to develop fine they have nice TPS
I got no issue with that you know I need
those bbds right we're always chasing
more bbds to continue to feed those
pre-roll lines um so yeah I mean so are
you grading yours with the screen and
then separating them like that or how do
you guys do yeah yeah uh exactly so
again every trim cycle every Cult of our
slightly different we've got certain
strains like our grease cookies that
that we found in our in our in our
monkey berries hunt so we run a
strawberries and cream and a grease
cookies and that grease cookies we can
we can practically trim every single nug
on that just because it's so dense um
we're definitely big in defoliation so
we we try to you know we do a week three
and a week six def um so we we we want
to make sure that we're getting that
good penetration down there but you know
with with what we get out of the fluence
fixtures um we're averaging 12 1300 ppfd
across the tops of the canopy and we're
getting good penetration there so yeah
yeah yeah uh so yeah it's just been it's
just been a process of of iterating and
evolving and chasing always I mean it
drives my team nuts uh but I'm just
literally relentlessly experimenting
just constantly trying new things and
seeing how we can improve and that's how
we that's how we got onto the beant
stock Trin is because I felt like there
was a way to get fertility to go with
the biology that we knew is critical and
with all the compost tees and some of
the different uh the photop
photosynthesis plus we're a big fan of
that Armory we run Armory um and so
we're we're big into ensuring that all
the fungal bacterial load in that soil
is optimized to cycle those nutrients
right but I knew that the fertility side
of things could be more efficient and
potentially more cost effective and
that's and that's why we've been
experimenting with beanock now for for 5
years um yeah and and we went through a
phase where we started it at 100% um and
one of the big challenges and I would
say to anyone who's interested in trying
the bean stock 110% try it but be
mindful of a couple things if you're
running in soil in the same way that
you're talking about the tissue culture
testing every three months as part of
that sop you have to soil test every
single round that gets loaded into our
rooms we run a soil test with Logan Labs
it's bucks why would you not want to
know every single time what the the the
the composition of your soil is yeah
Logan laugh is great love Logan Labs
yeah totally right so shout out Logan
Labs I I think that I think that part of
our process was understanding you know
what our bulk soil was was like cycle to
cycle how could we continue to stoke
that fertility and how can we do it in a
way that makes sense and when we first
started running the the bean stock we
were running it at 100% we were running
all the lines the fortify the KOST the
absolute flower running basis and veg
and we weren't minding the store with
regular soil testing we saw our salinity
start to climb as soon as we as soon as
we noticed it we were like oh [ __ ] like
the salinity is a bit out of whack and
so you have to be mindful of soil
testing and and monitoring salinity
levels monitoring everything but but
certainly when you're running a
salt-based a mineral based uh uh input
like that you do need to be you need to
you know keep an eye on that right you
do reuse your soil right we do yeah we
exactly exactly yeah if you're not
reusing your soil it's not a big deal EX
if you're reusing your so again that
pencil is better for us so we've got a
bulk vendor up there that I mean we at
this point we've got over 100 yards of
soil on the farm and and we just mix 15
yard batches at a time we re amend uh
with dry amendments uh we bring more
bioch chart of the party etc etc so
we're constantly cycling that soil so we
are testing and testing and testing to
make sure that the composition of that
soil is what we really are looking for
when we load in a room so when we
started working with beanock we we we
ran the RX that they they had laid out
for us and it worked I mean we saw it
just absolutely heroic yields just cycle
after cycle the yields were absolutely
through the roof and one of one of uh
you know my my current Garden manager
shout out Morgan um is uh you know one
of the you know pickiest [ __ ]
when it comes to flavor of smoke and
he's all about running [ __ ] in an
organic soil medium like that's it no
salts and and and when we started you
know experiment with the beanock we kind
of lost him yeah he just was no longer
passionate about the grow he just lost
his his Mojo and it was really
disheartening for me and it was really
frustrating to see that he had no longer
really you know committed in the way
that he was before when it was just
compost teas and dry amendments that we
were scratching in every round and so we
started doing the Pepsi challenge every
single Harvest every single cultiv our
yeah
and which one did he end up picking over
and over again the one run with beans
wow and so all of a sudden he's like wow
so a hybrid model actually is kind of
interesting and so that is what
ultimately sold him and that is what
sells anyone when it comes to
experimenting you have to see it for
yourself you have to try it for yourself
you have to then taste it and you have
to see does this meet my standard does
because on paper it can look completely
different where you're like okay well
this or you have a the mindset that it
has to be 100% organic and I only want
an organic product I don't want anything
else because the best the plants don't
[ __ ] care I'm just going to tell you
right now they need what they need and
if if if what they need is not there go
ahead and let me know how your garden
looks right so part of it for us is the
way that we think about being stock so
what we started doing is we started
doing a a 33% a 66% and 100% dosing and
we just started playing around with it
we started running just absolute flour
we started running absolute flour with
uh with with K boost we started running
every conceivable combination we could
at every conceivable dosing that we
could and and what we found is this
hybrid model represents essentially a
perfect insurance policy for an organic
soil-based approach make sure that the
fertility is there make sure that the
biology is there if the plants need it
it's there if they don't need it cool
but our our our by far best Harvest and
it's you know cultivar to cultivar
you're going to find differences sure
but for the most part our sweet spot is
basically a half dose of that RX in the
absolute flour that is that's the home
run for us when we run flour yeah um we
there are certain Cult of ours that love
that extra potassium and so the K boost
really does play a great role and some
are heavy feeders some are lighter
feeders and and so you talked about we
talked about a moment ago that it takes
about a year to feno hunt talk about
getting to know a so once you found that
feno you're all excited about it cool go
ahead and factor in another year to dial
or more or more or more to then go okay
so more light less light more food less
food whatever the case is and that PL
changes in that first year it changes a
little bit right and it's going to
settle out somewhere between the the
first year and the second year to where
it has that same expression every time
you grow it yeah because so yeah between
the the first colonal generation second
colonal third fourth there can be
changes sometimes it's subtle sometimes
it's drastic uh the most drastic is from
seed to that first colal generation but
for sure from the first colonal to the
fourth colonal it can it can change
slightly over time too so yeah yeah yeah
I I just think that you know at the end
of the day um you know everyone wants
heavy yields I don't think anyone would
say no I don't want heavy yields
everyone wants flavor right everyone
wants those TPS in there everyone wants
that potency right um and so you know
the
beanock fertilizer represents a really
really effective way to ensure that your
fertility program is on point we're
we're managing in our busy Seas we're
managing somewhere around 7,000 plants
right which you know for some grows that
might
for other people that might sound like a
huge number for us it's daunting as [ __ ]
because you can't have you know 50
people on staff managing those those
plants and expect to have your margins
make sense right so you're running as
lean a team as you possibly can in order
to you know make sure that everything's
being taken care of but the the the
fertility program that you run has to
pencil and it's got to be something that
from a labor perspective is extremely
efficient right so the the you know we
we we ran uh be stock for quite a while
and and and then we we stopped to see if
like okay if we actually were just you
know redoubled our efforts with you know
top dressing and dry amendments and we
redoubled our efforts on this organic
approach maybe we can pull it off and it
was just it's just so hard you're just
trying to land a you know like a rocket
on a fraction when you're when you're
running that program at commercial scale
with that many plants that many moving
Parts it's just to damn hard in my
opinion yeah everyone's got their own
take on it but when you're looking for
something that ultimately works and
pencils and works for your
team the beanock is the way that we have
found and we call it our hybrid model
right it's the mother mag hybrid model
and it's running really great soil
that's absolutely loaded with you know
fungal and bacterial uh dominent uh uh
biology and then you just the fertility
is taken care of we don't stress about
it yeah it just works so that's that's
been our story with it nice yeah yeah I
wanted to add that uh Tom is actually
currently doing a lot of work on YouTube
on his own personal Channel kind of
taking people through how he actually
uses the product right so if anyone
after the podcast is interested into
delving into a more
granular pun maybe intended
there no I appreciate that so yeah the
mother Magnolia cultivation YouTube
channel is brand new we've only got I
think about 12 videos out but part of it
is just the The Passion of talking about
you know these different things that we
work on from uh these different products
to you know lighting all the different
things that go into cultivation but
we're trying to we're trying to to find
a sweet spot where this you know the the
Nexus of of of of cultivation you know
really is something that people can
connect with because I I I firmly
believe that you know we're all
cultivating you know cool things in our
lives everyone's you know got their
thing that they're cultivating right
that that that list is is almost
Limitless relationships relationships
creativity cooking whatever health and
wellness like there's so much that goes
into you know a day-to-day you know
cultivation program and we we want to
ultimately use actual cultivation as a
place for people to understand that that
mindfulness that intentionality that
Focus that discipline that Relentless
persistence through the resistance that
you get when you're trying to cultivate
actual plants where bugs are trying to
you know hijack your crops and all of
the different challenges that go into it
is a direct correlate to to life and
everything you're trying to actually
work on in your life and if you can use
a garden as a place to work on those
different skills they are transferable
skills
100% I agree I agree and as far as like
the industry yeah I mean what's your
opinion on going to school to learn how
to grow I mean I think so this is a
tough one because we've talked about it
with other people and I as a chef yeah
went to culinary school but I don't
think other people should go to culinary
school and I feel like cuz cooking is a
mentorship yeah skill kit to learn how
to cook in K it's a it's it's a mentor
type the best experience is a mentor
type experience where you have where
you've learned from somebody who's
learned from somebody else and put their
own touches on it transmission direct
transmission I believe that the the
garden is the same thing I feel like the
best way is to go work as a water boy or
whatever it is you want to get out there
you want to learn go grow at home go go
work for somebody go water their plants
if they like you they'll teach you some
stuff totally if they don't like you
they'll fire you but but uh I think that
that again that hybrid model is exactly
it do it yourself go dig it out of the
dirt yourself figure it out right and
then where you're if you're really
passionate about it and you really want
to pursue it further 100% you got to get
tucked under somebody's wing and you got
to you got to Shadow and you got to just
you know be in those trenches and
understand all of the different nuances
that go into it because it's you know at
the end of the day um you know again
just my opinion I think that cultivation
um is a really really challenging uh uh
thing to do at a very high level yeah I
think it's really challenging to do at a
very high level it's it's not that tough
to just grow plants you know whether
it's but at a high level with
consistency with consistency scale scale
with multiple
employees so for the typical hom grower
though who's just ultimately hey I just
want to do three or four plants whatever
maybe just a couple that in and of
itself is not a a just a giveaway that
and of itself will have a lot of
challenges I think something like this
is absolutely a killer solution for the
hom grower who simp
Simplicity a lot of times if you start
simple you're going to have good results
if you try to over complicated it true
you know that's where you go for sure
and there's there's going to be some
some core sort of you know major through
lines whether it's for hom grow or at
scale but I think that ultimately you
just have to be in the trenches you have
to actually do it day in and day out
like any skill like anything right
cooking learning guitar if you really
want to take it to a really elevated
level where you want to cultivate that
skill it takes a lot of effort it takes
a lot of up does it just does or just
you know and then if you want to be
great yeah if you want to be great it
takes a lot more right so what I'm
hoping for our YouTube channel is that
we can sort of throw you know our iron
in the fire give our perspective about
what cultivating you know our our style
of cultivation in Oregon on our farm how
we run it yeah hoping that we can
actually learn from other people that
actually come into that community that
have comments already just in the first
you know three four weeks of posting
videos we've gotten great comments and
great feedback from people I'm like damn
that's another way of doing it yeah
absolutely there's so many different
paths to that Mountaintop I'm hoping
that by actually just sharing what we've
learned over the last 10 years of
cultivating cannabis at scale I'm hoping
that we're going to learn more as we
actually share that information that
becomes sort of this great feedback loop
where we can share what we've learned
and then we can learn from other people
that are saying you know this is how I
do it this is what works for us so
beautiful right now and the community
aspect as well is 100% that's it I mean
I think that's at the end of the day the
e system up in Oregon it's super super
tight-knit and there are some phenomenal
Growers up there I have to give my you
have different genetics up there too you
know you have completely different gen I
I go to the dispenser I see all kinds of
stuff that we don't see in the Bay Area
we see more sativa you know they're
definitely more sativa and more stuff
that's you know I think there's more
diversity up there but there's always
been I feel like we back in 1997 I grew
the organ blueberry it wasn't DJ shorts
it was these spear plants that grew
really tall there's a three blueberries
that I know there's Oregon blueberry
there's the DJ Short Blueberry which was
a short planty right and then there was
a one that was from Canada the Canada
blueberry right which my friend just
gave me some of which was good and
that's why our blueberry short stack is
currently on ice and not in our lineup
yeah because the plant structure yeah
was such a [ __ ] to deal with you
know in production and the yields were
just not great the flower it's some of
the absolute best flower that we have
ever grown full stop and people
absolutely hit us up on regular basis
like when are you going to bring back
the blueberry there's a few cultivar
like that just go blueberry muffin it'll
work that's a good one it yields
finishes quick those seeds are pretty
homogenous I'm not sure but I I we the
cut the cut the Clone is great so again
then this is why company this is why we
wouldn't do that is because there's
blueberry muffin out there like I like
it I like your model so then it's like
from our perspective it's a strain game
as a producer up in Oregon it's such a
competitive market and there's people
that are doing it at such a high level
that we don't want to be growing
something that somebody else has we
don't want to have to have so yours are
all exclusive pretty much you either
pheno hunted them or pretty much there's
clearly going to be some overlap you're
not growing Jagger no no and and so like
the Exotic stuff like we we feel like we
were early to the Exotic party and that
other Growers started seeing our exotic
gear that was that we were you know
posting on Instagram and putting out in
the shops and then people start then we
started seeing exotic slowly start you
know percolating through the ecosystem
up there I could be completely wrong I'm
not what whatever but the point is that
you have to be really careful and at
some point if you've got a a strain that
that that you're loving and that's
working really well and then all of a
sudden two three other people start
running it that's probably time to go
ahead and retire that and move on to
something new um it's it's it's just uh
it's a really competitive market up in
Oregon I don't know the the SoCal Market
uh the California Market R Lemon Cherry
gelato
got it yeah yeah I mean runs sorry runs
called 10 different things it still runs
Lemon Cherry G called 10 20 30 different
things it's still the same my phone I
just course yeah so I just I I I went
ahead I wanted to just you know have a
quick you know rundown of some of the
genetics my brain does not function the
way that yours does when it comes to
genetics and keeping all the different
strain names and it's kind of the guilt
that I was talking about earlier I can't
[ __ ] do it I love it so much I can't
not keep
so back in the 90s in Oregon we got
stuff from Eugene we got the dog we got
the fourway dog well I never got the dog
[ __ ] but we had the dog which was chem
dog right we got it as D AWG was from
for they they renamed it because it's
really dog but we had the Trinity which
was pretty amazing there was the
four-way there was the corn and there
was the snow not the snow cap we just
got it was the snow it was very
different but those were the organ
genetics that I remember that came down
that just blew my mind like that's when
I was like organ has the genetics they
have the stuff because we had good stuff
in the bay bay area too obviously I mean
the bay area has been an epicenter for a
long time but or's done it yeah I've
been getting genetics from from the 90s
it's almost like all the way back then
Bay Area was like a cultural epicenter
and we were kind of hijacking a lot from
the
pnw it almost like from from a genetic
perspective genetic perspective like I I
felt like a lot of it I think Santa Cruz
was like a big epicenter right and I
think humble also like I think there's a
lot of people that never got credit for
their amazing work in Humble especially
like the farmers up there I mean there
was so many farmers doing it and then
you know we've had guys talking about
generation after Generation Um obsolete
you know it's like he's uh I don't know
if you're familiar with obsolete Allen
from obsolete he is obsolete but anyway
you know Farmers going generation to
generation they'd select their best
plant and they they'd basically
pollinate it and those would be the
seeds for the next year almost like
heirloom tomatoes huh I mean it's it's
the same concept they would do it like
like an a model right before we had
before they had clones even if they were
clone that that was how they brought the
genetics and kept them alive and get
next season's crop ready some of the
most amazing stuff interesting you know
and there was bag seeds and then there
was all kinds of stuff so there was a
lot of things going on there was a lot
of factors and the Europeans also did a
lot of interesting breeding as well
Strain Hunters strain yeah I mean not
just Strain Hunters the guys but yeah
Strain Hunters going all over the world
you know Ben droners Arian Ross Cam and
those guys killing it over at Greenhouse
Seed Company I'm good friends with those
guys but uh you know it's like early
days of Sensei seeds those guys did they
amazing adventures all over Simon from
serious seeds he did amazing work he's
like a true F1 breeder what a life they
must have lived man dude I mean just
really interesting stories and amazing
gentics and like to take land race
genetics and get AK-47 out of it it's
like most people they they couldn't even
fathom what it would take to do that and
I think a lot of people it's so far over
their head they would really need to
understand what happens with land race
genetics and how hard it is to breed
with this genetics unable and then you
throw stuff that's like yeah I mean just
wild that you would never use and the
amount of space it would take to do
something properly yeah yeah I think
that's the thing that's just so you know
so daunting when you when you look at
even pheno hunting regardless I mean
breeding is probably like pheno hunting
on steroids in terms of the difficulty
right in terms of actually achieving
what you're trying to achieve and the
time that it takes well a lot of times
you have a direction and you're going
this way and you end up over here but at
least you're making forward progress
right I just you know it's just I I
think that a lot of it is just you know
people just don't want to spend the time
because it's just so challenging it's
it's it's it's expensive both in time
and money and then with no promise that
you're actually going to get what you're
basically opening baseball card pack
that's that's basically it so why not
just you know get some cuts and and
let's move on that's why it's you start
to see the you know the homogeneous
layout of of of strain starts to emerge
and you get the purple punch everywhere
yeah I mean I think that's going to work
for some you get Jack you start breeding
stuff and you cross and stuff and then
you end up with Jack like like not and
not the good quality of Jack we use that
as a reference but it's like the you
know it all come Adam dun actually said
that originally but like you overbreed
stuff you end up with Jack right like it
all comes back to that TP lyine and that
that Prof like the haze profile a little
bit the lmon especially that pops out
and it's super dominant and not
recessive and will eat up any cool
profile you cross it with anything and
it ends up with that eventually and yeah
I mean trying to I think you know going
back to what you're talking about is you
know hunting land race right trying to I
guess what we're really trying to do
there is we're trying to find a new
color a new flavor that's maybe just
been hidden I need a magenta right yeah
you know yeah I need
some whe right and so that's an
interesting way of looking at it just
trying to find that new something that's
that's never and I get excited about you
know the most craziest things uh fried
chicken I want Fried Chicken turps you
know like that excites me though when
we're going through squeezy we're like
whoa we smell this or we smell that or
translate right like we get the Belgian
waffles they smell like Belgian waffles
and maple syrup yeah you know and
sometimes it doesn't translate to the
smoke but on the plant it's really cool
yeah no our current top turp is pot
roast ni in our snow skunk it's by far
the favorite smoke on on the farm and it
just smells like straight up pot roast
like that's what it smells like yeah you
open a bag and it's like that's your
denty Moore that you had as a kid or
whatever it's crazy you should name it
auu a it's actually a great name that is
a good name yeah it's it's funny you
might be stealing that that's good
that's good yeah yeah I mean certain
things and people get excited about
certain things so you know in in the Bay
Area and in La I think a lot of it's
like it's got to be purple candy gas to
check the boxes right if it's not candy
and it's not purple in this market you
can have gas you know gas is good but
you got to have the candy it's almost
like the evolution of the purple
movement you know it's like purple never
went away it just turned into candy gas
that's what it feels like to me oh it
went away for a minute it was like you
couldn't sell GDP to save your life like
20 years ago 15 years ago let see it
years right say 2010 is more the GDP
kind of went down GDP yeah maybe 2008
but GDP was on top you you know the guys
like Luke scarmazzo he's been on the
podcast it's like he built his career
his dispensary was built on GDP Jimmy
Meyers is the guy he was on the podcast
he's the one who brought GDP to the
market right he's the one who got it he
didn't breed it but he's the one who
brought it and got it named and it was
hot hot but then there was a point where
like you couldn't sell it to save your
life yeah and then with cookies has
started making a come super rare to find
GDP in the Oregon Market it's just here
too now it's just not there we have a
GDP that's crossed with our alpha blue
that we call Sangria Kush nobody wants
to grow real GDP though it takes a long
time to veg it's a short plant so so the
reason why this the the reason why our
Sanga Kush is on the is is again on Ice
we are going to bring her back in a
cycle is just because she's such a fussy
[ __ ] she's just a nightmare to work
with but the a flower that comes off of
her is absolutely stunning absolutely
stunning she uh you know checks the
potency box the turps on her is just
that loud Berry just blast it's
unbelievable right unbelievable and
she's been gone now from our lineup for
over a year and we were just recently at
a at a at a big nectar party event
that's our biggest you know customer and
they're the largest retailer up in in in
Oregon shout out nectar um and a bunch
of the bud tenders uh hit up the table
like where's that sangria Kush where's
that sangria kush yeah yeah so we're
going to bring it back nice yeah it's be
it's Grand it's the Granddaddy Purple
it's the magic of that granddaddy purple
that that that really is GDP is pretty
special yeah the flavor don't try to
tell me that GDP is not in cookies right
so that's oh so you Cherry Pie Cherry
yeah cherry pie GDP are almost they're
so yeah cherry pie Herms a little bit
GDP Herms a little bit um only one I
grew was urk I
thinkest had experience with with the
GDP
herming I had most the experience with
growing yeah I mean I did I had actually
I take that back I had a story where I
got seeds from some guy and I learned
early on that uh you need to pheno hunt
every batch of seeds you get from people
because the first batch no issues second
batch and up you know and we sold them
under our brand and I learned that you
make your own seeds you don't sell seeds
under your brand that other people have
made because yeah it was just access see
good you know I'm glad it happened so
early on with my brand because if it
hadn't happened who knows down the road
what would have happened but it made it
could have bit you bad yeah and I
understood and and you know that
was 14 years ago right what I I had a or
13 years ago but it was a it was a
wakeup call and it was like okay yeah
this is how you do things the right way
and you got to test everything right so
you test everything you test your own
stuff you test other people's stuff if
you're going to use it if you're going
to breed with it you want to test it
before you don't just get a cut and
breed with it and then sell the seeds
you got to make sure to test it I mean
we make 300 outcrosses a year basically
every year like sometimes more sometimes
a little bit less but we only release a
small portion of those to get tested now
sometimes they have intersex trades
sometimes they have some weird stuff
going on but but at least you can tell
people at least you can tell people and
you have honest feedback you know I mean
I think that's super important I mean
there's plenty of myself included if you
told me hey look this pack of seeds it's
got some fire in it but there's
also I'm gonna go for that pack that's
who I am but some guys aren't and some
guys are like I only buy rags and it's
like that's okay that's you you there's
no problem with only buying rags and I
you know and as as long as there's
disclosure on that seed pack I think
that's all fair I think it's fair game
right where you're like hey bag seed or
whatever it is go find it cuz there's
maybe a a golden ticket in there yeah
that's fair game I think it's when it's
it's presented as something that's not
that they get that's where the heartburn
kicks in oh there something yeah it's
like espe when you're spending $200 you
know for oh it's crazy what seeds can go
for these days yeah Leo from a ficado he
sells his seeds for whatever 200 bucks a
pack and you know he's one of the best
breeders I know to he's also a friend
and great breeder but uh it's funny
because like his seeds go for $2500 on
the the secondary Market what yeah yeah
once once like a seed pack is found to
be like a fire pack and then there's no
more
crosses for a while were going crazy
before sense before SE junkie switched
over some of his old packs were going
crazy because people just the original
Rainbow belts once those sold out and it
kind of had its little moment those
packs went crazy yeah and R rainbow
bills is the one that does does it for
me really like it's all right it's like
it's cool love it it's the 20 The Arc or
Fletch so the ones I've had Mo in it
yeah it
Bas moo doy right Skittles Skittles
moono Skittles yeah moono Skittles yes
Skittles and it's cool it's it's go
moonbow is way better think so have you
tried the rainbow belts 20 I the 2.0 no
the 20 that's that's the that's the one
that Fletcher Used to breed with I'm not
sure no I think I've had the 2.0 so I've
had two rainbow belts fenos that were
crazy one was one that I found but it
was an awful plant it was so good yeah
but it was just I mean sometimes I
regret not keeping the plant just
because it tasted so incredible but
we're talking about it gave 25% of the
yield of the next lowest plant yeah you
know it was just kind of like what am I
going to do with it was incredible and
what do you do with something like that
I'll tell you you breed with it right
you breed with it so anything you got
something like that where it's special
where it's like those trips are amazing
you don't grow that like that's
something especially if it doesn't hm
out that's something you breed with
because those things just those those
are very rare right and even though it
doesn't yield a lot if it has that
amazing expression you can still turn
that into something down the road and so
a lot of times people like nope it
doesn't yield well it's like did you
smoke it and it was amazing maybe you
should have kept it for breeding you
know at least that's that's how I think
for sure if you find anyone who is
growing the rainbow belts 20 yeah uh I
love it it's not as uh I would say high
high note trebly as uh Skittles right
it's got like a skittles to me is just
like a sweet sweet violin it's a little
bit more FR Loops it's got some like
milk and cream in there and some funk
not as funky as the the moonbow we were
talking about and it's nice and potent
so if you can get your hands on some
rainbow belts 20 that is that's a very
very very good feno like I it's one of
my I think it's in my top five all time
wow wow I will never get rid of that cut
I love that cut nice yeah okay you need
to give me some
noted gotta awesome so if people are
looking to find out more about you guys
where can they go yeah so we have our
website uh it's
www.bcf.com that's controlled relase
fertilizer so beanock CRF you can go
check us out there um we are in the
middle of kind of redoing our socials
our Instagram is at beanock CRF do go
follow us there we are planning on
posting a lot more content we're also
dropping our own YouTube channel we're
going to start posting on Tik Tok we're
really just going to modernize a lot of
our our socials um and then I think
another good place is to also check out
Tom's YouTube channel he's going to be
doing a lot of use case stuff with
beanock actually showing you how he uses
it and for us we just think it's so
valuable to show people how it's being
used at scale um and for Tom to be
putting in all this work on the video
side I think that's GNA be it's gonna be
a really great resource for us as well
awesome for sure yeah yeah and uh yeah
for us uh our Instagram uh mother
Magnolia media you can find us there um
we've you know been posting there since
2016 soot history for us there terms of
our cultivars and images of what we're
growing uh the new YouTube channel
mother Magnolia cultivation you can find
us there um and then our website mother
magnolia.com so those now if you're
driving through Oregon and you're
looking to find your product working
they go so easiest spot again shout out
nectar um we were really early to the
party with nectar they had I think four
locations when we first started
delivering to them in
2016 and it's a quick uh short story
here that we had uh same breeder who did
the alpha blue yeah and who did that
sangria Kush had gotten us a cut that he
called sour lime mhm super triny
dominant cut it had the white in it it
was just a phenomenal
cultivar and he was getting rid of it
was like you know do what you can with
this um and so we ran
it and it was uh you know we sent it off
for testing definitely was exciting dur
during the first grow of the first table
of it and on uh Saturday at 7:00 my
phone rings and it's the director of the
lab that did the testing and he's like
yeah we got an issue with that that sour
line that we tested I was like [ __ ] what
happened did we fail for something like
dude I don't know how to tell you this
but uh it came back at 30% and at the
time 30% was like a unicorn now it's a
[ __ ] joke because testing has gotten
so perverted yeah ex but but at the time
they had they hadn't had like maybe they
had another 30% inflated yeah it there
was
it super rare it was an absolute Rarity
and so we had I had reached out to the
team at nectar and IID said because we
we had the super strong lime profile I
mean like like Sprite with a couple of
slices of lime in it bright that loud
yeah and I and I said hey guys would you
guys be interested in having exclusivity
on this lime that we're cutting instead
of calling it sour lime we'll call it
nectar lime and it'll be exclusive to
you guys and they said yes so I show up
with 30% lime that like smelled like
fresh lime and it like that cemented our
our position in you know center field
for them as as one of the producers that
was going to be stocking their shelves
nice and we haven't dropped a ball since
and we've been one of their you know
their main go-tos for that entire time
and so nectar is where you know every
every week we're at nectar on Tuesdays
and Fridays dropping you know product
off and they always have a really good
lineup they have good fresh product is
such a big challenge right so and here
here's here's one of the filters that
nectar that that nectar imposed and when
they first imposed this it was really
daunting and it was really an
intimidating filter that they put on it
but but once we sort of adapted to it it
made perfect sense the from the test
state for indoor flour they do not want
anything coming into their uh their
intake at their wholesale after 30 days
for for for uh from that test date right
and at first that just felt really
daunting but what they were ensuring was
that that top shelf flower that indoor
flower was going to actually be fresh
and really really high quality yeah it's
such a problem in the California Market
I think some of the because everything's
prepacked here right yeah and it's like
the stuff it's prepacked and the big
problem is is like you might get stuff
that's four or five months old you get
excited about a brand and you get some
good flour one time and the next time
you get it it's four or five months old
exactly so nectar's done a really good
job establishing that level of freshness
on the shelves aming um so you know
anytime anyone rolls through through
Oregon just there's 45 locations now wow
so nectar's in southern Oregon they're
in eastern Oregon they're in obviously
the majority of their dispensaries are
in Portland but uh they're all over the
state so any nectar dispensary that you
roll through in Oregon will have mother
Magnolia flour and our complete lineup
of pre-rolls so um by all means that's
that's that's the place to check it out
for sure awesome yeah one more thing
anyone who watches this podcast please
DM I'm the one who's on our Instagram so
just go ahead send me a DM say you watch
the podcast and you want to try out our
one pot packs we'll send them to you
guys on the house send you a couple of
them if you have a facility you want to
just try out a little bit please reach
out we are more than happy to send you
out a little bit of bean stock for and
all the trivia winners we do trivia we
do live chat trivia we'll be getting you
know the so so it's gonna be great so
yeah it's exciting awesome that's
awesome this is really uh this is great
this is really a lot of fun thank you so
much for having us James thank you guys
lot of fun
[Music]
he