[Music]
you
[Applause]
[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James loud
podcast and today our special guest is
uno uno that's right beum yeah totally
and he's an actor he's a comedian he's
an activist uh he is hilarious other
things he's a writer yeah uh he knows
Angela Baka my
editor actually he knows a lot of my
friends I've done editing for your
editor yeah that's awesome yeah I used
to run a magazine back in the day which
magazine West Coast cannabis magazine
that's awesome that was a great magazine
oh thank you so much thank you shout out
to haral Le who did all the layout har
did the layout of my book haral Le is a
beast she's a monster she's incredible
she's incredible and shout out to my boy
Mike uh who who was the salesman and
he's he's also a monster in a beast it
was just the three of us we ran that
magazine and it was great for like three
years I remember all the good magazines
there was so many good magazines over
the years that had small runs um you
know Redeye magazine yeah yeah yeah yeah
yeah uh you know there was uh
International canag graphic magazin you
know just to name a few you know
throwing some stuff out there some old
school old school awesome magazines
besides 2005 2006 around in there
because uh a lot of the weekly magazines
weren't taking can ads back then right
so there was a there was a there was
space and there space I talked Richard
Le to give me some money to start a
magazine well speaking of Richard Lee I
just did a Oaker Dam class today so I
was on I was on oer Dam I taught a
three-hour class on uh horiculture
nice they say you can take a horiculture
yeah that's true but I don't know the
rest of it I don't I know you can take a
horse to water as well you can totally
take a horse to water yeah yeah you can
take a horse to water a pencil must be
led all right right we'll keep moving on
go ahead what were you saying oh yeah so
I taught a class at oaksterdam today it
was a lot of fun on horiculture on
horiculture like feno hunting or just
you know me I like to go off topic so of
course we went into pheno hunting and
yeah I'm one of those guys I I enjoy
talking about what I enjoy talking about
the class was really amazing there was a
lot of people from an Indian Reservation
we had people from all over the Canary
Islands I believe colia wow you know
over 40 people in the class it was a lot
of fun I love Oaker Dam because it used
used to be a very in-person thing then
Co happened and now it's basically open
to everyone all over the world
internationally you know it's great
having people excited about cannabis all
over the world I love it I think we're
in this beautiful time in a lot of
places and I talked about my class today
it is a beautiful time you know I think
it's scary for some people some people
are very upset about the way things are
but it's always been that way so for
cannabis not as many people are going to
prison that's the important thing yeah
and I think uh we just got a whole bunch
of Pardons for cannabis prisoners yes
and that is freaking amazing I I just
the one thing that's happened in the
last year was that a lot of well just
just recently not in the last year in
the last week we have people getting out
of prison for cannabis crimes that they
never should have been put in prison no
one should ever go to jail for weed
anywhere in the world ever no ever yeah
ever ever ever ever I cannot stress this
enough I agree never ever ever weed is a
plant it's it's a plant it's it's a very
useful plant I'm I'm still of those old
school Jack ha hemp can save the planet
you know what I mean we all should be
taking advantage of this beautiful and
glorious plant which is does so much for
humans and uh you know not to get all
woo woo about it but for real no but
cannabis can make the world a better
place and it's for me it's impossible to
argue it has it has it has every day it
has in my life in your life and so many
other people around us right it's made
their world a better place and I think
it has the it has the you know the power
to change people's minds right uh which
is one of the reasons they try to keep
it illegal because you get stoned you
start noticing yeah and then you're
like we got to change it something's
wrong here something's wrong something's
terribly horribly wrong yeah I mean I
think cannabis Tunes you in alcohol
Tunes you out that's why I like cannabis
better than alcohol even though I don't
mind alcohol whatever I J got a full bar
over there I noticed some nice Tequilas
actually we have some great Tequilas we
got some great whiskies we got uh we got
some Venom over there that's got a CO
Cobra and a scorpion in it yeah of
course you know why wouldn't you yeah
totally you know it's the James L
podcast we got to have something for
everybody have something for everybody
you never know the mariachi band might
show up you never know if you would have
ordered it we would have got it oh man
I'll keep that in mind for the next one
Absolutely I'll have a list yeah I mean
I think we're going to do a cooking show
later on this year do a cooking show
yeah we are what's your go-to okay
you're invited to the potluck you're
bringing something maybe you don't want
to spend a million days doing it but you
want to bring something that showcases
your ability listen my family we are all
good Cooks like you go to the family
reunion they will put your name on the
dish that you brought yeah right for
accountability so they can't be like who
made the potato salad you know damn well
that Aisha made the potato salad you
know what I mean totally don't eat that
one or the opposite we're going to eat
it she makes a great potato salad and a
really good like they we could all cook
so nobody's afraid to accountability you
can't say no I didn't make that yeah
there's a little uh a little pressure
well so I I mean I'm French trained I
have I have a background in culinary
arts I went I have a bachelor's degree
in culinary arts or Associates sorry
Associates close enough um and when it
comes to food I like making everything
you I do Fu Pebble Treats is one of my
desserts so you bring a fuy pebble Smash
Burgers you bring Smash Burgers I bring
pizza and I make pizzas to order you
know what I mean I do I show with your
my pizza oven yeah I have a pizza oven
we can take it I got a rock Box I will
come over with a Pizza
Oven I make the I make the D I'm
inviting you to all my potlucks now yeah
I mean I I go above and beyond I love
Smash Burgers I love perfecting things
but I also like uh I would just fry some
chicken you're out here
like chicken I made Korean fried chicken
yesterday Koreans learned that from the
from the black people yeah during the
Korean War it wasn't the colonel I swear
no it was the colonel have maybe you
know Colonel Jenkins who's a black guy
station in Korea during the war colel
Sanders the real yeah absolutely not C
Sanders but I love fried chicken too
that's one of my favorite things I love
extra crispy fried chicken now do you br
your chicken I do not mil you that's a
great way to do it though um you know I
think that like yesterday basically I
did I used cornstarch egg cornstarch egg
corn starch and then I fried it like
that and so basically you do twice fried
so you fry it once you get a little
crispy and then right before you eat it
you throw it in again to crisp it up o
and it's extra crispy and you can do
them strips you could do breast strips
if you want to go a little healthier or
you can do chicken I love chicken wings
chicken wings man I I'll eat chicken
wings 18 million different ways but I'm
I'm going to maybe start an argument
yeah I'm not always a fan of a brine
because I think it makes everything too
salty yeah and I feel like we overs salt
everything and I don't want I don't
always want like salt to be the first
flavor or the overwhelming flavor Sal
Salt's like a spice I like a little salt
on the skin and you get a little
saltiness but then the chicken starts to
chicken it up you know mean so I was at
shap penes for nine months a long long
time 20 years ago that's a still so so
what 20 years ago and so I was it shap
penes 20 years ago all right I was on
evening at The Improv in 1993 whatever
let just talk about it all right go
ahead shap shapes and so this is very
very important to our conversation
because I learned at sha penice that you
use things like salt yeah you use things
like sauces to elevate the raw
ingredients right and that's how it
should be that's how it should
so salt and sugar forward in a lot of
American Cuisine these days well and the
fat and the Umami they want this you
know have a lot of fat I like fat I'm
there's nothing wrong with little some
butter I don't care I love butter I love
do you love it deep fried that's the
important thing I love everything I'm
not picky when it comes I mean I'm picky
with quality but I'm not picky about
different things because I feel like
there's so many different ways to
prepare stuff to make butter yeah yeah
well you were talking about oxtail
earlier I love oxtail I think that if
you don't like oxtail but you like braz
meat you probably haven't had good
oxtail had the good oxtail I mean I used
to have how can you not like you like
how do you like a braz meat and not like
an oxtail I think some people don't like
the name oxtail well listen hey uh poor
people have always made the best food
yeah and it's a damn shame that the rich
people have discovered the tail of the
cow because now it's $12 a pound or
whatever when it used to be the cheap
cut of meat and so you had to learn how
to do something with it I mean tritip
was like that back in the day there's so
many different cuts of meat that were
really cheap and then people figured it
out it's like Terrace major is a new one
that's the petite fet right and so now
they're calling it petite fet just keep
calling it Terrace major yeah you know
do that there's so many different cuts
right that that were like the butcher
steak right that they call The Butcher
steak because the butcher they couldn't
sell it so The Butchers would keep it
learn how to do something with it yeah
yeah yeah yeah that's how it always goes
exactly right yeah if I got some chicken
bones and you got an onion we're going
to make soup yeah as a team that's
that's the way to do it Stone Soup is a
classic stone soup that was one of my uh
favorite books as a kid right it's a
great book great book it's a great book
I've always been a fan of that
Philosophy for sure yeah yeah yeah yeah
yeah I think we got off topic where were
we we totally got off topic so tell me
about yourself uh uh I'm 6' 3 inches
tall I'm an aquarius born year the
monkey you're the monkey yeah yeah I'm
yeah Dragon oh nice dragons and monkeys
get along
totally feary 16th hey I'm February 15th
happy birthday happy birthday happy
birthday bro I'll see you in Vegas yeah
it's that's right around Champs I think
the funniest thing is I get along really
good with people that were born around
my birthday I don't know us aquariuses
get along with other aquariuses that are
born around that same generally yes
platonically we can't always date but
platonically it'll be fine they're good
people right listen only one of us can
be unemotional and flighty
right
exactly but yeah I mean uh you do comedy
love your comedy yeah you know and then
we were we were 420 together um I mean
I've known long in San Francisco we were
at 420 together last year 2024 you were
the MC for the event I was um I was
there it was actually a really sad day
my friend Dave passed away we talked
about on the podcast he he passed away
that morning oh and you know it but it
was such a beautiful day so to celebrate
did Dave like weed celebrate he he loved
weed so there you go Dave got me
breeding for a effect I've breing for
flavor being a chef you know you can't
can't blame someone for bre I me flavor
and effect they kind of go hand in hand
and you think about different Tarpin
have different effects and the different
smell will give you different things
absolutely but I think there needs to be
more of a focus back on effect for
everybody how does it make you feel
forget about the flavor stuff and and
let's let's go down to the root like
does it make you feel amazing because
all these different cultivars all these
different cultivars that we have they
give you a different effect each one of
them slightly different right yeah uh
not that no two are exactly the same cuz
there a lot of them are similar but but
there's some that are special that make
you feel a certain way and our body
chemistry is so unique that what works
for me may not work for you or the next
tell people that all the time it's
always different you got to find a butt
tender who smokes like you smoke yeah
right or you just got to try a bunch of
weed right you got to smoke a that's how
you learn what you like is by trying
everything yeah and then you go back to
the stuff you really like I got I have
friends who keep notebooks they like
they take detailed notes have notbook
you can go to I think there's an app for
that now was it the Buddhist app or
buest yeah I should actually take more
advantage of that I think it's important
but you know sometimes I'm just St I
don't want to write down I'm just
like oh that was good weed don't for
remember that one well you know it's the
jar test right which jar if you have a
bunch of jars which one do you go back
to that's that doesn't have a lot left
exactly that's usually the one the one
that makes you feel a certain way the
one that tastes the best I like Skittles
for the flavor but also when it's grown
in soil I love the way it makes me feel
yeah right and you know white Thorn Rose
is another one it's a really good is
that what's right oh yeah so Johnny big
shout out to shout out what do
Huckleberry Hill Farm man let's go
that's one of the few weeds I actually
buy I don't really buy weed I agree I
will I will SP I love the I spend money
on it it's pretty much the only gummy I
buy Rosen gummies with with white Thorn
Rose I love white Thorn Rose and it
makes you feel the effects the flavor
the the vibe it's just it's just super
nice this um I also like a really uh
which I haven't seen in a minute I don't
know if he's still growing it but
chocolate hashberry um sticky Fields was
growing that out there and mindo I
haven't seen that one in a long time
chocolate haven't seen it in like five
six years uh if anybody's got any
chocolate hashberry call me up I'll I'll
come over the shishkaberry I haven't
seen that one in a long time last time
you saw when was the last time you saw
champagne so I mean Pink Champagne yes
but the old schoolis champ right San
Francisco I grew up in San Francisco so
yeah ciss and champagne those were the
90s
big shout out but smell this so this is
my new white Thorn this is
EDP it's special we're gonna smoke some
I can't it's way more on the peach side
so it's but you smoke it and it's
straight floral down to the roach it
tastes floral and it I feel like it
gives you a similar effect there's Blue
13 from Dave who passed away that's uh
the blueberry Haze time Kevin jre's
Louis the 13th okay there's the
Huckleberry Hill white Thorn which I
don't even know the genetics on that I
just assumed it was some sort of
forbidden fruit variation not sure but
it's special I I don't even try to ask
cuz I'm they just stare at me gifting
this to Johnny I'm not sharing it with
anybody else we're going to grow it here
in house right not in house here but
with our cultivation Partners yeah the
only people that are going to have is my
cultivation Partners in the city which
SF can right and then Johnny What's this
called again zdp zdp you down with zdp
I'm for sure 100% everybody that's tried
this really enjoys the effect uh we got
a bubbler here for that's perfect I love
a bubbler so this is a chg a kind of guy
that's my uh favorite bubbler it has a
bunch of little Millies that have
Grateful Dead uh oh yeah Grateful Dead
uh amazing little Muses in yeah we got
mushrooms we got uh there's all kind of
things there's a dancing
bear steal your face steal your face
right off of your head like I told you
what I said yeah good stuff so I take
you're from this the city
and you love Grateful Dead too I take it
yeah yeah I mean how can you not love
grateful how can you not love the
Grateful Dead they uh they they speak to
me I if you've ever done psychedelics
and smoked a bunch of weed how can you
not like the Grateful Dead it's my they
can get a little noodly sometimes but I
I like a noodle so it's not it's not a
problem for me I love the
noodling I love the pizza tapes so oh
wow you're deep into it talk about you
know noodling and it's like uh I love
the old Jerry stuff uh I like early
you know 70s I actually have a hard
drive right over here with every
recording of the Grateful Dead there's a
bunch of dat stuff I feel from like
maybe
1975 yeah maybe
1978 they may have been the best band in
the world at that time yeah now from say
to
93 fishbone was the best band in the
world I like fishbone too most people
don't even know about fishbone how can
you not know about fishbone if you like
the you should like fishbone because
they get down but they they get down
into very American groovy everybody's
locked in we're creating a higher
Consciousness sort of way absolutely at
least when they were at their Peak yeah
for sure yeah well in 80s was kind of
rough with music to be honest I think
there was a lot of electronic stuff
coming in that maybe doesn't appeal to
people today but there was still some
good stuff there some I mean listen
there was all that punk rock we're were
leaning into the industrial uh house was
kind of just getting getting creative
right after the Donna everything and
then people starting to figure it out in
Detroit and all that stuff oh yeah San
Francisco there a lot of early days of
San Francisco house early
90s then house yeah blew up I mean being
from San Francisco if you didn't go to
raves in the 90s you really missed out
on some amazing that was like disco
right once it's gone it's gone it was
never Raves are kind of they're kind of
an offshoot of the Disco more you know
crazier for sure that's awesome but yeah
City DJ too do you do everything
weed I DJ no I I was never a DJ chicken
oh you play guitar I play guitar of
course absolutely I play guitar yeah
well we should have brought our
instruments next time I'll bring a kunga
drum and we'll just sit here and hippie
out for three hours we get a Dr yeah we
get a little drum circle going next time
we're eating mushrooms we're getting a
drum circle going 100% Fire on the
Mountain that's what's up fire all right
so what do you think about I think it's
very tasty and clearly it makes me
chatty yeah I like I like the effects of
it I feel like it's a good hybrid it's
uplift just starting to kick in I feel
the uplift for sure you feel a little
behind the eyes a little bit U the
flavor is really really nice like you
said floral notes I get a lot more Peach
than just like straight tropical fruit
but that could just be me that be the
vibe that I'm on right now call it Peach
Thorn Rose nice nice but yeah I'm gonna
I'm gonna see Johnny next week and we're
going to talk about it I just I feel
like uh yeah it's it's got a special
look to it it's kind of like Skittles in
the sense that it's not super beautiful
as far as the structure but I think the
effect way
outweighs the the bag appeal it looks
and you know listen we it's so hard now
that they don't serve deli style right
first of all the worst first of all you
know you're it's sitting in myar the the
conditions are hot it's cold it's this
it's that it's not moving it's not
always maintaining the Tarpin like you
like and it takes 3 months to get the
approve so you know it starts to degrade
after a while you have to trust the
company you have to trust the grower now
you can't you know what I mean smell
smell the bag or at least look at it and
be like oh yeah okay yeah that's the
worst part about such a big recreational
Cannabis is the that we lost the deli
style where you can't actually so that
is some old school Funk right there I
smell a
little I definitely smell the funk and
like some
skunky uh oh yeah it's so that's the C
diesle what was it before run it was
just skunk it was just OG right so this
is very much an old school OG it grows
like a sativa though so it's it's got
that morphology where it's like really
bad node spacing thinner leaves taller
plants but it has that classic OG
structure and it has that really classic
nose burning OG gas but I'm also
smelling a little uh like a little
creaminess almost like a old school
Northern Lights or something like that
in there vanilla Luna remember that mhm
well this is just an old school cut from
Florida called the crippy the crippy the
crippy Florida crippy was that be late
90s early 2000s yeah yeah yeah maybe
even a little bit before then I mean I I
just we got the cut
recently um in the last couple years and
I've been sticky it's super like this
it's sticky like to where you can stick
that bud to the microphone stand and
it'll stay there like literally if you
thumb it over there you thumb it I don't
want ruin this Bud oh you can thumb
it I'm telling you when was the last
time you thumbed the bud to something
and it's stuck you know I
mean I love
that surface tension let's hear it for
adhesion adhesion not related to Ed
Rosenthal edhan yeah no yeah that's a
whole different that's a whole different
conversation right but yeah and this
stuff is super strong what's it called
again crippy crippy just straight old
school crippy stuff it's just old school
crippy I think old school is making a
comeback Sour Diesel OG Co Let's Go Blue
Dream all these things are going to be
making it come back here's the thing
about blue dream blue dream will never
at least to me Blue Dream will never go
away because what happens is it won't
you smoke a lot of Blue Dream and you're
like man I got to give other weeds a
chance yeah lay off of it or maybe you
found a blue dream that wasn't great
you're like ah I need a blue dream
tolerance break or whatever then you
smoke a really good one again you're
like God that's my why did I never
stop it's so good for a variety you can
watch a movie you can do stuff you can
hang out you can clean you could do
stuff or not do stuff right Blue Dream
is so well balanced it's so well
balanced it's such an interesting
variety green crack on the I like green
crack too don't get me wrong but Green
Crack you bu I hate the name too always
hat it's the worst name it's not a great
no and the thing is is the reason it's
called Green Crack is because you smoke
it and it gets you so high but you build
a tolerance to it right away so like
within a week it doesn't get you high
anymore it's like crack like
literally I would smoke it and then
I didn't realize that was the origin of
the name and and the thing is is like if
I only I did this one time where I only
grew green crack and so after a week my
literally a green crackhead yeah and it
was like so I'd give my friends over
smoking they'd be like oh this is so
strong and I'd smoke big joints with
them and I wouldn't be phased and they
would be completely out I had a friend
we were at uh this is
2012 at the parade for the Giants in San
Francisco and I brought big joints of
Green Crack to smoke with everybody and
I passed one of my friend Joe and we
were out in front of the library onean
crowd control committee oh yeah we were
in front of the library in San Francisco
and he took a couple hits from it and
had to actually sit down on the ground
he was so high I'm like what are you
doing dude like we just took a couple
hits and he's like this is the strongest
weed I smoke yeah you have to be
careful you have to be careful with the
amateur sometimes I've definitely killed
a party or two with a regular size joint
but you know what are you going to do
and he wasn't even an amateur it's just
different than what he's used to
smoke so yeah I was in New York
just before New Year's and we went to a
couple spots and a friend of mine knew
this
uh gray area half legal spot you know
what I mean right they'd been around for
a while was a smoking lounge and a
little little weed room but you couldn't
tell you had to you know walk up the
steps you didn't know what you're
looking for or whatever totally no sign
no sign there's no sign I I couldn't
even tell you where it was I was just
kind of following them around and then I
was like oh we're here and then on the
way back I was trying to okay don't
forget where you were and I was like I'm
too high to try to remember
what's going on that's a great way to
lose your car too oh man I've wandered
neighborhoods because I get sometimes I
have a rental car so I forget what it is
or what it looks like and then yeah got
stoned at the park or whatever and
walking three miles in the wrong
direction this is uh I haven't even
opened this yet somebody gave it to me
oh nice uh we were talking about strains
making a comeback Super Silver Haze dude
I have super silver haze in the house I
love it's coming back it's coming back
silver um in Spain they grow so many
hazes like they have the Amnesia the
super silver they love a haze and I
think it's a patience thing it is right
commercial Growers don't always have the
patience to go 12 weeks 14 flowering
varieties I love them and you know small
batch long flowering it's 0 for two good
one Aran from Greenhouse came to uh turp
Nami in San Francisco David Downs event
who was amazing this year by the way and
davs out big we got to love yeah I love
hash week IED I Love Weed week I love
hash I love TP Nami David DS is killing
it right watch out 2025 he's going to
drop it even harder this year him Jimmy
Divine they're doing great events right
now great events and I love these
Boutique fueling events where they put
so much energy and love into them and
it's not about the money it's about a
good shout out to the small scale event
producers who love good cannabis shout
out Tony B shout out uh my boy Nathan
who does the Missouri Growers Cup and
the Oregon grow Cup and the Arizona
Growers cup uh andest shout out canest
shout out my home girl Sage who does all
kind of weed events on the river was a
comeback this year I can't wait till
come this year we I was with an amazing
group of people big up the international
cannabis business conference here is
Berlin and Barcelona this year shout out
Al spab see you there see you at
spannabis spannabis if you like genetics
if you like seeds spannabis is really
like if that if you could only go to one
conference or one F but should be spab I
heard Mary Jane was better than spy is
great last year I think I went two years
ago because you know it depends on when
the international cannabis business
conference is so if I'm in Berlin while
it's happening I can get to go but I I
can't always afford to stick around two
extra weeks it's sealed it's sealed so I
can't open it but I'm ex I'll open it
for you yep it's like I said it's it's
fresh so circling back to hazes AR Aran
came here he was at tpami and he's
shaking his head and I'm like what's
wrong and he's like I'm just blown away
by all these hazes what's going on here
all these guys coming down from the
hills got haze there was more Haze at TP
namami than I've ever seen at any
American event no there was more
hazes than they have at spannabis and
there was different style hazes from all
over there was really terpinolene
dominant hazes where that terpinolene
limine tpine classic tpine is becoming
very popular yeah that the terpinolene
is very popular but we had all kinds of
stuff there was like some Durbin there
was some red Congo which is like one my
favorites my all get your heart racing
you have to be careful it'll kick you
it'll kick you in the chest I got a
years
ago a friend of mine had crossed like a
land race Tai sativa yeah with I can't
remember it was like a Durban it was a
Durban and uh sounds like a heart racer
well here's the thing it was really
tasty weed but I definitely had to learn
to use it for use its powers for good
right but people would come over right I
had a jar and they'd smell it and be
like let's smoke that one I'll be like
well here's the thing you came over to
hang out we're going to smoke this and
then 20 minutes after we smoke it you're
going to get up and go do stuff yeah
like no man I got time I got an hour and
a half I just came to kick it I was like
all right and then we smoked the joint
and then 20 minutes later like oh man I
was supposed to go to the mail the post
office I got to go pay this
bill my bathroom's a mess and they just
get up and run out just go start doing
I was like yeah man little anxiety
get you going yeah yeah yeah yeah it's
not being but it wasn't I I found it at
least that one wasn't not like some some
of them you get that anxiety like well
if I don't do something I'm going to
have a heart attack yeah but this was
just more like a motivator like I really
Malawi was kind of like for me things I
get the heart palpitations a little bit
from Malawi I love maloi I get Mala
ttimes Hawkin right now oh that is
that's so International it is so it's so
good I love that's like salsa music yeah
I mean I like my varieties but that is
my like go-to when I want to get lift I
want to get lifted I want to be focused
lifted
I'm drinking this uh this new coffee
it's a mushroom coffee called rise so is
it coffee with mushrooms in it or is it
just all mushroom coffee it has a rabika
coffee in it and it's amazing and it
makes me super focused before I taught
my class today I drank some of that and
I felt fantastic so it's like a lion's
mane and coffee it has like five
different mushrooms five different
mushrooms and then it it definitely
makes you more focused without giving
you that heavy caffeine buzz and I like
caffeine by itself but man I think
caffeine with mushrooms is this key it's
not psychedelic mushrooms but it's just
it's the good stuff it's the momy it's
the vitamin D yeah right mushrooms are
heavy in that it's it's all those kind
of things I love mushrooms I love all
mushrooms yeah there's not a bad
mushroom out there well some will kill
you well so those kind of mushrooms I
don't like but the other I'm sure
they're beneficial for the planet and
the environment and other different ways
but maybe you shouldn't kill it or eat
it maybe there's some you definitely
shouldn't eat more than more than a few
you shouldn't eat your mushrooms before
you get into them I also do like mus
love all the mushrooms that you can eat
that I've eaten i' I love all you never
had a bad mushroom you never ate one
mushroom and went like you know I think
so so I talk about it on the show a
little bit I do like golden teachers for
the fact that they're not super
introspective sometimes I like the
introspective right but sometimes I like
just feeling good and laughing with my
friends nothing wrong with that and the
thing with golden teachers is you can
eat so many of them and still have an
amazing trip whereas like you go penis
envy you eat too much of those and
you're not coming back for a while and
you're not wanting to eat mushrooms for
a while right can I brow your scissors
absolutely oh we had scissors here the
right the whole time I was like I got to
ask somebody for scissors and then you
know you look around become a I can't
open this I don't have scissors and I
did have scissors and you did have
scissors that's why we're a team you
brought the scissors and I noticed them
I'm going to try to make this as like
it's like ASMR right now
right oh
yeah so it's not annoying if it's
intentional exactly yeah so I mean I
think there's something for everybody
with cannabis and with mushrooms and our
body chemistries are so uniquely
different that with with these mushrooms
it's like some people I the new blue
Magnolias those are amazing I haven't
tried I got to be honest I haven't done
mushrooms in about a year I even know I
don't even know all the all the hip new
it's so funny that there's like mushroom
heads now like mushroom Chronos like oh
yeah bro I like to combine a golden
teacher with a I like 10 10% I micro do
three days a week and then I macro do
every other week I put cactus in there a
couple days and I mean this it's wild
I'm make an aloe vera dark chocolate
mushroom smoothie and it really really
cleans me out spiritually and physically
well I mean the spectrum of psychedelics
is so broad now when we were kids it was
like oh you want to eat some mushrooms
or take some acid right that was it that
was that was it there was go to San
Francisco you can go to Golden Gate Park
pick up some acid you know but but now
it's like oh what do you want to try you
want to cros this this this this or this
or 10 other things I mean and it's nice
to have a choice it's nice to that you
can be aware because convenience but it
can complicate things and paralysis of
options but it's also nice to be like
yeah I'm going to go uh to a concert and
I want to do some dancing so I'll take
some golden teachers right where it's
not you know it's not a little crazy
exactly I'm not going to sit there in
the corner thinking about choices that I
made missing my friends laughing and
crying you're not rethinking your life
ining which is's nothing wrong with that
no's time and a place for that for sure
yeah and maybe you know the giant Rave
with 15 of your friends who don't want
to babysit your high ass totally is not
the time not the time for that I mean I
go on road trips sometimes where I take
a big dab before I go and I start
rethinking my life on the way there you
know I I may or may not have had an
existential moment on a Greyhound bus in
the middle of the night because the
cookie was way too strong for me and I'm
just sitting there thinking about all
these things and you're on a Greyhound
so you can't really turn to the stranger
or the bus driver be like hey man I'm
really high right now you slow down can
we can we just stop for a minute can we
get snacks I need black pepper I can use
some sugar right
right like I said I just opened it uh I
think it may have been sitting around
for a while but based on the color yeah
I ain't gonna lie it was in the sun I do
I smell some ammonia I had a different
right I had a different Super Silver
Haze but I smoked it before I could
bring it over and it was really super
silver hazy I'm just glad it's making a
comeback I thought that one might be
exciting but I'm sorry that it's not
that's all right so I hope we can still
be friends I other things in my bag
though don't don't get it twisted nice I
do too yeah let's look at it yeah so in
fact I feel like all that buildup we had
to borrow scissors we had to cut the
thing open five different times I'm
still gonna we're gonna smell this one
first we're gonna do a blind tasting
with you
today like black
pepper that beta
caropine definitely
definitely I can't really smell oine but
I feel like it would be in there
somewhere yeah this is grown in a
specific substrate and then this one is
grown in a different substrate all same
strain same exact coltivar from the same
exact mom grown side by side with the
one in this jar with a different
substrate do I get to know the stra at
first or I just have to guess no we're
going to smoke these and you're going to
know the strain you're be like yeah I
know am I okay finger
cross is it Bubba cush no you know I
really love Bubba cush I don't 398 bubba
baby bring it back let's go I don't even
know where to find it but I wish I did
because I may yeah and I cannot I will
look there may be some seeds in my
refrigerator nice uh but I cannot vouch
for anybody's viability or whatever but
if I have some I'll break some off and
let me know yeah and we're you know with
the seeds it's going to be a different
genotype so I really miss that pre98
Bubba
yeah you know phenotype genotype it's
going to be different it'll be slightly
different expression 398 Bubba yeah 398
Bubba I love old school pre98 soapy
bubble where you smoke it and it's like
soapy and gassy and it just coats your
mouth that's headband coming back uh I
believe it's coming back Crockett gave
the 707 Headband cut to conception and
they're going to be selling clones of it
so we're going to be seeing headband
really soon if you like that 707 now
there's so many different types of
headband
um out there some sort of gas no think
candy try the other ones and then then
you can make your decision it's not it's
not a gelato no no it's not a gelato oh
it's this it's the genetic that I talk
about the most on my show probably I got
this infatuation with this candy
variety and all our Watchers know
exactly what I'm talking good for them
well whatever it is it's tasty as
yeah man I can't
I'm sure what you say I be like oh
duh oh yeah we're gonna go
through all three of the jars and maybe
by the end you'll be like oh yeah I know
that or maybe I don't it is fruity it's
not a cherry cherry pie or a cherry cush
because there's too much gas involved
it's not the Gorilla Glue because it's
not spicy you
heard huh TGs what about you know that
name uh D they're famous for how about
third gen you know what they're famous
for I don't know what they're famous for
I'm sorry I should really pay more to
Old School you that's a good thing I
should pay more attention to weed gossip
but also it's kind of funny I'm not
really here to argue about who had and I
get it like dog it's your legacy like if
you worked for generations and years to
perfect this one strain and everybody
wants to get it and everybody says they
had it everybody says they started first
of course of course you're G to get
fired up about it sometimes to me and
this is just My Little Hippie ass
showing uh cannabis like juggling is
open source yeah right of course
somebody's going to have it somebody's
going to you know there could be
parallel Evolutions or somebody you
never know how these things come about
and and I love them all and I'm a fan of
all the Styles but it's tough it's tough
to be proprietary and and and and I feel
like the Cannabis plan itself does not
like uh people who are too
proprietary yeah about it you know what
I mean I think right that's how you end
up with the Cavendish banana
which is going to be pretty soon the
only one we're really growing in any and
I believe in Sharing but I also believe
in being a steward of the plant and
giving it to the right people and not to
the wrong people right so like there
there's there's so many different
options these days and you can give it
to the wrong person believe me genetics
can go in the get in the wrong hands
unfortunately but I also believe that
sharing is caring and sharing good
genetics though everybody deserves
access to Quality flour right and
quality genetics that goes yeah I sell
seeds we sell we we have different price
seeds for everybody but we have
something for everybody at every price
point um you know and we're about to
start selling clones online it's going
to be a beautiful thing this one's a
more of a darker yeah right you know
what I mean like a a skunky gassier sort
of flavor and this one flavor are kind
of the same
soil that one of one of them soil I
believe it's one actually are you sure
there's no diesel in here because it's
got that diesel mouth feel where you
know what I mean where you're a little
coated it's candy
it's
candy which candy is
it you're going to tell me you're
going to tell me I'm just GNA be
like be easier if you smoked in a joint
because down to the roach you tastes
like candy you exhale you get candy this
not a strawberry no it's a starts with
z gitt yes and ends with
z gitt
I but it doesn't
it's yes of course now it makes perfect
sense yeah yeah I always think of
Skittles as a little more runy you know
I mean a little more deep skunk in it
some well and the beauty of Skittles is
you can Harvest on day 51 to day 53 and
you get one expression you harvest on
day 63 you get another expression I
think this was probably harvested
somewhere in the middle of that like day
56 okay so you get a little bit of that
gas turn to the side that's
burn a little bit gas coating mouth
Coating in this one yeah I mean I like
them both I can't really pick one well I
think there's one more that's
in is it that door number two yes this
is door number
three yeah but you're not going to be as
excited about this one I'm not going to
be as excited it's all right it's just
all right it's another one but and it
smells good they smell good they smell
Skitty it smells fine it's got all that
pepper pepper and fruit yeah well and
when you harvest Skittle at the right
time when you harvest that cultivar you
get a lot of melon so you get this
cantaloupe nose that I love I love you
call me cantaloupe Oh I thought you
called me cantaloupe nose I thought we
were GNA have a problem no nobody knows
cantaloupe like cantaloupe no the
cantaloupe nose knows cantaloupe nose it
does right and I love good cantaloupe
you can't go wrong with cantaloupe
cantaloupe is one the best that melon
you know same thing honey like R this
one smells good too I don't know why you
well the effect you know so one of
them's grown in Cocoa one of them's
grown in soil and another when grown is
living
soil so
yeah but like I said we're always a test
and everything so we try stuff some
stuff works some stuff doesn't work uh
life is an adventure so we're always
looking for that new adventure life is
an
adventure or it is nothing at all yeah
so you do you do standup comedy I do
stand up comedy I'll be at the Crest
Theater in Sacramento this Saturday
tickets are actually free because it was
a last minute show my boy called me up
it was like hey we had an emergency
Fallout come and do a show and I was
like all right I love stand up comedy
there's so many good comedians you know
there are just so many great comedi
Craig Conan is uh one of my new
favorites I worked with him at the crest
last year no way yeah I would love to
get him on my show someday he's like it
was me him and Steph toi dude the
amazing comedian he's going on tour
right now I think he'll he'll be in La
February 20th he'll be in San Jose man
you're a fan I am yeah you're like a fan
fan you know the T where's your T-shirt
you don't have a Craig C tshirt have a
tattoo actually
right that's I have his picture on the
mirror in my bathroom I say good morning
to him every day yeah I no I mean he's
he's big into psychedelics I love his
psychedelic jokes because they resonate
with people that do psychedelics so fair
enough if you smoke weed or you do
psychedelics you can relate you're the
target audience yeah my target audience
yeah my demographic is uh 40 to 55y old
males that smoke weed and do
psychedelics that's yours that's yours
mine is uh smart people who smoke weed
and get laid nice yeah yeah yeah well
whatever works for
you yeah I mean there's some overlap
there's clearly some overlap in our
demographics totally and I would love to
do standup comedy someday I just I just
I'd love watching standup comedy and I
think it's so amazing when you see these
comedians they can tell a story and then
Circle back at the end yeah and wrap it
all up nice and close it out and it's
like wow these guys are amazing um takes
years it takes years Tak years just like
everything else like learning to make a
sule yeah well you can you can learn a
sule pretty quick but yeah to get it
super right to get it superr just
cooking in any sort of skill set like
that it takes time doing podcasts I feel
like my podcast how you been doing it
now since Co all right so yeah and I did
4 two episodes on the Cannabis future
project uh yeah cannabis whatever
Canabis yeah future cannabis project so
I did 42 episodes future cannabis
project and we're on episode 90
something right now so I've done over
100 episodes I feel so much more
confident doing podcast now I love doing
podcast of course and I what I realized
is podcasts are all about the guest it's
not about the host it's how can you get
I don't know you talk a lot no I'm
kidding I'm kidding I do no I I I do
talk a lot love talking and I love
elevating my guest though I feel like
it's all about highlighting your guest
what they do I'm definitely elevated I
feel like and it's probably a cumul
cumulative effect yeah but um that third
one seemed to kick everything else into
overdrive it does right right so I don't
know if you lined it up like that
specifically yeah but uh we put DMT in
the last one I'm joking I'm totally
joking that would be funny if we did but
we would never do that DM Isle hilarious
yeah it would be until you started
seeing little elves don't secretly dose
your friends I might have a funeral to
go to later dude I got to go to court
this is not the time this is not the
time for this trying to be Court yes
you're honor elf sir yeah seriously yeah
yeah but yeah I mean so cannabis
cannabis cannabis it's just an amazing
thing and we're in amazing time with
legalization with all these other states
going online and other countries and
other countries countries Germany I'm
going to be in Germany for the
international cannabis business
conference late April like April April
it's around 27th through the 29th yeah
yeah yeah I'm actually I got to come
back to the States I'm going do some 420
out here and then I'm going to go back
because I'm going to Barcelona and I got
to come back I'll be in La for 420 we're
doing a big seed drop with the Cannabis
Brothers oh yeah they've basically
phenoh hunted some of my genetics we uh
forming the big
Voltron do this little limited release a
SE drop like
first I imagine you guys just you know
in a helicopter just dropping seeds drop
seeds not bombs absolutely pass joints
not judgment yeah but uh but then I
realized it's like a shoe drop or
whatever selling the seats we are
selling it's not the WKRP turkey drop no
it is not no by winess I thought weed
seeds could fly we're sharing the seeds
with the world and you know I do my
share of giving back oh no I I wasn't uh
I wasn't casting aspersions I was just
high and visualizing you weren't
gaslighting taking literally as
Stoners do that's one of those things
like when you're entertaining a room
full of Stoners cuz you know I've done
dispensaries and all the time it
can be kind of challenging because they
will take everything literally like if a
comic goes yeah me and my girlfriend
just broke up they're oh man is that all
right you're like no we break up every
time I do this bit yeah right this yeah
we've been broken up for years but this
bit is still good so don't worry right
you know but it's it's it's just one of
those things but yeah uh I forgot what I
was talking about you were talking about
I was talking about cannabis and and
Germany and you're doing a seed drop oh
yeah yeah well I want to talk about you
and how you got involved with cannabis
where did you get your start I started
smoking it when you're were eight no no
uh I tried one time when I was 12 but my
parents caught me and they well that's
not true once when I was like 11 uh the
counselors at the summer camp let me
hang out and smoke a joint with them one
time yeah but then not again till like I
think it was fifth or sixth grade and
then me and Alex stter no it might have
been eighth grade was eighth grade me
and Alex stter used to smoke weed and
then one time my mom called us and uh so
she gave me a lecture and then she
called my dad which this I knew it was
serious because my mom and my dad didn't
really get along so if she called my dad
about something yeah it was real and my
dad who was a big pops smoker was like
you just got to wait till College bro
you're you're not ready just don't yeah
you know what I mean don't uh don't get
into it like that your your brain is
still forming you got you got
responsibilities so then as soon as I
got to college I like yeah I'll
try it so you did listen yeah smart guy
my kids are the same way I've been on
them since they were like five no drugs
till college no drugs till college now
they're adults and they're doing fine
and they they like to smoke a little
weed yeah every once in a while they
smoke we their dad my son's always like
dog you and your friends smoke weed like
I just wanted a h you guys get high like
yeah to it's a culture it's a lifestyle
you know I was on a cooking show yeah
um but uh yeah so that's how it started
so I just started smoking weed in
college I was like I really like this
weed and I come from a long line of
activists so then I started like you
know looking into it and and reading
about activism of it and the history and
then Jack Harris's book came out a
little around there in the 90s I and I
met um Debbie Goldsberry and Don from
the Cannabis Action Network from back in
the day and I was like yeah man I'm I'm
here for this whole thing cuz to me
canus legalization does a lot of things
right it it helps cops be less racist
because they can't just pull you over
for weed yeah uh or they can't use it as
a pretex to pull you over for weed it
keeps people out of jail they search
your car CU it smells like weedar man
that's one of my favorite things listen
yeah cuz I always smell like weed uh
always always always it's my cologne
always when I'm in the coffee shop
smelling like weed and the cops walk in
and I don't have to trip bro it's great
I was smoking a joint in downtown
Sacramento one time and it was it wasn't
very crowded it was like me a couple
other people on the street and I'm
smoking a joint waiting for the bus and
three sheriff's deputies walked by right
and I'm just smoking a joint and they're
like hey what's up I was like hey what's
up yeah and that was it yeah it was
beautiful totally it was beautiful a lot
of the other ways they set up the system
in California I'm not a fan but just
that part that's amazing yeah man great
for the blood pressure well I heard
Dallas anything less than 4 ounces they
will not arrest you for you'll get fine
but they are not arresting people
anymore in Dallas for four in Dallas
less than 4 o in Dallas not Austin not
San Antonio Dallas Dallas I love it I
love it I love and you know my family
lives in Dallas right and so I'm excited
you know I've never been to Dallas I've
been to Corpus Christie I've been to San
Antonio I've been to oil town or oil
Dale I've been
to El Paso I've been to all kind of town
I just never Houston yeah Houston's
great Austin so Viet Cajun food in
Houston food's great there I'm here for
it Houston is a good eating Town same
thing with
Austin hum oh listen when I'm in Austin
or Texas uh it is a struggle to maintain
any sort of vegetable because I just eat
brisket I'll have a brisket Taco for
breakfast I have brisket at lunch brisk
eggs brisket sandwich for lunch brisket
plate for dinner right why are you
mucking about why it's hard to get
brisket that good anywhere else it's so
good everywhere your odds are very
wherever they got the brisket your odds
are good maybe I'll get a queso with
brisket in it for the appetizer well
it's so funny cuz Texas has some
barbecue spots uh that are super
expensive that you have to wait in line
forever but there's also like the
hole-in-the-wall place that not a lot of
people know about that's just absolutely
amazing that's $10 still it's just one
of those towns where you know if if
you're going to put your name on some
brisket yeah you better be you better
come correct yeah I mean I love brisket
with some white bread and a side of
beans andever you didn't even need beans
dude I I'm like I need a pound of
brisket just brisket you want any sides
it's going to get in the way yeah it's
going to get in the way me most of the
places the cheap ones the the sides
aren't even that good you might you
might find one thing that's okay but
like I'm not taking the risk bro just
hand over the meat run me the meat and
no one gets hurt yeah and do you like
the fatty part of the brisket do you
like the point or do you like the flat I
like a mix yeah uh if you lean toward
the fatty burins is my go-to I'm always
a burn in if burn ends on the menu just
hand me the burn ends that's one pound
of burn ends please one pound of burn
ends and a good sauce I'm not always a
fan of the Texas I like a Kansas City
style sauce right cuz I grew up in
California so we had like you like a
little more vinegar a little thinner a
little less vinegar a little more corn
syrup a little thicker oh it's a little
thicker right A lot of these Texas
sauces are some of those North Carolina
guys with your mustard and two vinegary
no no I don't like the vinegar myself
personally you know listen uh you could
almost say that uh burnt ends with a hot
sweet barbecue sauce is like the general
chose
chicken right just put a put a sweet
sauce on it you know good hunk of meat
Americans love that right Americans
love little crispy on the outside
Americans love crispy on the outside you
can't go wrong with it can't go wrong
with this is the sweet and sour pork of
people who don't eat sweet and sour pork
exactly exactly that's the way to go
though right yeah I mean I I love
ketchup is the soy sauce of America
according to my daughter yeah yeah I
mean my nephew he used to eat ketchup
packets for for food that's what he l
love Hines ketchup packets gross well I
mean I guess if that's your thing yeah I
mean that was his ice cream I I I've
never liked ketchup really no don't like
like okay if it's a homemade ketchup if
somebody made the ketchup yeah I will I
will take a dab made ketchup if it's
homemade if you if you make if it's a
homemade ketchup if it's a homemade
ranch dressing you don't need 57
different types of tomato in your
ketchup uh you don't need any of that
weird vinegar corn syrup concoction that
you know an excuse to sugar on your meat
that they call ketchup
yeah you don't like ketchup on your
steak nor on my eggs nor on my baln
sandwiches nor on my Burgers nor on my
fish or my potatoes yeah on the potatoes
especially I think that's a big one in
America is don't ketchup with potatoes
the Dutch put mayonnaise on their
potatoes so who are we who are we to to
talk Dutch mayonnaise is different too
though I really like Japanese and I like
Dutch mayonnaise Dutch mayonnaise sounds
like either a wrestler or a sex move it
could be dangerous either
Dutch mayonnaise that's his signature
move is the Dutch mayonnaise that's why
they call him Dutch mayonnaise yeah you
got to watch out the BL the blue waffle
and the Dutch mayonnaise gave the Dutch
mayonnaise off the top rope it was over
over they just said
damn because the Dutch so I like eggs a
lot I've been working on egg salad
sandwiches Japanese style Korean style
all that stuff there's a spot in
Sacramento called panes and they're
mostly Italian y but they put a little
curry powder in the egg salad sandwich
and it's just oh it's so good so curry
with mayonnaise makes one of the best
aoli yes and I love it especially just
where it's a hint of it where it just
it's it's slightly yellow but you get
that Curry it lifts everything up right
that's one of those on just a little
something just a little yeah little SM I
mean the world is about diversity and
differentiation from place to place I
love that where you can go to someplace
and they got something special like that
where it's like wow just a little you
like to have somebody put a Twist yeah
right if I wanted everything to be
exactly the same I would just go to
McDonald's which is great sometimes
because you do want something to be the
same I don't like McDonald's but yes I
agree no I understand consistency is
amazing I understand that listen
McDonald's is is mostly evil mostly evil
it's the evil empire mostly evil yeah
just sometimes dark cidus I like to see
how their expression of the culture is
if when I'm in a different country uhhuh
uh right you know cuz you can get a goat
cheese burger in Barcelona right they
put goat cheese on it you can't no no my
parents love McDonald's out of the
country like they want to go see what's
going on there sometimes you just want
to see sometimes you just want to see uh
I'm not eating there every day it's like
oh my God thank God there's McDonald's
but you know I'm kind of sewing water in
the streets you see McDonald's let's go
see this goat cheeseburger let's let's
see what the lamb ma let's just see what
they're doing right right but yeah I
love a I love a local twist or or a
however however you like to do it at
your spot as long as you're not too
heavy on the pickles no and then I see I
love good homemade pickles too a good
homemade pickle once again though
there's a difference sometimes between I
mean vasic makes a good pickle I'm just
not a big I think it's a vinegar thing
I'm not a big vinegar rer yeah I mean
I'm skinning a so I pickle everything
sure we pickle everything you whatever
you can pickle we'll pickle that I'll
pickle everything yeah see yeah you I
love pickles but you know pickled
carrots pickled
you make the pickle sandwich have you
seen that where they use two big slices
of pickle and they put all the meat in
the things but no bread it's just a
pickle sandwich yeah yeah it's great all
right I do pickled strawberries with
jalapenos and they have a little red uh
red wine vinegar and a little white
vinegar and a bunch of sugar bunch of
sugar but what you what happens when you
use the red wine vinegar is it doesn't
let the strawberry lose its color it
maintains the color so it has it's this
but you have to eat them 24 hours after
you make them I was going to say how
long do you pick so it's a it's a
quicker pickle it's a quickle yeah it's
a quickle yeah and you do it in the
fridge the refrigerator pickle so you do
that overnight you eat them the next day
they're good for about 24 to 48 hours
max all right and they're spicy because
you slice that especially when you use
jalapenos and it gives you that
green jalapeno flavor with a little kick
of spice it's great do you put it in a
salad you just eat them straight out the
jar you have them put them on a bagel
with a cream cheese oh yeah that would
be great that would be amazing yeah I
mean I can't wait till we do a show that
right there
yeah you put those with cream cheese you
put them on a fresh bagel I love
homemade Bagels toasted bagel I will
make bagels yes to you don't have to
toast Bagels if they're fresh right if
they come right out and they can be room
temperature if they're really really
really fresh is corre shout out lock
smith Bagels in Seattle That's my boy
shout out Main Street bagels in
Sacramento we love you I have not been
there but I love Bagels okay I mean even
though as Bagels is okay in a pinch in a
pinch it's okay in a pinch but it's in a
pinch it's in a pinch bro you you don't
go to Noah's Bagels you end up at Noah's
Bagels exactly it's not a
destination it's not a destination
location but yeah right but if you're
there it's not the worst you know the
line at the brunch spot is long maybe
you get a small Bagel while you wait for
your actual meal or whatever okay well
so there's these freezer bagels and I
don't make the name off hand but they
have robots making these freezer Bagels
they're freaking amazing for what they
are and they're at like Boutique lardi
has them in their freezer section I was
they're made by robots we have a new
spot a new Bagel delivery service in uh
in Sacramento but I'm just outside their
Zone cuz you know they make them all
small batch by hand and then they
deliver them on bicycle that's fre on
bicycle on bicycle bro we're keeping the
the carbon footprint low low low low low
low dude that's what's up right and I'm
I'm here for it and I wish I I don't
really wish I well sometimes I wish I
still lived in Midtown but I have a
really nice spot and it's not super
expensive uh and it's just 5 minutes I'm
just rambling at this point weeds yeah
you got the blend the blend High yeah
I'm I'm on like five different weeds
right now yeah yeah five different weeds
three types of mushrooms and some DMT
that sounds Partridge and a pear tree or
a great one or a great one or a great
one depends on your mindset so where did
you get your start with comedy uh San
Francisco nice I was always kind of
funny as a kid you know self-defense
mechanism becomes a career I guess
totally um yeah I was always kind of
funny class clownish a little bit and
then one of my teachers one time in high
school asked me to uh do a set it like
the intermission between bands because I
was in the band yeah so like the one
band would play and I did like 10
minutes it was terrible right I just did
other comic stuff yeah uh and then you
know in college raw uh old school like
the red fox that I could tell the
students and a little uh I don't think
it was it was long it was before Eddie
Murphy Raw it was like around wow Eddie
Murphy comedian so I was big Richard
Pryor Bob newart Steve Martin Classics
red fox yeah a little Eddie Murphy
because I was like 14 when that happened
Robin Willams Back Robin hero a monster
amazing goes so fast so fast classic
comedian super talented super talented
yeah uh using utilizing all of his
talents on stage sometimes I think
in in standup comedy we can forget that
we have a lot of of skills you know but
if you watch Like Richard Pryor like
he's acting his ass off yeah while he's
doing that if you watch Robin he's
utilizing all his physicality all his
voices all his things uh Jonathan wyers
uh all those guys and even you know we
talk about 80s 90s cats uh Bill Hicks uh
Areno Hall was very funny yeah so Areno
one of the kids I grew up with my
friend's younger brother was the guy the
kid that drove the I think it was a
Ferrari or Lamborghini on the in the the
intro to the show he's the one who
stalled it out and they that was
basically he didn't do it on purpose but
they ended up leaving it in because they
thought it was funny because it's funny
yeah yeah yeah my friend that's what
happens sometimes the universe also has
a sense of humor does it does over and
over and over again yeah yeah yeah and
so then you know uh I'd been a comic
maybe two years before starting to
become like a more serious cannabis
activist and so I'm always like let me
host your thing let me MC for this we we
used to throw the occasional cannabis
Comedy Festival which is what we call it
cuz sometimes we wait a year and throw
it sometimes we throw two or three at a
year sometimes we'd wait two years to
throw one so it wasn't like the annual
it was the occasional totally the
occasional Canabis Comedy Festival um
and so we're just mixing that and doing
that and doing the Seattle Hemp Fest and
yeah just going anywhere I can and you
know talking about it on stage right uh
all the time not all the time I have
other jokes I talk about
quantum physics and sex and being a nerd
and all kind of other things but you
know it's like go back to Canabis it's
like anel on a pizza you mentioned weed
twice now now you're a weed comic not So
Much Anymore that weed is legal back in
the day when it was against the law
everybody's like oh he's a weed comic we
don't we don't need him and now they're
like we need someone to come over here
and talk about weed for a minute yeah so
sometimes they call me and sometimes
they need someone younger
right well so where is the place that
you had the most fun doing
or what what's the biggest crowd you've
done stand up for I don't know comedy in
the park San Francisco I mean I grew up
in San Francisco right so I started like
the holy city zoo and the rose and Thorn
and a little bit of the other Cafe every
once in a while and my first paid gig
was at the El Rio on Mission Street I
don't know man I've had some really good
shows in some really weird spots uh
Idaho Falls Idaho used to have a great
club called the pepper tree out there
you used to always have a good time out
there yeah sh Oakland San Francisco I
them at The Warfield yeah just
everywhere man every Show's a good show
bro if you do you like small more
intimate shows or the bigger shows I
like them all I just like to stand on
stage and talk man I'm kind of funny and
you know it's a different it's a
different uh approach yeah and and how
you do the things you know what I mean
sure uh when you're doing the smaller
show you can talk a little faster
especially if they're all right up on
you you can make smaller faces but more
intricate faces yeah you know what I
mean right because everybody can see
you're you know it's like watching a
close-up magician at that point and then
if you're at the big spot where it's 25
200 people or whatever you got to talk a
little slower you got to wait a little
longer because that joke's got to go all
the way to the back of that giant
freaking Auditorium and then come all
the way back to you yeah you know you
have to make uh bigger faces and maybe
fewer of them because I mean now with
the modern technology they got the
bigger screen so it's easier yeah to
treat a bigger room like a smaller room
so sure
yeah you see these guys doing stadiums
and they have these huge jumbotrons or
whatever it is comedy needs face it does
it's a physical activity right so you
you really need a lot of the cues you
get from the eyes or from the from the
face or whatever so totally it it helps
it helps you mentioned although I used
to listen to albums like this all the
time and imagine their faces you know oh
yeah I love doing that back in the day
with vinyl comedy of the theater of the
mind yeah yeah I mean I loved reading
books and imagining what was happening
you know we have these movies now and
everybody's so focused on movies but you
know I I also love books read the book
you can put the movie in your head yeah
I would cast the whole thing I'm like
this one's going to be an animated
feature because clearly with the science
blah blah blah this and I get so LED
down with movies sometimes because of
reading the book I read the book and
then I'm like wait a second what's going
on here two different universes two
different completely different two
different universes the book universe is
different from the movie universe and
you just have to accept it yep it's that
Multiverse it's the Multiverse you just
have to accept that that's that's the
thing right I'll tell you a story yeah
guy goes to the movie theater and he
notices that the dude sitting next to
him has brought his dog that's not so
weird but the thing is the dog is way
into the movie the dog wags his tail at
the happy Parts he whimpers when it's
sad he growls at the villain yeah so
when the movie's over turns to the guy
who brought the dog he says man I was
really surprised to see that your dog
enjoyed the movie and he goes I was too
he hated the
book Old for laughs
yeah that's
great hold for
laugh that is absolutely
great he hated the book all right he
hated the book yeah yeah so yeah so
growing up in San Francisco that's where
I grew up yeah you mentioned champagne
yes what else did you like did you so
you liked weed before they even had
names when it was green bud and brown
bud bro uh yeah when it was weed it was
it was a nickel bag sometimes you could
get for
$4 right uh weed was $308 and it was
just weed every once in a while some
would come oh it's Lambs bread oo
oh it's this oh it's that uh sometimes
it had seeds in it sometimes it didn't
right since Amia was really just getting
started right right um it was H it I
enjoyed some of that seated stuff to be
100% you felt lucky when you found a
seed too yeah man a lot of that Mexican
stuff there was good and bad there was
different levels to it
you had to know somebody shout out Janet
shout out uh Dr John uh shout out all my
old ween shout out my boy Doug shout out
all my 80s and 90s weed weed people Dr
John Hudson man but he rest in peace he
wasn't really a doctor but we called him
that he he like Dr Pepper he he got into
growing cannabis because he thought his
sister had cancer and he had heard that
it could help so he started growing
cannabis and then it turned out he was
really good at it he was really good at
growing weed man and uh he used to grow
great fantastic weed and uh he got
busted back in the day he had opened a
little uh dispensary um he was selling
because his weed was so good he was
selling to all the clubs of course he
got busted by the feds
twice right and I was like man why don't
you quit he's like I'm crazy this is an
important thing to do right and I was
like yeah all right man but just be
careful and then uh one day the DEA
showed up and just scared off they were
like just you need to quit right now wow
and so he disappeared for a while and
then he came back and then he passed
away well it's so sad so sad yeah I mean
welcome to sad talk James listen to
James loud talking quietly about s sad
things yeah yeah yeah I mean it's funny
because I think if you were to look a
hundred years in the future you would
think it was kind of crazy this whole
thing that's gone on with prohibition of
cannabis you know you look 100 years in
the past too I think people would think
it was crazy why people act like that
how could we have been so blind why are
we we so shortsighted when then they
watch the James live podcast and H the
answer is usually either racism or
sexism right that's usually the answer
to why things are not how you want them
to be right yeah and I know it's hard
for some people to look at that but yeah
that's generally the answer if you go
way back it's pretty complex too there's
like the financial it's pretty simple
generally it's either racism or sexism
yeah a lot of times it's just racism
especially in America
it's really weird and I'm I'm sure
you'll probably get some comments and uh
when I'm watching this on YouTube I will
try to chime in if you remain cogent and
don't lose your mind we're going to have
a reasonable and a reasoned and audite
debate don't get up here just talking
all willy-nilly but a lot of times in
America the reason cannabis was against
the law was racism 100% 100% yeah 100%
yeah right uh you can take you yeah it's
complex as it is you can break it down
right all the way down to racism I agree
100% right that's that's the that is the
reason yeah that's the exact reason yep
right why a lot of cannabis laws were so
strict yeah racism which is funny
because black people smoke weed at a
little smaller rate than white people
yeah but whatever right so anyway moving
on moving on I mean I think these are
important topics for my show though so
so as I'm here listen I'll come on every
week we'll just have a little serious
debate for 15 minutes 15 serious minutes
with wum and James loud absolutely you
know but but it's these kind of things
that that change people's perspectives
right and I think true if you don't have
the hard conversations how do you change
things amen amen so yeah and and I love
talking about stuff I love talking about
the hard conversations I think there's
so many we can talk about here's a
here's a hard question for you yeah cold
water hash or
BHO so this is a this yeah I'm going to
get a little bit of hate for this
one I asked the tough questions man this
is the tough question question so if we
look at BHO BHO as far as processed with
solvent with butane you actually get the
water soluble Tarpin that you don't get
from bubble hash now as far as for a
flavor M I think that there's nothing
wrong with butane I enjoy the flavor of
BHO if it's processed and made correctly
with I think BHO is an amazing product
minimal amount of explosions yeah and I
mean even minimal amount of explosions
eyebrows all those things intact yes
there was a a trend when when uh when
blasting at home or whatever first
became a thing you know the dab heads be
like oh yeah man I'm doing that be like
man it's dangerous so what happens like
someone learn about it they learn the
technique they get into it they set
themselves on fire and then they quit
yeah San Francisco there was multiple
there was Hotel fires it
I've had I me to about it but I think
it's honest you know and and people
people had accidents do yeah you know
but as far as like a product I think the
product BHO is a good product I think
bubblehash and rosin are great too uh
but they're not true solvent list water
is the universal solvent talked about on
my show y there's nothing wrong I really
enjoy those uh now static hash is I'm
super stoked on the static hash lay this
lay this process on the L so static hash
is where you you know you can do it the
simplest way to do it is to put the your
your basically your ke or your sift on
on a piece of parchment and you rub it
with the glove and then whatever sticks
to the glove you brush it off into a
bowl and you know it's it's basically
using static you can go over it this how
to get like the tiniest little all the
it magnetically draws the glove and then
so you're getting this product uh
there's machines that do it that's like
a super fancy finger hash it is it's
like and so so now we're Reinventing the
wheel we're going back to what we did
years ago our static hash is lovingly
handcrafted by only Superior people with
small yet delicate hands they wave the
static and they brush we use a oh yeah
ostrich plume yeah and they actually
have machines to do with plates
ergonomically Mag plates right yeah and
yeah I'm I get excited about that
because that is a true solventless
product you're not running water so
you're getting getting a you prefer a
press to any of the other concentrating
Styles I mean I like I like good bubble
hash I really you like bubble really
really like it I like Rosen 2 but I
really like good bubble hash U you know
I got my old school classic Adam Smasher
I use still the three hole bowl that has
the holes on the side where on the
bottom you heat the rod up you push it
down I love that wow hot knives we used
to do hot knives too I used have I have
a joke of act about back in my day we
didn't have Vape pins we had two hot
knives in a broken wine bottle yeah or a
toilet paper tube toilet paper paper
towel tube whatever you can't really hot
knife no one really has a gas stove no
we're going to do a hot knife next time
you're on the show though all right I'm
here yeah I'm here for it I'm here for
under glass oh yeah yeah yeah I love
those old nostalgic things and bringing
back the past showing people how to do
it people think they're Reinventing the
wheel with some of the stuff that we
were doing 30 years ago there nothing
was everything old is new again or some
like that I think that's what they
say bell bottoms Bell oh wait jenos
hey J jeno should have never left I'm
going to say that right now I love a
baggy pant twice material H twice the
price you know it just it shows you're
affluent yeah and I mean I I still have
like my collector's edition jenos I have
some I with the I have the ones the
Corduroy with the wide pipe the what is
it whale piping or whatever it's called
the wide whale wide whale quarter run
yeah I yeah those were good stuff I
don't have my jenos and uh I lost my
food fubo I don't know where my fuboo
Jersey went I had a old school fubo
Jersey those space boot looking shoes
that they had space boots no not the doc
Martins not the doc Martins they they
had a specific was there a brand it
wasn't ug no it wasn't it was pre- Uggs
this is in the 9s and I held on to my
Sho it wasn't lugs but I did oh no it
was lugs was it lugs it was lugs it was
lugs they look like space boots I mean
they did have the construction looking
ones the lugs the white lugs I held on
to those till probably 2018 and how much
raving did you do a lot yeah clear I
love I loved parties what's your Rave
name yeah we can't tell anybody that no
right somebody listen be like that's him
I know that guy yeah yeah yeah yeah he
was my dealer
no that's what I can't remember who it
was uh some celebrity uh cuz Harrison
Ford was like a handyman right and other
jobs in La before he hit big so she said
she went to see uh Star Wars she's like
why is my weed deal
he a carpenter and a weed deer yeah
exactly
classic but yeah we had some of the best
from Han Solo dude that that would be
epic but yeah the Raves we had we that
would be actually pretty cool we saw
early days of DJ Danning Donald GLA and
Christopher Lawrence was one of my
favorites and Tony and yo just to name a
few but uh you know Mark ferino with
mushroom J such a game changer wow you
want to start dating yourself you throw
names out like that people Mark finina
man he was all over San Francisco at the
time Mark was crushing that mushroom
Jazz was am amazing for you guys that
don't know what I'm talking about look
up mushroom Jazz Mark finina absolutely
amazing r i yeah totally I mean we had
some San Francisco house music was epic
and break beats before that was that
around like the eye beam and lips
ellipse underground and uh the home the
home 1015 for sure home parties you'd
end up at the end up in San
Francisco you'd end up at the end up the
end up cuz the end up would stop serving
booze at 2: yeah and still party till 6
and then start serving like mimosas and
breakfast at 6m yeah people would look
so bad at the
end like 10 in the morning it was rough
but we had a party called strawberry
Sundays and that was epic so there there
was some After parties I like the After
parties too Raves and then you go to the
After parties stay you know we used to
Rave for like four days in a row
sometimes that's crazy Eat Sleep Rave
Repeat oh yeah yeah rinse repeat every
day that's a lot yeah but great music
great people I really enjoyed my
childhood because this was in my you
know pre 21 years you know resilient
yeah you're resilient you bounce back
from that stuff sleep is for wussies
exactly yeah man exactly listening to
great music and partying coffee and the
Molly
for well yeah and it's like the one
constant with all that stuff was the
weed though like we all smoke weed uh I
loved weed back then I've always loved
weed it's been let's see the constant
Lance red champagne Romulan Romulan
train wreck Odyssey I remember when
train wreck just first came out I
remember when white widow finally made
it to the states cuz we had gone to
Amsterdam like a year before that and
smoke some White Widow and every was
like oh this is amazing then like a year
later it started showing up totally in
the states uh GDP was a little bit later
but the madin or the Alaskan Thunder
that was special obviously Northern
Lights is a big one Northern Lights
number five skunk we had skunk skunk one
we had skunk one we talk about my
podcast we called it it was called
strawberry because it was strawberry
sized nuggets right right right right
right skunk it was the real skunk we had
skunk there was also I'm trying to think
of the ones before the 2000s you know
that was a long time ago that was a long
time ago but there was some there were
some good ones yeah the shaman good ones
I first well maybe I did but I don't
know so so many though and you know
Northern Lights crosses and stuff you
can still get a little tie there was
Sometimes some um like a Maui woi yeah
there was Maui wow I remember getting
that occasionally there was one I don't
know what it was but I used to get this
from my boy I just call it magic Harvest
because my homie knew somebody in
Portland who grew he's retired now so
don't go looking for him but he would
Harvest on the solstices and the Equinox
right cuz like he had it super hippie
dialed in on his indoor and it was
so flavorful and the high was super
Pleasant and it was just stinky yeah
like it was stinky like I'm driving it
down from California I got it in like
two Ziplocs in a plastic thing wrapped
in another ziplock and my car still yeah
still like I had a little bit in my
jacket and my home girl from across the
gym was like what dog is that you right
I made a friend because the next door
neighbor smelled us smoking it and he
came over he's like hey hey what's
up I got to see what's going on yeah we
used to have to put it in coolers now
obviously they have bags that that are
resistant but coolers were a great way
to transport stuff back in the day D but
I'm saying like we tried I you could it
was just stinky it was just one of those
on some of the weed was back just one of
those on the weed back in the 90s when I
was smoking there was some stuff that
was you couldn't get the smell like ciss
was one of those ones it was so loud
there was nothing a tenth of a gr would
smell your whole house up house you know
and we're talking about this little tiny
piece right here that if it was in your
pocket everybody everywhere you went
would smell it cats come walking in from
the next room like what is going on yeah
that's that's one of uh one of the
reasons I really like uh the synonym
loud for cannabis because it it
describes exactly what's going on that
weed is loud dog I could hear it it giv
you synesthesia I could hear you smoking
that weed I can hear that weed from over
here you open that bag yeah yeah yeah
yeah the bells went off like right right
loud what's your favorite new synonym
tree fire gas loud I like all of it you
like all of it fire that's one I like
yeah yeah I mean I still like dank Dank
I'm the Dank Diplomat so I'm on your
side yeah I like that word I love which
means I'm uncomfortably moist I'm
kidding right totally that's why I like
the name
dank dank yeah dank is just a great name
it's a great description of it
especially that real you are you're like
a '90s kid dank Dan hella dank chronic
chronic dank right
we had the sure but chronic I think
chronic comes from like habitual like
he's a chronic and habitual user of the
cannabis plant I like that KGB you know
we had the killer green Bud killer green
bud we're releasing with the Cannabis
Brothers KGB for a California gas bill
spelled with the K oh nice so yeah so it
would be the cgb KGB California SP the K
I'm sorry KGB we're going back to the
KGB right you so how you think you're
Russian exactly take your time that's
why put
yeah but yeah it's a WiFi type zbx which
is a skittles back cross all right and
so you get the best of both world you
get the candy and you get the gas and
it's definitely heavy on the gas that
nose burning gas with a little bit of
great color great structure great effect
how much how much emphas emphasis yeah
do you place on color like are you
always trying to get a little pink a
purple in it or do you sometimes I mean
train wreck is just bright green okay so
here's my thought on the whole process
on me the market loves purple right now
the market always love purple well there
was a time where you couldn't sell
purple to save your life purple Cadillac
there was GDP and then purple C I
remember having problems with purple
Cadillac well I never I never smoked it
but yeah and so there was a point where
GDP came out everybody loved it and all
a sudden everyone hates it right and so
it's made the with cookies it brought
the color back but I feel like if you're
pheno hunting and you're really going
through stuff and you look at the purple
feno versus the Green feno in a progyny
of a bunch of different
siblings yeah the ones that are louder
are going to be more green right I find
a lot of times yeah you're correct and I
also find a lot of times that if it's
too purple yeah like the high will be
nice but it'll be shortlived short lived
like I don't know cuz they're picking it
early to keep the purple I don't know
what's going on but a lot of times that
purple but a lot of times that purple
the high doesn't last as long as you
think it's going to last as you get with
maybe something the same way in green I
don't know why that is I know I think
it's very cultivar dependent some
cultivars are meant to be purple and a
lot of people try to force their to
be purple and that's no good what what
beet you can't just put beet juice in
your water no let's go with cold temps
let's put ice on the plants we're going
to freeze it throw in some beet juice
yeah we're going to do all the things oh
it's like whatever it takes to get it
purple because purple is what sells and
that mentality
is it's here but you still keep an eye
on color when you're picking fenos or do
you just % of what I TPS I want effect
effect right but at the same time T well
effect and turps are two different
things I onage yeah you want the
Entourage but how does it make you feel
but really we go through and take the
loudest smelling stuff we smoke
everything with all those 600 we had day
like literally everybody smoked
everything listen I can help if you need
some help I'm a former judge of the
emerald cup my rates are very reasonable
yeah yeah we pay in weed yeah so we we
we basically sit around and talk about
it and we we fill out forms right with
all this stuff you have to we're really
you're taking it seriously we're taking
it very seriously because we're trying
to find that next new winner and it
takes a lot of work and energy and you
can't just grow it out once you have to
grow it out another time and then
compare to the first time now let me ask
you this sure on uh on average how many
seasons will will we will assume a
season is 12 to 14 weeks uh does it take
for you to get a good finished pheno
from so you started with 600 so maybe
two months later you have 60 right so on
that first batch you're growing and out
of those 60 we have Superstars already I
know you already have five five you like
I would say we have 10 out of those that
are superstars where I know they're
going to be special okay I already know
my lines anyway so we already knew going
in that we wanted to pop more of these
than other ones because there's going to
be winners you know my drips that you
can get online there was 20 things and
out of the 20 15 were Keepers where it's
like we got to regrow 15 of these
they're so good that's very rare a lot
of times times I'll pop a 100 and we
might keep two okay you know so and it
just depends on how well you know your
line what you're breeding for so you got
that you're breeding let's say we're
breeding for uh seeds and cuts or seeds
well let's say we're we can breed for
commercial viability what's going to
work on the commercial Market that's
candy gas that yields really well that
that's molden mildew resistant right all
those things are important quick quick
finish finishing is important no quick
finishing will make you more money
because people want let's say you have
something that finishes in 45 days yeah
you can get nine rips per year nine
Harvest per year right and so there's
value in something like that and now if
you have something that finishes in 42
to 45 days which is very rare isn't that
fast it is but it's not impossible but
we have one that finishes in 42 days to
45 days they you get three pounds of
light it has over 20% T has 25 how tall
is it is it bushy it's bushy but it's
very vigorous and it's also purple right
and so how's how's the mold resistance
on a bushy fast gr see the thing is is
with does have time to get mold it
doesn't have time right and so these
things have a lot of commercial
viability it's far as is the tur profile
the best no but it's really high in THC
so for processing for extraction when
we're processing for hash it's a really
good one right and it has potential for
that so there's different that's an old
school one that is a great old school
one G3 G13 how about Vortex you remember
the vortex I don't remember the vortex
yeah
I all of the above I remember the aota I
also remember the sage the sa sativa
Afghani genetic equivalent yeah from
Adam Dunn genetic equilibrium yeah THC
the old school DJ Short
Blueberry I do I remember multiple
blueberries we had the organ blueberry
we had the DJ Short Blueberry very
different did you ever smoke any any of
that uh there was a New York blueberry
diesel out of Portland one time that was
I remember blueberry diesel for sure I
don't remember New York blueberry diesel
blueberry on the inhale and then all
diesel on the exhale I haven't seen it
that sounds amazing oh it was so good
yeah strawberry Durban diesel oh that
was special I went to high school with
him nice yeah yeah I mean there was some
old school winners we had some special
stuff back in the day bring them back
who's got the seed Vault you probably
have something I have a really special
seed Vault there's all kinds of stuff
from all over I have land if I were to
write a heist movie we would just be uh
taking some samples from somebody's seed
Vault yeah
well we got seeds we got lots I noticed
is that what those are yeah those are
all the BC and dgr seeds oh really so
which one is this one yeah that one is
uh most of those don't germinate and
that's why weuse we run them through a
machine you feed them to the parrots you
could but we use them as a prop it's
like you put a hole in them put the hole
in the playing deck yeah at the uh the
card deck at the casino and then you can
just take them home with the old ones
exactly okay cuz I was wondering yeah
and then we got coffee there so when
you're smelling and you're feno hunting
you're going through these things you
can clean your pallet of course got to
love coffee I know you do a lot of feno
hunting and whatnot in your life but do
you also judge events and whatnot like
I've judged for High Times in the
emerald cup and some of the early early
cups I used to throw I threw the LA
medical cannabis cup uh I think we threw
three of them in LA in the early the mid
2000 like 2005 through 2005 to 2007 I
think that was a good time well and I
throw events I did the Dabo last year
for Mila Dao
hashen yeah my my friend Sam uh rosin
Tech and focus V yeah we did that
together we did the Dabo we're going to
do it again this year and need a host
yeah I I love hosting I love yeah so we
we might we might need a host a real
host I'm just the guy who that hosted
but but that doesn't mean we don't need
a real host no no no no but yeah you
definitely need to come to the event and
try all when is it we haven't picked a
date as soon as we know we will yeah we
I'd love to include you that'd be great
I love to be included yeah and those
kind of events are just it's just so
nice to be asked yeah well and it's so
nice to have a good MC oh it often is
thank you yeah I mean uh there's good
ones there's bad ones there's everything
in between I've seen it all and that
goes across the board with everything uh
that that goes across the board with
everything everything is everything and
everything in between yeah what do you
think which way do you think the the
genetic Mark Market is headed this year
like is is gas making come back sour gas
sour gas Kush I would love to see it all
come back so you predict the a return of
the classics retro vintage throwback
jersey weekend absolutely the bell
bottoms are coming back bell all the way
back to bell bottoms this is wakin It's
Panama Red I would love to see I've
noticed aapco gold and I don't know if
it's the old school aapco gold but
people claim to have aapco gold in a few
different spots I'm seen it in Seattle
I'm see it in a couple other spots I
think the Trap world for you know the
Trap scene probably not there always
about the hype right but I see on the
wreck Market people wanting aapco gold
Wanting Blue Dream people wanting Panama
Red if you had it you buy the AA Poco
gold you give it to your granddad or
your dad they're like oh man right happy
birthday I also see that one to one
coming back the the THC CBD 1: one for
people like I'm going to go so far as to
say I like a three to one I like a three
CBD to one THC you smoke it all day
while you do your things and not a lot
of this and you
know we can get it the too much THC is
not bad but stop stop judging yeah right
uh but yeah and also sometimes I don't
want to be that THC high for my whole
day I'm trying to do a bunch of stuff
feel good just trying to you know that's
what you like white th Rose I love white
Thorn Rose it's like one of those things
I feel like that's one of those ones
where you smoke it you feel good you
feel great and it's the smell smell of
it and it's not everybody jam and that's
okay I don't know I haven't met one
person who smoked this with me and was
like I don't know it's not I haven't
either but you'll see people in the chat
they're like e it's not strong enough
it's like where they strong enough yeah
but that that's but that's not the point
dude when you when you go out drinking
do you always just do shots of 151 right
are you just chugging ever clear right
out the bottle green alcohol are you
shooting GRE catch a buzz yeah and I
believe that's the beauty of it you can
smoke and the rosin too it's one of
those ones you can dab after to catch a
nice Buzz man so great I'm going to the
movies I'm not trying to be crazy huh
I'm going to a a place that's very where
I don't really know anyone so I'm not
trying to be crazy high right or
whatever right I'm just trying to have a
nice little not afraid to talk to people
Buzz little smile on my face there's a
time and a place for everything find me
by the snacks I don't have to smoke red
Congo all the time you know although I
do like red Congo but red Congo makes me
giggly and laugh uncontrollably yeah so
you got to be careful yeah that's all
totally that's all pick the right the
right the right weed for the right
activity smoke responsibly right you're
an adult hopefully well I act like a kid
half the time doesn't you're still an
adult right right what's that what's
that old you know people often confuse
me for an adult because of my age right
yeah that's how I feel yeah absolutely
yeah yeah we're all just big kids
trapped in old people's bodies so I'm 47
I'll be 48 in a month congratulations I
will be older than that yeah in a month
well you've aged well thank you I think
it's it'sa the lifestyle yeah old
Stoners are always cuter than old drunks
that is for for sure yeah you know I
it's just the argument it's hard to
argue the the quality of life with
cannabis versus quality of life with
alcohol I mean listen everything not
everything's for everybody some
people can be fairly healthy responsible
drinkers yeah you know it's a social
thing the French the French are pretty
good at it yeah I mean I'm I'm not a I'm
not against canvas I'm not a non-
drinker I will definitely have a beer on
a hot day or every once in a while oh I
got a full bar over here every once in a
while you should not maybe not should
not for everybody but every once in a
while the right move is to get a little
hammered yeah I think it's great but not
necessarily you're doing that every day
or every weekend no but if I go to Spain
I want to go drink some good wine with
my friends have some good food and make
some good memories we're going to spend
6 hours eating some long ass dinner
drinking all the wine and then you kind
of stumble home singing maybe you end up
at somebody's private chess club yeah
yeah exactly no I'm with it 4 in the
morning you're rolling up joints hanging
out a good old time if you've been
drinking I think there's nothing wrong
with that he that's how it's supposed to
go that's America well that's Spain
actually yeah so I'll see you out there
then where are we eating absolutely
posadas Del pep okay uh there's so many
good plays so many Vaso De Oro is
another hidden Jam I haven't been
theread Del pep there's no sign on the
front door you walk down this Alleyway
this is what we're going to do we're
going to have to pick a day yeah so I'm
throwing a party again and we're going
to wander around I'm going to take you
to a spot yeah you're going to take me
to a spot oh yeah so this is my my city
and I love it Barcelona's your city it's
my city I your city I spend a lot of
time well it could be your city too but
it's definitely my city if I think of
all the cities out there I uh San
Francisco Barcelona those are my cities
I I often start looking for apartments I
don't think I would ever move but I
often sometimes when I'm there I'm like
well I could live in this part of town I
could have a little p right over here
where not like it used to be bro well
it's still pretty affordable so so drink
it's no longer cheap still inexpensive
when Co hit we were looking at signing
like literally the day before they were
getting the paperwork typed up for an
apartment yeah it was I think it was
either 15 or ,200 EUR a month which is
very that's very affordable probably had
a little
balcona it's like walking distance to
everything yeah but that's way cheaper
than here you know and that's like a
vacation apartment basically right right
right and luckily Co happened when it
did and not the day before because I
would have signed that lease and
stuck but as it happened we didn't end
up sign signing the lease uh I do love
spending time there as some of my best
lovec one of my best
friends you know it's like uh shout out
to my friend Abba shout out to Abba yeah
he's a good friend we've been friends
for a long time what's your what's your
social club of choice Social Club of
choice uh there's so many but I I spent
a lot of time at Strain Hunters of
course you do the most Dam style of the
ones it is and and they probably have
the best food although all their food is
kind of sugary and deserty but it's all
really good yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah
yeah yeah and it's it's very expansive
it's very comfortable and they got the
booths yeah it makes sense but yeah I
mean it makes sense I like Dr du Dr du
yeah yeah I mean and there's so many
good clubs over there I think so many I
should write a list go to my patreon
next week and you'll find I'll write a
list of my favorite uh cannabis Social
Clubs yeah Bloom room's another good one
you're looking for some exotic flower is
nice yeah yeah yeah it's just lalada
those guys love the concentrates out
there yeah they know concentrates really
well out there I haven't been to the new
DOA doa's got a spot out there like yeah
there's there's a couple new ones that I
haven't been to but uh Barcelona's just
such a great City and everything's very
convenient to get to dude you can walk
around everywhere you can uh you can
find a like so many good local weed
clubs because it's technically illegal
so you're just supposed to smoke in the
club so the the best although Barcelona
isn't as strict as other spots of Spain
but they're cracking down because a lot
compared act yeah well 10 years ago you
could you could roll a joint in your
restaurant of twice 10 years ago can't
do that anymore no what your goto toas
uh Vaso De Oro which I shouldn't be
telling people so then then it might
ruin it for everybody because it's so
good but Vaso De Oro C of Gold Cup of
Gold yes and they have really good beer
there but also nice toas um Pinchos is a
great is is a great spot for Tapas okay
okay uh but posadas Del pep is my
favorite place but there's there's so
many good say we'll spend a day bro
we'll just we'll get small by this is
one of the things I'm a grazer so I love
I love Barcelona I love b b because
they're graze friendly hon a bco a
little bit the pork gives me the wind
yeah so I'll definitely have a few
slices of it here and there but I can't
just I can't go crazy on it because then
all my compatriots would be mad at me
and my flirting opportunities would be
severely diminished right right
understood understood totally understood
but toas are amazing in Barcelona I did
go on a quest for the best Papas bravas
one time it seems there's so many
different ways yeah yeah there's so many
great barcel a good one I think your
producers going to stare at us cuz we're
just going to start we're talking about
food and travel again like hey this is a
weed show you guys I know we're not
we're not but now now here's how we
switch it up when I'm high I lovea
which is one of my favorite things which
is octopus octopus yeah with the
potatoes and the olive oil and the
paprika and it's when it's done right it
is absolutely amazing uh I I don't
always eat the octopus because I feel
bad because I feel like we should be
learning from them more than we should
be eating them you watch the octopus
teacher no even before then oh really
even before then they're clearly they're
intelligent sentient beings right
clearly clearly so we're just kind of
being not cows are not intelligent
sentient beings as well no and like so I
have this relationship with alpaca I
worked on a farm we we had a farm up in
Lake County worked on there and they had
alpacas there was six of them and I had
a relationship with them they would know
when I was coming they would come greet
me they would give me hugs they
literally put their neck on my head one
time my friend came and he saw this
these alpacas coming up to me giving me
hugs I'm talking to these alpacas like
we're friends and they're like looking
at me were communicating oh yeah totally
and I would go smoke weed with them they
had red eyes and I'm like man I hope my
red my eyes aren't this red but I bring
my friend and he's looking at this and
he gets all excited so he starts walking
towards him he gets spit on from six
directions he literally couldn't cover
his face fast enough from both sides bro
we don't really know you yeah they were
like who the are you can't just be
walking up on alpacas no yeah you got to
make friends yeah and alpacas are
amazing you know it's like that's my SP
and they're delicious no I'm kidding
I've never had one I've never had one
either but you know I saw on some
cooking shows I've seen them as like the
mystery basket where they get the alpaca
the alpaca you treat it like a lamb
right you slow roast it well you don't
have well you don't have time if it's if
it's like you make it like a alpaca all
but but I feel like alpaca's a little
leaner than camel well I don't know I
don't know I've made camel tacos before
like
literally I haven't eaten your taco
that's not an inside joke but I've also
had well we might be talking about two
different camel Tacos yeah but Moose
Knuckles camel tacos camel toe Taco is
one of my favorite treats it's a
delicacy it's not an acquired taste
right so I liked them from the beginning
and we band and we're band what what
what I can't have a succulent Chinese
moose knuckles like you going to pickle
them with your Scandinavian we pickle
moose
knuckles it's reindeer and moose
knuckles dude like Scandinavian deler
and moose knuckles this sounds like a
private ey show coming to Fox it's gonna
be on tub next week yeah it's a it's an
autistic deer who knows a lot and a lady
in tight pants reindeer and moose
knuckles this fall on tuby dude
we can go any Direction with that oh
everywhere you want everywhere you want
yeah so where do you see the world going
with
cannabis I personally would like to have
it where I can buy Moroccan hash the
same way I buy French wine you know what
I mean right if I if I want a Spanish
Haze and a Moroccan hash for my local
spot yeah it you should be able to do
that I should be able to get New York
Diesel from New York or whatever they're
growing in Maine and Vermont right now
I'm all about as long as no child labor
violations happen yeah you oh yeah you
got to be careful with that but yeah
Charis all that stuff but you know that
Charis the best chars comes from the the
tender hands right I have a bit in my
ACT where I talk about the best hash of
course made from the thighs of the
virgins after they run naked through the
Cannabis Fields three days before the
Harvest but it's hard to find a virgin
out here yeah but um so I I would like
that to happen and and you see you see
it getting closer right Canada's legal
Germany's legal Switzerland will
probably be legal in the next few years
if you can buy Heineken you better be
able to buy weed from everywhere just
the same way in Switzerland you can buy
hemp you can buy High CBD hemp in the
liquor store already like it's up to 1%
THC so it will have an effect on you it
will have a it will we we we in the
beginning people used to say CBD is not
psychoactive which is not true it is
psychoactive but it's not psychoactive
the way that THC is cyle no it does pass
the blood brain barrier so in that
regard yeah sure definitely has side
effects that are very
psychedelic no no
psychoactive yeah and sometimes which is
different than being an active psycho
yeah it's much better than being an
active psycho which there's plenty of
those an active psycho on psychoactives
never turn your back on a drug I don't
double negatives you never know you
never know they could be hella smooth
yeah it might correct you might correct
things right exactly so yeah we live in
this strange time it's a beautiful time
but it's still a strange time but I
think it's always been a strange time
right I'm sure as far back every day is
a strange day but it's a little stranger
than it usually is yeah I mean long
right there's a lot of people who want
to be Emperor yeah you know this is why
you shouldn't always teach the classics
these guys want to be Alexander the
Great yeah anyway yeah well we live in
an age where there's so much information
it can be For Better or For Worse you
have to be able to discern for yourself
and you have to make good choices yeah
well I didn't talk about why I'm not not
smoking today but I had surgery last
week and so they gave me a gum graph oh
at that age they've been telling me I
need a gum graph for 20 years finally
finally got one congratulations yeah so
now I can't smoke though and it was for
how much longer H probably two more days
how many Edibles are
you you know that's how it goes you can
I can eat some edibles Rosen gummies I
love Ros and gummies um so it's not that
you're not utilizing
the medical benefits of THC you're not
smoking yeah and I drink this coffee
it's amazing it's mushroom that got the
mushrooms in there are they a sponsor no
they're not maybe they should be you
should talk about them I love yeah well
you know I'm all hyped up so but uh rise
I'm on Rise and Edibles yeah I mean
seriously you canb that with THC if you
pour a little Moon Shine or I was going
to say if you pour a little uh Moon if
you pour a little corn liquor yeah into
that coffee then it's rise and shine
rise and shine yeah it took so long to
get that that would have been so much
funnier orange sunshine orange Sunshine
In Your Shine wow Rise and Shine for
those of you that know what we're
talking about right good morning star
shine yeah the Earth says
hello yeah yeah it's like getting a nice
warm hug from your ancestors something
like that yeah well you know that's but
not in the scary way no no and that's
what Johnny said about white Thorn Rose
it's like getting a nice warm hug from
your ancestors I love that saying I
think it's great that's so funny I
showed
somebody years later a friend of mine
had gone to uh humbled State yeah and I
got a really good bag of train wreck
from a homie and so I hand her the bag
she opened she's like yeah smells like
college
nice yeah remember when trade W first
started because yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah
train wreck and we had BC Bud too so we
had the orang
crush so much but everywhere yeah Orange
Crush uh to name some of them
Juicy Fruit yeah it all blurs together
but there's the Trinity that was one of
my favorites that was the Trinity
Trinity it was strong that stuff was so
strong it would hit you it would hit you
it would punch you in the face yeah
that's before a n9b hammer or whatever
yeah did you
ever a lot of Jagger Meister out of
Oregon that was like mid 2000s though
were mids too like I no no don't I never
got excited about I think I got it on at
late so I tried it dog from Oregon
was great you had to you had to go up
there yeah and find your homie who
actually couldn't just cuz I I can agree
that sometimes you get it down here or
whatever you see it somewhere else
you're like what this isn't the it's
kind of like dream is hated I'm sure
there's Jagger you got to get the right
one you get somebody put put a bunch of
love into it it's probably gonna be
amazing or they just called it Jagger
yeah you know that's still still that
danger or you had green B on a little
while agoing from up there right he is
he's from Eugene and his flower is next
level he's he's a Monster yeah so good
the effect from his flower is so special
kind he
left I do at the house I do it the house
yeah I'll follow you right yeah come
back I wish I could man I have so much
to do we'll just get you on every day
yeah uh fine my rates are very
reasonable nice you have to pay me a lot
of weed though cuz now I got to go sell
it
Ser yeah whenever in the magazine people
always like we want to buy an AB can we
pay you a weed I was like no you give me
an extra job like the day I could go to
the printer and be like let me give you
five pounds you run 30,000 copies this a
day you could give me a quarter pound
absolutely right yeah quarter pounds AR
worth it with they used to be either but
now I got to like you know I got to turn
around and sell just make the money like
I can't I can't pay him weed they take
cash hugs and smiles don't cut it
anymore yeah no as much as I like a
handshake and a pat on the ass yeah I
can't I can't appla you can't go to your
landlord like we really like living here
thank you so much yeah totally so but
yeah so if you had one piece of advice
for your younger self take a marketing
class oh yeah I love it it's all
marketing these days right uh that's I
mean at least in comedy too because you
you know everybody also take a video
editing class apparently because I just
thought I was going to be a comic I
didn't know I had to be like a video
editor and a sound mixer and a a master
marketer and all the stuff but that's a
lot of what it comes down to uh in a lot
of ways I mean it's always been that a
little bit but even more and more now
and especially now
because everybody's just expected to do
all those things social media is like a
whole another job and so now you have to
be a social media person you're also a
stand up comedian you also got to write
things and you also have to be uh a a a
Content not when I say content creator
but you have to be a production facility
yeah
right so those are the things yeah
that's what I would say so what do you
have planned for the future for yourself
uh Tranquility inner peace yeah uh
profitability yeah all those things I'm
going to be like I said I see you in
Barcelona for the international Canabis
business conference I'll be at the New
Mexico Growers Cup in mid-march that's
why I got to come back from Spain yeah
that's like the 22nd in
Albuquerque uh we're working on some
things in the desert hot springs I'll be
at the Missouri Growers cup I'll be at
the Oregon Growers cup I don't think
they're doing an emerald Cup this year
so I probably won't be there but I'll be
has that been canceled officially
because I thought they had a five they
had a fiveyear contract in Oakland so I
believe last I heard yeah but it's been
months since I talked to those guys so I
have to send some emails but last I
heard they they weren't going to do
another one we're getting Tim on the
show it's hard it's hard not to do those
because they are so much fun I love
Emeral cup you know what to me the
emerald cup is the one that really I
think takes time to celebrate the plant
itself and not just partying well the
the problem with an emerald cup is it's
supposed to be the Harvest Cup right
it's it's the Harvest cup that happens
after outdoor is done where you can
share your outdoor with everybody else
CU I grow outdoor in my backyard so I
love bringing de fres outdoor to show
every yeah yeah and everybody gets
together to start trading seeds and
getting together for for March or for
April when they're going to PL well all
the stress is gone for the year pretty
much hopefully right right before you
all leave for Thailand yeah
exactly guy who drives the truck just
got back from La it was a good week you
grew the right things that purple hay
diesel is crushing it right now
totally so if people are trying to find
more about you yeah just come to the
house in Sacramento South South thas ask
around they know right uh I'm on all the
most of the social things right um Blue
Sky NG a IO
420420 Instagram 420 puff puff passport
yeah on Instagram too CU if you if you
put in NG AO belum they will probably
take you to puff puff passport because
I'm lightly shadowbanned but if you go
to NG AO 420 I'll pop right up and I'm
going to start posting more stuff on the
puff off passport um yeah that's it Blue
Sky Facebook you can follow me on
Facebook yeah Instagram I lurk on
Snapchat so you can find me on Snapchat
as well I'm not on the Tumblr do people
still do Tumblr I don't know I'm not on
that I don't know I'm not on that I was
on Tik Tok or Tumbl those you know never
once I mean I have accounts but I never
really enjoyed either one of those out
no I've never been on Tik Tok Tik Tok
does not like weed so why would I hang
out with those guys exactly and they
make it so hard I'm not one of those
guys dude I came up here to talk about
weed they you can't you know I'm I'm not
really trying to put broccoli in my
grinder wink wink nudge nudge I'm not
trying to spell it o UI apostrophe D
like I come from back in the activist
days where you stood up for it but it's
so harder now because back then just
stand up for weed and they can't really
kick me off my job I'm
selfemployed so I can do what I want
right but now I got to rely on this
Instagram to get my word out to do my
marketing right and there's censorship
heavy censorship for us I can't even
just like you can't tell anybody where
to get it you can't tell them what it is
like I can sometime if I post a stupid
if I post a weed meme yeah then they
don't care they think that's hilarious
they'll spread it around everybody but
if I post some like this is beta
corh and it's found in these sort of
strains here's a picture of a plant blah
blah blah they're like hey hey hey hey
hey education goes against our
guidelines well Mark Zuckerberg claims
that he's going to stop the sensorship
or reduce the censorship only you know
censoring really bad stuff we'll see
what happens with that well I think what
he's talking about is political ideas
which we don't have time because been
here two hours already is he's going to
try to stop people censoring that which
is a whole different set of
disinformation but them restricting the
flow of cannabis education I think will
continue because it's I wish it didn't
well of course not and it shouldn't it
shouldn't be a thing people come to my
you come to Uno 420 because you want to
see weed and weed related I'm like the
Hank Hill of cannabis I I mean I don't
sell weed and weed related accessories
but you've come to learn about cannabis
or to hang out on in the Cannabis
culture so not being able to do that is
a drag go to my patreon patreon Ino 420
then we can talk more about it and it's
only like a book yeah though get into it
I'll be there I will see you there
absolutely thanks again man man thank
you so much for coming feels better
thank you very much we'll see you next
week Absolutely I'll see you next week
we'll do this all over
again thank
you oh man what a great episode don't
forget to like And subscribe click down
below