[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James OD podcast
and today our special guest is relle
Gordon relle the writer how are you
doing today I'm awesome James how are
you doing I'm doing fantastic so I feel
like our roles of reverse today because
I feel like you've interviewed me a
couple times and I feel like I get to
interview you today and this is great
I'm really excited I love when the
tables are turned yeah yeah so we've
both been in the industry for a while a
good amount of time and doing all kinds
of fun stuff you have really done
amazing work writing uh you know
highlighting some of the most important
people in the industry yeah it's it's
been amazing it's been a huge blessing
to be honest with you to be able to
share the stories of the people who
built this industry and who are
pioneering in this space I mean it's
really really humbling to have people
who are willing to open up to me and and
share and let me amplify their message
it's awesome yeah and I mean there's
some writers that have big Egos and I
feel you're not one of them so I I love
that about you I think you do a great
job with your
articles um yeah it's amazing stuff no I
appreciate that I try really really hard
uh to stay humble because I come from
humble beginnings right and so and
honestly like this is not about me this
is about you and the community right
it's it's a team effort so yeah and you
know writing so writing a breeding book
I got my uh hands dirty or my feet wet
writing a book took me five years but I
learned I think by the end of the book I
really learned how to take my ego out of
it and try to write the book for people
I don't know that I got everything right
there's stuff that I definitely got
wrong but I did the best I could and I
there it was a contribution of more than
20 people's work and a lot of fun and
yeah I I am glad that I did it and it's
done and I don't have to do it again
it's a lot more work I think Than People
realize I have a lot of people coming to
me like oh I want to maybe write a book
or whatever and I say it's not just
about typing right it's really about
putting passion and knowledge and then
you have to Market it and like edit it
and there's just so much that goes into
it so five years is quite a journey um
but I'm super stoked for you that you
got it across the Finish Line I know you
gave me a copy uh at weed week I loved
it and I was actually at the hydro store
down the road right before I came here
and I saw a bunch of copies of your book
sitting out on the counter I was like
sick this a full circle moment yeah it's
it's great and you know I've written
articles and I you know I had I've
gotten my hands dirty with articles
before I written for a bunch of
Publications and I think I've written
some good stuff but it's it's really
about
inserting uh something special in each
article to really highlight the the
person or what you're writing about and
you know and and also just not writing
to write I think that's another thing
totally it's kind of for me like doing a
puzzle right like I listen to the
person's story and I'll look for that
narrative and that Arc and then I'll
pull the quotes and I'll put it all
together how did you do it when you were
writing articles like did you follow
that same formula or what was your
process you know I I reverse engineer
everything in my life right that's just
how I do stuff and so I start with a
bunch of uh bullet points and then I
start trying to fill in the bullet
points that's what I did with the book
too like that's just I did it in the
same way that I I read an article when I
tried to tackle the book in the
beginning and I wrote five versions of
the book before it was done like
literally I scratched the first version
completely um well I wouldn't say
completely I had a you know obviously
there was knowledge in my head that was
put back on the paper but like what was
written 30,000 words the the book is
115,000 words total and so the first
30,000 I believe it was close to 30 got
scrapped and so we had to redo it and
that's when I thought I knew how to
write a good breeding book and I thought
I knew what I was doing and I had no
idea especially once I read it and I was
like this is not worth putting out to
the world cuz at the end of the day
writing is an art I think that there's
the art behind it and I also feel like
uh when you have something that's art
all you can do is the best you can do
then you got to put it out to the world
and the world judges it and the world
accepts it and appreciates it and it's
one of those things and that's what I
love about books that's what I love
about articles and articles it's almost
more subtle because you're writing about
somebody else and so you're having to
figure out how to highlight that person
the best way
possible um and you know and there's so
many angles to that how do you do it
honestly it's a lot of pressure
especially when I really like and
respect the person that I'm writing
about because I so desperately want to
get it right and try to do right by them
and amplify them in the way that they
want to be heard right and I've actually
been really really fortunate that I've
been able to successfully write articles
that people really love I've never
really had much push back or you
misquoted me or anything like that cuz
I've heard horror stories from other
writers who you know they put out
something and then their subject was
upset about how they came off or how
they were presented and oh that's
happened to me before too for sure yeah
it's I I'm just like so grateful but the
pressure is is difficult and it gives me
anxiety sometimes like I'll avoid
writing the actual article because I put
so much pressure on myself but what I
try to do is just speak from the heart
that's always what I do and I feel like
if I can do that and capture someone's
Essence their truth will come through
yeah authenticity is so important
totally and capturing authenticity is
even harder yeah right and that's I I
think people just don't get how hard it
is to actually CCH capture authenticity
because that's just it's like one thing
telling a story and then capturing the
authentic side of it and that just it
speaks so highly of these authors that
do it I mean some of them have big egos
too that do good job you know but like
and there are some really good writers
out there you know we're we're in a
special time because we've we've kind of
gone away from print not completely
because we're still doing print and
you're you're doing print you're doing
online digital stuff you're doing a
little bit of everything but we've gone
into like this Mass Spectrum of
different forms of media you know social
media we have magazines still we have
digital magazines there's just so many
different versions of stuff that you can
read and get information from yeah and
that's been a really interesting
evolution especially with social media
as a journalist especially working um in
print it's kind of a Dying art in a way
but there's still something really
special and magical about having a print
copy I mean I'm sure when you got your
book for the first time you know a
special feeling yeah exactly and so I
love being able to give that gift to
people I actually we did a special
insert for 420 uh we distributed it to a
bunch of dispensaries and then it was in
the Sunday edition of the San Francisco
Chronicle it went out all across San
Francisco and a couple of the stories
that were in there I didn't tell the
people that were the subjects that it
would be there and then they were
surprised like wow I'm in the chronicle
this legendary newspaper it was a really
cool gift to give to them yeah that's
awesome yeah it's really special yeah
totally um how did you get your start in
writing in cannabis in cannabis writing
I guess let's take it back did you start
writing in high school and you start
with journals and then writing in school
or how did it go well it's interesting I
always had a passion for writing when I
was young I would write a lot of poetry
and short stories and I would Journal a
lot but I never really thought about
writing as a career in fact I actually
studied early childhood education and
social justice and I was working as a
teacher wow for many many years and I
actually ended up getting arrested not
at school after school uh with some
weight and uh lost my career and I was
able to get into a drug court uh
scenario to fight my felony charges you
know because my addiction caused my
crime right um and was able to get
through that wasn't a felon thank god um
but I lost my career I didn't know what
I was going to do and I ended up writing
um on the side is more of a side hustle
I was Finding gigs doing freelance stuff
mostly sustainability education that
kind of stuff and then I got out of drug
court and the legal industry started
happening around the country and I
started finding G
in that and then a lot of right place
right time sort of stuff and now I'm
running a cannabis website owned by the
San Francisco Chronicle so it's been a
really interesting Evolution and I often
joke that if I hadn't gotten busted I
wouldn't be where I am today so yeah you
know I reflect on a lot of that stuff uh
as I'm getting older like stuff that
seems to be so bad in the moment
actually if you just breathe and you
just kind of move past it and you just
put one foot in front of the other uh uh
they can be life-changing things that
were meant to happen for a specific
reason right exactly it's really
interesting I do believe that everything
happens the way it's supposed to happen
Y and that the Universe puts you where
you need to be um and so yeah at the
time I was really pissed and you know
sad and whatever that this thing
happened to me but it worked out for the
best honestly at the end of the day
totally and you could be an equity
partner in Oakland yeah right
exactly so yeah so and then you go to a
lot of events so many events like all of
the events um and all of the events I
swear you go to all the events like I
used to go to a lot of events and then I
look on Instagram I I see you on
Instagram a lot and you're at all the
events like literally all the in in fact
I don't even know how you do it
sometimes how you got to spannabis and
you were in
California uh I can't remember the event
that you at like two days before span
Abus and then you jump over to Spain and
you're just you know jet setting yeah
it's a cool lifestyle it's exhausting
but it's really fun and I again never
thought that would happen and I've been
able to go all over the world um writing
about weed and meeting people and It's a
Grind for sure and people often laugh
they're like wow you know we don't
understand how you do it how you are
alive and breathing and putting out
articles like someone was commenting
about I was at mjbiz last year and I've
been going hard all week as one does and
it was literally Friday I'm in the Press
booth and it's a big glass kind of box
on the show floor and I'm writing an
article that I have to file immediately
and people are just like are you serious
right now how do you do it and I guess
I'm just blessed to have a brain that
can compartmentalize and function and
grind because I've always uh had that
kind of Scrappy Hustler sort of nature
even as a kid and so I guess I just keep
going I do break down once in a great
while where I'm like it's too much right
uh but for the most part I just put it
into perspective and think about what a
blessing it is to have this life and to
be able to tell the story and to share
this information with people who so
desperately need it because that's
actually my real passion James is the
ability to advocate for the plant and be
a steward of the plant and inform people
who may not even realize what this plant
could do for them or their families I
remember one of the very first events I
ever did I met a woman and she had a
daughter who was born with an incredibly
rare uh condition and she was only
supposed to have a life expectancy of
one-year-old and they started treating
her with CBD oil and she was four years
old at the time is this Hazel um Yes
actually yes um awesome story super
awesome and I was crying you know and I
couldn't believe it and sharing that
story you know meant so much to me and
it made me really realize that this was
what I was meant to do my dad had
epilepsy growing up and he was not
treatable and he went in for for a
surgery to get his brain corrected and
he had a massive stroke and was
paralyzed um never walked again he had
severe brain damage he was like a
nursing homes my whole life he passed
away in 2020 long-term complications
from his stroke knowing what we know now
about epilepsy and cannabis I have no
doubt that the plant could have maybe
saved his life and we never got the
chance to try it because we didn't know
any better now we do and that's why I
just keep advocating telling those
stories telling Hazel story everyone you
know yeah because people need to know
what this plant can do education exactly
and awareness I think education and
awareness are slightly different yeah
and I think people just need to be aware
because I feel like there's still this
stigma with the older generation that
cannabis is bad or cannabis is that you
know the flower is drugs and I think
even with this schedule three thing now
people are like well the stuff they're
smoking that's not that's not a that's
not a medical drug that's a that's a
drug people are using that just to get
high and that's not the case
unfortunately yeah I mean I think that's
a big part of it too and I will never
stop sharing and advocating for the
plant and people can do with the
information what they want to do with it
but they can at least have it I remember
when I first got into this I had an aunt
who was like you're obsessed with
marijuana your career is never going to
go anywhere like you know whatever
you're ashamed of the family and
literally two years later she's like hey
I have a friend who says she feels 20
years younger on this CBD oil you're in
that space aren't you can you can you
get me some and I was like sometimes
that's just what it takes it's a
personal connection or something to
click and that's why I just won't stop
yeah sanj Gupta wrote the 60-minute
article and that changed my parents
lives for as far as cannabis is
concerned and and CBD the second you can
put kids in front of people and go how
do you have a right to judge a parent
for giving a kid something that could
make their lives better judge a parent
or a kid you know and how could you take
that away from parents or it's just
we're in a silly time where people are
still like not getting it fully uh but
things are changing you know I mean even
with the schedule 3 is bad as it is it's
good in a lot of other ways I mean
there's there's the good and the bad
with it for sure yeah I think for a lot
of mainstream folks they see that and
the government for the first time is
admitting that there is medicinal
benefit to the plant and so if the
government can admit that I think that
will be a spark for a lot of people
those of us in the industry we kind of
know the nuances with rescheduling
versus Des scheduling and what we would
prefer but I think if that's what it
takes you have to meet people on their
level that's what it comes down to
really mhm yeah agreed yeah it's
interesting I mean our government had
patents on cannabis years and years and
years ago in the
70s so it's it's it's time that we make
change I think there's so many people
that are on board with it I mean there's
so many Advocates uh we just Lo lost a
good friend Dave damit rest in peace
we're gonna have his seeds available on
my website uh I'm germinating seeds
we're going to be doing some pheno
hunting with his genetics he has
something really special he's Blue 13 oh
wow and I don't know if you you've had
white Thorn Rose I would assume and you
know the way white Thorn Rose makes you
feel yeah the Blue 13 does the same
thing really it has the it so I I feel
like and I was talking to someone at his
memorial uh his what do they call it now
it's a celebration of life celebration
of life and you know we've changed it
but yeah and it was a celebration of
life it was amazing but I got to meet
one of his friends and she's a ganier
and she's probably the only person in
the whole world that's tried both of the
the Blue 13 and the white Thorn Rose and
we both looked at each other crazy when
we were like they have the same effect
wow right and then she kind of validated
the fact that I was thinking it and I'm
now I know I'm not crazy and she knows
she's not crazy and so now we're like
well we need to research this stuff so
we're going to be doing some tests on it
and they've already been doing tests on
the White thron Rose y so and it comes
down to a specific turp in it's very
unique and I can't think of the name of
it we'll post it on the podcast but uh
yeah really really cool and uh it just
makes you feel really special but Dave
he was a huge advocate he was a great
person he's gonna be missed you know I
think of him every day still I look at
his seeds and I'm like okay how can we
do justice to Dave with his seeds and do
something special for his family so
we're going to sell his seeds on my
website uh and raise money for his kids
and he his older kids but they're still
kids um yeah great kids that's so
beautiful that you can do that and use
the plant in the way that I'm sure he
would have wanted you know uh and keep
his legacy alive you know he was such a
great guy and I mentioned this I know we
did the tribute episode and you featured
my clip which I appreciate but yeah I
mean canacon was one of the very first
events I ever did and he put his hand
out to me and he encouraged me even on
social media he'd watch my journey and
he was always just so positive and
encouraging and I mean I really give him
a lot of credit for helping me to step
into this industry into this role that
I'm in and I can't wait to grow his
seeds and and to smoke that because it
sounds amazing yeah yeah it's special
and I want to share it with everybody
and I think he would have loved that he
would have loved to hear that he was
just such a genuine person yeah and yeah
I just I miss him a lot um it's funny
because you go through different phas
phases of grief when somebody passes
yeah and like I miss him more now for
what ever reason I feel it more like
when it first when you're processing the
whole thing it's difficult but then it's
like after he's gone it's it's it's just
grief is a weird thing it is and then it
triggers you in like unexpected sort of
ways right you know something will
remind you of him or something more
visceral like smoking a certain strain
right could like send you back to that
strain and so yeah it's just it's
interesting how that works I get that
with my dad all the time you know little
things that remind me of him and totally
I lost my dog last year that was a big
one it's been almost a year that that's
that was the toughest thing I had to go
through yeah no it's it's that's really
hard pets pets should live forever yeah
it's it's sad they should well I I
wouldn't want them to outlive me though
that's the thing so I feel like at least
I got to give my dog the life you know
the best life possible totally Yeah we
actually my fiance as you know uh grows
hemp and he actually makes CBD dog
treats yeah really cool yeah um the
doggy dreams and they help so many
animals and it's really really cool to
see actually just lost his dog Lucy um
she was a great great girl and it's been
really hard for him to continue with the
dog treats because he's so emotional
they remind him so much of Lucy and I'm
like man there's so many other animals
out there who could use this medicine
and we see how it works you know dogs
who have joint pain and epilepsy and all
these different things separation
anxiety is huge right and so I'm like we
have to keep going in her name yeah you
know no matter how hard it is there's a
lot of work to be done yeah for Dave for
the people that have passed I mean yeah
I mean breeder too there's so many so
many people that have passed yeah and I
think it's really cool what you do you
know and that you really want to keep
their memory alive through the plant and
through the genetics um I think that's a
really really unique way to honor
someone especially in this community I
think it's our responsibility totally
you know I think that's one of the
respon you know growing up you have lots
of responsibilities this is just another
one is being a steward to a plant and
being part of a community that's so much
bigger than yourself MH and that's what
I love about the plant yeah that's
Absolut I mean the plant brings us
together like we're here together
today uh that's the beauty of this plant
is like it can bring amazing people
together that wouldn't normally
associate with one another but this
plant is so special and it brings people
together for good reasons for
benefiting not only the community but
benefiting the planet and other people
yeah absolutely and I think that's one
of the things that I really like about
you James is that we're very similar in
that sort of way you know I don't see an
ounce of ego on you you understand that
this is bigger than us and I feel the
exact same way and I've always felt that
way um and just knowing what you want to
do for the people and the plant and like
your passion it's just so inspiring and
I've always just loved that energy about
you because I could always feel it you
know I don't know if you remember this
but uh there was that MJ Biz where we
were we were both at some party I think
it was maybe at the MGM and you remember
this the
uh I do so for those uh listening
basically we were sitting outside on
this patio and I was adjusting some
stuff in my bag and I pulled out my puff
Co I didn't even have it turned on and
the security guard who was standing
there saw it and bounced me from the
party like do not pass go do not collect
$200 like walked my ass right to the
elevator like we don't tolerate that in
here and I went downstairs I was by
myself I was like okay now what and then
you came down and you were like man
screw those guys like come hang out with
us for a while and we just went and had
a great time and it was BS it was such
BS but it was so nice of you to like
have my back and just be like no it's
cool like roll with us for a while like
we'll have some fun it'll be great and
it was it was really special and I was
like Wow James is such a nice guy he
looks out for me yeah I mean we're all
part of a group you know and we're part
of a special group part of the community
that you know I feel like there's
different clicks within the groups uh
and you know and some of them are egos I
used to have a lot more ego than I do
now and I think with age that changes
too yeah I suppose age and experience
yeah but also I mean I just like having
a good time and I like my friends to
have a good time and I just I think it's
just a lot of fun like living is a lot
of fun yeah it certainly can be and I
love that it's like it's really really
easy to get dragged down by everything
that's going on the stress just existing
in this world is hard it's it's really
hard but there are joyful moments too
and it's a blessing to have this life
and we should be celebrating it and
living life to its fullest because not
everyone has that opportunity I think
about that with my dad all the time it's
like he was in a wheelchair for the last
third of his life you know and being
able to go out and take him to like
concerts or something where he could
just feel free for like a couple hours
was just so he still had blessings he
still had amazing things going on in his
life even though I mean we all do and
and you know it's like you gota you know
I reflect a lot on on everything that's
going on uh you know I meditate and I
reflect and I think about what's going
on and what went on and you know it's
really interesting we just got to count
our blessing because you never know how
long you have uh and all you really have
is the moment you have right now and
there's so much to be grateful for
totally you know trying to live in
gratitude is just it's difficult to do
and trying to live in the moment it's
it's easy to talk about but it's really
difficult to do yeah it is and it's
interesting that you bring that up like
I've studied Buddhism quite a bit and it
just makes so much sense in a practical
sort of manner and I was at a Dharma
talk one time uh maybe 10 15 years ago
and when I was younger I was a lot more
not aggressive but angry right I had a
lot of pain in my heart and I had a
really hard childhood and I was
resentful right I had a chip on my
shoulder and I was listening to the
gentleman do the Dharma talk and he was
talking about when you wake up in the
morning and you go out and you face the
world what emotion are you leading with
yeah you know is it sadness is it Joy is
it and I was like wow I've been facing
the rule of anger my entire life and
that changes right now and I decided to
just switch it up and have an attitude
of gratitude and all of a sudden my
whole world changed and it was a really
beautiful thing it sounds like that was
maybe your experience a little bit too
for sure I think you know and we go
through trauma everybody you know we go
through you know we go through so much
growing up and from childhood and
becoming an adult much different than it
is
today I guess it's not all that
different it's still it's it's changed
but it's not all that different it's
difficult no matter how you look at it
whether it's today whether it's our
generation our parents generation it's
all a difficult thing uh you know and
there are you know we all experience
trauma in one form or another Y and so
moving beyond the trauma and being able
to recognize that it's trauma and not
letting it affect you negatively that's
something that uh you know it's not easy
to do and I'm I'm grateful that I can do
that and I can look at the world from a
different perspective totally what are
some of those moments for you I'm gonna
we're gonna switch the script now I I
want ask interiew you now um this feels
very familiar yeah what are some of
those moments for you when you really
are like wow this makes everything worth
it this is what my calling is what are
some of those moments for you cold
plunging that's everyone on the show is
like yeah but I talk about cold plunging
a lot but I
think I mean those are the when I do
cold plunging yeah it makes me relax and
makes me feel grateful for everything
but you know I had milestones in my life
right so like there's been Milestones
winning our first Cannabis Cup in 2012
was a big one uh my publishing my book
graduating from culinary school I
graduated top of my class out of a lot
of
students um and you know we've these
milestones and I'm just grateful for the
little things though but those are the
big things it's like the little things
like I got up at 5:30 this morning and
or I got up at this morning it was 4:40
but I went to the gym I was in the gym
by
529 and so like that's a big deal the
sun was just coming up and it's like I
want to try to do that and and like
these are like non-negotiable deals that
I set with myself I'm like okay I'm
going to do this right now and I'm going
to change the way I am and change the
you know and those things I can reflect
on and be super grateful yeah but uh you
know it's like eating good food I I
enjoy food everybody knows I I post a
lot of good food I'm a big guy I love
food I I love
not just the food and the way it tastes
and the the differences with texture and
the sweet and the sour and the Savory
and the different flavors just like
cannabis with the with the flavors but I
love the social aspect of food and going
out with my friends and hanging out and
having a good time and knowing that that
experience is only going to happen once
and we might have another experience
together but it's not going to be that
same experience yeah and that's really
really special and it's really cool that
you recognize that you know every single
meal and every time you can break bread
with your friends and family it's a
blessing for sure and yeah I definitely
see a lot of great food on your on your
page I'm like oh I don't know where he
is but I want some of that yeah I eat a
lot of good food and I cook a lot of
good food now I'm like focused on I'm
gonna for the for the next couple months
I'm really focusing on this facility but
also cooking right and so we have a
kitchen here we're going to have the
outdoor kitchen but so I'll be cooking
for people here it'll be nice but also
for myself and I enjoy cooking I don't
enjoy doing it for a living as much
happy that I don't have to do that in
some ways but there is some you know
there is something special about making
food and then giving it to somebody and
they're like wow that's amazing yeah
that's that must be really special and
unique like I'm curious though it's the
same thing with weed though when you're
like this is my [__] and then they you
give it to them and they're like whoa
this is freaking phenomenal or oh dude
this sucks yeah I don't I don't get that
very much with either one I assume I
would assume not yeah but but yeah I
mean I think just the reaction but at
the same time you you know it's like
other people have opinions on stuff and
you at the end of the day know what
you've done and you know you can't worry
about other people's opinions too much
either and you know you the thing is is
like if you're just trying to please
other people that's not a great way to
live either you really need to please
yourself and I think that's the most
important thing is figuring out how to
make yourself happy and that's the only
way you can really make other people
happy totally I would agree with that
and that's something that I've actually
been working really hard on because I'm
such a huge people pleaser yeah that
like it's difficult because especially
in journalism it's like oh well I want
to you know do write by my friends I
want to amplify them I want them to like
this piece I want to do whatever I can
for them but it's like you can't play
favorites either you know and you can't
just do stuff to do stuff there's
journalism ethics right and so that's a
fine line for me and not overextending
myself to and over promising because
sometimes I get in my head I get anxious
like oh wait like do they actually want
to hang out and talk to me or do they
just want me to write about them and I
have that weird internal dialogue
sometimes and I'm like no it's cool like
you're you're a good person tot don't
sweat it yeah and there's a lot of good
people in our industry you know I think
some are mostly good yeah I would I
would say mostly yeah for sure there's
definitely more good than bad honest
like and when you surround yourself and
you with good people and you get what
you put out in the universe mhm right
and I feel like you must really
recognize that as well because you
emanate such joy and such passion so I
bet you get a lot of that back for sure
and you know whatever you put into
something you get out of it too so like
relationships are the same way totally
yeah yeah and so what's your favorite
strain right now as far as I get we're
calling it strain on the show guys
because uh that's just what most people
call it correct or incorrect cultivar
whatever you want to call Variety it's
okay strand call
see know that's the one that drives me
nuts is strand when I hear people say
strand I kind of cringe wonder strin I
just it's so commonly accepted yeah uh
even though it's incorrect yeah cultivar
this
cross are correct I've been saying
variety a lot lately but anyways to your
question it's a tough one I've actually
been smoking a lot more High CBD strains
yeah lately which has been awesome H the
sapphire Sue from moonmaid Farm is
awesome um my fiance grew this sour jet
fuel High CBD strain which has been
great um I also have been really
enjoying um this goua from snow till I
have not tried that but you're the
second person that told me about it so
really yeah yeah it's I don't know it's
just it's very cerebral it's very mellow
uh we also grew a bunch of super high
life from ated Rosenthal and Humbolt
Seed Company um and that's been really
great I've also been enjoying the um uh
snow Dream from a golden state that
one's really good but yeah the sapphire
Sue I just keep going back to that
because I can actually smoke it all
throughout the day and it's not overly
heady like the CBD is very balancing and
I have to give a big shout out to the
CBD strains and the minor cannaboids I
feel like they don't get enough respect
in the market especially with everyone's
emphasis on high THC we both know that
that's BS but I mean that's you know
it's like oh if it's not 30 plus% 40%
it's like [__] and it's like no like
there's a lot of really really good hemp
and or just High CBD strains and I'm
actually judging the alternative
cannaboids category for Emerald cup
awesome and I specifically was like
please let me judge this category
because I want to amplify the power of
these minor cannaboids and show that
there can be some fire CBD out there
because I don't think it gets enough
respect in the market there some super
amazing stuff yeah we're going to be
doing some amazing stuff here like
that's just I mean that's one of my big
breeding goals is to bring a lot more
flavor into the high CBD varieties the
high ratio CBD varieties and some of the
CBG I think is super important I think
CVG medically is super important I love
CBG the
effects um I feel like it's special yeah
so and a lot of people have never even
experienced it they don't get it no they
don't and it's really popular um in
other states you know California is such
a bubble right but in other states where
they've kind of been forced into the
minor cannaboids if they can't get high
THC products and they're just
experimenting with other ones I think
that's been really really interesting to
see how in more prohibition States some
of these minor cannaboids are more
popular um what about the thcv have you
been trying that out at all I've tried
it over the years I haven't found a thcv
product that I really liked I love the
data and I love the concept of it I love
the theory of thcv I think it's like you
know interesting and I think it has a
lot of potential you know as a diet drug
and all these other things and the ones
I got it just didn't give me a great
great High okay in my experience nothing
that I would say was super special I
didn't feel super wiry from it like some
people
get um what's your opinion I have been
enjoying the thcv uh Kurt my fiance had
grown some double Durban uh which was
really good and I tried some from I
can't remember the name of it now but
when I was judging the women's K Awards
there was a high thcv strain from some
Sacramento producer that was good but I
also tried a a thcv dab at a party I
think it was Garden Society I think
because they do their thcv gummy and I
think they were r&amp; ding uh some oil yeah
and so I tried that at a party and
lately dabs and I like do not really get
along I can't really do a hot dab
anymore I just get too anxious but I did
the th CV dab and I was focused I was
clear I was talking to everybody at the
party no paranoia and I was like huh
maybe this is something for me yeah I I
think with those type of things it's all
about the
right product yeah and I haven't had
enough to say it's bad or it's because
it s like everything I've read about it
and everything I've heard about it is
it's amazing and I just haven't I've had
some CBD or not CBD thcv dabs that are
pure thcv and maybe it needs to be full
spec
right that's the other thing where it's
like mostly thcv just like how I like
CBG or I like CBG with
THC um same thing CBD I like them
Blended I think they they work really
well together yeah same I love a little
salad moment have you tried the uh the
pink boost goddess theer it's in my book
it's I have not tried the flower guys
but yeah totally yeah Dale Hunt helped
yeah did Pink c yeah it's it's awesome
yeah so yeah I haven't tried it yet but
I'm I'm looking forward to it I mean the
fact that they've gone and work they're
working on patents and I think they're
doing the right thing yeah the emerald
Spirit shout out to those guys they're
really crushing it and I really like the
farm cut too I think that's cool I know
that some people are like oh why would
you buy larhe weed but I like the idea
of like it kind of remaining intact like
for more Tarpin what do you think about
the farm
cut it's it's an interesting one um you
know so it's funny cuz Huckleberry Hill
Farms
gave me jars of their uh of their white
Thorn Rose and I love white Thorn Rose
yeah but I try to share it with some of
my friends and they're like dude this is
boof and I'm like dude you don't even
smoke they're like bro they give me the
bro and it's like dude you you know it's
it's funny because you know we talked on
my last podcast about how Instagram is
kind of ruined weed and that's the
perfect example it's like this the stuff
is amazing and and it's also subjective
because what amazing is is subjective to
the individual yeah but but that flower
is super special and is super good and
it does look like it's okay you know
it's outdoor and I I still like Outdoors
so I I don't mind and I like ugly weed
too so same I think about that with the
Canon country 26 yeah you know like it's
a little stemi it's you know it's very
very dark um it tests slow but that's
some very very special cannabis and it
gets you laid out for being 177% cuz
that aamine turp is so wild and and I
agree with you 100% that the market has
shifted in a in a not great way and
people don't even know what good
cannabis is I write about it all the
time it's like I really want to know
more about the consumer's psyche and how
they decided that weed was good or bad
and I always judge it when I'm at a
thing like Hall of flowers or whatever
and I see a package to me it's like the
crazier and brighter the packages the
worse the weed's going to be inside and
then the most basic package or like the
backpack weed and the ziplock like you
know that's going to be fire the Mason
jar the ziplock yeah yeah totally and
yeah know ugly weed has its place
totally yeah and someday when we have a
pre-roll brim that's just focused on
pre-rolls and you don't get to see the
weed people are going to love it you
know and I think when you can take away
that aspect of it and that's why rosin's
so great too because rosin really it's
like it's either good rosin or it's bad
rosin you're not looking I mean yeah
people look at the actually that's not
true people look at the Ros and they're
like oh it's not the right Tech this or
that the color's off the color's off
it's not light enough yeah but really at
the it's about the taste and the effect
totally right and at the end of the day
you know obviously we eat with our eyes
the phone eats first when we're you know
totally I say that all the time dude
it's so funny but like at the end of the
day it's all about flavor and effect
yeah that's how it should be yeah I
would agree I mean judging cannabis has
been very interesting when you're
looking at the appearance and and what
exactly are the the metrics like oh how
many of the tricomes are intact what's
the color right how's the trim job right
you know how can we rate cannabis on a
really objective scale to me the effect
is difficult because that's subjective
um you know something that feels really
great for me like that thcv dab maybe
wouldn't work out well for you so how do
you think we need to evolve as an
industry to be able to set those
standards like they maybe do in other
Industries like wine or whatever and
it's all about consumer trust and time
yeah I think uh you you build your
consumer trust from having good products
and you know people try them time you
know you you you have someone try the or
buy the product three times they're a
customer for life at least that's what
they say and so we're finding out that
with the seed sales over the last year
our website's been live for since
January of last year and the ones that
have bought over three are the ones that
keep buying for sure and so if you can
get them to try your product they like
it three times you're good to go and so
really getting people to try your
product again one time might not do it
two times might not do it but that third
time you're you're good and so exposure
getting your brand out there but also
having a consistent product which is I
it's a lot more difficult to do than
people think and the dispensary model
that we have right now I mean the the
infrastructure and the way we have it
set up isn't designed to store products
long term and so that needs to be fixed
we need Refrigeration we need
Refrigeration of the dispensaries we
need or not even not full Refrigeration
but we need to have cooler temps that
we're storing our flour at and people
don't get that and so you may have an
awesome product and it may go to a
dispensary and sit on the shelf for six
months and somebody buys it and it's in
La where it's hot or it's in the valley
even worse so the store gets 100 degrees
on some days your product's not going to
be good after two weeks we need to fix
those things we need to have all of the
all of the delivery vehicles should be
refrigerated all of the dispens should
have some form of cooler temp that
they're storing stuff in you know and
this is just my opinion but I feel like
the fresher you can get the product the
better but if you can't get it fresh you
better have good
storage right that's I think that's been
a big challenge in the marketplace and
that's why companies like Grove bags and
Bova are game changers yeah literally
it's like I love my Grove bags I love my
tur blocks and the thing is is like I
have so many friends that were just like
me that are like yeah right or I don't
believe it I even had somebody here the
other day that was like basically
calling BS and then he did the research
and he texted me this long text and was
like actually I take back everything I
said make sure you don't tell anybody I
said that and the thing is is the proof
isn't the pudding with this stuff it's
like um I've been against the cryocure
model yet I believe there is potential
for it K from triome technology is one
of my good friends uh he wrote an
article on it and he's done I think he
might even have a p P for it but I think
there's really big potential for it I
just haven't seen anything that's not
astronaut ice cream we got a some guys
coming on the show in a few episodes
from now and we're going to be doing
that their cryo here and we're going to
be testing it with flower harvested from
facilities and we're going to do the
smoke test and we're going to do the COA
test and so I've heard you know you hear
all the good stuff and on paper it's
like higher uh canabo higher tpin
and so does that translate to a better
smoke maybe maybe not so far no but I'm
I I try to keep an open mind with
everything because it's like technology
evolves so fast the second you say
no you get corrected a couple years down
the road because they figure it out like
we're we're smart people are smart
there's a lot of science involved with
this stuff there's a lot of people that
are using and and there's there's so
many people working on it now and with
the D scheduling or rescheduling
sorry uh we're going to have even more
people and more scientists working on
stuff so trying to figure out how to do
stuff
better uh I'm excited for the future I'm
always excited for everything but for
the future I'm super excited to see what
happens with the plan I think there's a
lot of people that are scared about
what's going to
happen but I'm excited to be honest as
you should be and I am too I'm excited
for what we don't know that we don't
know right and what we what we are going
to discover and I think it's really cool
that you are willing to see how the cryo
here works out even if you're uncertain
about it even if you're mildly skeptical
you have an open mind it's more than
mild it's more than mild I just don't
believe it but that doesn't mean that
I'm right and I'm I'm one of those
people who I'm okay with being wrong I'm
okay with making mistakes you run a
business and you you fail enough you you
start being okay with that stuff and
then learning how to do it the right way
but I know that my way isn't always the
right way so and I think that's cool
because I feel like a lot of Growers and
breeders are always like the best grower
or breeder in the room right and it's
their way or the highway and so I think
it's really cool to hear that you are
willing to make mistakes and you're
willing to be wrong and and just have an
open mind I think it's really important
yeah I think that's a great way to live
you know just go through life uh with
less of an ego but like same thing with
the breeding book it's like I I have a
great breeding book it's the only
breeding book out that's current and I
don't think
it's the it has the potential to be even
better and I feel like there's other
people that could have probably wrote a
better book I think there's better
breeders than me I think there's smarter
people in the industry than me but I try
to learn from them and I try to improve
myself and I feel like that's all you
can do at the end of the day you know
you're never going to be the smartest
you're never going to be the fastest
you're never going to be the best
there's so many people we're talking
about s billion people on this planet so
the best thing you can do is learn from
other people and do what you feel that
you were meant to do on this Earth yeah
absolutely I think human beings struggle
with that I think it's hard because I
feel like let's say that you were wrong
about something it's almost like you
take it so personally like oh I'm less
than but it's not it's just a learning
experience to your point and I try to
approach my writing with that all the
time it's like please comment please let
me know please let me know if there's
anything I can do better or if there was
a theory that I put in here that might
be incorrect or that I could
thought about it a different way I
always invite that sort of feedback we
can't take it personal yeah and I I care
less and less about what people think
and say about me the older I get yeah
and so I you know it's just it is what
it is you know your truth I know my
truth and I know who I am and like the
more you know who you are the easier
that is too totally I would agree with
that and that's definitely something
that I've been I've been growing with
you know and that's it's difficult
sometimes because especially being so
public facing and I know that you know
what this is like there's a lot of eyes
on you yeah and to go back to what we
were saying earlier it's a lot of
pressure but as long as you know deep
down inside what your mission is and
what where your heart is that's all that
really matters people are going to think
what they want to think they're going to
say what they want to say but you know
the truth and that's really all that you
can control and what matters so yeah
it's an interesting World we're living
in and uh so where do you think it's
going oh man that's a loaded question
it's absolutely a loaded question well
if we're talking about just the Cannabis
world yeah it's it's a really
interesting time right and there's a lot
of uncertainty because not only do we
have the rescheduling potentially
happening but then we have the farm bill
coming up and initially they weren't
really talking about any of the
intoxicating cannaboids any of the thca
sort of stuff and then all of a sudden
this amendment came through in committee
and it could turn the hemp world upside
down it totally could like if if they if
they go by with what it says in that
Amendment that's crazy because it it's
going to screw the whole hemp in
industry because what they're saying is
that
thca uh is basically the same thing as
Delta 9 is what they're saying yeah but
that's not right that's not true thca
and it does so easily convert that's
true you heat it up it converts to Delta
KN but by itself um it be like I eat THC
I can eat a gram of thca and it doesn't
get me high at all yeah it actually
makes me feel amazing but it doesn't get
me high there's no
psychoactive effect to thca by itself so
it's it could totally yeah you're right
it could totally turn
the hemp industry upside down we'll see
what happens I mean I think if they
apply it to edibles but the whole thing
where it's like I I don't know how to
control it I I don't know how they're
going to re write it to where like the
stuff isn't legal they legalized it on
accident right and then but to correct
it to where it doesn't have a negative
impact is going to be really difficult
are they not going to allow CBD in shops
you you know I mean I don't think so I
don't think I think it's too big of a
movement to slow down but I think
they're going to try to figure out how
to control all the sales of this stuff
that's taking away money from Cannabis
businesses in in States like California
and New York and states that are
impacted by the whole hemp loophole yeah
it's it's been really interesting just
to see how it's become sort of a hemp
versus cannabis situation and we saw it
in Minnesota when they were trying to
pass their legalization bill because the
hemp products were popping and they
still are the the Delta 9 drinks and
gummies you know you could buy them at
the liquor store and get them at the tap
room where everyone is right and people
in the hemp space were anxious right
because they were worried that if we had
dispensaries that their business would
suffer and it's vice versa right and so
it's interesting to see how it's
lobbyists for big cannabis groups coming
out you know in support of this hemp
Amendment and the the infighting when at
the end of the day like I thought we
were all on the same team
you know and so it's been kind of
disappointing to see the contentious
nature I totally understand it from a
business perspective right but I just
wonder if there's any sort of way to
level the playing field and just let the
consumers decide yeah I don't know yeah
we're gonna find out we are we're gonna
find out this year probably yeah I think
so well I mean a lot of people don't
even know if the farm build will pass
you know because cannabis and hemp is
such a small small part of it there's a
lot of other stuff up for debate in an
election year and such a contentious
time in Washington it's like who even
knows if the bill will pass yeah so it's
hard to say and then you have the
rescheduling thing how will that play
out in my opinion I feel it'll be more
like business as usual I don't really
feel like it's going to affect the
day-to-day operations I feel like if
they can get rid of 28e and there's more
cash flow that's fantastic I would
obviously rather see it descheduled um
but I just I don't know if it's going to
have this wild impact that some people
theorize it will have well and the thing
is is it's as of right now it is not
deschedule right it is a pathway yes
deschedule and so it's very different
and if people are like oh it's done it's
not done no there's a lot of stuff that
has to happen for it to even make sense
so we'll see I mean we taxing the
taxation of it yeah how is it going to
be taxed I mean I think there's so many
aspects that need to be dis thoroughly
discussed thoroughly thought through um
and I believe now is the time where you
can send uh a letter to your
government if you uh want to comment on
uh the whole process so yeah people
should have their voices heard if they
want to take take part in the Democratic
process right I was actually uh covering
Croots Festival done in Monteray last
weekend looked awesome it was a Vibe it
was profit BR they were there Luke
scarmazzo he's been on the show he's
amazing yeah we were actually sharing a
booth with the equity Trade Network so
we were hanging out he actually helped
us judge a uh I did a Gyver bong contest
I saw that I saw the Winner's bong too
that was pretty cool yeah his little
apple filter yeah he crushed it um and
you know Luke like you know I know a
thing or two about DIY pipes being in
prison for 15 years but um I was talking
to a lot of consumers there you know
about the rescheduling because we exist
in such a vacuum in cannabis right I'm
always so curious about what consumers
think and what their understanding of
everything is most of them don't even
really know what's happening and the one
who do are definitely confused they
think it's already a done deal they
think that it's just less restrictive
they think maybe it's legal but the
consumers really have no idea about
what's going on behind the curtain and
what the implications are and a lot of
in a lot of ways we don't either and I
think that's really interesting because
the consumers are the one that are
driving this industry and they need to
be aware of what's happening so they can
have their voices heard and make an
impact but I think at this point they're
just like well weed's weed and I'm just
going to follow along with whatever I've
been doing right all the Sheep
for real but yeah I mean there's a lot
of people that they they don't want to
know they don't care yeah they have so
many more important things in their life
or it just doesn't impact them at all y
because they're not real smokers if you
even if they smoke every once in a while
it doesn't really impact their lives
like there's so many people that are
just uninformed but that's what
awareness is all about yeah and that's
what I think you know I'm trying to
accomplish in my career is just to
inform the people whenever I get down I
try to remember my mission and my
assignment you know remember the
assignment which is to get the
information about the plant to the
people that's it that's the assignment
and if I can do that if I can inform
people I feel like I'll have done my
part like I said earlier they can do
what they want with that information but
they need to have it and it needs to be
accurate and accessible I'm very
concerned about the mainstream narrative
around cannabis I do think that we're
kind of in this weird reer Madness 2.0
every day you see headlines of oh
teenagers sick from gummies or can abis
causes psychosis right all this
fearmongering is continuing just in a
different sort of way and so I really
want to combat that do I think that
cannabis is for everybody absolutely not
but do I think that everyone can benefit
from some accurate information about the
plant 100% yes yeah yeah
totally yeah it's it's interesting the
people out there are just in every
direction and and we're so divided yeah
so politically divided it is interesting
though to see how bipartisan support for
cannabits has increased right like
totally Republicans get high Democrats
get high like everyone everyone's just
getting high so well politicians are
making money on it on both sides too
totally so yeah and I mean it's just
it's one of those things it's for
everybody I I think it's for everybody
it may not be for you but it it is there
for everybody yes yeah it is there for
everybody and frankly going back to the
minor cannaboids maybe there kind of is
a cannabis for every person when you
break it down and I speaking of the
future future I think that's going to be
really interesting because right now
we're only really talking about a
handful of cannaboid and a handful of
tpin but what are we going to discover
and isolate and see and like the strains
that will grow in the future will we
will will there be different cannaboids
that we don't even know about yet dude
you go to the doctor and they give you a
custom canono profile that's designed
for your your specific receptors with
your ailments I mean there's there's all
kinds of potential for stuff you that's
abstracts you follow them a lot think
they do some amazing stuff I think
they're pushing boundaries I like the
direction they're going uh I think we
need more people doing that and more
people doing it publicly there are
private companies that are totally doing
a lot of stuff say similar research they
know a lot about it uh but yeah I think
just the general public needs to be made
aware of so many different aspects of
the plant you know beyond tpes they're
you know they're talking about
flavorants which I think is awesome you
know which we called THS back in the day
but now they've really started to Define
them uh there was just a post from Max
montros and he was talking about Jack
herrer why the pens don't taste like
Jack herrer and why you don't have the
same Association to like the extract
like an extract uh that's added turps as
you do to the flower but Jack's changed
too I used to like Jack back in the day
yeah and I don't like most of the Jack
no why do you think that is because I
think they have a phenotype that's
inferior I think people are growing
stuff that's not as good I the jack that
I had was completely
different uh you know it was similar
like very
limey uh but I would say it was way more
complex and it had a super amazing taste
better than the one today the one today
is okay but it's not as complex yeah
right jack is okay for me it's like on
the the bottom tier so whereas Jack back
in the day if we could we' pay $60 for
an Athan Jack back in the day damn and
it was freaking
light your light your uh head on fire
You' be
ripped and you know and we used to smoke
the little small joints of it be super
high and share those with three or four
of us wow and now that's like a personal
joint you know we smoke the big the
bigger ones now yeah so what do you have
in there we got some Skittles oh
Skittles nice it's fun it's daytime weed
we love a skittles yeah you can't go
wrong with Skittles that's something
like everybody likes but we have to call
it the original Z now right we're we're
not allowed to say the The Strain formly
know SK it's like the prince of weed do
you find that interesting um the fact
that we have so many varieties named
after other things and kind of dude
trademark infringement all over yeah
like yeah I mean I think that's that's
the sign of an immature
Market
um that's just how it goes I think
especially with cannabis because it was
illegal there was no trademark
infringement who you go after you know
it's like so people just did whatever
you know they wanted some Jedi strain
they were going to call some violate
Disney trademarks and got their Pikachu
or whatever the Skywalker OG right I
mean a lot of them there's so so many I
mean grape Hau one of my favorites
that's violates you know cop it's
copyright infringement um but even my
buddy he got in trouble TOA
colola uh Beyond bomb extra Jack in I
think it was 2004 he got busted and he
got in trouble from Hershey's he had
like I believe it was like Coca-Cola and
violations like that but he had some
awesome sodas and he was making some
amazing amazing
extracts he did five years in prison in
California wow total
[__] but like they went after him
for the IP not it wasn't bad enough that
he got busted they were like oh no yeah
they went after him for his money then
of course that's how they did it yeah
really sad I mean and that's how it was
there was a company called tainted those
guys didn't do any time they put it all
on one guy different company um yeah
really sad yeah really good guy he used
to make the bang back in the day oh yeah
that was like hallucinogenic bang damn
when people talk about how like THC
isn't hallucinogenic they never had the
stuff that I had cuz that [__] [__]
would [__] you up I mean that was like
you would be yeah it was it it was very
we it was almost a ritual we had we I
remember going to this Rave called
freedom and I believe it was on the 4th
of July and it was like in Oakley up on
these Hills these and it was like Sandy
and grass and like the it wasn't like
dirt regular dirt it was like dirt with
sand in it and we had tents and then we
drank this bang and it was like you
might as well have done some acid or
something like that it was on that level
no way yeah that sounds I've never I've
never consumed it I've heard a lot of
stories about it um you saying that
though makes me
anxious it was but so he used some stuff
that was like not to where my heart was
palpitating I didn't get the bad the
negative effect oh good like we
sometimes with Edibles people freak out
I didn't freak out at all yeah and I
freaked out from Edibles before yeah
unfortunately I've been there for sure I
had an incident on an airplane one time
coming back from La I think I I ate like
a I don't even know what it was it was
it was some traditional Market thing so
there's that right there you know you
know it's going to be strong and I got
on the plane and we were taxing to take
off and I started feeling really hot and
like my heart started racing and I felt
kind of sick almost and I was anxious
and the guy next to me he just thought I
was anxious about the flight he's like
don't worry it's fine this is just
another flight and I was like I start
freaking out I start feeling I'm going
to be sick and we start taking off and
I'm like I'm going to be sick you know
you can't stand up you can't do anything
there was no sick bag and so as soon as
we were kind of up and it was almost
like acceptable to stand up I just ran
to the back and it was just like sick
and I was just like sweating and just
paranoid the whole flight it was just
such a nightmare I was like oh why did I
eat that that's rough yeah it was the
worst I'm really always an advocate for
knowing your limits you know and this
whole you know go slow start start low
go slow yeah that whole thing because I
really hate the idea that people try
cannabis for the first time and I think
this is happening more often now people
try cannabis for the first time they're
not well informed and then they end up
having a bad time they have paranoia
they get sick you know they're
uncomfortable whatever it is literally
you know and then they're going to tell
their friends yeah and they'll never do
it again exactly and that's I have
friends like that when we were kids that
they never smoked after that I mean I
talk to them now sometimes but uh they
got too high the first time and then
they never wanted to smoke yeah yeah no
it's unfortunate and like
I'm a huge huge advocate for knowing
your limits for knowing what's right for
you take one little hit yeah wait 5 10
minutes you know you're going to eat a
gummy you don't need five milligrams two
and a half milligrams I get really
concerned about what the bud tenders are
arm of the gummy Bear just start with
that just start with the arm one one
little toe yeah yeah Joe Rogan had a a
comedy show I think he was in San
Francisco when he talked about that
about how the Edibles are so strong you
just need like the ear of the gummy bear
or something
hilarious no it's it's facts and I just
I really get concerned about how the bud
tenders are portraying the plant and
it's it's not on them right and I think
that they don't necessarily always have
the best training but I'm wondering what
you think about that you know what can
we do on the retail level I mean I'm
trying as hard as I can with articles
and you know online but what can we do
to actually educate the consumers so
that they don't have a bad time so they
don't freak out on an airplane give them
CBD with their weed yeah I mean but but
other than that I mean honestly I would
say that you awareness and education
people need to know that like if you do
too much it's not one of those things
you just do as much as you can the first
time you need to really take it slow I
think the more we share awareness about
it the better it is for people um you
know they in California we do have like
super super like low THC Edibles like
it's super low MH you know so I think
that in you know it's what is it 5
milligram dose and or up to 10
milligrams per dose and only 100
milligrams per package right right so 10
milligrams that gets me high I get high
from that that's a pretty good high like
but even five milligrams that's a great
place to start for an edible for the
average person but some people can go up
to 50 back in the day we used to eat 500
not even think twice you know it's like
we literally tried to put as much as we
could in the brownies like literally we
we had butter we we wanted it the
strongest butter possible and it was
strong I bet it was somewhere between 3
and 500 milligrams of brownie and we
would eat those you know I've often
wondered about that what were the
milligrams in my homemade brownies and
cookies you know back in the day I
definitely remember having some pretty
intense times I tried to go to a hockey
game one time after eating one of my
brownies and I had to leave after the
first period I was like I don't like
this
energy but yeah it's it's always a it's
a guessing game but I would almost push
back on on the five milligrams I feel
like that can be too much for a first-
timer I think I think two and a half
honestly is a great place to start for a
lot of folks just because you don't know
that's why this Show's good we're
talking about awareness now I'm like
five and years two and a half and you're
probably right and I think less is more
especially with drugs totally and this
is a drug coffee is a drug I'm not
saying anything negative about the
planum it's a drug and I think it has
impact and starting in a small place is
great there's nothing wrong with micro
doing either you know it's like with
micro doing weed where you don't even
feel it there is positive benefits to
that too yeah absolutely and you can
always work your way up the problem with
with weed and a lot of other substances
is you can't necessarily work your way
down you know once it's in there you
can't get it up it's on you just got to
wait it up yeah and like maybe you can
take a high high dose of CBD or actually
my staff writer Cara she's working on a
piece right now testing out all these
products that promise to help you come
down if you get too high there's several
things on the market I don't really know
what they are if they're just like a
high CBD energy shot kind of it looks
like I don't know the formulation but
I'm really interested in hearing how
they work out and if those products are
viable on the market because I don't
really see them in dispensaries or
anything like that I don't see anybody
pushing these products so is it
something that we should have for for
harm reduction purposes you know
available or maybe yeah throw it in the
uh in the outbag like a high CBD 50
milligram capsule or something just in
case I mean it's because these are the
things that science is going to help
formulate over time to how what's the
fastest delivery mechanism that we can
do is it taking a dab is it eating a
pill that has you know that's that's
basically has some form of fat or some
something that'll basically make it
absorb
faster um sublingual yeah this like the
sprays under the new ways of doing patch
yeah new CBD patches I mean it's really
cool this stuff is really cool and you
know I find it really interesting all
the different uses and all the different
potential uh methods for delivery that
they have and some of them are wild and
some of them are unnecessary and that's
always going to be the case when you're
doing stuff it's like I see stuff all
the time that's maybe not necessary but
it's like someone was creative and you
have enough creative ideas you're going
to come up with some really cool stuff
as far as you know weed technology and
Innovation we were in a crazy R&amp;D period
over the last decade you've obviously
seen a lot and especially when it comes
to breeding and growing all the
technology but on the consumer facing
level whether it's you know devices or
use cases what are some of the things
that have stuck out to you as like okay
that actually is a game changer LED
lights yeah Game
Changer um crop
steering Game
Changer um
breeding
Skittles no I mean I love Skittles I
think that there's been some genetics
over time it's just like there's two
guitarists that Chang the world jimmi
Hendricks Eddie Van
Halen um beyond that there's been other
amazing guitars too but those those were
the ones what do you think that the
genetics were that changed the world
that's a really good question because
you go all the way back you know you
think about the original land race
strains and how far they've come but as
far as genetic markers within our
timeline of the last like 10 20 years I
mean obviously like Girl Scout cookies
was huge right it's it felt like for an
entire decade everything was sort of do
turp you know and the Skittles I think
as well you know that Z is everywhere
people love it people continue to ask
for it and so I think that's really
interesting but going back I think you
know strains like blue dream for sure
like Jack Herrera the OG Kush obviously
I'm waiting for another one another one
chem 91 I think was the biggest game
changer I think chem 91 it was the bag
seed that was found uh on the lot yeah
legendary well really I mean there's
more to that story but but it was the
meeting happened on the lot the seeds
came later but because of the Grateful
Dead um really really amazing uh and
Game Changer to this you know I think
that's what got gas into everything
that's when people started really
appreciating gas uh OG Kush that's
another one and like if you look at the
phos studies of OG Kush they have 90
different things that aren't called OG
Kush that are genetically identical to
OG Kush really yeah so that means people
rename at 90 different things which
means it was probably 500 different
things um so OG cusher Game Changer yeah
blue dream I think is a game changer too
I think that's a super important one uh
cookies yeah uh Jack Herrera in its day
Super Silver Haze yes I feel like super
silver back in the day was a huge game
changer I mean we could go back even
further with like Hindu Kush and some of
the people that brought the original
kushes you know those were all game
changers we had the Master Kush and the
Bubba Kush and the
ogs those were all in my lifetime but
before that there was you know Afghan
people were bringing stuff back
pre-soviet Afghanistan yeah no I'm
really I love hearing about what weed
they were smoking back in the day my
friend's dad's always talking about
Panama Red yeah and I remember people
talking about like tie stick when I was
a kid and and I went to I was an opair
in Amsterdam and I had been hearing
about the tie stick and the chocolate
tie when I was really young and and gray
area that coffee shop John from the gray
area great guy so I was in there and I
was talking about like oh is there any
place where I can get this type of weed
and he's like oh you don't even know
like we're growing a chocolate tie right
now it's not ready yet but it'll be here
in like March this was in maybe November
or December at the time and I was like
okay I'm going to come back I'm going to
keep my eye on that and I end up leaving
Amsterdam I got fired for my opar job um
and I never got to try their chocolate
tie at gray area and it's something I've
always regretted my whole life you know
then I was smoking a lot of silver haze
a lot of white widow like all the white
widow I want to see some of those
strains make a comeback what strain do
you want to see make a comeback this is
not a trick question everybody who
watches the show knows I want ciss that
is absolutely the one that ciss like
that is uh I'm sure our producers been
waiting for me to say cat piss on this
episode but I love I want the cat piss
we are doing the documentary on it we
keep talking about the documentary but
like we're going to be recreating the
capus uh
doing several crosses to get something
similar to what I remember as ciss but
ciss is also the description of an aroma
I think there's multiple cat pisses I
don't think there's just one cross I
think there could be potentially several
and it's not like blue dream or Romulan
or super silver haze where there're a
specific name and it doesn't really
describe the aroma or you know the smell
of it where you CA something piss I mean
you could it
I could see how that could get you know
changed into several things over time
yeah absolutely well and I think that is
also very interesting uh in our
community is the fact that you have so
much of that where it was like maybe an
OG Kush but then they changed the name
or whatever and it was kind of lost and
then those genetics continued and the
lack of consistency in the marketplace
and people don't actually know for sure
what they're getting but they think they
do right the consumers are like oh the
package says OG Kush so it must OG Kush
right and totally it ruins weed that
just yeah I mean that's the same thing
where like the first impression is so
important like if if you get a for the
first time you get something that's
called OG cush and it's garbage you're
like OG Kush sucks yeah right and so
like that happens all the time and so a
lot of people are like oh this sucks or
that sucks and there's a lot of cut
fishing going on so on top of all this
with the cut fishing then somebody gives
you something like this is OG Kush you
grow it out you don't know any better
you think it's OG Kush and that happened
10 times over so there's 10 people now
that are giving and sharing and Crossing
it and saying I crossed this with OG
Kush but it's not really crossed with OG
Kush and so that's where the Dilemma
comes in like how do we solve this big
problem because this is a problem this
is a huge problem and I think we're not
talking enough about how big of a
problem it really is because it's
happening all over all the time how does
it make you feel as a breeder I think I
can look at stuff from the outside and
it doesn't piss me me off as much as
maybe it pisses off other people I'm
more of a Solutions based person anyway
so I'm like okay what's the solution
fingerprinting we go to my flid DNA
shout out to those guys we can
fingerprint all our genetics now if we
sell the cuts we can fingerprint them we
can verify it if somebody calls it that
then we can go look at my floor we can
test their flower sample we're like okay
they got it or they don't have it which
damn it that cut leaked they it got out
to the world and I think technology is
going to solve the problem right because
there's so many people that are
just okay with uh changing the names
apparently yeah there are people that do
bad things and then there's facts and so
hopefully we can win the war with uh
facts and beat these people out that are
just totally yeah I mean there's there's
bullies and there's bad people all over
yeah absolutely and I guess both of us
are doing that in our own individual way
yeah you know as a writer I'm trying to
work for truth there's a lot of fake
news out there even in the weed media so
much you know and how can we approach it
from a space of just truth and wanting
to do better as an industry and and
wanting to level us up and help us be
more professional in the eyes of the
mainstream American who's just waiting
for us to clown yeah there's so many
people who dog on us because they know
that at the end of the day it's like oh
you guys are just an underground Market
you don't know what you're doing out
here in the real world but we do you
know a lot of us strive to be
professionals and to be good stewards of
the plant and so and it's it's hard when
you see so much infighting and [__]
talking you know when it's like we're
all on the same team it's really
frustrating yeah well and I think so
back going back to fingerprinting and
and why that's valuable I think when you
have a fingerprint of something that you
created or that you have in your hands I
think that that's valuable yeah and I
think that there's no negative side to
that because you Prov that you had it at
a certain point in time right and so as
a breeder with our collection being able
to collect uh markers on everything I
think is so huge also for for breeding
in the future it's like part of what we
do is data collection you know that's as
a breeder what you do is data collection
I would say that a large part of what we
do that we don't even talk about is data
collection yeah so and you know the the
more advanced we get we're using sofware
now it's not all on little books so I
think it's it's amazing that the
potential with AI in the future too is
going to be super incredible uh
especially predictive modeling for
breeding I mean that's a GameChanger
yeah I would assume that there's a lot
of excitement around that and I think
there's a lot of people scared of it too
and it's like man you got to embrace it
it's going to happen no matter what so
let's embrace it and let's figure out
how to make it work for us yeah exactly
and I think it would have huge benefit
for the producers and just the supply
chain in General right I mean well I
mean a lot of people think that breeding
is just crossing this with this and you
get this and that's not that's not what
real breeding is it has a lot to do with
the selection and then breeding over
time and um true breeding takes a lot of
work yeah no I would assume so and so
this would take some of the guest
workout no it would and it increases the
potential of what you can do which I
think is the most amazing thing I mean
there there's one it's one thing to be
breeding and look at a plant and going
okay well this one yields and this you
know we're going to bre the one that
yields the most with this and then the
next time you select okay in that proy
we got these specific turb profiles and
this is the big producer right and then
you can do that over and over but using
data to breed is going to be the biggest
game changer ever because now I mean
they've been doing a big a for a while
and now taking all that information and
applying it to cannabis we got guys
doing incredible things and that's not
even uh GMO
we're talking about just data driven
breeding what do you say to the people
who are anxious about the technology
coming into the grow who feel like it
doesn't have a place what do you say to
those
people uh I think that everybody has a
purpose and whether you feel that it has
a place or not it's
happening um and maybe your purpose is
breeding maybe it's not if you know you
want to get on the bandwagon you want to
still do it your classic way up in the
hills and you know uh
go along with the the traditional Market
that's okay you can do that I mean
there's nothing wrong with that I think
that's slowly going away but like
breeding is getting a lot more
scientific and people are taking to the
next level so either you educate
yourself or you get left behind and I
think that's kind of what my book was
about at least to start that dialogue
and then the next version of the book is
going to have even more information on
you know the more I learn the more is's
going in the book I like that you want
to share the information with the world
I think you're right people can do what
they want with it just like I said
earlier with my writing it's like you
have the information now that's
all do with it what you will we put it
out there all we can do is put it out
there and if the world likes it the
world likes it and if they don't they
don't yeah but yeah I mean it's like and
the thing is is with technology it's I
think it has the potential to make the
world a better
place now whether that happens or not
that's a whole different story but the
potential is there yeah I don't think
we're going to see Skynet in the grow
room or anything like that not yet no
totally no so yeah or Monsanto comes for
for all my seeds yeah no I don't think
that's going to happen they're not corn
seeds yeah but cannabis is becoming such
a huge cash crop though like I've been
watching you know they always put out
data like oh now it's bigger than this
and bigger than that and bigger than
that do you think that Trend will
continue or do you think there'll be
more Market compression especially if we
go into a an interstate commerce
situation I can't wait for interstate
commerce yeah but I feel like we're
going to have our ups and downs and uh
there will be heavy consolidation there
it's just it look at Colorado you know
Colorado is the best example if you look
at Colorado the consolidation that
happened there is going to happen
everywhere uh especially with interstate
and msos Multistate operators are going
to be everywhere because people want to
expand their brands right and so that's
good but I
also uh look forward to Humble County
Trinity mesino and
somoma having designated areas for
terroir yes and to be able to do the
farm to table experience yes where you
can go up and you can meet the grower
and it's like a w Winery Brewery hybrid
that you get to meet the grower you
maybe maybe there's a bed and breakfast
there you could stay in the bed and
breakfast or you could just go to The
Tasting Room taste this stuff when
they're harvesting you can go walk the
fields and watch them Harvest and I
think that is a cool experience and that
can be Boutique and that can be you know
craft and there's nothing wrong with
craft there's always room for Budweisers
and there there's plenty of room for
Lanas and Russian River and these small
breweries Lanas is now a big Brewery
they're like the hybrid too they're
they're like they were they were craft
and they grew and they grew and they
grew and now they're you know a
multi-billion dollar company but they
produce good beer and so there's somewh
there's something for everybody and
that's the beauty of cannabis is there
something for everybody not everybody
likes the top actually everybody likes
the top but not everybody requires it or
would be willing to pay more money for
the best of the best of the best right
exactly and I 100% agree with you there
should be opportunity for every type of
consumer to get what they need and what
they want what's right for me might not
be right for you and that's okay and I
really love the idea of people being
able to connect with their grower if
they want to it's just like you can go
to the farmers market and get your
Tomatoes or you can get them at Walmart
you know but consumers should be able to
have a choice Walmart has yeah they have
Walmart groceries man it's a
thing I'm not saying they're any good
but they exist totally they do exist
yeah that's crazy so but yeah you know
it's like I think I just want to really
see the folks in the Emerald Triangle
survive and be able to weather the storm
and be able to invite those Folks up
which a lot of them are doing right like
I know Johnny and Rose they do stuff at
their farm and soul Spirit they have
clamping Retreats you can go and it's a
full yeah uh experience I can't wait for
that to expand and that to cuz that's
the evolution of the Emerald Triangle
right I see that as being and there's
huge consolidation that happened there
you know there was way more Brands there
was way more people doing it and it
became less and less and there's still
guys doing it successfully but I it's
going to grow it's going to grow again
because it's meant to and I feel like
there's plenty of places in the United
States that could grow good cannabis and
I'm all for it I love California I'm a
Californian but uh where are some other
places in the country that you think
have fire weed Oregon for sure
Washington has good weed yeah back
East uh you get everywhere from Maine
down to Florida there's there's good
weed that can be found there I don't
know if they're growing good weed in all
those places but they're definitely
doing some good stuff in Florida now I
mean I think we've got some guys from
Plenty of guys from Colorado they
decided to go to Florida MH you know and
then same thing Maine
and uh Massachusetts and Rhode Island I
think they've got good stuff over there
I have friends over there that are doing
stuff so I know I haven't seen their
flower but I'm assuming that it's top
top top and uh some of my friends that
used to you know people aren't having to
come here for flower now they're just
producing it over there I've heard that
they have crazy good weed in Maine I've
been waned to try it like Maine and
Vermont I've been hearing amazing things
about their bud I like the bud in
Massachusetts too nice yeah
Massachusetts another dead head
Community there you know I feel like
anywhere there was a big dead head
Community there was like some good weed
and good weed being grown yeah
absolutely where do you think they
there's room for improvement let's keep
it political you know
California so yeah well the funny thing
is is like we have seen tons of
improvement here but there's could
always be more and I think on the on the
rec side there is room for improvement
everywhere definitely there is not one
place that is hit it out of the park
that's [__] that I know of yeah that
has just knocked it out and I feel like
we all have our problems Washington has
their own problems and they have fire
weed I love the weed up in Washington
man my friends my friends up there crush
it they all crush it all you guys in
Washington crush it I love the weed
Oregon there's so many good places in
Oregon but then they gave out licenses
to everybody and then they did the stuff
with
betrus I mean come on guys like they
didn't do it right either we we're no
better I think uh Arizona did really
good overall I think Arizona's model was
good um I think there's good flower
there there's for sure good flow um
Earth ceilings got some good stuff uh
there's there's other brands I'm sure
that have good stuff in Arizona because
I've seen it yeah um New Mexico I've
have some friends in New Mexico that are
crushing I think that but as far as like
room for improvement everywhere it's got
to improve because California look at
2018 when it first hit the market it was
garbage the wreck weed was garbage now
you can actually find good stuff in
wreck but not as much as you should
there's still a lot of mediocre product
uh overpriced
boof uh we can change that we need to
change that it's G to happen it better
happen yeah they need to get on that in
New York because so far what I've been
seeing in on the regulated side there
it's like and it's expensive as hell
it's no wonder that people just want to
go to these illicit all the Bas yeah
literally it's like not only are people
confused about what's real and what's
not what's legal what's not but if you
you can get something for a quarter of
the price and it's maybe even better
twice as good but a quarter of the price
yeah like what are you supposed to do so
yeah I just I hope they can get it
together because I really feel for the
regulated operators out there there's
some good people who are really trying
to do it right and they're just miles
behind of what these bodas are doing
it's just it sucks for them yeah but I
also be fair feel like there's always
going to be room for the traditional
Market too and I'm an advocate for the
traditional Market because I do think
that people should be able to go to
their farmers market or wherever their
craft place and get what they want and
know their grower and know their farmer
and that if you want to go to a
regulated dispensary you can do that too
again it comes back to Consumer choice
and just education I will assume the
risk whichever path I take right yeah so
did I get a strain from you if you could
bring back anything what would you bring
back I mean honestly thinking about that
white widow I mean you don't really see
white widow around we have the white
widow I've seen in my life we had one
white white Widow in the 90s that I
think it was unrelated and you know
there was some stuff out of Florida but
like I never like white widow it was
like the vanilla weed oh okay yeah the
stuff in Europe it was like you cross it
to anything and it vanilla fies that
doesn't mean that I got the right wrong
White Widow it probably means I got the
wrong and maybe there was really good
white widow we had stuff called The
White Widow we called it the sweat but
it was really supposedly White Widow oh
okay but it made you sweat it would get
you so high and it had a little nose
burn to it M slightly kind of hazy but
like that nose when you'd smoke it it
would it burn and get you so high your
eye it would be real tight eyes and we
call it a sweat literally you'd start
pouring in
sweat and so that was the only time I
got good white widow when I was overseas
when we bought White Widow and I Spain
Amsterdam never saw anything good that
was like real white widow over there
interesting yeah I always I'm trying to
remember where I used to always shop
there was this
place called a brais or I feel like they
had they had decent white widdow um
there was a strain that I smoked when I
was young called Orange Crush at least
that's what the guy called it Orange
Crush I I absolutely remember Orange
Crush I I always had an affinity for
orange turps now it's kind of changing
uh but I feel like Team Elite genetics
has like an orange soda that's probably
the most similar to that experience um
but I'd love to see that one what turps
do you think are making a comeback right
now or what TPS I think gas is making
comeback yeah I think so we been going
back and forth with gas and like the
gelato M so like that floral candy gas
propably purple candy gas what they call
but really it's like the floral candy
gas and some of the stuff leans heavy
like the Joker leans heavy on the gas
and I really like that side of it too
and I feel like those are a lot a lot of
times those are the stronger ones as
well like the stronger smoke but I feel
like we're going back to more gas we're
going to go back to Citrus
yes I think Tang is going to make it
come back this next year I love Tangi
yeah I think there's a lot of hate
people on this show in the comments tell
me how you feel about that but I feel
like there's a lot of hate on Tangi yeah
I like Tangi I I personally I mean I
think you get sick of Tangi and then the
world got sick of Tang it was so hot it
was like this huge thing in
2013 it was the it was the hot [__] it
was the hot it was the hot hot hot it
was I mean Girl Scout cookies was
popular here OG but like for High Times
in like that
Community it was that was the one it was
the most awarded thing every time it won
and I think there was where people the
judges would be like oh yeah they they
know how it is so they how already set
before they even started judging when
they got to the Tang they were G to pick
the
Tangi yeah it it was definitely a
standout and I know it's contentious but
my fiance is actually growing a Tangi
CBD strain for me right now and I'm
super stoked about it honestly awesome
yeah but I'd like to see more hazes too
I'm doing some Haze work I'm doing so
yeah I feel like that's the Lord's work
these
things these these plants take off I got
a I got some maloi versus W hawen that A
friend gave me okay uh from Mexico and
I'm super excited about those they smell
crazy and they're just super vigorous
and so I'm I'm like ready to jump on
that I think doing some work with that
and then Crossing that back into some
shorter flowering plants is going to be
part of what we do this year lot of fun
it's always it's always an adventure
truly yeah it must be so exciting I mean
for both of us in our own different ways
right there's always something happening
there's always new innovation yeah is
there anything that people would ask you
to bring back that you wouldn't bring
back just on a personal level you're
like purple punch you're over it no I
never was into it oh okay I never liked
purple punch I didn't like it for the
first time I saw it I liked it yeah it
was like one of the it's Instagram weed
it purple punch was the one where you're
like oh wow looks amazing can't wait to
smoke this same thing with some of the
wedding cake fener types there is good
wedding cake there's no good purple
punch purple punch maybe an extract you
can get some okay tasting extract or
whatever but as far as like rolling a
joint of it you would light it up and
instantly it would taste like nothing
like you you don't get turps in the
joints it was mild turps anyway to begin
with and when you smoke big joints of it
like the first hit you might almost get
a little turp and then it would just
taste you might as well smoke a
cigarette yeah that's that's how it was
and there there's a bunch of stuff like
I'm not a big Oreos fan either like the
smoke of
Oreos but I've said on my show a million
times they're all one cross away from
being amazing that's the beauty of this
stuff is like you find something like
purple punch you can cross it to stuff
and make it great yeah it it does really
well as a breeder Oreos does well as a
breeder I've done some really
interesting work with Oreos but as far
as like it has like chocolaty mild TPS
that aren't aren't interesting at all
for me it's not interesting I like
interesting turps yeah I don't mind
Fried Chicken turps you know what I mean
like but I want interesting yes so and I
love finding those in the garden where
you squeeze it and you're like oo that's
fried chicken my my buddy I was in
Seattle not maybe two years ago and uh
we were going through and he's like dude
you got to smell this it smells just
like fried chicken dead on Fried Chicken
turbs wow and I like I like a little bit
of everything so I like variety I think
variety as far as flavor you you get
used to one thing and then you want try
something else the only thing is is like
Skittles a lot of times I enjoy Skittles
so much like if I have 50 different
things and I get Skittles I'll smoke all
the Skittles before I go back into
everything else and sometimes it's
whatever the best is yeah the Blue 13 is
another one it's like straight amazing
blueberry turps green weed so what do
you feel about that you like Green you
you have preference on green versus
purple or purple versus green I'm a
bright green girl yeah for sure um no
shade on purple weed or or dark green
weed but there's something about bright
green especially with like that lime
green color yeah you know it's just
there's just something about it and that
almost looks fake yeah right like it
shouldn't actually be weed is I feel
like a lot of the cryo cure ends up
looking like that to be honest with you
totally a lot of it does but is that
more about bag appeal for the cryo here
or do you think there's something there
with that we're gonna find out yeah I
guess so I'm actually I'm not sold on it
at all I don't believe in it at all but
they I'm willing to like see if someone
could change my mind because I I think
the science of it there's
potential so we'll see and maybe people
figure it out maybe they won't and but I
think that that we have to do this stuff
over and over and over to try to figure
stuff out to see how we can improve the
plan improve the processes of drying
curing storing you know LED lights LED
lights are way more efficient than HPS
and the thing is is now we have
adjustable Spectrum so we can mimic uh
certain spectrums and I think that's
great because we're [__] up the
environment using HPS lights yeah at the
end of the day they're they're not
costeffective either and they're really
bad I mean we're producing so many you
know if you want to do what's best for
the planet we' just be growing Outdoors
but I think mix light's the future too
yeah I I definitely feel like mixed
light doesn't get enough credit Yeah in
our space and I think that they're doing
a lot of really interesting stuff going
to yeah it has to yeah well if you think
to compete your your prices have to go
down and so your costs have to go down
if you want to make a profit and so to
have to run the lowest cogs you're going
to use mixed lights to get the best
quality product that competes with
indoor but costs a fraction of the price
and so I think it competes and maybe
beats indoor eventually and I've seen
some amazing you know mixed light and I
I think it has the potential and I
think as as a whole it's going to just
get bigger and bigger and bigger because
people are going to be more competitive
especially for
Quality um so we'll see it's exciting
times it really is I can't wait to see
how it all plays out and get to write
about it too
absolutely so if people are interested
and finding out more about you where can
they go that's a great question James
you can follow me on Instagram at relle
the writer you can hit me up on LinkedIn
obviously linkedin's popping for
cannabis um and definitely check out
greenstate that's the website that I'm
the editor of and we put out lots of
amazing content and we have a great
newsletter it comes out on Tuesdays at
4:20 and people should sign up for it we
promise we won't spam yeah I think you
even were calling me on there at one
point yeah and we're still doing some
work you know with beard Bros uh mg um
skunk obviously so trying to get as many
names in the mix and amplify on all the
different channels because there's so
many different audiences so I just
encourage people to be in touch too if
you have a story if you have a story
that you'd like the world to hear please
get in touch with me don't be shy uh my
DMs are open and always happy to hear a
pitch um and I feel like there are a lot
of people in our community that deserve
to have their voices heard and they just
don't know necessarily how to get it out
there you don't need necessarily A
publicist no shade on the publicist love
you guys um but not everyone can afford
that or know how to go about it and so I
encourage people to just share their
stories uh with me or with anybody else
there's a lot of amazing weed writers
out there who are just killing it and
who want to share these stories so
people should really reach out I seen
that movie Almost Famous yeah the
Cannabis industry kind of reminds me of
the kid from
famous yeah yeah we have our Squad yeah
totally good stuff well thank you so
much for coming on the show today it's
been a blast I look forward to doing it
again maybe I'll have to write an
article in a magazine about you next oh
that would be amazing no thank you so
much for having me it was a blast and
it's always just a pleasure to see you
James you're such a great guy I'm just a
big fan of your energy overall awesome
thank you very much for sure
[Music]