he
[Music]
how's it going we're here reg on the
river with Marlin Asher how you doing
Marlin oh wow you know it's good it's
hot but you know I'm fine you know here
regy on the river we're ready for the
performance blessing you know 2024 oh my
God it's been a while yeah you've been
getting me the regga shows forever yeah
well this one 12 years this one I hope
is going to be the Epic one because I
think so reg on the river has been
missing for a while and it's back and
we're here remember back in full force
it's wild so many people were Juiced to
come here it's like it's amazing the
camp situation is crazy too man it's a
beautiful day you know reg on the river
we here ready for the performance
[Music]
and it
how's it going out here with Rick from
Royal gold at reg on the river
2024 amazing event this is the first day
it's pretty wild already it is man it's
heating up day one first time back here
in seven years but obviously this
thing's been going for over three
decades so it is a big family reunion
everyone's coming back to the spot that
they love they've got memories
everybody's excited everybody's talking
about yester year and the things that
have happened and the music that they've
listened to and the the great things
that they've experienced around music
around humo County and around the
amazing plant cannabis totally we all
have great reg stories for the past I
had to sleep on on the Rocks one year
that was an experience I love this place
I love the music I love the passion
everybody smoks weed it's a beautiful
thing it is 100% yeah this as we get
older we notice we're bringing camping
pads and even pillows but yeah when when
you're were younger I definitely have I
came down here where it was like Yeah
The Rock was the pillow just like that
famous song You Know tough it out
exactly have an amazing weekend yeah
they've done a great job man just
setting everything up the way that they
positioned everybody all the vendors uh
all the
sponsors uh it's it's it's very
Community Based they've kind of put
everybody together where uh depending on
what you're doing if you're doing food
obviously those guys are always together
in a food Zone but you know it's kind of
nice between like the the jewelry the
the clothing and then you got the the
more cultivating based companies all
kind of in a Zone and so it's just yeah
it just feels familiar it just feels
like a big family reunion yeah it's like
coming home seeing your friends that you
haven't seen for a while luckily we get
to see each other more often but
absolutely but yeah dude it's uh it's
fun I'm stok that you came up man we we
talked about this obviously you know 6
months ago or so we were on for the
podcast y I was on for the podcast and
we mentioned this afterwards we were out
to dinner and uh and it's one of those
things you know sometimes you can
mention something like this oh man R get
in the river is going on you should come
up and a lot of times people just want
oh yeah it sounds like a great idea but
it won't happen sounds like fun a week
later you hit me up and you were like
man I really actually want to come up I
want to take you up on this I think it's
a great opportunity to not just do
podcasting and and get out there and
talk to our audience but to get back
into the roots and and like the magic
that surrounded us with in regards to
this plan right as we go more commercial
as we go more legal things are changing
man and it and it's very very important
for us to remember where we came from
and and the magic that happened in these
Hills you know these mountains the we're
here abolutely that's where we all our
teeth with this plant you know 30 40
years ago for some of us um so it's
important man it's it's all about coming
back being a part of the the Cannabis
Community here in southern humo County
in the anald triangle and giving back
and sharing and all that good stuff it's
great cuz you meet the nicest people
here too it's like everybody's in a good
mood everyone's happy to be here uh I
think there's more cannabis consuming
alcohol which plays a huge role to like
the people tuning in rather than tuning
out sure and it's a lot of fun not that
there's anything wrong with a couple
beers or anything like that's always
great but I feel like people here are
tuned in and it's great to be around a
whole bunch of people that are tuned in
what's going on and happy uh just just
in general even though that whatever is
going at home is going on at home when
you're here you're here and it's just an
amazing feeling to be around people that
are just so happy to be here 100% man
you couldn't have said that any better
cuz back in the day when you know this
has always pretty much gone on the first
weekend of August right and
it was it was almost like a a
celebration of you're you're you're
you're done with with planting and
really kind of getting into the and you
get everything set up with your garden
right and you were just about to go into
the into the real part of county in
theal Triangle everything flips where
the where the copters were going to
start flying she was about to get real
let's get together let's gather let's
celebrate each other the plant the music
cuz these next couple months
you might even still be sexing plants
like this time of year Outdoors if
you're going regular seats you know like
this the time of year y you know plants
are big the bigger ones show their sex
early on typically but you'll still get
some oh absolutely we've all been caught
off guard you know seed companies have
been built off of that you know big time
amaz time so yeah man it's it's really
good I think you know everybody being in
a good mood I think it's it's where
we're at right now where where people
you know postco I think that that was
you know a traumatic thing for for
people like us our tribe our our culture
We Gather we we like to Circle up and
ceremony and uh and those years man it
was really difficult for us to so of get
back to something like this and and
where we can actually share in all the
good things that we love and and why
we've all been drawn to each other over
the decades man it's feels great we go
through a lot of trauma just in life you
know in existence there's trauma Co
whatever ever happens you know over the
period of your life that kind of stuff
these type of events are good for that
kind of stuff no doubt they're they fact
they're the best I think being able to
get around other
people in this nice warm weather y you
know and listen to some good music at
the end of the day the music really kind
of just ties it all in together like
we're here for the music I mean we're
here for all of it oh yeah but then the
music just elevates it all it elevates
the whole experience I'm excited about
the lineup man I got some really dear
friends in the band checkered past nice
they're dear friends of ours um we I've
played music with them personally over
the years nice and uh and it's just it's
a it's a new Twist on Scot music which
I'm a big fan of growing up in New York
City got turned on to Scot in the 80s
some people laugh at Scott they they
just think it's like a funny quirky
thing to be into Scott music is the most
uplifting happy let's [ __ ] dance I
put that [ __ ] on on Sunday when I'm
ready to clean my house you know what I
mean ties with and SC it does
the roots of it all before re there was
Scot and it's Checker pass you got to
check them out they're on not on the
main stage they're one of the side
stages uh tomorrow Saturday that's
awesome um and then of course you got
ceton you got sister Nancy I'm so
excited going Mar Asher
Mariner to see Marlon Asher he's amazing
J bu J I love you Maui I'm going J and
Marlon go up and perform together man
you know you go way back with Marlon so
put in your little elbow rub see if you
can make that happen because that would
be amazing that would be an amazing end
to to Sunday
night absolutely I love the music and
and we got multiple stages we got DJ's
Nick here DJing he's one of my good
friends y lots of fun there's no end to
the fun there's a lot of good boost here
too we got Cutting Edge right next to
you guys yeah yeah we're we're we got J
Mansion right across from us we got this
little entryway into the Cannabis Zone
which is super fun a lot of us go way
back we've known each other for quite
some time um and then we're sitting in
the The Big T for canest canest is uh is
run by Steve Gater who's a old school
Humble County entrepreneur he had grow
Stores um dispensary he's been throwing
on the Cannabis festivals for years
getting the people together from Emerald
tridal and Beyond he's done an
extraordinary job over the last two and
a half
decades and uh and here he is we're
under the canest 10 here R in the river
he's throwing his own canest in
September first weekend of
September scratch that second weekend of
September 7 8th and it's on the
waterfront eure it's got a great lineup
more drifting away from from Greatful
Dead esque Or R but more Grateful Dead
kind of with lettuce with oal and
friends he's got um uh Melvin Seals from
jgb band I mean it's a great great
lineup Juday Festival right on the water
front so that's going be a lot of fun
we'll both be there I'll be filming
there too we're going to do podcast
stuff perfect get you out there again
and we talk some more we should be BL
don't J me with a good time I'll be
there yeah we'll be smoking we can lead
for
[Music]
how's it going everybody I'm here with
Rue from R's goofy growing and the seed
to harvest podcast how are you doing
today R good good good I'm doing really
good dude we're here R in the river it's
amazing we're smoking bunch of we yep
yep yep enjoying stud yeah yeah oh been
enjoying them since before they even
started you know what I'm saying so yeah
it's been good so this all started with
a phone call that we had about two
months ago yeah correct correct and I
was like man I think I mentioned going
to R you're like I like R I'm like you
want to go and then next thing you know
you're here there you go man yeah like
you said you know you're on the right
path when [ __ ] just starts happening for
you yeah when [ __ ] falls into place you
know you're on the right path I said I
just I I've always believe squeak will
gets the oil so yeah you said it I was
like what's the worst that could happen
he just says all right I'll might see
you there you know what I'm saying yeah
so there you go so but yeah you said
come on and I I got my money for flight
me here I am you yeah man it's going to
be an amazing weekend I love this I love
this venue I love everything about the
event just the the people are great it's
nice weather you can't go wrong there's
a lot of good lead as far as variety
we're going to see tons of everything
right there's good good deps that are
coming down right now that are fresh I
love those there's good indoor there's
good hash there's good everything y y y
we're smoking so flora and Flame Donny
burger that that rosin is next level
dude that's the best stuff we've been
smoking yeah been loving it all the r
yeah that St is man the flavor we get
off getting off of all we we smoke some
white Thorn Rose a little bit ago you
got turn white Thorn Rose for the first
time that is like you said that is a
good make you feel good it just makes
you good and it tastes good I feel like
it's not it's not too strong it's not
too weak either it's just perfect it
kind of feels like What's um how you
kind of like I imagine be like when you
get high for like I like that good that
good vibe you know what I'm saying they
gives you like a good vibe it's like a
warm hug for your ancesters that's what
it feels like like oh
yeah yeah but this and then what else
did we smoke we smok some of that 11
coffers we smok the big joint of that
yeah that was really good from planta
that was really good we smoke some SF
caner
cherry cherry and some of that Nemo
Skittles yeah the Nemo Skittles is fire
yeah yeah yeah all SK candies all skitt
and five yeah so what else are you
looking for weed wise what other things
would you like to smoke this weekend uh
I'm one I'm looking to try some of your
sativas you've been saying that so I
always been trying those out so I'm I'm
always looking for a good sativa yeah we
got super silver from Flor Flav it's
organic gluing soil [ __ ] amazing it's
some of the best weed that I have with
me I do got a bunch of variety yeah try
and then I can't wait to see everybody
else's stuff like I'm super excited we
got seeds here we got a booth you're
going to be pre-rolling some pre-rolls
tomorrow I've already met Marlin yeah
Marlin dude like stop by that is
awesome so what's going to happen on
your podcast on satday since you're not
there uh there's that fill in I told
them I might try to come in if I can't
get reception so yeah they'll just
they'll do it I'm okay so it's a
blessing and a curse I would like to
communicate with friends post stories on
Instagram I'm happy to be disconnected
I'm 100% on board with the phone not
working and I'm going to be okay for the
weekend and I'm going to really enjoy my
friends and not tune in to the phone too
much cuz yeah yeah exactly I mean you
get the tune out tune everything out
it's getting just for a little bit every
once in a while it's for taking we post
on Monday or whatever but like I just uh
you know there's so much to to absorb
the next weekend yeah you know as far as
different
experiences you don't have to post it
right there and then you can post later
oh yeah so you just be in the moment
capture it and then keep on living man
yeah I mean we're here at the canest
canest Town yeah yeah yeah H Fest T is
uh going to be amazing we had an event
next month I'll be going to that I'm
going basically doing the same kind of
setup or we do little interviews and
have a lot of fun yeah s like a great
time man I wish I'd go into that but so
Al Cana got to go next year bro we got
to get him out here yeah hell yeah dude
we got all the no so what we have to do
is every year that they have the event
we go and we invite one new person there
you go right so next year El K come on
baby event come on next do it you're
next come on baby yes hell yeah keep it
super limited so like every year gets a
little bigger but not too much bigger
I'm down I'm down to do it let's do that
that's not like a great yeah dude the
Royal gold put us in the sponsorship
area with the tent we got a we're under
a tree their name is
gold they are gold dud Royal gold is a
great company I use f Royal
gold you know I use Royal gold in my
backyard i' I've Tred all the different
soils out vital with royal gold are my
Su go yeah I want to try them out yeah
it's some of there it's really good yeah
like I said I'm uh I want to try to get
like a good like a 7 gallon fabric pot
going with some organic something soil
just all that their T is really good and
everything they make is really good it's
a good company I feel like they're very
authentic and genuine and you know
they're thr up in this area a whole
bunch of passionate people work for the
company yeah yeah for sure for sure they
love it yeah dude we'll do this again
[Music]
la la
how's it going everybody I'm here with
Lance from tur loock well from Grove
that makes the tur loock that's it one
of my favorite things of the whole world
especially the Kier you guys maybe get
rid of a whole bunch of glass containers
I still use mine for salsa so I do I put
the TP lock in the glass containers and
that's cool so they'll get smashed y but
uh you know it's like we used to do
things a different way and now with the
modern advances you guys have kind of
changed the curing game game completely
and I love
it% yeah dude like they're great and you
guys have been hooking me up with t
blocks and dude like I've been giving
them out to our customers to buy seeds
sick cool and yeah we did that collab
bag for you know nice little surprise
and I think we have another something up
our sleeve on the horizon here but um
it's been sweet it's been sweet man and
you've been great to us and we love
being great to you I know introduced a
couple friends from Alaska that need
some uh latest greatest gens and we got
you caught up with that span ofis which
is cool catch up with you r missed you
in Berlin though I know my God Mary Jane
was ridiculous I was hand watering oh my
God I wasn't really hand taking care of
that stuff I'm like like D's got the
time now I work on the weekends honestly
I fill in on the weekends for my guys so
they can have the weekends off typically
we now have one guy that has to work out
Saturdays with me yeah but uh I have the
best staff ever like honestly the best
fire
ever we're F hunting 60 lights right now
and so my God we're going to have a ton
of new fire new different stuff 20% of
the stuff in the room is completely
weird and strange and old school or
whatever that 80% is like the candy oh
my God so but I love it all and I'm
smoking on some super silver haze this
weekend it's going to be amazing you're
talking about that I can't I can't get
wait to give that a try but I like what
you're talking about because to your
point there's a lot of guys especially
like you said with the dessert cultivars
right all this cakes and pies and and
all the candy strain so on I love how
you get into the Weir like to your point
like not a lot of people are chasing
Super Silver Haze or Lemon Haze or
headband and you know how big that is in
Europe like you and I both go over there
enough that was still it's never big
still right very relevant yeah Tangi is
relev Hash for over there they love the
Tangi hash dude it's everywhere the
really good Moroccan Tangi hash I love
it it's amazing I'm not the hugest T
Tangi flower guy but I do really love it
in hash for yeah very interesting and
what about what are you ripping on the
uh fresh fros you doing a live right now
so House of cultivar is actually doing a
bunch of stuff with my genetics or our
genetics that I've worked with Jason
huto on but they're doing some of the
freaking grape soda and grape gas
crosses that I made and some of the
apples and banana stuff that I did gosh
that's just coming out phenomenal bet
we've been smoking the live live in the
[ __ ] uh the rosin the Donnie that
works for the compy he makes this
amazing rosin and it's just like candy
and then I have some Flor and Flame we
we could probably smoke it right now you
want to try some RIS I'm always down oh
yeah everything you bring is fire so
that goes without saying but yeah 100%
yeah so flora and
Flame dude this is their rosin and it's
Donnie burger and it's maybe the best
Donnie Burger I've ever
smoked oh my gosh it's the stuff that
makes me just want to smoke more I love
the TPS on that yeah you just push on
the button there's a little bit on there
to get a nice fat
hit that is T yeah it's like candy it's
kind of
like candy popcorn tasting like in a
good way not like the negative side of
popcorn no no not the really sweet it's
just that bright kind of flavor but it's
like right there it's it's I think it
hits it hits really
solid well October 1 I'm doing a dabad
do I don't know if you're available to
come to the dabad Francisco I got uh
Marlin's going to be there I think SF
can will have some representation
Canabis Chris would probably be there
yeah yeah so it's going to be an amazing
event yeah dude it's it's it's going to
be a special event I don't do events
it's not I think so I'm going to do it I
want to do it right we got some amazing
sponsors everybody's going to have the
most [ __ ] amazing extract to SW uh we're
going to have a belt for the award Bel
belt one time thing you know you grow up
with WWF when you're when you're
bringing a belt to the table huh it's a
fight I wi man I'm definitely down
anything that you touch like I said you
you've been absolutely killing it as far
as the genetics
been a long F because you geek out on
the r you have a huge respect for land
race I know you geek out on the more
unique and in special things not just
the the trending stuff right I sometimes
think that with the market we we're
stuck on this one thing yeah that
doesn't mean we can't try to sneak
things in to get people interested
things where they're like oh yeah this
is cool it's got the look it's got the
smell maybe it has something unique
about it you know like it's exactly true
and you hear and you know this I'm sure
I have friends up here on the the hill
that they're sneaking sour d back in
they're bringing blue diamond back in
like they're bringing some of these
these fun things from kind of Circa 9s
2000 a lot of this stuff is just
reoccurring so like Don Burger is
supposed to be it's like a S1 of GMO GMO
is basically a stronger version of Kim D
so really you're getting the evolution
of Kim Kim dog like Kim dog D in my
opinion all this stuff is it came from
there like we can recognize that and we
can appreciate it and it's special for
some of smok it as long as I have to be
able to see the evolution I don't feel
special but I really feel special being
part of this bigger thing it's so
amazing that we're here and we're part
of this thing too and it's like I think
it's a mentality you and I both Carri
like for us and not toight I mean
there's some people that are so build
busy building their name and building
their brand and the Ary doesn't escape
you it's James live genetics but but
you've never made it about you you're
like me it's always been an us and we
not an i and me and like you get that
which again I think that's why you're
having success on the global stage like
seeing friends of mine from the Czech
Republic and from Italy and from Germany
coming up to your booth as spous like
dude this is the book I need this is the
book I want like that's freaking sick I
I didn't even tell any Barry Jan yeah I
had a friend flying from Austria
actually this guy's buddies with him
this guy just bet he's like he listening
to your podcast with James loud on the
flight over he's like dude he's like
that guy's killing I'm like 100% because
he cares about this community not just
about about the industry and where it's
going you know so definitely you got it
podcast is a lot of fun I just have fun
with it I have a good team that I work
with and it's like they make be and it's
just it's a group effort and it's like
it's also the group we're highlighting
the the guest right like we're
highlighting the guest and I get the
most amazing stories for people dude I
love that some of our guests are just
some of the guests I think that are
going to be like okay they might yeah
could go either either way and sometimes
they just knock it out of the park you
know it's like Julie from SK magazine
was I mean I love Julie been friends for
a long time I love John too from a stunt
back in the day and when Julie came on
the show she just the first 30 minutes
of our interview it was kind of like how
our interview went I got the same
VI catch up but like she had a lot to
say and she said it it's such a precise
way and it was so amazing and you just
never know when you're going to get
those moments with people in their life
where when you're interviewing they hit
it out of the park and I've been
fortunate enough with some of these guys
we had uh Jimmy came on from Myers Creek
genetics okay Myers Creek C he's the guy
who brought the GDP to the market right
which I love I invested in operation
down south and we found a rogue Harley
Quin Pros with GDP yeah absolutely fire
absolutely so you have a really ectic i
notic a obiously i watch them all the
time yeah you you bring on such an
Eclectic so many
that that podcast are trying to just go
for the cloud guys or the obnoxious guys
the ones who are really trying to put
themselves front there you have like
this total like I'm dating myself it's
like a beniton commercial from the 80s
like just such a variety of people I
think that's what's cool we're trying to
tell a story with the podcast right it's
the story of cannabis in the modern time
in the last 40 years what's happened how
did how do we get here and so to tell
the story properly you need as many
opinions as possible cu the opinions
stories you have you can put together
this beautiful picture right so at the
end of this the end of My Life we'll
have put together this amazing story
right yeah it's so much bigger than just
myself or any one of the guests because
it's all of us it's all of our stories
and then my contributing I just am like
so blessed to be part of this [ __ ]
amazing thing part of my French but it's
like and I can see it turn into a
documentary be honest because you and I
both have lived I just just tell one of
these guys here you know re on the in
cannabis activation it's like yeah this
is my now actually it's my 208th train
Show exper event the Cannabis industry
he's like holy [ __ ] I'm like d you have
no idea like there's just so many and so
much opportunity we've seen so much over
the years but to your point like
sometime has be a documentary right to
pause even for California you remember
man like 1990 with prop P 1996 with 215
2016 with 64 right this this state's
been through a lot on legalization you
and I have been through that ride right
I mean that itself is such a crazy story
right for sure so just for sure it's
it's so wild it is you
know yeah it's just great it's a great
time to be alive and then when you start
going deeper into like what's what's
your purpose here it's like I feel like
I don't want my purpose oh yeah great
feeling to be like okay I serve my
purpose for whatever that was I feel
like I'm serving a purpose that's much
greater than myself that we're all part
of it like I'm just like this Catalyst
for our guest and it's it's great you
know it's like I really think you are
you balance a lot man I mean that's the
thing like you just talked about earlier
but I I remember you remember another
funny story we talked about our podcast
over a mutual uh buddies at Ros Do's
house and we smoked through everything I
brought everything I grew and and
brought along and so he bought us out a
bag I mean straight out of our youth man
it it was like Mom's sandwich bag I'm
like God this smells like fire this
looks like fire I'm like where'd you get
this like I got from James I'm like in
this
bag well of course get me used to it
baggy so that's how I came up with the
doing the collab with you but I think
it's those kind of stories man and
people don't understand it's such a
tight Niche Network and again you and I
are even more unique in that that
Network expands internationally like we
have mutual friends throughout Europe
Australia yeah everywhere I run into
guys are like oh I messing with James J
X here back East I just share you on IG
buddy I working with p e I'm like my God
he's everywhere he's all over the place
so so you are J I think you're in the
perfect
place yeah I love it I'm glad that it's
working out you know it's a struggle
right now for some people and I'm pretty
happy with where I'm at right now like
it's it's it's a great place you know
it's like it is a struggle life is a
struggle so we make it through the hard
times and then the times get better and
then there's more hard times in the
future but then they get better and it's
like AB this industry is amazing though
it's like uh right when you think and
the thing with t walk is like right
you're another reason that I still
believe in new things because right when
you think you got it all figured out you
I'm I'm old right I'm not old old but
where we're gen xers so I feel like look
I I figured it all out right like that's
when like I thought I figured out with
lighting and I didn't need LED if they
were garbage the blur bols whatever now
LEDs are the [ __ ] they
perfected may they perfected them
they've improved them to amazing Dee now
with canopies and all these things but
tur it's like right when I thought I
knew how to cure weed complely along
something that makes me go [ __ ] I I
could have done it differently and this
makes the product better right minded I
mean I you triing I have friends that
hate the trim rush I love the trim rush
I'm a huge trim Rush finger trimming and
trim Rush those those are the ways and
you rough got like me I noticed with
your bud huge props to you man because
yeah there's some things that may be a
little bit better trim that came out of
the 80s but like but it's not one of
them I love I there's plenty of trikes
on those sugar leaves I love how you
don't over manicure your stuff is I'm
nice and velvet velvy they can be smoked
they're not going to get harsh not at
all not at all man so I agree with you
like the technology and that's what you
probably notice this as well that's what
we do love about the international
market is we aren't talking to people
that think they know everything they're
like hey you're from noral man you've
seen it all like you've probably come a
long way with some of the things you do
what is that yeah let me tell it's like
the friend is it sending your way at
spous like oh you want like genetics
yeah we're on top of our genetics look
at what James loud has so there's people
out there but it seems like to your
point internationally they are more like
us so they're open to this being an
evolution not a revolution an evolution
right while some others and it is again
more so symptomatic with domestic
Growers I run into you know been there
done that but doing it since I was a kid
I know everything I know and it's like
well things are constantly changing man
you know fine so definitely stuff dude
why St to catch up up here definitely
always always a pleasure man to catch up
with you yeah for sure you going to come
do another podcast I do we got get we
got to get your boy here on the show too
I know man we got to get he jokes around
about being my uh he's he's only seven
years younger eight years younger than
me yet I'm his uncle evidently with the
same last name so right got to keep the
Lambert strong in the in the uh business
here yeah love be back on it Emerald cup
is coming up so I think we're going to
run up the way for that yeah I'm getting
a TRL tattoo we were talking about this
yes I'm getting a TRL tattoo on my chest
this is real guys nothing but the best
nothing with the best dude represent you
know definitely man we'll appreciate it
thank advertising
M branded for life good Stu
[Music]
[Applause]
how's it going everybody I'm here with
anak's perform at reg in the river 2024
on Sunday how are you doing today I'm
doing fine thank you me absolutely
thanks for coming on this interview man
you're the first you're the first artist
I'm interview I'm good friends with
Marlin Asher oh yeah we we're going to
get some good I'm I'm a G that I'm a G
that that's right yeah so what do you
think of reg you this your first reg on
the river first my first time coming reg
on the river and all I can say is a
wonderful Vibes already so what part is
are you from well I am from St Mary and
um between Kingston and
oers you know what I mean
so um frequently in Kingston excellent
you know like every day or every other
day yeah you know what I mean I like how
is you like what is absolutely 20 years
ago 20 years ago 20 years ago for come
forward man absolutely I even went I
went to church in elos on the hill I was
staying at a resort and they invited me
to go to church and they said there's a
reg I said I'm in there's a reg
they they were at the was as the sun was
coming up at dawn they had church
service on Sunday yes the most beautiful
amazing Services I've ever been well I
live I live 20 minutes away from o wow I
live nearby the beach yeah um I'm doing
a Airbnb there right now like a Healing
Center too excellent you know what I
mean so that's why why I'm out here
promoting um my music and these
initiatives ex to get people really
involved to you know what I mean cuz
we're seeking business partners to to
really bring forth this joyful thing
that we call Bliss you know what I mean
because there's too much war and
violence in the world right now so we
have to do what we can do as as activist
to put things in place to you know what
I mean keep the Consciousness alike is
amazing place yes man yes man you should
come forward don't don't go like you
want to come to Jamaica you for being
Jamaica every
year yeah yeah
man excellent so you that's about the
the the the strains you you do mix of
the strains yeah I make genetics I do I
do what type of genetics cuz when you
say mixed chain you know we as Jamaican
we smoke the natural herbs yeah so is it
when you mix it is it still natural is
it is it still not so so I made genetics
for St Vincent I'm going with Marlon
later this year to St Vincent the gr
we're going to present to the minister
of Agriculture a collection of seeds
that we made specifically for them with
a banana cross because of the island and
their history with bananas I went there
and talked about cannabis with Marley in
2018 and 19 and so I promised that I was
going to make genetics and bring it to
them this year we're coming through with
our promise we're bringing banana
crosses we have 20 different banana
crosses we're gifting to the country
right that can be for the country for
the people they're meant to give out to
everybody it's all about life life is
about giving back this culture and
Community is back so so when a genetics
is is like is is a seed I do seeds and I
do clones okay so when you're giving
away now like say you go to Jamaica or
or or um the the Trinidad and tobo you
give away the seeds we give away the
seeds we give the seeds to the people
okay we give clean seeds clean we we
test our seeds making sure they don't
have any virus or bacteria like so
everything's passive paging yeah test
and pathogen clean okay that's good M We
Roll big J
okay so what's that stain
called This is a sour diesel times Girl
Scout cookies okay s diesel Girl Scout
cookie
[Music]
yeah actually that one tastes more like
super silver
haze okay that's super silver super is
the 1997 Super Silver Haze
cut how's that flavor taste good
man yeah right this
taste
[Music]
yeah yeah I not try
so you need an aaki strain yeah in
Jamaica we need a Lambs bread cross yeah
man Orange Hill times lamb B CL you have
the Orange Hill yeah I have some seeds
from Orange that Marlin got when he us a
j you get you got some orange seeds L
Bread on orange man that would be a good
cross yeah man that that be a good cross
I don't think anybody's done that yet
either that I know of but I love
gentics yeah you have you have next
sativa down there call original um
original MAA yeah it's like it's like
it's kind of findy but it's sativa but
it's the original sativa if you can get
that
Str that would have been good
yeah yeah make a special place yeah
that that
man
gja when you come
Jamaica me me bring you on my farm oh
yeah a little farm not biging them doing
you know I
mean what I'm going like uh a mixture of
you know what I mean um Tangi you know I
mean cookie yeah man when you come
Jamaica man line up on some Mig gam some
real Jamaican stre so it's nice to be
here in County nice to be here in the
county Li first time in on boat yeah
yeah first time here and it's a joy do
you know more yeah just him just link up
a while ago yeah he the guy picture and
so he's my connection to the scene to
the scene with yeah with for sure he
bringing me to Reg I mean I used to get
shows in the 90s before I knew him miror
time Hall in San Francisco okay Bernie
spear with uh who was Bernie spear he
Mouse
and Zulu Zulu
spear Zulu spear is badass man and I I
took uh I took some mesculin
and it's like LSD right and the mesculin
was super strong and and they come out
with Spears in they like you know they
got traditional [ __ ] it's amazing you
know and then seeing that when you're
tripping one the most profound
experiences ever you get you get a
result own there you know yes sir B
Spirit canot you can never goong with
ber spear can't can't go wrong with you
Bernie spear is from s to is from like a
parish near St Mary so I'm from St M
burn exper I'm St that's like next door
right you know what I mean yeah some of
the most amazing musicians have come out
of Jamaica Lots definitely definitely
definitely without I doubt you
know yeah man and we are the ones them
right now where
really keeping that energy alive keeping
that spiritual energy alive in the
Western Hemisphere right now you know
what I mean yeah so what do you
think why why do you think so many
amazing artists come out of Jamaica you
think it's partially the struggle and
the ones that have made it past the
struggle and then they can sing about it
well that's a part of it the struggle is
a part of it but the culture too and and
and then the bloodline itself you know
right for sure yeah black people on a
whole is is is is more lean towards art
and and culture you know I mean yeah so
the culture of Raa far to is is is is is
is a big influence and why so much
artist comes out of Jamaica cuz if it
wasn't for really R far right and this
music called reg music you know what I
mean
see even I and I would even be here here
right now you see me holding a
conversation with you know I mean so is
a j you know say the them that had laid
and had set the pav the way before I and
I yeah you know I mean um they did a
wonderful work and is that really make I
can be here right now Bob Marley you
know I mean Peter touch you know I mean
same burning spare all of these on yeah
they the way for everybody name long
call you know I mean so you know I mean
is a Jo you know I mean to be as a
younger generation carry on to carry
thech message
yeah and there's a lot I feel like
there's a lot of responsibility with
something like that you know I I think
there's there's so much importance
that's for me is not an option we can't
fail so we have to get the real
connection them just like connect with
the eye now so we have to go and get the
right connection them to the right
people see May thing flourish we were
just talking about this earlier when
when you're on the right path Things
fall into place and it's like we're here
today because of that both of us you
know serously that is it you know I
think it's just talking you know what I
mean yeah it's amazing when you're
you're on the right path right and then
you know what you're supposed to be
doing on this planet you know what I
mean when you have that connection like
it's not about yourself but when you
figure out where you fit into this whole
world your purpose Purpose Driven Life
is the most important purpose find a
mission you know I mean and then you
just TR on the mission you know and
music both music I work in cannabis but
both music and cannabis make the world a
better place right at the end of all
this we're contributing to a better
world right and there there's a lot of
responsibility with that but like we're
just doing the best we can do we put it
out there and it's pretty amazing yes
man yes man is a man a yeah man give
thanks far you know yeah man is a yeah
[Music]
how's it going I'm here with Steve at re
on the river 2024 from Steve's from
canest he's putting on event about a
month it's going to be amazing I'm going
to be there what's up Steve what's going
on brother it's real good to meet you
finally in person here too and it's nice
doing that here in the shade out here at
r on the roof got this nice big
tent official Lounge over here we're
kicking back we got some retailers we
got some Farmers some makers some of the
finest hash and rosin and NorCal some
Fest flower our Bud bar and the dab bars
over here and just chilling out serious
made this little little spot to kick
back and so you got an amazing you got
you have an amazing event coming up can
you tell us a little bit about can
canest yeah I would love to uh canest
was born uh in 2016 yeah the first time
we ran it a few times at our local uh
Fairgrounds yeah and then they changed
laws about how we could do the events
right and so we had to get so we waited
a few years and then during co uh we
couldn't really do events in California
so we're like let's take this thing on
the road like we intended to and anyway
yeah so we to we went out to Chicago and
St Louis and Oklahoma City and and then
um last year was the first time we had
canest again in humbal since 2018 and it
was a great you know cannabis family
reunion I would say I love it so I'm a
big fan of kacon my friend Dave mesford
who recently passed on 420 was one of
theing guys with kacon right on right on
and yeah I mean I love the evolution of
the Cannabis Cup whether it's every cup
High Times kis cup the evolution of what
it's turned into is really cool and it's
also turned into the like r on the river
that are continuing the Legacy now that
we can have a smoking area right yeah we
just brought this whole Zone here it's
all regulated the DCC was here meeting
was today and all this and right just
making sure people do whatever you know
wait for their envelopes what they're
supposed
to and uh you know and um it's just a
community event up here Canabis is a
bigger thing to our community up here
it's really a experience of generational
kind of thing and whatnot so it it
totally makes the world a better place
and we can all agree on that you know
completely no it brings a lot of good
people together all the people I know
yeah and and you look at the generations
right we have this I'm a little older
now and we have this up and cominging
generation of passionate cannabis
enthusiasts people that have grew up
with the plan for the time they were
born right like
definitely with technology and the plant
and I think they're going to be carrying
the torch eventually well we put the
torch in our logo this year for can
ofest because we really believe that's
what we're trying to do and that's kind
of what our community is doing right now
coming together I feel like we're going
through a Cann ofis Renaissance
absolutely you know I really do and um
it's bringing some of the real heads
together to navigate the future you know
that's really how it is and there's a
lot of things that have shifted yeah uh
you know concerts in general festivals
and then the whole cannabis World kind
of gotten turned around the last few
years I would say and so we're trying to
represent the future of uh bringing that
together well we'll bring in this whole
thing to other events for have our full
Festival proper in humbold and other
places you know yeah I mean it's a
beautiful thing carry on Legacy right of
something that's so much bigger than
ourselves on all levels with the stuff
that people are doing now and I think
there's still browny pushers there's
people still changing the game trying to
make a better plan a better product for
the end user something that's more
special that has you know different
flavors or different effects got me into
this I started you grow my own herb yeah
when I was like 16 I grew a few plants
and put them out in the back of the ball
park where I grew up playing baseball
and whatnot cuz I learned about compost
yeah and that the soil was active and
super rich and I thought if I was going
to plant some weed in the woods and not
have to go back to it as often I needed
to find some soil that was rich could
hold a lot of moisture and nutrients and
stuff and I was learning about that [ __ ]
at school and they've been dumping all
these um leave piles but sweeping all
the streets outside of Philly wow in the
back of the park they' have been dumping
this [ __ ] for 50 60 years yeah so there
was some compost piles at the far end of
that that were just I planted my first
place there and the light came on and
then I moved to California right when
they started writing scripts and I was
growing my own weed in my house like
soon as I moved to California I was like
oh okay now it's legal and I have this
little insurance card right and then I
open my own grow shop so I've been
helping will grow for over 23 years it's
awesome and then doing the whale stuff
but producing this whole community
events is kind of like that's my true
love and for sure that's kind of where
it all comes together yeah that's where
I spending my time right now mostly I
love the collected Consciousness right
like all this effort from people in
these different directions all coming
together and events like this happening
and events like yours how that are
happening and how it ties into the
industry and you know it's it's pretty
amazing I was born at the time 77 and
we're 76 here 76 yeah so we're the same
they're basically the same age right and
yeah I'm a dragon so yeah same same fire
dragon Scorpio Dragon yeah I'm at the
last the tail end of in 77 cuz Chinese
New Year
end but uh yeah dude we're a special
time because when we grew up it wasn't
popular it wasn't the popular opinion
that cannabis is okay it was a small
group of people that said no it is okay
they're going to go to jail for it
they're going to do whatever and the
kids today are being brought up in a
world that's normalizing it slowly but
surely right 100% way different than
when we were younger and people were
getting 32 year 100 Year prison
sentences some of even like Richard Deli
served 32 years of 100 Year sentence
100% yeah no it's a different world and
it's um it's way more open yeah we can
be attracts more people and so many
people have found the medicine because
of well we can talk about things like
this podcast all the time we can like
pop up now in the middle of reg on the
River where everybody's been smoking
weed forever yeah so it's almost an
interesting scenario being here I ree
with like the legal weed scene right in
the like heart of the outlaw cannabis
culture right right absolutely so it's
like originally it was like well I don't
know how are people are going to react
to like legal weed being in the space
but our whole Community is so rooted in
the what the future of cannabis looks
like yeah and we have like Legends of
the past it's rooted in what the future
can be truly and it's it's undiscovered
I feel and it's like well the potential
is so great who knows what's going to
happen but the potential is so great you
can see the direction the trajectory is
going in the right direction at the end
of the day 100 years from now cannabis
will fully be normalized we won't have
any of the haters like we do now there
might be some haters or whatever but it
won't be the same right people will
understand it a lot more you know
especially not growing up in a world
where they criminalized it and they made
it they made us Outlaws right we were
it's a plant we're talking about a plant
here that they turned all of us into
Outlaws and said we were bad yeah and
now that's changing over that we're
normal people too we're not hurting
anybody and I feel like as long as
you're not hurting anybody what's the
harm you know what I mean like you
should be able you should have the
freedom live a country of Freedom you
should have the freedom to consume
things that don't hurt other people uh
you know obviously you don't want stuff
that could potentially harm somebody but
at the same time like we should have the
right to use plant medicine too what
that that's just a such a crazy thing
right it's it's not just a plan that's
the problem right so it's such a special
plan that it competes in the market with
all these Pharmaceuticals right and but
they're going to have to accept it
they're going to have to we used plant
medicine for thousands of years you know
and we need to go back to it because
when you talk about homeostasis and the
body being in an optimal condition
cannabis can be a big part of that
whether it's neurologically or
physically so that's say it's special
it's a fact yeah it's uh it's been
bringing people
together it's around the Vive yeah you
know people start vibing out on their it
makes the world a better place it
totally makes the world a better place
eventually like this make my life a
better place for sure right and then
yeah and then being able to like you're
saying talk about this on here and do
this catus like thing out loud something
that we love right to be able to to
speak about it to the world you know
it's just we don't have to be in the
shadows right in in 2015 we did the yes
we can Community parade nice and we it
was it was humble's first cannabis
parade and not only the person only and
we've done it a few times since we'll do
it again this us this year for can ofest
yeah really on the Sunday morning we
come March it through town and it's a
cannabis Pride Parade yeah and the first
time we did this we had a whole a whole
crew of us we wrote all these
affirmations kind of like you know out
of the shade and into the light you know
and really it is about being proud of
something and having to not hide what
you care so much about or necessarily be
looked in a way that doesn't even align
with yeah what's going on you know I
feel you it is a positive plan and it
makes the world a better place at the
end of the day man it's just such a
positive thing
that a lot of us find comfort in it a
lot of us you know we our social network
is built around it you know I feel like
it's a it's a beautiful thing and then
this whole Community was built around it
we on the shoulders of cannabis
definitely right here at the heart of
Ray G on the river that couldn't be more
true right it's like this whole this
whole venue here at the mat Community
Center and the other businesses that
make this happen and support what we're
doing
um it's all built on the Canabis culture
I mean I feel like if you look at the
community that feeds the community right
the trickle down economics within the
community yeah uh where it goes down
where how how it's supposed to work in
in the real world which it doesn't right
but in this community it does cuz these
people feed the other people in the
community they they buy stuff from the
other people in the community we all
support each other and I feel like the
canis industry is really good and
humbled even more so with everywhere
with within the money the cash system is
where it's at though I've been here for
20 I lived the rumble for 24 years it
didn't take long to figure out what was
going on as far as you know I opened up
a groc store and I didn't even know
anybody about tomatoes in we yeah I mean
I used to go in Garden we had to say
tomato garden they were a great customer
and a client and good friends and
supporters of us for years House and
Garden was something that uh we brought
yeah to the US and U from Holland I
thought let's connect humbold and
Holland nice what are they using for
nutrients over there and just tapped
into that yeah I got a lot of friends in
the
industry uh Josh Freeman he sold to
growa he sold growa to Botanicare way
back in the day or but yeah I mean I
grew up this area a lot of not not this
area but California yeah for sure and so
the connections are deep you know
great and then we're all tied to the
Grateful Dead which is even more of a
wild thing right like there's this whole
Grateful Dead tie within the bay area of
people that love the dead that have
great stories about the dead that are
more or less an evolution of the
Grateful Dead in our own expression
right and that's that's the most amazing
thing to be part of that as well from
California it's like Logan Brewery I use
that as an example all the time Tony
McGee I believe he is an evolution of
the Grateful Dead in his own expression
and just as powerful and just as amazing
creative expression yeah and it's like I
do my stuff and it's it evolves out of
the Grateful Dead like the Cannabis
scene evolved out of the Grateful Dead
too of course of course and other things
too but the Grateful Dead was a heavy
influence and and part of the reason
we're here today that whole movement in
the 60s and 70s I mean that's why you
know this we brought we're bringing oot
and friends to danif fest with Steve
kimok Melvin Seals Jason Crosby uh St K
son I forgot Johnny Kim and we're going
to be doing podcast all weekend there so
it's going to be a blast dude it's going
to be a lot D yeah I can't wait it's
going to be epic we wanted to bring the
festival goers together with the
cannabis event goers because it's a
tough thing to do we've been a lot of
events seen you know a lot of times
people don't show up for the music or
they don't show up for the weed it's
like it's always hard to hit both sure
because of the way the laws kind of make
it separate so we've always tried our
best to like integrate what we're doing
and normalize the herb so it kind of
Fest we do it on a 3 and 1 12 acre part
on the bay beautiful weekend of the year
at the weekend after Labor Day and it's
always just like the weather that time
of year is like it'll be like 73 degrees
and sunny yeah you know it's just like
the perfect weather um I don't know
we're really looking for fall late
summer well it's not that far from that
we're a month away right yeah yeah we
got like five weeks so we have reg of
the river five weeks is your event and
then another three weeks I'm doing the
Dabo in San Francisco for MAA oh right
I'm hosting it I got Nick T coming out
we got Marlon hopefully he's performing
there right on uh it's going to be very
exclusive it's not private it's
inclusive but it's also exclusive cuz
there's only so many scenes oh yeah it's
not like these big events we got I think
we can put 70 in there and at least 10
guests Ed roseval is definitely going to
be there and his wife it's awesome came
CEST last year we had an interview with
me and the Royal gold crew you're
amazing Ed Ed is a character that's a
character yeah had L good friends pretty
sick being here right at the back of the
main ball amazing break on the river
blessings many
blessings thank you very much for your
time I do
[Applause]
yeah even when we're [ __ ] around
we're not [ __ ] around
[Music]
n
oh
[Music]
breaking down
how's it going we're here day two reg in
the river
2024 I survived day one somehow
miraculously I actually got sleep last
night it's incredible uh we got a
amazing lineup tonight really good music
we saw Nick a te this morning went
swimming in the river uh smoked a bunch
of weed did all the fun stuff and now
we're here at the booth we've got John
and Sean from Cutting Edge down there
and we're just chill selling books and
uh smoking weed with
everybody how's it going I'm here with
Sean from Cutting Edge we're at reg in
the river 2024 how are you doing I'm
doing amazing man I am so glad to have
reg on the river back uh last time I was
here was like
2016 and Cutting Edge has always been a
part of regga so to see it come back and
to be back like in a community level not
in a big corporate showout level and
like hey this is The Vibes it's amazing
I'm so I I love the the vibe here it's
amazing we're definitely on the same
vibration I can tell by your shirt right
uh but yeah it's it's been an amazing
journey so far I we're on day two we got
one more day uh I've been here since
Thursday you as well yeah it's been hot
it's been hot good line up great lineup
and I think today the music is going to
be just off the charts it's going to be
wild we got clie buds tonight that's
going to be great I can't wait for that
uh and then Marlin tomorrow night's
going to be amazing yes I always love
hearing marlin so what are you guys
doing here you guys are one of the main
sponsors yep so we've always been a part
of the Matti um ever since like early
early '90s before cutting edge even
existed right and uh yeah we wanted to
throw some some good times good vibes
here we're just giving out shirts just
hanging out with the the community it's
a lot of fun you guys let us use your
table we're there slanging books smoking
with everybody well that's the thing I
mean people show up and they see the
Royal gold Booth they see The Cutting
Edge booth and they're all people that
have fire so we're just trading smells
trading jars and enjoying to see like
everyone's work that they put in over
the year I got at least 50 different
samples from people some stuff that I've
[ __ ] never seen before we I saw some
Nigerian land race amazing yes did you
see that nug that was just so super
scraggly but the nose on it wild he's
going to be on we're going to film them
tomorrow I want him to come down and
talk about a podcast and get hooked up
but yeah like and then I found the real
a sour diesel I've been searching for it
forever and I tell people like yeah I'll
look at it but this guy was like if it's
not the real one I won't have hurt
feelings just tell me the truth and he
showed it to me and I was like I can't
believe it's the real one and I was in I
wanted it almost not to be the real one
I had my mindset that it was going to be
another fck fake version or or not even
fake but not just not the that I
remember right and so I was totally
Blown Away to smell that smell after all
these years and and this cuz sometimes I
think your memory can be mistaken after
time passes your memory might interpret
things differently right but then when
you smell it you're like oh no my memory
was right they weren't the right ones
all these years keep smelling and you're
like you want it to be that sour you
want it to be that and just like the
super silver haze that flower you showed
me yesterday I gave it to John and he
was like that's it it's like the The
Vision Quest is over but to find the
original sour I'm still looking for I
have it over in a sample over in the
we're going to smoke it little we're
going to have to go smoke that well the
funny thing with the the sour that I
remember is it wasn't just burnt Tire
burnt rubber smell which most of the
sours I've seen are more on that with a
very little bit of citrus and this one
has the balanced Citrus it's loud like
when you open the bag it was and this
was depths and you open the bag I was
like wow so yeah pretty impressive it's
like the funk that hits you but that's
the thing is like it's always burnt
tires that's what that's what people
think sour is now and it's not if you
don't have that Citrus back it has to
have like this citrusy balance right and
and it's also got this pungent Funk to
it too but yeah it's like nose burning
and not just from that not just from the
burnt Tire you know cuz that's and
that's what people think sour is too I
would say that most people all the
people that have shown me S last year
sorry guys but it's been that burnt Tire
chem 91 is smell more than the sour that
I remember right so what do you have
there oh dude this is something special
that's a super silver haze joint that I
rolled nice this you gave me one of
those last night yes Donnie Burger live
rosin from floran flame whoa let me see
uh smell that
[Music]
whoa whoa I really am enjoying anything
Donnie burger like well so I I have
that's delicious I this this is the best
I've had I'm not super impressed with
the flour but as far as a washer and
then I have GMO Ro in here so we were
smoking the GMO and then this and
comparing and you could tell you
definitely tell the lineage in that all
we need is some chmd and then we could
really do the trifecta but uh yeah wow
and the dip device too so you do you
know Matt from dip device I do not I got
this at uh squash off in Barcelona it's
really funny cuz I met so I was in a
hotel in Mexico City for a Cannabis
Conference and it's actually where I
bought this shirt ni but I ran into Matt
at the hotel bar cuz he didn't know
Spanish and he was trying to order beer
oh wow and we started talking and he
gave me one of these and I was like no
way I've never seen this before and now
see them everywhere and they're so I'll
tell you what I do like my nectar
collector my boy Uncle Stoner Big Ups
Uncle Stoner but he gave me a nectar
collector at uh
the the squash off in Barcelona this
year and I love that thing I love for
the turs but this is the convenience
right here and it does get more
convenient especially if you like
extract and you don't want to smoke big
dabs you can smoke 50 50 of these in an
hour and you'll probably be high but wow
feel really good that's delicious that's
absolutely super super clean floor and
Flame they're metric they're down at
Oakland they do living soil in soil beds
two-tier Game Changer I feel like Chris
Castle the one of the he's an owner and
head grower he is amazing he just
crushes it and he believes in living
soil and I I also
love living soil you know yeah I use
cocoa I I do other substrates for my
mom's I use grodent but living soil for
flavor yeah it's hard to beat you really
can't I mean I know it even being on the
fertilizer side of things there's
certain things you're looking for and
different Expressions you get from
either really good biology or just
straight feeding programs oh yeah you
have a plant in Rockwall in a commercial
facility vers a living soil I mean it's
a whole different product you're going
to see a completely different end
product well expression is different the
the and the effect like especially like
I would I would argue that the effect is
different in almost 100% of the my
experiences with it if you have two
things side by side you're going to get
a different effect yeah especially if
you look at the tpping profile just the
actual by itself y but also you know
they look different and I think a lot of
people love that Instagram weed and
there's nothing wrong with that I'm not
going to put anybody down for liking
beautiful looking flower right but at
the same time some of the ugliest [ __ ]
I've smoked over the years is some of
the best [ __ ] and so you can't count out
the ugly kid you know exactly well I
mean you get like a really funky IPA
that's brewed in someone's basement it
might be the best beer you've ever had
but you can't you can't make 12 30 racks
of that real quick where PBR comes in
you can't even replicate those again
sometimes they're like you know it's
like and that's the boutique flower you
know it's like it's grown once and it's
a certain way well the same guy grows it
and it's slightly different variables
right so like whether the humidity was
just slightly different or the
temperature was slightly different
because the outside temperature like
threw it off or the outside humidity had
impact it can come out not completely
different but it can come out a slightly
different expression it's just like
micro brew where you doing you know and
I I love that about Boutique products
you know I think the market needs
consistency with products like Cutting
Edge right sure but on the grower side
just like on the micro beer side we can
have those Boutique products that have
slight variation and and appreciate them
equally exactly and you guys have a
really good product too it's very
consistent you
guys believe in the plant I feel like
John is a amazing contributor to
everything that we've done here the
reason I'm here the reason you're here
is because of people like John and
they're the generation that we really
need to acknowledge now while they're
still here and uh yeah it's great to be
part of all this and having him here and
seeing like these younger kids too like
you got younger kids coming they're in
their 20s and they're excited about
cannabis they're excited about nutrients
all the other things yeah it's beautiful
dude it's like there's so many different
directions you can go and be successful
but there's nothing better than getting
started early and finding what you love
when you're young yeah exactly exactly
and like people like John that's how
they started like John started growing
when he was 14 hitchhiked his way out
here and started growing in the hills
and learned from other people this isn't
something that you can just I mean
nowadays a little different you can pull
up something on the Internet learn how
to grow weed but to really do it from
the the heart and like of what the
culture really is uh you got to learn
from the other people that have started
before you right and and if we go
generational like we can learn from the
previous generation who learned from the
previous generation if we think we can
do it all ourselves we we're kidding
ourselves right and so Improvement
happens over time whether it's breeding
or whether it's nutrients and
understanding how to make the plant work
more efficiently grow better you know
improve the quality like
we're doing the same thing but two
different sides of the coin right we're
both trying to make the plant Express
itself better or help the plant become
optimal right we don't drink and we
don't we don't want to have that I will
drink every once in a
sure and I'll have a crappy free roll
every once in a while too but but that's
not what we want to see for this
industry or for this culture and that's
why we're doing what we're doing I mean
the work that you're doing from a
genetic standpoint from a culture
standpoint it's like ungodly you know
like absolutely amazing oh I'm I'm just
filling my part of the gap of the
industry you know what I mean I feel and
when you find what you're doing in the
industry that you were supposed to be
doing with your life it's a really good
feeling I mean I know that you can
relate because I feel like you're doing
exactly what you were meant to do on
this planet you know you're following
John's footsteps and really have stepped
up and and it's amazing to see that
generational where where you can you can
it fir hand where the two generations
are still there cuz sometimes that's
it's not the case you know what I mean
exactly well I me in in our situation
like I don't have to do anything right
I'm doing this cuz I want to and John
brought me to a hill when I was 14 that
changed my life that made me move west
that made me understand something
different about the plant and then I get
to the point where okay John's in his
late 60s what is Cutting Edge going to
be you know corporate companies offer us
a buyout and I look at that and go John
we could be offered a billion dollars
with a B I don't give a [ __ ] we're not
taking the money because it's not about
that and nobody else is going to stand
up and do that and we've watched it
happen over and over with all of our
competition so we've got to kind of
stand up and fight for the community got
to stand up and fight exactly for sure I
mean it's happened over and over we look
at all these nutrient companies that
sold out to bigger companies and they
Chang the formula or do whatever and
it's hard when you take the the life
blood out of a company that built it
from the ground up and you lose that for
sales yeah yeah you can't sell your soul
for sales I mean you can people do it
but that's not really sell the soul of
the company either like companies I mean
you can sell a company you can sell
intellectual property you can sell
recipes you can sell genetics you can
sell all these things that that we can
that we can quantify but like on the on
this the level of the soul of the
company that built that company that
struggled to be successful you can never
fully sell that because it's hard to
even describe what it actually is for
one thing and it's like because it's so
many little things that have happened
over a period of such a long time
typically like for you guys and the
evolution of where John came from to get
where you guys are now oh yeah is wild
you know but even you from the time you
were 14 to where you're at now so many
things have happened so many that have
yeah so many things in the world that
have happened and then I mean on top of
that so many things that have happened
to you yeah it's just this is an amazing
story and it's amazing to be part of all
this I mean yeah it's it's beautiful and
then we're here at ree it's funny coming
home and it feels like coming home and I
see a lot of people I haven't seen in a
long time I'm seeing people I've never
met before who watch the podcast which
is amazing that's a cool feeling that
grow my genetics they're giving me
genetics back hearing stories about my
genetics being grown 10 years ago and
stuff like that where you know it's it's
funny how people remember stuff and you
know and how we're interpretting
interpreted in the industry you know and
it's like this is the community this is
the community this event like this is
the Cannabis Community for Northern
californ this is the heart of the
Cannabis community and there's so many
other aspects of it but this is
like where Modern cannabis came from is
these Hills you know and more so the the
the mental side of it the the so as far
as people smoke weed all over the world
right but how it evolved in Humble and
people had to go hide out and grow
indoors we wouldn't be doing that if it
wasn't for humble because they were
growing outdoors and didn't want to get
caught so they started growing indoors
now indoor is super popular and there's
nothing wrong with either one I love
indoor I love outdoor I love mix light
and Greenhouse and you name it yeah but
uh we're here because of the people in
in this
community they pushed this forward so
that we could be here today regga regga
on the river has always been like a
buying show yeah it's always been July
end of July early
August first depths are done everyone's
here slanging like that's what it was
always like it was
before I feel like now is I don't see
the people slanging packs there's like
right people maybe hustling a little bit
but what I see is people that are
passionate about weed sharing samples
and giving samples to each other and
like us talking about stuff and US
seeing land race genetics that Nigerian
was crazy that Sour Diesel that I saw
was crazy I've gotten joints from a ton
of people I saw this
crazy flower from last year I smoke some
flower I smoke the white B Road it was
from last season that was really good
you did too
you yeah and John gave me that three
months ago I preserved it and like I was
like saving it and couldn't be a better
place than ree to smoke that you know
exactly yeah it's it's uh definitely
some really good weed going around
there's a lot of good stuff there's a
lot of mediocre stuff too but there is
some really I mean you're going to find
good stuff here there's people that love
weed and people that just know weed and
I saw some old school hash too I just SM
yeah that you saw sunshine has
good she's going to come on the podcast
I smoke some with the Dipper great yeah
that stuff's amazing well and that
that's like the nostalgic side of
cannabis where there's not a huge market
for anything like that but when I see
something like that I'm like oh yeah I
like smoking that and I hit it and I'm
like reminds me of 199 [ __ ] 6 y you
know when we got hashed in the Bay Area
and like the it's got that
pliability it's not full melt or
anything like that it's not supposed to
be it's just Play-Doh exactly that has
that kind of funky Sandalwood smell
there's like hers hers had like this
distinct Sandalwood smell that I
remember from the '90s like when I when
I rub my fingers together I'm like just
just remember that smell so a little bit
of pine comes through and you're like oh
that's the hash yeah exactly that
amazing well thank you so much for
coming on dude of course well I hope
that that we can link up soon and we you
the come I'm here with Uncle John from
Cutting Edge he is a legend and uh I'm
happy to be here with you we're sharing
a booth we're doing great things you
guys are doing great things it's lots of
fun how's ree for you hey it's great to
be back reggae is back and that's who LS
yeah yeah sold out yesterday completely
sold out completely sold out the venue
is great I love this place I've been
king for a long time uh 24 years wow 3
four years was my first R game and I
love it it's it's like coming home it's
like a lot of I'm seeing old friends I'm
seeing new people I've never met I get
to see people I see all over the world
like you guys I get to see a lot of
people a lot of different new varieties
that they've been working on yeah I
smoke them and when I get really high I
think that I know that person why do I
know that person it's actually the son
or daughter of somebody and I and I
haven't seen the son or daughter for
like 15 years and now they're in their
20s right I'm like w
it's see the legend of all of this
continues through them it's amazing I
was talking with Sean about about being
second generation and you know people
like yourself that we're on your guys'
shoulders you guys really push the
industry forward we wouldn't hear be
here today with legalization everything
without people like yourself they they
cared enough and even though it was
illegal said it's not right and the
world needs people like that and I think
that now it's our respons like my
responsibility with my podcast with my
genetics the things I do that's where I
fit in the industry and you know it's
amazing seeing people like yourself
still in the industry working with Sean
and you know I think he's doing a great
job he's a he's an amazing person and
you guys are pushing forth this this
company that's going places and that has
good ethics and a consistent product so
family business everything is made in
house
chemistry microbiology and plant
pathology labs in
house we we trust our own work cuz if we
don't get it right we take more samples
and we get it right for sure and and
just like you do you you feed on and you
you you follow a certain pathway and
then you're not happy and you back up
and you go another direction we do a lot
of backing up you know it's it's part of
that process is going and trying things
and going okay this is this is great
this is great these 10 things are not
great you know and how can we move
forward with that to where we're serving
the plant the best to where we're
optimizing the plant for specific
environments um you know I think we're
both here to do the same thing is
improve the plant or not even improve
the plant
but make it as observable as possible at
the outcome whether it's through
nutrition whether it's through genetics
they're both key elements to Growing
amazing flower it's true you know we've
always we've always used our fertilizer
to work with people who want to express
tpes yeah and you know as a chef you're
and these flavors I'm all about the
flavors you know and I've gone back to
effect too though I feel like you guys
you just have a really consistent
product you have a good recipe along
with it and then customer service is
great I always appreciate what you guys
have done as a company and how you stand
in the industry you guys are all very
everyone that works for the company is
proud to work for the company everyone
believes in the product and you that
says a lot yeah I like it when one of
the workers I over hear him talking to
somebody else and they say I love what I
do so I don't go to work every day it's
not work and cuz you know we we're
always working on something new we're
working with new people or helping
people turn around crops you know
they're in different soils they you know
they're people that get your genetics
and they want to repeat your results and
I say it's 108 Dees out here right
you know it's going to be different but
it's going to be worth it so keep going
Bri push forward push forward yeah so I
was talking to one of your employees
he's been working with the company for
20 years and he's here at re hanging out
and having a good time with his daughter
with his do yeah right so Miguel has
worked been our production manager for
over 20 years yeah we moved we moved to
Oregon we moved to White City across
from Medford but I took all the
employees with me and their amilies I
don't leave anybody behind how you have
quality and consistency if you move and
then hire all the people but his
daughter Raina is also here and she's
like I think 24 now yeah but she started
working for the company when she was
five wow I gave her a time card and
she'd come after school and I give her
she'd get little tasks to do with the
office to you know clean the keyboards
or whatever she's five years old child
labor laws back then we're
different oh yeah there's big fins for
that but but you know she's like she's
like family yeah and now she's our uh
in- housee coordinator of shipping
production and office so she oversees
everyone and make sure makes sure that
everything is flowing and she knows how
to do that just by looking at people
imagine growing up in a company and
watching these people watching your
father yeah and how he deals with people
for 20 years yeah you know it it it now
it's it's instinctive and
intuitive what's going to happen and so
she's always ahead of the game it's
great so that's why we don't need a big
company we just need a tight well-run
company well and you have you yourself
have Legacy in the industry you you a
good Legacy you've left behind a good
Legacy you're we did a podcast together
we're doing another one soon with Sean
guys are com down I'm looking forward to
it uh and you guys can check out the
facility I'm doing some trials with
different nutrients right now so I'd
love to show you kind of what we're
doing and the direction we're going and
it's a lot of
fun fun continues and yeah you know I
guess I went from being Infamous to
somewhat famous but I worked really hard
to never have a search warrant fulfilled
on
or a felony filed on me yeah that that's
not easy that's not easy sh we can't all
see the same but you know but you know
we do our best yeah I think it's one of
those things that like I think people
it's it's a tough time for a lot of
people in the industry the guys go
flower where it's like a race to the
bottom you know but you got to keep put
one flood in front of the other and
moving forward and you know you didn't
you didn't just blow up overnight you
put a lot of hard work over many years
he then started in the black market and
then evolved into an amazing business
that you have today yeah you know we
started I mean I started in
1978 yeah so there wasn't even
traditional or black market even news
you were just an
outlaw so yeah the outlaw days brought
brought me up into where you know props
2115 passed and then I saw an
opportunity just to work more closely
with different PhD scientists um one of
them being uh eler C and uh uh cure and
law at at Leaf works yeah and their PHD
PL geneticist and other small groups
like that that uh I was able to to build
on my knowledge base and also get deeper
into what plants need because you know
we have a whole p of things we can
custom blend for you that we know work a
certain way that you can see the result
of a certain couple of Turpin or turine
pop up right so well and more and more
we're talking about chemical expression
so Cho something that you can get
consistent results with where it's going
to give you same chemical compounds at
the end uh consistently each run you do
it which using the sun is very difficult
well in an indoor environment I think
it's possible where you
know for synthesizing different drugs
using cannabis or creating stuff use you
all just drug disc Discovery we're just
scratching the surface though but it
takes a consistent product and uh yeah
it's amazing it's amazing what you years
are doing do yeah and you know I kind of
backed off on growing so I could move
forward into traveling as much as I do
to all these different operations going
to Columbia yeah doing the Colombian cup
down there you guys do that every year
yeah yeah we do the Caribbean cup and
we've actually helped influence people
uh through working with black black to
to Seed Company in Santa Marta Columbia
yeah amazing people I love black C oh
yeah Carlos great guy and uh Sergio who
works for them is uh great at going out
and fighting seed he's uh got you
know so Carlo was he was busting
knowledge on me about uh Colombian gold
and why it's called colan gold and then
he was telling about how Panama it's the
same exact genetic line what expresses
differently because it's in Panama same
thing with most what most people know is
W hawen is actually the same Colombian
land race that's expressed differently
in both Jal and in Waka right in fact uh
Sergio now has the cleanest lines of
land race bu Roa and so now they're
running trials like Acres of Trials am
at their farm at at the black T company
farm and sativa nativa in order to
actually see this see this trend come
out so the changing fertilizer
requirements on some of these plants to
try to adjust to see those different is
to see p red yeah come out of BU
ROV so really cool yeah and there's
other varieties there too and a lot of
this last Caribbean Cup on July 26 we
had a lot of uh invited a lot of Growers
out of the mountains you know the Sierra
Nevada Mount de madre mountains are
right there they're e 18,000 ft tall and
snow cap right behind Santa Marta so
imagine all the different climatic
changes yeah on the front of the
mountain that faces the Caribbean and on
the back side that
faces Magdalena River at the plain right
so M they're similar they locations that
are similar but completely different uh
climate changes not climate changes but
completely different environments yeah
you know just like in Hawaii where you
have you know a shade uh hurden of rain
over one side the other side's dry yeah
you know so well it's kind of like
somoma and cadero cadero is like the
northernmost part of Sona but it's
completely different as far as like
compared to sebastan pool as far as
climate and like that banana Bel up
there it's extremely special yeah yeah
you go up to guala and there's actual an
actual bananabell close to the coast
that doesn't pull in fog right and I I
mean I knew people that were growing
there in the uh in the late 70s and
their herb was coming out amazing and
they were getting seed from Waka to grow
there amazing which is co you know the
Waka is totally different but yeah we're
down to Waka too and
guadalahara Costa Rica and Colombia
basically we're we're working with any
Growers that are passionate about
growing for plan yeah you know there's
no time for people that just want to yes
just we're just going to spend $50
million create this facility blow up a
couple of different strains and we're
going to push you know unicorn poop
out that happens all the time though
yeah right that happens the funny thing
is is like we joke about like Fu but it
happens all the time these guys are like
we're going to make money off this and
that's not only true in cannabis that's
true in in everything you know that is
true you know I was up at uh White
Salmon Vineyard uh in the fall cuz I
also go up to yaka there's some Growers
up there that I I like to drop in and
see what they're doing yeah and uh it's
Peter brm's Winery and he's you know
he's got a Vineyard he just turned 90 I
went out walked the field with him went
up the hill smoking a joint and he's
like yeah I think I'm going you know I
think this is the year I'm going to
retire and I'm like Peter you know when
you were 76 years old and you said that
and I said it was too soon now it's too
late I go you're such a legacy that you
actually have to die in this Vineyard
yeah he goes what do you mean I go do
you realize that I can never retire
either I have to die in the field this
is who we are that's what was at a
certain point you at a certain point
you're like look at
Jerry look at
Jerry he's the example man you got to
follow but uh yeah I mean once you've
created this Legacy walking away from it
you'll never be able to walk away from
it this is who you are you know and I I
feel the same way where like I'm I'm not
this is what I love doing I'm doing it
and uh you I see people like yourself
that have become successful that are
just passionate about the pl it's
inspiring it's definitely inspiring yeah
people are people you know I was talking
to the Caribbean comp about you as a
matter of fact the your seed company and
they're like oh man we're you know we
know we're going to win with our flower
but you know we looked at the seed
varieties and James loud seeds weren't
there and I was like yeah you know we
couldn't get everywhere quickly enough
in order to be able to bring him down
but next year we next year we'll make a
point of doing it and he was like yeah
you know I look at what James L's doing
and you know it's super impressive and
he's a lot younger guy but that's what
you're looking at people think wow if
you can do it through all the hard work
and sacrifice and be where you are now
and be happy they want to be there too
one day at the end of the day we all
serve a purpose on this planet prior is
a weird thing but to be proud of being
part of all this that's that's where I'm
at you know I'm just happy and excited
that I get to be a part of this every
day I love what I get to do I I feel
like I found my place I found my
people uh you know and it's just an
amazing community of people that really
care about something bigger than
themselves and there's so many faces I
get to see events like this events like
the cups that I've been to over the
years and like really passionate people
that are part of the community and and
they've done something to move the plan
forward however they've done it you
know yeah even if forward is and a
Direction you don't think is really good
because you don't agree with the
genetics they're working with yeah you
got to appreciate the the work they put
in in order to get there on legacies are
built over Lifetime and you know I think
one of the biggest things is you know
you're on the right path when stuff
falls into place right when stuff's
crazy and it falls apart sometimes you
just have to have the get gets to keep
going but you know you're really in the
right place when it starts calling into
place right like Serendipity like you
get serendipitous events where you meet
someone twice three times four times and
good people you're doing business
unintentionally you start working with
them and they do good business
exactly I I've come across so many good
people just in the United States that
are have held on to things you know like
the the guy that won the cup for sour
diesel in Rhode Island uses our uses our
products and he got his Sour Diesel seed
from his friend whose dad grew Sour
Diesel out here well in like in red way
in like uh early
90s crazy so he was able to take to
start a bunch of that seed and just get
a few seats to pop yeah and a couple of
them were female and he just ran with it
and now two years later he's you know
the it looks like the right structure it
has the right smell it has the right
smoke so you going to check out what I
got today I but I smelled it and I'm
like that's it absolutely it it's not
just the burnt tires it's got the like
the Citrus back to it where it's real
and bright but it's not just burnt tires
which is like more of the Kim 91 side
where it's all kind of got that cheem
spell uh I love sour and to see that
here this is the perfect place of course
it's going to be a regga you know well
this is what regga on the river is all
about it's our community it's about
people coming around and coming together
and there are people out in these Hills
still that are just growing the real
pineapple like the real original
pineapple and they have this little
Market Niche that they sell to and they
don't grow a lot yeah and that's it
right and you know you can completely
miss it sometimes I feel like I'm going
down the freeway at 90 M an hour I'm
missing my exit you know the GU of these
people yeah it's funny some of the guys
do on the old school stuff especially
you know I mean there's a niche market
for it I wouldn't say that it's wanted
by everybody but like I think a lot of
people if they were shown it in the
right condition they just smell it
they'd be like oh yeah I really like
that you show them me it's saw purple
and you're in the city they're like no
no no this super silver HS I don't know
about this stuff and it's like how can
you not like that do you get to see the
super silver from floor and Flame that's
my friend Chris Castle That Grew that oh
okay and you know he's he's the steward
of that cut it's from tissue culture
from uh apical biotech but that is one
of my favorite Cuts I love that I love
the effect of it I love the smell it's
unmistakable it smells just like the
original super silver that I first saw
in 1979 oh wow now without seeing the
plant that's one thing he's he's got a
uh a more compact blower yeah but you
know he's using Moder fertilizers I mean
stuff that didn't exist in 1979 right so
you know you didn't have a ton of
options in
1979 you know you had bone meal yeah
bone meal compost and bone meal you know
yeah so there was options I mean people
B girlly plants a long time it's just
it's got and the thing is I can say that
in the '90s the biggest problem with n
companies is they had recipes and they
were never good by themselves and now
that's different now there's a lot of
testing done like jum days like yourself
where you actually test the recipes you
can follow your recipe to the tea and
get amazing results you know and handful
companies I feel like they do the same
where they put forth the effort they
give you the real recipe there's no
hidden secrets it's a good recipe and
not even a base recipe you just follow
that recipe and you good results yeah I
mean yeah you know we have an hlc and
the gcms but yeah you
know us having to test everything in
order to know what it
is people can just send the customer or
the breeder can just send it into a lab
yeah and they can get the results it's a
lot less work for us and I'm happy for
that and plus it's like a third party
testing too yeah so it's even better
well it's like we weren't doing all the
testing even with genetics I wasn't
doing the testing like we're doing now
it's like we test everything we have
coas for all our all our flowers all our
phenotypes that we keep we have
coas and the model for us is to be able
to show the finished product right and
right now I'm doing a trial with LED
versus HPS with same cultivar so that
customers can see when you grow on HPS
it's like this when you grow it under
LED it's like this these are both good
results what do you prefer what do you
have and then what's optimal for your
environment right so like you want a
specific amount of grams per watt these
are the options that you have if you're
trying to go for that if you're going
for this specific ear profile if you
have a HPS it might do like blue dream
does way better at HPS my op oh yeah it
needs that big deep breath needs that
heat too you just sweat the heat yeah it
just swells up there it's like yeah yeah
it's amazing how the plant
or changes yeah with not just with time
but with what we're talking about the
evolution of the fertilizers the
Biologicals used the soils and the
lighting and the lighting is the big one
and stuff they used to really figure out
now with LEDs and con concentrated ppfd
when you get it right in there it
doesn't get the fox tailes like it used
to some this St are shape but they don't
get the fox tails so I think a lot of
that has to do with heat too cuz we used
to goow with HPS for everything and I
love HPS oh yeah I I don't love what it
does for the environment but LEDs are
definitely more efficient I don't know I
like mix light the best I think that's
the future of the industry anyways we're
all going to go towards mix light
because we can use the sun the sun
creates amazing uh amazing flavor
molecules when we're talking about PES
Turpin flavorant whatever you want to
call them uh the aroma is impacted by
the sun in a in a good way right and the
sun spectrum is it changes it's not even
a constant like the solar flare that
happened this this summer right that
almost knocked out all our cell service
uh you don't think that affected plants
people don't even know really what that
did for a lot of their plants they they
see uh changes in and what elements it
picks up Canabis as opposed to other
other plants in agriculture cannabis is
a very resilient plant that can adapt to
almost any environment whereas some of
this this you know over time with
climate change and the these climates
changing so much we'll see what happens
to the the national agriculture that
does really well that may change from
region to region you know it's like cuz
we're experiencing hotter hotter days on
Earth than we've ever had in and not in
our lifetime but probably in the last
you know 100,000 years yeah I mean I see
just in the Rogue Valley before I left
so many people switching to red shade
cloth wow you know and the difference
between 25% and
50% and I looked at uh 50% and the veg
time was shorter the structure was
better and uh I don't know how it's
going to end up but for instance West CO
West Coast Farms up in up in Talon uh
they use the 50% jakcloth yeah very
start and they 50% is that's takes a lot
of sun out but it's amazing you you hold
a uh infrared gun on the soil outside
it's 145 you step inside and it might be
108 or 110 and that's huge and then you
put it under the plant and it's you know
might be in the low 90s and then the
canopy might be in the high 80s and so
now all of a sudden that's a big big
shift right there it's a huge game
changer for cultivation and not
stressing the planets out you know you
get like going above 105 and it's not
going to be
happy even above 90 it's
not up here it gives full every day
right but about 105 that's no good right
well the plant respirat so it can drop
its temperature as long as it has
moisture yeah but you know I'm years ago
I went to what uh one garden and the
person was like freaking out because her
plants
were were uh getting spots on them and
all these different deficiencies and I'm
like you're using our fertilizer you're
getting deficiencies and he guy was
really really worried so I went up and I
checked out his place it was in Willets
yeah and I said great so you you think
you're planted at the EDG line of an oak
forest but what's happening is the sun
has shifted from being high to now it's
being low and it's hitting all the bags
and he goes no he he goes this not
happening like okay I'll come back
tomorrow afternoon we'll see what's
going on and I'll bring a a thermometer
a soul thermometer and his soil was like
at
118° I go this is great because you've
killed all the bacteria and fungi in the
soil so you're completely rying on
injecting fertilizer yeah and the type
of PL you're growing doesn't want that
you know he's growing like
AK-47 which we know is totally adaptable
but when you strip out the soil and have
high heat like that it's done just like
why you're supposed to SC Rock
outside you might as well to be H like
right you're us I mean that's the the
beauty of using soil you're taking away
the most valuable part of of using a
substrate right but those black grow
bags right they get hot they cooked yeah
he didn't believe it I said put your
hand in he went oh I go yeah imagine if
you're a
rude you're have nowhere to
go well thank you so much for coming on
today there I said was we need you get
you uh down the Bay Area come check out
the facility we got a lot a lot of fun
stuff to show you hey so yeah
[Music]
how's it going we got Michelle here
Horizon girl at Instagram we're
Instagram friends and we've met once
before and I'm so glad to have you come
talk with me for a little bit it's an
amazing r on the river how is it for you
thanks for the invite it's been so much
fun it's been really really really hot
awesome uh but we've been able to do
this dab bar I was invited to be a dab
tender originally and Steve asked me oh
St guer he asked me to well do you want
to just leave that because like you know
the other person backed out I was think
yeah I mean why wouldn't I want to like
get everybody bed you guys got some
really good flavors over there I love
the fact that they have a wreck area
where you can consume consumption areas
are always like we need to move this
forward a little bit faster you know
across the state especially it's like
consumption just it's a natural
progression for
cannabis especially for normalizing
it's important for the community and
it's it's just really important in
general uh with in the 215 era I come
from the 215 me too yeah and uh back
then I made texures and I brought my uh
flowers to different dispensaries
locally and my was played by I brought
towood uh true story uh but uh back then
when the with the dispensaries came out
and they had these loues like for
example hemp Center hemp Center had this
stage where people can like music
couches all around the bar it was like
the first place that had the bar where
they had the alcohol the volcano the
bongs and they like just did it for you
like volcano yeah it was still it still
actually uh she a tall trees daeve and I
we we we found the we found the volcano
Parts like some of these old volcano
parts we just like we caught a couple
volcano one we just like like let's just
check this stuff out I don't know what
we yeah that's
awesome yeah a lot of stuff is still
nostalgic
yes v no hot dabs are like literally you
know I can't do hot dabs I don't like I
have me too so typically I will smoke
like I like to do the hash Bowl Infamous
go makes it's nice pass while you do the
wand I love the wand because it's like
you can hit it hot I mean hot for wand
right and and get like that you know hit
but then at the end you can like
actually taste more I love watching the
waterfall a cascading down the I like
chps I like Flavor yeah I like effect
too don't get WR I like effect punch has
white Thor I just wait who has white
Thor uh P has white Thor and uh yeah so
that's a good one yeah as far as of fact
this has been a great event though um
I've noticed with the crowd everybody
everyone's been on a good vibe loving
the event um there stok they can come
over here and roll you know we have you
know this rolling table people are like
what if I can just roll some some L
joint yeah and like come back later get
get more yeah I we're on 50 joys in two
days so
far yeah yeah I'm looking forward to
that yeah so we smoke Steve we get Steve
we smoke that yeah yeah yeah oh we will
if you want to try you want to show the
extra I've got some Dy burger from Flor
and Flame it's lios and organic living
soil sweet sweet sweet sweet we at the
little Dabber here oh Afghan aghan
gushers well that's the container really
it's dony Burger so I really like dony
Burger the genetics on that dony burger
I believe don't get me wrong but I
believe it's a it's a S1 of GMO that's
why I'm like I'm smelling like onion I
have GMO in right behind there that tent
I have GMO rosin and so we were smoking
M like it's definitely related you could
really tell yeah well it's like you get
that you get that onion thing going on
wait what so all you do is push this
down and then touch the hot end to a
little piece of extar Dabber it is yeah
it's got It's like the nectar collector
electric all right thank you it's fun
and convenient I just I really like it
for events like this to where I want to
try 50 different things in a day and oh
that's so neat ceramic it is it's so
much better than um the previous things
I've tried well thank you so much for
your time and you got to come on a
podcast I'm really looking forward to it
we've had some really amazing people in
the last year come on and I'd love you
can contribute thank you so much it's
it's been a blast doing this so thank
you yeah oh that was beautiful the lemon
wait you didn't need strawberry banana
Cherry yes I took some pictures of that
that's so beautiful I've been telling
people like it does look good but it
also tastes good I can't wait well going
to destroy the structure yet I'm like
I'll get to that point you know my
little one hiter you I'll get to it
thank you thank you very much how's it
going everybody I'm here with Steve the
Rosen
maker production expert all that good
stuff for tll Street Society thank you
so much for coming on talking to me man
it's a pleasure to have you we got to
try some of your amazing rosin yesterday
it was spectacular you gifted me with an
amazing gram of some really really good
stuff uh some flower too the flower was
actually really good super turpy super
it was good it was really nice thank you
so much about it was good and you could
probably wash it and make some amazing
egg Shack with that same exact flour
absolutely Tall Tree Society were
actually uh based at a Redwood Valley in
Menino County nice and we actually are
completely single Source in terms of
where we get our flower material to make
wash hash at s and jza like when I clock
out of the hash la for the day I walk
out and right in front of me is the
greenhouse that has the mothers and the
plants all other green houses
surrounding as well
you have a grower your your head of
cultivation is is looking for an optimal
day to harvest are you involved with
that as well um I've actually had the
opportunity to go walk through the green
houses with the CEO and the garden crew
who are attending the next rounds
Harvest and comparing the genetics and
one thing I love is the CEO was the one
who was uh squishing the rosin before I
came along and had the took the offer
that he gave the opportunity for yeah
and we get to go through and he he
honestly hears my input about what in
the past be in the past from making from
being a manufacturing Specialists who
make very wonderful solvid W products
yeah and here's that and very much very
much agrees like it's it's been
wonderful hearing his hearing him take
the wisdom I've learned and applying it
to his own his own grow basically his
own garden nice yeah it's really cool so
I'm doing an event o October 1st I want
to invite you I've been inviting random
people throughout the weekend they're
involved with Ash but I'm working with
mil we're doing a dabad do in San
Francisco cic culture so uh yeah we're
going to have a contest uh we're going
to have a few different categories I
also have an old school hash category uh
but yeah we're going to have obviously
rosin because rosin's where it's at
right now but I'm going to have a bubble
category as well and there's a
heavyweight belt that's going to be
given away for the davo we got to see
it's going to be a lot of fun that's
awesome exclusive but it's inclusive we
want people to come but there's only so
many seats right so it's a smaller venue
it's still going to I want that Boutique
Vibe it's going to be a lot of fun so
yeah awesome awesome I definitely hope
to look forward to hearing more in the
future for sure so thank you yeah dude I
guess let's let's talk about hash for a
while since we're since we're here we
can talk about hash and I love talking
about hash you love talking about hash I
love has though please what are your
favorite varieties that you're working
with right now that are different than
all the other stuff like I mean there's
the GMOs a lot of people are running GMO
derivatives of GMO crosses and I like I
like this dony burger right so that's
like absolutely special but I feel like
there's so many other directions we can
go white th Rose is getting extract too
white Thor Rose has been white Thor Rose
that's P that's beautiful medicine
Johnny and Rose G up there at hubery
Hill Johnny's been on my podcast I love
Johnny he's great man I think he's the
real deal I love when people come on and
they're just so authentic and it's like
it just resonates with everybody not
just me but
everybody that watches it gets the
experience and it's like it's a
beautiful time it's a beautiful time to
be alive to get these stories to on the
podcast thank you for taking the time to
let everyone like take time to talk with
you so you can people who love listening
to your podcast get to hear the wisdom
every single one of us everyone who has
had the opportunity to talk and we're
recording to share any wisdom and I've
been talking about it a lot this weekend
about like finding your place in the
world where do you belong and I feel
like a lot of people when they found the
industry that was home for them it's
like we're all contributing to so much
something that's so much bigger than
ourselves it's just amazing time to be
alive and to be able to contribute to
this thing that's just a collective
consciousness of energy and of passion
and spirit and these people that are in
this industry are extremely special
because they feel the same way that we
do about the plan it's like you're
smiling right now and I can tell you
love cannabis it's like it's contagious
when people start seeing that it's like
how can you argue that that's wrong or
that that should be criminal or that
we're not Outlaws we bad people we love
something that's extremely special to us
that is a freedom that we all deserve to
have you know absolutely absolutely
we're humans too yeah what are the
genetics you like that you're working
with now and what kind of washing you
Shane who's the CEO of to Tre societ
Society the founder of it he actually
has I got the opportunity of having a
cut of the sfb OG yeah I like sfb I like
it a lot it's a crazy looking plan
though like if you go too long with it
it totally looks crazy it was it wasn't
the best yielder I as we usual OG's
wasn't the best yielder but what I was
able to cold cure in the rosin to show
him what I could do with cold curing his
his his resin that he and the team grew
yeah and he literally just sent me a
picture and just goes oh my goodness
this is beautiful yeah and everyone
who's that everyone even said in terms
of a concentrate form it they brings
them back and hearing people have no I
used to love the scissor hasher I I grew
sfv my friends grew sfv we grew a lot of
it but the scissor hash for sfv was
always the best you know there there was
a handful of things where it was like I
still remember the way the scissor hash
taste it was different than it taste
exactly like the plat spell yes and so
that's what I love you know like good
scissor hash should spell exactly like
the plant spells yeah you you're getting
those turns in it's perfect form yeah
you know yeah people have said when they
say that it's like it brings them back
it like it's not the plant burn like or
like a chlorophyll but more of the pine
that that Piney earthy Pine with a
little Citrus right but like not just
Pine but pine needles like you have that
fresh [ __ ] pine needles you can smoke
that and the beauty of a dab is it's all
chapped into L hit you smoke a joint and
it's amazing too I love joint absolutely
then you get that over the Peri of the
joint it tastes good all the way down
the road is special but when you smoke
it into form of Ros and it's like
encapsulating that whole joint one hit
and you blow it out it's like it's
amazing that's what I love about it
because you're getting all that flavor
condensed into one hit and it's just cuz
really you're getting the the TPS and we
were talk about Flavor molecules but
you're getting all those flavor
molecules of much larger amount of
cannabis all compacted into one
hit yeah yep and then uh I got to I'm
going to be squishing our wash team
actually one he's a single person he's a
great guy Nicholas doe the the washer
who's I get to press that beautiful
resin he washes and he just washed I got
to collected for on the next press will
be melted
strawberries what do you think about
Skittles
rosin no there's been a real Pho hun
craze for it so there's been a lot out
there I'm like okay it Skittles and then
there's some where I dab it and I'm just
like oh my God I'm like early 20s right
now and I taste candy like the first
time I hit a joint of pure SK like what
Skittles was so I still remember the
first day I tried Skittles it was at uh
the high Canabis Cup in 2014 in
June and I remember the first day yeah
it was it was it was
amazing and it's one of those
life-changing you know I feel like
throughout my life I've capis was one of
um you know Sour Diesel was another one
like these are things that have affected
me to this day and had impact on the
direction I went in life for with well
what I liked about cannabis the OG cush
was one we had a master cush and a Bubba
cush the Bubba cush was like soapy and I
still remember that soapy smell
sometimes I smell like Irish Springs or
I wash my hands with soap like smells
like Bubba cush yes same thing pine
needles if you eat the young pine
needles off of a redwood tree or you
know these pine trees but off a redwood
tree the the needles uh the very young
needles it reminds me
of so they're high vitamin C that are
actually Healy oh my God okay I I live
in Anderson Valley up in mesino or down
from here in Menino County I should say
so I love hiking through some of the
Redwood Forest so I'm going to tell I'm
mushrooms and eating oh so many so many
varieties turkey tail is such a
beautiful find out there well you guys
get tons of different variety you know
and the further north you go too I think
there's some areas towards Oregon yes
that get some crazy crazy mushroom I
mean there's people all over here that
go mushroom hunting yes yes very much
facts I've seen I've seen in some towns
in medino County setting up literally an
Extended Stay room just being like will
bu mushrooms on a sign right next to the
motel and that's that's awesome yeah how
about mushroom chps and weed have you
ever spell any Savory mushroom chps they
say you it's like they say J but I don't
give mushrooms and GMO SP one pheno one
pheno I watched about three seasons ago
yeah that's I'm trying to recall cuz I
remember washing about 3s ago which it
was it tasted like mushrooms and it was
fresh and then as that rosin almost cold
cured out it get turned more into onions
but when it was more fresh that was the
only time I could ever recall like
having my a mushroom tast yeah I've
smelled
gravy Fried Chicken oh yeah oh yeah
horse chicken yes yes chicken yeah yes
alien hand grenade was my first
experience with that one of all things
and I I miss that I miss that like
orange chicken Turing taste right what
do you think about
Tangi I love the tur Bean Tangi I love
that that specific if it's l type of
line with it yeah like however as a
solventless h uh ice water sift and
solventless hash
maker on its own it's never been a
washer I remember it has to be dry
shifted right like I thinky I think
that's what they do Morocco Tangi is the
most popular thing there Tangi 24 K all
those are beautiful they're they're the
they're the right group to be doing that
in Morocco that's the perfect
climatology G dry dry yeah exactly i' no
nutrition it's all these clear out there
I mean not no nutrition but low
nutrition yeah yeah it's yeah I always
was blowing that's actually seeing like
on a documentary about hashish being
made when I was living that's what kind
of inspired me Morocco has some of the
most amazing hash I've seen in Barcelona
it's like the real Moroccan it's like
once you experience it my friend is like
a morck and hash Cur and he has like
frozen samples of so many different
things and it's like they're all just
super special
beautiful good stff man well thank you
for coming on we'll need to get you down
to Hayward you can come check out the
facility I'd love to have you down
therec to share that time with you
please thank you thank you so much for
your time today thank you James for
sharing space with me for sure
[Music]
[Applause]
oh
[Music]
[Applause]
how's it going everybody day three Re on
the river I'm here with Dave from balero
how you doing today Dave I'm doing good
thanks how are you I'm fantastic thanks
for coming on talking to me for a little
bit we met yesterday over Sour Diesel
something I've been looking for for a
long long long time I've gotten samples
of Sour Diesel from so many different
people and you came up to me and said
check this out if it's not the right one
you can be honest with me which I
totally appreciate because I get that a
lot and uh you got the right cut right
on and I haven't seen it in years and it
has I mean when you squeeze it you just
get the real sour smell you get the
aroma it was grown with mix FL too so I
think there's we were talking about
there's something to be said for the
people who grow it in the way they grow
it to get those specific profiles and
yeah it's special right on well yeah I'm
I'm just stoked to kind of still have it
I've had it for 21 years and when I got
it I knew it was special so I kept it
just cuz it was special to me and I'm so
the cat piss it gives me hope that there
is real cat piss still there's someone
out there that has it someone that has
the real well so and there's so many
different cat pisses I'm sure they're
they're real to those people that have
them all these different ones but the
one that's real to me that I I miss the
most has been gone it's eluded me for a
long time and my friends that's like the
Romulan for me I had this one Romulan
and it was the one for me and nobody
else had it and like I've been looking
for it ever since and you so Romulan was
amazing you know 20 years ago Romulan
was the one uh the Romulan we had the
shaman but it was like a really we just
call it the shaman but it was like a
Romulan back Cross or a shaman back
cross with the ra Romulan and it was it
was just amazing the was it was one of
those purple ones that didn't have the
effect that matches the color you think
of Ron it was more of an uplifting and
Powerful smoke okay yeah mine was the
exact opposite we used to call it the
head denter wow I mean that was like
straight the most sedative cannabis I've
ever smoked in my life um but it's so
it's different to see the different
expressions and like we were talking
about earlier the way it's grown can
express itself and how also different
effects yeah um and I think a lot of
times with the sour you know it can be
really good or it can be not so good
real easy and there's kind of like a
fine line there if you mess up the cure
there's none of that good sour smell and
it go it goes to Hay yeah it totally
goes to Hay which is mostly what I see
to be honest with you most of the stuff
I've seen is hay you know people and
it's hard to tell if it was even the
real cut when it's hey you know so yeah
there should be some of it in there you
know but I've grown it you really got to
squeeze for some sometimes but but uh
I've grown under HPS and led and I will
say the LED is nowhere near like the HPS
um I grew it for a long time under HPS
and the first led Harvest I was like
what what happened to the sour like this
is not what I was expecting there's heat
and there's far red and so there's some
big differences with those and I agree
but Blue Dream is another example of
something that should be grown under HPS
that does better I think it performs
better under HPS some of them do you
know it's just like outdoor strains that
don't do well outside you know they do
better insight and all that so that's
part of kind of learning how to grow
different varieties what they like what
they don't like right uh
yeah it's a lot of fun but yeah all
these different sours I've seen there's
there's that sour in there or it has the
structure or it has a little bit of the
smell sometimes it even has the smell
and the look and then I go to smoke it
and you're like it's just not the one
it's not the one that I remember you
know and yours is the first thing I've
seen in 20 years not maybe a little bit
less than 20 years probably probably
like 12 years 14 years something like
that cuz it really went away in like
2012 2014 Gorilla Glue kind of was the
pivoting point I think for to basically
everybody switched to Gorilla Glue that
I knew it was hot for a while and then
it's like everything people start to
grow it and then you get enough Bland
batches or mediocre batches and people
start to gravitate towards something
else that's better real quick and then
you call them they're like yo I got the
sour and like it wasn't good last time
I'm on to something else sorry you know
whatever the case was um you know I
think a lot of people lost it for
whatever reason I heard someone talk
about how they got busted and they lost
their cut hot plate and viroid I mean I
think the the genetics deteriorated with
hop plate and verid so when people were
growing them they weren't getting good
yields it was
dutting uh you know I think they've
contributed to one of the early vectors
of hop PL and that got spread around
which I remember it it wasn't the same
some of my friends grw it just wasn't
the same too so yeah I've often thought
maybe mine has some sort of virus after
growing it under an LED and then just
seeing some weird stuff but then I had
one of my best yields ever under LEDs um
and I almost gave up on it but my buddy
grew it last year in his outdoor patch
wow and I was like okay it's still got
it like it probably needs to be dissu
cultured but what we want what we're
hoping to get out of it is still there
so I was like all right I'm going to
roll the dice and I'm going to put 20 in
a greenhouse and see what happens um and
I'm really glad I did because it came
out kind of what I've been kind of I've
been looking for it even though I've had
it the whole time right um I haven't
done as much growing recently so I had
some friends grow it outside it came out
really great yeah with then when I grew
it inside I was like oh this is
disappointing um so I think a lot goes
to how you're growing it where you're
growing it what nutrients you're using
when you're using them what do you think
are the best fruit nutrients for for
sour specifically ah I mean it likes
nutrients you know the first recipe was
the GH recipe back in the early 2000s I
think it's like the Lucas recipe just
that basic GH right um I think it likes
Organics though you know I was growing
it side by side with a friend soil
versus Hydro rock wool you know um the
the uh the clay pellets and it seems to
just Express itself to its Fuller
potential when grown in soil um with
organic nutrients I mean my same friend
was growing in soil but with chem
nutrients um and then I think one thing
that I started doing I was like okay
what nutrient is most responsible for
smell and flavored so is uh sulfur you
know and I think there's been some
studies that came out recently that suur
is responsible for that like skunky
Aroma yeah abstract Tech they're call
them flavorant but it's it has to do
with THS and sulfur and sulfur being so
I don't think that's necessarily what
gives the sour it skunky smell but I did
start kind of gravitating toward I think
that's why it's pungent though is is
from that for sure some Epsom salt you
know from the store just cuz it's cheap
and easy right I've used a lot of
different nutrients on I've used banic
hair Advanced Nutrients bio Biz Organics
alive um and I think it just likes good
amended soil this last round I used a
blend of Organics alive and some biolink
with some inoculants um you know just
kind of standard run-of-the-mill
Organics but I really do like uh some of
the more water soluble organic stuff
just cuz I do in jackon totally and you
have lines yeah I've got kind of it's
not automated but I've got the five rows
are all separated they're all on emitter
so I just turn on a couple lines at a
time and then just you know watch the
tank go down switch the lines
and a lot of stff stilles clog it even
the really you know soluble organic
stuff some of yeah some of the stuff
just just clogs but good organic stuff
clogs yeah um but it's pretty basic I
mean nothing special you know it's got a
greenhouse with some good ventilation
nice so you you're not just a one hit
wonder you showed me some other land
race genetics that were you know stuff
that you just don't see you might see it
at rig in the river but you really
typically wouldn't see it anywhere else
in California other than in the Hills
yeah um I haven't seen a lot of it
myself I'm you know I'm still learning
I'm it's new to me you know I've been a
kind of a traditional kind of hype guy
almost I mean I grew a lot of sour
predominantly yeah and I guess I've
never really kind of I've always gratit
towards stuff that was different you
know and just held on to that and kind
of ran with it MH um and then my
father-in-law has been collecting seeds
and pollen from around the world since
the 60s wow and as soon as I met him I
knew that he had something different
going on but it took me a little while
to kind of experience what he was trying
to share with me and I kind of like to
call like an indicia detox you have to
almost only smoke these types of
varieties to really understand the hide
because they don't slap you in the face
super hard instantly MH like a good OG
cush for example you know it
just um it's hard and quick where some
of these other varieties it kind of
builds up to this thing where you get to
a point where you're like damn I am is
so high right now yeah and that can be
subtle but when it takes full course is
actually really strong and then once you
start to
notice that experience kind of from
start to finish and some of it does come
on quick you know like the African Haze
11 is a really quick acting Strong high
and it lasts for a long time and it can
be pretty intense um those pearls that I
showed you yeah are similar but I feel
like it's a little less racy and more of
that like good giggly feeling where you
just feel absolutely fantastic right
um so it's hard they take a long time to
flower you know a lot of things can go
wrong in 14 weeks and then the pearls
they look like something you might throw
away Dr grinin is like yeah I mean yeah
it looks like most people would call
that undesirable or they'd be like
that's what I used to see in High Times
in the 70s yeah and people associate
that with have some for some reason have
a negative connotation right but I think
a lot of it just comes down to to well
be honest with yourself did you grow it
to its full potential because if you
didn't then you can't really say it was
or wasn't good sure I learned that the
hard way with LEDs I recently got rid of
some good genetics that I thought
weren't good um I later found out they
were and I should have kept them um and
then just you know sometimes the yiel Is
Not Great sometimes the yiel is actually
really good so I think it just takes
someone that is really after the
experience and the high the whole kind
of enchilada of growing it rolling the
joint multiple times to figure out what
to do with it too like how you can
improve it totally cuz you know you
could grow it once and it didn't come
out that good and you grow it over and
over and over and that's how I learned
how to grow really good I grew the sour
repeatedly as many times as I could for
years and years and years and it really
taught me this is a nitrogen deficiency
this is a cow mag deficiency and I was
able to identify certain things so that
when I grew other plants it was like
okay I know what to look for as opposed
to well it could be underwatering with
this plant or overwatering or issue but
you don't know until you do it multiple
times and then you know what a good
version of sour is or a good version of
Bubba cush is right because you've done
it enough times to know well I love
Bubba Bubba's name got ruined in the you
know 10 starting 10 years ago when they
started mass producing Bubba in huge
warehouses and so I think a lot of
people think of Bubba is something
completely different than what I know is
buba and what you know is Bubba that
pre98 soapy has a a you know it has an
amazing Aroma it's gassy it's soapy it's
special it smokes good it it has a good
effect it in my opinion it checks all
the boxes right but there's like the the
whole in Oakland San Leandro uh they
were between Oakland and San Leandro on
San Leandro Avenue they were going
filling warehouses and just growing up
pulling it 53 days or less sometimes 49
days so you know it's like depending on
who you grow and what cut you have
that's the other thing is like just cuz
it's called one thing doesn't mean that
it's necessarily that like Bubba Kush is
a great example cuz there's several cuts
of Bubba Kush and there's there's one
good one in my opinion that I've seen
over the years yeah and I get that a lot
with the sour people ask me what cut is
this and I say well I don't know because
it was just the sour yeah it was pre any
names you know and people's reaction
like yours was often like well I haven't
seen this one you know since back in the
day or for 20 years and so it's like
well what what do you have like I had
some friends um they got a batch from my
buddy that had seeded itself and they
grew those seeds and they said for years
that that sour that came out of those
seeds wasn't the same as the sour clone
that we had oh wow um makes sense though
you know it was a little bit watered
down maybe it got a little bit of pollen
from something else maybe it was self
who knows but um that sour cut you know
it was just as sour and I'm thankful
that I've kept on to it you know cuz I
feel like it is a special one and I kind
of knew just my gut was telling me just
don't let go of this don't let go this
you know I really connected with it in a
really strong way yeah and was around
other people that had that same really
strong connection when it was really
popular and it's interesting to see you
know I kind of just throw my arms up and
be like man it's just sour you know it's
just a good batch of sour hopefully the
next one comes out that good you know
totally yeah and I mean it is farming
from Harvest to harvest is different
comes out slightly different you know
it's like you try to get it as
consistent as possible and
if you do it right it's going to be good
if you do it wrong it's not going to be
as good but typically it's going to be
good yeah and you know I mean growing in
a greenhouse versus indoor and outdoor
it's all going to be different you're
going to have oh to totally different
and and structurally too the bud can be
structurally different indoor versus
outdoor versus Greenhouse versus mix
light and I found that the area sour
stinks more than the really dense sour
yeah um for whatever reason there's just
more like like air surface area for that
smell to get out but I find like on the
indoor the bigger buds would be less
stinky than the smaller buds that were
maybe weren't as dense right which is
now you're getting into the same plant
grown the same way but different parts
of the plant are producing different
types of of butt you know sides as
opposed to the top a lot more curp yeah
it's really interesting yeah well we're
going to have to get you down to the B
area get you on a show I'd love to do a
whole podcast come down we could smoke
the sour together talk about it smoke
some of the other stuff that uh it was a
Bubba Haze that you had that was pretty
Bubba Kush original Haze yeah really
nice real Bubba Aroma like nostalgic
Bubba smell but it has something else to
it it's a little funky a little sharp on
the nose too yeah it's it's a good combo
that's one of my favorite hybrids right
now and it's a great yielder too yeah
awesome well thank you so much for your
time today man we'll do this again soon
appreciate it y
absolutely how's it going I'm here with
Nick he is uh at reg on the river 2024
with me you did two sets how you doing
I'm feeling blessed man I'm feeling so
blessed just to be here at reggy on the
river to have this Festival back I've
been going to this festival for over two
decades yeah me too we the first time we
went you know I met my wife this was the
first vacation we I was here that's
what's up man so yeah good times I it's
been a beautiful weekend and like they
they had reg for several years so to
bring it back with this kind of energy
you know you did some amazing sets uh
both Friday and Saturday morning I
didn't I missed the Friday but the
Saturday set was great you got good
energy I mean couldn't have a better
place to be a DJ at you know what I mean
or a musician or just you know as a
spectator it's like great to just be
part of this bigger thing yeah man yeah
it's been a hot weekend but it's such a
blessing to get to see all my friends
and I I'm seeing people I haven't seen
in over a decade because you know we
haven't been here on the River Bank well
I kind of knew you were going to be here
I just I I saw your name somewhere on
something and then like just driving in
you're like walking in it's like okay
Nick is here it's going to be a good
weekend yeah everybody's here yeah
totally so we got Marlin here you know
and then the acts they've had so many
good performers over the last couple
days tonight's going to be another
amazing night you know last night
finishing with Capleton and then they
did the the battle with the with the dub
plates last night that was pretty sound
was sick to bring that real real
Jamaican culture here is really the
first of its kind to bring that to
reging on the river so I love what Leo
has done with this festival and the acts
that he's brought as you were mentioning
it's not like all the big headlining
acts it's a lot of this underground
reggae music and and sound system
culture that he's booked there's 41 dj/
sound systems that he brought to this
event and so I love that aspect of this
event so I heard that that sound system
was a million dollars down at the river
I don't know what the price is but
christop fari Royal Sound and Lighting
they know how to tune a sound not only
setting up the sound it's not only their
relationship with void Acoustics but
it's tuning that sound that Chris and
Zach and the whole royal Sound and
Lighting family just have on point you
can turn that up so much louder down
there and not hurt your ears the main
stage was a little a little ringing this
morning because the main stage but the
dance allall is a beautiful thing to be
able to play on let alone listen to it
in the in the crowd totally so what were
your favorite acts this weekend so far
man
um so many good ones it's just
conscience really threw down last night
um Leela I made me cry wow it was
emotional for me yeah
um and uh oh man there was
uh oh there's there's been so many
already I'm already losing track so I'm
close enough that I can hear all the
acts even though I don't go to all
Capleton was amazing was beautiful I've
seen Capleton 15 times 20 times yeah
totally brings energy Anthony was great
and you knowth got a little cheesy for
me but he was going old school he's
recovering for a surgery I heard yeah
yeah yeah give him a little credit sorry
sorry cable didn't just Crush every time
it's like so much energy The Crowd Goes
Wild the big flags in the crowd moving
around at the same time and it's like oh
you know who else I loved is DeMarco set
like I really thought DeMarco set was
great there was a little kid that that
wrapped some to short yesterday that was
yeah Lake crushes it every single time I
think I got to see one of his first
performances in Tahoe at the Tahoe
Reggae Fest a few years back and I was
like all right this kid is going to this
kid going and now his voice has even
changed but it's getting better and he's
even more you know just in tune and in
key like with the the songs you know
he's singing every lyric it's it's a
yeah it's amazing just the energy here
is just you know you're talking about
you just went and got a massage they got
they got it hooked up everywhere here
and the food's great I mean we're doing
our own food too I love cooking but like
I know the food's good here I mean it's
just it's amazing and it's sold out it's
completely sold out and I feel like
everyone's in a great mood sometimes
when it's super packed people get all
bummed out or like pissed off or
whatever but that's there's none of that
here no it's a beautiful Vibe and energy
throughout the entire weekend I haven't
had any bad vibes I'm camping with the
good vibe tribe over here so absolutely
are no bad vibes literally the good vibe
tribe I've seen a couple people
wandering at like four in the morning
looking for their tents but you know
that's bound to happen this many
people yeah so yeah good stuff well
October 1st I'm doing the Dabo in San
Francisco and I'm trying to get you out
there so hopefully we can do this 10y
year anniversary thing cuz 10 years ago
we did it with with douge and Mila in
San Francisco and it was a good time and
hopefully we can uh repeat that I'm
going to get a heavyweight belt so the
person L is getting a dabad do
heavyweight belt anything for MAA I'd
love to be involved totally 100% she's
the queen she is she's amazing she put
me on so you know a lot of people thank
me throughout these festivals for
putting them on or teaching them about
solventless you know but Mila put me on
so I owe all all the love and credit to
Mila yeah she's just a kind soul and
just cares about the industry and cares
about people like very few so for real
for real and she still hitting so many
events every year and Joints she throws
her splits yeah she hits she smokes
harder than most of us young guys I'm
not young anymore but like even still
yeah I think her and my homie jaw Weiser
from jaw Warrior shelter another one of
my mentors who's DJ this weekend they'd
be battling it out in my world like a
lot of the judges that I see throughout
they can't smoke like mil and jaw Weiser
like those two they're my they're my
judges for sure well thank you so much
for your time man I look forward to
getting you on our podcast your last
podcast was a hit so it's always a
blessing and a pleasure man thanks James
absolutely it's day three I'm here with
Marlon again how are you doing Marlin
I'm fair to fine thank you it's so good
to be here reg on the river what an
amazing show ceton last night wow man
ceton was on fire you know I always
expect you know he brings it every time
I always expect an amazing performance
from CET you know it's a blessing yeah
just it's it's and the sound system down
at the river is actually pretty amazing
too I think that's a million doll sound
system they have down there I think they
went all out to make sure that this reg
on the river was a success and I think
it it paid off you know yeah very
successful and you're going on tonight
yeah I play like 6:30 tonight uh it's
going to be great going to be a lot of
good vibes going on on the stage you
know I think it's a pleasure to
represent the roots Rock Reger music you
know a lot of people
in that segment so yeah man I
appreciate so many good acts so much fun
so many people and and they've sold out
for the weekend and you could tell they
sold out it's packed it's really packed
with Happy People yeah you know that's
and the thing about the lineup everyone
was you know they they put the right
artist together on the right days yeah
it it all made sense you know the
balance the energy exactly so yeah it
was a good vibes fantastic
well we're probably going to talk again
tomorrow definitely but yeah thanks you
thank you very much appreciate
it welome more
[Music]
so we're closing day three Re on the
river
2024 I'm here with r we survived we made
it saw the most amazing artist epic
weekend epic weekend we just got seen
Marlin Asher first time I've ever seen
him it was a great performance
mindblowing I can't believe I'm still
here dude so let's talk about the
highlights here weekend you started by a
phone call and then two months later
we're here together yeah yeah you
calling me I you said you you had to do
selfie I was supposed to try to do the
podcast said you had to go to R the
river at that time I was like what's up
like GG a and uh he said I'll call you
back or so I know yeah hit me back he
said now you're here he said if you come
out I got you and I said all right got a
fundraiser and I'm here yeah man it was
a good time it was good Adventure I feel
like the experience was great the river
was warm uh there's a little algae in
the river but you know I can't wait to
come back next I can't wait next year
man that be awesome uh the river was
great I you know what I'm saying is you
feel like it just floating in that River
have the music in the background
everybody's partying having a good time
lots of dabs lots of FL what was the
highlight of your weekend as far as flow
uh probably that uh Sour Diesel you gave
me oh that was F that was good that was
good we got to little some long rips of
and that FL was good that in the
Nigerian Haze was amazing I spoke some
Nigerian Haze that was like creeper weed
and just creeped up gently lifting you
up to the right place nice nice you know
it was just amazing weekend yeah great
great could have been better so if you
guys want to come next year join us in
person we're going to have a booth here
we're going to be doing it up it's going
to be lots of fun I hope you guys
enjoyed the video and we'll check you
out soon check into the podcast
he
[Music]