[Music]
how's it going everybody I'm James loud
and today's episode we have special
guest Dave mesford better known as Dave
damit by the industry April 10th I
called Dave to check in on him and he
wasn't doing
well uh he'd been fighting cancer for 3
years he uh wasn't sounding so good and
I told him man I really wanted see you
I'll be up there on Monday and he said I
don't know if I'm going to make it till
Monday so I got our plane on Friday
morning and uh we've been talking about
filming an episode of the podcast for a
year since we started the show and I
really wanted him to come down and see
the facility and he's been going in and
out of issues with his bladder cancer
that has metastasized and spread to
other
Oregons U and on 420 he lost his battle
to answer so the next two hours of our
podcast are dedicated to Dave there's a
gofund b to raise money for his family
that you can see in the description for
the show and uh if you guys can donate
that would be great that the money goes
towards his medical bills that his
family has to pay and also contributing
to his memorial service uh thanks for
tuning
in this shows difficult at times to
watch you know but
uh Dave was a tough guy I one one of the
toughest guys I know and one of the
nicest guys I've ever met he uh met me
or I met him uh in 2012 after I won the
Canabis cup for High Times in Amsterdam
he took photos of me in
Washington and we'v been friends ever
since uh he was one of those guys who
lit the whole room up he was always just
an amazing person he had this crazy long
hair that was always perfect curls good
guy you know and he was passionate about
so many things but we really connected
on
cannabis food and
photography and he was very passionate
about all three of those things and his
family was his number
one uh so I hope you guys enjoy the next
two hours a year we talk about the world
history of cannabis and this is an
important part of it thank you for
tuning in how's it going everybody
welcome to another episode of the James
live podcast we're here on location
we're up in Washington with my good
friend Dave mesford how you doing today
Dave doing good jve great to see you as
always for sure man uh I wish I could
have come under different circumstances
but I'm glad that we get to hang out and
do a podcast together I feel like uh the
oral history of cannabis is so important
and you have a lot of great stories that
I hope we can share with everybody as
Isn't that cool how um suddenly us old
Stoner hippies are kind of the the elite
um keepers of the story yeah it's a hard
feeling to describe you know I still
it's like kind of pooo it away it's like
yeah whatever yeah it's just weed right
it's just it's just weed just weed
although and I think a lot of people
think it's just weed but it's so much
more than that and you in your own way
or our revolutionary as important as so
many people throughout history that have
tried changed and succeeded in changing
the future and when I first met you we
were at my Uncle uncle's house and we
were doing gy shooting some photos for
high timeses what I after I'd won the
cup I was featured in high you came and
took those photos that's where we met
and I remember the first time coming to
your house you were growing canabus in
your front yard and yeah grew up past
Seattle a little ways and it's a suburb
oh lywood is County I mean one of the
more red definitely one of the reddest
counties this side of the mountains yeah
so in Wester Washington yeah but you've
always been a boundary Pusher you know
you've been in involved with heest for a
really long time at other events as
well so yeah but but growing cannabis in
your front yard when it was still
illegal but going in the direction of
being legal uh you know that was to me
that was impressive cuz I never had the
balls to grow in my front yard and I
think they the plants would have gotten
taken it took a long time to get the
balls just to grow in my closet y you
know once the dam is broken the dam is
broken yeah I grew up here man the
lywood cops have always known the mesord
kids yeah you know so it was just kind
of part for the cars right put put a pot
plant in the front my neighbors loved it
they're like wow that's a really pretty
plant my neighbor across the street knew
exactly what it was but um asked me he
says what are you going to do when the
cops roll out ask you about the pot
plant in your front yard I told them pot
plant is that what that is that's all I
doing right didn't have any plan
[ __ ] neither did I ever get contact by
the police you know they yeah see on the
bottom of a dead end they come and sit
down here in their cars eat their donuts
or their sages or whatever yeah nobody
paid any m
nice yeah yeah you've done all kinds of
things uh you're a breeder you're a
cultivator you've been involved with
cannabis for a really long time and uh
you know when we talk about passion for
the sacred plant I feel like you embody
all that as well thanks thanks I
um you know over the last couple of
years I've realized that it really is a
passion and every time I stop growing
for one reason or another I have some
pretty major health issues ISU was going
on as you know right for a long time it
just wasn't something I could do it's
getting to that point again where I'm
really scaled
back and um it makes me sad just really
makes me sad when I'm not growing yeah
I've done it for so long and it's just a
so it's a source of pleasure yeah was
just awesome pleasure and um the most
Joy I've ever
gotten out of growing weed out of
growing
CIS is giv pot to somebody yeah hey BR
so weed
right it just doesn't sharing with
people you care about yeah totally there
people that you don't even know it's
just giving them something not not for
the social media hits and Views yeah
just to give it to them man behind your
back sh you know yeah just that's that's
the best pleasure that I get out of your
own lead is just sharing it with people
yeah people like it say oh wow that's
really good yeah I love that totally who
doesn't like that they appreciate it
yeah it's like tooking somebody a great
meal who doesn't love that absolutely
yeah yeah so yeah it's it's um God yeah
something I would never trade yeah so
tell us how you get started with canvas
really it was just a matter of it was
the drug that all the kids were doing
did not like drinking alcohol hated
being drun yeah ended up smoking weed
like like most all the other kids in the
neighborhood and did you grow up in this
area or actually was born and raised in
this house born and raised in this house
was definitely a family home um yeah i'
I've lived around the world I've lived
all over the place worked and sailed as
a merchant marines yeah did a lot of
parties TRS had a girlfriend for three
or4 years in
Yokohama that was awesome they had more
video rock and roll then I I didn't even
know something like that existed because
MTV didn't exist yet but they had it all
in Japan just a real cool colorful life
that um that I am blessed to have had
but yeah Canabis really kind of takes
the cake for all of it along your
journey it's been there the whole time
it has yes it has I've always come back
to it uh for a long time I never left it
yeah you know
circumstances getting married having
kids you know transitioning all of that
stuff uh credit's hard to get when all
you can show them is pictures of your
latest greatest Bud right maybe we can't
get dude I just [ __ ] gree that's my
latest man right have all these
assets seeds for these things wa talk
about
yeah yeah it's just always been an
adventure of the people
so the canvas plant can lead you to
people people can lead is the Canabis
plan however that might work I don't
know but I will tell you from just
meeting people through smoking and
growing and sharing pictures of each
other's weed I met some real cool people
that um eventually got me involved with
hempest and hus was really the change of
my life right um I spent nearly 20 years
as a volunteer this was a it's a all
volunteer production um you we bought
Services reged equipment did all that
but the the infrastructure was all
assembled and disassembled the events
were always run by volunteers 100% so
diving in the
Hempfest uh that is one of the most
profound experiences that you can get as
far as canis goes uh because of the
collective consciousness of 300,000
other people yes totally there has never
been a larger event um in the city of s
300,000 people plus we latest 420 years
so um hanging out in those three parts
over three days you can combine the
World Series or a Super Bowl or you know
Stanley Cup all together in those crowds
still sold out aren going to aren't
going to meet the attendance of a him us
you it's he for sure or come even cl to
the passion the passion the passion is
is um somebody told me day that might
have been you fion is is another
vibration level vibrational level of
love there's not much more than
authenticity authenticity and passion
yeah the passion at one of those events
the ticity they're all based on on on
love when getting so many people
together those are the type of events
that changed the world you know the Hest
and we're talking about people that
aren't there for the money maybe there's
a handful of people there for the money
but that's like the 1% you know that's
not the the real world you know it's
like there might be the 1% that's out
there to go try to make a buck but the
people that chill up in events like
Hempfest those are the people that love
weed that love cannabis or people that
are curious about it that maybe learn
something new I mean CU it it was about
legalization yeah it was about Freedom
it was about enjoying the plant for what
it is and you know and also friendship
and meeting new people exactly I um head
back to the passion with an event so
huge so undeniably huge yeah uh we
worked throughout the decades almost
three of them with the Seattle Police
the port police the fire department all
of the city agencies that you can
imagine and you can also Imagine That
going into these events in the early
years skeptic ISM on the part of the
city or or the officials is such a such
a huge understatement you know these
hippies can't do anything yeah I mean I
think the hippies get uh but yeah people
they relate to cannabis to hippies and
then like the hippies they're they just
get high and and not smart right that's
never been the case and Bly St but it's
also Bly stma that cannabis is bad yeah
and that's that's yeah first we wanted
to have
legalization and then we wanted to have
normalization and now we just want
destigmatization because it's normal as
hell yeah there's nothing abnormal about
it what makes the world a better place
happiness yeah love authenticity and
what helps bring those on yeah yeah and
I'll tell you what um the nearly 30
years that hemp prevailed in those parts
annually there was
never a major incident not one gun
violence in
that not one death thank whoever it is
that you send your thanks and ask your
hopes Crum
into there's just no I don't know how to
explain it um well I kind of do was we
never allowed alcohol at our eventss
that was a big thing no alcohol no viets
beautiful that that was just such a
simple recipe and it prevailed for ideas
yeah something to be proud of it's
really impressive that the whole H the
model that they
had I mean to have an event that
successful for that many years without
major problems I mean that's almost
unheard of if you involved alcohol that
it would be the polar opposite oh
totally totally or it could have
involved a for-profit business model for
sure the chaos could could is yeah an
amazing time and they were amazing time
and and we're still in them I mean it's
how we navigate the tail end of
legalization um so much work
to again um destigmatized
normalize allow H grows like some some
states
have there's a lot of work to be done
still fighting for some of the laws here
in Washington that's are really screwed
up laws hey we were the first state to
legalize us us in Colorado well
everybody learned from Washington in
Colorado on how to do it right now to do
wrong and most of the states made their
own mistakes anyway yeah they did they
did over taxation being one of the
biggest over taxation huge over Taxation
and a ridiculous sh Washington we
finally rescinded the uh the excise tax
which should go into a effect this July
and um along with that comes no more
taxation on medical cannabis right so
you're going to see a Russian black
market growth and you're going to see a
rush in medical patient registration
yeah those are the two yeah and the part
the state's going to hate all of that
because it's LW of their revenue yeah I
mean I we were talked a little bit
earlier about how we live in such a
special time you know throughout history
to be part of this
and I feel like the two of us are are
both doing not only what our 18-year-old
s would be like super proud of yeah but
we're doing what we were supposed to do
when we came here you know to this
planet I feel like when we came here we
were meant to do what we're doing now
and I just I reflect on that a lot so
yeah I I agree I think that
Destiny is something that I think we're
all given yeah born with um or at least
given to us as a model here's a possible
thing for you we're not all cut out to
be rocket scientist computer programmers
or cannabis Growers y you know um so
yeah desly definitely I believe Destiny
plays a role in in our lives yeah yeah
wouldn't trade it would can't think of
much I'd trade it for wouldn't trade the
Cannabis you know the Cannabis lifestyle
it's it it's real interesting how it's
changed how we were in the shadows for
the longest time and we had to be in the
shadows because of the risk right there
was so much risk
and that's changed and now the younger
generation they don't even know the risk
they don't know the risks they know the
glamour yeah uh and all of the stuff in
the middle is disappearing and what is
that stuff it's the passion right it's
still love why we get started this from
the beginning yeah the passion yeah the
passion's falling out for profit it's
falling out for glamour check out all
those weed events with the freaking
tuxes and you know five piece I don't
even know what's cool in style anymore
because I'm not a bud and young Canabis
executive those D can dress yeah but
where's the passion for the not just the
passion for the plant but the
passion that this plant
brings to other just to others when once
you're passionate about something as
healing and healthy as cannabis it's
hard not to be passionate just about
loving other people yeah just a part of
our society that just is
um has long been overlooked Peace Love
Rock and Roll what's wrong with peace
and love Yeah interesting how our
society is is picking up on these chages
and yeah a lot of them are are are
passing mustard pretty easily people are
figuring out oh
it's it's not killing
anybody yeah the sky isn't falling
and it's the collective effort of so
many people these are you and I included
Hipp Sten hippies can't do a d exactly
Stone the hi and and just regular people
that said that this this thing is okay
yeah and now there's more than 50% of
the United States is in approval of
recreational cannibal right which is
where it should be in 100 years ago they
didn't care right 100 years from now
they won't they care we care right now
though yes we do we're going to make it
half of right now absolutely yeah
um yeah and so what do you think um
about National legalization Federal
legalization Federal legalization
interstate commerce it has to happen it
has to happen it's really sad and
there's no reason that it should be
scheduled I'm all about
Des we need to deschedule it and treat
it like we treat alcohol and tobacco
it's a lot safer than alcohol and
tobacco for one thing yeah right but but
another thing being able to use
interstate commerce I think that takes
away the black market to a degree in a
good way I think interstate commerce
allows us to sell to other states uh you
know I just think it's silly that it's
not treated like alcohol or tobacco and
we're trying to reschedule it as a
schedule three drug I mean this is so
ridiculous it doesn't really make sense
we were talking about logic or common
sense how common sense is it
um you
know I don't see enough back door money
politically to make it a thing that a
guy is anti-cannabis and you can you can
vote on him based on that there some
wayone in that for politician and
there's a lot of money in it for States
and
municipalities should they you know be
able to have an actual Market
yeah these propped up markets they're
not
functional we're seeing you know the
we're seeing the best quality product
just um yeah knocked down Penny by Penny
by
Penny and the top shelf weed now seems
to be the [ __ ] weed the guy that's got
27 different grows multi-state operators
he's got the most money in marketing
exactly yeah I mean I think we get back
to our roots to a degree with uh
Boutique
flour I think I think but but also
there's a lot of people prioritizing
things like perple flour and I think
these things are fads I think that you
know purple flour is is nice but I don't
think it's any nicer in green you know I
think we need to go back and look at the
effect of the plant uhuh and the taste
of the plant those two things I mean for
me all the other stuff is just hype
anyway it's like yeah you know we can
talk about the way the ash burs and we
could talk about all these different
things but at the end of the day how
does it make you feel and how does it
taste tell you it I I want my pot to
smell to taste like it smells yeah I
like it to smell like it tastes yeah
that's that's what it's all about those
are the two first old factory senses
that you can bring to bear because so
Canabis Planet the smell one it's so
subjective it say is definitely a
subjective trait or quality yeah yeah
well Blue 13 spells amazing it's got a
tiny little bit of haze the tpine lme
and has a little bit of lime and it has
very heavy fruit
blueberry it's it's it's special thanks
thanks it does have quite the
combination and it's good that they all
they sink well they go well together at
any yeah yeah that's one of my uh so
that was one of my male breeding
projects yeah which that really baffled
me that um breeding males um
get what it was I was smoking and we
were looking at pictures of weed and
getting ey somewhere in a partner's
house down in his basement with they I
thought why all people breed their
males and I obviously knew all of the
answers because they didn't want 18
million seeds they wanted to be able to
sell their butt right oh you know I'm
thinking well there's ways just got to
be really
careful got to have a house on either
quarter of the 30 acre yeah no yeah but
it's so it's so much more simple than
that you know you can you can have a
safe pollen tight room to flower your
flowers you can have some stringent
dress codes pene rules you know clean it
shower shampoo whatever it
takes but um it's not that hard if you
put some work into it but right that's
just like growing any other way it's not
hard just s so work what you put in you
get out yeah yep and I was
um real surprised with that blue 13 mail
on the back of your book your latest
book yeah so let's let's talk about that
and and well I want to talk about
breeding more but let's talk about the
book so if you guys have seen the the
breeding
book this is my single favorite photo of
all time that's ever been taken of a
male plant and some people think it's
reversed I I've got a lot of comments
that they're like no that's a reverse
fight well it's not this guy is the one
who grew that bred it took the photo of
it and ever since I saw that photo I've
been in love with it and so it's just
it's a special photo there's nothing
quite like it uh you just kep and the
beauty of that is you captured it in the
moment it's not you know it it can only
be captured on film it's gone it's gone
that was at its peak and that was like
right before it started just dumping
huland dump as yes yeah you could tell
and it's just it's super healthy super
happy there's purple there's green it's
just it's an amazing photo and uh you
know for forever that'll be remembered
yeah at least by me and by the people
who read my book is one of the best
photos of a of a mail ever that's a huge
compliment and I I take it happily and
will anyway yeah there's um it was
actually I went to you to talk about
reversing yeah and that was I don't know
a year or two after this probably yeah
yeah still that was a while back yeah it
was there's no chemicals
no
silver sulfine or what there there's no
uh there no reversing tricks or well
there's all kinds of stuff all kind of
stuff and there's sowing if always just
skin a cat to still get good results but
you started breeding with males and how
many years ago was that because it's
been quite a while about 10 15 years
yeah and you did you made a mimosa you
made a mimosa before the M of the people
yes yes yeah yeah but the thing is with
that like [ __ ] man I can't put this on
the market it hadn't been [ __ ] back
cross you know just I didn't do the
stuff to stabilize it yeah there's a lot
of dudes that just Chuck pollen and
[ __ ] now they're a breeder or
accidentally make seeds now they a
breeder that happens too that happens to
by the way sh but uh I mean throughout
history you know there's other people
that just buy seeds and call themselves
breeders and it's the the hype train and
yeah you know I don't hate on anybody
and I don't call anybody out for
whatever they do I could care less I
just want to focus on me and improve
constantly trying to improve myself
because I'm not there yet I still have a
ways to go we got this book you took
photos in the book you're an amazing
photographer by the way thanks so yeah I
think uh we got some good pollen shots
and you you know you uh do the poll with
the desicant so dud I could so I'm
reading through that and the part about
uh one of the universities that have
been studying about by been in Israel or
somewhere and then their methods for
collecting and storing
Hall so these guys been to my house yeah
they know that right and and and it's
it's just hit or best double off with me
common sense right in common sense I
think a lot of it common sense isn't so
common but a lot of the if you think
about stuff you know and use common
sense you can be successful yeah how do
I get it dry how do I know it was still
dry I don't want to open up bottle in my
house yeah wor sealed how do I know it's
still good yeah you know this is all
about putting out a product you don't
want to put out [ __ ] put out a crappy
product so yeah that was was a whole
reason for me not selling Mimosa seeds I
hadn't stabilized him somebody came
along use the name snooze L yeah you had
a was it l Roa lunar Rosa lunar Rosa
what's his yeah what's his name was it
Belushi yeah is
growing lunar Rosa now something like
that same name yeah I think he took the
law the beginning yeah so it was L lunar
Rosa yeah real purple an thein so you're
right they're just they're not a flavor
flavonoid um they don't really I don't
know what it is that they can add to
something
ingested you know they smoke yeah um
it's it's a good um it's an anti
inflammatory I I think there's you know
and there's nothing wrong with purple in
the you know the the full palet of
different color possibilities you know
we talking about pink flower the other
day I was talking about how sfv actually
it'll turn pink at the end and some
flowers like if you go longer you're
making seeds with sfv certain genetics
they turned pink and I think that that's
beautiful I think that purple is
beautiful but I don't think that it's
more for me it's not more special just
for me personally it's just not my
preference and there's nothing wrong
that other people think that it's
amazing and they love it and that's what
the market Standard is cuz whatever it
is it is you know whatever the people
want the people want uh you know you can
change it by showing them something
different and maybe better but then what
is better right it's so subjective uh
you know because I think we're a little
bit older and so we like the hazes we
like the more up
Twisted yeah and I I love all of it but
I definitely love sativas and I love
that uplifting flower and there's
something that's special about the nose
on some of those you that are really
strong and just really loud yes yes I
can't get enough of them sometimes and
but but it's also you have to have a
pretty good tolerance for some of that
stuff you do it's not just the couch
loog tolerance right well you know you
can get paranoid if you smoke too much
tell palpiti you're looking out the
window yeah hiding from the cops they
there so we put meth in my weed yeah and
there's a lot on TV on the news these
days a lot of reports some of them are
soan just ridiculously obviously aimed
at an agenda but then again the science
really isn't there on either side so
definitely more science needs to be
brought to bear and that's something
going back to Federal legalization yeah
or at least say
cers this would be a v help when we're
having these discussions whether they be
political or legal or just societal
right um that we use accurate
information yeah I was telling you about
when I was first diagnosed with cancer
then it was a real bad cancer still is
I'm still fighting it but what I found
out was like well [ __ ] I'm this weed guy
everybody knows me from H out of Stave
the guy with the weed you with the long
here and H me yeah why can't I just do
what they all do and just cure
myself
and I you know I was kind of skeptical I
was always little skeptical but fck if
that's what they said they needed that's
what you got here here's all my super
diversity or Inda this will help you
yeah again whether it helped him or not
it prob help me right with benevolence
but what I found out
it you know the whole gram a day 30 days
or 60 days I did four grams a day
because I already knew I had a heavy
tolerance yeah I do for 120 days it
seems as if it didn't have an effect and
then about that same time just feel a
little bit after my first TR out of
chemo and then my surgery I discovered
that certain types of
canono can kill certain types of cancer
yeah but if you think that about that
again logically or with common
sense there's another truth to that
which has been verified with empirical
data is that certain types of conoids
can exacerbate certain types of cancer
this weed can [ __ ] you up and can kill
your cancer this weed couldn't kill you
through your
cancer who would have thought it you
know
yeah so that kind of my little rant I
haven't been online much lately but my
rant is whenever I see somebody
especially if they're try to sell oros
or Pico or whatever yeah if this kills
cancer C yourself but D we did this 20
years ago 30 years we already said all
of that [ __ ] yeah and we know it's not
true yeah and unfortunately there are
still a lot of folks out there pushing
it as
factual and uh robing people of a chance
long lot nothing else I know people
personally throughout my H best family
over 30 years said that's right man [ __ ]
that Western medicine [ __ ] those guys
and those doctors it's all about big
Pharma man big Pharma and uh we watch
those people die at death yeah and this
that's really the sadest part right to
me it was s so well it's to the
individual's body chemistry there's so
many things and so many factors it's not
straightforward it's not a one- siiz
fits-all solution if it was we wouldn't
have cancer anymore right and so it does
work for certain types of cancer it's
been shown to work for certain types of
cancer but also certain ailments Crohn's
disease man yes it's amazing for Crohn's
disease right but that other things uh
not so much and but but that every once
in a while you get somebody who's cured
from certain things so it's so
individual and I mean we're just
scratching the surface of it and that's
tied into the whole Federal legalization
that's why it needs to be federally
legal so we can study it and they are
allowing some studies but they're not
allowing enough studies once Federal
legalization goes then or or
decriminalization or rescheduling any of
them to be honest we can study it a lot
more in the United States they're way
ahead of us in Israel way ahead of us in
Israel and other countries as well but I
think we are making progress no doubt
we're making progress since we first met
it's a whole different moral oh jeez
right I goodness met in your uncle's
Fortress of a garage yeah yeah he was
going a bunch to my genetics and yeah we
got some good stuff and one a cup with
one of them yeah yeah yeah in amstr D in
amster D in
2012 okay y so it's amazing the things
that bring us together you know right
right and it's it's amazing how many
people you meet along the way that you
meet one time and then that's it and
then other people you know I talk to you
more than I talk to Uncle Pat oh so but
but yeah I mean you meet people and you
connect with people and you know there's
there's some Synergy and you know you're
in a breeding you you you know I think
we've had a lot of good conversations
over the years in photography you you
know we went out to squim at can
Organics and you took photos when we
were running the Autos out there with me
and
Kyle uh and Marlin I thinka came out we
had a good trip on nor yeah we did Mar
Asher yes sir sir good times yeah
totally good times I like arguing with
you about being a breeder though I still
I swear I'm not a breeder I don't know
ah you're you're more of a breeder than
most of the guys so all you can do the
breed you get the breeder card with me
as far as I'm concerned you're a real
breeder and you're actually concerned
about the things that matter we know
that I think so many guys are world
worried about what it looks like on
Instagram than what what they're
actually doing to the plant or creating
or feto hunting unfortunate yeah and a
lot of people don't understand the the
part about breeding to really be a
breeder you should be Fen acting and
selecting and finding winners if you're
not doing that you're just a seed
producer in my opinion you know you can
call yourself whatever you want I'm not
going to pagle on anybody but at the end
of the day the real process of breeding
is the selection process selection yeah
yeah so and that's what makes it special
and that to me that's one of the best
parts is you never know it's kind of a
watery to a degree I mean you might know
your Lin so well enough to go okay I'm
going to get something like this and you
have a good idea but sometimes it's [ __ ]
a lottery you CP 50 seeds and you never
know and and maybe you get nothing and
maybe you get all winner and sometimes
you get exactly what you think and
sometimes you get completely different
stuff that you're like where the heck
did this come from I had none of this
raspberry and any of my stuff a you know
I mean I think fruit pops up different
types of fruit mangoes guers some of
those are yeah I I love when those pop
up and then I love banana too Banana's
good I like smoking banana flour I've
never really had much luck with could
say luck but
um satisfaction with banana strains yeah
like gr big and wunky and chunky which
obviously like but the flavor is say
I've never really tasted God damn it if
it says banana in they want to taste
banana yeah for sure smell it well so so
I did a banana Skittles cross and the
banana Z House of cultivar they have it
and it ought to have them send you some
but the selection that was selected
because you get it all over the place
with within the selections there was
banana chip there was like banana cream
there was like plantain like a green
banana kind of smell there was like a a
couple different variations of like ripe
banana and then there was the candy
banana and that candy banana is what I'm
all about I wanted to smell those banana
e banana yeah well you know the banana
ruts candy I wanted to taste like that
where it's almost like fake chirp banana
and then even the extract when you smoke
it it has that fake banana turp and so I
you know but when I did my crosses I
made Regular seeds so I used multiple
males so that gives you a wide variety
of possibilities so if you're a breeder
and someone who's actually doing
selection you can go in and you can go
okay well this cross is like chem 991
and it leans towards the chem but it has
a candy banana or has a a unre banana as
a very green banana taste or as banana
chip or banana custards uhhuh you know
you get some of those banana custardy
ones
and I love you know it's kind of a
choose your own ADV interesting and
that's part of the fun of it yeah
totally and for a while there that's
interesting you should talk about
multiple Naes I've never really known
how to pose that
question or to who or where
um what does what's the advantage other
than variety so increasing genetic
diversity in the F1 populations when
you're Crossing things together for the
first time if you don't know the
breeding lines and you're trying to
select a male I would me personally I
wouldn't select just one male I probably
three males that represent different
sure Expressions yeah right and so you
know it's like once you know your lines
you're like okay this is the male this
is the maale that I Envision is the mail
that I'm going to use you know this
one's squat it doesn't flower right away
or what whatever your your goals are I
like the way this Stacks yeah you know
there's so many things but like for me I
did the the sent hour and with that I
used three different Vees that
represented three different things that
I liked you know and then when we did
that the PO populations now you have
more variety and diversity so you can
pick it's Choose Your Own Adventure
again and so and then the more seeds you
pop I have large amounts of seeds so
it's like okay we can pop 100 seeds and
we can SE what we like and if there's
nothing good there we don't have to go
for other 100 but if it's good maybe we
pop 300 or you know and you can do that
on a smaller scale you can do on a
larger scale I have some friends that
are popping a thousand seeds one thing I
think that's a little extreme personally
but uh I mean I guess it comes down to
resources yeah it comes out of resources
and you know what you're willing to do
as far as time because all that stuff is
very time consuming and obviously
expensive you know when it comes to
resources and is that the best use of
your resources 18,000 or 25,000 seed
fenite and if you have the space and the
time and the money maybe it's worth it
for unicorns yeah but a lot of stuff you
can find within a good population you
you might not find unicorn the next
whatever it is yeah you you may identify
the next OG Kush but lot of that stuff
is Lottery anyway like obviously like
the OG cush you know I feel like
something like that is has very
recessive traits and so that one was a
very you know whereas chem dog you look
at all those chem se's those were all
fire those it wasn't a winter winter
chicken dinner lottery ticket it was the
okay we popped the first one and it was
a fot it we popped the other ones they
were pretty good winners and then Sour
Diesel came out of that is you know you
know The Offspring of the chem 91 and I
think that so certain
things they just have it in there and
other thing is it's the watery where
it's that one in you know 18,000 or one
in 5,000 or the loud Berry that Jason
Midnight Rider hunted of my we popped
thousands of those seeds he got a 10
pack and found the winner in one 10 pack
and so you know and sometimes it's the
way it was grown and sometimes you grow
something out one time and the next time
you go ass out the same too so it's how
about they grow stuff out multiple times
you know and that always makes me wonder
well where does where did the difference
come
from no from one time to the next yeah
so so there's so many things I mean
there's uh chemistry changes that happen
within the plant uh as the plant matures
so you're getting maturity that's why
from going from seed to that first
generation you can get a completely
different expression and then even the
Next Generation so we grow it out
multiple times and we change our minds
on what we think is the best along the
way and yeah I think looking at data
plus actually being able to uh compare
side by side that that's probably the
best you know but like you grow
something out three times in you though
that that third time okay also you may
have to treat that plant a little bit
different you that plant easily thinned
out more here or it can be pushed harder
we can feed it more nutrients calling a
generation another seat you're just no
I'm talk clonal generation okay so we'll
do clonal generation so from from the
initial seed start I I've been debating
this recently but I always get rid of
that seed start and I don't grow the
seed start out so I start with the first
colonal generation and what we do is
we'll basically take that seed start
grow a big enough to take clones off it
right now we're getting five clones
we're going to clone those get rid of
the additional seed start because you
don't get that anyway so I don't want to
see what I can't have now if you're
selling seeds that could be valuable if
somebody's growing those seeds in a
field to know what kind of Expressions
they're getting but if you're trying to
sell clones and you want to or license
genetics like the stuff that we're doing
uh when you talk about licensing
genetics you want something that's
you're going at this representation of
what you'll get you're going to see in
the future what your customers are going
to see what people are going to see you
know for years to come hopefully
uh and so that's why we start with the
first generation and grow it out to its
three colonal generations before we
really make the decision on what's the
winter that's it for this time yeah
really it so I gotta get you down the
the Bay Area to check out the facility I
feel like we're doing some really
incredible stuff you know and I'm
excited to share with people like
yourself that we've been talking about
this kind of stuff forever and turning
it into reality is pretty amazing
seriously just seriously yeah very very
passionate for it again as we keep going
back to
um yeah can't think of
anything that requires passion that's
the negative Endeavor yeah in life so
throughout this journey you've learned a
ton of stuff I mean I feel like we've
all learned We're Young we think we're
so smart and we think we know everything
and we're so invincible and then as we
get older we realize we're not
Invincible we're fragile uh we don't
know everything we know very little
compared to what we could know and it's
you know forever we're learning yeah but
what would be your one piece of advice
for the younger generation that's coming
into the in Industry that's passionate
by cannabis follow your heart don't
follow your wallet and just [ __ ] the
money if you want to make money in this
industry maybe someday you will as you
can see these multi-state operators with
millions and millions and millions of
bankroll behind them but you know you
see those guys fall in by the ways side
really rapidly too yeah
um they don't have the passion for the
plan um they don't have the passion for
the
knowledge um I don't think they I don't
think a lot of these big
operators have an understanding of of
the power of this
plant so I would just say follow your
heart man follow your heart and have
good intents and and always be cure when
it comes to the plant just be honest
about what you're growing if you're
spraying it with something be honest
about what you're spraying it with yeah
you know um if you're having issues get
help there's so many people out there
that want to tell you everything yeah
because there's a lot of folks out there
that know everything literally it's
amazing how people how many people out
there know so much about growing really
good weed again it's um it's something
that takes some passion and and
commitment so yeah just don't get into
it unless you have
that I think it's as simple as a
authenticity there you go authenticity
absolutely thank you so you got quite
the guitar collection got a few back
there yeah you got some nice fers and
yeah yeah
so he's B Fender guy I'm more proud of
the Hempfest artwork up on the wall and
that was just like no other well you've
done other events too not just s so yeah
s and a friend so I was
uh like I love growing weed guy needs
guy needs to um fix his lights or his
exhaust or some [ __ ] in his room and I'm
working in a uh working for sea green
you might even know him have the first
i502 license in the state right and P
had a dispensary pretty close so
whenever I was out of weed or needed
something or I run over this place by
and weed became Pals you know talk about
growing weed he had a bunch of we GR in
the back of his
dispensary and um and I was up working
on lighting or saw him some company
giving a bunch of Lights in comes one of
the venders dve dve you got to check
this old guy out man it's crazy he's got
like the purplest weed I've ever seen
and it they're in a can it's in a paint
can so when I looked and yeah
about and talk about what I was doing
show B his weed and purple [ __ ] it was
uh stray called it old old Toby old boy
yeah we won't go much further we'll just
stop at little Toby
yeah there's a lot history with that see
yeah oh boy we'll talk about that later
yeah that's a all other show yeah
totally but anyways so we was really
good and uh we chatted for a while on
these so like do you do this work is
that to
do a carpenter all my life what he done
I do it right and uh well here's my
address my number I come over and need
to look at my exhaust in my Grow rooms
so that's how Bob and I H up he was
growing weed I was growing weed nice um
look at his system helped him upgrade it
he's a pretty good room designer but we
were sitting down in his basement one
night smoking cie missed the real cie
missed the real deal yeah real
this talk about sa
but getting back to the to the Cannabis
events Bob looks over at me says
Dave what do you think about
canacon I didn't say anything I'm trying
to figure out how to get to my phone and
buy that domain real quick yeah C that's
dumb Bob no like C like ComiCon but for
cannabis and I just couldn't come up
with any more excuses it's like yeah
okay it's a [ __ ] good idea that was
how canicon got started CL was always a
sales guy and uh had a history of Ring
Home shows so Home and Garden shows
basically so it was the perfect fit to
get into the round out trade show you
guys killed itas we killed it for a long
time killed it yeah you guys tored all
over you yeah pretty impressive yeah
than it was a lot of fun I'll tell you
and Sops that's where I came in yeah um
Bob had a 3x5 box of cards and he says
this is your uh this is your C own
customer relations
you it's a box of cards bu now well you
put the name and the number on the first
one you call them you don't sell
anything foot it to the back of the box
want to next one keep calling keep
calling make a note on the make a note
time date called would you say put in
the bag it's like dude I got [ __ ]
software for
that computer a like man you can't run a
business like this without being online
yeah and so we uh he Rel to we got some
CRM software um the website that we had
somebody built for us was a clunker as
usual so there was some chasing down of
uh IP guys that became my role um
helping
us navigate the whole Jungle of Ip Pros
you know right but we got a couple of
good
companies well in the biggest was the
digital
map um people want to know where they're
going to be in relationship to the
bathrooms so it's a lot of traffic to
the bathrooms they want to know whether
they're in relationship to their
competitors or just whatever yeah and
they definitely want to get the booth
that the salesman sold them and we got
guys we have a big paper cab drawing on
the wall of our office and the guys that
go check mark something or you know what
hold for three days guys are selling
Booth out from under each other left
right yeah and so when the guy calls
back with the check he I want to pay for
my booth
now uh uh well um I got you this gray
one over here it's a lot better than the
one you chose you know that's not a way
to [ __ ] we you do not build a
clientele that way yeah so that was
another contribution and made sure that
we got a map that was digit all and
clickable all and right all the stuff I
mean we were each in all right had um a
decent amount of skills but it was
definitely the um the combination yeah
that that gave us ws and actually
allowed us to to run this
professionally so
um that was kind of the role in the
beginning for me and of course it's
there's always the uh the plcity and you
know long haired Stoner hippy try to St
stuff to other long hair
hippies was was a hit Yeah by
sometime yeah you guys had a good run
this could to be an interesting Road
there's a whole lot of shows that are
going under yeah after the the beginning
we saw what Indo Expo that didn't last
long no there's some details behind that
one too but still perfectly viable event
that should still be around the dudes
that put it on were authentic well see
you've better part of two
different events and annual events and
one one that was on tour the US kind of
win all over what do you think the
secret recipe for success is with with
doing that in the EV in the event space
in the event space it's matter of a few
things first of all you need to know
rules and rigs in that
region public smoking lab public
consumption
um can you buy or
sell at the site that you're producing
this event on y even though the state of
the city allows it will will the event
center allow it that's always been a big
one but but the state says but the local
but yeah but this is our building we say
no so that's a tough one um so
definitely know where you're going and
what you can do once you get there yeah
that's the biggest thing because now you
can design an event
that fits the parameters of what you're
able to do right or you're able to do
what you're design originally
intended that and now Outreach yeah I
see people straight up selling weed on
Facebook sell seeds on Facebook it's
this that's the craziest thing ever the
the seed thing for me because you know
it's like I see I sell seeds legally we
can't use metaphor marketing to sell the
seeds yet even though it's to have
product is still a gray area with meta
for MPH they called it well no meta
which is other meta Facebook and
Instagram so I can't sell my seeds
legally through meta right now it's a
gray area like they won't let me do it I
could promote my book I could promote my
podcast but I cannot sell seeds and
that's fine but I do see other people
doing it you know they're they're uh
they're doing like the Gorilla Marketing
style and do it until they get caught I
guess it's what happens with us y we
type cannabis in one of our posts some
were taken down the next day yeah shut
down um there's an
event that we believe is has a good time
monitoring our pages and turning Us in
yeah seems to be sport among some other
F these businesses yeah there's a lot of
haters out there I wish they would all
just uh focus on making themselves
better but yeah I just you got to ignore
them unfortunately that's just the way
you go right and again it we'll go back
to allowing us to build stronger models
stronger business
models well you know your enemies are
the the ones who make you strong yes so
a lot of people don't understand that
you know if like your enemies are the
ones who make you successful and strong
yes and so you know everything comes
with a grain of salt but I think the
people around you are the ones you know
that influence and make you who you are
and that's okay too completely and yes
that they are you you are your
environment you are what you eat being
as simple as that yeah yeah
so then you
know components change some things boil
to the top of the pot yeah as they're in
the process of cooking and also those
are kind of my things you know like I
said the cream Rises to the top yeah you
may be in that pot with a bunch
of ingredients here know sure
about doesn't matter take on the take on
the essences
take on the other qualities yeah and
come up to the top of the F yeah you
know yeah fight your way if you have to
amen amen yeah yeah and you know I think
for me one of the things was I I was
told like you want to make life easy you
want your kids to have an easy life what
I've learned is struggle is what defines
you and struggle is what makes you
strong and so going through struggle is
not necessarily a bad
thing I at know hard work is good for
hard work is definitely good for people
yeah we need a lot more hard work out
there I think the younger generation can
of LAX that work ethic yeah but in a
couple Generations we can get it back so
remove it y yeah and we will I mean it's
it's a natural progression it's a cycle
yeah so as far as your breathing
philosophies let's dive into that for a
minute and to the first sh that I don't
have any of yeah well so I mean you
don't have any but you do believe in
breeding males you do believe in doing
male selections yeah so let's let's talk
about that you know as far as male
selections what do you look forward to
me like I said it's all yeah it's all
personal preference right yeah I like
what I like I I like a nice pointy spear
shaped nug and I like to see that in my
males I see a lot of males that that are
people's freaking unicorns and it's
interesting to me that they have some
little tiny top nugs and kind of Wither
away to the bottom yeah and I would
think that a more
vigorous chunky plant would yield the
same in the female of Warg chubby plant
so it was just that physical that first
physical observation of the of the plant
that that helped me decide right which
which was my favorite
I aromatics are a bit of a thing with
males but they're important definitely I
mean definitely important MH the clex um
combination of of TS and flavonoids that
you named off as you were smelling that
blue 13 you don't smell any of that
while they're little baby males W in the
dust no you know you get a lot of GRA
you get a little stem rub and like yeah
you get a little stem rub and get
something something in there yeah you
get a little green a lot of green a lot
of green but yeah for the stem rub but
for me I've always got chlorophyll some
of the time you get like if it's orange
you you'll get orange yeah you know or
if it's there's certain specific things
hazy was sometimes you can get that the
haze on there you know and but yeah
definitely like orange pops and lemon
pops CIT Citrus ones really pop but the
sub tees don't come out until the flow's
grown out and you can actually smell the
flow yeah the female flow the female
exactly and so that's where it goes back
to time it just bringing good we takes
time time and patience patience yeah
yeah I mean life is short the the irony
is life is short but you have to have
patience right victim but you know um at
a point that was where I was at in my
life I had plenty patience canacon was
doing really well yeah so I didn't have
to go out and hustle twice as twice as
hard as
before so so yeah that allowed me I was
blessed with the ability to have
patience yeah all of us a blessing it
this really is so that was what got me
into breeding males was why are people
talking about breeding males they read
this with that this with that how did
they breed it there are a couple of
females which one was the male which one
was the female yeah I mean all of those
questions popped up and said want to
read some [ __ ] males yeah and see
what happens well and taking photos of
males you've taken some amazing photos I
know a lot of great photographers out
there but not a lot of great
photographers that have taken pictures
of males right right so it's you hard to
come by yeah and they're under B yeah
yeah
exactly um the F and the and and the
photography opportunities yeah and and
the window is also short where they're
in their Peak to where they look amazing
so you really the the guy who's doing
the photography is probably the
photographer typically I mean I've had
photographers come in and get some of
the stuff of my Maes but but man if if
you are a photographer and you have
males it just makes it even better
because there's a very short window of
when it's in Peak yeah yeah F so then
when the when the basically when the
grenades have all opened up and all
those pollen sacks have open up the
pollen is released it's a beautiful
looking flower too yes you know M or a
or a minut for minute yeahor ptis or
whatever we had totally all on turns
pollen turns you got to really you know
basically separate that pollen pretty
quickly once they start opening up like
that oh totally but once they're open
and you hit them that's that's for me
that's one of the most satisfying
experiences is when you have a big male
or reverse female and you have the co
the huge Cola and it's opened up where
you know the P's going to fly and you
hit it or you shake it and that pollen
just flows whether it's in a room or
Outdoors Outdoors is even more
impressive yes totally you know I was I
was down south of San Diego with my
buddies uh and they were doing the my my
buddy created the well not created but
he decided to use the leaf blow with the
Mason jar of pollen and you shake it
Leaf flower and you know there's videos
online from this so the leaf flow is
turned around backwards to be a vacum
yeah well Leaf flower blows right so to
the back of it it sucks air put the
pollen in the dry pollen through there
and it just shoot shoots it out over the
field you know and this is this was done
on the offse but to see the wave of
pollen the plants and you know it's just
locking on and you're making a ton of
seed I mean I love that but even a wave
in the room that kind of floats above
the canopy of pollenly goes from Ed Edge
when you smack that plant well I like to
because I grow
indoors and you do the infinity tents
now like we have something in common
with I like those in CH this yeah the
controllers once you get the controllers
dialed in they do everything for you I
think they're really straight for easy
and if you're looking for breeding
Chambers if you have a house you can
separate your stuff but even if you have
a facility see Infinity tents work
really well for keeping your plants
separate you have to maintain this size
of a room or seven plants or 10 plants
exactly yeah when they make them in
different shapes and size different
needs I me the little 2x4s yeah I had a
couple of those so that one hanging
around um I put my Mals in there and
just flower my Mals yeah um definitely
taking care and caution with my exhaust
systems MH but once those males are big
and they're ready to go um I take a big
ass mason jar quarter pound jars yes
call them clean the hell out of it you
know do all of the sanitary stuff yeah
and I turn off all of my air light off
cuz they have bad cheapos head pans um
turn all the air off no move as little
as
possible zip the zipper open just enough
for me to get up in there yeah and I
take that big ass [ __ ] top Cola and a
couple of the other branches and I'd
squeeze them together and you loing
little po floating down sure to this
point just upside down with that mason
jar I don't know if I can hold on to one
right out upside down with that mason
jar and oh yeah had some quite you break
the stem and then you just give a slap
just a slap and you're watching it all
roll down the side of that jar roll it
around a little bit more damn just a
slap and just like gently pull it out of
there as you're pulling pulling with it
oh I'm sure oh yeah and then you just
cap
it lock everything up you go out on the
front porch or wherever so it's not to
you know contaminate your indoor air too
much
total give it a spank on the lid I just
watch that stuff roll again down the
sides of the jar solid yellow wave
just [ __ ] love it yeah that's that's
my favorite part of deina ating a mail
yeah and I collect it and clean it and I
think a lot of people would love to hear
about how you clean your pollen and
store your pollen I think that's
valuable I don't talk about that enough
on my show but you know I think you're
an expert in that regard so why don't
you share how you uh colle from that
point how you separate clean it store it
uh dry it out yeah and a lot of little
black bugs that I don't get indoors that
I get Outdoors yeah I don't know if they
are but I know a good reason to grow
indoors with your
males but um pretty simple take U you
know six or eight um sheets and and put
them on a table something like this
table right here um of just typing paper
you know printer paper
mhm and it'll take it have a round
rimmed
um calling her a s a screen just buying
screen plop that on top of the jar turn
it all over I get to have fun Bing my
pollen down the sides of the jar again
just the other way B smack B you know do
it for a
while until you get till you feel like
you get everything that's going to roll
out of there um now I've got a piece of
paper kind of tap the S side well ways
to get it into a singular file I'll
crease the papor down both sides yeah um
make end up making like the old cocaine
things the folds with the snow
seals that little diagonal thing they
big coke and but snow seals I remember
so I basically give a big snow sh powder
envelope powder envelope yeah thank you
yeah yeah yeah and um at that
point um I'll sit it in there I'll DP a
bunch of desicant beads in it um color
changing desicant beads y they're easy
to find Amazon has them all day long and
these are just a plain beads they're not
inside the packets the packets would
just get a lot of pollen stuck to them
and just the plain beads and I you know
squish them around a little bit I seal
that little pouch up and stick something
on top of it yeah for a while a couple
of days come back SI out all the beads
they've turned all Pink by now yeah so
Ty to change a bead s them out on that
same little SI I was talking about the
little ra screen um redo the process St
it back on the paper you can see if
there's debris in your falline right and
um that's the first thing you would do
is pick out a little tweezer or
something to pick out any debris growing
indoor I get very little yeah um and I'm
not beating the heck out of the plants
I'm getting really virtually no Leaf
debris mhm so you got some pollen it
it's pretty damn dry do that about three
or four times until I get literally no
pink Beats back and it take a week or
two and try to do it out in my garage
where it's cool yeah in the 60s or so I
try to keep it cool I fight with
moisture out there I really have a way
to you know to mitigate or to control
the whole environment and that's where
I'm thinking about adding back that
little 2x10 tent right so I can throw
humidity in there take it out just as
easily as I could control the
temperature yeah so a pretty good
environmentally controlled pollen curing
if you will I had never thought of the
idea of curing pollen until I read your
book or that section of your book it's
like [ __ ] these better do everything I
do yeah they stole it
room the big university in amster ever
somewhere those
[ __ ] had a little funnel and then he
put it in glass got a little funnel I
put it in the glass while I try to mix a
good amount of the color changing to get
me along with it right sea tight as hell
um of course I make my fast little
labels with the little crow on them yeah
with the brand basically the what it is
it's this times that harvested on
something such to dat when you're brand
blue Crow
correct and you've had that since I've
known you yeah because I remember the
first photos I got were like in a
Dropbox type thing where you blue photo
or the blue grow for a long time mhm
don't know why it was a random thing
took a shot actually out the front
window of my house there's a crow Bing
down eating AA that's cool just clicked
it and going through my stuff days later
it's like that's a really cool picture
and I make a nice logo or something
that's so luk Crow was born yeah Crow
eating a peanut on the side of the road
yeah well you've made a living as a
photographer too you worked as a
photographer for a long time we didn't
really Touch Too Much on that other than
saying you includ you were included my
book but you've done tons of photo work
all throughout the years I got stuff in
High Times I don't even you I heard
you've been in books that authors
haven't credited you properly as well
you don't need to throw them out of the
bus but I've heard that you've been in
symbolics where you weren't credited
several yeah several of them and those
guys I'm not sure which one's worse the
play
all that's just playing old fevery but
then there's the IP F that people don't
get yeah and that goes to the Z's all of
the
Z's and um tells there's a brand here
that uses the Mr Yuck sticker remember
Mr Yuck yeah that's straight up brand
that's he changed it changed the name
but same symbol you know we paid a ton
of money with the candies another event
that may or may not come to fruition
over the next several years right
somebody big company big testing out in
California
decided they were going to change the
letters from NN i s to NN Ys yeah canes
um first off there is is a real lame way
to spell the
canes um but secondly still steel ini sh
yeah not big with that thiefs yeah you
know the industry is kind of been built
on that with genetics wise people
renaming and thank you look at run Slim
Sherry gelato and gelato
33 and the comparisons where people have
just cut fished other people for
whatever it is and that's not just the
only one it's been throughout the years
I mean OG Kush in it's really sad that
it's gone that way and you can never
really trust it but
also what is really what is subjective
to the individual and what they have
been given unless you got it from the
breeder who knows maybe you got this
awesome cut and it's called this but
really it went through seven different
people got renamed along the way and it
thought that or it's a sugar I'm growing
out of small badge right
now um five mediumsized
plants and I have a friend of mine who's
genuine friend great girl and you know
she's like I keep forgetting the name of
that what the hell is the name of that
strin D It's like a dog EP cook what's a
dog F cook I said I don't know but it's
alien dog times four un cut cookies how
else do you shorten something like that
a dog fut I don't know she why don't we
just call it this no I kind like a dog F
cook that's wild it's catchy and once
you if if you're into genetics you'll be
like get it they don't know alien dog
they know forarm cookies a dog F cook
just makes sense it's kind of
creative I like it but it's not thievery
yeah she's hold me she's I can change
the name no problem with says I can't
yeah but I can said no you can't I can't
you can't nothing down my [ __ ] Garden
is going to get rename that's some
[ __ ] right oh she got it took a
minute but she got it yeah and that's
huge that I mean that goes back to auth
authenticity it comes back to
thievery um once I rename it now it's
not obsolete genetics strain
anymore what does that mean means I
stole it yeah and has had a lot of that
happen over his career
obsolete uh I don't know is he still out
in working he's a good dude yeah I just
he's supposed to come by next week and
we're going to hang out and [ __ ] a
gentleman said hello love to meet us
someday and I love the a dog F cook and
a have to I love that I can't wait to
show this clip to him that's that's
great I don't know and he's just a
really good guy I think people have
really tried he's a great breeder by the
way his work has been abused by other
people and you know it's so funny how
people uh are so easily willing to take
other people's genetics and put their
name on it or call the the thing
something different than what it really
is or just call their [ __ ] somebody
else's yeah it's yeah it's just so
that's sad y we live in a sad World
though unfortunately yeah huh that's I
always say it's a choice Joey tell my
son as he's going off to work in morning
have have a good day it's a choice
happiness is a choice a choice
absolutely you know so is ripping
people's J off that's yeah this is a
[ __ ] Choice yep leave you would they
laughing
this so This podcast is actually a
two-part podcast filmed on the 12th and
on the
13th uh we were able to sit down because
of Dave's Health we did in two two uh
batches so we did the first hour and a
half uh and now you're going to watch
the second hour and a half
but before the second part of our
podcast here some messages from his
friends and family hey everyone Michelle
the writer here I just want to give a
huge heartfelt thank you to Dave for
taking a chance on me when I was still
young in my career canacon was one of
the very first press passes I ever
received and was one of the very first
cannabis shows I went to and it was in
Seattle in 2017 that I realized my
destiny of being a cannabis journalist
and a steward of this plant and if not
for Dave and his support I don't know
that I would be where I am today and I
can't believe that you're gone but you
just did so much good for this community
and for the world and I'm forever
[Applause]
grateful so walk along through this
beautiful part water on the way to
Oregon for a canabus event or seems
fitting to uh make the video to
commemorate Dave and all he's done for
this PL and what he's means to this
community he will be
missed never forgotten but think about
Dave how much he loved to play it or she
L people involved with it and how honest
he was thanks for bringing people
together from multiple ways from hempest
to
kog to just being an all out great d
thanks it's
[Applause]
forever hey just a tribute to my friend
Dave man you're a good dude I met you at
the Seattle Hempfest and we just kind of
hit it off and you just were maintained
friendship with me for all those years
and you had a good impact man you were
just a really quality person it's always
hard to say goodbye to a friend but the
truth is you never say goodbye the
memories stay with you forever and I'm
grateful that you reached out to me for
some assistance when you go through your
struggle it it just let you know that uh
you have faith and trust in the
relationship and
it didn't turn out the way I had hoped
it did I really had hoped you succeeded
with that battle but you succeeded in
Touching us as friends and you succeeded
in Touching The World by being a good
human being so I'm going to miss you
brother I'll see you in the
afterlife hi I'm Jennifer Allen the dope
Duchess
and Dave Dam it and I had a very special
friendship and
relationship uh we met at a 420 event in
2017 uh the Cannabis Grand crew um and
as soon as we met we were instant
friends exchanged numbers uh we're in
contact immediately hung out and it was
so funny cuz he tried to date me and I
was like No we're going to be best
friends uh cuz it wasn't necessarily age
appropriate but he was like you know
what you're [ __ ] R lady and I have to
happy my life so that started a 7-year
[ __ ] fantastic friendship between
Dave Dam and I we had a unique
friendship because he you know jokingly
I would say he was my canid daddy
because he was like a father and a
mentor and a best friend for me in the
Cannabis industry he supported
everything that I had created and he had
my back on all of my wild ideas and he
listened and you know some of my ideas
were absolutely [ __ ] Bonkers but they
were legitimate and they were real and
they were creative and he absolutely
adored it and supported me completely
and followed it through all the way to
my pitch of my comic book to different
magazines so you know I I joke that he's
my canid daddy but really he was more
than that he was my best friend uh he
was someone who I confited in and grew
with and our love for cannabis Bloss in
this most amazing friendship between us
with our love of animals and plants and
you know just exchanging information and
being good humans and enjoying life um
there was a lot of different things that
we inspired within each other and that
we healed within each other and I know
he did that for a lot of different
people uh Dave was so intelligent and so
kind and so humble and he had such a
loud and booming voice but he also would
be so quiet and direct with his
words um he was a very very special man
he was so knowledgeable and he was
absolutely humble kind and generous and
hilarious he was a he was [ __ ]
hilarious we had so much fun together we
would always just go eat delicious food
smoke a joint and laugh our asses off
listening to awesome music and rocking
out and dancing and we just have the
biggest fattest Smiles on our faces cuz
we were just enjoying life together
smiling and just having a ball and we
would crack up all the time we' dress up
silly and we would just literally
enjoying basking each other's ridiculous
energy and we magnetized each other we
went to every event together and we had
like silly little competitions between
us with our hair and we'd flip and dance
Dan and we you know roll joints together
and compete on who rolled the best joint
you they've taught me a lot of different
things and I'm so thankful and grateful
we got to be friends for that long and
enjoy so many facets of each other and
just really live and I absolutely Lov
watching him at Hempfest and being you
know in his Groove and in his space uh
he knew everybody he loved everybody he
supported everybody and he was the most
generous being ever I I mean literally
every time we would hang out and he
would see someone on the side of the
road he would always give them money and
always support them and always smile and
give him something positive and say
something absolutely kind and lovely
because that's the type of person Dave
was Dave loved everybody and he just
wanted everyone to be absolutely [ __ ]
happy and he was a [ __ ] gem in the
acamis industry and we lost one of the
most amazing breeders geneticists
pioneers and human he was literally a
force to be reckoned with and he
highlighted and supported and magnetized
and loved everyone around him people
literally could feel the Dave damit
vibration when he came into a room and
you could see it you could see that long
curly ass beautiful [ __ ] hair that
man had the most beautiful damn hair you
would ever see in your freaking life
I've never seen more women jealous of a
man than when Dave damit would walk in
and he was adored by women he had like
12 Hempfest wives that he got co-
married to because absolutely everyone
thought he was fabulous and we just love
and adore Dave Dam it and we will
forever ever miss him and we will always
smoke to him on 420 and we will never be
forgotten he is an international holiday
and we abs absolutely celebrate and love
you dearly I love you my dear dear best
friend I missed you and this is not
goodbye it's goodbye for now I will see
you again in the near future I love you
so much to the moon and back goodbye so
this is the second interview of the jam
R podcast with my good friend Dave
mesford AKA Dave damn it AKA Dave damn
it damn it Dave damn it Jam yeah so
let's talk about the first time you
started growing yeah so I must have been
about 13
and uh
14 and a kid used to I I was born and
raised Catholic hardcore my mom was like
the church lady she went to all the
things and did all the stuff and uh we
were kind of isolated here in Lynwood
and this very dead end you're looking at
right now is actually where I was where
I was raised wow and uh bunch of
Apartments finally went in over the
bushes it was a forest over there it was
great kids started coming up and down
the road they'd H the fence and they go
up to the public school which is just up
the street M and um finally made friends
with one of them this kid was walking
walking to school every morning with his
can Coke turns out it was beer you know
so hit these guys and that was my first
experience smoking weed was with uh
bones well Bruce and Brian couple of
twins became my first public school
friends you smoke it out of the can
smoked it out of the can nice yeah so
for
those of you that don't know a lot of us
had their my my first experience was out
of a can as well but you know I soon I
soon transitioned into a bong after that
you know we had the plastic Graphics
bongs back when I was a kid right but
yeah so you started smoking out of a can
I smok on a can decided we were going to
grow some weed put this little
fluorescent light in my closet oh my God
if my mom ever found it you know yeah
and I didn't know the first thing about
growing weed put in dirt keep it in some
water you know keep it moist and grew
great couldn't figure out how to get
flowers on it didn't even know there was
such a thing as flowers because the
commercial stuff we were getting was
just that commercial Columbian whatever
it was so it was really good sometimes
but yeah we didn't get much flour in our
bags right and so I didn't didn't really
learn about growing flower for quite
some time so we smoked dried up leaves
yeah yeah wasn't very good didn't get
very high just her out for very long
because of that yeah we all have origin
stories though we do
eventually uh hanging out with the older
brothers of Bruce and Brian we met some
older dudes and they were the weed
dealers we learned a little bit from
them yeah about where it came from and
and most of the weed up here was brick
weed that had seeds in it there wasn't a
lot of hom grow right maybe in the 80s
there started to get the ' 80s was when
we had the the hom grow bag appeal hit
Affy thae ay thae ay Tha bro I sure
missed that stuff and it wasn't it was
so interesting how sticky it was and
I've yet to
see in modernday cannabis the same
qualities where it sticky literally I
could throw it it would stick on you
yeah right pick it yeah you don't see
that anymore no it didn't but it wasn't
just wet weed right it was res it was
resin yeah it was resin you could stick
it the glass no problem you can th it on
anything yeah you got it's going to be a
[ __ ] to wash that piece of glass off
yeah yeah so we went through that
transition here that was my learned how
to roll weed with that stuff learned how
to roll joints wow what a pain in the B
that was yeah chopping it up your little
bits with scissors trying not to get it
clunky yeah so that was it back to
growing weed wow it took another couple
of years for me to actually try to get
serious about creating buzs and flowers
once we saw the appy thae of course
since selia when we were learn about
cilia too was like yeah when you get
some seeds from that stuff there at No
Seeds bro cilia
right found some decent weed to grow
some decent seeds Columbian weed wasn't
bad man Hawking and all of the stuff
that DJ Short loves to talk about yeah
damn um we grew some good weed out of
those seeds yeah yeah they finally
learned about the light cycle nice yeah
miracle I don't remember what we did for
fertilizer we dug in my mom's Miracle
Grow under the kitchen sink that she
used in all of her house plants right we
NPK man F NPK is some of the most
rebranded repackaged hyped
[ __ ] couple of entities on the planet
they I mean just you know totally basic
so there something we said for basic too
I think uh totally a lot of people want
to get so complicated and on some level
you can go really basic and get really
good results you know as we get older we
want to refine stuff and we want to make
it our own
but on some level there is the beauty of
Simplicity and I remember amazing stuff
and maybe our Palace were different or
whatever but like there was a lot of
stuff that you know less is more in
certain instances for sure I started
using this this guy's nudes I always
wanted to grow organic but you know that
really takes outside it's tough to grow
organic unless you're
outside um now with modern technology
technology to grow organic um it's a lot
easier now there's a lot of the provide
they starting soil at the very least I
mean there's organic soils you can buy
organic inputs you can argue that promix
is organic or not certainly they add
some
uh no not vermiculite but the other
light perite perite rather thank you um
that was always my base I just started
we started to use a make a super soil
yeah and adding all of our own inputs
and the tarp method Shake of a corner
shake you know go around it and mix the
heck out of it but um after a point I
met a
guy
um who was making his own nutrients up
in Blain up near the Canadian border
yeah and uh Dominion Organics if anybody
remembers the brand nice uh Blaine
passed away didn't have any PL with
family or friends to carry on the
business but he built some of the finest
finest organic
inputs never grown any better weed than
with his wow yeah just just good stuff
and unfortunately he died you know the
re ofes who knows where they are who
might have them family isn't interested
in in any upkeep of the company or the
product seem be happening a lot lately
pardon me that happens a lot with these
the younger generation not wanting to
follow suit with the parents for
thousands of years the St the son or the
daughter did what the father did
typically it was from father to son
father to son and businesses got dressed
on and and names you know yeah totally
they followed the father and the son and
their business right but uh
unfortunately that didn't happen
here and um so it's really interesting I
quit growing there for a while got sick
um had some health issues uh minute
growing just all the work of growing was
overwhelming to me so I had to quit and
I so I quit for a couple of years during
that time this is when Blair
died and um so getting back into growing
I had a couple of half buckets of this
half buckets of that and grew out my
first batch
and made me real
happy second batch I ran out of the NES
wow like damn and I finally found out
where you know why I couldn't get them
they weren't out there neither was their
maker and so I'm shopping around for
organic nutrients and Alaska fish
fertilizer came up I thought yeah that's
organic as hell I'm going to use that
and I found out they also had a blue
they the low end and the high end
thought this is perfect man it was cheap
man super cheap so I started growing
with this
stuff and I don't know what was going on
my plants were growing and getting huge
and turning brown cardboard Brown all at
the same
time the hell's going on with my weed
man um and the one thing that I really
took me this whole most of this whole
batch to figure it out duh no greater
check my
pH during this time this six or eight or
almost 10 years time that I grew with
Blair's nutrients yeah the dominan
Organics I ended up hanging up my pH
Meer never never needed I was like why
do those even use a pH everybody's all
like got to check your pH got to check
your pH well was always great yeah six
65 67 you know just right
there so I never really pH I never
bothered to after a couple of years of
going through that breaking a pH made
hell they were 500 bucks or something
back in the day they still probably are
well you can get the $30 pH feder and
you can get the $500 pH right you can
even spend more than five you sure you
oh yeah you sure can but um and there's
the middle of the roads but uh I finally
decided I should probably check
something yeah you know where we where
we fans dying so I checked the
pH
2.0 2.0 oh well that explains a lot that
explained a lot like yeah I've been
growing weed all my life I'm I'm a
master grower man
yeah um but those are valuable lessons
totally you know
I I know I happen to find a um a
nutrient mix that went well with the
water that's always 7.0 yeah perfect
yeah so got myself a pen and some up and
down and yeah but I just still didn't
like the Alaska fish fertilizer I don't
know I'm using it hesitantly because
it's
organic um and obviously with a pH meter
having you know results like I did yeah
the the turps and the flavors flavonoids
that's kind of yet to be seen I don't
know that that blue 13 yeah that was a
Alaska fish fertilizer yeah that's got
some decent turs it has great turs yeah
yeah it has really good turbs yeah so
and it's really complex and that's the
one thing I like I like complexity with
my flavors if it's just straight
blueberry I might like it in the
beginning for a day right but I get over
it real quick uh my favorite things have
a lot of complex to them yeah our visual
friend
Allison Hell she's come by Till It's
Gone quarter pound at a time her first s
stash yeah she just blew through it I
can't smoke anything
else yeah once you find something that
that you get along with like that where
you like the taste you like the
effect and it's available yes you know
that's the thing is is like it's a fresh
product so like availability it might be
available once every 3 months if you're
lucky it's available more than that but
typically you know Back in the Day stuff
was good stuff was available once every
three months you might have a little
window of a month
so but uh we had droughts too where you
couldn't get stuff for extended amounts
of
time that was also a Time coming into a
time where um medical laws were enacted
in California and then Washington and um
that was the Wild West for quite some
time so well availability was pretty
good well let's take a step back into
the 80s because I feel like not a lot of
people that watch the show unless they
were there not a lot of people know
about the 80s ' 80s was before my time I
started smoking in ' 91 but I would like
to hear about the scene and the energy
in the 80s you know CU that that's when
it was really illegal across the board
federally on a state level yeah
everything else it was kind of scary man
I mean cocaine was right there in the
80s too yeah and it was like you know if
you were balling you had the good weed
and the cocaine and all that crap but uh
weed was interesting um we did go
through droughts yeah in those days boy
I remember my wife was pregnant with my
with our first child my
son and you know we were just sick and
not having any weed and I'm like [ __ ] it
I'm going downtown I'm just going to go
[ __ ] downtown and buy some weed I
just know I can and H A
Little Hippie want to be biker all my
life [ __ ] you know yeah out there
causing trouble hitchhiking up and down
the roads you know hanging out downtown
places I didn't
belong so we hopped in the truck brand
new big four-wheel drive she's pregnant
you know I'm balling union carpenter you
know doing pretty good and
uh parked remember we backed in against
the back of this building and in front
of us was a Jack in a box and I said
just hang out here I'll be back in about
15 20 minutes I'll will come back with
some weed yeah and sure enough I did
found a dude on the quarter up man you
got
weos paid him 15 bucks per a grand wow
yeah nice backgr but I mean still 15
bucks for a grand yeah if you look at
what it cost today for that $15 Grand
would have it's like $100 Yeah well yeah
especially given the circumstances the
legal um but there were $5 grams and
there was $15 grams and it was all over
the place back then too but but it was
also a lot more illegal the given the
legal climate um yeah i' have paid 20
bucks for that gr or more yeah but yeah
so I'm in my pocket I'm like cool
looking around I'm just a guy going back
to the truck I get in and um I said
something like H yeah I told just so put
it on the seat we were getting the bowl
out about to smoke a bowl out said well
yeah I me too I got some too what do you
mean you got some too but you just [ __ ]
pregnant right you're just going to stay
in the truck come on man that's not cool
but right on and and
um I've got the weed between my legs on
the seat and the bowl protop pipe
remember the protop I Absolut we've
talked about on my show before I love
the protop pipes
that's but uh so I'm busted it up kind
of in the bag
and got a load a bowl and I looked up
and I
said
oh this
guy's the dude pulled out of the parking
space really weird at an odd angle and
he backed in backed out and stopped like
right in front of me making it
impossible for me to drive out of there
oh wow and I felt it I mean I felt it
right then it's like what the [ __ ] is
this guy doing I come on man we're
leaving I started the truck let me out
of here and then I saw the guy coming
from Over Yonder who was talking into a
brown paper bag oh and then I knew it
was over [ __ ] all over I dropped the
weed on the floor tried my best to kick
it under the seat with the pipe they
came couple dudes on each side they
grabbed her didn't want to even talk to
me yeah because they sold her the weed
it was a sting oh wow put her in the
back of this van like so he sold weed to
her actual weed yep to her and then
busted her for then busted her for it
while she's pregnant to the 80s while
she's pregnant welcome to the [ __ ]
see that's wild that's just wild that
that could have ever happened I tried to
follow him in the van I lost him finally
get a phone call on my old next flip
phone and um they had taken her to this
underground Garage in one of the
precincts yeah and where they were
processing people and she was the stuff
that she was hearing was just like yeah
no no we don't want that get we need
that one that was worth a lot more money
they had a bunch of Mexican dudes all
handcuffed same B all all of this [ __ ]
she was just in a garage pregnant as
[ __ ] on a bench with some
dudes yeah get the boat definitely she
was telling me there was like the
vehicles they had down there hot rods
badass cars I don't know what was an
expensive car in the 80s but they had it
down there in their impound this is all
the [ __ ] they were doing under the um oh
what the hell was the name of that act
there was a federal act that that went
around and was enabl in all of the
municipal cities to do this stuff so um
yeah that was the 80s wow I got busted
selling a quarter pound to a cop who was
um my buddies and their their biker
lifestyle and the bar and all of that I
fight a [ __ ] cop in a biker bar yeah
this guy been up there everybody's
looking for
weed um my buddy's youngest brother he
was like the high school kid we were all
the cool kids he was like just this
little kid nerd but he was the dealer he
was making Buck he always had weed for
the old guys right right and uh he'd
been out too told him [ __ ] Scotty I can
get some weed from this dude that hangs
out with your
brother and uh no way said yeah come all
up to the bar it was here and um my
buddy is like we were just out in the
car doing Lions Coke of course he's no
cop he was part of the snow County the
multi-county task force he was a cop and
they sure were snort and Coke wow come
home man we made a deal for the next day
to meet this guy and we uh we had the
cash found him in the parking lot of the
holiday in hopped into the truck with
him he showed us the weed he says let me
see the money Scotty whipped out the
money and here it went Deja
Vu the guy under in his trunk with the
fishing rods he wasn't getting pushing
Rod out of his trunk he was just
standing
there the car that was coming towards us
with all four of the doors opening as
they're rolling through the parking
lot said set up it was a total setup
sting operation dare remember the Dare
movement dare program big old [ __ ]
dare t-shirt I was wearing yeah oh the
cops should not like that they push my
face in the [ __ ] ground man oh I bet
they kicked the [ __ ] out of
me that was just the middleman yeah yeah
but yeah that was that was weed in
the80s um that was one of the periods in
my life where I quit growing H like nah
man I pregnant my wife we're gonna have
a kid N I can't do it I was just too
scared I was not one of those dudes with
big balls yeah keeping everybody
smoking well on that notion you got some
big balls later on in life because this
is the same yard where I came over to
your house and you're growing big ass
plants like right behind where I'm
sitting right now you had some plants in
the same
bed uh so you did have some balls yeah a
lot less to lose at that point too right
you know a lot less to risk right yeah I
mean I'm I still smile every time I
think about those plants you know like
in your front yard we're not talking
about the backyard I mean everyone grows
in their backyard true not a lot of
people grow in a suburban area in their
front yard you know I think what are
those pot plants in your front yard sir
oh is that what that is cool
right but uh yeah that was that was an
that was
a that was a middle finger Danny cop
that drove down my dead end yeah living
at the bottom of a dead end you know
they look over here as they're turning
around yeah that was well that was the
the point where it was going legal you
knew it was going legal and yeah she
basically just said [ __ ] you medical I
got a medical card I mean all of that
right yeah so uh n let's talk about the
90s a little bit cuz you so California
in
96 uh went medical right and that was a
big deal prop 215 25 yes uh and that
kind of changed the landscape for
everybody uh especially Washington
followed suit with medical or in
followed suit several other states yeah
it's definitely been a West Coast thing
the thing about Washington coming up
here since the 90s smoking weed up here
since the 90s
uh I always found that it was more moist
and I for the longest time I didn't
understand it fully but there's so much
more humidity up here you go to Colorado
it's really dry you come up here it's
moist right like so you leave it out of
the jar for just a couple minutes it
seems like uh it would be spongy so
there was a lot of spongy butt up here
not that it was bad or anything like
that but there was it was spongy Bud it
wasn't until I feel like the 2000s in
the midd 20 where people were using
controlled environments to dry and cure
their bud before they put it in jars
they're getting that uh what I would
call back then California quality and we
just have naturally good weather in
California so it made it so much easier
for that drawing and curing and the
longer shelf life yeah completely
completely yeah I agree and that was
something you know that was something
that we eventually got into yeah um you
know like I said in the 90s medical
happened and uh
so did a lot of huge commercial grows
yeah that took a lot of weed out of
state tons and tons literally up here in
the in the area right here out of
Seattle yeah growing in Barnes I think a
lot of people grew in Barns where was
downtown in the middle of [ __ ]
downtown Seattle wow yeah talk about uh
air game VI on point I was worried about
my eight lights like when I went to
eight lights it was a big deal back
that was where I
realized that there was a there were a
couple of places to fit in this culture
yeah there were the medical folks that I
was always down with that helped promote
and then there were still the top secret
guys which had always been there yeah
that that they were just making so much
money so much Bank yeah and you know
fists I believe the the medical folks I
believed everybody
who said that cannabis helped their Al
helped their
ills and that's where I decided I would
land yeah and that way I could grow
small amounts didn't have to worry about
getting you know 10 20 year sentences
right um and yes there was the medical
legal sure justifications but those
still were not a not a sure thing but um
I ended up I ended up knowing everybody
on the
planet that need needed weed they had no
money a lot of them had no money because
they couldn't work because they couldn't
get the weed cuz right diverticula just
you know simple [ __ ] that probably
wouldn't kill them very soon but God if
they had some weed they could punction
like you and me yeah like an average
normal guy so that kind of that hit me
in the heart yeah that's the direction
that I ended up going in so yeah I never
made the tons of money that a lot of
dudes
did yeah I mean I would say that the
the Elder the the lady that basically
turned me onto the
lifestyle of you know having plants she
she gave out a lot a lot of flower a lot
of flower and she was part of the the
AIDS movement and she constantly was
giving stuff out uh you know she was
selling stuff too but I would say she
probably gave out as much as she sold
and exactly you know and that's that's
how I met you originally is through her
and through Pat and so it's it's the
same kind of thing and I feel like she
was pushing Organics before anybody else
I heard it from her Organics grow grown
with soil you know things like that and
uh yeah I feel like when you can give
back I mean I feel like cannabis just by
itself you're making the world a better
place and if you can give it to people
you know obviously you can only give
what you can give I think there's a
there's a line where we can give back to
a degree but we can only give so much to
where it's benefiting other people and
not hurting ourselves I had to I mean I
subsidized my garden out of pocket I
don't know how many times yeah it's like
now am I G to pay my rent oh crap yeah
hurry up and
dry but when you're dealing with people
that actually need it cure an a not even
to cure but maybe to help them whatever
they're to get through the next day and
some people that's all they need is to
get through one more day yeah yeah it's
it's an amazing beautiful thing that
brings so many of us together yeah and
it's that it's that Care
Community that's the true cannbis
Community right I would say that's the
foundation of it all yeah and I think he
goes in other directions but the
foundation and the
origin of the legalization wasn't the
financial side it was the people that
didn't want to see other people go into
prison and the people that knew that it
helped other people the CIA
compassionate action um so many groups
that were
literally um founded on compassion yeah
and Care yeah and yeah definitely proud
to have been to have even played the
smallest part in that so many people
were involved and I can't sit here and
say man I gave out all my lead to sick
Bookers
so many people did that so many people
did that but it's a on another notion
though it's it's a collective effort of
so many people so much effort and and
just making positive movements in the
right direction you know I think that's
how you make change it's it's all starts
with one action it can start with you or
anybody else but it's a it's a group
effort and it's a beautiful thing
because we're here now talking about
ited you know we couldn't talk about
this in public and probably even record
this oh my God 30 years ago in your
front yard no we we'd be in big trouble
by now your neighbors might call the
cops on us you know 30 years ago God
looks like he's got a pot leaf on or
something and there's three of them and
they're in the yard no they got cameras
yeah totally it just gives my heart Joy
could so it keeps giving yeah it keeps
on giving I I can barely give my weed
away because everybody's already buying
it at the store they didn't know some
dude still grows it yeah there's some
folks obviously that do but um just to
think about it and to actually be able
to own that that Karma that good sense
of good yeah that's really awesome you
know karma is always this mysterious
thing that you never
really I guess well karma is real
whether you believe it or not that's
what I've been saying my whole life it's
like karma is there karma is real it
doesn't matter whether you believe in it
but to be able to feel it and as a
affirmation that it really is a thing
and that is there for sure yeah it's
that's amazing yeah I agree right yeah
totally so for the ones that have uh
done me wrong Karma's there whether you
believe in it or not you
know uh yeah and we we live in this A
Beautiful World and there's Beauty in
the world even with the you know there's
sad sadness tragedy all these other
things but it is a beautiful world that
we live in we're really blessed to be
part of something so much greater than
ourselves amen amen and we're blessed to
be able to recognize that right yeah I
mean I think that's that's part of it as
well being able to be grateful and have
gratitude yeah and living in gratitude
and I mean you know we we don't choose
the cards we get dealt always but we can
choose how to deal with them to play
them
right yeah yeah we we are blessed for
sure cannabis is giv back to you quite a
bit too I mean traveling with canacon
being part of something so big that has
a legacy right and canacon is is really
actually cool it's very unique event
couple War shows coming up um in the
next few months we got three more shows
this year the biggest coolest event yeah
was always the Seattle hempest yeah
always I mean the hash bash they've been
there a decade or so longer than us sure
Kudos man um well there's no Hempfest
this year right there is none that's sad
very sad there's no 420 in San Francisco
this year at Golden Gate Park big free
event yeah I heard that was done done
too I just heard about that last week or
yeah it's really sad I mean they're
losing financial support to be able to
put these nonprofit events on the
Hempfest the sale Hempfest we talked
about it yesterday it is was and always
will be the largest
Canabis
event on the planet yeah huge 300 and
some thousand people in our busiest
couple of years yeah our 20th and 25th
anniversaries 300,000 people through
those small parks in the downtown area
of Seattle
beautiful Puget sell views me snow and
all of the beautiful people in this part
you it will never be reproduced and uh
and there's nothing quite like it there
no there's other events there's other
great events yeah but there's nothing
quite like Hempfest if you've never
experienced it it's something that if it
still comes back you need to go check it
out Amen on you know especially there's
a lot of
people uh that talk about right and
wrong with cannabis you know we got
Freedom
Fighters um like
yourself you know that have helped put
it on and I just thousands of us though
not just me I'm such a small part in
this well but you guys are all cogs in
the the big wheel yeah totally totally
yeah there was a lot of cogs yeah and I
was just one of them Co came y 2019 2020
that was a big hit to us 502
legalization came yeah and the laws
prohibited um commercial cannabis from
advertising yeah the advertising laws
killed most of our Revenue that we would
use to put on the event the event cost
almost a million bucks yeah to put on uh
they were talking rent and port I mean
it's it's an event like any other yeah
you got to have the infrastructure sure
got to have the people and of course the
cities they would always throw some uh
they would always throw some something
at us sideways but we'd manage
to manage to very
nimbly um catch the throw and make the
play for sure activism isn't cheap it's
not cheap it's not easy yeah it's not
cheap it's not easy you just got to do
what you believe in you do it y yeah I
guess the final part of that is
that we achieved our mission statement
yeah we really we didn't you know we
enabled um 502 to pass here we enabled
legal cannabis the idea that 502 is any
good or not is still up for debate um
but I will say this for sure when you
get pulled over and your car smells like
weed you all you got to do is tell that
officer I'm sorry officer but the smell
of cannabis press or burnt is no longer
um a valid reason grounds for you know
see longer grounds for a search or or a
seizure yeah but you know you can go to
the store and you can buy an ounce of
weed and drive home now yeah I sold Rick
Steves his travel goo Rick Steves in
fact that's an issue that that's a image
that I shot for High Times They beaten
stock and Rick
Steves um showing and they they asked
for the prop yeah I said uh you're the
photographer Dave hey yeah this is Dave
I'm with highes we're going to do the
shoot for Rick Ste I'm like cool he says
um so any way you can provide the
prop they he couldn't even say it on the
phone right that's how deeply embedded
this paranoia is for sure still is still
was but um we went and did the shoot and
I had some that blueberry a before I
crossed it yeah with other stuff and
they were big nice nice hunky nugs and
Rick Steve's had him in the bowl at his
piano his Rick ste's say sure after the
shoot they both were
like the prop for
sale so I sold Rick Steve's his his
first legal outs nice well gifted it to
them that works under the law that's how
we did it right but uh Good Times yeah
good times but yeah back to the Hest man
we killed it because we were successful
yeah and um there's been the world
cannabis Freedom March going on for
decades and decades M but remember the
some of the core parts of hempest were
also core leaders in in the localized
cannabis Freedom march here yeah in
Seattle and uh I marched with them that
year it was the last year I did it yeah
get screamed at from obvious po hippie
in their cars the [ __ ] out the road you
stupid hippie we're trying to go to work
or you know I mean come on what are you
[ __ ] with us for yeah weed's already
legal you kid I could go buy something
going to buy some weed right now you
know yeah with all these legalized weed
we not legal you you know the the Min
the minuscule issues of legalized weight
you know is it really legal that's the
arguments you have so much you can only
do this with it now they're trying to
regulate uh THC levels and concentrates
here in Washington silly very silly they
don't understand that they're proing up
the black markets every time they make a
move with their policy yeah
yeah no only profit up the black markets
in terms of
availability quality there again more
doe diverse selection right dude Black
Market isn't just some [ __ ] we got
some [ __ ] from the sidewalk yeah oh no
dud that's the guys that are growing
craft weed it's the most craft produ tot
production of craft cannabis in the
state of Washington is what what sinks
most businesses what sinks most
production companies MH it ain't easy to
sell your [ __ ] for you know 25 cents a
gram after what you got to put into it
it's again it comes to the multi-state
operators with enough money to buy or
Price everybody out of the markets is
what we see here yeah I think it's what
we see across the country Washington has
some good brands though there's some
people doing it right house of cultivar
my good friends over there and can
Organics and there's a bunch of guys you
know I think that those are just a
handful of them that I'm friends with
but uh those the guys I'm friends with I
feel like they do some of the best work
in the state for sure it's all
subjective but because that that kind of
leads into my next question is how do
you feel about
legalization what did they do right and
what did they do wrong not integrating
vertically I think because the biggest
mistake yeah really not allowing
vertical integration actually was none
yeah so you can't own your own
dispensary if you grow right right huge
it's a huge hit to Growers yeah it's a
huge H dispensary operators it just it's
the market is not a true market it's
propped up here and there yeah um you
let a market go it will correct itself
markets just do that right um ours
hasn't self-corrected because it's got
so much hesty structure over here it's
just not the true market yeah um a lot
of what we didn't see the DUI for vision
was another huge one um five nanograms
in your blood that's a subjective number
too it's such a subjective number the
state you've probably got like 10x on
that right now in your system see the
state's
toxicology um lab uh lead Professor CEO
whatever you call him he was totally
against it and he showed what
yeah and he showed how the comparisons
work between alcohol and cannabis and
amounts levels in your bloodstream yeah
and uh it just is nonsensical so it puts
people at risk who just took a hit
yesterday and you know or it was Friday
they got off work they smoked the bowl
it's Monday they're going to work well
they hadn't been high since Friday they
damn sure got five nanograms in their
blood right and now they've got DUI the
DUI is a really life
destroying little piece of law
infraction if you will that's just no
good it lead you it costs a lot of money
yeah um for some people because of their
background it might cost them a whole
lot of time away from their families or
off work going through some kind of
treatment program getting a job if you
don't have a job and it's not your
record um yeah yeah not a cool thing at
all as far as what do they do right I
mean it is they did something right they
passed it to where I think they went in
the right direction yeah totally um I
can go right now and buy some weed yeah
I just go to a store and buy weed yeah I
don't have to like hope I know the guy
or does he remember me or right because
my guy is out you know yeah hopefully
he's still do you remember me yeah so
convenience definitely for convenience
yeah testing is a good thing it's a
whole another debacle whether testing is
done properly accurately should this
event tested how should it be tested
what should it be tested for um I'm all
for testing because we're ingesting this
stuff yeah why not sure we test the
quality of beef we chickens we test most
of the stuff that we ingest yeah I mean
I think the levels at which we test are
higher than any other Agricultural
Product okay I and I haven't compared
but yeah I accept that assertion yeah I
agree I I imagine that's true yeah some
of the stuff may be a little bit extreme
but at the same time if we're doing it
we we can do that right yeah yeah
exactly and that that's a whole another
whole another philosophical battle in
the in the world of cannabis between the
powers that be and the yeah the actual
powers that are meaning the The Growers
The Producers
processors uh unfortunately we don't
wield as big a stick as you know the
municipal folks and the yeah the
legislative folks what would you like to
see in the future for
legalization homegrown has to happen it
has to be legal they took away homeg
growing in the state of Washington yeah
that's one of the also one of the
biggest mistakes they took away medical
and they took away well they didn't take
away medical per se yeah but you do need
to register with the state and have a
medical card and of course you can um do
they still have medical dispensaries
they have no not strictly no but they do
have dispensaries that cater to medical
patients
give them a price break yeah they they
still have to pay tax though still have
to pay excise tax yeah and that's on
just about anything you buy here in
state of Washington anyways yeah but as
as of through the Cannabis Alliance yeah
is another group that I'll shout out
cannabis Alliance to yeah um they've
just achieved a great victory in the
Senate and through through the
legislature I should say that does away
with excise tax on medical cannabis so
in July it starts sometime in July if
you're a medical cannabis patient with a
card of course um you can go buy your
weed completely tax-free that's how it
should be yeah I think that's great
totally and I think it
also will lead into
um uh medical providers hmos and all
those guys to pay for cannabis
prescriptions yeah essentially I have a
prescription from my doctor mhm it
allows me to grow a few plants and then
I have the extra plant um right in that
she did those do they should give you
some free electricity too that be great
yeah wow I had thought of that there
some solar panels whatever you right so
give you some solar panels for your
plants I think that's great oh yeah it's
a great idea want to go green let's go
double green all right the future is
bright um and you know we're also de
deal with a bureaucracy that is our
government so the future is slow and
cumbersome and falling all over itself
right it's still pretty bright there a
bright pile of [ __ ] rolling
underground but uh better than a dark
pile of [ __ ] better than a dark see yeah
we're getting there getting there slowly
but surely guys like you that are
driving this it's a team effort I say it
all the time and yeah I mean it's we're
all just in it together to be successful
and there's people that are passionate
there's people that driven by the wrong
things but there are people driven by
the right things there are
people that have passion for the sacred
plant like I talk about a lot like
yourself like me the saying is it takes
a village but the truth is it takes the
world man it takes the world it's slowly
changing people's mind about the stigma
of cannabis I think that's and so there
we go it's the stigma and what how do
you beat a stigma education it it comes
down to education and that's where I was
going when I was thanking you for doing
what you're doing you're putting this
out there um I don't know how much you
can monetize a podcast unless for some
big Rockstar it was it was never about
money yeah this podcast was never about
money or accolades Awards any other
stuff thank you for the awards I
appreciate the awards that's great but
this podcast is about the oral history
of the plant and uh it's it's a
beautiful thing and also I have so many
friends in the industry being able to
share their
stories uh
makes me feel
great you know being able to share your
story makes me feel great talking about
Legacy we we talk about that a little
bit your legacy you have kids you have
grandkids M I have two grand kids two
grandkids how do you feel about Legacy
and what is your legacy you know my dad
was a merchant of the union rep for the
C fars International Union sell deep sea
I sell deep sea yeah getting in trouble
as a young boy young man um got shipped
off like a lot of kids probably did
right it's just something I was not into
you know then I got married and had a
kid and definitely didn't want to be
gone all the time yeah and uh this
wasn't something for
me uh went into construction union
carpenter for decades it's not something
for my son though he's not into growing
weed he's not into growing or you know
he works construction pseudo but I'm
afraid that my IM immediate family
doesn't have the desire to carry on my
legacy yeah and so that kind of leaves
me in a Lurch you know um what am I
going to do I've got some great genetics
man sitting in little bottles and jars
in
refrigerator getting old going bad you
name it you know run the gamut just like
any other guy that breeds probably I was
saying the value of seeds is in their
use and not in their possession amen and
there's so many people that collect
seeds and it's like that's that's great
sad but it's sad on a whole another
level it's sad that you're not using
those seeds and finding out what's in
there because there's magic yeah there's
there really I mean we we can we see eye
to eye on that and there is Magic and
seeds there's stuff that's still waiting
to be discovered there's tons of stuff
out there where are they though where
are they they're in D refrigerator in
his laundry room by his garage right
then that's an issue for me right now
I'll give it my health issues yeah well
and your legacy is so much more than
that I feel like we were talking earlier
about the
2013 it was it 13 or 14 with Snoop Lion
yeah uh in Denver we were at that cup
you were at that cup you brought your
daughter for her 21st birthday to see
Snoop Lion you got to smoke with snoop
Snoop Lion and he was Snoop Lion because
they didn't pay him enough because he
they couldn't afford to pay him a lot of
money but he still went on and djed
instead of instead of rapping yeah and
uh that was a magical cup that was a
magical experience but you have been
able to share the those experiences with
your daughter and passed on experiences
that she can pass on to Jasper to Jasper
yeah really cool and I mean there
stories like that where you you know she
got to experience it and she was telling
me earlier about the story on the you
know on the on the lot when she was at
the event and they have all the free
samples that they give out and it's
she's not the only one that's happened
to but you know they have samples and
there's like all these cool Edibles and
if you're into Edibles that was the
place to be because there would be
cotton candy and there would be ice
cream and there would be hter sticks
Savory stuff yeah crackers that had you
know infusions and there was just 500
milligrams dude and you and back then
they weren't really concerned with high
milligram doses now in California it's
like 10 milligrams per dose 100
milligrams per package back then I mean
in the 90s we never even thought about a
milligram it was like how strong can we
make it to where it still tastes good
but exciting times you know back then
it it was the New Horizon and everything
was new and I when you're younger it's
kind of like that anyway oh yeah but
like all the stuff is new and exciting
and smoking out of a can for the first
time or even after you've done it a
while it's like what else can you smoke
out of what you know you know and they
talk about cannabis being the gateway
drug right I feel like we hear that a
lot I think alcohol is a gayway drug in
my own opinion he man hey man TR but uh
truly but yeah I mean truly alcohol is
the gateway drug and cannabis is the
kind of opposite in my opinion mhm yeah
it's the gateway to to Enlightenment to
Enlightenment to sobriety if you're
having issues with other drugs it's
definitely well it's a self-reflection
drug so if you smoke if you get high mhm
cannabis will help you self-reflect yes
and see the world as it truly is you you
may not want to see yourself that way
and I think the people that El spoke
they feel uncomfortable and because
because it really shows you who you
truly are psychedelics do that too yeah
they do and they really show you the
truth whether you want to see it or not
yeah and uh it's a peaceful thing oh
very much so very much so and again
there are a lot different strengths of
psychedelics when you said that I
almost you this really isn't a
psychedelic that's a pretty tough
blow but you know and in that respect
yeah I have to agree it changes
perception perspective perspective and
perception yeah and uh you get really
high you're going to think things that
you wouldn't normally
think and uh you might get real hungry
yeah get real hungry and you're gonna
the thing is that you're going to think
so much of things you might not
ordinarily think
of but you're going to open your mind to
allow them if they come by there they
are well you might not see the things in
the same way you would see them if you
were sober and I feel like smoke allows
you to see things from a different
perspective exactly yeah and I feel like
if we were all smoking it would change
our perception and perspective on the
way we see things yeah you see good and
bad and you know I feel like uh you see
the world as it really is sometimes
psychedelics even more so you dive into
some psychedelics and then you start
lifting off these filters you can be
gone for a while yeah yeah cuz what
happens is I feel like we get real jaded
from the experiences of life from the
time where born we have these
experiences and every experience puts a
filter over your eyes right over your
mind yeah and so sometimes it's great to
lift those filters off and see the world
as it truly is agreed so because we
we're all we all live in these bubbles
we all see the world from our bubble
because of the experiences that have
been you know there's some genetic
involvement sure and psychological stuff
but you I think we inherit some stuff
potentially M but uh lifting those
filters off and mus mushrooms you know
all psychedelics mushrooms LSD yeah iasa
you know DMT forms and P right I feel um
even I were talking about mushrooms
yesterday and how they're kind of not
really the most fun high um the stomach
High I hate getting the stomach High
yeah they're not a very social high for
me just depends on the for for me it's
the opposite it depends on the mushroom
it might have been my brother I was
talking about yeah yeah yeah yeah so for
me it's the it's the opposite I would
say that it's depending on the mushroom
but my good friend Mr Marlon aser uhhuh
we uh have eaten our fair share of
mushrooms together
and they and if it's too much I I'm very
antisocial yeah but with the right dose
and especially the right kind of
mushrooms I can't quot laughing and I
have the greatest time and this guy is
someone who goes out and performs and
sings ree in front of thousands and
thousands of people high on mushrooms no
uhuh absolutely and and you know and so
I it's a public speaking thing for me
too sometimes I'll do public speaking
and I'll eat a micro do before because I
feel like uh my memory recall is better
and I'm able to respond it's it's like
caffeine with memory recall for me with
the micro dose interesting so I'm able
to do a lot of public speaking and and
you just have to get once you're past
that fear it allows you to open up right
and I don't do it all the time I don't
need to do it on my show but uh I've
done it on my show and I've done it at
MJ Biz when I spoke uh at MJ Biz before
and um yeah and it's a beautiful thing
but heavy doses of psychedelics are
definitely for reflection yeah you know
going inside and
seeing the world as it truly is or it's
it's a great way to reflect on who you
are and getting rid of your ego and
looking at it from the outside
right so his ego is just a it's one of
those things we all have to deal with
ego yeah we do we do I agree it's an
integral part of us I mean without an
ego that's that's a whole new different
consideration yeah if we all lo you know
kill your ego that's always been a thing
where we all be if nobody had an ego
we'd all be one would that
work was that like not like
um homogenizing every single Canabis
veto out there it's like no it's just
weed yeah kind of weed weed it's just
one thing just one thing yeah so I
wonder wonder how that homogeneization
of
humanity well I think you know we were
talking about canono and
cancer yesterday we touched on that and
people selling RSO under the guys that
it'll cure cancer and some cannaboids
are good for and have been proven to
help and be beneficial and other kabon
can exacerbate certain conditions
certain types of cancer and but some
people are using the RSO as like a
blanket statement that my product cures
cancer yeah yeah and just just floating
the idea out there that it's a Panacea
of some of some sort yeah it is no
Panacea there really is none you know um
with a little with science thrown in
halia cannabis can do a lot of things
I'm sure yeah and possibly may be able
to you know cure cancer or at least be
you know one of the one of the
prime sources of that of that who know
and RSO to a degree there's many types
of RSO too it's not not all RSO is
created equally all of my hardcore canus
ofici a out there every time I say RSO
they're just go oh SHO themselves in the
head oh oh CU right evidently Rick is on
the well I get it it's not a clean
product it's not a good
product PCO now or Pico full extract
cannabis oil is the thing right and I
know that in my circles if I don't call
it that I'm beat
right so that's for all you uh Pico fers
out there yeah well and it has the
potential to do great things it doesn't
always do great things but it's so
subjective to the individual and our
individual body chemistries and thank
you so much for coming on the show and
for giving me the time to interview you
thank you I mean again you talked about
Legacy right and this is part of my
legacy I've got some I've got some ideas
out there that I hear you pick up on
from yesterday yeah and that that makes
me proud yeah
awesome I know that I'm also
contributing to the greater
the greater cannabis database in the sky
right yeah you know we're building it
we're building it we're building it one
story at a time and I mean if we don't
record it the stories are gone the
experience is still happen but the story
is gone and this is all it's a
generation that is aging out yeah and
you got to get their stories yeah oh
they're still here to tell them they're
great stories I mean your stories are
great you know and it's
like the collected effort because
there's so many people involved with it
and we're not going to get all the
stories but I'm going to get as many as
I can as many as you can yeah yeah I've
already lost a few oh that yeah I mean
people passed on and yeah yeah oh gotcha
yeah yeah so yeah well thanks again and
keep up the good fight and I want to
keep up the good fight and so yeah and
we'll see you soon okay love you brother
love you too
man thank you guys for watching the
episode I hope you guys enjoyed it got
perspective on an individual that was so
important to our industry uh the
GoFundMe information is in the
description of the podcast if you guys
can donate please do so it means a lot
to everybody he was an I can't stress
the fact of how important he was for our
community kacon is an amazing event
Hempfest was an amazing event and his
photography will live on you know the
photo on the back of my book will be
there forever and it is by far the
greatest photo of a male plant of
cannabis that I've ever seen to this
point in my life uh so thank you guys
Dave we love
you uh your family um and I thank you
guys for tuning in again and have a
wonderful afternoon
[Music]