[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James loud
podcast and today our special guest is
Tim also known as Bobby bags from fav
and lighting how are you doing today I'm
good I'm good thanks for having me man
I'm really excited yeah me too thanks
for coming on the show we've been
talking about doing this for a little
while you know we met not so long ago uh
we met at the so at the connected event
where you spoke uh and talked about your
your under canopy lighting yeah and I
was really excited to hear that it was
you know a success and I've heard from
other people that it was a success and
now we're going to be triing them in our
spot here and I'm assuming it's going to
be a great success too I'm super excited
about it yeah I'm uh I'm gonna go ahead
and say it'll probably be a a smashing
success here but excited to see I'm
excited to see it's the Natural
Evolution I've had friends that have
been talking about this for 5 years
saying this is what this is this is
going to happen and I'm telling you that
this is going to change the game and
then you did it and I'm like okay so
here it is yeah my buddy Justin he was
talking about this for years and you
actually executed and I think the
product is great I mean as far as I I've
seen so far it's great some people are
even using two rows yeah oh yeah so one
one every foot yeah pretty much so let's
talk a little bit about your lights
first you know I think the the best
place to start is like where the need
and like where the idea for faven came
from and you know so I've been growing
for about 15 years now and 10 like 10 of
those at you know somewhat of a large
scale you know I think scale gets
redefined every like two to three years
right like 700 lights two years ago was
a lot now 700 lights is a pretty
standard facility right and right you
know couple of hoop houses in 2012 you
were doing it you know 20 lights in 2012
you were you were doing it you know so
scale gets
redefined but um you know where the
underc canopy really came from was um
I got a job at connected and alien Labs
there in Sacramento and the head of
cultivation there was um a big a a
previously big a um R&amp;D just wizard to
be honest with you he was I learned a
lot from the guy um and one day he walks
in and he's like all right we're going
to do under canopy trials and
intercanopy trials and I was like I have
so much to do you're going to add this
on my plate like I was not happy about
it I'll be super super honest with you I
was like really not happy about it but
then you see them and then you start
turning them on and then it only takes a
couple days of watching the plants
sufficiently lit in a whole different
you know really kind of
reworking our idea of lighting the plant
right and it only takes a few days and
that's kind of where it all spurred from
but you know I worked from I worked for
connected for a year and you know every
time I get the chance I I shout them out
because they really gave me you
know a great Launchpad for
just about everything in the legal
cannabis space like it's it was very
hard to break into legal cannabis you
know a couple years ago and little
easier now but man you really had to
know somebody to get into a facility
back in 2020 you know and it was it was
tough going so um big shout out to
connected for really laying the
foundation for successful cultivation at
scale like I learned so much in the year
I was there um you know after I left I
kept pulling the under canopy thread
just because I knew something was there
and there really wasn't anybody on
market doing it right and um I think I
told this story at the talk you were at
but I walked into my my partners partner
in faven uh his office and it was just a
day where I was frustrated or something
I don't know and I came in and I was
just kind of complaining about every
product on market and how these
companies with like some kind of under
kopy light were just they just didn't
understand they didn't get the big
picture like they were lighting guys
they weren't Growers right right they
did didn't understand anything about the
growing potential like they didn't they
didn't understand the skew as a whole um
and so my partner just kind of looked up
from his computer stale face just looked
at me and was like then do something
about it like make your own like you
stop complaining kind of thing and like
that day you know faven was was born so
um you know faven was created out of the
need to provide Growers with the right
tool for the job you know like I am a
grower first I'm still a grower first
first like faven takes the majority of
my week now but first thing I do when I
get up in the morning is check my graphs
and make sure everything watered you
know so I'm very much still in the
throws of growing and um there was
nothing that really was there that could
handle the rigors of of scale
cultivation you know like putting a
light underneath your underneath your
plants are they're subject to you know
water down there they're subject to
sprays like there's a lot you know it
there was a lot that went into actually
designing a light that fits into
facility workflows right um we nailed it
with faven it's the killer product so
but yeah that's kind of where it all
started so I've been been working with
under canopy for about four years now
and um fav's been selling lights for
since June so it's been 10 months not
even nine months when you guys hit the
ground running oh yeah oh yeah and we
you know we knew how to go about it and
we knew we knew to get the product in
the hands of the right Growers and um
bear up in reading a golden state bear
cannabis was one of our first actually
our first tester and um we knew he was
going to tell us if we were on to
something or if we were faking the funk
and you know I got a call from him like
three weeks in and he was like geez like
we have six more weeks to go and it
already looks like a like a banger you
know so um you know we just we we really
hit the ground running
and gosh it's been a whirlwind sense man
it really has I'm yeah it seems like
you're super busy every time I see
you're on the phone and it's always
something yeah um I actually I actually
have this week was the first week that I
felt like I had the team in place to
really really start executing on the
bigger larger goals and the bigger
vision of faven and um it feels really
good to get there I me tell you that
like having the right team around you
can make everything you know the right
team is everything you know because you
can't do it all yourself but you need
people that would do the job if as good
if not better than you when they're
doing it you know they represent you
whether you know if you're a cultivation
facility whether it's a grower that you
know but they're an extension of
yourself if you have a team you all work
together it's a fine-tune machine yep
that's what it's all about yeah you know
that stuff makes me smile yeah it's it's
it's the fun part like building a
business is a little scary because I've
never done it before yeah you know and I
like not to repeat myself again but I've
just been growing like I've just been
growing you know and I have a Consulting
business but like that's me yeah growing
you know it's way different yeah um so
it's it's been a lot of learning um I
love the learning I'm very uncomfortable
right now so I have to learn to get more
comfortable well you like getting kicked
in the nuts cuz that's what happens when
you start a business and I'm going
through similar stuff like it's it's
like waking up getting kicked in the
nuts a couple times and smiling you know
and then knowing that tomorrow you're
probably G to get kicked in the Nets
again but it's okay because you got your
business and you know it's fun yeah and
today I'm sitting with James lad on his
podcast so I mean come on yeah seriously
I mean it's it's it's an adventure and
there's a lot of unknown and there's
stuff where you're like oh next time I
do it I'll do it this way I mean I think
I've learned a lot I think distribution
is extremely important no matter what
you do distribution is so important
having those distri doesn't matter how
good your product is I mean you always
want to focus on the product but really
the distribution totally is just as
important if not more important than the
product because there's a lot of
mediocre [ __ ] that sells I'm not saying
people should make mediocre stuff but
I'm saying that they have good
distribution and mediocre stuff sells
exactly you really have to it would be
very easy for me to just dive into the
unit at all times but really I have to
know that we did a great job designing
this we went through many iterations to
get to where we're at today this is a
fully fleshed out product this isn't a
version one two or three this is our
version right we will iterate in the
future but smaller tweaks like we don't
have R&amp;D samples going out to customers
this is a fully fleshed out version so
it would be very easy to just keep
diving in and keep tweaking and keep
tweaking but my where I'm most needed is
the distribution channels and getting it
in the hands of Growers and and and
really kind of breaking down that
barrier of under canopy seeming like a
gimmick you know because it was kind of
a joke for a while well and I I think
with most things if you tell people I'm
G to get 25% more
yield or you I'm G to get you 25% more
yield they're going to laugh at you yep
you know because we've heard it so many
times over the years I've heard it time
and time time and time again you're
going to get 25% more you're going to
get 50% more all these fictitious
numbers typically and you came through
with something that actually gets you a
bigger yield yeah yeah underc canopy and
faven in particular is is the most
revolutionary thing since since the
teros 12 right since you know substrate
monitoring came out because we watched
facility
efficiencies you know increase so
substantially from like 2020 to 2022 you
know just everybody got better at
growing because we now could see inside
in the substrate and so underc canopy is
very much in that same vein where is
going to be like if you do not have this
in your facility it is going to be
extremely hard for you to compete and
it'll cost you money yeah I mean you're
GNA leave it on the table for sure
you're leaving it literally leaving it
on the table there go I mean uh it's
funny because I remember you know so
I've I've been doing this a while you
know and back in the day you know I'm
talking in the '90s 2000s it was two
pounds of light was good like you
literally when I was growing cookies
back in the day I would get 3/4 of a
pound per light with the you know and
that was acceptable it wasn't good but
the prices were so high it was a whole
different thing exactly um now the
prices are much lower and the the yields
are much higher yeah you know two pounds
is like eh yeah you know for a lot of
people and there's still people that are
okay with two pounds but as a commercial
cultivator two pounds is kind of rough
you know if you look at your cogs you
know look at what you're leaving on the
table looking at your potential and
we're talking about potential yeah we're
talking yield potential right and yield
potential without sacrificing quality I
think you know a lot of this is going a
lot of this podcast will be about yield
potential and that but really the thing
with THC canopy and the thing with faven
and why it took us so long to get to
Market and is because we prioritized the
quality of the of the extra yield as
well right it's not just like hey here's
extra yield because you can't
we we can't just boof out our plants and
expect it to sell on the market it
doesn't work like that well you went and
focused on the the problem part of the
plant which is the smalls so many people
have tons of Smalls Smalls are a big
thing right now people are buying Smalls
left and right people are going to hate
me real soon man when they realize the
smalls are going away seriously and how
so what kind of decrease do you get in
your smalls so I'd say industry standard
you know um without under canopy you're
looking 15 to 20% is a acceptable run I
think genetic to genetic right we're
looking difference well and we'll kind
of leave genetic variation out of the
conversation because we won't get
anything done if we talk genetic to
genetic sure but you know we're really
looking for 5% and really that 5% is
they're still purple they're still
mature they just may not meet the size
requirement like they're completely
mature and
THC color uniformity they just may not
have the size so it's a true small right
but there's no more greens Smalls right
like there's none like and in in sack
where I'm based out of you know Green
Smalls fetch $100 to $200 less per pound
than purple Smalls same genetic oh yeah
so you're talking a revenue increase
just right there you know and then you
talk the yield and then you talk you
know the the uniformity of Bud in the a
bags right anytime we talk yield or I
talk yield I'm only talking about the
bags that go at the highest price yeah
that's all that matters right now is how
many bags go at the highest price from
that
right that's your yield it's interesting
because every grow is different and some
people two you know two pounds of light
is is their minimum and like anytime two
pounds of light comes across the board
on yield they get a little nervous you
know and three pounds is where we need
to be but you know unfortunately yield
is the fastest and the easiest way to
decrease your cost it really is and it's
really unfortunate but it's where we are
at in the market it's really pinched The
Growers you know I feel like I feel like
a lot lot of people in this industry can
kind of doesn't matter how well the
Growers do they still have a job they
still make their margin everything's
fine but it's really really those
margins have compressed on The Growers
and you know faven is here to really put
that ball back in the Growers Court like
we really want this tool in the hands of
the grower so that they can expand their
margins they can you know hire the help
they need they can live a comfortable
life like they should you know so
instead of The Growers being squeezed
now like we're really putting the power
back to the cultivator the industry's
been very rough on cultivators in
general you know our margins have
compressed a lot where yeah everybody
else has kind of maintained some kind of
margin but cultivators have been
absolutely demolished just getting
killed yeah and it's it's unfortunate
we're going back to We Are Farmers now
and same thing with farmers of lettuce
and tomatoes and it's it's all the same
thing we all get treated the same and
you know I think using the platform and
and using the tool the under canopy tool
it really is going to bring back a lot
of power to the cultivators well so when
you talk about quality what do you
attribute that to you attribute to the
Spectrum uh well I'm sure there's many
factors yeah quality you know I think in
and spectrum is a big one and that you
want to talk about difference in
genetics there man you know some you
know crazy crazy Varian is some plant
perform better under HPS and some
perform better under CMH and some Led
You Know It's Just it's all over the
place yeah so we so we kind of
approached that um because you know HPS
and LEDs are completely different light
sources so we did not want to treat them
the same um and HPS very high in red
orange yellow right um very easy to kind
of strip that plant of the excess
nitrogen that's kind of built up in it
it's easier at least for me I know other
people have
other uh instances but you know it's
it's easier for me to pull color
underneath an HPS bulb and most likely
that has to do with being able to strip
that nitrogen out yeah so when we went
to design the Spectrum to fit underneath
a you know an HPS top light I really
pulled back on my days of mixing metal
halides and HPS up top checkerboarding
those rooms and how turpy and how just
yeah how exceptional that weed was right
because you just got a full spectrum
there for your plan it's absorbing just
about everything is fully represented in
a in a mixed Spectrum so what we did is
is we really looked at bringing in some
full spectrum diodes but we wanted to
make sure that we still took care of the
farther red right so we've got a nice
balance of a little more white light and
definitely some farther red some 660
some 680 make sure we're getting that
pull out of the plant make sure we're
there on the color side of things right
conversely with the toplight LEDs
um I'm not a huge fan of how lacking in
red most of the toplight LEDs are you
know most they really really
underperform in the Red Spectrum and you
know if you look at a a regular chart
that a lighting company puts out it
looks like it has plenty of red but it
once you put it on your plants you can
just tell right it's just kind of
lacking right and white spectrum is
always going to deliver a massive yield
like we I think we've established that
like the wider your spectrum the more
full your spectrum you're really really
going to you're going to see a massive
yield and that's great we all need yield
so what we did was we kind of took that
lack of red and just reversed it right
we put full red um almost full red um
into our our Spectrum that's slated to
go underneath the LED uh top lights and
cultivators will call me like week seven
and they're like dude my lowers are
purple my tops are purple like they're
already on their way I usually don't get
this for another 10 days like and and
you can just tell that they're not only
excited they're relieved because they
can they know this product is going to
meet the demand that the consumers are
asking for and they're going to have the
extra yield too like they're going to
have the extra yield but but the whole
plant and all of that product is better
yeah top to bottom you know so we take a
lot of pride in the Spectrum balancing
that we introduced um I think it's
killer I love it um I get conversations
all the time when people want to know
the intricacies of it and I'll I'll geek
on them with forever dude how does your
light affect stretching depends on how
you irrigate yeah so if you and we're
actually um Co not coincidentally uh not
on purpose doing a side by side of one
gallons and two gallons with thunder
canopy on them yeah and you can really
tell that the plants in the two gallons
have a lot more resources a lot more
water availability so they can grow a
lot more right they can kind of put on
that extra size yeah um
and for everybody still growing in one
gallons because we still I do some
genetics in one gallons and some in two
gallons some just don't root in that
well right so in the the one gallons um
what we see is they won't stretch as
much right there's less resources
available to them and you can irrigate a
little differently yes and and you can
give them what they need yes but it all
depends in substrate size if you've got
a bigger substrate that plant's going to
keep going you know so um and then
something else kind of on that same vein
is I see a lot of people over irrigate a
lot I want to say over watering is
probably the number
one issue that a lot of cultivators have
um especially novice cultivators right
it's easy to just give your plants water
you know every morning cuz the book says
too you know and what underc canopy does
is it actually helps them dry out a
little better so people will call me all
the time and they're like this is the
best room I've had top to bottom top
Cola bottoms everything and our charts
are better and I'm like oh okay yeah and
in my head I'm like okay you probably
were oversaturating just a touch you
know a lot of rock Woolf slab guys that
are like oh my goodness like this is
crazy you know like Coco kind of kind of
dialed in but rockwool slabs or uh Hugo
guys yeah I get that all the time and
it's I'd say it's about seven out of 10
times when I get that call it's the rock
wool right 50% increases
yields exactly why it's kind of relative
but we can talk talk about GRS per
square foot or pounds per light whatever
whatever anybody wants to talk about you
know so that everybody understands
exactly what we're talk we're not saying
we gave you know this guy got 100% yield
because he was at one pound of light
like we're not I'm not here to sure to
fudge the numbers I'm I'm really not no
I think that's great I think the
product's great I appreciate it what do
you
attribute going from two pounds to four
pounds of light and then actually two
pounds to three pounds yeah and then
three lounds to now potentially touching
four maybe a little over four oh yeah
what do you think the big change was
originally you think that basically
monitoring dryback uh basically crop
steering I think crop steering is the
the easier answer right it's definitely
crop steering but it's just you know
crop steering has been around for
decades in big a and it's and it's very
much just finding its way into cannabis
and we're I think we're finding the
boundaries of that very quickly right um
and obviously genetic to genetic is
different but when you're talking about
a genetic I'd say most genetics on a
medium run are about 2 and a half pounds
of light yeah you know a medium good run
where cultivators are happy there wer
weren't too many issues you're two and a
half right on a 4x4 yeah and without
under canopy steering and understanding
when to send those triggers to the plant
is very important and that's how you
kind of start breaching the consistency
of two and a half and into the threes
right genetic to
genetic with under canopy you're adding
light to your room well you're going to
have a little bit more yield that's I
mean light and yield are linear you know
this isn't that it's not so much rocket
sciencey there right it's what you do
with that extra yield that was really
tricky um if you're adding you know 140
watts to faven bars per 4x4 to a 4x4
that had a th000 watt HPS above it well
that's about 25%
extra light you're adding right there
well there's your 25% yield yeah okay so
there's your 25% yield I'm not saying
it's guaranteed but it's a pretty easy
equation to get
there on top of that now how do we get
past 25% well now we're looking at where
that light is that light is is is just
actioning a previously underutilized
area of your plant the bottom third of
your plant that bottom third of your
plant is good for
genetic to genetic but that that's good
for a yield increase and then really
where under canopy shines is when you
can and this is the the overarching goal
of underc canopy in general is getting
the perfect mix of top and bottom light
in the center of your plant because the
center of your plant holds the highest
yield potential by far you know there's
so many nodes going on in there and so
many so much potential there that it
usually just gets overshadowed because
you deaf yes but it's hard to you know
HPS drops off real fast you know it's
not it's pretty common for me to walk
into a facility I'll do a walk through
and talk about faving with them and I'll
put a par meter in there and it's 250
yeah and I'm like man you can clone at
250 you know like your plants need more
if you expect them to do better so so
you know it it really comes down to
where the light is um and how well you
manage that light and the mix of the top
and bottom light I that's your those are
the two big keys so now things like
thinning when you're using an underc
canopy light how do you thin your
recommend thinning topping thinning
stuff like that are there tips and
tricks oh yes
and before I forget I want to make sure
we have a ton of resources on our
Instagram and our YouTube like we're
putting out as much educational content
as we can around this yeah just because
it is um it's scary for a cultivator to
kind of dip their toes into this and you
know a lot of us are are run run right
now we can't have a bad run you know
can't afford to so we want to make sure
that that Growers feel very comfortable
and they have a verse a very good first-
time experience with faven yeah um and
so when it comes to
pruning please stop under
clearing people still get our lights and
they still under clear stripping them
stop it stripping them please at least
the first run don't touch it please
please please just watch watch and see
and I guarantee you will not have a bad
run because of it so so reduce under
clearing stop under clearing but
reducing under clearing really is
allowing for all those node sites
underneath there to become something
things that we usually would throw away
are now going to be extra yield and
they're going to be mature and they're
going to be cracked out and they're
going to fit in your bag just like top
all the way all the way down to the soil
or so whatever substrate so and to be
specific good thanks for bringing that
up to be specific if you've got your
lights you know flush with your pot um
we like to say put the put the
favin the base of the faven flush with
the top of the container rock wool one
gallon
whatever that way you know for sure that
you're not blasting your substrate with
light because that's a waste we don't
want to do that um and then I have a
couple people who are like you know I
grow you know four to five foot plants
so I'm actually going to raise these up
a little higher and so if you raise them
up a little higher than that then go
ahead and under clear underneath where
that light isn't you know making it
that's you know again it's a lot common
sensey stuff that we've been doing right
you know um Common Sense isn't so common
I know I know well it's a common thing
that Growers do but yes yes but that's
why we put out all the resources because
I was like oh this is a no-brainer
because I've been using it for four
years right I kind of forget how scary
it is to like introduce a new technology
like this right it as a grower you're
like yeah I'm not ready for that I've
got a lot on my plate right so we're
just trying to make it very easy and
approachable so reducing under clearing
which also reduces labor we can talk
about Labor savings later but reducing
that labor is really nice strategic de
Leaf right and really again making sure
you're getting upward mobility of that
light is key so usually I tell people
days three to five do a light light de
Leaf remove any of the little the little
sucker nodes at the bottom maybe there's
a weird one that kind of made it through
the cloning process and it's kind of
coming out of the soil like go ahead and
take that guy off too you know right
remove all the ones that aren't going to
be anything but leave the majority of
everything on on that day 3 to 5 little
light under Clear DE Leaf MH go back in
day between depends on who you talk to
18 to 25 there's a week there where
people like to get in there or they
don't day 21 yeah yeah it's the day 21
couple guys are like nah we don't touch
till 25 and some are like no we don't
care we're in there at day 14 you know
it just totally whatever you do yeah
totally and so you're really just going
in there pulling any of the huge fan
leaves that are really impeding the
upward mobility of the light you're
really just trying to keep it open in
there and make sure there's decent airf
flow right we just don't want it to be a
jungle underneath there um and so you
know you're really looking to do that
and then once you get to that point once
you get to day 25 end of week four call
it let just talk day 28 you kind of know
what's going to develop into a good butt
and what isn't you know you can kind of
see it because the hairs are maturing
and the butt is maturing at the same
same rate as the top they've been the
lights have been on for 28 days top and
bottom yeah you know so from there I
kind of let Growers take over and do
their own not let I don't let them I'm
like hey whatever your sop is you can
kind of continue from there you know and
I like to do a touchup around day 40 and
then a heavy strip for the last two
weeks we still do that I think it's a
great approach um but something that
comes up a lot when you're not under
clearing anymore is there's a lot of
congestion underneath in your under
canopy right mhm so what we I'm not
saying you have to do this again if
especially if you're on your first bench
of under canopy you're just trialing it
you don't have to do this but reducing
plant count is one of the biggest
benefits you can do to really prioritize
air flow in your under canopy and one of
the biggest benefits for yield increase
yeah like dropping plant count and
letting every plant really optimize
itself is is probably the biggest
takeaway we had from the first run at
Connected was just like we slam going
from like 16 to 9 going 16 to 12 going
yeah if you're four if your floor plants
wide you need to think about three
plants wide yeah you know even on a five
by bench it's just try it just try it if
you're on a four wide four foot wide
bench and you've got four plants wide
you definitely need to try just three
plants wide but yeah I like that nine
number 12 sometimes depending got some
biscotti sherb that doesn't like that
doesn't rage you know so that's a little
higher plant count man I love me some
Skittles Skittles with underc canopy
we'll tangent this is Skittles is so
much better of a plant with underc
canopy I bet it is just it is meant for
it it's lateral its branches are all
like this we talk about it a lot on this
show but yeah it's a struggler it's it's
but you see it with under canopy and
you're like oh my God this makes so much
sense just because it's built for it and
the nugs are already so light and lury
you know Smalls from Skittles is just
lar it's nothing it is it is and yeah
but you put some light underneath there
and tighten them up and Skittles is
commercially viable again yeah I get
some sticky Skittles nugs yeah yep oh
yeah and I bet you can get a little bit
of color in there too man oh just a
little bit but nobody wants any color
don't you don't you give me Skittles
with color people want color on
everything n if you if it's real
Skittles and it has a hint of color it's
good oh it's good yeah hint yeah but all
the um all the propery from proper
doinks yeah all that stuff's faving
ground all that you know those guys
those guys R they roll killer oh God
yeah yeah yeah oh yeah I know those guys
those guys are they're killing it they
think they love they I'll get a I'll get
a text from from Paul or a DM from Paul
a couple times a month and it'll just be
like I love faven bro I love the
Skittles he's yeah we're trying to get
them on the show next oh Adam and Paul
come on man get over here it's a quick
it's a quick little Drive yeah yeah but
yeah there's you know pruning
is pruning is so different cultivator to
cultivator and we we try to put out Sops
that are very
loose and malleable I guess you could
say grower to grower but you know what
we put out the content we put out we're
very comfortable with like hey if you
follow these steps within these steps
you will have success your first run
after your first run then start to tweak
it to your own right you know and I talk
to guys call me all the time and they're
like hey I'm going to try this and I'm
like go for it you just have to let me
know how it works like that's the deal
is you just have to let me know you know
cuz now I'm interested yeah um so and
and that's the thing but
really limit your under clearing like
all that is usable product you will be
shocked like g41 I got a um we've got
some double Stacks Amplified Farms has
uh they were help they helped us do our
double stack trials and uh we put g41 on
the top top level and I was like H you
know I I don't know how g41 is going to
do but this will be a good trial and oh
my goodness week five you were kind of
in there like that doesn't look like
much gosh I just um the fir by by week
eight you were like oh my God those are
golf balls you know it just it just set
on so late chunked out yeah and because
g41 is one of those where it doesn't
have the Super Active hairs yeah that
that like the bud grows into they're
those kind of squirmy hairs that stay
inside the bud but it just like kind of
swells together I don't know you know
but it doesn't look like much and then
oh my goodness I actually just left
there yesterday and they have g41 in the
same spot on the top deck and I was like
man I was kind of worried about this run
and head grower Zippy was like dude you
always worry about these runs and I'm
like yeah I know I know but they always
come through you know so the nested
bracks yes there you go nested we talked
about this the first time I was over
yeah
yeah good stuff yeah very much so but
yeah it's it's a whole new world it does
doesn't change your workflow too much
but I mean I have 700 life facilities in
Sacramento that have fully dropped their
third party labor because they don't
need them anymore there's no more under
clear weeks you know hey it costs a lot
of money it's labor is not cheap anymore
labor especially in
California finding good labor is the
hardest thing is oh my goodness but but
labor is also one of your biggest cogs
and you cannot get around it so anything
to lower even 10% labor in
taxes Damn Damn You California your
Silent Partner the
government but um but yeah man it's um
you know we're really just scratching
the surface we're really just and we
have a ton of things that we're
monitoring and watching and really
trying to put out some good content and
good resources you know nice it's so you
have a Spectra we have one light for HPS
and you have one light for Led yeah
really cool yeah just because they're
different light sources you know and
yeah no I think it's great you can put
light in either room you can put
Spectrum in either room but we really
did that to balance out quality so my
big uh interest with your lights is
going to be the seed production room so
we're going to do seed production we're
monitoring what you get with the faven
and what you get without and I really
like I'm I'm looking forward to seeing
bigger yields in seeds and I'm already
getting close to 50,000 seeds per light
and so if we can break that 50,000
threshold per light that's with auto
flowers but still that's still that's
that's great and if we can break that
50,000 seed threshold it's amazing I'm
super excited about that I'm and and
breeding was something that the uh you
know 20-year-old me when I got into
cannabis was like how how long does it
take to bring a genetic to Market two
years like no I don't have time for that
like you know a 60-day harvest is is too
long for me to wait anyway a minimum a
year to get something to marrow gosh man
and you're and and the Funky breeders
out there just kind of throwing seeds
around and packs around like not vetted
and stuff right like we're talking about
fully vetted genetics that have been
runed genetics yeah I mean there's a lot
of there's a lot of bad players in the
game these days but you know it it never
was interesting to me I just loved
growing yeah and so I never got into it
but you know you and a couple other
people have really kind of shined the
light on what seed production can be
with underc canopy and and your issue
being immature seeds lower yeah same
thing that you know Ro guys deal with
immature tricomes totally it's the same
idea well now you've become a solution
to a problem and that's
amazing inadvertently I was just trying
to put out a good product for Growers
and then people got it in their hands
and they were like hey you can do this
this and this with it and I think that's
the just the coolest part you know
that's the coolest part to me totally
yeah well so let's dive back into a
little bit of your history you know when
did you first start enjoying the plant I
wasn't a big smoker growing up
um I was the oldest of three boys kind
of a single mom situation and so I was
kind of setting the tone you know and I
um early on my grandpa kind of sat me
down and was like hey you're the man of
the house you need to kind of act like
it you know kind of thing like you know
so always kind of had to stay away from
that and set a good example um and then
I was soon as I could I was working you
know and um I play 16 18 15 and a half
you know as soon as I could soon as it
was
my first job when I was 12 working for
my parents yeah there you go there you
go you know and um and know I played
Sports I played soccer growing up I ran
track in high school you know I was
always doing stuff and so like you know
canvas was everywhere it's Kali and high
school and whatever you know literally
it's everywhere is everywhere but it
just like you know I think I hit a joint
at a party my junior year and like I
don't know I hit the joint I passed it
back and they were like you know people
were like oh Tim smoked you know but it
didn't do anything you know right um but
you know I didn't really get into it
until I think senior year I got high
after watching Harold and Kumar of
course you know after though people
think that's funny that I got high after
watching it it just seemed like so much
fun I was like I hit my buddy up and I
was like you know let's go right and um
so when I left High School um I went up
to Chico um and all my roommates there
smoked and it was like you might as well
and I think the second day I was in
Chico one of the like this local like
kind of homeless SE guy whatever that
hung around the apartment complex
brought us a hash ball that was like
this almost the size of a tennis ball
and I had no idea what it was and then
he pulled out like a 20 gram nug like
outdoor nug like a banana nug you know
what I mean like would not fly these
days but some huge banana nug you know
big deal back then big yeah yeah big
colas was a thing you know so it it was
pretty quick after getting to college I
I started you know consuming but did
Chico for a year um money kind of ran
out it was tough so I I came home for a
year um still doing the college thing
real JC kind of didn't know what I was
doing just I was working at aumi that
was fun you know like and that's
cannabis culture right there like Zoomer
zoomi skateboarding cannabis like it's
all you know and I've been snowboarding
for like 25 years so like snowboarding
you know big Roots there so everything I
was associated with was Cannabis esque
you know right um but but really um
after that second year or that that year
coming home my really good friend at the
time was dating a girl in San Diego and
he was like hey dude I'm moving to San
Diego like I'm out of here you know and
I grew up Solano cish you know kind of
bay like just outside the Bay Area just
right outside yeah yeah not Bay Area
just to be clear but a lot of bay
influence almost almost in the bay
almost yeah the bay stops at Bart as we
used to say there's no Bart in
Fairfield but um and it's windy out
there really really God it's so windy oh
God Cordelia is the worst man yeah but
uh but yeah he was like dude I'm moving
to San Diego I'm going down here and I
was like well I'm not staying here dude
like I'm coming with you and then by the
end of it we had four guys moving down
with us you know like by the time moving
day came like there was another you know
there was a couple guys so um we got
down there we all worked jobs we all
went to college tried to do our best and
man it was so expensive down there that
we really were not making it like we
were working full-time jobs everything
and we just weren't making it wow and uh
probably about 3 months in we had it was
a two-bedroom apartment we had two guys
in each bedroom our freaking mattresses
basically touched you know what I mean
like it was like you we were good homies
by by the end of that year we had two
guys in each bedroom one guy on the
couch and then we had another guy move
down and sleep on the couch and this guy
moved down and he kind of saw the
situation and he had always kind of side
hustled in high school a little bit or
after high school I think and he was
like Hey you know there's a there's like
a big price difference between you know
the Bay Area packs and and down here in
San Diego we're like no we don't we
don't know man you know so um pretty
quickly he had a good plug and um we
were up in San Francisco scoring units
and then we got introduced to vending we
got introduced to vending and we started
hitting the clubs and at that time it
was like
2011 want to say yeah and there
was 7 800 clubs between San Diego and la
oh I bet I me it well I mean I Wild West
dude we sold a little bit here and there
while we were on Camp we were actually
living on the San Diego State campus but
we weren't going to San Diego State it
was blast and uh it's probably why we
were broke um but you know uh somebody
turned us on a vending and you know we
had we had good purple from the bay and
good OG from the bay GDP cookies oh yeah
we didn't have any cookies yet um not
yet that you know what cookies was so
elusive for me it took me forever to get
my hands on one the cut yeah and two
just packs of it like good legit packs
of it but you know um you know we
developed a good reputation because we
would show up on time you know the club
bu the buyers would be like hey be here
at 10: a.m. on Tuesday with all you got
and we would show up at 10 a.m. on
Tuesday like there was no pot grower
time for us yeah yet like that that came
but you know we were you know it was
crazy to us that you know we were making
maybe 1,500 bucks you know each a month
working our full-time jobs and we can
move a few packs and and pretty much
scrape that up in a in in a couple days
you know so to us it was just like oh my
gosh like we can live and we can like
not that we had the business mindset
like we can scale this but like we can
do more you know yeah and so
kind of a weird chain of events um we
actually got introduced to the guy who
owns ingred I don't know if you remember
ingred it was a trademark strain still
is a trademark I remember the strain for
sure yes and held a ton of medicinal
value still does that's that stuff will
still take my headache away in five
minutes I love that genetic I don't even
know where I'd find it these days I can
put you in touch with the right guy
that's for sure um still in the meno
Coast in the heart of of Fort Brag
medino nice and you know put us in touch
with um with you know the head guy who
basically feno hunted ingred and kind of
turned it in he trademarked it he turned
it into a whole thing and so once we got
ingred on the menu all the clubs wanted
us like we had Holistic Cafe we had
green door right we had the these really
big clients within like two or three
months of starting to vend like we had
legitimate clients that were like hey if
you don't show up with what you say like
we're going to be we're gonna be mad
we're not going to buy from you again
you know so right so we started um there
was like four of us and there was two of
us would run you know run up and grab
units and two of us would Hustle the
clubs and collect money and distribute
do whatever we needed to uh you know
under the guys of 215 all 215 legit
and so we did that and and once we had
ingred on the menu we really exploded
you know ingred once we had that that
gave us all the Bubba that was coming
out of the Coast all the You2 that was
coming out of the coast all the Cherry
AK that was coming out of the coast
man lip smacking like you can't say
Cherry AK without just salivating a
little yeah you know so it really
legitimized us and we didn't know what
we were doing at the time but looking
back on it that was a really big
inflection point and so we did that for
a while with them and then um couple
months and then they started offering to
like teach us how to grow and you know
we're talking going to learn on the
mesino coast like it was wow we were
like indoor or indoor wow so we learned
indoor first and homes that were blown
up from the kitchen to the bathroom bro
like every square foot you know clones
in the bathroom totally moms in the in
the kitchen you know everything else was
flour and uh parabolic hoods and and
rolling you know everything with tomato
cages and on rolling uh rolling trays or
uh little plant trays saucers yeah we we
learned up there for a couple months man
and um you know just just like
everything and and I think early
cannabis Partnerships were rough
and um not with the angry guy just just
the other people we were growing with
and so pretty quickly we were like okay
we need to Branch off on our own and and
figure this out and so we kind of got
the growing basics down a little bit we
were actually growing veganic um we
learned veganic first which was wild
like Kyle kushman veganic like yeah like
I learned from a direct friend of
kushman in 2011 badass pretty cool yeah
I didn't know what it meant at the time
but looking back on I'm like that's
pretty badass yeah yeah so yeah we
actually ended up uh building an indoor
in elderado County um we found a killer
uh house just and this is a this is like
2011 end 2010 2011 and houses were cheap
you know this is after the housing
market and we're in you know the boonies
of Eldorado County they're like please
just rent the house from us please like
take it you know in 30 lights yeah and
you know we actually we walked into this
place and there was it was a 4,000 foot
house alog together with like if you
total up the garage and then you open
this little side door and there was a
basement built into a side of a hill wow
it was 1,200 square feet almost 12200
square feet probably we ended up with
probably a th000 square foot of
cultivation space two rooms 20s
something lights nice four guys in a
house killing it yeah you know just
living the dream like literally living
the dream 30 minutes from Sarah Tahoe
you know like we went you know all
winter we snowboard anyway I'm getting a
little ahead of myself but but that was
like our first our first grow and we
ended up actually we took that down in
2019 that ran for eight years wow I know
like that's great though lowkey yeah and
yeah man we you know everything was
great and then I think it I think it was
the end of 2011 or mid 2011 the feds
came in to LA and San Diego and ruined
the party almost in like a week it
seemed overnight and so we were kids we
were oh want a pound here you go you
want a couple pounds here you go they'll
pay us they need more of our stuff you
know they need us and you know we took a
really big loss because I
knew James at whatever Collective on the
corner of wherever you know and that
place disappeared and so did James you
know and maybe he got seized but like we
never heard from these people again he
owed you money of course yeah know they
had Consignment they had and but it was
the it was a good lesson it was the big
first L and Consignment kills people
though like that's still to this day
look what's going on now kill business
yeah I mean it's rough it's rough and
you know the whole term game that's
going on now in 2024 is ridiculous it's
just absolutely ridiculous I mean I've
gone through it with seeds too just
lesson after lesson I think I've learned
my lesson but you just never know you
never know you hope you do but yeah
there's people that still owe me
hundreds of thousands of seeds or money
for those seeds yeah and uh yeah and
then I I have another friend who just
sent me after two years finally sent me
my seeds back after hassling him for two
years oh my goodness so not getting paid
but at least I got my seeds back you got
your seeds back I
guess maybe maybe have you popped them
well yeah we're doing germ tests right
now on actually so we'll see they do
feel a little
light but yeah you know it was it was
good but that was like our Turning Point
from really understanding that we really
wanted to be in the grower the grower
position and
honestly growing was something that like
young Tim like 20 year-old 21y old Tim
like really needed like I needed
something to put like just to throw
myself at and well it's something so
regimen that you have to water them when
they need water yeah you have to harvest
when you have to harvest there's a lot
of discipline required to grow good
flower like at the end of the day
there's a lot of discipline involved you
know some some of these guys that you
see out there they might be lazy in
other aspects of their life but if they
got fire it's because they had a lot of
discipline and they did things right so
it's not the plant doesn't grow itself
yeah no it really doesn't yeah it's a
weed it'll grow but but if you want good
stuff especially now yeah I mean it's
tough yeah but it was it was good
because I needed to I needed something
to kind of pour myself into and and you
know the difference
between you know taking the risk to grow
cannabis and like working at working
retail was you know you could kill it
and an 8 hour shift at retail maybe get
an hour of overtime in and feel good but
you could
spend that same amount of time in your
grow room and your plants are
exponentially better especially back
then when you're handw watering and
you're really paying attention to each
PL you're going in right it's not it's
way less of a production right you get
that LoveHate relationship with the
handw yeah I still you know I still
start him off with a handw waterer
though I still handw waterer my outdoor
plants my back
okay I still enjoy waking up in the
morning you know and hitting them
checking the plants out I feel like it
gets me right in the head yeah more
therapy than uh yeah that's cool that's
really cool I'll have to take you I'll
have to do that I can't do anything in
the backyard I got a two-year-old right
now and he's curious about everything so
he end up eating the damn thing or
pulling branches whatever oh dude he
pulls all my wild flowers I have I have
pollinator Garden in my front yard and
they're starting to kind of pop up here
and there a couple couple poppies are
going right now and he's just like Dad
flower and just ripping I'm like dude
it's fine you're two you're two it's
fine but but anyway yeah it's you know
it it it was really really cool that you
know we had the opportunity to learn
from who we learned from and you know
find our own path in it because after
that we really became Growers like we
always had Outlets because that's you
know you had to have a secure Outlet
back then and cuz you couldn't just roll
up to the grow and fill up your your
Yukon with packs like you had to know
somebody who knew somebody it was much
more of a Growers Market back then oh
man it was so ni and yeah it was great
it was great there wasn't as many you
know there was people that brokered
there was people that grow that were
Growers there were buyers and people
kind of did one thing and now some some
of them they they want to do everything
yeah yeah they're a single vertically
integrated human well and and you know
back in the traditional Market we you
did have to wear a lot of hats a lot of
times you were doing your own extraction
yeah you doing your own extraction you
doing your own construction you were
doing you know you had stuff break you
couldn't have a AC guy come over CU he
you know that wasn't that wasn't in the
cards typically right so not unless you
had a guy which we had a guy but not
everybody had a guy not everybody had a
guy I had a I had a guy which was oh my
gosh the best yeah oh man he was a great
electrician who knew just about
everything it was awesome but it's
always good oh it was so nice but um but
you know it it it was great man I I
I really like developed such a love for
the plant and really I think the the
lifestyle it afforded was so cool too I
mean we just chased snow all winter yeah
you know we I think the year after we
built that indoor we got outdoor
capabilities in Willets great growing
climbing in Willets good place to grow
just cool enough at night real real hot
during the day but just cool enough
during the night to really pull some
tpin man just they've been growing fire
out of there for years long time long
before me yeah but uh we we rolled the
dice big man you know we were um we got
a property it had a we called it the
plywood Palace it was a three-story
plywood building that had indoor
capabilities nice which it was not
insulated it had nothing in it so we
outfitted it that was when the uh the
trip XXL Raptor hoods were big oh yeah
so yeah so we were we were putting those
up the the ballast that were like 80 lbs
like those things would rip your
freaking arm out of your socket if you
grabbed it the wrong way you know like
those I think they were the Miami
ballast I don't even know why they were
in Miami but someone needs to have a
light museum for all the old stuff I
would go D I would totally go too I mean
that's a great idea how cool would that
be that would be that would be awesome
see some a a collective effort from all
of the companies because everybody's had
their you know contributions and I feel
like everybody has their place that's
created so funny you say that that's a
great idea I mean I love the adjust
wings I did the oh I know the a wings
were killer yeah and then there was like
the air cooled lights we had the first
it was like the 4 in and then it like
the upgrade was the 6 in air cool bites
and we had cool tubes I mean there was
so many things back in the day that do
not see anymore it's and good cuz gosh
man the fungus knats that would get in
those
freaking the fungus knats that would
crawl up there and die by the Thousand
dude and like yeah oh God getting in
there and cleaning in between runs cuz
you're like if I don't clean that that
that freaking glass that's probably
chock with lead yeah like Ser I'm going
to get no yield you know so it was
that's a great idea the the museum the
that would be awesome Noy B so people
get experience oh my gosh yeah full full
immersion you get the experience where
yeah plants are being grown with all the
old equipment I mean how cool would that
be he whip out your cell phone and it's
the freaking zebra stripes again cuz the
magnets are jacking your camera up
remember that yeah that was those were
good times though man that's why we
don't have any pictures of this [ __ ] cuz
you couldn't take a picture in those
rooms with the ballast our adjustable
Spectrum we have the science adjustable
spectrum and uh those Dragon Alphas you
you get the zebra vertical really yeah
yeah vertical vertical so you get the
vertical oh interesting I'll have to
I'll have to I have to check that check
it out have to go check it out but um
but yeah uh you know we so we went ham
and Willets and um we put out you know
99 circles we did our thing and you know
had to go up this crazy switch back you
know to get up to the top of the plywood
Palace and so we were I mean we were we
were roughing it and there was about six
of us just boat
strapping yeah just doing whatever we
could you know we didn't have irrigation
we didn't know how to irrigate 99 you
know 300 gallon pots like so we were we
were carrying five gallon buckets back
and forth every day watering those
things you know we all had we all had
traps up to our ears you know we were
just yoked from you know chest up you
know but you know we did what we had to
do and we had the indoor and and um ELO
going and you know we kept it going we
turned on the indoor for a couple weeks
we had a
70 kilowatt whisper W generator didn't
know what we were doing with a generator
of course you had to have a g generator
mechanic and do refills and we were just
a bunch of kids we had no idea so we
spent I don't even know how many tens of
thousands of dollars to build out an
indoor inside and then it became very
unfeasible for us to do it um so we
turned our focus on outdoor to kind of
recuperate all of what we had thrown in
and uh August uh fed showed up and cut
us down oh [ __ ] yep and they went in and
their favorite thing to do is go into
your equipment and cut all the cords you
know oh they cut they cut all the cords
they cut it you know they did the whole
n they field day oh they love it but you
know what crazy is we really do believe
to this day they let us leave and then
went and cut everything down because
back then they got paid by how many
plants they cut down and not matter how
many arrests they made they didn't care
about arresting you they just wanted to
cut it down that was the cool part about
the Cali like traditional Market is like
unless you were messed around with BHO
like they probably weren't arresting you
you know unless you were transporting
hundreds of pounds like they probably
weren't arresting you you know yeah just
especially up there I mean the thing is
the community revolved around cannabis
so if you had a kid in school other
parents parents were involved with
cannabis it touched everybody right
especially you know the Emerald
Triangle everyone's livelihood revolved
around it so if you owned a shop you
know people that were buying stuff from
your shop were involved in cannabis so
it normalized it way way earlier than it
did all around the rest of the United
States because it's fairly normalized
right I feel like we're good overall you
know over 50% of the people like
cannabis but yeah you know I mean over
50% of people don't like you know
whatever peanut butter yeah you know I
mean so what not peanut is not a good
example but there's so many tomato
tomatoes are 50/50 with people man I
swear I love them give me some heirlooms
please so I think we're doing really
good and I think we made a lot of
progress yeah we definitely have and
it's nice to see I think I saw a
statistic the other day that was like
based on like population like if you
just look at population and urban
centers like more than 90% of the United
States population wise has has access to
Legal cannabis yeah you know and I think
it's like almost 40 States now are you
know Med or wreck right it's it's coming
like you know but but yeah you're right
it it was so regular up there and you
know we still nobody could be like now I
feel like you could walk down the street
with a plant in your hand and like
people would be like cool bro like what
are you doing yeah you couldn't do that
back then but like you know it was it
was just regular day you know and um you
know we got when we got hit it was it
was pretty gnarly and uh it freaked us
out a lot you know we were kids we
thought law enforcement had their stuff
together a little more than law
enforcement probably did you know so we
thought they were kind of on to us you
know right and uh a couple of the a
couple of the guys went and like kind of
hit
out um we have a cool campsite to this
day that's still pretty remote um those
are the Eldorado County you know and
yeah real real sneaky spot or you can
get back into town in about 25 minutes
get your supplies and get back up the
hill you know so real real good SP
and uh almost simultaneously our spot
that we were kind of we were still you
know we were still working the San Diego
La Market almost simultaneously that got
hit so it really put us on high alert it
was a complete coincidence but y you
know the day it happened we were like oh
my God we're tapped you know like you
know you just your mind starts going but
um couple of us stayed up there hit our
clone guy on the coast and replanted
through Days Later wow yeah and back in
the day you know it was you know it was
early August so we kind of babied him we
hardened him off to the sun made sure
everything was fine but you know we
replanted everything that this guy
didn't need for a clone order you know
we we we drove I don't know how many
trips back and forth from the coast you
know to Willets on the sketchy ass 20
and put everything in the ground and we
pretty much broke even for the year yeah
you know monetary wise which was just
insane can't do that now better than
losing oh yeah it's better than losing
and a lot of lessons dude there was a
lot of lessons that it didn't cost too
much right so a lot of Sweat Equity but
we're 22 man we didn't care like swe was
was all we had nobody died nobody went
to jail and you broke even I mean those
are life got a freaking a ride up man
like we didn't even get a ticket you
know like we didn't get anything so we
we felt pretty lucky but yeah but that
kind of closed the chapter on the group
that we had kind of assembled all the
guys that were with us like there were
six or seven Us by that time and we had
our hopes on really hitting it big and
getting more properties for people and
and keep expanding like we had all these
Grand you know I was going to buy this
truck and you know like fit in with the
broozers going around meno you know but
it really was kind of the it was the end
of that era for us and it's it it's
really great to look back on those few
years because it was so raw and it was
really a family yeah you know it was
your family is what who we who we did
everything with and um you know you lose
together and you win together you break
bread together like it's a it's a bond
that never can be really broken and
those are the best kind of relationships
they're awesome and you know a couple
guys were like yeah cannabis isn't for
me I was doing it because I was hoping
to you know fund my whatever whatever
and and go do this you know and some of
us were like oh no I love the plant like
I'm in this so we kind of broke up found
our own ways and ended up back in El
Dorado and um I ended up getting some
outdoor capabilities in El Dorado the
next summer with like $2,000 to my name
dude like if I had an indoor run that
was like if I don't hit this I have no
money to run outdoor so I need to get
into this spot and my my buddies will
tell you to this day like they didn't
see me for like six to eight months
because I couldn't leave the I had no
money yeah like I could go to the
grocery store and back to the grow like
that was it you know and that's what it
took to be able to have the money to run
outdoor the next season and then once
you know successful outdoor season then
you were good and you could you know
parlay it into the next season but right
but yeah did that for a while man and
chased snow all winter and grew all
summer and it was a killer life somebody
showed me how to pull tarps in like 2013
started depping and Game Changer there
just you know getting two three runs a
year of sfv yeah didn't have to leave
the property people came to me you know
running we were running 400 gon
pots uh 99 of them on a hillside bunch
of little dep houses I mean it was it
was a dream you know 20 acres was a
dream dude yeah and the outdoor was
going for more than the indoors now
pretty much man yeah what actually ended
up what what really not only getting
burnt out on legalization came you know
a couple years after like I had a few
good years legalization came things got
weird right yeah legalization was scary
it's been going up and down since like
2017 heavy 2017 somebody came in and
offered me like 1,200 bucks for my
freaking sfv or my sherb or something
and I was like this is ridiculous I'm
out of here you know like I'm not doing
this and so I actually started to um
kind of get my college credits back in
line and so I got my credits back in
line I actually went to Lake Tahoe
Junior College uh there in South Lake
and got everything back in line and by
2018 I was ready to kind of leave
cannabis I was really burnt out
legalization was weird people were legal
but still getting raided like it was
just such a confusing time so weird yeah
and I didn't have the attorney and yeah
I could have figured it out but you just
heard about the millions being poured in
and I was like well I don't have that
Canada coming into the US yeah you heard
just all the crazy stuff so I actually
just like I thought I had retired yeah
you know and I went back to school um
was lucky enough to get into UC Davis
and uh the College of a there and
started playing around with some pretty
cool stuff and that's actually where I
was introduced to LEDs yeah yeah so I
hated LEDs back in the day the purple
LED SPC it was always blurle man GH I
couldn't do it and and the guys every
every single guy that tried to sell me
on the purple LEDs they grew like [ __ ]
and so I'm like there's no way they were
also like 30 Watts like the ones you
dropped into the canopy yeah there was
like no intensity to them garbage yeah
totally and so Auto flowers back in the
day and the purple LEDs I I was like I
said I wrote those off for for the rest
of my life and it took a lot you know
same thing with Co Coco Coco is another
one cuz we had the blocks of Coco and we
had to break them up and I hated that so
I was like I'm never using Coco but now
I use coco I was prox till I die I use
everything I I like all the substrates
for different reasons you know for rock
rock wool's grape for certain things
same thing with Coco I mean I'm a huge
cocoa fan yeah I'm a but soil I love
soil too yeah I know same same and I
think the the right application right it
was cool man I you know I went back to
school the the craziest thing was was
like I didn't have Wi-Fi you know all
those years in the Hills growing so I
stepped into like middle of Davis and I
got these kids that are brilliant CU you
transfer into to Davis you don't have to
be as brilliant I'm G be straight up
with you you trans you come from high
school you're top of your class wow
different I was not top of my class in
high school not even close you know um I
only transferred in because they were
like hey like there's a guarantee from
South Lake JC to UC Davis wow like hey
sign up for this do all these things
boom boom boom and you're almost
guaranteed as long as you have a good
GPA and you meet the requirements and so
I it's called a tag I transferred in and
then I always try to make a point to say
it when I when I have a a public um
platform but I didn't pay to go back to
college if you're over the age of 24 or
25 and I think it's still going on uh
for a lot of the UC system if you're
over the age 24 25 you make a less than
a certain amount of money then it was
like $80,000 like if you make less than
$80,000 on paper they'll pay for your
education and so I actually didn't come
out of pocket at Dime like I had to live
in a very expensive city which is Davis
is very expensive yeah and all my food
and stuff like that and all my books and
stuff but I didn't pay for my education
Davis is a great school if you want to
learn about cannabis not just smoking
but but actually agriculture it's a
great AD school yeah and and what was
really cool is um I think my second
quarter there there was a zero net
energy like elective and it was a
master's elective so I was in there with
a bunch of Master's kids and I was
getting my undergrad my bachelor's
and there's these there's these things
called growth Chambers do you know what
growth Chambers are you ever heard of
these maybe maybe once I so just imagine
the size of a refrigerator yeah okay and
it's a grow room that fits inside of a
refrigerator yeah it's got temp control
humidity control lighting yeah so was
like once I once I explain so and
they're actually pretty expensive
they're like 40 Grand right so anyway
Davis obviously being the a research
school they are they have like 200 of
these below like one of the science
buildings and each one of these things
is rented by a professor who's doing
some kind of trial yeah and once they
trial there then they can take it to the
outdoor plots you know in wherever
there's you know Davis has acres and
acres and
ACR and so the school is looking at
still is trying to figure out how to get
to zero net energy right everybody's on
the carbon neutral path right now and
was in 2022 or 2020 as well
um and they were all using HID lights in
these little boxes right and these
little refrigerators they're just
blasting metal highlight or HPS or both
they had the Dual ended with different
with you know the the opposite bulb
those are cool right um so actually the
project I was on was retrofitting those
with LEDs oh wow and so it's so funny
that I got put in that class in that
program because I had all this knowledge
of like HID lighting right and so all
these kids with me who were Master's
kids really brilliant just brilliant
kids I was like running the show because
I'm like oh no we
need it like it was just so it's so
funny how it worked out um but yeah so
we actually had to you know figure it
out over like a couple months figure out
the the payback you know how long it's
going to take for the payback of like
you know Energy savings and um the cost
of the lights and which ones the gr
which ones the professors need and to to
make sure their research is
uninterrupted and yada Y and it was so
cool man and so we actually had a big
presentation for a lot of like higher
ups at UC Davis and this is me like six
months into going back to college like
you know just winging it but it was
really cool that was my first
introduction to LEDs and and dodes and
understanding um efficacy and just like
all the little things right and and
spectrum and you know and there was a
couple big players at the time but it
was still in his infant stages in you
know early 21 know so the adoption
adoption was on its way but it wasn't as
flushed out as it is now you know no not
even close not even close everybody was
still running blur yeah that a people
are going to go blind in HPS yeah yes
seriously but anyway now California HPS
are going to going away according to our
governor I we'll see I what's what's
your thought on that there's no way it
doesn't go away like it just has to I
just if I mean dude they're trying to
limit gas power generators around here
you know like those are worth they
waiting gold right now in California
like it's just ridiculous and I
understand the indoor like it's
extremely energy intensive right we
really should be growing in in green
houses right mix light it's the perfect
world yeah it is yeah and you can get an
amazing product I think people don't
agree sometimes because they don't know
yeah it's the lack of Education yeah
it's the lack of Education because that
is the perfect world growing green maybe
with supplemental Lighting in a
greenhous that is the the key because
you're getting the the natural light
from the sun save you a little money
lower your cogs exactly put some under
canopy oh man the greenhouse under
canopy is wild so
honestly my biggest interest with under
canopy when when I listen to you lecture
was the greenhouse application because I
feel like that's where so much product
gets wasted more than anywhere else is
the greenhouse that has the ly stuff
below and now if you can correct that
now you got a really amazing product
game changer for a lot of people you get
bigger yields you make more money and
everything everyone's struggling right
now so anything to increase that margin
for Growers so they can keep operating
and take care of their people you know I
kind of take people catch people off
guard when I say this but Greenhouse is
actually a better application for under
canopy than indoor yeah indoor is so
sufficiently lit that like yeah there's
potential yield potential like for sure
you know like just about everybody we
know first-time users fav in 25 to 35%
like I'll stand by that number it's it's
pretty much there right now when you're
talking
Greenhouse you're at the mercy of the
sun you're at the mercy of the weather
yeah you know you have some bad days you
know and and we talk winter runs a lot
of people shut it down for winter
because their par readings are 250 300
at canopy you can't you're not it's just
not worth it so we actually had a lot of
Trials over this past winter um
and the results are mind-boggling um
couple people were really close to 100%
increase compared to Winter runs prior
and that's awesome the quality was
everything went over a thousand yeah
went over for a thousand everything
because it had the Spectrum was there
right we were we were siding with our
more red spectrum because the sun's
going to give you the full spec so let's
side on what the plant benefits from
most well that's the you know the red
side of thing you know so we went with
that and really not only is the yield
increase just absolutely ridiculous
because you're dealing with such low DL
Li that the plants are actually
struggling but the proximity of the
lighting like we're we're delivering
Coast close canopy lighting yeah to
these plants where and and that's really
the struggle even even the mix light
facilities I mean you're hoping to get
to 600 right you know par canopy you're
hoping if you can push 700 750 and
you're greeny you're on but you know if
you can do 5 to 600 at top and you know
500 in the middle and
you know or higher than that in the
Middle with under canop but you can push
it in the middle there I mean sky is the
limit really yeah and you want to talk
about lowering planting densities that's
a big one right that's a huge like the
amount of plants that green houses deal
with like if you can lower your plant
count 10% yeah we're talking thousands
of plants you know yeah and so and the
workability around faven too right we at
277 you can run 20 of these in a daisy
chain you know so you can run full
benches on 277 volt all the way down and
deliver so much light to these plants
yeah um and Greenhouse is really really
where my heart is like I love indoor I
love how controlled it is and we're
still at the mercy of our hvx for sure
and dhomes for sure and irrigation
somebody unplugged the you know the pump
whatever but Greenhouse is really the
art right in the cultivation space it's
understanding your microclimate outside
your greeny and inside you're greeny
yeah and so to me guys like you know the
tur Mansion guys up in Humble just
killing it you know Dave Paulie
preferred Gardens like killing it
absolute Beast you know wish him well in
his new 40,000 sare foot project out
there and YOLO he's absolutely killing
it the guy's guy's awesome yeah but you
know it's such a tough go in green
houses right now because there isn't
that much of a difference in price
between outdoor and indoor is so cheap
that people a lot of times buyers will
just go get indoor because they can get
indoor for almost you know for a couple
points more you know it doesn't make
sense so that yield has to be there in
the Greenies so really like that
application of under canip liting greenh
houses is the absolute best in my
opinion yeah me too yeah it's just
ridiculous they're meant for each other
they are yes yes very much so but I'm
really looking forward we have a lot of
cool Partnerships coming up that and
people who have trials right now that I
I really want to to discuss yet but
you'll be seeing it very soon but people
are people are geeking on these things
in in in green houses man they're
they're having a lot of fun let's just
let's just say that really yeah it's a
it's a great application for it's just
perfect yeah doesn't matter how you grow
it too me you could be soil you could be
you know you could be organic doesn't
matter man you put them in the
greenhouse you're going to you're going
to see a much greater yield potential
increase than indoor because yeah yeah
you're going to get more resin
production oh yeah you're G to get botom
yeah so so many benefits so many yeah so
that's that's what I'm excited about
more than anything I mean yeah the seed
stuff all that stuff but like I really
see the across the industry that's where
I think there it's goingon to have the
most impact yeah agreed and should we
all be cultivating green houses yes y
yes we should not be growing indoors we
shouldn't be but you know I'll enjoy it
while it last you know I mean yeah it's
it's scale yeah I mean that's why they
have these 100 Acre green houses coming
online and stuff like that yeah yeah
well and if you go to like Holland and
look at like the the Dutch green houses
dude the ven oh man you want to know
like where this all is going it's there
like let's be honest so for sure but
yeah it's the greenhouse application is
it's what I'm most excited about too and
it's just something about looking at a
plant inside a greenhouse like it's just
something so natural about it and so
beautiful and right I feel like in
indoor they still have that beautiful
green but outdoor in a greenhouse that
emerald green is just
so rich yeah that color is just in
between the look of the outdoor to the
indoor but you can get an indoor looking
product that has the crystals the
structure the density you know I think
those things are important to people
that visual where like not not that
there's anything wrong with outdoor
because I I love Amazing Outdoor you
know if you do outdoor right killer it's
the best ker but typically for the
buyers on the market that are you know
the consumers that are buying from
stores they're going to want something
that looks like an indoor product and
the next best thing I think is the
greenhouse most definitely most
definitely so we working with a lot of
Partnerships coming up and um we're
excited to kind of get get talking about
those but uh yeah man there's so much
cool stuff on the horizon yeah is just
opening the door for not only like
growing in times when you shouldn't be
or in areas where it's very tough like
you know winter runs and Greenies but
also genetics that don't really have
that much yield like all these genetics
that we can't run in scale you know
Skittles being one of them one of those
like you can't really do it in
commercial settings because it just
doesn't make money I mean my friends do
yeah yeah I know I know I know they're
killing it I know your friends they're
killing it they're killing yeah yeah
they're killing it shout out to those
guys I know exactly who you're talking
about yeah SF can among yeah other
people with SF Cana killing it with
Skittles and it comes out amazing yeah
yeah so actually SF can right out there
oh what's yeah so yeah so if people want
to find out more about you where do they
go so faven lighting Instagram um we try
to put a ton of resources there um faven
lighting.com that's where you can order
you can fill out a lighting layout um
lighting layouts are great because it's
a three minute questionnaire tells us
everything we know we need to know to
spec out your facility you fill out one
of those we we send you back exactly
what you need hey you need this many
lights you need this cord you need this
um we send you out your lights that's it
three-step process man how about your
Instagram so we got faven lighting
Instagram faven lighting.com and then
I'm Bobby bags on Instagram that's my
personal right you know and so I have
I've been I think I have a presence
there for about three and a half years
or so yeah I am now on team faven I
appreciate you being on team fav man
looking forward to doing all these
trials together and we'll have to get
you on a podcast once we have some
results so we can go over the results
with everybody I think that'd be a lot
of fun we should do it to where I don't
know what the results are too yeah like
it you know like I I I want to be you
catch me on air like with my reaction
because that's so fun like I wake up all
the time to text messages from people
that are like bro it was 35% you know
40% yield increase and it just makes my
day because you know that that just gave
them some kind of financial relief you
know when we're feno hunting with it
we're doing all kinds of stuff so it's
going to be a lot of a lot of
interesting things going on in the next
six months yeah this is awesome this is
the best part about getting tools in the
right people's hands man well and trying
something new that you know is going to
be beneficial it's like it's a
no-brainer for me it's a no-brainer I
feel like there's a lot of things out
there where it's like H we'll see how it
does but I feel like it's a no-brainer
I've seen it work with my friends so
yeah most definitely yeah well thank you
so much for coming on the podcast today
this is awesome thank you so much you
have a killer platform I love it keep
doing what you do congrats on your book
before I forget they're out people were
happy they're selling like hot cakes so
happy to hear it man I wasn't sure how
they were going to do you just never
know how books are going to do I know
how F would do it's my first book I
don't know how I mean I look at guys
like Rob Clark and Ed Rosen and I see
I'm like their books sell and they're
good books there's no other breeding
book besides Greg greens which is 25
years old yeah you know I'm sure someone
else will write write another breeding
book but of course but yeah I'm excited
to have the breeding book on the market
kill man I'm so excited to hear that
dude and congratulations again I don't I
don't know what it's like to write a
book and I hope in the next 10 to 15
years that becomes something that I
start doing so I just Big Ups to you
that's a it's a lot of dedication thank
you so much and thanks for coming on the
podcast and we'll do this again all
right dud later
[Music]
back
CR yeah
[Music]