[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James L podcast
with extra special guest Rue R goofy
growing that's me how you doing today
I'm doing great man thanks for coming on
the show rud thanks for the intro I
appreciate it I appreciate everything
you've done for me this weekend dude I
appreciate it so much man thank you for
all the stuff you've done for James loud
genetics over the last you know six
eight months uh you've been sharing a
lot of content online that's how we met
was Instagram yeah yeah I mean that's uh
like I said I really honestly I didn't
know about you until I started growing
and some dude turned me on your genetics
and uh I just had great success with
them and I I love them right off the bat
uh there's other things other ones I've
tried there were finicky and this and
that and um the first ones I got from
you somebody gifted to me and there was
those frosted biscottis and they thought
they were photo periods so I grew them
like I do with my photo period in a Solo
Cup and they were about this tall or so
and I saw a couple of them started
flowering I was like oh these are not
photo periods this dude that gave them
to me was mistaken uh but I transplant
him in time and that's one of the only
Auto flowers I have ever had success
transplanting ever yeah ever two of them
didn't really make it or one of them
didn't make it one I kept in the Solo
Cup uh but those are the only olif
flowers I've ever got to transplant any
other olif flower I've tried
transplanting has always died uh or they
stay small or yeah not even die they
just I've had the struggle to I mean
I've I've learned how to do it with you
can transplant them as long as you
transplant them early enough if they if
the roots catch it all you're that it's
it's over they stay small they never get
big no yeah you got be Auto AO whis
frosted yeah you got to be the
Autoflower whisper for sure yeah yeah so
I do all my autof flowers in the my
hydro buckets and they just they thrive
in that so I love it yeah so that
frosted biscot special we didn't even
start selling until just recently I
wanted to thoroughly test it and you
sent some amazing photos we've had a
couple other guys that grew it sent some
really cool photos yeah it just comes
out really Frosty I mean I think most
people don't think of it as an
Autoflower when it's finished yeah no I
mean I know in all my videos I've always
said when I said frosted biscotti I said
that is the the perfect name for it cuz
you won't believe how many triones pack
on this thing you know for an Autoflower
it is insane like I've I've grown all
everything I've grown for you from you
is autoflowers and I everybody I give it
to is does not believe that they're
autoflowers they think that I'm lying to
them or something just can't believe it
so I'm having great success with your
autof flowers I appreciate that because
it's helping me out you know what I'm
saying awesome yeah dude I I love autof
flowers just as much as I love photo
periods I I don't discriminate
especially with autof flowers I think
that they've gotten so much better I
mean you look at my stuff but even some
of the other guys out there that are
producing really amazing stuff it's like
you didn't see anything like that 10
years ago yeah no I mean that's what
I've heard I'm not I haven't been
growing for 10 years uh but yeah I've
tried other ol flowers and so I kind of
see what they were saying you know what
I'm saying there's still some of those
janky a flowers out there stuff has like
bad turbs you get the yeah so yeah when
I was kind of I was totally going to
switch from autof flowers which I mean I
did I did photo periods but once I got
my hands on yours um it kept all the
flowers in my garden like I said I loved
growing them in my little veg room
having you know vegg and stuff and
flower and stuff at the same time
seedlings uh to me that's just a happy
place Heaven you know what I'm saying
just seeing all stages uh right then and
there so it's just great which other
ones have you grown you grown the Cherry
Cola OG and the Cherry Cola gelato I
think yeah and then the uh purple punch
yeah that's a winner and then the
the gorilla Z's OG Kush cross and then
the frost of biscotti yeah from Fast
buds fastbuds made all the receivers on
on that line like the Cherry Co the I
feel like there's one more that grew but
I can't remember yeah all of them
successful like I said I couldn't
believe when the dude you know told me
their photo periods I had those olif
flowers in the cup and they were doing
that and I mean they didn't get huge but
I mean they were still like that and
that main Cola was still there and I had
still good four branches coming out um I
don't ever really weigh my stuff right
off you know Harvest so I don't I
couldn't tell you uh but it was one of
the most successful harvests I've had
from Autoflower like I said I uh
definitely shocked it a little bit from
transplanting it I know I did but it
still was successful so yeah I used to
transplant with one liters into three
liters from the chore uh their Coco and
I always had success with that yeah so
you know and so you can do it if you do
it right transplanting but like if you
go and you have them any longer than 7
days usually in in a cube that's when
they get root bound and then you have
problems yeah but there's also
autoflowers can be finicky if you don't
know what you're doing or if you have
cold nighttime temps you know the beauty
beautiful thing with autoflowers they
can finish in as early as like 60 to 65
days yeah from germination yeah and so
I've had one of yours now that I can
remember uh it was 50 seven days wow 50
I can't remember I think it was the the
purple punch I could I could have pushed
it longer if I wanted to yeah that was a
personal preference but it was still
dense buds I've gave it to people they
didn't ask what's up with that you know
what I'm saying yeah oh man it's you you
got that good push still when you put it
in the grinder you know what I'm saying
right so uh yeah I mean that's that was
it 57 days I remember now yeah so less
than two months from seed you can have
finished flower PS yes yes sir good good
finished product well finished flour you
still got to dry it and cure it yeah
yeah yeah yeah that's yeah that's from
you know seed to the old chooo you know
what I'm saying yeah when so how many
years have you been growing now a little
over probably about four or so so uh I
started growing just because I don't
drink I don't do anything else I used to
drink and do a lot of hard drugs uh so I
I kind of broke away from that and uh so
I still had to get flour from other
people I tried to mainly get it from my
brother uh but there's a couple other
buddies and I went to go get it from
them and they had you know
extracurricular activities we'll call
them on the table here and there uh and
I just saw it and I kind of just didn't
feel right you know what I'm saying this
wasn't what I was trying to do this
wasn't bettering my life like I was
wanting or it was but it wasn't what I
was still looking for I guess you know
what I'm saying I was trying to break
away from that scene all together uh and
so um I just yeah I got a knot in my
stomach and I just think why not just
start growing my own you know what I'm
saying yeah uh so that's how it started
I I got a a little Cheapo light you know
off Amazon uh got a little corner in my
closet and just started uh so yeah
that's I mean if you want to grow your
own weed anybody can believe me it it is
a lot simpler than you think it's it's a
lot of learning that goes along with it
but you know what I'm saying it it off
the bat you'll you'll like you'll find
out if if it's for you or not and it's
as simple or as complex as you want to
make it that's the beauty of growing
right you can keep it simple and have
success yes you can take it to an
advanced level that most people couldn't
handle and you can have failure or you
can do it slowly and be super successful
I think that there's there's different
levels for everybody in scale as you get
better you can go up in scale yeah but
like it's great starting out with the
one line I mean that's I got a lot of
respect for you and what you've done and
your enthusiasm for cannabis like you
were just a you you love the plant I can
tell it's contagious you know I mean
you're like smoke weed baby that is
that's what I want everybody to do if
you enjoy weed you need to smoke it you
need to uh for me it it betters my life
you know it makes me deal with things
I'm I'm off all Pharmaceuticals yeah I
don't really like taking any type of
pills I maybe take Ibuprofen if you know
the Cannabis can't handle you know my my
knees and my back screaming at the time
but uh so yeah for the most part it's
it's helped me in so many ways so uh I
need to give it the respect that it
deserves you know what I'm saying yeah
totally yeah well and it's a beautiful
plan because as much as you give it
it'll give you back yes you know correct
correct correct the more love you put
into it the more love you get back the
better smoke you get or however you
consume it Edibles or whatever it is ed
dab whatever we huffing yeah yeah yeah
the lady said you're huffing and I'm
puffing we were yeah that's so funny R
in the River it was like we had a lady
and she had some old school hash that
was it was good hash it was good old
school hash we were smoking it with the
the Little Dipper the little yeah the
Little Dipper and I tried to get her to
take a hit of some rosin from flora and
Flame that was amazing this Donnie
burger that I had and she was like no
that's huffing yeah yeah I'm HFF huffing
she was a little offended like what are
you trying to do turn me into a drugie
yeah and I think everything has its
place yeah yeah for sure their own too
we are we're going to get on the show
yeah and I'm going to try her yeah
people like that that have their own
thoughts and stick to their gun you know
what I'm saying like that's that's a
beautiful thing you know what I'm saying
well and I think that there's something
to be said for staying in your lane and
just getting better and better and
better at that one thing that you do
whatever that is correct your trademark
saying is smoke weed baby yeah and
Ronnie Coleman who's a famous
bodybuilder from Texas also yeah yeah he
says lift weights baby I don't know if
you heard that from him but yeah he's
from the Arlington area and so before or
lightweight baby is his his saying so he
says lightweight baby and
so when you said it for the first time
it reminded me of Ronnie Coleman and
he's so passionate about lifting weights
he's he was you know Mr Olympia yeah I
don't know 10 times or eight times or
something like that and amazing
bodybuilder just a really nice guy but
like it's it's that kind of stuff that
that kind of drives people for with the
passion and I love it I love it when
people are super passionate about the
plant because I also so love everything
about the plan and there's so many
benefits to it and the more people we
have on board that understand that the
better and I feel like it's contagious
to a degree when you love something so
much people become curious about why you
love it they're like what what is up
with this guy they either think you're
crazy or they're curious about why you
think that way or a little both and I
mean it's the plant too it's uh for me
it's the whole aspect of it you know
what I'm saying not even just the
smoking of it you know what I'm saying
the whole getting to know this plant
learning it uh just you know what I'm
saying that that that's helped me
mentally so much yeah uh going in my
garden be able to sit there uh like I
said I open like when I do mine uh I'm
not a huge huge uh on controlling uh the
environment too much I control my uh
temperature mainly I have an AC in there
but when my stuff opens I open the doors
I open the tent if lights are on I'm in
there I'm talking to them I play music
for them um you know saying I open up I
ask them how you know y'all are doing
great I encourage them you know what I'm
saying uh so yeah that whole thing for
me and maybe if I you know didn't do all
that maybe it would turn out a little
bit better but that's for me right now
that helps me so much mentally or maybe
it wouldn't or maybe it wouldn't you
never know and I feel like and I'm I
feel me I think I'm getting good
products you know I'm happy with it and
anybody I share it with is happy so so
I'm just going to keep rocking and
rolling do what I'm doing right now yeah
I mean you're the customer that I love
the most this you're the type of
customer that loves the the finished
product loves everything about it and
it's like I love supporting the home
Growers I mean yeah we have commercial
Growers too that are buying this stuff
but it's like the lifeblood of this
industry that we're in was built on home
Growers and home grow yeah yeah for sure
people that are passionate about it
where it's not about money like even if
you didn't get paid a penny for your
stuff yeah you still do it because you
love it yeah yeah yeah I mean like I
said this I didn't you know even if you
lost a lot of yeah I feel like you're
one of those guys even if you're losing
money you would still do it yeah well
like I I know I mentioned a couple times
if I get my outside grow going I might
just be off the grid you know what I'm
saying I you know what I'm saying it's
it's it's that you know what I'm saying
that that I know I need now you know
what I'm saying that that uh growing
with that plant and um it just helps me
so much so yeah it's I just love it so
by next year we'll probably see you
living up in Humble you know reging on
the river you won't even have to go more
than 10 miles no no I'm going to be just
walking down that mountain right there
you know what I'm saying just swimming
across the river and there you go you
know what I'm saying that's GNA be me
nice I'd love it man I'd love it it's uh
man yeah the the environment up there is
just you can tell is weed growing
environment uh it gets nice and warm dur
the day and cool at night but not too
cool that's the beauty of it is it's
still warm at night so like those plants
will really thrive going to stretch too
much I think you know the the heat
there's a little heat there but it's not
overly hot like some places just get
insane yeah I'm I'm from Texas so uh
like our when we do get extremely hot I
mean we could be at 90 by 10 a.m. or
something you know what I'm saying
really and if it keeps cranking we can
go 105 or something so um yeah those you
know really hit you hard but this one
you know it's not too bad I mean we got
90s I don't know we couldn't check the
temperature but I guarantee it's 90s uh
a couple days there but you know it hits
you later on in the evening not too hard
not too too much so it kind of not too
bad you know what I'm saying like it's
it's definitely g r a sweater at night
you know what I'm saying too so it's
definitely cooler so yeah I I guarantee
you people just growing outside there
would you know have great results which
I which we all know they
do that's where it comes from theal Tri
was built on Emerald Triangle emal
triangle I made it I was up there and
humble and I feel like yeah they have
great conditions for cultivation yeah U
and the people up there you know I feel
like there's just an amazing Community
up there and you know the more I can
support them the better yeah for sure so
yeah everybody up there is great
everybody up there is great it's and
it's just that's another one it's just
contagious when you're around
like-minded people that that feel the
same way you know and it's these people
were Outlaws back in the day and finally
when we're moving forward unfortunately
some of are getting left behind but like
I feel like there's going to be a time
where we can lift them back up too yeah
yeah for sure for sure yep yep yep so
yeah and it's like in Passionate people
it's like it's not even about the money
it's about the plant right at the end of
the day it's about the plant and what it
does for us and how it makes us feel and
for you like the soety side of it where
where you're basically sober you're
using cannabis as a way to stay sober
correct I think that's great I I
experienced it this weekend with you I I
unfortunately tried to make it this
weekend without drinking and I drank a
couple beers yeah yeah hey I kept it
simple yeah you know but it's like and I
just try to do the best I can do and I
don't give myself [ __ ] I just you know
and I did smoke a lot we did you know
and then we got back and we tried you
know we tried all the samples from the
can those and put them in order so now
I'm going to go back through them
probably five more
times sort in them rosin entries were
pretty special yeah yeah yeah no there's
a couple that were really good really
good uh so yeah that was fun put you
know testing them put them in order uh
so yeah I mean this whole weekend has
been a mind-blowing experience I'll tell
you that right now just from you know
meeting the the one and only James loud
hanging out with him to like I said I I
was it not crazy enough was I camping
with James loud our neighbor was Marlon
Asher yeah you know what I'm saying I'm
waking up drinking coffee sitting there
burning one and he comes rolling out his
tent you know telling me good morning
and stuff and I mean we actually helped
him move a little bit of his stuff and
he was right there and it was like such
an amazing thing that yeah he's such a a
cool dude I mean he's just he's a
regular dude I mean you are you know
what I'm saying like you know we all
know that that you know people are
people but it's like once you you see
them and you meet them and you know that
it's crazy people are people so they can
be [ __ ] people yep yep they can be
amazing people they can be somewhere in
between all of that they can be amazing
[ __ ] people too you know what say
hey yeah yeah we all have different
varieties of assholism in our in us I
guess yeah but let's take a little
rewind back to how you found out about
re on the river uh well I found out
about it because uh we were doing one of
our monthly phone calls or something
like that and uh we're trying to do
something and you were like oh I'm going
to Reay on the river right then I was
like well I like Reay what's what's
going on bu so so Rue is an ambassador
for James Lin he is our main Ambassador
correct we have two ambassadors he's the
main one and we have flow Garden is the
other one yeah yeah and he's amazing
he's amazing he's amazing too he does
great dude he does hemp in in Tennessee
I believe yep yep Tennessee does amazing
flower he's growing some of my stuff
great pictures great pictures great
photographs does really good photographs
you great you do great photographs for
home photographs I mean yeah yeah I'm
working on it we wouldn't be friends if
you didn't have good photos you know
what I mean like that's what really got
me excited was seeing your photos of the
quality of the work yeah yeah I
appreciate it for hom grower but we were
on the phone and talk we do a monthly
meeting where we talk about stuff and uh
with the ambassadors and he promotes the
brand and you know I TR try to promote
him and we were talking about music and
we talked about Ree and I love regae
dude it's it's one of my ghost too now I
mean that's what that's actually
probably the Main Music I listen to now
after I kind of got you know off the the
booze and stuff I stopped listening to
my country music as much and stuff going
more towards the the rosta vibe you know
what I'm saying of the smoke weed and
less of the like I'm sad cuz I'm drunk
yeah EXA yeah I lost everything cuz I'm
drunk well no [ __ ] buddy
yeah yeah I think you know ree music
definitely embodies all of that you know
this the spirit way more uplifting way
more uplifting love it's all about love
and
happiness you know I think there is some
you know there is they do sting about
struggle too and I love that oh yeah
yeah you know but like most of the
reggae it has a good beat to it you can
move to it and it's just good vibrations
good energy I just saying like you know
majority of Ray artists where they you
know they come from you know Jamaica or
whatnot they ain't got the great
conditions and just goes to show you man
that you jamming good music smoking some
good ganja you probably have a good
attitude you know what I'm saying as you
can see it affects people and Al all
over the world you know what I'm saying
that just goes to show you man uh what
what it'll do for you I think it changes
your mind on what you think is good and
bad and what you actually what you might
actually need in life you know what I'm
saying yeah and I think happiness is a
choice too yeah to a degree I mean we
can choose to be upset we can choose to
be happy we can we can choose in this in
the moment Y how we want to how we want
to be and how we want to live our lives
and correct sometimes it's harder than
other times but like at the same time I
feel like it is a choice to a degree I
mean there's obviously there's moments
where it's going to be tough and you
were're GNA have these emotions but all
that stuff is a choice and reggae music
definitely will put you in the right
mindset oh yeah for sure for sure it
just that's I I I I hear it and I feel
it you know what I'm saying you hear it
you feel it and then you just start
grooving and moving and just man puts a
smile on my face and just brings me a
happy place yeah so yeah so you flew in
last Wednesday we hung out at the
facility a little bit and then and then
we drove up north yeah yeah I think it
was what about a 4 hour drive from here
or something like that uh it wasn't too
bad of course I wasn't the one driving I
was just
uh but yeah we got up there set up camp
and uh man yeah the the spot we had was
just fabulous I mean uh like I said
thanks to Royal gold they big shout out
to Royal gold Cutting Edge but Royal
gold for the spot Rick's an amazing
person R and his family they're great we
we love them uh good people and he
hooked us up with a beautiful spot to
camp in we had we were under a tree yeah
oh it was flat we had the coolest place
around there I guarantee you
I mean it was cool like it looks cool
but I mean temperature- wise it
wasse it was great yeah oh man it was it
was uh it felt like uh felt like home
while we were there really it uh it felt
like when we when we were leaving the
booth or whatever I feel like well we're
going home now you know what I'm saying
well yeah I mean I can't spend too much
time up in hble County because I'll end
up moving up there that's the problem I
I got to come back sooner than later
because I just I love it up there and
the people up there are just great um
but yeah Rick from Royal gold big shout
out to Sean and John Cutting Edge we
used one of their tables we set up in
the area with all those guys and Sean's
a wild man SE Sean's a wild man yeah I
love that guy man he knows how of party
Sean's a good dude Sean's good dude he
knows how to have a good time and I love
it and I think he's great for the
company and and Uncle John he's
contributed so much to our community and
to our industry and he's just a really
great guy
yeah I got to meet him too I got to meet
Uncle John so yeah he's a he's a cool
little dude yeah old man uh smart guy
just really smart guy good at business I
feel like they've done really good with
their company uh they have a product
they believe in yeah I believe in their
product too you can tell they just have
nothing but good vibes too like I mean
just being man that whole Booth set up
that whole length like I said those two
other booth next to us like just man
You' go to the booth sometime I've
worked a little booth before and you got
crappy neighbors or whatever and it
really feels like work the whole time
dude this is just re on the river right
there you're just in the booth instead
it was happen and having a good time
with those guys and everybody over there
was great yeah it's a great event Nick
another guy we got to see Nick you got
to meet Nick he's one of my good friends
yep yeah well he was two t down or yeah
with he did two DJ sets yeah he was
killing it he killed it yeah that that
set we saw was just he was on fire he
was and he is great I mean I think yeah
he also got to see the sour diesel so I
got a sour diesel story yeah yeah yeah
but yeah I got to I get to meet this guy
Dave and Dave's from up North and he
came to me and he said I got something
to show you if it's not the real one you
can be honest I won't have hurt feelings
but just tell me the truth yeah yeah
yeah and I got some Sour Diesel to show
you and sure enough it was the real Sour
Diesel that I haven't seen for a long
long long time I've seen so much Sour
Diesel over the last year
but none of them were this grown grown
to this particular standard maybe maybe
it's the same cut we're going to test it
genetically to compare yeah but it was
as sour as it gets like the real nose of
Sour Diesel that was like not just burnt
Tire it did have a little bit of that in
there yeah but it had the Citrus back it
has like the Citrus in this funk I
remember smelling it Nick verified it so
a and my friend Stevie verified it
yesterday and everybody's like wow I
can't believe you have that flower and
so that was super special yeah yeah yeah
no like I said uh I can't remember if I
smoked it or not who knows you did smoke
some bong R yeah yeah oh I did I did
that's right I did uh so yeah uh man it
tasted good but yeah that the when you
let me smell it I was it was uh smelled
really good really yeah it's super
special that's a super special one and
Dave also had the Nigerian Haze that was
another one that looked terrible but
then you smoke it and it's one of those
ones that it creeps up on you gently
lifts you up and then you're like you're
cool yeah yeah it almost look like um
like little weeds or something almost
like you pick up off the ground yeah
yeah like little little yeah it was pody
and it was like these little small like
just little small bracks that were like
three inches apart from each other was
like on Twigs it was crazy it was crazy
it was one of the craziest looking weeds
I've ever seen land R for sure for sure
yeah good stuff so what was your
highlight of the whole weekend I mean
probably my most highlight was seeing
Marlon Asher perform live I haven't ever
done that seeing him put on his show was
awesome he puts on a great show to me he
was to me he was the best singer there
like or that's just my personal
preference I love his music uh I mean
all the artists they were great all the
artists they were they were great but uh
yeah to me that was like his performance
was special so so I've seen Marlin
performed many many many many times and
that sound was some of the best I've
ever heard it made his voice sound even
even better than his he was just on on
you know sometimes when people were just
on but also the sound system the way his
voice carried over the crowd and where
you could stand because we were in the
back and then we went to the front yeah
and we were at the side and then we went
to the other side and then we were in
the back again it sounded good
everywhere but like his voice was just
perfect yeah you know and and his band
he has this this band they're newer uh
they've been working together recently
and they just sounded amazing the backup
singer sounded great and you could hear
everything it wasn't getting meshed
together everything was very distinct
and just the the the time like almost
like a boom box sound instead of like
when you know saying live sound gets too
like I said too loud or whatever it just
mushes together uh this was real you
know fine like you like you could tell
like somebody took time and the the
sound people really did their job
everything just sounded good uh so yeah
thank you reg on the river y'all did a
great amazing job and uh keep doing what
you're doing yeah can't wait for next
year yeah for sure for sure we're going
to have to bless one person a year we
don't want too many people one person a
year we're gonna have come with us and
just build well just don't kick me out
of the group you know what I'm saying
for sure for sure yeah good times yeah
you're gonna have to bring the whole
family next year yeah yeah for sure for
sure they uh they were missing me so
yeah uh if I could do that that they
might even get hooked on you know what
I'm saying so get them to move there
yeah that's the secret way there yeah
there you go I'll bring we're going for
ree we're just going to go check it out
for re and then next thing you know
you're living there yeah yeah yeah where
are we going oh we're just going home
yeah are we're flying home no we're
driving home yeah right on the river
yeah right on the river river station
come over
here right by the river stage for sure
for sure that would be great I'd love it
yeah I mean so we started by rolling up
20 joints the first day 20 24
joints and it's the best way to start
out in adventure well you're just saying
joints yeah these are about an eth
that's my joints they about an eighth uh
a joint people so uh that's what he
rolls so that's what we do yeah that's
how we do it yeah so yeah 24 of those
first day got got there started rolling
uh got to work you know what I'm saying
yeah so let's dive into genetics all the
stuff you've been growing over the last
four years so I've been growing a long
time I've been in the industry a long
time so I've seen all the different
stuff but over the last four
years what have been the
highlights um
highlights uh one of my like I said I
first started off I got the like I said
I just got a small little light of
course I went the uh I love growing
marijuana route uh you get the 10 by 10
which you know it's it's the ilgm.com
yeah yeah uh which I mean like I said
one of my favorite plants came from them
uh you if they hit or miss a little bit
nothing against them but I mean to me I
went that route cuz like when you first
hear oh you're going to have to kill
plants you're gonna have to you know
this will happen so it's like oh buy 10
get 10 uh so yeah I got I first started
off with them I did grow a photo period
from them uh zittles and um it came out
nice and purple it was one of first ones
I would say I had really good success
with uh was theirs and then so skittles
from seed yeah yeah or Z or whatever you
call yeah whatever you want to call it
got purple yeah yeah it it came out that
was like one of the first plants I
started getting praise for uh people
were like oh damn you know what I'm
saying love the fade love the color uh
so that would have been my first little
highlight that I love that uh but like I
said their genetics aren't really
consistent or whatever um so yeah I
started draw doing some other ones um I
had a um a Northern Lights from Grower's
choice I think is my next good
successful one that uh uh it actually
didn't look the best but for for me I
got [ __ ] weight off of it and it
smoked great yeah I don't know if it's a
true Northern Lights but uh it it the
effects were really good uh and then
yeah my nexts were were yours like that
Frosty biscotti that first tried like I
said uh I knew I was on to something
special when I got successfully to do
after I transplanted an Autoflower I got
him somebody thought I thought they were
photo periods uh transplanting them so
that was a highlight too was that first
success of uh of uh uh Autoflower
getting transplanted and then yeah so
everything I've grown from you like I
said then this last uh one that has been
really I've been getting a great a great
praise for another the gorilla Z's OG
Kush cross uh man that the fade on that
one has just been amazing and the smoke
on it too so I mean that flavor a lot of
flavor a lot you know a good effect and
it looks good you know what I'm saying
that that the trifecta of what you want
in the in weed there uh and so yeah I
I'd probably have to say all in all that
yeah that gorilla z zoji Kush cross that
last one I probably like that last one I
still have it pinned on my Instagram uh
I have a picture of It kind of like
almost dried up a little bit after
harvest like got one lane down or
whatever I have a back a black
background trying to be a little more
professional on my uh my photos there
right uh but yeah that one like I said
was just is probably the most
highlighted one uh like I said do your
purple punch OG Kush cross I love that
one it doesn't to me the one I did
didn't it didn't pack as high as a punch
but the the flavor on it
man I've never tasted anything I can
only describe it like as a pickle
deal flavor there's nothing else like it
I've never and I mean
it's like you sweet though yeah it has
like yeah but it's not like a a sweet
pickle to me like it's uh like a regular
pickle or kosher or whatever you want to
call has still has that like a a a kick
to it you know what I'm saying little
bite yeah a little bite man when you hit
it it's like you hit it in that back of
the throat and it's like man I every
time I Exel on that one um I think
pickle man it is just great so uh all
the trifecta would be the gorilla Z's
and and then uh like I said all just
that flavor-wise would be that purple
punch man like I said I would just break
off little pieces and put in my bong
just if I went to the I smoke in my
restroom for the for the most part if I
had to use the restroom wash my hands or
anything I'd grab a little piece and
just get that flavor nice it tasted so
good so in the last four years what's
the best weed you ever seen Grown by
other people I was about to say that
that guava Cherry probably not the best
I seen but that was that was special
tast yes yeah uh there's one other I
can't
remember what it was called off hand but
man the structure on it was like just
had like a like little buds together uh
the aroma off of it
man I can't remember yeah yeah but yeah
uh so much good stuff this weekend yeah
dude uh yeah and so much good stuff that
we were consuming this weekend that it's
still consuming hard hard to recul
sometimes remember yeah yeah yeah and
those entries for the yeah can of Fest
we got to try all those entries last
night we went through 10 of them I think
we went through nine out of the 10 yeah
for yeah I don't think we hit that last
one but but we did try nine yeah yeah we
did our best pretty good entries pretty
good entries yeah overall pretty good
yeah yeah yeah can't complain can't
complain good Ro we had good Ros in to
smoke all weekend oh man you we were
dabbing smoking flour whatever dabbing
and dabbing dabbing that Little Dipper
Dabber you have is one of the best
invention since since last bread man A
Little Dipper man that's great it's just
so convenient yeah they make it too
convenient yeah oh man you can just open
your jar and right there or your
friend's jar yeah your friend's jar
there you go there you go there you go
yeah so tell us a little bit about your
grow setup how you how you're doing
stuff you because you do you used soil
and you also do like a hydro setup right
yes yes uh I'm having more success with
my hydro I I run five gallon buckets and
I I was going to do like the the r RW or
rdwc the
recirculating uh but I find it better
and easier just to do whatever call
Bubble buckets or whatever where I just
I drill hole on my side
I put the air hose in there drop an
AirStone uh and I just change it weekly
you know what I'm saying um right now
I'm using rise nutrients I'm have I
think I'm going to try a cut an edge I'm
going to try their run theirs next next
um so yeah I do that and I have great
success with it uh but you know of
course soil always tastes a little bit
better and stuff so I love my soil but I
also you know I think there's a place
for everything yeah for sure I mean I
saying like
the once you or for me once I saw the
the how quickly the rapid rate of uh of
uh these plants growing in the hydro
just blew my mind you know saying I
heard about it because I I first started
off with Coco and then I really for some
reason I couldn't get that going like it
just wasn't going so I switched to soil
and actually had a pretty good success
and then I kind of got funky on that for
some reason I don't know uh I think I
was trying to learn too much at once you
know what I'm saying I was just honest
canv canvas canvas canvas people should
start out with soil cuz there's a buffer
and I I like soil you know there there's
I like a lot of things about soil but I
do like the buffer that you have with
soil yeah whereas Hydro you screw things
up you can kill your plants I mean it's
it's like that it's yeah it can be just
like that yeah you know if you and then
Coco uh if you're talking about Coco
that's completely inert you know it's
like uh that doesn't have anything in it
you got to feed it properly right from
the get-go and you know you can overfeed
it or underfeed it there's all these
questions where a soil it's like there's
this little bit of a buffer yeah yeah
and you use good soil and it's a great
place to start it's it's you know
everyone has their opinion on how to
start but I feel like soil is just an
easy way you know Rockwall I think takes
it's it's like the Ferrari right like in
some ways like as far as not everybody
knows how to drive a Ferrari and it
takes a long time to learn how to drive
a Ferrari but once you learn how to
drive a Ferrari it goes really fast I
think that is Rockwell I think that
Rockwell has its place for certain
things
like especially mothers and clones yeah
okay especially mothers and clones and
then dwc I've seen great flower come out
of dwc my friend Alfred Master Yoda he
is the king of dwc he's won many many
cups with
his culture yeah yeah he's he he's solid
he's got the master yoa cush he's yeah
yeah he's a he's just an amazing person
he's a really good grower but I mean
there's so many different ways you can
grow so many different substrates you
can use yeah yeah so I try to keep the
hydro buckets and soil in my garden all
the time uh like I said I I won't ever I
won't ever kick either one of those out
I don't think uh like I said so I have
my closet um which uh I I veg there for
the most part I I've been doing 16 hours
when I get back I'm going bump it up to
20 hours for autoflow you got to go 20
that's one one thing people don't
understand and I feel like the you get
the most yield and benefit even though
it costs a little bit more yeah for your
you know for your veg well same thing
like veg I veg at 20 hours too but that
that's you're you can do 18 you can do
whatever but like I veg a little bit
longer stuff like blue dream than I used
to have back in the day if you did less
than 20 there's a chance that it would
kick into flour a little bit and so the
Clones wouldn't be as healthy but uh I
would say that for autof flowers you get
the best bang for the buck at 20 for
yield and everything else some people
like why I have to pay more for
electricity it it pays for itself you'll
get a better yield you'll get better
structure it looks amazing well you got
me excited because dude like I said I
the like I said I don't even people ask
me why I run I don't run even 18 I run
16 hours and the results I'm getting off
your you can still get good results
don't get me wrong you can still get
good results but at 20 I think it's even
better well I saying you're getting me
super excited about seeing these results
off the the 20 hour and who knows maybe
you'll find the 18 is better for you you
know what I mean or or
16 do at and they don't like autoflowers
and they do them at 12 well that's why
you got to use more light that's the
beauty of the autl is you can keep the
light on and it's not going to go back
into veg not going to stress out the pl
it's going to thrive I think people grow
their Auto flowers like I do like in the
same tent same environment but they're
they're flipping that whole thing so one
one half of the time they're growing it
it's getting 18 to 20 hours and then all
of a sudden it's getting 12 12 when you
know that's not what it's designed for
it's designed to get the exact same
amount of light you're giving it it
doesn't need to be flipped I mean you
can grow in Alaska where it doesn't get
dark for that period of the year and it
won't affect their flower cycle it loves
it yeah yeah yeah for sure so yeah aut
of flowers pretty trippy you know oh man
I love them like I said uh people people
bash on them all the time there's plenty
of people to bash on him but it's like
such a personal preference thing and
that's what people don't understand is
maybe they're not not the right choice
for you but for a lot of people out
there they like autoflowers aof flow
there's some companies that make
millions of dollars a month on selling
autoflow seeds and there's a reason for
it yeah yeah uh yeah because they're
good to to for certain environments for
certain people for certain conditions
they are fantastic if you want to just
have a plant that you grow on your
window sill and you live in Barcelona
correct autoflow is easy yeah yeah like
I said you don't really need a light
schedule right so uh I mean yeah they're
just like I said they're just amazing to
me because like I said it you can all in
my one area like I said my I converted a
walk-in closet to uh to my veg area
thank you from to my wife for letting me
do that it was actually a functional
closet we had clothes hanging in there
that's where I first took over over the
corner uh I took over a little bit more
uh I was talking about I need more tents
and maybe uh building something and then
she finally gave me permission to just
take it over so yeah I I took over uh
that so um I love having that like I
said in that area I have my veg and
seedlings there and I have my auto
flowers that are in flower so that whole
set up right there I get to see the
whole basically the life cycle of the
flower you know of the plant and so then
I transplanted I got a 4x4 where is my
flower ENT yeah so um if you ever seen
my podcast see the see the Harvest
podcast uh if you ever seen that one
where I sit behind me is that that's the
tent right so right behind me is that
4x4 tent and so I'll uh I'll just take
them from you know from there and
Transplant them over and then flip them
in there uh I have a AC unit that sits
right out outside of it to uh can
control the temperature like I said when
everything turns on I open my stuff up
and like I said I just start talking my
plants make sure what kind of lights are
you using right now uh I have
two uh Spider farmer SPF uh 1000s I
think uh just two of those uh I have a a
bar light on the side I don't even know
what I got from my brother I don't even
know what company it's from but it's
actually pretty are you measuring ppfd
you measure your par no I don't I need
to get par meter I don't like see right
now with my my uh
my uh Spider Farmers like they're the
old ballast yeah so I have to take them
off and readjust them like so I don't
even know if I'm at 50 or 40 really you
know what I'm saying I need to get a
meter to adjust those uh so right now
like I said I'm not even uh trying to
measure all that stuff because it's hard
for me to uh change the lighting system
on it but I don't try to I'll probably
just drive myself crazy honestly you
know what I'm saying uh so I actually I
keep those two uh spider Farmers cranked
up to 100% And I just adjust their
height if I think to and I really
haven't ran ran into any problems doing
that so far uh a couple plants that
maybe stretched a little bit more than I
wanted uh but until I really can get
more money to get more system I need to
get a light that has canopy next too
yeah yeah faving faving we we might even
have some for you all right hell yeah so
yeah I need to get that going and then
yeah like I said I have a bar light on
the side and then in my in my tent I
have a a fluence light and that's just
man I don't even know I got that also
from my brother but that thing hits
every corner that 4x4 so yeah it's it's
packed in there and that one has the
little you know the adjusting like you
can go from one two three four five you
know what saying all the way to 100%
yeah that that light's badass uh so yeah
I I when I go in there I probably start
off about 50% or so on that one and then
I probably crank it up to about 85% or
something I don't think I've had to do
anything 100% in there yet what do you
try to keep your temperature and
humidity at uh in my veg room uh I try
to keep the temperature it stays about
like 74 to 76 or so um I freak out if it
gets close to 80% you know what I'm
saying I know I know in my head
everything will be fine for the
temperature or humidity uh temperature
temperature you like keeping a little
lower temp in your yeah yeah yeah like I
said I only have the one so where I'm at
humidity you don't worry about too much
I really don't I do I have a
dehumidifier I have a humidifier I don't
run them I was actually tripping over
them more than anything when they were
out there in my closet it stays uh CU I
have so many plants I have the buckets
in there it stays about 60% 55 to 60%
humidity uh the flower tint um nice will
stay roughly about the same times it
will drop when I have cut the AC off but
when I that AC itself creates humidity
yeah so um I don't really have to worry
about it really spiking it doesn't
create you know what I'm saying it's not
a humidifier so it doesn't just bust out
like um you know spits you know spits of
water right so um like I said just
naturally I'm sitting about 6 50 to 60%
humidity on both of them uh if a storm
comes in or something one time we did
get a whole bunch of rain I had a whole
bunch of stuff flowering and drying at
the same time uh it did it dry it did
dry it did it dry actually I think it
helped me man it rained for like a week
but luckily it hit like when I first
started doing it so when you first dry
anyways it's you're hitting about 60%
humidity or so right next to the plant
that that I've seen you know what I'm
saying because I normally dry in a
cardboard box uh I don't have a drive
room or anything like that nothing
professional uh I do it as I go I either
I make like a makeshift wall out in my
upstairs living room uh so I need to
work on that but yeah I'll I can do that
put it in the room and the the room
temperature of my bedroom stays probably
about like 60 60 degrees uh so yeah when
the lights are in the flower ttin it it
probably gets up to about like 73 and
then my nighttime temps uh probably hit
about like uh 68 69 or something wow
there's not too much fluctuation
with uh the the uh the barrier like I
said I have that AC right outside that
flower tint and I thought it would maybe
get colder in there than it does that it
would actually get to like the 60° and
just having that tin in there and those
those plants make heat you know what I'm
saying they're a living right they're a
living thing so they're creating heat
themselves so um well the light
definitely creates some heat yeah yeah
yeah for sure I'm saying with lights off
you know I'm saying yeah yeah yeah
saying I thought maybe it'd get colder
like around 60 but and it's insulated
those tents are yeah saying the tents
are thicker than you think and stuff so
um yeah like I said mainly I control my
temperature because like I said uh my
bedroom is above a uh garage so whatever
they did to try to insulate or didn't
insulate between the garage and our room
so if it's hot uh in that garage it just
goes through the uh the room so before I
even started growing our bedroom would
be in like summertime like
75 maybe 80° and that's when the the AC
trying to cool it down to 72 degrees
like it would just like come through
there so yeah I gotta keep that AC on
all the time if not it'll just it really
does Spike yeah I feel you that's the
last thing you want is hot yeah well uh
anybody that's been following me for
like I went to
Disneyland Disney World like two years
ago and my right before I left my AC
broke so I have a video of help me help
me help me tell me what to do people I
need help like I said I was only growing
for like two two years at the time I'm
showing temperatures of 92 in my tent uh
luckily I made it through uh everything
got harvested 92 is better than 102 yeah
yeah for sure for sure for sure so 92
you can you can survive yeah they did
they survived that you know uh well two
it was
what really freaked me out this is two
or three days before we had to go so I'm
trying to tell somebody how to take care
of my plants yeah and then they're
dealing with the heat issue and so I'm
like freaking out about that and it's
just like man just the the the extra
stress of like I don't know if you had
anybody try to take care of your plants
but you're like all right you do this
you do this and they say something wrong
you're like no no no no no no don't do
it that way no know you got to do it
this way
and so uh so yeah I was just freaking
out that something would have you know
they had messed something up a hair or
something and then just the the
temperature itself would have just
killed them but they they made it
through the first time I left to go I
was going snowboarding you know this is
when I was 17 and I had an apartment I
was going snowboarding and I had my
buddy watched the plants that were in I
had three guys there was three of us
living in a one bit apartment I had the
main room
bedom the closet was mine I had plants
in there and I had my buddy and I'm like
one tablesp of fish ulion with a gallon
of water all he heard was gallon and
fish emotion and so he's like well I
just put a gallon of fish emotion and so
oh write stuff down it's important to
write stuff down the weed tasted like
salmon I never smoked it we somebody
ended up buying it not for a lot of
money but they bought it and they smoked
it and they were like it's fine and
nothing I would smoke yeah yeah but was
like some salmon weed yeah not not
Salmon Creek big bud but salmon Bud dang
dude so fish you can't flush it up yeah
there's no flushing that much Salon it
was towards the
end so we went and harvested but yeah
you got to be real specific and write
stuff down when you have people taking
care of your grow this was when I had a
closet grow this was you know I'm 47 so
this was 30 years ago that's 30 yeah if
you were 17 that's 30 years ago yeah I
mean I I keep notebooks for everything I
do I write write down in my notebook uh
I I would recommend everybody get a
notebook if you're growing especially
like I have so many systems different
things going on right I'm trying this
trying that so I got my buckets uh you
got to keep on top of that KN when you
know when you change them if I don't let
them go longer than a week uh when you
know when they start stretching you got
to change them every other day every 3
days depends on the strain or whatever
uh but yeah uh I don't let them go long
than a week in my bucket so yeah I write
everything down so I know when I changed
it uh when I you know if I have soil
going maybe uh you know strains drink
differently so you know you might not
have to water this one every time that
you water the other two or something
like that so yeah yeah is to me is very
important to have a notebook write stuff
down and that way if your bud has to
take care of it like I do I write the
day I write this I write I put 9 in make
sure they write it down too yeah for
sure that's the best I mean everything
should be kind of logged in what you're
doing yeah um you know we have automated
equipment but it's still we record
everything yeah you're just not hand
doing it's just no and we still do check
stuff by hand you know it's like
especially calibration we make sure you
got yeah machines can need calibration
if you're doing pH or EC um you you
should calibrate those regularly we
calibrate them before we use them every
day yeah like we used to be once a week
and now it's like we calibrate them
every day and if we're comparing
carrying them and one is different then
there's a reason so we need to
investigate why that's different because
that can throw everything off yeah but
uh you know and it's like our we measure
runoff we we check for runoff too I want
to know what the runoff is testing at
yeah what how much is the plant eating
you know what what's it what's going
through what's going on is the pH
changing in there if there is I mean
those are little telltale signs that you
have issues yeah yeah for sure I mean
that's great like all these monitoring
systems now that we have like you know
what I'm saying I wish I can get one you
know what I'm saying that's that will be
in the future but yeah like I said you
all the data and all the the problems
you can search for and um I mean it's
just it's great so we can get the best
results out of this plan you know what
I'm saying which which it you know
that's what this plan deserves the more
information you have the more you have
an opportunity to make a better decision
on what you're going to do moving
forward and how to adjust stuff so the
more data you're working with the better
it paints a better picture of what's
going on and then also having someone
who's you know better than myself look
at the data and go dude what are you
doing here or or dude you could try
doing this and maybe this will improve
yeah just different set of eyes
different thoughts you know what I'm
saying different ideas that can come out
of sharing information list if you
listen to too many people's advice and
try to combine it all you're going to
screw everything up yeah it's better to
listen to one person's advice do all
that and if it doesn't really work
switch to a different person and follow
that to the T yeah and eventually you'll
build your own system and then you can
ask for little bits of advice and you
can change one thing at a time and see
well does that help does that not help
yeah yeah but this is a long-term thing
and a lot of people don't understand it
they think it's just like from cycle to
cycle well you know there's a commitment
to the plant that you're making by
growing and to learn how to grow really
well or to learn how to do any of this
it takes a lifetime right you're con
Master like four years I've been doing
this for a long time and I'm not a
master by any means I think that I have
some friends that are way better at the
cultivation side I may be better at seed
production I might be better at this or
reversals and all these things we all
have our own Niche but like it's great
when you can bounce ideas but also
having the data to where this is what I
do you know let's look at grow sense we
use grow sense from grodan and and we
use their sensors and it's like these
things they're egro software and that
the grow sense sensors and it's like
yeah these things are amazing agretech
and we have redundancy so not only do we
use one we're using multiple and we're
in a beautiful time where we can use two
different things and then we can compare
the data and go okay something's wrong
here guys yeah yeah yeah yeah I mean
like you said it's cool that like you
said like people like kind of specialize
in you know their own little thing and
that's way like you everybody say you
can do ideas off them and stuff and I
think it helps you know if you're not so
good at something you can get a little
advice and help and you said not
everybody might not be the best at
everything you know what I'm saying so
right we need to help each other well
writing writing stuff down also when
when I need feedback on this like what
on genetics or something like that if
you have it all written down you can
tell me what you did and yeah you know
you can and that's the beauty of being
able to help other people yeah so yeah
yeah I mean that's I mean writing it
down to like if somebody's like oh dang
you had great results how' you do that
I'm like oh [ __ ] I don't know off
hand with this yeah so I could go back
and look at it and tell them you know oh
I had to I did I did it weekly for this
long and then whatever I I had to start
swapping them out and uh so like when I
run my hydro nutrient
I'll uh I'll do a good week of uh veg
still or at least maybe not a week but
about five days yeah I'll I'll do I'll
run them straight and steal the veg
nutrients for about five days and then I
swap to a half and half of veg Bloom for
a week and then I go straight to the veg
or Bloom so yeah I mean I saying that's
just stuff I learned too uh you know
it's helps that you write stuff down so
yeah if somebody was asking hey what do
you what do you run them which people
have asked me before uh what nutrients I
run in my buckets and how I do it so
yeah I've helped a few people out and
that's I've I couldn't helped them out
if I didn't write it down you know what
I'm saying I would have never known what
to tell them because by the time they're
seen it and they want to know what I did
on something that was the plant I grew
months ago yeah it's funny so 30 years
ago there wasn't a lot of information we
we had to use a lot well in a lot of
recipes you get from nutrients and stuff
like that you would actually have to go
in and figure out your own recipe and be
combination of stuff that like because
the recipes that they gave you on the
back of the bottle yeah I mean you could
do three-part from GH and that would
give you consistent but that wasn't the
best you wanted something better yeah
yeah yeah it got you through but how can
we improve this dude and now it's like
you can use Cutting Edge like Uncle John
Cutting Edge you whether it's Cutting
Edge United Frontline
Athena uh you know we could house and
House and Garden I mean all these
companies if you follow the recipes that
you get from these companies you will
typically get good results yeah you know
it's like just following Te You B
basically just following step by step
from what they give you you're going to
get good results whereas 30 years ago or
even 20 years ago that wasn't
necessarily the case you would have to
use that and then we need a little bit
of liquid Karma or we use dark energy or
these different things and we use these
to get better results and you can still
do some of that stuff but a lot of times
just right out the gate you can follow
the recipe that's on the back um yeah I
mean I like when I first started off too
one my f i did the soil I I did the fox
farm and you know they their little
nutrient line Farm's great wasn't super
the best but dude like I said it will
get you through I think it gets you to a
good spot like I said that uh to know if
you like this or not you know what I'm
saying and uh like I said all you got to
do is read the instructions so like
companies like Cana and these other
companies they they you know that we can
name all the nutrient companies we want
uh a lot of them spend a tons of money
on research and development to give you
an amazing recipe that works really good
uh and then it's just a personal
preference of what do I like do I want
it to taste amazing do I want it to look
amazing because I think they all have
yeah different boxes that they check
when you use them and yeah for sure for
sure yeah like I said you can you can
start
tweaking that that recipe a hair you
know what I'm saying I wouldn't go crazy
and just half nutrients or whatever for
the most part I just use the stock
recipes and we might adjust a little bit
on um you know and I have a guy that
comes in and helps me do that he's much
better than I am and it's like because
just if you're if you're doing 50/50 on
something that's like a two-part you
want to go 6040 it's not just a straight
6040 because there's this amazing change
that happens when you you do it and it
doesn't adjust perfectly this chemical
change that happens when you add the a
to the B so but you you're doing 6040 of
A and B of one of the other or something
so if we're running like a
6040 let's say we're doing 50/50 I'll
use United as an example because we're
use I mean we we're in R&amp;D facility so
we test everybody's stuff but we're
using United right now and we went from
a 5050 and we were getting a little bit
of stretch and we were getting tip
burning right with it just straight
50/50 yeah and so we had our guy uh who
works with United he's amazing he came
in he's like we should probably just try
a 6040 and we'll go 60/40 and see how
that does with what what you're doing
and we're going to lower it from 3 EC
down to 2.5 EC we're going to go a
little bit lighter yeah right and then
we're going to go 6040 and we'll see how
it does problem solved that's what they
recommended you and he there's a
calculation that he used yeah to help us
get to that perfect 6040 because it's
not super when you're tie trading these
things yeah it's not just straightway
forward
so it's it's great having somebody I
mean and this is following their recipe
right yeah but well and another thing is
like you said you reached out to a
nutrient line or whatever if you're
having problems man call these people
call these people yeah the Tex them hit
them up message on Instagram whatever
they will get back to you most of them
will get back to you and these these
companies care about their customers
they want people to be their customers
obviously so yeah yeah I mean I think
customer service is half of it you're
good customer service if you want a
business and you want to be successful
customer service is key for sure for
sure yeah that's what I'm saying um I
mean like I said R I run the rise
nutrients uh it was my first time doing
Hydro I actually got them for soil and
uh like I said I was doing other soil
nutrients at the time but I wanted to
start my buckets and so I hit them a
message I think it was just on Instagram
I just left them a voice message saying
hey I got your nutrients are these good
for hydro buckets and they text me back
of course they are you know what I'm
saying uh blah blah blah and they
started conversation so and that's how
um uh I'm an affiliate for them now you
know what I'm saying um so that's how
that works you know what I'm saying just
start talking to these people man we
will gets the oil man don't don't be as
shy yeah speak up speak up yeah
especially if you're having problems
with your cannabis and well and if
you're buying a product you you want to
get the best results with it there's
nothing wrong with hitting up the
manufacturer and going okay how can I
make this the best it could be or you
know I mean I I do like if you got like
a TV or something that wasn't working
that you thought was supposed to operate
you go back and say hey dude this TV
ain't working the volum doesn't work
what's going on then why don't you go
back and say hey dude these nutrients
ain't working the way I thought and
they're like well they'll ask you what
are you doing how are you doing it so
that's once again write it down so you
can tell them the correct and accurate
information if you're telling them
something wrong and they tell you to try
to correct it and maybe that wasn't even
the problem to with there's so many
little things that beyond the recipe
like if you're filtering your water like
filtering for chlorine or whatever yeah
using a basic filter like you're going
to run it's going to run a a different
different pH right coming out so you can
have pH issues that you're not sometimes
you need ph up sometimes you need PH
down yeah it's just and then depending
on where you're located in the country
in the time of year you're your EC the
yeah basically can fluctuate your EC and
your pH can fluctuate just from using
City Water yeah yeah I I just use tap
water whatever uh I'll sit it out
declinate uh for 24 hours and so yeah um
I I just have to pH Down normally after
I dechlorinate it let it sit out it's
like 8 3ish mainly is what I normally
get sometimes eight you know you always
got to check it is the best thing uh but
yeah it's mine's always about eight and
I always just I just declinate I'll let
it sit out you know what I'm saying
what's your EC at coming out of the tap
I don't parts per I don't I don't test I
don't have an EC uhuh really yeah dude
I'm I'm I'm the kiss keep it simple
stupid for sure uh
I like learning and I learn about
certain things when I need to at time
but that's saying if uh if I'm not
running into the problem at the time I'm
trying I don't need extra stuff in my
head I guess you know what I'm saying I
got too much stuff balancing around as
it is uh so yeah um like I said I
haven't even had to go down that road
people have asked me all the time you
know all these questions I was like dude
I don't monitor that stuff I don't need
to worry about and you're like what what
I'm like I don't know dude you know what
I'm saying I tell you let's talk about
your podcast because you also do a
podcast I love your podcast see the
Harvest podcast it's me see the Harvest
podcast elur can Chris um so it comes on
Saturdays uh 5:30 Central Time on
YouTube um it's three of us they
actually were the two that came up with
it uh they were bouncing ideas off of
each other for a while how to get
something started uh they start off on
Instagram uh they asked asked me one
week if I'd be a part of it and I said
yeah yeah dude that's cool like me and
El first started uh we were messaging
and hang you know helping each other
back and forth for a while and then he
he knew Canal Chris and so they started
and they were asking me if I'd jump on I
said yeah we're having problems with the
Instagram of course uh so I think we
only did a couple episodes there so we
moved to YouTube uh having way more
success I think we're at like 500
subscribers we've been doing it for
six months now or something this is
season one we grew out the uh ponia glue
Skies from uh crop culture uh so yeah
we're having fun with that um so yeah
it's the three of us they were like I
said they were doing it they asked me to
be on and uh I'm the the it's the slogan
is grow with the show so yeah you can
get the genetics and so yeah uh the
thing is we'll give you the germination
uh date when we're germinating so it's
it's a it's a community thing we're
trying to get people to come along and
grow their cannabis if you have
questions or you're scared to start
growing this is what we're you know
that's what they uh put it together for
I think L is the one that actually came
up with the seed the Harvest podcast
name and yeah just you know the the idea
of it of you know helping people to do
this so yeah it's grow with the show so
you you you grow with us at the same
time so if you're running into a problem
uh you it's not just us hopefully
there's more people in the community
that you can reach out to and you can
ask them well this is happening with
this genetics so we're all running the
same genetics same time uh so yeah and
we're checking out to see what in
different environments do you know what
I'm saying I'm in Texas El's in Arizona
and Cado Chris is in C you know Colorado
yeah he's in Cado yeah canor uh but yeah
so we you this the whole thing is just a
whole bunch of different environments
different people testing it uh so we
invite you to come on and grow with us
and you if you're scared of growing I
think this is a great opportunity for
you to go like I said you'll you can
grow with a group of people at the same
time the exact same thing uh you're
going to maybe ask somebody what
nutrient lines they're using or whatever
to help you out and yeah if you find out
they're doing the same thing you got
more of a person to uh help you through
or whatever uh but I guarantee you
anybody that you ask that's with our
podcast or one of our you know our
regulars dude they'll they'll definitely
help you out yeah for sure
nice so yeah and then it's how long is
it you guys do about three hours two
hours no no we do an hour some of them
have gone I think we've had a couple
guests on that go hour and a half or so
uh roughly an hour is what we keep or
something uh short and swe yeah short
and sweet it's not super super long uh
like I said if some reason somebody
wants to jump on we we share a link you
can uh jump in whenever you want we try
to share a link regularly so you can
come on and show your grow and so ask
questions and um so yeah like I said
we're there to help you and like I said
it's it's trying to be a community thing
uh it's trying to get more people in and
uh just yeah help them grow weed man
help them grow their own cannabis like I
said uh when we were at this show
everybody we walk everybody walking by
us to go to the the dispensary area and
I'm like stop I'm like dude grow your
own canvas man you never it's so
rewarding and so so great Hest see yeah
we put some hash out for people yeah
yeah yeah yeah I think uh people some
people were definitely thinking it's too
good to be true right for sure for sure
yeah for sure they were like this is a
joke yeah now the one dude finally asked
me he's like what is that that's hash
dude he's like can I take it I said yeah
dude take it take it bro and he was okay
California it's legal yeah yeah yeah he
he was still like while he was grabbing
he was like oh hell something's about to
happen
to me yeah these these ain't even the
right dudes for this tent run somebody
else's tent right now G [ __ ] away
seriously so let's talk about uh
sobriety a little bit for you you know
with with our audience because I feel
like there's a lot of people either
struggling with sobriety they're
interested in how do I get clean how do
I stay clean you're a good example of
someone who can go to a a ree show and
be around alcohol you don't even think
of it uh um that actually took a lot so
if you're struggling dude keep trying
keep trying keep trying um like I said
I've had problems like that um I'm 44
now um since I was 14 so 30 years I've
pretty much well not I've been clean for
a while now but you know what I'm saying
um i' I've struggled with it numerous
times I've tried uh and i' all every
time I was doing that I take a night off
and I just sit home and smoke weed and
that felt so good yeah you know what I'm
saying uh I felt like who I was uh just
from where I came from I felt like that
that is what I had to do uh I felt like
in the morning when I I I drank first
thing in the morning um I'd open up a
bottle and I I'd I'd stare I didn't want
to man I didn't want to drink you know
what I'm saying I think maybe that point
it has to you have to get to a point
where you are [ __ ] sick and tired of
it really uh at that last end I was like
I'd look at that bottle and and i' you
know it's just [ __ ] horrible so yeah
like I said it's and it's not even just
the actual cannabis itself like At first
I just still just you know getting
cannabis from people and that it's
helping me uh but man without the
growing that changes I've never been so
happier in my life I've never really
been so much happier in my life uh like
I said just drinking all the time waking
up with a hangover uh thinking you got
to do these drugs to get through the day
because you got to hangover you're
drinking constantly throughout the day
um it just it's takes a toll on your
body for sure and without cannabis I
would not I would not be where I'm at
for sure so I said yeah I can I can sit
see people drink now uh it doesn't
affect me oh yeah you're around it all
weekend when people drink around us no
probably the first year when I did it
was hard a little bit seeing people uh
I'm seeing people drinking it looks like
they're having a fun time but I
guarantee next morning they're they're
feeling it um you know what I'm saying
and people can have fun on booze I just
don't know how to control myself uh once
the once that train leads the station uh
it's hard to stop it you know what I'm
saying and I was uh Drinker that did not
like to be told to stop I did not like
bottle counting I didn't like you know
what I'm saying all that [ __ ] don't tell
me when to stop don't tell me this yeah
I go how much have you been drinking a
day and I you know I hated it but I mean
that's just people looking out after you
you know what I'm saying people are
concerned because you're you're slowly
killing yourself yeah uh you're you're
polluting your body uh I mean one of the
first things that people would ask me
they're like oh you don't drink I said
no I don't it's for [ __ ] ass sissies
for one thing and uh to me and I iect I
do believe that to a certain degree I
think it makes you weak I think people
consume it too much I think it makes you
weaker um it just it's it's not good for
your body if you booze all the time
you'll you'll definitely feel it in your
body for
sure definitely not for everybody no no
it's def it's not definitely not for me
no more for sure yeah I don't think it
ever really was for me I just like I
said I thought that's what it was yeah I
mean cannabis in general is it makes the
world a better place I think alcohol uh
in a lot of ways does the opposite
unforunately and I think people there
are people that can have a good time on
alcohol and there's nothing wrong I
don't judge people either way no to each
their own to each their own but like so
cannabis definitely makes the world a
better place and for sure 100% I'm all
for making the world a better place and
you know leaving something to the Next
Generation and trying to lead by example
I don't always lead by example I do the
best I can and I think that's we can
strive for the the best we can do and I
think that's okay we're all human beings
we're Nobody's Perfect no nobody's
perfect you know there's perfect is
imperfect yeah for sure for sure I mean
that's that's that's a perfect saying
right there you know what I'm saying
yeah uh yeah I mean that's if you try to
reach Perfection of whatever you're
thinking you're going to drive yourself
crazy you know what I'm saying but I
think the goal is perfection right we
want to we want to strive to be the best
we can be yeah and along the way if you
make mistakes yes you want to improve
always impr gradual Improvement is great
that's the goal is to gradually improve
and maybe you know I drank this weekend
or whatever I'm not I'm trying not to
drink as much so I'm I'm actually
achieving what I'm trying to do is by
not drinking as much no yeah doesn't
drink there's a couple of people online
that I talked to that I I uh I've helped
out that like you know
um he he posted something and he was
like oh [ __ ] I you know so many years
down the drain he posted his drink um
and saw actually we're pretty good
friends now I just told him I said dude
um I said it's not about the the time
that you weren't drinking and that you
just lost it's about what you're gonna
do after this yeah you know what I'm
saying what are you doing at this point
all right you [ __ ] one day up you
drank you probably feel like [ __ ] you
know what I'm saying so use this as a
reminder for one thing and get back at
it and don't [ __ ] drink again and if
it happens again you just you you know
you're a human being and all you can do
is work on yourself and sometimes don't
be too hard on yourself while you're
doing it sometimes to I think that's one
of the best pieces of advice for people
is don't be too hard on yourself uh when
you [ __ ] up as long as you recognize
that you [ __ ] up and made a mistake
and and try to move forward from that
whether it's alcohol or anything well
that's what I'd use as a a CR or an
excuse for when I when I would try to
get clean and sober uh I'd maybe do it
for a little while if I start drinking
or whatever I'm like well [ __ ] it now
you know what I'm saying yeah uh I'm I'm
a drinker you know what I'm saying can't
control myself I went back to it uh so
yeah I like I said you exactly if you
mess up you're not perfect correct it
and try to you know correct it for the
future yeah I'm not a big fan of AA
personally and I think it works for some
people I think it's great for prr uh
yeah me neither I mean maybe here too
cuz like in Texas if you work it over
there and you tell them what I'm doing
they'll you're not working the program
because you're using cannabis or
whatever you can smoke cigarettes yeah
yeah yeah you can smoke you can change
yeah stupid yeah I don't do AA either I
if you need it and there's nothing wrong
with it I think it's great for certain
people I think group some people need
that and I think the structure of it
whatever is perfect for some people is
just not not my cup of tea and I've had
friends that have have had great success
been sober you know for for 20 years
yeah you know from AA and they still go
to meetings and that's great for them
and that works for them and yeah yeah no
I'm not I'm me yeah same thing I'm not
an AA member or I don't go to AA uh yeah
like I said I don't I've tried it before
and um like half the time D half those
people in there are getting sent there
because they're on paper or something so
they have to be there I've done it
before where I've I've been sent there
because I was in trouble and same thing
I've linked up with people and there's
been times where I go there actually
trying to get clean I went out there on
my own and I ended up leaving with
somebody drinking and drugging that
night because you know what I'm saying
you start start people start telling War
Stories and you know what I'm saying
sometimes uh some won't have they try to
tell you don't tell the war stories or
whatnot just talk about what happened
but it's I saying you're with a group of
people everybody's going to do their own
thing and try to do what they want uh
but yeah like I said majority in my
feeling is I guarantee about half those
people are forced to be there or
something so well and I think the it's
the the right path for us it's all
different and there's nothing wrong with
trying everything and seeing what works
I mean obviously you tried all the drugs
and you tried all this stuff so trying
all the different ways to get Sil that's
all right too you it's like there's
nothing wrong with going to church if
you think that God will save you or or
that if you think that maybe that might
be something that will work I mean bring
that's great I mean I think spiritualism
and religion and all these things are
great yeah you know and can be amazing
tools cannabis you can find spiritualism
in cannabis you can yeah you can find a
spiritual path in cannabis or
psychedelics or whatever and there's
nothing wrong with that either all these
things are great uh ways to try to heal
yourself because at the end of the day
we're all just trying to heal ourselves
yeah for sure that's a beautiful thing
too once you can get on the path like
that you're on where you've healed
yourself yeah because it's it's it is
healing and that that's another thing
that's contagious it's like when I see
you being silver I'm like cool I can
hang out with with Ru and I don't have
to drink yeah yeah even though I did
have a couple drinks over the weekend
I'm not going to beat myself up too much
because I had some
beers the the the abuse we give ourself
normally is some of the worst you know
what I'm saying what we tell ourselves
and Y yeah you [ __ ] up you did you
know what I'm saying that dud it's it's
okay you know what I'm saying you'll get
through it dude yeah just try better
next time if that's what you're shooting
for uh it's yeah you you'll get through
it but yeah we're we're always our worst
critic and so it is what it is so one
piece of advice for the younger
generation that you have just do it man
if you want something to do it like I
said I wanted to grow canvas but what I
did is I moved couple I moved my shirts
out of the way out of the closet that
was already my area I hung that light
there and so you just got to do it and
try um if you're not trying what are you
doing you know what I'm saying um I mean
are you just really that content with
what you're already doing and even like
I said I'm love growing cannabis I'm
still not content with whatever I know I
can improve like I said I need to get my
Dy room going I know I could improve on
uh on my dry uh so yeah that's where I
want to get so yeah you have to give it
your all you gotta go for it uh don't
listen to people man if they're trying
to put you down and be negative um don't
listen to the naysayers yeah yeah dude I
mean yeah listen to some people don't
listen to Nay s yeah some people are
they're rooting you on and if they have
good uh you know information for for you
or suggestions take it and try it and if
not sometimes it's not for you you know
what I'm saying uh Don't Be Afraid don't
be afraid to try something you know what
I'm saying nice so yeah get out there
and live your life so if people are
trying to find out more about Rue and
your goofy growing how can they do that
uh you can go to uh ruse goofy growing
on Instagram it's at ruse goofy growing
uh and I also have a a YouTube page ruse
goofy growing as well or you know seed
the Harvest podcast I guarantee you
start putting in seed the Harvest on in
the Youtube it'll pop up uh my other
ones I get Shadow banned a lot you
actually have to type it all out and try
to find me but yeah you can find me
there yeah big shout out big shout out
to the seed to harvest
podcast Saturdays 5:30 Central 5:30
Central Pacific is a little different
yeah yeah we off two hours so it's 3:30
yeah yeah 3:30 in California so if
you're in California on the west coast
3:30 you guys have a great podcast thank
you to come on one of these days again
yes sir good one thank you so much for
coming on the show today oh thank you
thank you I appreciate it and thanks for
going to ree thanks for supporting the
brand man oh man I uh no problem on
supporting the brand the brand is great
I love your genetics I fell in love with
them right off the bat uh so yeah much
love to you and everything you've done
and all you know you and Lady loud have
taking care of me all weekend long uh I
couldn't ask for any a better H Hospital
hospitality and man I love y'all both
and thank y'all absolutely thank you
[Music]