[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James loud
podcast and today our special guest is
Julie from skunk magazine how are you
doing today Julie I'm doing great good
to be with you James good to have you
here we've been talking about doing this
for a while I'm glad we finally got to
catch up yeah it's awesome I remember
being here like a year and a half ago
two years years time flies when you
first had it and it's just looking
amazing building a facility is no joke
people don't understand it takes twice
as much money and takes twice as long as
you typically start out thinking it's
going to so true and when you want to do
it right you're a long game person and
so am I right and so you take your time
slow and steady 100% and develop it
proper and uh good things take time so
very happy for you James though it's
looking good in here life's an adventure
it's about it's about the journey not
the destination you know cuz the
destination is death true no one gets
out of here alive no well that not that
we know of yeah right my favorite
teacher says it's all about becoming the
master dancer so you can dance with
everything that life throws at you yeah
and it's just a dance you know there's
all kinds of dances for sure but yeah um
I think enduring pain and appreciating
the struggle is part of the journey and
as I've got older that's the one thing
I've learned is the struggle is where
it's at yeah I just did a video about it
about how the worthy opponent or the
worthy Tyrant or things that cross us or
challenge us yeah is actually what
brings out our greatest Soul expression
sure and you don't run from it there's a
sense I'm almost 50 I'm 47 and so I've
been feeling also that same thing where
you kind of lean into it the pain and
the challenge and the intensity because
you know what's coming is the same I
always say that the measure of the
challenge matches the measure of the
gift your enemies make you stronger they
do y they do and so in that I think in
that mentality you can be a Victor in
every situation never a victim
absolutely yeah yeah that's very cool
yeah getting older has
it it's so funny because getting older
definitely has its benefits too I mean
when I was younger when I was 18 I
thought the
age I'm at right now was so old and now
that I'm at that age I'm like it's not
that old but I know we're the same age
too so it's funny I know it's a trip I
mean I think that cannabis Keeps Us
young even though I say that the
Cannabis industry ages you in dog years
sure and I definitely look a lot older
than when we first met yeah um but I
also think there's a sense of
youthfulness that comes from just being
with the plant and the kind of the
Purity not all the B [ __ ] of the
industry but the Purity yeah of that
passion for the plant as you always do
your hashtag that's what keeps us young
and vibrant and connected and
enthusiastic yeah I think we're blessed
in to be in an industry that you can be
extremely passionate about and I think
the more you put into it the more you
get back and whatever you do in life if
you're passionate about it you're going
to be good at it good at it at a certain
point I think so yeah just continue
see yeah it's it's all about
perseverance it's all about not stopping
yeah this industry is rough is people
are like you know how the [ __ ] you know
do you do this with the magazine and you
know I just say don't stop yeah because
no matter what happens if you don't stop
and you stay consistent you're going to
hit your mark and yeah I'm definitely
feeling that and experiencing that and
it's like you're you're your own
constant yeah you're your own Center in
the storm not circumstance not people
not situations it's you yeah and I feel
like that's also the kind of deep
Medicine of the plant too and I'm
finding that in business kind of very
cool that the spiritual and the business
are merging into one and and that's what
I feel the Renaissance that I always
talk about is about yeah that was going
to be the subject for the podcast was
the green Renaissance cuz I think you
you coined that term
and a large majority of the industry
definitely can relate to the green
Renaissance movement especially the the
people in the industry that were here
before
legalization that they even before you
know Pro 215 in medical but like that
green Renaissance movement which it is
you know I think there's a lot of us
that can relate to that I mean the newer
generation maybe they see it but they
aren't necessarily the ones who created
it they can jump on board right right
right yeah no I mean it's pretty
profound James because you know I became
a certified herbalist 26 years ago and
that's when I got key into just from my
background with art and culture and
studying Global theologies you know I
felt as a young woman that you know
Mother Earth was propagating
Consciousness with her plants and I saw
that the Psychedelic movement and the
Canabis movement the counterculture
movement in general over the last
century and a quarter was really about
these kind of counterculture Rebels
through time that were pushing the
envelope open and what the commonality
was was working with the plants right
and the plants opening up their
Consciousness and then I found it really
fascinating that a lot of these people
ended up being Visionaries who were
creating new styles of business new
styles of companies and how companies
you know the idea of conscious Commerce
or sacred Commerce that started emerging
from the hippies and you know it's just
carrying through time and the hippies
and the yippies yeah exactly and so you
know 12 years ago when I came into skunk
and I had the opportunity to really coin
it um I wanted to contrast that the
green Rush even though we were all
dealing with it and are still dealing
with it and we'll be dealing with it for
the next 10 20 years as prohibition
fully ends and we deal with the Quagmire
of
legalization I just kept feeling like we
need to talk about the Renaissance we
need to talk about what's actually
happening that we're in the midst of a
second Renaissance and back then it was
like who's this crazy [ __ ] [ __ ]
talking about a Renaissance yeah but now
oh my goodness it's like extremely
relevant and everybody that I'm speaking
to no matter where I go in the world is
feeling it and seeing it and that's been
really profound it's almost as big as
the separation between the right and the
left right because I feel like we were
all Blended more so before
2020 and then covid happened and there
was this big separation and I feel like
that
separation uh left and right it's not
the same as with the green Renaissance
it's you know but it is there it is and
there is a separation there's a sh
you're seeing it more so because I feel
like everybody before
2018 was really part of that movement
right to build it up it was illegal
people were pushing boundaries and now
we're seeing people that are in it for
the money or people that never saw that
side of it they never saw the struggle
they never saw people going to jail for
20 years or 40 years or whatever it is
right and so there's a different
perspective and I think moving forward
it's just great to be able to remind the
younger generation and the people that
are getting into the industry that have
only been here for four years that these
are the struggles that we had to go
through and oral history of cannabis
that's why we're doing this show you
have skunk magazine now yeah and skunk
magazine is an oral history of cannabis
something that a hundred years from now
we can look back on and go okay Mila
Jansen for example she was special and
this is why she was special and also the
crazy times you know I feel like there's
so much stuff that's counterintuitive
that people are like oh man this this
this and actually it's the complete
opposite but yeah yeah it's it's quite
fascinating I mean being a part of you
know I've been in the industry for 18
years and part of the global space right
so I got to see all the different
marketplaces and all the different
movements in unique countries unique
states but with skunk when I came in 12
years ago being a historian or telling
stories throughout the last 12 years
it's pretty profound and it's it's
suited to me because I like to think of
things in terms of decades and centuries
of time mhm mhm and certainly when you
were talking about the pandemic it's a
parallel in the last Renaissance 20
million died in the black plague and
that caused the shakeup of church and
state and allowed people to start to
find ways to gain wealth gain land gain
upward mobility in the economic class
and it's similar and different the
reason why I call it green is because
this Renaissance is really about people
becoming Earth connected again and
connected to the plants under
understanding how sustainable how
powerful and self-sufficient we really
can be yeah um when we learn uh that we
are stewards we're we're meant to
practice husbandry we're meant to live
in in communion with the Earth and with
the seasons and yeah it's been
fascinating to kind of hold that line
yeah for something so pure and so
connected with the heart and what's real
and what's true amidst all the craziness
of this industry and then also just stay
connected with the purity of the
storytelling based upon Merit we're not
a payto playay you know people can't
just buy their way in it's about Merit
yeah and like you said Nila for instance
has greatly inspired me as a woman in
business and as a woman just devoted to
the plants yeah she's like Benjamin
Button she keeps getting younger it's
wild yeah yeah yeah she's amazing and so
for me it just brings me great pleasure
when I took over creatively I really got
to evolve the magazine I took the purest
Parts but I started representing men and
women equally as Educators which can be
challenging because there aren't as many
female breeders or female Growers yet
and then just all the people around you
know black latino native Asian
lgbtq and a rich a rich culture of
everybody speaking in the space um you
know skunk isn't a homogeneous voice
it's really about spotlighting thought
leaders and Visionaries globally and
having them all speak in the space and
that just yeah it's um it's amazing and
it just it's all happened because the
universe and the plants led me here you
know yeah if you listen to the plant it
speaks yeah that's it that's my secret
sauce for sure I just listen within we
live in a really interesting time you
know I think they were talking about
like walking barefoot being so hippie
dippy 20 years ago now we got guys like
Gary bre uh who's talking about
grounding now yeah and it's not so
hippie anymore there's proven proven
studies that actually grounding uh is
good for you and it used to be such a
hippie dippy thing and now a lot of
things are going in that direction and
we're having science backup stuff that
we once thought was just really strange
and and different and yeah pretty
amazing times yeah no I I really we
truly are in a Renaissance and you know
I agree James it's been really
gratifying because when I was young
woman and studying herbology I learned a
lot of the kind of things that were not
really looked at from society like
sitting down and communing with the
plants yeah speaking to the plants one
of my courses we went out and we looked
at the genetic signature of the plant
and we sat with the plant and we let
this the plant speak to us about what
its medicine was and I think that a lot
of these things that seem so strange the
Renaissance is really
it's really fascinating to see how so
many people are coming out with it yeah
and as as you said science is now
backing it sure even Organics what I've
been really pleased about is like I said
I've been talking about Organics even
before I got into cannabis 18 years ago
I was fighting for organic textiles and
farm to table and organic farming and
sustainable
practices and um it's just fascinating
to me especially in the industry right
now back you know skunk is the only
cannabis magazine which many people
don't know is the only cannabis magazine
in the world devoted to Organics which
trips me out that we're the only one but
that's the truth and you know back 15
years ago it was definitely French and
it's still in the minority it's not the
norm most people are still using salts
but what I've seen is that a lot of the
quickening that's happening over the
last five years is a lot of people are
abandoning salts not because they
necessarily care about about Mother
Earth or the soils and the waterways
which we do but because they see the
science because they see the yields
because they see the turps and it's like
what you don't want to make money you
have a problem with making more money
and they don't give a [ __ ] about Mother
Earth but they want to make more money
and it's pretty crazy to see all of
these BigTime indoor Growers yeah
abandoning their salt programs and
moving into the future and seeing that
it's actually giving them better results
it's pretty gratifying yeah and I think
there's a happy medium like the Sanic
model where it's like you can use salts
you can do stuff I think at the end of
the day we want to give the plant what
it deserves to represent the best
version of itself yeah and I'm I'm you
know I believe in salt and I believe in
organic and I believe that it's all okay
I Do Love Organic if I'm going to smoke
stuff I I like smoking organic flour
just up at can Organics they grew some
amazing
amazing stuff but I also have friends
that grow with Coco and use uh inputs
that are also organic that do really
good yeah it's funny and on a commercial
scale I think there's a happy medium
somewhere in the middle yeah I mean I'm
not gonna you know I'm I'm about the
future and how we're evolving towards
and that's fine and and at the same time
I'm realistic about the industry yeah so
and I know we've gotten into this
conversation before my job is to hold a
standard of the future always said skunk
is a magazine of the future yeah I'm not
necessarily just covering culture I'm
creating culture I'm a culture maker
right and so my responsibility is is
towards Mother Earth and Humanity right
not just towards what works now or
what's worked in the past and what
performs sure in my mind James we're
like coming out of 125 years of
Prohibition yeah and what prohibition
did to farming uh and agriculture
culture in general and how we had to
approach it and go indoors which many
people around the world they're going to
have to grow indoors so I'm not you know
to me the epitome is yes if you can have
outdoor organic Sun grown flow it's
purest with mother nature but I'm also
not a Fanatic in that sense I want to
see I guess cleaner and more sustainable
growing practices across the board right
and just more Consciousness that oh what
happens Downstream from you yeah
100% that's it and to me it's like we
want to encourage people of of all
different types of growing yeah indoor
outdoor light dep Greenhouse you name it
Hydro I want to see if there's ways that
we can do things more sustainably and to
me it's a conversation and it's an
evolution yeah and it's education and I
think I I would guess that the majority
of people don't even know that the
reason we're growing indoors is because
of prohibition yeah so so it's so funny
because with without prohibition we may
all just still be going outside or we
wouldn't have gotten here so quickly and
we'd be behind technology wise but
people started growing to hide their
plants started growing indoors 100% and
uh yeah and and that's where I like to
go to the root of things and think about
that and then think about how I can
respond to that yeah versus just talking
about the effect right and so going to
the roote yeah you see the origin of
that was that and that's what why I'm
fascinated with oh well if we were just
doing this because it wasn't allowed
because we were hiding yeah and then all
the input output old system of salts
came into being from that that's fine we
don't need to shame or you know
denigrate the past but it's like okay
well as we free ourselves up can we
continue to evolve can we continue to
you know do better in general cuz I
believe James you know we're at a
Crossroads when I think about the
Renaissance it's like I know that we
have the intelligence and the technology
to be regenerative in in practically
every industry around the world that's
the truth the main thing that holds us
back as a society is not desire it's not
intelligence it's not the capability
it's the corruption and greed yeah uh
we're styed a bit by the fact that
corporations are kind of ruling our
governments and sty meing I think that
that forward progression yeah at some
point it's going to push to the edge and
push over and I do see that um but you
know we're seeing organic farming from
the you know the hippies and the 60s it
was like very Fringe yeah and now every
Market you go on to has an organic
section yeah the 80s and 90s and for
Organics was rough you know but I think
the 60s and70s is where it started and
gone back and forth with it but now I
would say the most of my friends eat
organic or mostly organic yeah and
people are aware you know it's aess and
I and it just takes Decades of time and
I know you know there's some things
happening on the planet that are not
going to wait that long yeah and it is
what it is but for my part you know I'm
devoted till the end of my days to
helping Foster more sustainable
regenerative practices and I use the
term organic but I I want you know
everybody know that organic is kind of a
bastardized term yeah and I heard you
use the term Sanic and I've talked with
different scientists I I think that
we're going to continue to evolve our
understandings and our vernaculars
myself included and skunk wants to
evolve with it you know so I just think
it's an evolution James I don't think
that anything is really set in stone no
and we're just learning how to optimize
the plants and genetics too like we're
learning about genetics and where they
should be grown especially when you look
at outdoors and what's optimal for what
region and you know understanding
breeding lines more absolutely you know
we're just scratching the surface of all
that and some of the big Pharma
companies they they've they're they're a
little bit ahead of us but like as a
whole we're sharing information we share
it in Skunk magazine I got my breeding
book yeah got all kinds of stuff so
there's information out there for people
that are really looking for it and this
is the kind of stuff that was it's this
is the beauty of the internet right
there's a whole dark side to the
internet and all the other stuff but the
beauty of the internet is sharing
information and if you know where to go
to get reliable information it can be an
amazing thing yeah I think so and I I
often say that the Shadow and light work
together it's universal law I'm very
into hermetic principles and one of
those principles is just that those two
polarities are always in Union yeah and
so they work together to birth new
realities yeah and you know it's just
like the womb and the the masculine
principle you know creates life and as
gardeners and Farmers people know you
know you're working with the Shadow and
light to to create a balance and to
birth you know your plants your food and
so yeah I like to think of that too that
you know we are in a a a land of Shadow
and light and there's a lot of Shadow
that's happening and amidst that there's
great
Amazing Discoveries of just light and
and Consciousness and I I think that
that is what always excites me and keeps
me going
yeah is is just keep pushing forward and
keep writing um this Evolution and help
in any way you can yeah to help the good
that's being fostered right yeah yeah so
spannabis this year was amazing oh I
love it it's a great event and this was
the biggest turnout in a long long time
yeah it felt really just pulsing with
energy and I've gone that I think that
was my 15th one yeah I've been going for
a very long time um my grandmother is
from Spain from Catalan um she was
southern France Northern Spain and she
spoke Spanish English French and Catalan
when she was growing up so whenever I go
back it's just like it's breathing and
it the food you know I grew up eating
Toria Espanola and P Tom and all the the
different coma I was like a part of my
life MH and so yeah just being there
just feels so wonderful and even with
the conservative
backlash that's happening well there is
conservative backlash for sure it was
ridiculous you could feel it there I
mean they they did raids the night
before the event just to flex like that
was their Flex like were in charge yeah
and it is what it is but there was I
don't know 60,000 people that were in
Barcelona not all of them went to the
event even but they were people were
everywhere yeah people passionate from
Cannabis from all over the world going
there to to hang out and have a good
time and learn about stuff uh among
other things smoke learn about stuff see
what the latest and greatest and it's
like this Collective energy and it was
just so bright this year uh postco it
was kind of rough coming back in and now
there's this New Hope and it's not kind
of you don't feel it here in California
as much there's like people are like
depressed about the industry there's a
lot of negative and over there you see
like everybody who went felt the
positive because people were so excited
about the industry so excited I mean I
feel like over in Europe there's like
this new turn of things Germany going
legal Portugal really you know pushing
for they you know they're doing
production over there that's going to go
International that's uh pretty amazing
and so the the energy is definitely
different over there and it's nice and
refreshing and I feel like bringing that
back to California bringing that back to
the United States is great is then it
motivates people all over again like
There's Hope absolutely James 100% I
mean what I've been feeling and what
I've been saying kind of over the last
six seven years yeah is that in any one
state or country you're going to be
dealing with the Quagmire of
legalization which can be extremely
depressing yeah and you're dealing with
genocide of farmers genocide of small
mom and pop businesses and take your
pick I mean any country or state they
all have their kind of own version of
asinine laws and over taxation
overregulation I'm hopeful for Germany I
got on paper it looks kind of very cool
it looks better than a lot of what we've
seen out there but what I've been
telling people for a long time is don't
be entrenched yeah if you can if you get
to the level where you can be a global
educator and have Global projects and
different Global things happening that
this is a wonderful way to protect
yourself right and I'm constantly
encouraging because I'm a brand
incubator I'm in service to Brands
Rising yeah to the next level and a lot
of times I'll advise people in any way
you can find a way to be a global
educator especially if you've given 20
30 years to this industry and to the
plant find a way to reach out even if
you remain doing Commerce in one state
one country but find a way to reach out
and extend your voice because I feel
like that's going to be the thing that
gives you lasting staying power and
those brands that are able to do that
Journey will I believe exist for a very
long you know the next several decades
if they want well it's all about Legacy
I think as you get older it's like what
do you want to leave to the Next
Generation you know which brings to the
next subject that brings us to the next
subject that I had which was the Next
Generation Sage yes we've got Sage so
I've seen Sage grow up your son's Sage
I've seen him grow up in the
industry uh you know from being this
cute little kid to actually becoming a
man who you know he's doing extract he
he's worked with humble seeds you know
he's kind of like seen it all and he's
finding himself and so we want to do a
podcast with him specifically and a
couple other the younger guys kind of
show where they are now yeah because he
has a long future in this industry and
he is the next generation and it's great
seeing somebody like Sage who is very
passionate about cannabis but sees the
business side of it as well yeah he's a
tourus and so he's just very practical
and you know he grew out 181 plants this
last season by himself yielded 71 pounds
moved them all at 600 a pound which was
a huge accomplishment considering the
climate and there were dark moments
where we talked and it was like you know
just [ __ ] can continue whatever you do
don't stop and stay with it and it was a
hard season too cuz it was a late start
wet season and then had to finish early
cuz it was wet rain and so it was
particularly challenging season as well
so I was proud of him but it wasn't
sunshine and rainbows and you know he's
seen I've raised him in a very um I
think old world way uh which we
connected on um but helping him to do a
lot of apprenticeship helping him I
pulled him out of conventional School
even though he went to a charter school
and he went to a constructivism school W
which was learned by doing but because I
raised him when I was a young mom I was
studying herbology and I raised him on
the land and I taught him a lot of
survival skills and you know how to
build fire how to build shelter how to
eat in forage wild edibles and how to
make his own medicine and heal himself I
taught him those things as a young
person and taught him also a lot of
practical things and I believe in that I
think that it's missing a lot from our
world right now but teaching our young
people how to cook how to balance their
budget how to save money how to go out
and shop responsibly had to have respect
you know for the dollar Basics too these
are the basics that aren't taught I mean
Common Sense isn't common unfortunately
but yeah the younger generation those
are the things you know it's like they
spend like all day in school but they
don't ever learn that and I've really
been a big believer and I think the
Renaissance definitely has to happen
within education because we know so much
yeah about how we have different styles
of Learners and a lot of people in
cannabis frankly are kinesthetic
Learners they learn by doing and they
need apprenticeship that's why growing
plants is so beneficial to younger
people whether you're growing tomatoes
or whether you're growing cannabis yeah
or whatever you're growing because you
learn commitment you learn
uh dedication and you learn that it's
not about you it's about what that plant
needs if you want to be successful you
have to be regimen you have to be able
to wake up and water the plant when the
plant needs water or give that plant
whatever it needs and sometimes your
needs or wants have to come second
totally and so that's what I love about
growing that's like one of the most
amazing things and so these younger
generation kids they all need to grow
whether it's tomatoes in their backyard
grow some peas some some herbs whatever
it is I think get connected to the land
again we talk about that a lot is
getting that connection back to the
Earth to the soil 100 and uh you know I
think that's one of the biggest problems
is the disconnect with that it's true
that's why I chose a charter school for
sage because they had a whole gardening
program yeah and they taught the kids it
was actually a a course and they grew
their own food and they did their own
maintenance of the garden and and uh it
helped me so that when I when he came
home then he had understandings of
things that I was ready to teach him but
I definitely would encourage you know
all parents to take take hold of that
for your kids and for yourself because
it does bring so much joy when we do
spend time putting our hands in the soil
and it is extremely healing and it's
cool because science is really proving
it yeah that scientifically we can now
prove that getting all of those microbes
and and working with the microbiome is
actually healing to our person and to
our own uh you know yes our own health
ex discipline aspect of it is just so
great and then it's so rewarding to be
able to eat something that you grew
smoke something that you consume it in
one way or another but like seeing it
from the very beginning to the end where
there's no disconnect where you saw that
and if you had problems you know you see
the problems at the end too oh I felt
like you know I this conversation with
sage but I felt like he grew so much in
ways that you can't learn from anybody
else and you can't learn it from your
parent just telling you you know it
really is about your ass being on the
line you're on the frying pan and you've
got to [ __ ] deliver for yourself for
the plants for your project and it it
does develop you it does develop you
greatly I agree James and I think it was
beautiful to watch uh you know and also
give space right give space to him and
yeah I mean it was an ass kicker and
it's just it's incredible because now he
knows what he can do now you you learn
how strong you are you learn how capable
you are Yeah by not turning away and
staying the course till the very end and
doing a job well done and finishing
failing failing a lot failing a lot
failing is a part of life that's it's
one of the most looking back failure is
one of the most important parts of life
because is you can't be good at
everything it's not god-given talent
that makes you successful it's failing
and getting back up and doing it again
and keeping keeping on and I think
that's just so important to experience
failure and experience loss and struggle
and all those amazing things but
especially failure it's okay to fail
it's okay to try something and fail it's
okay if you're older and you fail you
just got to get back up and keep on
getting up and some people give up and
that's really sad yeah
I I agree you know I went through a
battle uh last year that I'm not really
talking about just yet but I did find
that again I mean I was I know this
because I've read so many you know text
sacred texts that talk about the hero's
journey or the heroine's journey and how
you know being obliterated yeah is what
actually makes you into the greatest
expression of your soul yeah and I I was
talking actually with Nikki from Nikki
and Swami um and she's a friend I was
talking with her this morning and was
reminded of the Bhagavad Gita and how
Shiva um talked to Hanuman and ravana
and said that you know whoever wants to
play the hero or the villain the villain
will repeat many less
lifetimes and it always spoke to me that
the the villain or the person that
crosses you is sacred because it does
make you and I think that I'm stronger
than than I've ever been and it doesn't
matter what comes my way I know that I
can attend like I have the strongest sea
legs James that I've ever had in my life
and it was from the obliteration it was
from really going to zero and I think a
lot of people in the industry are facing
that through these different kind of
genocidal moments in legalization and
what we've had to go through to try and
exist in this industry that's just so
tumultuous yeah so I say it not just for
myself but for all of us that don't fear
like you're saying don't fear the
obliteration Don't Fear The failure and
understand that what was within you that
made you create something beautiful is
within you and nothing can take it away
from you no circumstance no person and
that you can create it again nobody can
take what's inside of you away from you
and I think that there's that strength
now that I have to know that that Center
can is Untouchable it's Untouchable by
circumstance and no matter where I go
I'll do the work that I'm doing and I
think that that's true for a lot of
people that have been able to withstand
test after test yeah and some days you
just got to get up and you got to get up
in the morning and show up for yourself
right and don't worry about your friends
don't worry about other people show up
you know and sometimes it's being
present and I think present is such a
big thing too uh because we can all live
in the future and think of how great it
could be or how bad it was but sometimes
we just got to focus on right now and
today and how do we make this day the
best it could be 100% present moment
Consciousness is that's my practice I
mean maybe people don't know some people
do in the industry but my I was in the
health and wellness Industries in yoga
industry I ran a yoga studio and taught
yoga to kids and studied a lot of the
sacred text and my practice is present
moment practice Yeah and in the present
moment practice I do think it's a very
much a secret sauce and business as well
because while everybody's getting
distracted by what other people are
doing or you know what's going to happen
in the future or what happened in the
past if you're in the present there's
always opportunity in the present
there's always treasure in the present
and if you're present and you're
listening you will get guidance on how
to move through and where to go who to
talk to where to be what to do the the
inner guidance system has answers every
second of the day and I think that when
we cultivate presence and that's really
my devotion James you know skunk is
definitely teaching people to grow fire
weed with fire genetics and that's our
backbone yeah but underneath that
there's definitely this feeling of
seeding Consciousness right so that more
and more people can access that for
themselves because it's available to
each individual yeah and I think it's so
powerful to know that the guidance is
always there uh I think of the bork song
her song All is full of love but she
speaks about how love is there for us
247 but if you're not picking up the
phone if your doors are shut if your
windows are shut if you're cutting
yourself off then you're cutting
yourself off from that which is
available for you 247 right and and it's
available for everyone no one's exempt
and so I do like that and I do want to
in my further work as I continue to go
um I'm definitely going to be working on
and I'm writing couple books and I want
to do more of that work as I continue to
stabilize skunk but those Worlds Of
Consciousness and commerce yeah and
plant medicine merging together in Union
not compartmentalized not separate that
they're in Union symbiotic yeah and that
there's this whole
right that we can all feel from like you
said it there's no place to arrive
there's no end goal we're just present
and we're on the journey yeah and we're
doing the next thing that we need to do
each step of the way you got to enjoy
the journey yeah I it's an amazing it's
an amazing experience once you can look
at it from that perspective too and I
think it it makes the tough times seem
less tough I think so I found levity I'm
a very um I think serious person and
very
sincere uh in in how I approach things
and yet you know the universe is is
really always encouraging us to I think
find levity and and kind of relax into
the Divine Comedy of it and and also
just attend you know attend with
discipline and sincerity to our task but
yeah James I I do think I mean and they
talk about it that I think that
transition from 40s and to 50s there is
an invitation if you've done your work
and you've done your inner work no
matter what field you're in no matter
where you are that there is a sense of
uh peace that can come from just being
present I agree yeah well and I think
going into my 40s is when I became a
better Storyteller and I see that with a
lot of my friends that are transitioning
from their 40s to 50s it's like when you
become a Storyteller because you've
experienced so much you can tell stories
and there may be some genetic side to
that where
uh we it's by Design so that we can tell
the younger generation this is what you
need to do to be successful or this is
what you need to do to stay alive in
business and other things but uh it's
amaz my book I would never wrote a book
in my 20s I would I never thought I
would write a book and then writing a
textbook it's pretty wild yeah uh and
then you guys have a magazine I've
written some articles over over the last
and I want you to participate in the
next issue I want to put an excerpt in
there but yeah I do and I I think
looking at nature I like nature to
inform me in life I think it's so cool
and what you just said about nature I
think of like the the trees that die and
they call them nurse trees but I learned
how they give and are giving certain n
nutrients that are needed to each
individual tree they'll give themselves
yeah to nourish their growth right and I
think that that's when we feel Joy I
think that the more we can I I forget
who said it if it was Joseph Campbell
but it was the idea that if you align
yourself to
Nature is the goal through observation
and that really is the ancient art of
learning yeah and study was through
observation and through observing nature
then we got the insight and the wisdom
and I feel like that is the Renaissance
too is those of us that are kind of
Renaissance people you're a renaissance
man I'm a Renaissance woman is that
we're the embodiments of it and in the
listening to Nature she's guiding us on
how to do things more like her more in a
better way and I think about that in
business a lot that we are strengthening
the my silal network and that's what I'm
doing with kind of the expansion that
I'm doing and different Revenue
generating streams and the way that I'm
doing that right now is definitely
attempting to model myself off of nature
yeah we live in such an amazing time I I
think it's just with technology we're
we're in the infancy of some of it and
we're long past that in other aspects of
it medicine we're just starting to
scratch the surface and we're going to
back to plant medicine yeah which is
amazing we're undoing
rockefeller's you know campaign of
ignorance you know that's profound to me
cuz like l literally I think on the
first class of herb school when I was
like 22 right
23 um they said you know Rockefeller he
went after the Apothecary and the
apothecarist his campaign was successful
he formed the American Medical
Association and he started pushing pills
yeah and they started to go down you
know and get herbs and plants say from
South America but then they would create
isolates they would isolate a
constituent they would concentrate that
constituent and that's why you know
people don't know but there's all the
Pharmaceuticals they have those crazy
warnings yeah because all the natural
plant buffers and the whole plant
medicine was taken away and so I learned
about Rockefellers harm and then I
learned also about the harm of isolates
yeah and how people became disconnected
from nature through that process not
knowing where things came from whereas
when you went into the Apothecary you
could see the tea or the tincture and
which plant it was from and so I see a
returning to that and I see again it's
exciting more and more people that are
going to get off of pharmaceuticals or
at least learn I'm not saying I'm not a
fanatical person so I'm not saying all
Pharmaceuticals are bad or all
allopathic medicine is bad yeah I'm more
of the modern and the ancient coming
together in Union yeah and I I think a
lot of times in modern medicine we're
treating symptoms than going to the root
of the problem and that that that's with
politics that's with medicine that's
with everything and it's so I I think a
lot of times I go to the the
counterintuitive side of stuff but it
seems the opposite of what it really is
and sometimes we just look at that
symptom is that's the problem and really
we have to go much deeper to the root of
the problem yeah and throughout history
it's been like that I mean we're
fighting
issues uh we've been fighting issues
forever throughout time yeah you know
and but that is the doing of the harm
and I think that you know this second
Renaissance is about going to the root
of things yeah and that we actually have
the technology like you're talking about
the tech the light side of this
technology and I've always said like to
fear the internet or to fear AI is to
fear ourselves in the sense that we are
that our brain is that and we were
talking when you're talking about kind
of
other perceptions or sensory perceptions
that we have beyond our five senses and
we do have them you know we are able to
communicate
non-verbally uh you know I've always
said that love is akin to light because
love travels at the speed of light yeah
if I think of you you feel it in a in a
split second and then you'll call me or
say something or you know that I was
thinking of you because you'll think
about me too this is all happening but
it's been so uh pushed down because they
didn't want us yeah to be as capable as
that right so now it's just part of us
all kind of coming to
remembering taking the stigma away from
what we just naturally do well yeah and
we talk about vibrations and love being
uh powerful vibration but the only
vibration that's more powerful than love
is authenticity oh my gosh that's so
funny I read that article yeah I that's
so funny that that made a huge impact on
me because uh for me when I read that it
was just a few like maybe it was a
couple months ago and it really spoke to
something deep because in all these
tests I think that what we're finding
I've always believed that like cannabis
you talk about Bob Marley and how he
said the herb reveals you to yourself
right and I always told Sage when he
started in biing I'm like listen the
plant is going to reveal you to yourself
and what she reveals you have to do the
work you have to integrate the lessons
that she's showing you you you can't
just use her and then not do the work
because she's encouraging you on how to
keep rising and I think that um you know
that's really what's happening is that
there's this this opportunity that not
only is she encouraging us to be
conscious but deeper than that is this
feeling of self-love and unconditional
love yeah because I've realized now as
an older
woman um that unconditional love of self
is really the practice because when we
get into a space of unconditionally
loving ourselves first off we can make
it through anything and then second off
we can actually be of service to our
community and be loving to our community
in a way where we're not expecting
anything from anybody we don't need
anything from anybody right but we can
just show up in our wholeness and be
present and the root of that is the
unconditional love and acceptance of
self and that to me is authenticity yeah
you can't be authentic if you don't
fully love yourself there's something
there there's something off and it's you
know I think a lot of people deal with
it and I have a lot of compassion myself
included of impostor syndrome or just
kind of not accepting the self or
judging or berading the self and I think
that that also as we get seasoned and as
we age hope if we're doing our work we
come into a space where we do accept
ourselves completely and I do accept
myself completely my strengths my
weaknesses my failures my successes and
in that unconditional loving I feel like
I can really be relaxed and authentic
and I'll actually do good for my
community yeah it's amazing I know it is
really cool so we are going to take a
moment and we are going to talk about my
good friend Dave mesford who uh is
struggling with cancer right now we we
filmed the podcast episode but he gave
me some special flower which I want to
share with you it's called Blue 13 oh my
gosh Dave it is amazing he's just a
great person we love you Dave and his
best bud Vivien mCP our managing
editor Vivien has been you know keeping
me
posted and sharing with me uh everything
that's been happening with Dave and I
just um my heart goes out to him he's
such a special fellow and I wish he
wasn't um leaving us so soon and yeah
it's been a three-year struggle yeah a
three-year uphill battle with cancer and
he's a fighter he's lived a lot longer
than the doctor said he would yeah uh
and it's sad but I went to see him and
he gave me the last jar of his Blue 13
uh blue
Crow Organics is his
brand uh and the flower is special so I
get a lot of I get a lot of flower from
people all over and everybody thinks
their stuff is special and Dave didn't
have to tell me this stuff was special
you can smell it it has an amazing
blueberry nose but the effect more than
anything is what I really like about
this got some pining in there too it has
a lot of good stuff I really like that
that's
beautiful and I'd like to
cover as a as a thank you to
Dave and Dave is is a great great guy
he's a great photographer he helped
start
canacon uh uh Hempfest he worked with
Hempfest he was a volunteer for many
years uh he took the first photo of me
when I was in high times in
2012 and he's also a breeder and a
grower and very passionate he's a
revolutionary in his own right and uh a
really good guy and he's always excited
to talk about flower and cannabis and
everything else seeds breeding storing
pollen he's special he is special the
flow is
special the effect of the flow is really
special and the flavor and uh the flavor
kind of matches the effect it's a
strange thing to say because we're
talking about two different perceptions
but the flavor is uh mild but turpy
uhhuh but it has this nice blueberry
like that coats your mouth and just
stays with you yeah and it's in my upper
palette there's this sense of like Pine
like a pine forest and then there's
blueberry yeah on the tongue yeah it's
complex it's not just one thing but even
the effect is like
uh it's it's not a super super long
effect but it's it's really enjoyable
and I feel like it's one of those things
I could smoke all day long and just be
happy I felt yeah I feel like a
brightening right away and it's one of
those ones it doesn't get you tight
behind the eyes it's very productive and
yeah Alison Drayson she really likes it
as well that's yummy so yeah we're GNA
get this this strain out there to people
well let's do a strain report in the
next issue let's do something in homage
to Dave uh I've been talking with Vivian
about it as well so let's do something
special I know he would be so happy to
see uh his herb come out and and
absolutely he took the photo on the back
of the book that is the Blue 13 male
that's on the back uh special stuff he
he contributed a whole bunch of photos
and he's just a great great all round
great guy so that's awesome well let's
celebrate him absolutely he deserves to
be celebrated yeah yeah I love
celebrating the conscious men in the
industry I really do for all of us our
time will come to an end at some point
and you know there's people like Dave
who are really revolutionaries and have
been advocates for the plant and uh you
know it's it's great and to be able to
record his story was an amazing thing to
be able to film a podcast with him I
think we got three hours of footage
and I got some great stories and you
know I love it and there's so many
people that I've known in the last 30
years where I didn't get their story so
I'm glad I had the opportunity to be
able to get that one that's a huge gift
and it does I mean honestly it brings
healing I I'm I'm serious when I say
that I really like covering the
conscious men in the industry because it
does bring healing to the whole
Community to see Men of Integrity men
who kept their word men who were
protectors men who were servants to
their Community it's so beautiful to
celebrate them because it's not only
about them it's about all of the young
men and women coming up being nourished
by that and our own Community being
nourished by that so yeah I am I am it's
a gift and I'm I'm very happy that
Vivian has had time to slow down with
him and be with him I mean what a gift
to exit in that way um my grandmother
mother just passed and we were able to
be with her and Surround her with love
as she journeyed um and I just love it I
just think that that's so wonderful to
have um a conscious transition yeah
that's surrounded by everyone you love
it's such a blessing not everybody gets
that not everybody gets that for sure
and it's just it yeah I mean we live in
an amazing time with cannabis being
where it's at where we can openly talk
about it and so it's great to be able to
get these stories and and be able to
pass on stuff for the Next Generation as
well yes it is yeah absolutely we got to
keep going absolutely so skunk magazine
is special in many ways but one thing
that I I think that makes skunk magazine
is really special is it's very inclusive
rather than exclusive for its writers
you get writers from all walks of life
for those guys that are watching or
ladies that are watching the show if you
guys want to write an article you can
submit it to skunk and they will
consider publishing it if it's good I
don't think you get that with most
magazines and I think that's one of the
beauties of skunk yeah thank you yeah I
really wanted it to have a a community
feeling a global Community feeling
because we are a global magazine and
that was really important to me and when
I took over creatively I said about to
create a different type of program with
writing yeah and so I have like 80 to
100 contributors globally and they're
all told of deadlines and they're all
invited in and they can submit content
which if it's worthy it can be published
in that issue it could be published
online or it could be published in the
next issue so it's
open-ended because you know dealing with
Stoners I learned quickly that if I just
had the set people I might be short a
few articles so now I have this flow
where we get more content that we need
and then we do that that thing where we
either push it online or push it to the
next issue and it works out really well
yeah and then you know a lot of people
will say they can write and they can't
write and so that's what it is proof is
in the pudding everybody thinks they can
do people can try and if it's good
definitely will'll consider it and we
want to encourage that you know Brandon
rust has been writing some good stuff
for you guys yeah so he's amazing in
Organics you know he does some good
stuff he's really well spoken he's a
real good writer
uh yeah he's really well-rounded and
really passionate about cannabis yeah no
I really likeed that and I it is very
different because and I've been you know
people have not understood what I was
doing but now I think that they are
understanding and there's something
about it where it's not like the other
Rags where you can just kind of buy your
way in and then there's an advertorial
article yeah I'm honing in on thought
leaders Visionaries M and they're
usually company owners yeah or somebody
on staff at the company and then they
tell the story of their brand through
education right I do believe that the
future of marketing is
authenticity and uh open-source DIY kind
of intimate feeling right that that's
what people are really responding to the
old way of just pushing advertorial
content and that feeling of lack of
substance or lack of soul soul or lack
of meaningfulness I think that a lot of
end consumers are really not into and
they're not going to respond to it as
they will with this type of thing so
what I love about it is that it's
actually coming from the people a lot of
the content is coming from the people
that are living it right and they're
sharing their insights and and then it's
actually something I mean I want every
skunk is is a collectible it's like an
educational tone right and I just pushed
the page is up to 160 Pages um yeah
after printing my book I understand what
that means and a lot of people don't but
it means that you're paying more money
for your your magazine and uh buying a
car every quarter yeah well we're 380
pages in the book and it's it's just
it's not cheap yeah I do it every
quarter without fail yeah and it's uh
it's intense it is intense but you know
after doing it for 12 years it's also
easy I know what I have have to do and I
get it done no matter what and you just
do it right but I'm really excited
because this year is going to be very
different I'm
launching uh seed sales with the
subscription the Seed Savers Club so in
the US you're going to be able to
receive the subscription with the choice
of your seeds yeah and it the Seed
Savers Club is all about protection and
preservation of genetic histories and
lineages and encouragement of proper
genetic work in the industry going
forward proper inbreeding proper
strengthening and development of lines
and just a lot more knowledge and
respect and Consciousness uh coming
forward that's why I definitely want you
to participate after we after this I I
definitely want to talk to you but it's
going to be cool because I'm
particularly talking with soul breeders
yeah people that are true stewards and
practice true husbandry of the plant and
and it's about nerding out and honestly
enjoying nature together developing
interesting and unique Expressions
together and then also um thriving yeah
together I think that you know in this
Renaissance also I've been told that
those of us that are activated globally
on behalf of healing and empowerment are
going to thrive in the bones of a Dying
World and crumbling societal structures
those that are actually in healing
medicine empowerment in some way there's
a pathway for you to thrive because
Millions more people around the planet
are going to need to access their
healing and and access you know
Alternative forms of medicine right so
and that's why I say just keep going no
matter what keep going um and that's
what we're going to do with these
different programs of monetization I'm
also I just sold 30 pounds of chocolate
skunk into the California Market with
Soma Hill Farms and um they're going to
be doing 30 lounds of seed no 30 lbs of
of flour and they're going to be doing
5x that for this season so that was a
successful program and I have another
you know 15 licensing deals on the table
so that's another way that I'm going to
be protecting skunk is working with
craft makers you know award-winning
flower award-winning hash makers divers
yeah and that's the way that I'm going
to protect skunk and remain agile yeah
and also do something of substance where
I'm I'm telling the story of what the
craft maker is doing all the way from
seed to the final sale and showing the
journey through the the magazine so it's
it's pretty exciting to bring those
worlds together and I've been waiting to
do that for a long time so a lot of
people think that books and magazines
are dying and they're going away yeah
how do you feel about that oh my God if
I had a nickel for everybody who has
said to me Prince is
dead and I mean it's just laughable to
me because you know I'm an alchemist in
the sense that I think of things
magically and um have studied magic and
the thing that I know about you know the
written word is that the written word
will always have
power um there's the power of the word
and there's nothing that's ever going to
change that and you know I've evolved
with the times we only do four issues a
year we do them with the seasons we do
quarterly and we have a rich
storytelling online Rich storytelling
through social and we're actually
bringing our forums back this year as
well right on the cusp of that um so
they will be back hopefully by the Fall
so I'm not about having all my eggs in
any one basket but there's something
about the power of print that will
always remain I believe and I believe
also that um you know in the pandemic a
lot more people went to you know
independent book stores started coming
back and a lot more people I think
changed forever yeah there's certain
things that change in our world where
we're never going back the the old way
of of doing certain things like the
classic 9 to5 and the classic office job
has kind of been turned upside down on
its head they still exist but a lot of
people so many more people work from
home or have Flex schedules yeah work
410 all kind I mean there's so that was
going on a little before but now it's
definitely more extreme than it ever has
been with people working from home
people people doing you know working
multiple jobs where they have small work
schedules yeah so I think it's Dynamic
it's about being dynamic more than
anything and being multi fasted and
that's really what I'm about I would
like to print skunk on hemp I'm
definitely want to do that but I will
always print skunk ouch yeah I know I
know it's wild well we got to talk about
that I think this it sounds amazing and
I mean I think it would be we're not
there yet no we're not there yet we will
be there we will be there we're just not
there yet yeah so I'd like to be the
first to do it um working on it and you
know we're going to be launching also
I'm working on a new project we're going
to be doing something called the
Cannabis guide book and it's going to be
a free magazine and it's going to be
more for the end consumer and more for
the mainstream consumer yeah and it's
going to be you know a mixture of like a
Michelin book showing the best in show
along with like a little bit of Rolling
Stones and a little bit of uh
monacle um it's something that I've been
waiting to do I did a free magazine like
years ago mhm um the highway but this is
going to be something different and and
again it's needed there's not really
anything out there that's going to be
quite like this we're going to have a
Marketplace component as well um that's
going to be very affordable to work with
us for the small mom and pop
dispensaries for the craft farmer so
definitely inspired by whole earth
catalog as well if you know that
counterculture publication it had very
much a Marketplace feeling so we're
going to be bringing those feelings back
cuz I'm like I love counterculture Rags
through time like I've studied them and
I really I don't know if you know
Richard jurgenson who has the archive up
in Willets but he has an amazing
collection of magazines uh through time
over the last you know 75 years 80 years
um and so I get inspired by things that
have been passed and then ways that we
can kind of bring those good ideas back
but in a modern way so I'm excited about
this and it's going to be bilingual but
again it's not to me like we still need
print and I think that print won't die I
just think it's evolving and I don't
think it's dead and I just I'll be a
long standing a person in that regard
because you know it's already existed
for thousands of years and
it's not going anywhere it's something
ancient and I think that it's going to
continue to evolve but we'll continue to
evolve with it right yeah nice yeah so
if you had one piece of advice usually I
ask about one piece of advice for
yourself but if you have one piece of
advice for the younger generation for
Sage's
generation one piece of advice that you
could share with everybody uh about the
industry about yourself what would that
be I say you know basically the most
important thing is be your own
constant be your own guiding force and
seek the answers within don't look
outside of yourself in the sense of you
know ever comparing yourself to anyone
else try as much as you can to cultivate
that presence with yourself in the
moment and listen within and follow that
follow your own inner Moonlight and let
that guide you because that will protect
you through anything and just turn down
the noise on the outside as much as you
can certainly get inspired by those
people that inspire you also seek them
out and I think that you know old school
apprenticeship I've always told Sage you
know learn from everybody that you can
and learn every aspect that you can and
you know he's been studying hash
making um for several years now and now
he's just been going through chopping
fresh frozen and that whole process and
it's fascinating and no matter what he
settles on doing it's just wonderful
when you show up for life and you're
willing to learn and study and grow and
attend to a a a situation I think that a
lot of young people um you know they
need to understand that it's about time
over time is how they're going to get
the best results and have the most
meaningfulness in their life yeah they
can't expect something to happen so
quickly in in one year or two years you
know that it's when you devoted 10 years
15 years that you start to see the
results of your work a lifetime yeah no
and just continuing on so and that's
perseverance I would say to a lot of
people interested in getting in you know
keep your your own be your own constant
and never never stop yeah never stop you
just keep going no matter what and
always seek The Way Forward mhm
absolutely yeah
amazing well it's been great having you
on here today this has been fun it's
been so awesome I love you and Janette
and I'm thrilled at what you're
developing James kudos to you uh to your
show to your book and uh yeah love you
my friend thank you for having me on so
if people are interested in finding more
about you and skunk magazine where
should they go they go to skunk
magazine.com they go to skunk magazine
uh type it all out because we're all
Shadow band on IG and
Facebook uh and they can also seek me
out Julie Kell I'm very easy to find as
well and yeah just pay attention to
what's going to be coming out we're
launching skunk genetics with the Seed
Savers Club we're bringing five properly
inbred skunk crosses to Market at the
end of May and so that's going to be
very exciting for people who've been
looking for that and yeah check out what
we're going to be doing in the year
ahead life's an adventure it is it never
stops thank you so much for coming on
the show thank you so much
[Music]
a