[Music]
Heat. Heat.
[Applause]
[Music]
How's it going everybody? Welcome to
another episode of the James Loud
podcast. And today our special guest is
Cubone Snoop Dog Chef. We met in Vegas.
This guy is a big fan of food. He does
an amazing job online with his food
posts. You know, I'm impressed by all
your stuff. How you doing today? I'm
doing good, James. Man, it's pleasure
being on your show, man. I've been
really looking forward to coming on here
with you, man. Just like we did in Vegas
and then you were cooking. Yeah. You
know, it's like all this stuff is very
serendipitous. You know, you come to
Vegas, we meet. Uh I'm doing a cooking
event and I'm actually cooking for a
change instead of doing my podcast or my
seeds or whatever. You show up, we start
talking, now you're here, and then we're
going to be doing a food show together
hopefully in the very near future. Oh,
yeah. Yes, sir. Yes. I look forward to
that, man. You know, from the day I met
you, man, I I I felt the vibe, you know,
walk the food is good, you know. I just
felt your vibe cooking and how you
participated with the crowd with, you
know, with the guests that you at the
house that day. It was very, very good
presentation, man. Caught my vibe. Good
vibe. Yeah. That's what I I feel like
that's what cooking is all about. That's
what I love about cooking, right? It's
like one thing making some food, just
giving it to people, but it's another
thing when you can provide an experience
where people are like they they embrace
the experience, they love it, and
they're like, "Wow, this was amazing."
Right. You get people blown away by some
food where you give them stuff that they
wouldn't normally eat together. Yes. You
know, where we're torching the s'mores
or whatever, you know, it's like I have
a lot of fun with it. Yes. You you
especially that cup with the cup with
the potatoes and the Oh, yeah. Roast
that prime rib or something in there.
Yeah. We had some sousie. So sousied
wagu with the the mashed potatoes
martini. Yeah, we had the mashed potato
martinis. It was A3 Wagu, I believe. You
got in a bag. Yeah, we Yeah, we sied
them. Yeah. So we sied those. Yeah. And
we did them. I think it was a threehour
sousie on those. So we put them We
seared them in a pan. Then we sied them
for 3 hours. We sliced them nice and
thin. We put them with mashed potatoes.
Amazing sausage Chef Ricky made. Big
shout out to Chef Ricky, man. You can't
go wrong. Yeah, Chef Rick Asian high and
stuff. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. It was that was
a whole night set the whole line of the
chef's got. I got a good footage of
that, too, though. I liked that, though.
Yeah, we had the little pasta station.
So, you got the pasta. We you know, and
it was a lot of fun. And I feel like it
was well orchestrated. We had a good
team. They had some good videographers
there to capture it. And then there was
good weed, too. So, you can't go wrong.
Oh, yeah. You can't say. Yeah. Yeah. I
love when they rent the houses like
that. And that that house was designed
specifically for parties, you know? It's
like I couldn't do that at my house.
They had they had a lot of houses um
that weekend um that I went to that was
based on a lot of that. That the one
night before that was just as big as
that too. They had um somebody else had
they had like um a clip from Florida
came down. Oh wow. Um some name bacon. I
remember her she had a Florida cook.
They they had seafood boiled and that
house been acting just like that one
too. But that one there was like took
the cake cuz it's you go around the
corner outside and Yeah. back to
waterfall and stuff. Yeah. Yeah. It's
nice. Yeah. I partied at Mike Tyson's
house a few years ago. A lot of fun. Oh
wow. Yeah. His Vegas house. Is that the
one that's in Vegas? The one house in
Vegas. Vegas one. Yeah, the Vegas house.
Okay. Okay. So, yeah. You know, you got
a lot of houses though. That Yeah.
California City now. I already got like
a compound to grow a growth facility
like a little city right there in
California City. Yeah. I think they got
education program all that stuff, you
know. It's like Yeah. He's really made m
making waves in the cannabis industry,
you know. Yeah. Yeah. He is. He is. Uh
Tyson OG. Yeah. Tyson 2.0. Yeah. He's
crushing it, you know. He's crushing
He's crushing it. And he participates
and he's fun. He has podcast going, you
know. I think it was Smoking with Tyson
up, something like that. Yeah. Yeah.
Smoked out with Tyson or whatever. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I mean, it's it's
impressive seeing guys that I feel like
guys that belong in the place like Snoop
Do Yeah. Snoop Snoop, someone who
belongs in the space, cannabis, you get
other guys that are trying to just
profit off it. And then you got guys
like Mike Tyson that believe in it. Like
I I believe he belongs in this space. He
belongs with us, you know? Yeah. And and
it's and he's and he smokes it not
because of the habit. I think because of
what he been through as a boxer, you
know, it helps him out, you know, cuz
you know, boxers fighting, he get
anxiety probably, you know, he's really
anxiety type person. I can tell probably
a post-t trauma type of person. So the
weed relaxes him and puts him in a movie
because if you notice, he doesn't get
into it with a lot of people like he
used to. Um he hang like I seen him and
uh Jake Paul at the I think it was some
event Super Bowl or something some event
they was the other and he was jump Mike
jumped on his shoulder and they walked
in together. Yeah. Recently recently
some Yeah. Yeah. It's pretty wild.
That's not the old Mike. That's That's
not the old Mike. Old Mike fighting you
in public and everywhere. Yeah. He
doesn't care. He doesn't care. Pretty
wild. Well, yeah. So, we have a mutual
friend Ricky Palamino. Yep. Ricky
Palamino. Man, that's I met Ricky
Palamato in 2005. We was on tour with
Snoop. Um, at that time I was a road
manager. I was even I was even cooking.
I was just cooking for fun. Like I
didn't even cook for nobody on tour. And
when I went home, I cooked. I cut
myself. I cooked. But never on tour. So
me and Ricky rocked real close at me
being the tour manager for my the
company I worked with and him working
with Snoop. We got really real close.
Like like real close. Like I remember
Ricky had short haircut. And then when I
seen him years later with the long hair,
I didn't know who he was. I really
didn't know who he was. I'm like, "Who's
you, man? You calling my name?" You
know, cuz I don't like people knowing me
and I don't know them. Yeah. And I'm not
going to ask you what's your name. I
feel that's embarrassing your name. And
he said, "Man, it's Ricky. I know you
know who I am." I said, "Palyamino,
that's you're the only Ricky Palamino I
know. Period." Yeah. Yeah. Good friend
of mine, man. Good. Time I see him, I
just give him a bracelet, man. You know,
cuz he u been through a lot. He been
through a lot. Yeah. That's my boy. He's
a stoner, too. He belongs in the space,
too. He's another good one. You know,
it's like Yeah. He's He's a great guy.
Yeah. And we had him on the show. Uh we
tissue cultured his plant. We're about
to give it back to him. So, he's got the
RBK Ricky's brother's Kush. Okay. That's
a good OG cut. The real deal. Okay.
Yeah. Small world. Yes. Real small
world, man. A couple people on your post
I've seen and known. Yeah. Yeah. We've
had a We've been really blessed to get a
lot of amazing talent coming on this
show, you know, from the industry. Well,
you James Loud, you know. Come on, man.
James Lou, your next you, you know, you
people want to come on your show. When
you have when you show your hospitality
and the conversation, the vibe that you
get out, the energy, you know, that you
bring, it makes people want to come to
your show. You know, like I said, you're
a people person. It's been a lot of fun,
though. I'll tell you, like when it's
not fun anymore, that's it. Yeah. When
it's not fun, the more it's not here.
Just like a relationship. When it's when
it's not romantic, the more it's over.
Yeah. Turn toxic. Well, and it's like
we're we're ever evolving. So, we have
this new So, I showed you the studio
just a little bit ago. We have this new
review show that we're doing and then we
got a kitchen and that's where hopefully
we're going to be working together doing
some fun stuff. I'm looking forward to
it, man. I look forward to, you know, I
look forward to come and doing whatever
I can do. Yeah. I I love cooking and I
love doing the podcast and now combining
them and it's like I'm a big Anthony
Bourdain fan, of course, you know, and
it's like I love the Food Network. uh
you know it's like I have so many people
that I look up to that have that have
you know moved forward in the you know
from from uh all these chefs you know we
got these chefs even Rachel Ray you know
I'm okay with Rachel Ray dude like I
think you know you can't hate on Rachel
Ray and Martha you know and she's
working with Snoop there's another way I
remember you know how they first met was
on the Justin Bieber roast and she was
sitting next to him and he started
smoking on the stage he was he was
smoking on never seen before smoking on
on the television show on a roast. He
adore it to the Grammys. We don't go to
Grammy but award shows, but he smoked on
that show. Then when she came went out
that they got close um really
conversating. Then then I guess after
she went in and came home, she decided
let me do a cooking show with him
because of his reputation and how he was
doing you know everything. So it turned
out good for them both. Turned out
really good for both of them. They cross
demographics. Everybody that's like a
Dr. Dre and Snoop with a cooking now.
Yeah. Seriously. Yeah. He understands
the collaboration model really well.
Yeah. Oh, yeah. Yeah. He's he's very
he's very adjustable to all type of
aspects. I watch him go from rag music
to hip-hop music, Snoop Lion, Snoop Dog,
you know, I watching Pimp and Snoop, you
know, just so many atmospheres of Snoop
that people don't really know about. And
me being his chef, but before I was a
chef, I was just a good friend, you
know, and he picked me out to be a chef
because, you know, I he I cooked for him
one time a long time ago. we uh with his
uncle June Bug. That's how he know I can
really cook. He first taste my food.
Some uh baked chicken. It was cold
outside. Yeah. So, we was going to get
on the grill. So, we had the chicken sit
in the refrigerator, party wings, and
nobody wanted to cook. You can't go
outside on the grill. So, nobody wanted
to cook. And he didn't want it fried cuz
so people let's bake it. I said, "Well,
let's bake it." Yeah. Nobody I ain't
baking that. I put in put in the oven
and baked it and oh yeah, this is good.
They clean the chicken out. They had
never ate my food ever since then. That
was like in like the late 90s or
something. you know, 2000 early 2000 and
you talking about up to 216 when I'm
cooking in on Facebook and he steady
logging on my Facebook live, steady
logging, steady logging every day,
seeing that I'm cook, I can see him
looking at it and he came on live one
day and said, "Hey, boom, I need to be
my personal chef, man. Come on tour with
me." Nice. Next thing I know, I was on
the tour. That's 216. Every tour now I'm
on with him. Wow. Yeah. That's really
cool. Yeah. Yeah. So, what kind of food
is Snoop like?
He and he's not a picky eater. He's very
finicky. I mean average. Uh he's what he
grew up on like one of his favorites I
can say hamburger helper. Yeah. Let's
say egg or waffle egg scramble soft
bacon grape jelly toast. Fried chicken
fried pork chops fried shrimp fish like
fish fried fish. Uh vegetables. You know
he's not going to force on the vegetable
if they're around. Eat the greens.
macaroni, cheese, string beans, love
rice and gravy. Love steaks and little
cubes. I cut them in little cubes for
him like that. Like abachi, but regular
regular steak. So he's a really just a
regular regular eater. Like if you
brought a lot of stuff to the table for
him set up to eat in VIP rooms like
that's all the different little
decorations on it. That's not his jam.
No, no, that's not his. Yeah. Regular
like egg waffle. You know what I mean?
He might well eat a waffle here a
little, but he he prefers egg waffle
sausage Jimmy Dean sausage for
breakfast. Just just a regular eater
like chicken and waffles. Yeah. It's
like nothing that you would have to go
hire a Michelin chef to cook for. Yeah.
Like if you hire Michelle to cook for
him, it's the wrong chef. Yeah. You need
to buy me somebody down home just
totally regular cooking. Yeah. Mac and
cheese. Yeah. Mac and cheese. And Yeah.
You know, I seen your mac and cheese.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. That's it. Yeah.
That's it. Just basic basic eater. real
basic eater, but he's a lot. Candies,
sweets, cookies. Yeah, it's l It's good
thing he's thin, you know what I mean?
Like, where' it go? Yeah, cuz he's slim.
So, you know, you don't you don't see
where it go. I eat all that sweets, man.
It just makes me fat. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. He That's what he does do.
He eats a lot of sweet Skittles and M&amp;M.
Love peanuts and stuff, cashews and
stuff like that. Well, I think some of
that kind of regulate when you smoke a
lot of weed, you want to balance it out
with some sugar. I like caffeine, sugar,
and weed, but like I try to cut out the
sugar. Just the caffeine and the weed
work really well together, too. Okay.
So, how do you So, you grew up cooking?
You you started cooking when you were
young or when did you start cooking?
Yeah. Well, my great-grandmother, you
know, I was raised with my
great-grandmother. My mother was young
at the time she had me. You know, I'm
the firstborn. Um, so I was raised in a
house with my great-grandmother, my
grandmother, my uncles, aunties,
cousins, and stuff. Now, I'm the first
born in my generation. I'm only have
seven kids. Um, at the time I was first
only 15. So my great-grandmothers taught
me how to cook, both of them and my mom
as time went on, but my
great-grandmother was my influence of
cooking. Um, I first learned how to cook
was eggs. Everybody learn how to cook
eggs. That's the first thing you
scramble for what you're eating. Um, and
then as I grew up, I just love to cook.
I had a passion for cooking, but never
created a business. Never tried to open
up a restaurant, never tried to go sell
a plate or do nothing like um as I got
older, um my this just like older older
like in my late 30s. Um I start doing
backyard parties, like if we throw a
backyard party, somebody cooking, I go
help them. What they call now sue chef.
I didn't know then it was just I like
helping them cook and I end up taking
over the whole cook. Hey man, move out.
You don't know what you're doing. Get
out of the way. I was on the grill like
cooking for the homies and stuff and
then I look back and they start liking
my food. But I just see him smiling all
the places empty and people smile say
okay I can cook I can cook you know I
season a lot I like flavor but I don't
like salty flavor I don't like too much
spicy I like just right balance it out
and I learned how to balance it out but
just from experience my teacher learn
looking at other people's seeds and
stuff and taste my own experience and
see if it's too salty or not and I
learned how to balance that and and make
that kind of like less sodium healthier
for good people you know right and
that's that's And that's that's really
how I learned how to cook with my
great-grandmother. She's was my mentor
in cooking. The same thing my parents,
you know, I grew up with parents that
both like to cook. My mother was also a
baker, owned a bakery for a little bit
when I was younger. Um, you know, bread
baker. She used to make amazing bread,
but also, you know, everything from
croissants to cakes, all that stuff. And
then my father was friends with a
Michelin star chef. Okay. Sorry. Master
chef from France. This was, I think,
even before Michelin died. He was a
Yeah. French master chef. Okay. and uh
by the name of Ken Wolf. And so my dad
took cooking classes from him. My dad
taught me how to cook. So by the time I
was 6 years old, I was in cooking
competitions. Okay. Okay. So yeah, I I
love cooking. And I The way you the way
you did that, like I would I mean when
you did that, I still to this day had
that vision. Um whenever I do cook for
somebody, um you know, cuz like I said,
I only cook for him. I never got a
chance to really cook like in the
setting what you did that day. Um I have
I've done it now know recently but
before I haven't done it. So when I seen
you do it I took ideas. I like ideas you
know. Um I like the cup the cup in the
martini cup with the potatoes and Yeah.
It's so fun. You just take a pastry bag,
pipe it in there. It's fun. People like
fun. Yeah. People like fun. And they
like the the way you steamed up the
marshmallow and the cracker. You know
the chocolate. Yes. We use the dab torch
dab torch s'mores. Yeah. Yeah. Dab torch
thing. Yeah. So you know Yeah. Put bacon
in the s'mores too. You know, it's like
all those little details and and that's
what personalizes it and makes it your
own. And I just love that kind of stuff.
You know, we we should do a dinner party
together here. Oh, yeah. Yeah. I'm with
it. I'm with it, man. I'm with it. You
know, like I said, it's it's, you know,
now I see the bigger picture. Um, that's
why I created Cooking with Cubone show
to have fun and, you know, go around
doing reviews, not reviews. It's like a
diners and D like a guy, you know. He's
one of my favorite. Um, I like the way
he just hosted people and you know, you
barely see him cooking unless he's at
home or one of his restaurants back or
he's supporting it. But most time he's
supporting. He can cook though. That's
why people can cook. He can totally
cook. He can totally cook. He's also a
great host. And he's probably known more
for being a host than a chef and a
restaurant owner. But it's like Ramsay's
Kitchen. Ramsey, he's like the the drill
sergeant of the cooking guy. Loves
yelling at everybody. But yeah, and
Gordon Ramsay, one of my friends used to
work for Gordon Ramsay, and he said the
only time he heard Gordon Ramsay yell
when he worked for him was when he fired
somebody and that was it. It wasn't like
he was firing people. He took care of
his staff, you know? I I think he said
you he just make you want to get on
point, stay on point. He just let you
know your your smallest failure could be
the end of your career, you know? Yeah.
But he also doesn't hire idiots, right?
Those for for the shows, they put idiots
in front of him and then what happens?
He yells at them. You know what I mean?
But like guys like that, they can't
afford to have shitty people working for
them as a restaurant. As a restaurant
owner. Yes. Yes. Yeah. I think you got
like three or four. Yeah. A lot of
restaurants. Bobby Flavor is another one
I like too. I like Yeah. I like his
personality and his cuisine style is
good. Giata, she's another one. Like
Yeah. She's everywhere. She's
everywhere. She's all over the place,
too. With the grocery the grocery uh Oh,
yeah. shopping thing gang when they cook
in the parking lot and like I like and
know and I and I really wanted to um I'm
still thinking about going on one of
them shows like that one day creating
one of them contest someday somebody
will pull me on there and I just you
know whether win or lose is just I just
want to have that experience that I
cooked against Bobby Flave and stuff.
Yeah. Yeah. Well, let me know. I'll
train you for one of those events.
Exactly. Exactly. I'm big into those and
I used to win cooking competitions.
Right. And especially mystery basket
cooking competitions. I love those.
Right. And it's that's where you can get
really creative, but you have to have
just a base understanding for what you
can make. Like going into the
competition, you have an idea. Okay,
this is what you know it could be
potentially. And then you build off of
those ideas. But my signature dish um
where I grew up on is spaghetti. Yeah.
So I fig I looked at around um a lot of
African-American restaurants, soulful
restaurants. Spaghetti is made in every
household outside Italian. um in in our
way, you know, just regular ground beef,
spaghetti, tomato paste or piggo sauce,
regular sauce. But I thought of three
meats. I want to do my three meats. Bell
peppers, onions, you know, different
seasonings, K style. You know, I do
turkey. I do three meats of turkey. I do
a breakfast turkey, sausage with the gr
turkey ground with turkey sausage. And
then I put all the ingredients in my
special. Then I at the end I you know I
hit him with a little secret sauce like
why it's called a Cajun that's I'm not
Italian so I'm bringing you a barbecue
flavor sauce or Cajun style some
spaghetti with lots of flavor lots of
flavor make you think you was eating the
sofa and it works it works and everybody
I have fed it to have ate it um on tour
um you know I do cook for like the staff
on tour I cook enough for Snoop but also
cook enough for the eight or nine 10
other people on staff and sometime
guests and I had people came to me and
said like man I ate spaghetti in 8
years, man. Your spaghetti the bomb. So,
I I figured, okay, here I go. That's my
signature dish. I'm I'm going to make
sure everything I cook, I got spaghetti
at the menu because nobody really has
spaghetti on their menu in the way of I
made it. So, I've cooked for a lot of um
venues now. I cater to motorcycle clubs
and stuff to some of my friends. So, I
go to their little annuals or something
or one of their game nights and I go in
there with that spaghetti that Traers is
so easy to do with a salad or sweet roll
and I'm winning. man. And everybody love
it. I I have not one complaint yet. So I
said, "Okay, I'm going to stick to
spaghetti, right? Stick spaghetti." You
know, that that's my blow up right
there. Keep it simple. Keep it simple.
You know, you can fry if I can fry fish
and fry chicken or baked chicken or
barbecue chicken on a grill. It matches
with spaghetti, right? It's a full It's
a full-fledged platter, you know? Well,
I feel like cooking is a lot like
growing. You want to learn how to cook,
cook the same thing over and over and
over till you've perfected it instead of
trying to cook everything in the world
and switch it up. And you can follow
recipes to learn how to cook. But
eventually you you need to cook to
taste, right? To your own taste because
there's certain amounts of salt levels
that you want, you know, and everybody's
different. That's subjective, right? How
much salt is in there. Some people need
more, some people need less. Some people
like spicy, some people like not so
spicy. Some people don't like spice at
all. Yeah. Some people the older you get
that spice you got to take. I'm the
opposite. As I've gotten older, I like
more spice. I I would say in the last
two years since I do I started doing
this cold plunging, right? where you go
in the freaking freezing cold water for
3 to 5 minutes. And ever since I started
cold plunge, I I could eat spicier food.
Okay. And so this is just in the last
two years since we started doing the
podcast really that I've been able to
eat pretty spicy. Like I would never
mess with habaneros before. Now it's
like, oh, I eat habanero. It's not that
bad. Ghost peppers. Eh, it's a little
bit out of my league, right? Like
habanero. Yeah, that's that's big right
now. I don't know what what made that
come out because of the spiciness in it.
Yeah. Well, you know, it's like I I love
that habanero. Over the last couple
years, it's really like the household
name now. Uhhuh. Yeah. You see them at
Safeway everywhere. Everywhere. Yeah.
Every making off top of even even um
Chick-fil-A got made a version of it. Or
the ghost pepper too, you know. Yeah.
Ghost peppers, too. And scorpion is way
too hot. Like Yeah. That's way too hot.
That's way too hot. I had It's so hot
that I took one scorpion pepper with a
whole flat of strawberries, some sugar,
some acid, some some lemon juice, and I
made this sauce. And I had one pepper,
one of these scorpion peppers. And if I
eat it, like just a spoon, I just take a
little bit on a spoon and then to touch
it to my tongue, my my ears turn purple
cuz it's so spicy. Oh wow. Too spicy for
me. And a lady sent me um her name is
Marie Strat. She sent me like a hot
sauces. Maria. She's from Bise. She has
like I haven't even tasted all the hot
sauce. I'm not going to say, you know,
unless somebody come my house and they
want hot sauce. You got a choice to the
flame and super heap for heat. They like
she's at levels that I'm like like
Tabasco was too hot for me. Wow. So
imagine I'm just throwing Louisiana hot
sauce, crystal and other you know that
super super hot sauce. Oo. No. Then I um
the pepper. Yeah. Oh man, if that that
you know that just get me in a sweat
box. I turn to the sweat box. So you
know I limit myself on spicy seasoning I
can do. Yeah. Like you know like creole
casian all that just a dab of kayen.
Yeah. Black and different ones like
that. Yeah. But when it come when like
jerk I love jerk jerk. I just started
cooking jerk chicken like couple of
months ago in one of my friends house on
the holiday. Yeah. I like pounding out
chicken breast and doing them jerk
chicken style like that. So you pound it
with a hammer. I'll just Well, yeah. So
I'll take a I have a mallet and I'll
slice it thin and then I'll pound it
even thinner. I put the jerk seasoning
on both sides and I I grill it. Okay. I
love that. Like you can do the legs, you
can do the whole stuff. I think you're
doing the smash burgers now. Oh yeah, I
love smash burgers. That's my jam. So So
what's the different? I mean, I never
really get into it because I I just
thinking I just smash fat fat fat. It's
a smash burger. But you got to hit it
with the hammer. So what you got to do
with the smashburger is basically you
got to use 70% lean is the best. 80%
will work. 70 is the best. Okay. And
what you do is you take a you make your
ball a quarter pound ball, right? And
then you put it on the grill when it's
hot. It's got to be pretty hot. You
smash it down with with a I have a
smasher that's specifically cast iron.
We're smashing. It's round. It smashes
it down. Um smashes it in the burger
patty shape. You take it off. You put
your onions that are sliced thin. Salt
and pepper. And then what you do is you
just cook it till you can see the edges
starting to caramelize. You scoop under
it. You flip it over. You put your
cheese on it. Once the cheese is melted,
you know it's done. And so this is like
a a minute and a half, two minute
process. Your burger is done. As long as
your bun's already heated up, you just
put it on there. I use my own special
sauce. It's kind of like thousand
island, right? And I use pickles and
I'll I'll put a little bit of shredded
lettuce, but I love smash burgers, but
the the important part is the beef with
the smashed burgers and the bun, right?
It's like potato bun or bio. You can go
either way. They're both good. I prefer
bio myself. Okay. I just had one down at
Rip Pizzeria, the pizza and beer in uh
Orange County when I was there the other
day. They use the potato bun. It's the
best potato bun I've ever had. Okay.
Really conforms to the burger where you
can you can squeeze it. Right. Right.
Right. Right. It's like potato burger.
Yeah. And you want that crispy. It's
almost crispy like bacon, but it's a
burger, you know. And I use American
cheese. I like they have a I think it's
a smoked American. Okay. Which is really
good. Or if you're really creative,
smoke your own American cheese and do
it. And how you smoke American? How you
smoke? A smoker. You
smoke cold smoked cheese. You put it in
a smoker. You do cold smoke. So it's
just the smoke and not the temperature
so it doesn't melt it. Yeah. And you get
all that flavor and then you do it as a
whole block. So when you slice it thin,
you just have it on the outside. So as
you're biting into it, man, that's
that's amazing. Yeah, that's tight.
That's I'm going to try that out. I'm
going to learn something every day.
Yeah. Yeah. I got all kinds of fun cook
a lot of people that you know the the
healthy eaters nowadays have caused most
chefs and most kitchens to serve food
with less flavor season unless you ask.
Remember, you have to ask, you have to
tell them, I don't want the season on
here. Now you have to tell them to put
the season on because they give you
straight blame food because they don't
know. They rather they looking at
health. They don't know your issues.
They don't want to underline you and you
go into a stage of hypotheria or
something like that while you eating
that food and it's so seasoned cuz you
know it's a lot of people I I had a
seasoning called Grandma Hands that my
auntie had created in Houston, Texas. It
was low sodium like you could put it on
potatoes, you could put it on any food
and you have to do nothing use nothing
allpurpose. You'll never use nothing
else on it. If you use anything else on
it, it was salty. Yeah. And I had people
that had like high blood pressure and
they would use that seasoning and they
would say, "Man, I can use that. Give me
order some more." I even had Chef's
Kitchen order. She know she just stopped
about a year ago. I'm trying to get her
to get it back, you know, back. But
she's elderly now and she just in her
own little world, you know, but I'm into
the real good the seasoning, the flavor.
Um, yeah, I like I like all allpurpose
seasoning. I'm just getting on Miss
Dash. Yeah, because it's not salty. It's
It's table blend. And I tried the lemon
pepper the other day. Now it's got
flavor. It brings flavor to the food.
What's your favorite barbecue sauce?
Mine's Kinder. I love Kinder. I love
Kinder. Everything, man. Now Kinders is
killing everybody right now. Come on.
You got roasted garlic now. You got hot
gold. They got a new wing sauce. Their
wing sauce is seen. Yeah. Yeah. Here we
do a lot of AB testing with plants,
right? So, we'll test this versus this
versus this with nutrients or with soil
versus cocoa versus whatever. I did that
with wings at the house. So, we did the
Kinder Wing Sauce versus the freaking
Crystal versus the Frank's Red Hot.
Okay. Kinders, their new wing sauce is
so good. It get I met um the son who
runs Kinder Justin. I met him through
E40 and Be Legit um years ago. And you
know, so yeah, me and them got real
close. And like I say, he he done added
more to the table than any other
barbecues I see right now. He's like
killing the game. But the one I say, I
can't think. He's got the he he's he's
in every store, too, though. He's But
he's based out of Atlanta. Oh, sweet
baby Ray. That's the old Sweet Baby,
man. Sweet Baby Ray. That's a classic.
That's a classic. I like that sweet and
spicy one, though, for sure. I like the
balance with that, you know. And it's
it's funny cuz my parents live in Texas
and Texas style barbecue sauce is a
little bit different. You got your
Kansas City barbecue sauce and then I
love the classic like like what Kinders
I love the the sauce they got there.
Killing the game right now. I just went
and bought something the other day the
roasted garlic. I like I love I love the
roasted garlic. I use that on my steak.
I I don't even use steak sauce, you
know. I use that on my all on my chicken
steaks. I I even use on my
taquitos, everything. I I even use that
like when when I make it my soups is
different stuff. I love that Kinders the
different flavors of they sauce. Yeah.
They kill the game, right? Kinder
barbecue sauce. They're spicy with
nachos is amazing. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Spice with nachos. They That's what I
use it on. I use it as Kendra on my
nachos. I put it on the nachos and the
cheese. I put everything else on it.
I'll put that lettuce on it and tomatoes
on top and I sprinkle that little thick
kinders in there. Boy, put that flavor.
Like you can really make a blade
hamburger. Yeah. And put nothing on it
and put that Kenders on it. You going to
get all the flavor out that sauce right
there. Secret to meatloaf is not just
ketchup. It's barbecue sauce. Have fun.
Oh yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I do barbecue and I
do ketchup. Yeah, barbecue ketchup. I
mix mines. My Yeah. My girl, she she
loves that with just the ketchup and she
don't use barbecue sauce. She said, "You
eat barbecue sauce on everything.
Everything we have. You just barbecue
barbecue." I said, "Hey, that's where
the flavors at. I'm just Call me the
barbecue king eater." I like switching
it up. Yeah. I like I like it. Yeah.
Switch it. I I was trying Mr. Stubs,
too, though. But, you know, I don't
know. It like a Texas barbecue cuz you
got the cowboy hat. Black with the
cowboy hat on it being there. Stubs. So,
what what's the difference between like
I ate um Kansas City barbecue sauce? Uh
Gates. I remember Gates. I It's more
vinegary, right? It's more the the
Kansas City is more vinegary. More
vinegary. Yeah. Now, what is Texas is
more uh like more it's richer flavor.
Texas is this thick spicy stuff, right?
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Cuz I had met a meat
company when I was on the road. We was
on tour. Um it's a meat company in
Texas. They do Wagu. Yeah. Burgers,
steaks, and everything. Um they doing
like 300 cows a week. Wow. 300 cows a
week. They're real big. And I love
barbecue though. Good barbecue. You
can't go off. Yeah. Yeah. You got The
only problem with most barbecue spots is
their sides suck, right? But but if you
go in there for me, the potato salad is
no good. The beans is no good. And I
love good beans. And I love good mac and
cheese. Like those are the things I
love, too. I probably eat those more
than I eat barbecue. Like mac and cheese
is something I I pride myself in my mac
and cheese, too. Oh yeah. I pride my Now
I make my mac and cheese different from
my my roommate. He uh my brother, he um
put me up on it. He instead of milk Mhm.
He uses cream mushroom. It comes out.
Oh, that's
different. Use cream of mushroom and it
Oh, man. It comes out. So like the pep
milk in the candy, you use cream of
mushroom. Yeah. Oh man, it it's it's
it's you got to try it. Nice. I I I'm
like now I don't even make it without
the cream of mushroom because it's also
melts the cheese, you know, and then the
cream mushroom, you know, it's thick.
Makes it creamy, too. Oh, it makes it
creamy, right? That it's on pl and it
has flavor. It gives you that cream of
mushroom flavor into the to the mac and
cheese. I do the truffle mac, right? So,
you put the truffle like we make I make
truffle oil from scratch, too, from real
truffles. And then we make I like the
Kender I like the Kender's truffle uh
steak truffle steak seasoning. Mhm. And
killing them. Like say Kender's not just
killing it with the sauce. He coming
with the seasoning. Yeah. And they got
the classic ball tip sandwich. That is
the best sandwich in the Bay Area is
that Kinder's Ball tip. I have the Snoop
Doggy Dog. That's on Dirt Dog. Mhm. Um,
Dirt Dog was matter of fact in Vegas and
LA. Um, they haven't opened one up here
yet. Yeah, they're aiming I keep asking
open one up here. Now, Dirt Dog has um
like 10 different hot dogs. They all use
a nation's beef links. Um, they had a
Snoop Doggy dog which is made out of um
coleslaw, the billionaire bacon, the
maple brown bacon. Um, you know, and it
has a special Hennessy barbecue sauce
and and a a gin sauce like out of
lobster sauce, like a creamy orange
creamy sauce, lobster sauce, but it's
got jen in it for adults. Kids regular
and it's made on a Texas toast bun. Um,
at the Snoop Dog, they have an exhibit
dog. They got the flame throw. They got
like seven of the the dog, the patty
melt dog, the pastrami dog. And like I
said, they in LA, like six places in LA,
they got four in Vegas. They have a
compound. Yeah, a big compound like
where they throw parties, low rider
shows at in the city of commerce in LA.
I don't want to create the Snoop Doggy
Dog Dog for for that restaurant. Like
Snoop didn't have nothing to do with
Okay, Bone, go ahead and make it for us.
So I created his billionaire bacon and
we created So you created the
billionaire bacon? No, he did create the
billionaire bacon, but I took the
billionaire bacon and put it on the
Snoop Dog. Yeah. Yeah. If you guys don't
know, Snoop Dogg created the billionaire
bacon. I cook billionaire bacon. So many
other chefs have made the billionaire
bacon. There was the millionaire bacon
and then Snoop had the billionaire
bacon. Made the billionaire bacon. Now I
need to make a trillionaire bacon. I'm
into the the seasonings. Um um
incredible um my folks. She has the
seasoning. Yeah. Um she was in Vegas.
She was in Vegas with um she has the CBD
seasoning right now. So we want to l
with THC. Yeah. Um she has um lemon
pepper, Cajun, cayenne pepper. Yeah. um
allpurpose, you know, she have like taco
seasoning. Sure. You know, and all CBD,
but we're going to do it in THC version
right now. But, you know, she travel the
country doing it in THC. She had the
butter, the honey butter, u the olive
oil, and all that CBD, but she want to
change up the THC. So, I'mma collaborate
with her with doing that. And um I also
have a Stoner brand. You heard Stoner
brand? Um they got a cocktail coming out
called Chronic Tonic. Nice. And they
going to the final stages of getting
that right now. And that's going to be a
tasty cocktail. Yeah. Fruit cocktail.
It's right. It's real nice smooth just
and so we'll be in consumption like like
it be on the counter, you know. Hey, you
want to drink it cocktail tasty four
different flavors and stuff, you know,
and everything. I love the way the
world's moving more towards cannabis
consumption than alcohol. Yes. Yes. You
know, and even like the alcohol, they're
making a cannabis style. It it has the
appearance of alcohol, but it's really
got cannabis in it. And and and you get
more about of it um healthwise. Um you
get you get more about it that you know
as far as taste, you know, because you
only taste THC and alcohol. You got
every other thing coming out of you
don't know what's in there. You know
what they doing. But I like the fact
that the THC cannabis is working its way
to America's land in the way we supposed
to. health, um, enjoyment, amusement,
entertainment, and even in bar like the
consump heard Governor Nuome pass the
cons consumption lounge. Yeah. Really
cool. I mean, I'm excited about that.
Yeah. Yeah. So, when do I mean, is it in
effect now that you can actually apply
the law? I believe that people are
already starting to apply for it. Yeah.
I mean, I think it's going to be a big
game changer, right, for I feel like the
industry is suffering. It's great that
we can have consumption lounges. I mean,
I think that's that's just a necessary
thing. They have There's no way you
really look at it. You can go buy weed
at any place and have nowhere to consume
it but in your home. You can't stand
outside. You can't be at a hotel. They
don't have no place. Even if you have a
business, you can't sit on the side with
your business smoking. You might not
want to smoke in the barber shop. You
might not want to smoke it in a
restaurant. You not want to smoke it in
a bar a lounge. So, if you have a
cannabis lounge like Aram does, nuh, now
everybody has some place to go. And now
the the profit of cannabis is starting
to explode more, especially in all
different ways with the drinks, the
cocktails, the food, the different
everything. Everything. Yeah. And I
mean, and then you can have this
consumption lounge that sells food. And
now we got more money coming into the
local, you know. Yeah. Exactly. More
it's economical profit for any community
comes in nowadays. I look forward to
that. I look forward to that experience.
I'm I'm going to try because, you know,
my brother, he um owns a cannabis can of
Oakland. Yeah. On 21st in MacArthur, you
know. Um and we just built the outside.
He built the outside. Um you know they
got the booths on the sidewalk cuz co
they had you outside. So he built a
cemented booth on the sidewalk. Cemented
brricked. Wow. You know most people
build a will they can move it off and
then probably they want to move. No,
this is built on the ground now. Like
it's not going nowhere. Yeah. Cuz in
Oakland if you don't do that they're
going to take it. That's how crazy it is
out there in Oakland. So they want you
to build something on the park on this
curve. Yeah. Well, no. I mean, the thing
is is if you don't, people are going to
steal whatever it is cuz Oakland's just
rough right now. Yeah, it is. It is. It
is. And drink MacArthur. MacArthur was
right there where he's at is it's kind
of I liked it right there down there cuz
I love Oakland. I love the city of
Oakland. Um Frisco, I experienced Fris,
but Frisco reminds me of New York,
congested, and you just can't figure it
out. It's like, you know, you can't you
can't figure it out really of Frisco.
Oakland is still historical. He still
have his culture from the 60s attitude.
The houses are still the same. The old
school people. Yeah. Yeah. You got
Berkeley right there. They're still
out mounts of bar lounges and food
places and every background that you can
see in Oakland, you know. So, I love
Oakland. I love Oakland. I have enough
complaint about Oakland. Both cities
have a special place in my heart. The
whole Bay Area, you know. It's like I
remember going to San Francisco to hate
street partying back in the days,
tripping on psychedelics. Yeah. We also
do that in Berkeley. Uh but yeah,
Oakland is just, you know, I've I've
lived in Oakland on and off throughout
my life, too. So, like we we've had
houses, we've stayed in Oakland. We that
grows in Oakland, all that stuff. I was
a chef in Oakland. Okay. Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. I love Oakland. I love I just, you
know, just hate the bipping. They they
tanked out. But, you know, when you But
when you know, I think what made people
more in Oakland and do the bipping is
because social media hyped it. Yeah. And
now you got copy. They changed the laws,
right? So they said anything less than
900 and whatever dollars is is they
won't even they'll issue a ticket,
right? Rather than arrest you, you don't
get arrested, you just get served a
ticket. That's the problem. I think San
Francisco's now changed that laws and
it's the places aren't getting robbed.
So I was in New York um years ago and I
was cooking for somebody. I went to go
to the store. I needed some butter.
Yeah. I went to a little little market
and they got a little Marcus, real
little small Marcus. And I went to
market and I um get some butter and it
wasn't none. I said I asked the lady at
the store um you have any butter in the
back or something? Because there's no
butter. I I never seen a store without
the butter gone, you know. Yeah.
Seriously. Like it's got to be who you
ran out of butter. Who does that? You
know. Um she said oh no they didn't came
and stole the butter. I said they
selling butter now? She said yeah and we
don't stop them. I said why? She said
because they told us that we're not
supposed to intervene with the thieves
and that's why they come and say and the
police is not coming out. So they been
did this in New York. They were doing
this years ago. Then I start seeing
years ago start here like oh wow we run
our store now. So they not they're not
really coming and then they promote it.
They let you know in the news and the
law they're not coming out for this and
that trespassing homeless in front of
your store. I hope no they're not coming
to move that you know. Come on now. You
going to make people take matters in
their own hands and that's when you find
vigilantes start growing and stuff like
that you know. So yeah I seen a lot of
we could use a Batman right about now
man. We can use a Batman, Robin, and
Captain America. Seriously, we can use
all the superheroes to come back,
including ourselves, to actually do what
they got to do right now because it's
it's it's a grace. It's disgrace, man. I
I was looking at the Martin Luther King
parade yesterday in LA and the
youngsters is fighting out there and
they quick to post it on social media,
right? And you see the police responding
to it, but instead of cuffing the
youngsters um of the to the payment,
they pushing them. Oh, wow. because they
don't want the backlash of of their
parents saying, "Hey, you pushed on my
you grabbed my kid and Sam to the ground
and hog tied him or some they going to
bring up some respiratory problem or
something." So now the law enforcement
just suppression. They just pushing them
out the way. And when they push and when
they push them out the way, they going
away. They're not going to jail. No
consequences. Yeah. That makes it again
and again and again and again until
somebody the consequence is only going
to be if they do go to jail or something
else happened. over that should have
happened but then again when they don't
do it parents complain oh man why y'all
didn't take I heard people take them all
to jail take them all to jail just
saying that well they wasn't doing that
and then you show on social media so
everybody post on social media and they
see not taking them to jail now kids
feel like okay now we can do this and
some now they look to fight it like a
real whole fight that just on camera one
girl was right here selfieing herself
and they just fighting right here close
where these jars is I'm talking about
tens of kids just they not fighting like
bro But she wouldn't have been filmed
and she would have been knocked down.
Police is right there on her side
telling her to stand back mask and they
just pushing by like wait a minute
what's going on you know when do you
when do you really pay attention that
these kids really need to be disciplined
but they really need to be handcuffed
and took into juvenile hall and then
they realize what's going on because
what's going to happen they going to end
up killed or or they end up doing this
doing this and then turn 18 cuz most of
them is about 16. I seen somebody like
11 years old. Yeah. It's wild. I mean I
was 11 years old out there fighting and
stuff doing mischievous stuff but not in
that attitude to where you know your
parent our parents are grandmothers.
Yeah. They don't have a lot of don't
have their grandmothers. A lot of their
grandparents is my age and my age. My
grandmother was my age then but they had
rules. It was consequences. It was go
out there and get that switch. Yeah.
They hit you with this glass. They get a
pot. They take this ashtray and bust you
across your head with you disrespecting
them. Yeah. It was a different world
when I was a kid too. Like you get
whooped. You mess around. Yeah. I mean,
[__] around and find out. That was the
V. You know, it's like you [__] up, you
do some stupid [__] you're going to get
slapped on the back of the head. Hell,
you can't even You can't You can't even
whip. They going and they know they call
the police on you. Yeah. They'll call
the police on make a lie. Next thing you
know, you sitting there in the house and
the police knocking at your door for
you, not the head. We used to get spang
with wooden spoons. We used to get
spang, you know, bells, wooden spoons,
all that. Racetrack, the stitching cord,
you know. Oh, yeah. You might get hit
with a pitchfork or something across
your back. You messing around your
parents like People were way more
respectful back then. Yeah. They don't
nowadays they don't they're not they're
not respectful nowadays because they
don't know they don't know what's going
on. So it's it's it's it's a big
difference at what people do and how
these kids carrying theelves. I mean I'm
I'm I'm still in the discipline of my
kids. I'm into um constructive
criticism. I'm in really telling them
Yeah. You know, hey man, don't do this.
Tell them what's right. They they know
the truth and when you tell them a lie
that don't make them rebellious or make
them go continue doing mischievous type
of stuff. Let them know the real
consequences of being out there acting.
Let them know that uh they don't even
going to church no more. So you can't
tell them God don't like wrong ugly. God
said respect your parents your days.
They don't even know that verse, right?
You know what I mean? They don't pay
attention to that verse. They don't know
and they they playing they playing the
wrong playground. You know they playing
on the devil's playground and he don't
play games. You know, the biggest trick
he ever pull in the world to make
everybody believe he don't exist or he
don't believe such negative. Well, if
you don't believe in devil, then you
don't believe in God. Yeah. Straight
out. If you believe in God, you should
believe in the devil because right is
right and wrong is wrong. Yeah. And
there's two sides to every story. Just
like love spelled backwards is evil.
Yeah. Spell love backwards. It's e v o
l. Yeah. Yeah. So, do you grew up in the
Bay? You grew up in this area? My family
grew up in the Bay Area. Um I have a lot
of cousins up here. Yeah. Um I moved
actually up to the Bay um 8 years ago.
Oh wow. Just for a change. So before you
in LA? Born born and raised in LA. My
whole family for generations.
Generations. Generations. Nice. My
great-grandmother, my grandmother, my
mother, my father, all my brothers and
sister, cousin. The whole family's in LA
right now. But I have
maybe 15 20 cousins up here though cuz I
have a big family, right? So uh my
father, he has 13 brothers and sisters.
Let's say three of them move up here and
they all three got kids. And my mother
family have kids up here. So I have a
lot of cousins up here and then uh
friends I have accumulated over the
years in LA cuz you know a lot of people
in the Bay came to LA so I greeted them.
So when I moved up here they greeted me.
That's where I got the sick with the
chain from be 40. Nice. Uh that's
because of
when I got it was because of 17 years of
friendship. Yeah. You know so me and him
is real real close. Like I'm the big
brother now um to him. So you know he's
really close to me. Um me and his
brother D shot together every other day.
Nice. Nice. Help me with his music and
everything like that, you know. Yeah. I
love the Bay Area, though. That's my
It's like my home. It's my home. 9
years, you know. I'm Bay LA. Yeah. And
LA's special, too. It's got its own
thing. I like visiting LA, but I
couldn't live down there. The traffic,
it's just different vibe. I'm more I'm a
more of a NorCal vibe sort of guy. So,
we're working on these pre-rolls. You
You're testing some of the new ones. I
like the glass tips. I first started
smoking we you know, Snoop, that's where
he smoked them glass tips. Um, a lot of
people wonder where you get them glass
tips came from. Real started those. The
funky field tips. That was the original.
The flat ones. I like the flat ones.
Yeah, they kind of good. Who they had
them on blunts and loose? Um Louis the
13th. Yeah, Louis OG. Louis 13. I love
Louis the 13th. That's my buddy, man. A
good friend of mine. And that's, you
know, a lot of people was saying, uh
man, somebody whose roles for Snoop, who
rolls for Snoop and Snoop does this for
Snoop and Snoop pays this person this
role thing? They would ask me every day,
is you is you doing that? No, I don't. I
barely know how to roll. I I wrote
something really come up short.
Um Louis 13. Yeah, that's a good one.
Well, that's what he co that that's he
smokes that. So he'll bring them already
pre-rolled up in a little gold package
and let's box. You know, he come to box
eight in the box. So he would bring
Snoop a whole bunch of them already
rolled up. Snoop have to roll them.
Nice. And he just light them up. Light
them up. Light them up. And wow. That's
where you know a lot of people got the
idea who's rolling. They didn't figured
out because you don't be around Snoop.
You wouldn't know it. Snoop know how to
roll. Um, but he's homeed in on a lot of
Louis the 13 for years. He smoked Louis
He smoked Louis OG. He smoked Louis 13.
That Louis OG is classic. That's toxic.
He's He's He's everywhere. He's
everywhere. He'll throw the weed out the
window. Yeah. Yeah.
So, tell me a classic story uh with from
when you were on tour with Snoop. Uh, I
mean it's really one of my classic
stories with Snoop is before the tour
cooking. Uh, before I got to cooking for
Snoop because I went on tour with him in
2005. Um, how the West One was tour um
and that was my first experience
um on tour with another artist on his
tour and I did a single with him. Um,
one of my most classic experience with
Snoop had to do with Suge. Um, you know,
um, defro had You had to get a sample
clearance to use certain songs samples
of certain songs. So we had bought this
song uh the company I was working with
called Bogar Music at the time 2005 had
an artist name and they sampled a song
called Snoop Dog J and Juice by Cry Dry
Y Cry. So they had to go to Sil Knight
to get that sample. By that time Snug
Knight had to publishing for Dog Death
Real Music. So he was him and Snoop was
getting to it. So you know he wasn't
talking so he wasn't releasing none of
the songs to nobody. Um, and we had
bought the song. We had bought the verse
from Snoop to get on the song with him.
So, we let let's get on the song. Um,
but nobody Suge would not release that
song to the nobody. Wow. So, everybody
knew I knew Suge and that's how I met
Snoop Dog. Actually, through Suge
Knight, me introduced me to Snoop in '
92 doing the gang truth and me and
Snoopy got close in jump 96. I started
working with the rapper artist Mystic
out of New Orleans and that's how I got
close with Snoop. Then he assigned to
Master P. Yeah. I'll be with Mystical
and he'll see Master P and he like, "Hey
man, you up here. You everywhere." I
said, "Oh yeah, I'm just like you, man."
This he just starting his career off
there. Um then up jumped in 2005, uh
when he's Snoop Dog doing his thing, um
he Snoop Lion and this and that. I had
to get the song clear. They got to me to
get the song clear. So I went to Suge
Knight and got the song clear. Wow. And
believe it or not, Suge Knight cleared
the song for nothing. Nice. He didn't
charge us nothing. He he he did it I
think because he wanted to show that you
know I could do this however I want to
do it on the right of this here. I don't
charge. Bone me and Bone good friends.
Y'all met Bone through me. Uh Bone has a
nonprofit and I give clothes, toys,
turkeys during Thanksgiving, Christmas,
you know, to his organization, you know,
sponsor this and that. So yeah,
everybody knows it's the city of LA that
Su has a relationship with me. Even
Snoop did. And um I got the song clear.
Wow. And it blew up. Blew up. And we
went on tour
and going on tour with Snoop. We got
real close. Real real close. I'm talking
about that was my most excited getting
that song cleared and I did something
nobody couldn't do. Whether it was the
label asylum or the label Snoop or they
influence anybody influence in the
industry. Little old me come from the
streets. Yeah. And get a clearance
a$100,000 $200,000 clearance. But not
even a penny. Wow. Not even a penny.
Really cool. Yeah, that was my I think
that was my most
experience working with him because once
I got that cleared, we did the video.
Yeah. We went on tour song and on tour
um when we was on that tour, one of the
most one of the most iconic things that
happened
um is we was in Seattle performing and a
guy ran on stage and hugged Snoop and
boy that's a kid came everywhere and I
was out I was on the bottom floor on the
front floor and it happened to be a
handicapped dude sitting in a wheelchair
in small like a chair one of them he
really paralyzed and he was smoking and
Snoop has a joint to me the blunt to
pass to. That's why I do I would be down
there, you know, passing a blunt to the
crowd cuz I'm a road manager so I'm not
really have to be any place. I can be
anywhere. So I chose to be on the front
row, you know, pass through the fans,
seeing the fans, reaction to the show.
I'm a people's person. I like I go out
the audience, they see me out there like
wait my way out there, you know, Snoop
see me out there like I go past them. So
when I seen that happen, I jumped up on
stage and ran up there. I pulled the
dude off the stage. They wouldn't get
beat up and you know, hey, what are you
doing? You know, how you get up here?
What's wrong with you? You know, you
know, so that right there was one of the
most
like econic and classic situation with
Snoop and me, you know, to be there for
him, you know what I mean? And then for
him years later to come back and be and
recognize that from 2005 to 2016, we
were just cool. Um, never did nothing
else on tour. I backed over being there
with the artist and went home. Yeah. And
had me a child care center and I was
working at home then with my family
because I was going to roll from 96 to
all the way to 2006
on the road in music, you know, 92 to
200 92 to 96 I was doing nonprofit in
the community. Had a nonprofit program
today gang intervention program. So I
know how to stop the violence. I know
how to deal with the kids in the
streets. When I'm talking I'm just
talking out of reading the book. I'm
talking from my experience like my name
rang a bell in the streets at
peacemaker. My name rang a bell
reputation in the streets being who I
was before peace, you know, diffusing
the situation. Yeah. Yeah. Diffusing the
situation, stopping the situation,
building a solutions more than anything
else. So that situation won't have to
come back because you can't replace
something with nothing. Yeah. You can't
tell a person to leave a corner, you
going to give him something. Mhm. And a
I'm not talking about to give him
something to eat cuz he going to go back
to that corner. Yeah. Yeah. And if he ad
mentally not right, you can't give him a
job because he's going to mess the job
up. Yeah. So you have to send him to get
help first and stuff like that, you
know. So yeah, you know, so yeah, my
history goes a long ways in these
streets as far as peacemaker and right,
you know, community person. I grew up in
church. Yeah. I did TBN network. I've
been to the White House. Bill Clinton.
I'm one of the youngest I'm King Senator
Martin Atlanta credit Scott King. I
spoke at her funeral. I'm an obituary,
you know. I travel with her daughter,
Bernice King. Me and her brother and
sister. She's addressed me as brother. I
got dressed her as my sister. Um, we
travel the country together speaking
nonviolence. I I teach I'm certified
facilitator. I can teach uh the Martin
Luther King 10 steps king nonviolence
social change philosophy curriculum in
schools, colleges, police reform,
clergy, city
councs. I'm certified to do that. Yeah.
So, you know, I wear many hats when it
comes to peace cannabis. I never know
how to grow. I just know how to smoke. I
just barely learn how to look at weed
and tell the difference of what weed is
a certain weed is. You know, I was just
a consumer versus smoking weed. I I
really didn't even smoke weed. One of my
best friends got me to smoke weed when I
came home back in 1989. Yeah. I said,
"Well, I was smoking no weed. I didn't
like weed." He said, "No, man. I smoke
weed, man. It humble you out. Come on,
man. You hanging with us. You look at
yourself in the mirror differently for
sure. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I said, "Okay,
you're right. You're right." Hey, I
growing up I didn't really smoke weed
cuz otherwise I would get in trouble. So
when I did like 16, 17,
um I snug and did it, but I still
respected my great grandmother. Yeah.
Then when I went to jail, came home as
an adult, my grandma passed, I still
respected my mother. Like to this day,
mother rest in peace, but even with my
mother right now, I wouldn't u smoke
around her. I it just I don't feel
comfortable doing that. Even if I was
around your parents, I you know, it's
just a little that's something that's a
kid is not going to leave you. It's not
going to leave you to respect your
parents or your elders. Yeah. I don't
smoke in front of my parents. I'll go
I'll go outside and smoke but I'm not
going to smoke in front of them. I'm not
like that. You know, a lot of people be
doing hit the pen in front of my
parents. You know what I mean? It's just
not me, right? That's just it's a
respect thing. And I think for being a
older, you know, older now, now that
we're older people, we're not old yet,
but we're older. Yeah. Right. But we we
have a different level of respect for
our parents, for than a lot of the
younger people do. And there's some that
that are, you know. Yeah. Yeah. That are
still respectful. And there's some
really good young kids, young people.
But yeah, but it's a different world. So
Ricky Palamino, when he came on here, he
talked about being in New Zealand, how
he almost got arrested for weed with
Snoop and almost took the fall, got in
trouble. There were cops were going to
arrest him if Snoop smoked on stage and
then he smoked. Do you guys ever get in
trouble? Even at the times, like I said,
I've been on road with him since 2005.
Yeah. Actually, that's when that first
tour I went with Snoop on the road and
got to know Snoop, start smoke, how we
doing everything. Me too. We smoking
weed. Yeah. It wasn't legal. So, you
know, you had to just make it different.
But, but the cities all embrace new
pretty good, I think. Yeah, they do.
They do. Yeah. Some Yeah, they I mean,
they did then because, you know, back
then it wasn't no $200 thing on the
road, you know. It wasn't none of that,
you know. It's that you just don't
smoke. You know, you smoke a cigarette.
You smoke cigarettes, they didn't care.
You know, no weed problem. That's what
really shopping because, you know, he's
willing to pay for it like right now.
Yeah. It ain't no ain't no if and buts
about it. Yeah. It's smoking going on in
his room in the hotel. No, they can say
they go they like they tell you find you
500. He go 500. Good smoking. Yeah. He
go 500. Stop smoking. Right. But they
it's bigger than just one little room
with me as a Snoop. He's coming to you
say he's bringing you customers. Yeah.
And he's and he can take away your
customers if he boycott this hotel. I
bet. Yeah. You know what I mean? So it's
like a battle between them cuz I mean
it's like Thunder Valley. Yeah. They're
not playing about you smoking a weed in
Thunder Valley, right? What? We was
smoking all down. It was smoke. It was
going down. But you can smoke
cigarettes, right? You can smoke
cigarettes all day long at a casino and
all that. Way worse for you as far as
way worse for you. You know, Hollywood,
you can't smoke cannabis on the streets,
but you can smoke cigarettes. Yeah.
Yeah. That's going to change. Yeah. You
know, um No, you could you can smoke
cannabis in Hollywood, but not
cigarettes. Not cigarettes on the
street. That's That's okay. Hollywood.
Hollywood is like cannabis friendly.
Yeah. That's why they um you know that's
there's a lot of places in LA that look
the other way when it come to that. I've
seen happen here too. New York you can
smoke freely. I just did New York Times
Square cooking for Wonderramama TV and I
smelling cannabis. So I look back and
Yeah. You can smoke on the streets. No
problem. And they're right there. The
police right there next to the police.
He just a blow. They used to be the
worst before. They used to be the worst.
Yeah. And they had the right to stop and
frisk you. They used to be the worst.
And I had a friend of mine um good
friend of mine long time ago um this is
like maybe n maybe early 2000s um he got
caught with a joint coming through the
Las Vegas airport they banned it for 6
months. Wow. I even come back to Vegas
for a joint. And Las Vegas is fully
legit now. They got dispensaries all
over. They've really embraced the
cannabis. I feel like they need more
smoking lounges there. But like the They
do. They do. I mean they they do because
you can't smoke nowhere. No. You you
know you you can't smoke outside on the
sidewalk. You can't smoke in the hotel.
So you know so if you have a really big
suite, you could smoke weed all you want
on the balcony. Well, no smoking the the
big sweet. Oh yeah. Yeah. Yeah. If
you're in a parlor suite, some of the
big suites you can smoke. Yeah. Yeah. I
had Yeah. They don't The smoke alarms
don't go off or anything, man. There was
people smoking cigarettes and everything
in the That was um I was at the Plazio.
The Plazio. Yeah. and let the next they
together two next poll right next to
each other. Um I was in in a big old
right a big old big night doing Champs
one year like three years ago doing
Champs. So me Ron Bass Dab Star Josh
Dabar Josh and his wife and a few of us
and we was in a big old room big my
cousin that rented big nice penthouse
theater room and everything. We was
smoking so much in there that the alarm
went off in the room. I thought the
whole hotel went off, you know, cuz it's
got the flash in the room. It was just
in the room. We just flashed it. But
it's smoked out. They had to bring the
big fan in there. I said, "We going to
kick us out. They going to kick us out
this room." No, they they said, "Hey,
man. Y'all smoking too much, man. Kind
of take it easy, cut the fan on, left
two fans in there to to blow the smoke
out, right?" And they did not find us
another. That's when I said, "You know
what? You that's a trip. You can smoke
in these big old suites and get away
with it. Ain't no ventilation going out
here. Then you got a little room where
you can, you know, flip the little
window out, try to blow out the window
or they come and find any tobacco. Yeah.
Loose tobacco wrapped up in a napkin. In
a trash can, they going to say you
smoked marijuana. Yeah. Not messing
around like Yeah. Don't throw no napkin
in the trash can. They'll take that
napkin out the trash can, open up, and
if it's tobacco that you done broke
down. Yeah. So, you can see I haven't
smoked the tobacco because it's just
broke down. It's not smoking. It's not
ashes. It's no ashtray. Ma'am, I took I
broke it down and rolled my cannabis and
I went downstairs to smoke, right? But
because it's on your clothing, when you
come back, the scent is in the room.
They figure it got on the curtain. So
that's it. They got to find you. It's a
It's a business of make they're in the
business of making money on all $500
every time. I just seen that all weekend
the other night at the Hilden Garden
reveal. $500. I said, "Oh yeah, [__] I
won't be smoking them in here." Yeah. No
way. I don't even smoke. Matter of fact,
I just wait till I left. Right. And then
when I didn't come back for a couple
hours, I just smoked and uh So if you
have one piece of advice for your
younger self, what would that one piece
of advice be? I would go back when I was
15 years old with my younger self. Yeah.
And when I I would say street life, I
would have took the way I did take it.
Gang banging. Yeah. Some of the things I
did, activities that I applied myself
to. Mhm. Um I would told my younger self
not to do that. attest to these 15 year
olds and 13 year olds today. Yeah.
Because at that age, you make a decision
to step into a whole
different life as a teenager to a grown
teenager because you at for 15 you
become that young adult almost because
18 you tend to do things before you get
21 preparing you for 21, right? That
three threeear cycle and everything age.
So 12 to 14, you're all right. Yeah. 15
to 16, you better wake up. It's sort of,
you got a decision to make. You going,
you know, you take your training wheels
off your bike. You You can go home. You
go to school by yourself now. You know,
enough to be dangerous. Yeah. You know,
so I would tell my
15-year-old, stick to the positive
things in life. Take advantage of
education in school. Take advantage of
your religious belief. If you ain't in
peace with God, keep it peace back then.
cuz that back then you didn't have no no
devilish attitudes unless you if you did
go to church you was going to church a
lot of people my I told my 50y old go to
church more go back to church more you
know participate in sports participate
in school um you know think a positive
future and you know you know that's
basically I can tell you live your life
but you know just grow I would tell my
old self just take your time I take my
time now so yeah I would just tell my
younger self hang with the turtles not
the rabbits Yeah, that's nice. Well, if
people are looking to find out more
about Cubone, where can they go? Well,
you can go mostly. You can find me on
Instagram at Big Cubone 52. Cooking with
Cubone Show on Instagram. You can find
me at Big Cubone on all social media
from Twitter with X they call it now.
Tik Tok. You can ask James Loud. Yeah.
Amazing. Well, it's been really great
having you on the show. I'm looking
forward to cooking with you in the very
near future. Oh, yes. Oh, yes. doing a
lot of stuff, man. I put a lot of stuff
with you tonight, man. Yeah. So, yeah,
it's a pleasure. Pleasure coming on your
show, man. Absolutely. Thank you very
much. You're welcome.
Thank you guys for watching. Please like
and subscribe down below.