[Music]
Welcome to another exciting episode of
the James Loud podcast coming to you
straight from the heart of Catalonia,
beautiful Barcelona, a city that pulses
with vibrant energy and a zest for life
like nowhere else on earth. I'm thrilled
to be here in one of my favorite cities
where the culture is as rich as the
history is deep. Barcelona, a city
famous for its breathtaking
architecture. From the surreal creations
of Gaudi to the medieval charm of the
Gothic Quarter, is more than just a
feast for the eyes. It's a culinary
paradise where every meal is a
celebration, and the flavors are as bold
and dynamic as the city itself. From
mouthwatering tapas to fresh seafood
that dances on your pallet, Barcelona
offers a gastronomic adventure that's
second to none. And what better place to
host spannabis, one of the largest and
most celebrated cannabis gatherings in
Europe. This year marks a bittersweet
moment as we celebrate the final
Spanabis event in Barcelona. It's a
significant chapter in cannabis culture,
drawing enthusiasts and experts from
across the globe to share, learn, and
celebrate the art and science of
cannabis. While it's sad to bid farewell
to such an iconic event in this
incredible city, we're here to make this
last one the most memorable yet. Join us
as we explore the vibrant culture, dive
into the dectable food, and experience
the amazing cannabis scene that
Barcelona is renowned for. We'll live it
up one last time at Spanibus, soaking in
every moment of this unique gathering.
First up is the Barcelona Dabadoo, a
very special event which is a kickoff to
the week of Spanabis and also to
celebrate Mila's 80th birthday.
[Music]
How's it going everybody? I'm here
kicking off Spanabis 2025 at the
Greenhouse/Strain Hunters Club in
Barcelona with Arian Rosscam. How are
you doing today Arian? We're doing great
guys and James loud guys this weekend
spanabis at the greenhouse booth. So I
hope to see you all there and have a
great weekend in
[Music]
Barcelona. I'm here with Dr. Green from
Trinidad. He was in a strain hunters
documentary in 2011 or 12. 2011. So we
met at the High Times Cannabis Cup in
2012. And then we got Ashwin here. How
you doing today? I'm doing very well.
Thank you, James. No, so I know James
for many, many years now. I sold your
seats. Yeah. Seat center over the
counter. But most
remarkable, something I will never
forget is when
Sunset Sure first landed here in
Barcelona. Yeah. And there was one man
that took it to
Spanabis and people were lining up for
that. And that's how it got here. I
don't know. But yeah, I I had it in
Spanabis. You had your hands on it. We
did that. I know. We did 2013. And it
was just Yeah. game changer. I will
never forget. And that's because of the
flavor, the flavor profile, something
unique and it lingers in in in in my
memory. So, I feel like the flavors from
today that people know as gelatoes and
all these gelato derivatives all really
started with sunset sherbet. There was
cookies and they're all derivatives of
cookies too. But really that sunset
sherbet kind of set the trend on that
that candy dessert profile
and sure that sunset sherb had power
which I think is also important like
flavor effect something that like when
you smoke you know that you're smoking
nowadays everything is flavor. Yeah. And
you can empty bags after bags when
there's so much similarity between
everything. Right. And Sunset Sherbet
back then really stood out. Very
special. Yeah, Mario did a good job
growing that, man. Got to give it up to
to Mario for growing that. Sherbinsky,
big shout out. 100%. Shout out
Sherbinsky. Yeah, I mean, there was
people that started seed companies off
of the bag seeds that came out of the
sherbet packs. I know that people called
it even Spanibus sherbet. Like Phenofer
has a Spanibus Sherp in their Totally.
He crushed it. He crushed it with that.
Yeah, he did. Well, it's great seeing
you here. What are you expecting out of
Spanovis 2025? It's the last Spanabis we
understand in Barcelona, right? So, I'm
sad to be honest with you because as you
know, most of us are here the last
decade at least at least 10 years with
clubs that we're accustomed to. People
were accustomed to. We were both here
when they opened this club up. Yeah.
2014. 2014. Yeah. So, we have our places
already. and to to see the expo move and
go to somewhere else cuz a lot of people
are saying oh it's going to stay the
same people are going to come but that's
not true if you can't sell oh sorry if
you can't market your brand in spanabis
coming from America coming from the UK
and all that are you really going to
come to Barcelona in March just to hang
out with how many friends are actually
going to be here so it's sad it's sad
for me that things are changing and uh
hopefully you know we'll all find a new
location to that's similar enough to be
together. Maybe Mary Jane like the
Caribbean. Maybe the Caribbean, you
know, that's definitely Mary Jane, too.
But it's not just once a year. We need
to get together multiple times a year.
It can't just be once a year. You know
what I mean? So, like we need our
spannabis type event right around this
time of year. We need the Mary Jane type
event. We need the Caribbean events. We
need the California events where people
are coming to California to the events,
I think. And and you know, if the right
people are listening, I mean, you know,
every show has its audience, right? But
if this show eventually maybe does get
to the political aspect of Barcelona,
the mayor especially, I mean, look,
Spain has a ton of money as a country,
maybe from the old slave trade days, I
don't know. But it's still, why would
you as a country discourage tourism that
is not affecting anyone that is taking
away from illicit market opportunities?
And we know that when when cannabis is
sold on the street, the monies from
those illicit activities go to more
illicit activities, firearms and all
these other issues, right? So if you
have a a licensed operation that I mean,
you look around through the video here,
you see it's a social club. People come
here to consume cannabis peacefully,
right? And then leave peacefully. It's
one of the greatest things you could do.
If anyone hears this, the thousands of
people that come here every year for the
purpose of consuming in the clubs, it
should be something to be considered to
be kept. Definitely. I for me, it's hard
to argue that this planet doesn't make
the world a better place, right? So, at
the end of the day, I feel like the
people here are
bringing positivity into this world.
They're, you know, whether they're
consciously doing it or not, they're
making the world a better place. And I
think that's my big argument for all
these types of events. I think sharing
our stories and experiences, coming to
these events together, you know, we've
been doing this for a long time. Yeah.
Yeah. That's almost a little over 10
years now. Yeah. 13 years together,
right? And then besides what we've done
on our own, you know, like, you know,
and it's like without these events, we
would never have met. I have more good
friends out here than I do in my own
country, you know. So, it's it's
something that it's something that
should be encouraged, you know, the
social aspect of it, the coming
together. One small event sometimes
brings 20, 30 countries together, you
know. That's impressive. That's
impressive, you know. So, Spanabis
brings definitely a lot more, you know,
as a whole. So, and it brings money into
the economy in Barcelona. I think that
the people here, they're they're not out
to hurt people. They're not out to rip
people off. They're not out to do bad
things. For the most part, they're
really good good people. And the most
important thing for the government to
understand is that because you know I
come from a regulatory standpoint so I
like to put it in is that without the
clubs without the social club system
even if you put it intoarmacies you're
going to encourage and increase the
illicit market which will encourage more
problems in the end. So the best thing
to do is to license legitimate
legitimize and regulate more clubs
simply. I think that's the best thing
that they could do here in Spain
personally. I mean everywhere, France
also, you know, most of the European
countries. So, well, thank you so much
for your time. Thank you very much.
We'll do this again this week. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. Definitely. It's going to
get busy. So,
[Music]
So, I'm here with Lance from Grove. How
are you doing today, Lance? I am doing
well, buddy. It's always good to see you
around the world as always. Absolutely.
It's always good to see you. We bump
into each other everywhere. We're going
to be bumping into each other more this
year at several events including
Germany. But we are here for the last
Spanabis today and it's the Puffpuff
Primortal, right? Is that is Yeah.
Puffpuff International Primordal. So
it's kind of the whole start of it. This
is the the birthing of the start of
Spannabis. As you know, we've been doing
this for years, man. Forever. Yeah. and
and it works up and it only gets better
day after day after day. So, we figured
we'd be a part of the Big Bang before
the official start tomorrow on Friday.
Really cool. And you guys have some
amazing food. There's a lot of amazing
guests at this event. You know, I'm
really looking forward to Spanabis this
year. It's, you know, they're saying
it's the last Spanabis. How do you feel
about that? Dude, this it's bittersweet
because this is my eighth year, I want
to say, sans co so doing it for a
decade.
Um, you know, Spannabis is a part of
Barcelona, like you and I both know,
like we come out being being California
kids, we're used to this weather, we're
used to this vibe, but to experience it
in the other side of the world is always
specialty. And so, the fact that they're
saying they're going to take it to Bil
Bao, which I get, they're finally,
they've been talking about destroying
the fairgrounds for years. Yeah. So,
they're taking it to Bil Bao, but it
doesn't have the same energy as
Barcelona. They don't have the clubs.
Maybe a couple clubs versus two or 30
hundred. Well, they're saying they're
taking it to Bilbao, but they've been
doing it in Bilva. They They did last
year. They did it in Bilbao. Well,
they've been doing Bilbao for a long
time, right? I think on and off. Yes. On
and off. And they did bring it back last
year cuz before they did Madrid and that
kind of Right. Yeah. And I mean, I have
bittersweet feelings. I mean, it's like
I've loved Spanabis. This is my single
favorite event to go to every year. I
have friends that I only see at
Spanabis, and I hope I'll see them at
Mary Jane as well. But it's like such an
amazing event, right? Like I mean one of
the best interviews I ever did was at
Barcelona.
You and I both, man. Yeah, we we had an
amazing amazing interview that no one
will ever get to hear. I know. They'll
get to see they could see it, but they
never hear it, right? They didn't record
the sound, but that's okay, you know. I
mean, exactly. We're still here. We're
still doing it. I love it. You know, I'm
excited for the next three days. It's
going to be a lot of fun. I'm too, man.
And talking to some friends that are
local coffee shop owners. Stefan from
Prettyme. Shout out Lorenzo from Turpps
Army. Screech from Dank of England.
They're all talking about getting
together as the coffee shops. Yeah. And
doing a weed week out here next year
regardless. They should. And I have a
feeling guys like you and I will still
roll up for that because to be able to
do all this and not have to go work a
fair for three. Sounds good. Yeah. It
sounds a little more intimate. It's like
when the big band goes and plays all the
small clubs. I love that. That's exactly
it. That's exactly I think it'll be
dope. Looking forward to it, man.
Looking forward to hanging with you this
week. Absolutely. Thank you very much
for the time. Yep. You got it.
I'm here with Sebastian from 420 Fast
Buds. So, how are how are you feeling
about this being the last Spanibus? It's
not the last Spanibus, just the last
Spanish in Barcelona. Maybe not. Who
knows? But last in Lfira for sure cuz
they're tearing it down, right? So,
exactly. They're tear tearing down the
whole fairgrounds, which is sad because
I feel like this pyramid maybe it's not
the most modern anymore and people need
something more modern, but it's iconic.
It has people with tattoos of the
pyramid on their backs. You know what I
mean? It's really it's it's amazing
event place. So, you know, as far as an
event center, some place where we've
been going for a long time to these
events. I I love the I love the venue,
right? And I every year I love the fact
that you can go to the same place and
find the same people, right? Greenhouse
is in the same place. Most of most
people are in the same place for a long
time. Always same. Always 196. You come
in first. It's first first move on the
left, you know. That's just Yeah. Um, so
let's put it this way. I don't want to
be one of those people who are like,
"Oh, the end of an era." It is the end
of an era. But is there something new
coming? Of course, there's something new
coming. Is Spanabis Bilbao, which is
going to be They've been doing it in Bil
Bao, though every year, too. But it's
17th, 18th, and 19th of April. So, we
have to check it out. And I need to
throw a 420 event the next day. So,
after everything is over, of course,
somebody needs to do it. And if not me,
who can do it? Absolutely.
But I go without any let's check it out,
right? Is it going to replace Banabis?
It can't. It can't replace here. It's 20
years of coming. It's a huge scene here.
It's a beautiful city. And I give VBA
the chance, but it won't have the
infrastructure to hold 50,000 people,
you know, like that, not to host them
and stuff like that. Well, Germany, what
they're going to they're expecting
100,000 people in Germany this year.
It's going to be crazy.
Let's see. Last year was cool as Yeah,
cool. But a nightmare. The organization
of the fair was a nightmare. There was
trash everywhere. Like nothing was
working. This year they organizing it
double the size. So I'm sure they're
prepared. Everybody learns from their
mistakes. And I am excited for this very
much. And I think that eventually Berlin
is going to take the place of Spanabis
in Europe and we will have events like
Spanabis Bilbao which will be amazing
but it won't be it won't be as impactful
as Spanabis Barcelona but it still will
have impact right there's still people
there's still people I know that go to
Bil Bao every year you know so yeah I
mean I'm really excited for the next
three days it's going to be really fun
it's going to be really busy but yeah I
I love this this is you know we're in
our element here. You know, this is this
is what we love. This is what we do. So,
I I come home at 1 2:00 in the morning
and I get up or I leave the house before
10. This is day after day after day
after day. Um, your body sometimes just
screams rest when you come home, but you
always want more. Or, can I maybe add
one more club, just one more dab? Can I
do this more? It It's We're, as you say,
we're just fully in our element. That's
what we live for. It's going to be wild.
It's going to be wild, man. Thank you so
much for your time. Thank you for
everything, man. Always. Always. Thank
you so much. And you know what I always
have to say at the end. No. Oh, yeah.
You have to remember that it's 4:20
somewhere. How's it going everybody? I'm
here with Dan Her. How you doing today,
brother? I'm doing very well, dude.
Thank you so much for uh giving me some
time, carrying the legacy on of the late
Jack that that's impacted so many of us
on so many levels, right? And it, you
know, it it's true. That's like every
every time I like we're here in Spain
and I see the things that he helped to
start and inspire here just as he did in
the US and so I get to feel his energy
everywhere I go. Yeah. I mean his legacy
lives on. His impact was so great it's
felt everywhere all the time. Yeah. I
you know the legacy by the way is not
me. The legacy is this. It's all it's
all of us. It's it's this you know I'm
Jack's son but this is the legacy.
Right. Right. Absolutely. you know, it's
so much greater. I mean, it's like the
Grateful Dead, how they've impacted our
whole industry. And Jack is is on that
same level. I feel I I I think from the
cannabis, you know, standpoint, I he's
one of the very few people I think that
has truly changed the world by, you
know, being as passionate and outspoken
and
unrelenting and and authentic and uh
unapologetic and unapologetic. Yeah.
Yeah. So, tell me about everything that
you're doing. And I heard you're doing
all kinds of wild stuff. Well, uh, we're
looking to bust into the European market
in multiple ways. Obviously, cannabis is
a is a tough, uh, you know, development
right now, but the the Jack brand is
more than just what people look at as
genetic, right? Um, you know, everything
from clothing to
wine. Wow. To be real. Yeah. So, we we
have a jacker wine. Nice. It's a It's a
German wine uh made from a Dutch
company. It's uh it's an alcohol wine
with Jack our Turppins. Yeah. With our
our partnered uh Tarpine uh company uh
Abstracts Tech. Oh, I know Abstracts
Tech very well. That's awesome. Yeah.
And then uh we're also partnering here
with uh a brewery called Gross. Nice.
And Gross Beer is doing a jack beer
which will be launching next month. So
you guys putting Jack Turpps in the beer
and Jack Turps in the wine? Yep. That's
amazing. And uh you know, we we wanted
to create something that was truly
sharable, like people would want to sit
down and and have the beer with their
food and sit down with uh a mate or a
date and uh and and truly enjoy a glass
of wine. So, if it's if it's not
something that you want to sit down and
share, Yeah. we weren't interested in
making a novelty product. We wanted to
make something that that really um did
more than collect dust on a mantle
somewhere. Totally understandable.
Totally understand. I feel the same way.
I mean, I think that authenticity
resonates so heavily with within our
community especially. It's just so
important to have something that we all
enjoy that you can give to somebody and
they want to use. I mean, cannabis is
supposed to be used fresh, right? Hash
is hash you can smoke years later, is
still good. Flower on the other hand
does not smoke good years later
typically. Typically. Yeah. But there
are some good there's some people that
have figured out how to store it. Well,
yeah. I I mean I can preserve it for
months, not years, right? But that's
true. But who knows, you know? I think
that the depending on what you like. I
think the turppines change over time.
Frenchie canoli always talked about how
tarpines changed over time, you know,
within the hash. Uh, you know, so he was
a smart man. He was a smart man. another
guy that just really contributed heavily
to the community around the entire level
of culture within cannabis like the hash
culture, the hash world benefited by his
absolute dedication to just his
devotion. Yeah. And same thing with
Jack. It's like these people are so
devotional. The these are the guys that
I look up to right every day. Yeah. You
too. I think you're doing some great
things. Yeah, thank you. I think being
the second generation and being the
legacy, I think you're doing a great job
and I feel like expanding into these
other markets where you can introduce
tarpen into alcoholic beverages is
amazing. I love it. You know, being a
chef and and having a background in
culinary arts, I have a lot of respect
for people that are trying to branch off
and to do things um that that aren't
being done, right? Anybody can copy
somebody else, but to pave the way and
try to go into other stuff, not knowing
if it's going to work, but having a gut
feeling, it's it's that devotional
quality, you know, that makes the world
great. I I I I agree. And, you know, I'm
I'm expecting push back. Yeah. You know,
you're going to get push back, but [ __ ]
them. But the the the reality is is um
if something's good, then it's good. If
you know, it's good food, it's good
food. If it's good wine, it's good wine.
If it's good beer, same, you know.
Absolutely. Um I I I I I don't uh
segment between alcohol and cannabis. I
mean, if you go to most any cannabis
event, there is alcohol and cannabis.
It's only it's only the government that
tries to keep everything separate. Yeah.
You know, but we we know what brings
people together. And this plant in this
community is is perfect for pairing a
wine with a hash or um you know, a dab
or a joint. and then being able to
experience uh a a plethora of
of you know taste. Well, the
experiences, right? At the end of the
day, these are experiences. And when you
can give somebody experience that they
wouldn't otherwise get from somewhere
else, you're on to something. That's how
I feel about it. So, I I I I'm I'm
hoping that we're going to be there for
the long run and and that uh people will
uh give it an opportunity because uh it
it is different when you get the notes
of cannabis in your wine. Uh, so it kind
of messes with you for a second. Sure.
But, uh, you you give it a chance, you
taste it, and you realize that I could
[ __ ] with this. Yeah, dude. I I think
it's amazing. So, Logan, I used to work
for Logan, right? I did I was a chef for
Logan. I did uh music festival. They had
a beer festival, music festival. They
combined it called the beer circus.
Anyway, Logan had a tarpine beer. Uh,
they were the first ones. I believe they
worked with
uh Absolute Extracts, not Absolute Tech,
but Absolute Extracts and and they
released it and they got, you know,
letters from the DEA, Cease and Desist,
and all this stuff, but it was amazing
stuff. Yeah. Well, we did a a beer
collaboration with Sweetwater Brewing in
2020. Oh, wow. They produced uh 10,000
cases of Jack uh Tarpine beer. They sold
it in about 30 days, right? And then
they were bought by a Canadian company.
and the Canadian company cut off all of
the cannabis branded uh or licensed uh
beers. Yeah. On the flip side, the beer
was delicious. I wish they would bring
it back. Um but uh you know, moving
forward, here we are in Barcelona. We're
working with a great brewery uh brewery
uh Gross Beer and uh I look forward to
coming back here next month and uh and
launching. You know what I'm really
looking forward to in the weed world is
people crossing Jack Carrera again.
Bringing back some of those old Jack
crosses, the Jack Flash, the Jack Frost.
You know, the the Jack hair is still out
there. There's there's versions of it
out there that are good, really good.
And but back in the '9s and early 2000s,
there was a lot of var variation with
Jack, right? There was so many people
breeding with it. You were getting all
kinds of cool stuff. And I would love if
the world came back with the Jack. Yeah.
Well, we do our own crosses. Uh but
we're really focusing on uh new
standalone uh genetics that are specific
to our brand. Yeah. And and we're really
hoping that uh expanding the oper the
the options for Jack pre-rolls infused
pre-rolls, the the multiple different uh
flavors and products that we have
through the the flower side of things,
right? That people will understand that
the the brand is more than just the
single genetic. Well, and it almost has
to be because the thing with Jack is
it's so dominant when you cross it to
other stuff. A lot of times you get
Jack. Yeah. Right. You know, everything
becomes Jack and Jason, right? You know,
it's like, oh yeah, that's Jackie.
That's, you know, and we want we want
people to enjoy Jack and some of the
crosses, but we also want people to just
enjoy cannabis and and something unique
and and hopefully they can find that
with some of the things that we're
developing with the brand. Yeah. Well,
if you guys are interested in fenos and
feno hunting, we're doing that all the
time. So, I'd love to have you up at the
facility. Come by, check out the stuff,
do a tasting. You can sit down, have a
lot of fun. We can do a pairing. I I
would love that. Actually, I'm doing a
new food show where we're doing uh weed
and food pairings, right? So, I'd love
to have you on it. Featuring you know,
we'll we'll send a case. We'll do it.
I'm down. I'm super down. Thank you so
much for your time today. Many
blessings, brother. For sure.
[Music]
Yo, what's popping y'all? It's your boy
J Rocker. We out here at the Hash
Calabash 2025, Barcelona, Spain. You
already know what it is. We out here
celebrating Hashish cannabis sativa in
the name of the late great Frenchie
Canoli. So give thanks yo for Frenchie
and all the teachings passed on to the
hashishins worldwide. So we out here
united in the name of a legend and we're
having a great time breaking bread,
checking out turpps from all over the
world international. We got 20 different
countries in the house with us tonight.
So people brought out turpps from
Canada, from the States, all across
Europe, from Africa, and elsewhere. So
it's a beautiful thing. We love y'all.
Thank y'all for coming out. Thank y'all
for showing
love. Heat. Heat. N.
[Music]
I'm here at the Hash Calabash. We're in
Barcelona. I'm here with the Cannabis
Brothers. You guys just flew in. How you
guys doing today? Oh, [ __ ] better now
that we just got here because I need a
[ __ ] dab, dog. That the plane ride
was rough, I bet. But we're here and
it's our first time and we're [ __ ]
excited. Yeah, man. This is great that
you guys finally made it. Last time the
only thing that showed up were the
seeds. Yeah, we're the seeds. Seeds and
a little hash. And this time, this time
we we uh we brought some seeds and we
got some uh special [ __ ] We brought
some elkui for Spanabis. That's awesome.
Yeah, it's going to be a really amazing
event. They say it's the last one in
Barcelona. How do you guys feel about
that? I'm I'm glad we made it cuz it's
our first time here. At least we made
this last one. It's going to be epic,
especially for me and my bro. It's going
to be really epic for the for our our
friends, the the brand. It's [ __ ] I'm
excited, man. You guys just blew up
again. It's not It's not the first time.
This is the second time, you know? I'm
back. Yeah. It's good to be back with
all our with all our original friends,
James. Oh, totally, bro. Saw the
Olympics, dude. Was really amazing.
Like, your booth your booth was crazy.
Like, literally, every time I walk by,
there's a line at your booth for people
trying to get flowers. It was It was
dope. Yeah.
[Music]
Every year I host a dinner at my
favorite restaurant in Barcelona, El
Pasadis del Pep. It's always great to
share an incredible meal with my closest
friends.
[Music]
We're coming.
Barcelona.
I love Barcelona. It's amazing.
[Music]
Day one, Spanabis 2025. We're here at
the greenhouse booth
56. Man, it's uh bittersweet. They're
saying it's the last Spanabis. I'm
hoping that's not the case, but you
know, it's amazing. It's been raining. I
wasn't sure how the attendance was going
to be. And we got people coming in in
droves. Lots of happy people, lots of
excited people. You know, it's it's
pretty wild. The energy here is alive.
We got everybody from the States is
coming here that hasn't been a Spanamas
before. I'm blown away by how many
people are here, you know. Come check it
out.
[Music]
I'm here with the legendary Adam Ill.
How you doing, Adam? I'm I'm great, man.
Staying high in Barcelona, smoking weed,
chilling out. We've been coming to
events for a long time. I've been seeing
you at High Times Cannabis Cup 2012.
Yeah, the old school high times kind of
the very first American Cups. You were
in all those. They were good times. It
was a different time than what it is
right now. It was a lot more taboo back
then and a little bit more like, you
know, still secretive, but it's so good
to be in a in like a in an international
city where I'm smoking weed from like
Switzerland and Finland and Germany and
Spain, like all sorts of different
countries. Oh, no. Morocco. I had some
stuff from Iran. A guy from Iran.
There's a breeder from Iran here, too.
And it's like that guy has balls, dude.
To be able to pull that kind of stuff
off, that's very impressive, you know.
But, uh, you know, we've been doing this
for a minute. It's good to see you still
out here making it happen. And, you
know, just love to see the evolution of
cannabis in the whole event space.
Fighting the good fight, dude. Yeah.
Doing it. Just making it normal. Just
normalizing it. Changing the the the
tone. That's what needs to happen, bro.
So, thank you so much for coming on.
What? Smoke more weed. And shout out to
all the growers, too. Please keep
growing great weed so we can smoke it.
I'm here at Spiniz 2025 with Rob from
Pacific Rim Fusion. He's been from a lot
of things over the years. We go way
back. We go back to before cookies was
even cookies. Absolutely. Yeah. Yeah.
Put it on the map. We're out here in
Spanish, though. 2025. Feels like
California 2015. [ __ ] loving it out
here, man. That vibe is great. So, is
this your first spanabis? This is my
very first Spanabis. Uh took me a long
time to get out here. We were supposed
to come out here in 2019. Then CO hit
and ruined the whole thing. So, put a
little damper, but I made sure to make
it out here. Thank god I did since the
last one in Barcelona. Yeah. Yeah. I
know. It's It's bittersweet. It is. Tell
me some of the highlights of your trip,
man. Uh, you know, being in the industry
as long as you and I have, we've seen we
we've seen this, but we haven't seen it
in a long time, right? This feels like
California 2015 to me. Uh, which is very
honestly, this feels like 2010. It's
always had that early high times vibe
where we had these cups and it was very
it's nostalgic for me because everyone
was so passionate about weed. They
weren't bitter about the industry yet.
They weren't jaded. Now these people
walking around here love weed. They love
everything about the plant. They get
excited about edibles still. They get
excited about, you know, brownies, the
hash. They love the hash. Not even good
hash. They just get excited about hash,
dude. Like it's just it's an incredible.
It's still about the love of the plant,
you know? It hasn't been ruined yet by
the by big business. corporations or or
just the evolution of where it's going
to go with the legalizing, you know.
Sure, sure, sure. The people that don't
make it, the big guys kind of start
taking over. The little guys fall to the
wayside. And uh yeah, but out here, the
vibes, the vibes big, it's strong. I
love it. I can't believe it took me this
long to get here. I can't believe it
took you this long either. Glad you're
here, though, bro. Thanks, man.
Appreciate it. So, tell me about your
new venture. Okay, so I recently joined
uh a company called Pacific Room Fusion.
about eight months ago, they brought me
on as as a consultant to help them kind
of build out the user interface, their
new their new platform. And then uh both
of us kind of gained more and more
interest in the other the other person
or the other group. And long story
short, we're few weeks away from launch.
And it's essentially kind of a a B2B
weed maps or or a eBay for for cannabis
and hemp CBD. And it's worldwide, right?
So, North America, Western Europe,
Southeast Asia, South America, any hemp
producing country, uh businesses can get
online kind of post uh uh like a whole
like a eBay type listing for bulk
product. So whether that's seeds,
whether that's hemp, whether that's
biomass, isolate, flour, or whatever,
they can it's an international
marketplace for people to communicate
with each other. And then in regulated
areas, say like within the states,
regulated companies can meet each other
on there as well. Really cool. Yeah.
Nifty little idea. It's pretty novel,
dude. Thank you so much for your time,
dude. I look forward to having you on
the podcast again. Yeah, I would love
that, man. I appreciate it. Good to see
you, James.
I'm here with Dave C from the Adam Dunn
show. How are you doing? How's your
spanamus going? You're loving it? I'm
loving it. It's a great event. I'm a
little sad that it's the last one in
Barcelona. Uh we'll see how Bill Ba goes
next year. Yeah, it might not uh have
the infrastructure yet, but they have uh
a year to prepare for us. Absolutely.
We'll see how it goes. What are some of
the highlights of your trip? I love
catching up with old friends that don't
come over to the States for uh the US
Canada events. I was hoping there would
be more technology here, you know, for
to sort of uh focus on the European
market, but it this is a breederheavy
event. I mean, a real breeder heavy
event. I don't know about a seed
producer. Maybe there's there's a
handful of breeders and a lot of people
making seeds these days. There are
truckers out here. Yes, they are just
throwing anything forward. But uh there
are a lot of people selling genetics.
How about that? Yes, there's a [ __ ] ton
of seeds in the building. That is for
sure. Had a great time here. I'm looking
forward to next year. I'd like to see
more of Spain. I'd like to see more of
you. You got to come out to the podcast.
I need a host, a co-host. Uh, you're
you're Are you trying to recruit me on
camera? I'm recruiting him on camera. I
just offered Dave double the salary.
Double? Holy [ __ ] So, double zero time
zero. Why don't you go four times? Yeah.
Yeah. Okay. Four times. Okay. 0 time 0
time 4 is still zero. Adam, step your
game up. I might. Well, maybe he'll sign
a big contract. Write it for me. And uh
I would love it. Yeah. I mean, you know,
you're you're a great co-host, Adam. Big
shout out to you. If it wasn't for you,
I probably wouldn't be here. Yeah, I
still remember scooping out uh several
hundred of rosin from your jar.
Absolutely. The emerald or wherever it
was. Yeah. Thank you. For sure.
Appreciate you. Thank you for your time.
You got it.
[Music]
Nat.
You're making loud noise and smoking
loud weed on the James Lou podcast in
Baron Spa at the Spanish baby. Take a
look around. It is a beautiful day to
smoke weed. It's a beautiful day to buy
seeds. It's a beautiful day to be alive
and to be involved. Enjoy
[Music]
yourself. Hey, we are on location with
Meno. Dope. Could it get any louder in
here? How you guys doing today? Oh man,
we're doing so good right now. This is
epic to be out here. Yes. Super fun
time. We are stoned. Absolutely. This is
the place to do it. The smoke is in the
air. It's uh 6:00 on a Saturday night. I
I'm loving it. It's still packed. This
place is packed and doesn't seem rolled
up. Yeah, we got some CBDs rolled up in
the blunt because we've been smoking so
much good stuff while we've been out
here that we haven't smoked any CBDs
yet. This is the So, this is Flow
Gardens. Flow Garden won CBD at Spanabis
third place last night. Boom. Third
place. That's even more such a big treat
for us to be able to enjoy some of the
top contenders. Top tier CBD flour. Like
I wonder what the first place looked
like cuz I'm impressed on this one.
Yeah, me too. Maybe it's rigged though.
You never know. You never know. It's
always rigged. It's always rigged. So,
how's Spanabis treating you? You guys
first year out here? Yeah, this is our
first time out in Europe. First time at
Spanabis and it's been like amazing. So
ex just crazy all around from the the
views of everything, the food, the
people being out here at Spanabis to
enjoy it in Barcelona before it changes
makes it so special to us. You guys are
out here performing, too. You're a hash
calabash. We I missed you guys. Like we
left we must have left right before you
guys came up. Yeah, I saw a picture this
morning. I was like, you were there on
the couch where we were? What? I didn't
know you were there. No, that event was
great. It was a cool little event. Yeah.
So, being able to perform out here on
the main stage, totally unexpected. Uh,
snuck on there and got to do two songs,
which one of them was a dedication to
Frenchie Canoli. It's coming up on our
new album. It's called Ooh La. And it
was just so awesome to see the whole
crowd vibing with us. Like, perfect
timing. It's such a good crowd here. The
people are so passionate. Yeah. I mean,
not just the Spanish people, everyone
from all around the world. Everyone is
loving it. It's just good vibes, right?
Pure vibes. Good vibes. Good weed. And
there's really good weed. So when I
first came to my first spanabis, the
weed sucked. There was like Don and
Aaron had good weed. There was a handful
of people with really good weed. How
long ago was that? 2012, 2013. Oh, wow.
Yeah. That was my first year. So I've
I've been to a lot of I love this event.
Major revolution. And the X track game
out here, dude. Like pretty ridiculous.
I bet the Skittles rising out here has
been next level, dude. Oh, really? Wild.
Yeah. Yeah. So with the water and the
climate that different regions have in
the world is so cool to see strains that
we've kind of got to know especially in
Cali or even in our own county of
Menescino or you're the Bay Area grown
and then to see some of this grown in
Spain and see what turpps it kind of
expressions brings out from this climate
and this I think the water has a lot to
do besides just climate these days. Oh
yeah, the water that you're feeding it
can change the flavor also and bring in
the vibe from wherever your region is.
Well, most of us have such chemically
treated water in California. Very true.
So places like this makes sense. It
should be. And the hash makes sense
because once you're using a lot more
water and you're cleaning it. Yeah. It's
very awesome. Very delicious. How is
that? Delicious. That's like super bomb.
It's so smooth, too. It's like just on
the inhale, exhale. Nothing but just
smoothness. I can feel it's like insta
calming almost relaxing me already.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I love it. It's nice.
19% CBD. It's got to have like 4%
turpps. See, that stuff is wild. It's
tasty. It's It looks nice. It smells
does not look like CBD. It looks like
THC. For sure. Yeah. But you can smoke
that whole thing down and you're just
going to be relaxed. You'll feel the
tobacco more than you'll feel the weed.
Yep. For sure. Yummy. So, how's it been
for you out here though? Cuz you've been
rocking at this. I love this event. I
love the people here. I love everything
about it. Like, we got a lot of people
that watch some podcasts from all over
the world that have come up and wanted
to take photos and want to hang out,
smoke. I got a lot of gifts from people.
It was really cool. So when I was
younger by I won a cup in 2012 in
Amsterdam and I saw people come up to S
and gift them stuff. There was guys
crying when they gave S stuff. Like
literally crying when they were giving S
stuff and I was like that's pretty cool,
you know, and to just get a lot of, you
know, getting positive feedback from
fans. I just we have a lot of good
people out there, you know, and I feel
like my podcast isn't really just me.
It's about the guest, right? That's what
So it's just great acknowledgement when
it's like they're telling me I'm doing
something good, you know? For sure.
Yeah, I could totally dig that. It's
been so cool to be like this far from
home, you know, for our first trip out
to Europe, out to Spain, and like to see
like how much love and from people from
all over the place coming up to say
what's up, and how long they've been
following us for the past 10 years, and
like you guys are crushing, dude. I
mean, you guys,
a long time. And it's so dope how so
many people have been like real hardcore
supporters of us from the beginning and
still here with us. Well, and there's an
evolution of what you guys did. you
know, that's spread out al across the
globe, you know, there's all kinds of
stuff, dude. It's it's amazing when you
throw a a pebble in a pond and create
those waves, dude. And how they [ __ ]
just take their own shape, right? I
mean, in a sense, we're all an evolution
from the Grateful Dead here, right? And
then you guys evolve from the Grateful
Dead to you guys into all these other
little projects that people have done
and bands. I mean, it's just it's a it's
a vibe, right? It is. It's a total vibe
and we love it. This is the cannabis
culture. This what we represent and
support. And uh [ __ ] James Loud, man.
He's our homie right here. Real deal ser
like real deal breeder, you know,
passionate about this culture. Someone
who really knows what's up and like this
the kind of people that we need on the
on the front line, you know, standing
our ground with real Ganja soldiers out
here and we're doing it together and
we're about the community. Community
about all about all of us. Yeah. We're
all stronger together. Our roots
combining. We're building an unbreakable
foundation out here. Right. Well, and so
many of us see ourselves as individuals,
but I love looking at the community as
one. Yeah. We're working it. You know,
we're trying to just master our craft.
Go out there and spread this culture and
just have fun with it, too. You know,
the game is hard right now. There's a
lot of people getting taken out of the
game and big corporations coming in, but
with people like James Loud, people like
us, and these other companies that are
holding it down for real, like this
culture will prevail. It will prevail.
And it's through the collaboration
model, right? Through the collaboration
model, we can all work together. And
it's a beautiful thing. Yeah, it is.
It's a It's a worldwide collaboration
now is what's really cool. Seeing this
really opens my eyes to what's been
happening and what we're seeing
happening in this moment, too. It's just
like a lot of really cool worldwide
possibilities for us to come together,
not just as a community uh or a county
or a state or a country, but a world
now. It's crazy. We're taking it back
over cuz we're still blown away that
they took it from us all these years
ago. How did the world go hate the plant
all at once? Such a money-driven
scandal. And now we're turning the
tables finally, right? And we're talking
about a plant that for thousands and
thousands of years we used it as
medicine, right? And then all of a
sudden it's gone, right? And then and
then the people forget, right? They they
forget, right? It's easy to forget for
people raised with it. So they're like,
"Oh, it must be bad." We're told it's
bad, right? The stigma of it stays with
people way longer than I somehow
understand. Still there's that stigma,
right? Still there slowly but surely
because people our age, right? The next
generation has changed. After our kids,
it's over. Well, we got donors like us
smoking hard and people seeing it and
we're productive people. Exactly. You
know, I mean, productive Americans.
We're doing our job, you know. We smoke
tough, but we get the job done for sure.
That's right. Well, thank you guys so
much for taking the time and I really,
of course. Hey, thank you for having us.
Shout out to James Loud. Shout out to
everybody out there. Dope, dude. You
guys killing it. Kaka. Much love,
everybody.
I'm at Spinabis 2025 with Eric from Flow
Gardens. He just won third place last
night for CBD. How are you doing, Eric?
I'm doing good, James. Thanks for having
me out, man. Absolutely, man.
Congratulations on the big win. I think
it's a big deal. Going home with
hardware, for those of you guys that
don't know, it's a big deal. Spanabis is
one of the biggest festivals in the
world, and to go home with hardware your
first time is a big deal. It is. It's
actually a dream of mine. Uh fair dream
of mine, and it's never happened. So,
good job, dude. Like, thank you. Yeah. I
mean, I won high time skin cups. I won
other stuff and this is the last one.
So, I won't be getting a Spanabis piece
of hardware in my life from at least
unless they have another life, right?
Well, I entered your pl hoping that
would win. Uh it didn't take the place,
but that's okay. Yeah. I mean, that's
indica is a tough category, right? Like
there's a lot of good flour coming in
for the for the entry, right? Yeah. So,
yeah, THCA, you guys are crushing the
THCA. Yeah. So, I was just smoking your
flour with Meno dope, the applesauce,
the high level C. That's That's high
CBD. I was taking big hits out of a
blunt. And the funny thing is I felt the
tobacco more than I felt the weed in a
good way. And like you can smoke a whole
big freaking joint of it and you just
feel amazing. Exactly. Yeah. But it
satiates you in the same way that
like Well, not in the same way a a
non-alcoholic beer does, but like it
satiates you in a way where if you like
smoking, but you don't want the effect,
you don't want tight eyes, you don't
want to be tired, uh it's a great
alternative, right? Yeah. It gives you a
good head change and it lasts for like
30 minutes, you know? Right. Well, thank
you so much for taking the time. Of
course. Thanks for having me, dude.
How's it going everybody? Day three. I'm
here with Kelly from Dragonfly Earth's
Medicine. How are you doing today? I'm
awesome. It's super nice to see you
today, James. Absolutely. It's been a
year since we saw each other. It has. We
had a great debate last year. It was It
was amazing. I love when people can talk
about stuff openly and debate stuff and
just, you know, and have a difference of
opinion sometimes, but still be able to
talk about it in a nice sensible way.
Yeah. Yeah. Well, I feel like if it if
there's respect for one another and
there's true respect for the plant, then
it's really easy to find that common
ground. I agree. And I think at the end
of the day, we're all here because of a
plant, right? Something that changes the
world, something that makes the world a
better place, something that makes us
smile when we talk about it. Absolutely.
And you really can feel that energy and
vibration here. You know, the people
that you meet from all over the world,
multiple different languages, all
different kinds of strains, and really
the vibration is super high because
cannabis just keeps us at that high
vibration. Absolutely. So, what are some
of the highlights of your trip so far?
Oh. Oh gosh, I really We did a whole
bunch of um club reviews this year and
that was really fun. At the beginning,
we just thought, "Oh, we'll just sort of
mess around." and that it turns out that
not a lot of people have done club
reviews. So, I felt like so welcome and
like family at every single club that we
went into and to review them and really
highlight them and put them out into the
world. It felt really good. So, I'd say
that was one of my highlights. That's
awesome. Yeah. And it's such a I mean,
they're saying it's the last year. I
mean, that's kind of sad if it's going
to be the last year, but everything
evolves, right? So, it's never the end.
Yeah. Yeah. And there's Berlin. There's
other things. I love this city, though.
This city is so special. This city is
really special, especially to walk
around in the night and I think a lot of
our events are late night so there's
that quiet time where nobody's out in
the streets and you can really feel like
the ancient city and I know I know that
a lot of the other cannabis people are
walking around because we see them late
at night too and that's pretty magical
here. Yeah, it really is. And there's so
much energy and so much history here and
it's like from one place in one area to
the next there's different energies. You
know, the Gothic corner has its own like
strange energy like it can be kind of
dark in certain places. Now, you look at
some of the architecture and it's kind
of dark some of it and and then, you
know, you go into the Borne and it's I
love I love Borne. It's like it's
interesting. Yeah, the Borne district is
one of my favorites as well. And then,
you know, you add a little bit of micro
doing or even some macro dosing to that
and things are really interesting and it
comes alive in a whole different way.
Yeah. Monzerat. If you guys haven't been
to Monzerat, we have. It's so amazing. I
love the energy there is so next level.
So next level. Yeah. I mean, there's
like energy swirling out there, you
know. And unless you see it, you would
never understand what I'm talking about.
Or maybe you would. You would. But uh
Yeah. I love Monzerat. Yeah, I do too.
and to really see that uh Madonna and
then how it's recreated with, you know,
the baby Jesus or whatever that vision
is and the fact that it's in there. The
mystery is really elusive and beautiful.
Well, it's amazing that they hiked up
into the mountains and carved this out
of the the mountain side. Or did they?
Or did they? Or did they? There's so
many big questions here. You know, I'm
really really more than anything I walk
around this city and I question our
history and like, wait a minute, that
doesn't really make sense and maybe this
doesn't make sense. But that's the
mystery and the beauty of it all.
Absolutely.
Well, are you going to be in Germany?
Going to be in Germany for sure. It's
awesome. Yeah, we'll be there for
probably ICBC as well as Mary Jane and
maybe even having a little bit of a base
there for a while. Wow. Wow. Really
cool. Yeah. Yeah. I'm really looking
forward. I've never been to Berlin. I
missed last year, but I can't wait to go
this year. Yeah. So, we'll see you there
for sure. Thank you so much for your
time. Thanks so much, James, for
everything that you do. Thank you. Have
a great day. Yeah. You're coming on the
podcast in the near future. I'm coming,
everybody. She's on the podcast in the
near future. She said it here first. I'm
coming. Thanks, everybody. Thanks,
James.
I'm here with Aladdin Khalifa Genetics,
Spanabis 2025.
How you doing today? I'm very good,
James. Dude, how you doing? I'm doing
fantastic. I'm I'm doing really good,
man. It's really great having you on the
show. We need to do another We need to
do a real podcast. I'd love to have you
in California. Absolutely. It'd be an
honor and a pleasure. So, you are the
exclusive so far, the exclusive guy with
the books in Europe. If you need the
breeding book, you're the guy to see.
You get it on khalifetics.com.
That's what I heard. Yeah. Apparently,
we're the only ones in Europe. So,
that's great. And you guys have been
selling through books, which is great.
It's great for me. It's great for you.
It's great for the community. And the
feedback on those books is great. Thank
you. A lot of people that order from
Germany mostly. Yeah. Some people from
France as well and Spain and the
feedback is great. Great. Yeah. I mean,
you contributed the book as well. A
little bit. A little bit. It's all a
little bit of everything together made
the book what it is, right? Well, yeah.
Without those components, the book
wouldn't be what it was. Well, I was
very surprised by the quality of the
info that's in it. you know, there's a
lot of scientific terms and it goes
really really in in depth into those
things. You know, there's a lot of
details and there's so many pictures and
like you said, there's so many people
that contributed to it, too. Right.
Yeah. And that's the beautiful thing
when we can collaborate on these levels.
I mean, collaborating on genetics, we're
doing some big collaborations coming up.
So, I'm looking forward to it. Yeah. And
it's like I want to collaborate with
everybody. I love being able to
collaborate and work together with good
people that are like-minded, sharing
genetics, and we all have our own
styles, right? That's the beauty of this
whole thing is like I can use my style
for genetics, you can use yours, and
together we can collaborate and create a
whole new thing. Well, yeah, cuz we all
have different tastes and different ways
of selecting of cultivating everything.
So, totally different. But like once you
combine those two different things, you
could get something very surprising,
right? Quality is so subjective. People
think, oh no, quality is quality.
quality to you and quality to me.
Especially at that level, there's
there's like these nuances. Yeah. And
that's what I love about it. Especially
some of these breeders. They Some guys
are very outside the box. Some guys are
very straightforward. They just do the
same thing over like everybody else. I I
like the I like the innovative outside
the box guys. Mhm. Well, like you said,
you know, like you said, it's like,
well, it started, you know, with like
only THC and stuff like that and
everybody was into THC. And now where
there there's a lot more people looking
for different things, nuances of
secondary canabonoids, rare turpps. So,
now it's the market is evolving,
maturing, and it's way better. So, I
like it that way. Me, too. I can't wait
to see where this goes in a couple
years. How do you feel about it being
the last Spanabis? This one? The last
one? I didn't even know it was going to
be the last one till like what 2 weeks
ago. Yeah. That's a little bit
disappointing and I don't know the the
reason why it's the last one. Honestly,
they're tearing this whole building
down. Yeah. But and so they're going to
move it to they they say they're moving
it to Bil Bao. Um but Bil Bao is not the
same as Barcelona. It's different vibe
and I think that's great. But I heard
they're also going to be doing it on 420
weekend next year. Okay. So that's going
to be really tough for me to go to
unfortunately. Oh man. Yeah. And it's
not as international as it is here. No.
It's harder to fly there, right? So,
yeah, everything is a little bit more
complicated. So, yeah, I'm I'm surprised
that we're weren't able to find another
venue here in Barcelona or in the area.
This is my single favorite event of the
year. Absolutely. I love Barcelona. Mary
Jane, we're going this year. That'll be
great, too. But yeah, and I watch your
podcast and you talk about Spanabis so
often on there. So, yeah. Well, I mean,
I have so many good memories hanging out
with people like yourself. It's like I
have so many friends and the only time I
see a lot of them is here. Yeah.
Likewise, man. Yeah. very special. The
weather is great. It's not that great
over there. So, I don't know. So, what
kind of new projects are you working on?
So, we're working on a special project
with the Frosties Purple Freak, which is
a mutant. Yeah. Which is also purple.
Very tiry as well. Yeah. And you gifted
us some seeds last year. And now we're
trying to create an auto version of it
with one of your best autos. So, it's a
very ambitious project. It's very, very
hard. It takes a lot of plants, a lot
of, you know, you need to hunt a lot in
order to to recombine those highly
recessive traits, but it's fascinating.
So whether it works, whether or not it
works, we'll see. But it's very
interesting to be doing that. I believe
it'll work. It's just about how long it
takes. I think it's a numbers game.
Yeah, you're right. We'll see, man.
Statistically, it's possible. We got
Statistically, it's possible. It's just
a matter of time. Yeah. Time and energy.
Time and energy. Yeah. Patience. But
like when you're radar, you know that.
Right. But yeah, it's the long game. Oh,
yeah. If it we'd be growing flour if we
didn't want to do seeds, for the short
game, right? That's And I would like to
ask you a couple questions. Sure. How
long have you been a breeder for before?
Like you were a grower at first and I
was a grower. I grew. Yeah. I started in
closets, right? Closet growing and then
breeding. Uh we started early 2000s
playing around with it. I was a really
bad breeder in the beginning. I just,
you know, I was like, put some pawn on
here. The the thing is is anybody could
make seeds in the whole world, right?
Anybody who can get a male plant, take
that palm and put on a female plant can
make seeds, right? The magic from
breeding actually comes in the selection
process. You know, it's like you're
talking about double recessive traits
and stuff like that that you're working
with. That's real breeding. I mean, it's
it's in the selection process finding
those new phenos to actually breed with
to to share with the world. Yeah. You
make seeds, you want to call yourself a
breeder, I don't care. I don't really
care what other people I look at myself
but like for myself breeding really was
like for the last 15 years we've been
doing real work you know I mean I think
for the last 15 years there's some guys
that have been doing a lot longer you
know but I think it's a passion-driven
industry anybody that wants to breed can
breed you just have to understand that
the selection process is the real
breeding seed production is seed
production yeah but I have a question
about that so do you think it can be a
breeder from the get or do you think it
has to be a pollen chuck at first and
then you start breeding after you get
get the hang of hunting and all that. I
think it almost should always start as a
hobby. But I think you should learn how
to grow really, really, really, really
well so you can make the plant express
cuz if you're not growing it well, it's
hard to select your keepers. You know
what I mean? Everything looks very
similar, right? You're not getting the
expressions of the nose, you're not
getting expressions of the structure
properly. U and so the better you grow,
the better you can do selections, the
better breeder you become. Exactly.
Right. Yeah. You have to have that
dialed in and then you can, you know,
take that to the next level, right?
Don't just jump in the industry and I
want to be a breeder. Like, yeah, you
can want to be a breeder, but learn how
to set that foundation up for success.
And read the book, right? And read the
book. Yeah, definitely. And read the
book. Yeah, it's available online, too.
So, but yeah, dude, thank you so much
for your support. Thanks, Billy, for
your time as well. Absolutely. Thank
you, man. I'm very glad to see you
again,
bro. Thank you, bro. Thank you. I'm here
in Spamis with Dust. I know. from
greenhouse seeds strain hunters. You are
a strain hunter and you're I'm a
wannabe, too. And you're a good friend.
Nah, you're and you're an amazing
person, dude. You're always happy. You
have this contagious happiness vibe that
just spreads throughout the industry. It
touches everybody. I try to keep it
smiling, you know. Yeah. Yeah. Well,
someone's got to be happy all the time.
Not me, but man, it's it's contagious.
You're a happy guy. Yeah. Yeah. I try to
be happy, dude. Don't be humble. So, so
how's your spin of going? Great. Great.
It's uh Yeah, it's a lot of meetings,
you know, a lot of people that you're
going to see probably for the last time
cuz who knows what's going to be the
future, you know. Yeah, that's when you
say it like that, it makes me sad. But I
I there's some people from this industry
in Spain, you know, that would come
here. I don't know if they go to other
places or so. Yeah. There's a lot of
people I only see at Barnabas. Yeah. So,
I'm appreciating every every minute, you
know, I just say hello to everybody. A
lot of people coming to say thank you
and stuff, you know. So, it's always
amazing to meet all those people
watching the videos. You never see them,
you know. So, and you've been working in
Thailand. You're doing all kinds of
stuff out there. It looks pretty fun.
Yeah, man. Thailand is like a paradise
now. That's why you're smiling all the
time. It must be. Yeah. It's so good.
Oh, yeah. And the good weed. Yeah. a
really good weed you know we do really
good everything R&amp;D we can do a lot of
R&amp;D on everything you know take hunting
every trains one by one make from it
make rosing from it see how many persons
each you know so all this is stuff we
can document for the catalog for
everything so it's great and you get to
spend a lot of time with plants these
days a lot of plants fantastic so tell
me about some famous amazing moments
that you've had at Spenabus
uh Well, some of my best memories here
go was before opening the club, you
know. So maybe 2012, 2013, something
like that was also the beginning of
dabbing. So here you could really see
the first really good BA shows, you
know, like cuz in Spain it was not a big
scene yet, extractor scene. Oh yeah. So
people from America would bring great
stuff, you know, and so it was the first
times that you had those kind of
turppins that get to your mouth cuz it
was a [ __ ] kick in the face, you
know. You guys was over turppins, right?
that all with Franco. It's just the
amount of of flavor, you know, that you
get from a BH dab at that moment in the
history, you know, it's like, wo, what
is that, you know? Yeah. Mind-blowing.
So, I I still remember those days, you
know, and yeah, great times, you know,
and hanging out with Don and Aaron. They
always had really good extracts and
stuff, you know, and and then the
Spanish people here got really good at
it. So, Oh, yeah. They really did. You
know, it's funny the evolution from 15
years ago in Spain to now with
extraction, with flour, with everything
else. Exponential exponential growth.
And you know, people are they take it
real seriously here too. The guys that
are really passionate about it take it
serious. I would I would say that some
of the best hashmaker in the world are
in Spain now. Most of them are Italian,
including everybody. Yeah. They all
here, you know. Yeah, they're all here.
And they all got inspired by this
culture, you know, by this energy that's
in Spain, right? in Barcelona in
particular. You know, Barcelona is a
different vibes. Yeah, I've seen some
amazing hash in the last couple days and
all over the place. You know, a lot of
stuff is amazing. Great hash, great
flowers. Yeah. In the States, we have
like the papayas and the GMOs and stuff.
There's a lot of diversity out here and
diversity with types of hash. A lot of
people still love bubble hash. It
doesn't have to be rosin. Yeah. I love
it.
And we still have the love for the
Moroccan, too. Oh, yeah. The real the
real tradition. This is where Europe is
really attractive, you know, right? You
also have like the roots. Yeah, for
sure. You got the new school, the old
school all together and everything in
between. Yeah, that's all there. Nice.
So, thank you so much for taking the
time. It's a pleasure, man.
[Music]
[Applause]
I'm here. Day three, Spanabis. It is the
final countdown. We have hours left of
this day. It is the last Spanabis. I'm
I'm a little sad. It's bittersweet. It's
amazing that we're here. It's Saturday.
It's the last
[Music]
day people. Hi again, Homegrow TV coming
to you from Spanabis 2025. We just
picked ourselves some fresh James. We
got the drips and we got the foam party,
baby. So check it out. Homegrow TV. Hi
again YouTube channel. We're going to be
growing these suckers out from seed to
harvest. Oh, and Basement Grow Show.
Shout out to you, buddy. Couldn't make
it, but he's going to be growing them
out, too. And wash testing these
suckers. So much love
[Music]
everybody 2025. I'm here with Aaron from
DNA Genetics. How are you doing, Aaron?
Good. Last in Barcelona. Good to see you
here, you know. Absolutely, man. The
last time we saw each other was it was a
kind of a sad day. Sam the skunk man.
Oh, yeah. Skunk man. Sam passing. Yeah,
it was it was a nice memorial. It was a
really nice memorial. Really good people
showing up to the memorial and you know,
he his contributions to our industry
were huge. Did you sign the book that uh
Douggee has over at his booth? No, I
need to get over there. Oh, yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. There was a booth over
there. He said, "Oh, you got to sign." I
the only booth I ever went to except for
like right here. Yeah. I'm the same way.
I did not leave my booth the entire the
entire weekend, you know. I'm here solo.
I got my cameraman, but I've been
running the booth myself. It's been uh
it's been a lot of fun. We got our
collaborations, too. The chocolate runs
I made with your chocolate. Chocolate
cuts. We may be having cuts available to
the public in the near future. We'll
just have to see. Direct to consumer off
our website. Yeah. Hey, keep your eyes
open for those cuts. The show been good
for you? It's been amazing. It's been,
you know, I It's amazing. Every time I
get to hang out with you guys, it's, you
know, we've been hanging out together
for a long time. But seeing my friends
just like you guys at events. It's like,
it's great bumping into good people that
are out there for the right reasons,
that respect the plant, that have been
putting in the work. You guys put in the
work before anybody else coming out of
the States. You know, you were kind of
the first American seed company to
really almost I mean, there there's some
others in front of us. you know, we
can't forget like Watson was Dave Watson
for I mean there's guys coming out of
the 70s and 80s, right? But but as far
as like modern times, West Coast
genetics, bringing OG, bringing that gas
to Europe, showing the world how it's
done and showing guys like me that you
could do it, right? Yeah, you could do
it. Like you just put your foot on the
gas pedal and we got that common
connection with S because S's uh been
part of our lives at different points in
our lives. But yeah, S was an important
pivotal part in my life as well as
yours. Yeah, S's here. Uh before we
started DNA. Yeah. Good times. So tell
me some what what's your best memory of
Spanovis? I think the best times of
Spanish are the times I don't remember.
Nice. Yeah. There's lots of those. You
know, lots of those for sure. Like we've
gone out and had dinners over the years.
Yeah. You know,
and and you know, it's just it's just a
party. Yeah. It's one good party. It's
one good party and you you know you end
up going from one place to another place
and you know I'm not from around here so
I couldn't tell you where the [ __ ] I
really went. Yeah, I feel you there. But
there's I love this. I spent a lot of
time here. The dinners the dinners here
are amazing. Thank you so much for your
time. I look forward to seeing you in
Berlin or at home if you guys are coming
up. We need to do another podcast. We
need to smoke some more weed. We need to
release these clones to the public so
everyone can try the cross. It's it's
been uh it's always good to see you.
It's always good to see Oh, bro. It's
always good to see It's always good to
smoke out with you, you know. Well, I
think we just ran into each other like
at the Z Olympics, so we could Oh, yeah.
We were literally at the Z Olympics.
That was the last time we saw each other
was Olympics. We were both so high that
Yeah, that was a good time though. Yeah,
that was amazing. That was like 2012
high times cannabis cups. Like that same
vibe. Medical days. Wild. Shout out to
James Loud in the Loud podcast. Much
respect DNA 2025. Perfect. I am here
with the man, the myth, cannabis. Chris
from SF Canada, San Francisco,
California, my hometown. How you doing,
Chris? I'm feeling great. I'm doing
great, man. Spanabis is amazing, dude.
So, this is your first Spanabis? Yes.
Very first one, dude. Amazing. And so,
what do you think of Spanabis so far?
Again, uh I've only been here for the
two days. I missed the first. Um but the
two days I've been here has been [ __ ]
wild. Yeah. Second day was crazier than
the first. And uh today seems to be
shaping up to be an amazing day as well.
You feel me? Highlights of the trip so
far? Highlights of the trips are well, I
would have to say I can't say too much
about the party last night, but um all
the dope little social clubs that I've
been walking into. Alma social club, um
the 420 uh area 420 yesterday. Uh what
what's the other one? We met at We met
So we we met You came to the bar, right?
Came to the bar. That was Paradiso. It's
the number two bar in Paradiso. Paradise
all of Europe. Paradiso. We had the back
room out. We We blew secret room. You
walk through the back door, through the
toilet. I mean, the [ __ ] is wild out
here, man. Yeah. The Speak Easy. It's
like very uh American style speak easy
secret back room to the bar. Yeah. It's
my first time in Barcelona, period. And
it reminds me a lot of I swear I was on
Market Street in Frisco a few times. I
swear I was in LA, uh, New York a few
times. Uh, it just has that vibe. Um,
and again, I'm having a great time
smoking the best, out smoking the rest,
per usual. Uh, what about you, James?
Don't get that [ __ ] confused. Don't get
this [ __ ] confused, man. Hey, if it
ain't cannabis, Chris approved. Keep it
100. Uh, look for some new drops. Me and
James got some [ __ ] fire dropping,
man. Uh, oh, no. We're dropping some
stuff together in a couple months here.
Literally, we're dropping some fire.
Some [ __ ] fire. some loud [ __ ]
genetics that are coming exclusively
from the man to the right, you feel me?
So, uh, look for that and look for some
new music. I'm dropping some new music.
I am an artist and, uh, you feel me?
Again, you got this cannabis [ __ ]
confused if it ain't cannabis. Chris
approved, baby. I'm here with Dave from
Gas Town. How are you doing today, Dave?
Super good, man. A little baked, but you
know, we spanis to be expected. A little
tired, a little baked. Had an amazing
weekend. You guys had a busy booth.
There was people all around your booth
the whole time. Yeah, we're grateful to
have the community. You know, this is my
eighth span of And uh I think our fourth
year in the booth, so uh we seeing
people year after year. Luckily, they
come back and say hi and it's really
cool to see the familiar faces and the
love and year after year. And I love the
chill vibe of the greenhouse booth. You
know what I mean? It's like we got Chris
from
Cipher, you guys, and us just having a
good time here with Greenhouse. And I
mean, these guys are very inclusive.
It's exclusive, but it's inclusive.
Uh so grateful to be part of this booth.
These guys year after year treat us like
family and just give us an opportunity
that I'd never be able to have any other
way. Um we're front front and center and
uh just like you said, the vibes are
super inclusive but exclusive at the
same time. And all the top brands and
names in the industry uh always come
through here and say hi. Arian and the
crew is just a no-brainer. And just to
kind of witness and be a part of that
energy is a really cool vibe for sure.
Totally. It's like one big family. I
love the community. I love I love the
industry we're in and they we can be so
cool with everybody else in the industry
and there's so many good people, right?
Everyone's doing their own part to kind
of elevate the plant 100%. And like uh
the good people definitely have been
drawn together over the years as they
see it and then just more and more you
see them kind of getting drawn together
and raising each other up and lifting
each other up. Yeah, that's it's a
beautiful thing. It is for sure. So tell
us some of the highlights of your trip.
highlights of my trip. Uh being in
Barcelona, the the dinners are probably
the highlight of my trip here to be
honest. And obviously connecting with
all the people um whether it be people
who, you know, follow us and are huge
supporters or people who I look up to
and uh get to see year after year. You
know, there's all the people being from
Canada, just a little brand. Seeing all
these big names from California that I
get to connect with. Um, I'm just super
grateful to have these relationships and
uh it's just just really cool to uh to
be able to come all the way out here so
far away from home and build these
relationships that are really cool and
people that I've always looked up to.
Absolutely, man. Well, thank you so much
for your time, dude. I really appreciate
it. My absolute pleasure, James. Yeah,
we got to do another podcast. I I got to
come up to Canada. We'll see if they let
me in. But yeah, either way, I'm down to
come down to the podcast anytime now.
Definitely lots to talk about.
Fantastic. Thank you so much, Chase. My
problem. Cheers. So, we're here wrapping
up Spanamis 2025. I am here with the
king of cannabis, Arian Rosam, and Dust,
his uh right-hand man, killing it over
in Thailand. How are you guys doing? I
think we had an amazing amazing the best
Spanish ever. Yeah, absolutely. It's
been great. Crazy turnout, but like
crazy. Everybody came in. Oh, man. Thank
you guys so much for the hospitality.
You know, this is the third year I've
been at your booth. You guys have saved
me a lot of heartache from having my own
booth. It's great to be part of
something much bigger than ourselves.
You know, I I couldn't do what I do
without guys like you. No, it's We are
very happy to have guys like you in our
booth and give people from the other
side of the world an opportunity to be
with us and feel the great feeling of
Spain here and the cannabis world here
in Europe. So, thank you for coming
again. Absolutely. So, tell me some of
your best memories of Spabis.
Yeah, there's so many. There's so many.
opening our club in 2014. I was there.
It was amazing. It was during the spies
also. That was quite I think maybe the
most amazing moment for us. Yeah. Yeah.
That was special. I was pretty happy.
And still until now. Well, last night
you saw every night the club is packed.
Every night. That's wild. Yeah. Very
successful. Super happy with that. Some
of the best flour in the whole city.
Yeah. Good food. You guys have really
good food there. So like if you're
looking for food, you got to go check
out Strain Hunters. Absolutely.
Barcelona. The burgers are the girls on
fire. The hash. Yeah. The hash. Next
level. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. New school. Old
school. He's does the QC on the hash.
The quality control is right here.
Everything has to go through. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. You got to QC guy. QC guy.
No, but you know, we like good food. You
know, we all we all love good. We love
the turf. T all about the turfs. So
here. Yeah. Yeah. It's all what tastes
good. Otherwise, we don't eat it. We
refuse. Yeah. There's no point. Why?
Yeah. I mean, you're the one who you
said it multiple times. Why would you
eat [ __ ] I'd rather not eat than eat
[ __ ] Yeah. Yeah. In America,
especially. Yeah. One one time a day you
have to find a nice restaurant or you
have to cook nice in your house or you
have to eat with your friends. Only
actually one time a day is enough to
eat. You can try two times a day if
you're lucky. Yeah. And same with the
smoke. Yeah. Yeah. Why waste your why
waste your lungs and your life on
something that's not amazing, you know?
Yeah. So, in the final moments of
Spanabis 2025, we're planning for our
dinner later and we hope to see you guys
in Berlin. Uh Mary Jane this June. Your
next holiday destination, Thailand.
Thailand. You got to go check out
Greenhouse in Thailand. You guys are
just blowing up over in Thailand.
Amazing. All this stuff. I think the
number one holiday destination in the
world. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I'm looking
forward to going to Thailand this year.
Yeah. Yeah, you have to come by, man.
You're going to love this for sure. For
sure. So, yeah. Thank you guys for
everything and I look forward to seeing
you guys very soon.
Peace.
[Music]