[Music]
oh
[Applause]
[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James loud
podcast and today our special guest is
Dave Perkins from butero we met at re on
the river how you doing today I'm doing
pretty good thanks for having me on I
appreciate it absolutely so when we
first met you came up to me and you said
tell me the truth you don't have to lie
just tell me tell me what you think of
this and I'm like what is this guy
talking about and you bust out a bag of
Sour Diesel and you said if it's not the
real Sour Diesel it's no big deal just
tell me your opinion and right when you
said that I was kind of like who is this
guy I've never met him before in my life
but he's saying something interesting
because usually people give me bags of
sour they're like dude this is the real
Sour and it's usually this gassy version
of sour diesel that's not what I
remember as Sour Diesel it looks like
sour diesel maybe it smells a little bit
like it but it's a much gassier version
and then when I cracked your butt
open it made me think that there's only
one type of sour that I ever remember
and that's it the one that you have is
the sour we it was only called sour when
I first started smoking it and you came
to me with his bud and I'm like it
brought back all these memories from you
know the last 25 years of Sour Diesel
and it it's the one it's undoubtedly the
real one I've showed it to so many
different people smoke some with Jason
Pinsky I smoked Nick all these guys have
also verified and are all excited about
the sour so thank you very much oh I'm
I'm glad I'm glad you enjoyed it you
know something that I I knew was special
when I got it and I knew I had to do
whatever it took to keep it for as long
as I felt necessary yeah when you've had
the cut for a long time yeah 20
three I got it for the first time wow I
believe yeah 2003 um and yeah I got it
from this guy in in the bay and I had
been buying sour I bought it for the
first time in 1999 out in Kirkwood um
out in Animal House if you know Kirkwood
you know the Animal House the employee
housing I was like damn this stuff is
you know it's pretty good yeah uh fast
forward a few years later was able to
like still get it and this guy one time
I was at his house he was just like hey
you want to you want to cut you want a
clone and I was like sure what is it
he's like it's the sour and I was like
yeah I'll definitely take it he reached
into his closet where there was no grow
light of any sort and there was just a
plant in a red K cup and he's like here
you go here's the sour wow so I took it
home and here we are yeah and the sour
is really special and I feel like my
opinion of it is that it's a chem 91 bag
seed there's all kinds of different
opinions out there I mean I've done as
much research as I could and it's led me
to believe that not just from the
stories from other people but but the
way it grows and all these other
phenotypes that are very similar that
actually test genetically different uh
that lean heavy on the chem that are
they remind me more of the chem from
chem 91 or that chem D than sour but it
has the same structure right and so
these are all derivatives of each other
but I feel like that sour is got its own
thing and you know I've seen so many
different things that that people say
are sour or cuts that I've seen in the
last like especially the last 10 years
that's it's like okay it's sour and then
it's not sour um and I think you also
mentioned something about probably the
way it's grown can definitely make it
express differently and I think there's
a lot of Truth to that I 100% think that
and I think that about about all herb
you know my father-in-law won a cup um
with a variety called the Cherry slider
and it was like a grow off but it was
back in the early 2000s everybody got
the same cut and then when they got
together to kind of like show his was
totally different than everybody and
people are like why is yours so
different and he won that year with that
cherry slider um and so they're like you
know what's the deal what's the deal um
in growing environment the person um you
know time of year type of grow I think
these are all things that go into it
yeah the Cure I know for sure is
probably the biggest part I I think more
so than the way it's grown or who grows
it because I've had sour that you know
is like right where it needs to be and
then it can quickly disappear if you
don't store it in the right conditions
or if you don't seal it up at the right
time um so I think that as much of it
has to go with the Cure yeah as it does
like this cut of the sour but I've also
had people grow like Hermes seed or like
self seed from one of my friend's sour
batches right it was a room full of sour
nothing else in there and they came back
and they're like it's just not the same
sour um and I've been you know pretty
transparent with people about like how I
grow it what what I've used to grow I've
grown with a bunch of different
nutrients a bunch of different ways and
comes out different in every way yeah
you know some people say oh the sour
that I've seen is loose and Airy um the
real Sour is loose and Airy and I'm like
well I've grown loose and ay sour and
I've also grown like really tight sour
outside and I've grown it inside yeah um
so it's like a you know every plant is
different depending on who you give it
to and how they treat it so I think
there's a lot of variation within that
and then a lot of people striving to say
like I got the sour and I've had it for
a long time so I've never really felt
that need for validation mhm um I think
is what it is well and I have a cut
called the weasel Diesel and that is
supposedly sour and it is a sour but
it's not the sour that I remember from
back in the day and there was also an
AJ's cut that we got probably like 2005
or 2006 that was more lemon and this is
before I knew AJ and knew the whole
story and so I feel like a lot of these
things are probably bag seeds
potentially but what you're saying about
drying and curing I know for a fact
because I used to grow sour and I
remember there was one time where I
yielded way more than I thought I was
going to yield and I didn't have the
capacity to really dry it all properly
and I dried it too fast and then I tried
to rehydrate it a little bit and I
killed the smell completely and so it
looked like sour it looked like the most
amazing sour but then you'd have to
really squeeze it to get in there to get
the nose and then the smoke just didn't
translate because sour you should be
able to take a joint and smoke it all
the way down to the roach and it should
taste like sour you should be able to
put it out five times you light it back
up and it still tastes like come back
the next day and it still tastes like
sour come back a week later and you
could tell that roach was a sour diesel
roach and that's you know that there's
only a handful of things I've
experienced in my whole life that are
capable of doing that that's one cat
piss is another one I mean there's a
handful of good herb that'll do that but
it's it's just compared to everything on
the market you don't get that across the
board and it's a pronounced flavor in
the roach you're not just like oh it's
kind of like it tastes like the first
hit oh yeah and your room smells like
sour people walk into your room and they
know that it's sour if you've been
smoking sour uh yeah it's just something
extremely special so thank you very much
for that yeah of course you're not
linear in the sense that you're just
about Sour you have so many different
things you gave me some Bubba that was
really nostalgic as well which I haven't
seen real good bubba a lot in the last
10 15 years it was huge in the late 90s
early 2000s and then the market like the
traditional Market in the Bay Area they
had a pheno that was like a 53 day feno
and they probably Harvest on day 47 and
they were just rocking it and turning it
and it it was reminiscent of Bubba it
smoked okay but it wasn't like the
pre-98 I guess pre-98 Bubba we just call
it Bubba Kush back in the day but then
they came out with the pre98 or the name
pre98 so yeah tell us about the Bubba so
this is uh it's a Bubba cush cross with
original Haze so the Bubba Kush is from
Caleb at CSI humble yeah he did a 100
plant feno hunt S1 with his pre98 Bubba
yeah and so he grew those out took a few
of those fenos a few of the winners over
to my father-in-law's house Tony aka
budo yeah um and they went through them
and so my father inlaw Tony he picked
out the number seven yeah and so the
number seven turned slightly purple it
had more of like an OG cush kind of
smell and flavor to it yeah um and so
out of all of the fenos that they had he
was like the number seven's the one and
he named that the bomb threat Bubba so
if you ever hear of the bomb threat
Bubba or number seven that's what this
is crossed with the original haze from
Sam the skunkman ni it comes kind of via
some guys in Germany that got the
original haze from Sam the skunkman and
then did reproductions of that right um
and so they use that um the pollen from
that original Haze nice to create this
um and it's great because it's very
reminiscent of the Bubba Kush but from a
cultivator standpoint it grows really
fast and you get a a really good yield
so it's kind of like Bubba cush on
steroids and so you know being able to
offer something that you usually has a
slower or uh a lower yield and a slower
veg process you know I mean you can put
in a foot tall plant and end up with
like a three foot four tall plant wow
and and get a decent yield on it yeah
because Bubba is a little bit slower to
veg it's not the biggest yield it's like
a medium yield and it has this amazing
soap character and I love the the flower
that you gave me has that little bit of
soapiness to it okay and I really like
the gas with the soapiness I think
that's what makes it special but I also
love Haze and I love you know the land
race varieties that you're working with
because you seem to have a good
collection of land race and pearls and I
think reintroducing pearls to the world
that that may be your purpose for being
here on this planet I don't know but
like I feel like that's extremely
special I feel like I'm definitely here
to grow the sacred herb you know I I
view it as a sacred plant like we all
got to be able to survive and do this we
can't lose money to do it right um but I
I still 100% believe that you
can survive and treat a plant as a
sacred plant right um yeah and the
pearls are a great example of something
that checks none of the boxes except for
the effect right it wins in the effect
category um you know so it's a it's a
Colombian Mexican tie and my
father-in-law got the seeds it's from uh
Charlie Garcia canab Biogen it's a
destroyer and so he popped the seeds I
think he got one of them that spit out
pearls and so he finished it which you
know he could have gone two different
directions he could have said oh there's
nothing on this plant it's not going to
yield anything I'm just going to toss it
and that would have been that on to the
next thing but instead he was like you
know what he's been growing for 56 years
he's got a lot of wisdom when it comes
to watching plants grow he's not just a
weed wizard yeah he's got um you know
knowledge um and an understanding of
plants from the whole entire world the
whole entire plant kingdom Ian he used
to travel all around the world to get
seeds of rare Palms bring them back home
um he's got like a a tropical Palm
Plantation at his house up in Humble you
know he's got all these varieties of
plants from all over the world wow and
so when he stumbled across the pearls
you know he let it do its thing 16 weeks
finished it and he smoked and he was
like man this is this is what I've been
searching for after 56 years of smoking
you know he still smokes every day lots
of joints um he still really loves herb
and he's like this is what the tie stick
made me feel like the first time I I
found TI stick and so for him it's this
like lifelong quest of smoking herb and
being quas satisfied you know he went
through the whole like OG craze the cham
craze the sour he's grown it all and
when he found the pearls he was like
this is it this is what I've been
looking for my whole entire life this is
all that I want to smoke right and so
now he's got I think six or six or seven
different fenos of the pearls that he's
found um and it's pretty much all he
wants to smoke yeah and so it's just
interesting to me that he could have
thrown it away and we would have not
ended up with the pearls but he has the
wisdom in foresight to know that just
because a plant looks like crap doesn't
mean that it's not going to have this
amazing effect that now a lot of people
are starting to see and recognize and
really really like I mean you know I
think a lot of people that we surround
oursel with a lot of people you've had
on your
podcast and myself included up until
about a year and a half two years ago
had not felt an effect or had an
experience like this from any other
cannabis flow yeah um it's just it's
different you know I was smoking some at
the hall of flowers last week with uh
Dan Herer Jack harr's son and he was
blown away he took one hit and was just
like I feel he basically like I feel so
good I just want to stop right here and
enjoy it yeah and for me too I took that
one hit and I was just like I want to
just I just want to hang out right here
and be this high and be high like this
because it it feels great you know it's
something you don't want to get rid of
yeah well and it's so hard to classify
when you start talking you know they
want to classify indicia and sativa and
and you know Broad Leaf versus narrow
leaf and for effect and I feel like it's
somewhere in the middle and there's a
handful of things that I feel like are
just their own thing right it's really
hard to classify that I mean you could
say equatorial maybe in structure but
then effect is just its own thing and
you gave me some last time we were
together I think at canif Fest the
African Haze 11 the African Haze 11 yeah
yeah the interesting thing about the
Indica sativa you know wide Leaf narrow
Leaf is you know you could have
something that has maybe more of a
sativa high but has a broad leaf um You
Know Jack her is a good example really
quick flowering time it's like a 56 day
you know we'll finish in September in
mesino yeah but it has skinny leaves so
a lot of people say oh it's got skinny
leaves it's a sativa right but the
length of flowering and the effect are
things that we have to consider and so
I've been learning a lot from my
father-in-law about just plants in
general you know um you know we don't
want to box ourselves in and and say
this is this because it's like is it
really you know the flowering time the
amount of days it takes to flower seems
for us in my experience to correlate to
the type of high that you get with it
right so when you're on the 45 50 day
Spectrum you get this very sedative
feeling and when you hit the 100 100
plus 120 it seems to move towards this
like euphoric
soaring uplifting type of high right and
so we can call it whatever we want but
the effect is really what is the measure
of how high we get and the type of high
that we have and for me the longer
flowering the more uplifting the the um
the highs and the shorter flowering is
that more sedative and so I I feel like
that's a a a better place to start yeah
than wide leaf or narrow leaf or you
know or I I totally agree you know and
my friend Dave passed on 420 and so he
redirected my focus back into effect
and I feel like meeting you and then I
have a collection this big collection of
land R seeds from my buddy fritzy who's
been all over India in fact he's there
right now and so he's collecting all
kinds of stuff from India and so with
the access to the genetics that I have
it's like the possibilities are really
they start becoming endless um where
it's like I mean it just takes so much
time a lot of people don't understand
the amount of time it takes to go
exploring for new things and then for me
part of what I need to do is I need to
make it appealing to I mean there's
there's stuff that I can have that's
completely just for me but then as far
as a seed company I have to make it
appealing to other people so I feel like
maybe my job is to figure out how to
cross it with modern genetics to where
we can sneak it into people's minds
where they're like oh maybe it doesn't
have to be purple candy gas or maybe it
doesn't have to be this and maybe I can
just smoke it for the effect you know or
maybe we can find some happy place in
the Middle where they can get a little
bit of both to where it spawns their
curiosity to where they're like well if
this is good maybe I should try this you
know CU I always walk around with the
super silver haze late lately the last
year it's always been the super silver
haze I I try to share it with people
especially the people that are like oh I
don't like Haze it's like smoke this and
tell me you think it tastes great you
smoke it down and it has a great effect
it's organic living soil my buddy Chris
he grows it flora and Flame and that's
extremely special to me and then with
your stuff it's like I'm able to give
that to the same kind of people
especially my friends who who trust me a
lot I'm like okay well I just rolled
this let's smoke it and getting getting
their opinion so I feel like it's almost
our duty as as stewards to this plant to
be able to be the ones to have the
foresight to be able to reintroduce this
stuff to people that have never
experienced it because there's a lot of
people that love weed and they they
think they love this one thing because
that's what they've experienced but they
haven't really got to experience the
whole world of what's available with
cannabis and it's like if if you've
never been to Europe you don't know if
you're going to like it or not it's the
same thing with flour it's like until
you've actually tried it and you smoked
these things and maybe white Thorn Rose
is the the one for you you know I feel
that's extremely special and maybe
that's the one for you but maybe you
smoke one of these new varieties not
even new but these land race varieties
have been out forever but new to you and
that's what you can attach yourself with
is I want to feel like this yeah and I
mean I I'll pull out some of the pearls
um and this you know this is new to me
this is this is also new to my
father-in-law who's the one that is
responsible for these being in this box
you know and he's he's been growing and
smoking for a really long time and uh so
I think the fact that there's things
that we may call new but that have
actually been around for centuries is
amazing because we're still kind
of discovering things about the plant
whether it be medicinal properties you
know the different compounds in it but I
think for
you know for a a he in his mid 70s for a
75-year-old man that's been growing his
whole life to come across this and then
be like this is the one yeah you know he
like you also has a lot of credibility
respect in the online community um a lot
of the younger humble Growers uh that
were kind of in our circle of friends
would go to him for for herb because he
had he had the high grade and they were
growing a lot of outdoor you know so
they would go to them for their head
stash at the end of the year here and so
they would trust him okay yeah Tony
knows what he's talking about cuz he's
been growing longer than like most
people that we know and smoking and and
still is really passionate about it so
the fact that he's like hey this is it
to a youngster like me is like man I
need to pay attention to this and now I
feel like we're in a in a time where
people are open
because they it's magical people are
curious there's a lot of new smokers
there's a lot of people that have never
tried a vape pen or an edible and even
those things can be new to people when
for other people like oh this like it's
nothing new this has been around forever
but so it's always going to be something
new even to some of the experienced
smokers out there so I think something
like this you know when you when you
pull it out I think a lot of our viewers
probably don't even know what pearls are
and you know so this is the number one
so we so this is number one we have uh
seven six or seven different fenos
there's a one or the one the two and
then the a b c and d yeah and the a is
the one um that's like the in pearls you
would classif like Dr grin spoon would
be you get pearls from Dr grin spoon
anything that creates a a single Brack
bud is a pearl right not necessarily I
think it's a I think it's a trait that
exists within cannabis there's another
uh there's somebody else on Instagram
that's one of I think maybe one other
person I've seen with pearls and they
have pearls from the Destroyer oh and so
I think it's a he was referring to like
a single braat or it was like a certain
type of plant that actually spits out
this type of kaix or brat yeah so it's
not just the Pearl plants um but these
ones in particular there's been some uh
some plants that have selfed and have
we've got some seeds out of them when
those get planted they also turn out
like pearls so we've got some W hawen
pearls that we're working on right now
yeah it's a strain from Waka that spits
out these single kix's it's definitely
different um and and so far it's it's
one of the few varieties out there that
is uh putting out pearls we used to get
the grin spoon in Amsterdam and that was
what it the grin spoon from Amsterdam
was this most it's some of the strongest
flour and it's very
reminiscent of Green Spoon so I asked my
I asked my father law the other day
because every single person says
greenspoon I mean even DNA genetics uh
commented on DNA is the one who gave me
a bag of grin spoon when we in Amsterdam
in 2012 Dawn from DNA was like you ever
smoke grin spoon I'm like no he's like
here you go somebody gave me some grin
spoon okay he's like it's super strong
be careful and I was like whatever you
know I'm like I've been smoking Haze and
it was so strong that uh you know it
makes it would give me heart
palpitations yeah I I get that all the
time I mean I'm I'm at a point where I
don't say I'm not going to say I like
heart palpitations but I like i' I've
learned to deal with the raciness of the
highs right um you're going to hear me
talk a lot about my father-in-law Tony
because he's the one that really has
turned me on to all this and has really
dropped a lot of knowledge and game on
me and it's like there's these hoops of
fire right you got to get through them
whether it's 120 days of flowering or
it's a low yield or someone going that
looks like crap why would I ever want to
smoke that you know and it's the same
with the racy high like once you get
comfortable with that and you know what
going to happen you can be a little more
okay with how high you're going to get
yeah but you also take it easy and not
smoke quite as much in the beginning and
then as you you know I feel like
everybody has different tolerances right
and so maybe you don't need 10 hits
maybe you only need three you know
that's one of the things that I really
like about the pearls is you don't need
a big fatty you know um it's really
shifted a lot of these sativas these
long flowering varieties have shifted my
perception or my expectation that like
you have to have you have to smoke a lot
of weed to get high yeah and sure there
are some I mean I you know people give
me weeds some of the more like shorter
flowering varieties don't get me high as
much or they get me high in a different
way for a very short amount of time yeah
these varieties you know they get you
high for a really long time and and
something interesting about the Green
Spoon and I'm and I'm trying to get Tony
my father-in-law to kind of to get
online and clear this up because I was
talking to him about this the other day
because uh my buddy Danny from GW smoke
break we went to high school together
shout out Danny um he's all about the
pearls he's doing a great job at kind of
showcasing them right now now he's
definitely um got you know some Pearl
content that he has um and he made a
post recently everybody says Dr
greenspoon I mean every single time I
post it so I was like Tony what's up
everybody says Dr greenspoon and I'm
gonna mess this up right now but I'll
try and say it in like a in an authentic
like kind of uh true way is that that Dr
greenspoon
was something that somebody else
purchased from somebody yeah
they took that and then called it the
greenspoon so it wasn't like this the Dr
greenspoon that everybody knows is Dr
greenspoon was something before that
sure it for sure was named it after Dr
Lester greenspoon right but so so Dr
greenspoon for most everybody is is this
one specific thing but it was actually a
strain that was made by someone else
that they saw and they're like oh we
want to buy the seeds to this and then
they gave it the name right this has no
genetic resemblance to that it's its own
thing sure I mean I've seen LR stuff
that that that bust out pearls that I've
popped before yeah I saw somebody
recently they're like oh it's not rare
if you grow out fields of thae and it's
like okay yeah it it might not be rare
if you grow out fields of thae but who's
growing out fields of tie right like
there's nobody else has this really so
it's rare even if somebody else is like
oh I got a lot of that it's like for you
the sour like the sour is gone it's rare
well I've had it the whole entire time
it's never been rare for me so it's all
this
perception of who you've met what your
experience is like I got a buddy and you
know you say oh I got some good weed
well I got a buddy he was at like the
top tier of that I got some good weed
level you know I knew when he said he
had good weed it was going to be better
than everybody else's because his
experience with good weed was elevated
from that of everybody else so it was
like he had uh an experience that was
that of above maybe say even me and then
my father-in-law is quite a few notches
above where I am with that it's like you
want to know what good weed is ask
somebody that's been smoking for 60
years for sure anybody that's been
smoking for an extended amount of time
they'll have their opinion on what's
good and what's not good for sure and
and that just comes with experience you
know he he has no interest in seeing any
of this sold he stands to make no money
off of it yeah it's just what he likes
and it's you know he's like I said he's
smoked a lot of other stuff in his life
um and this is what works for him you
know some people might like blue dream
and that's their favorite that's a great
strain I mean that I think that's one of
the
gonna go down as like the most overhyped
yet most underrated hybrids of all time
yeah it is I think it's the best hybrid
of all time I mean you take an Inda and
a sativa for back of lack of better
terms and created something that just
had this crazy Vigor that went wild
outside and you could throw it up
outside and get huge numbers you know
with a great smell right um that's what
I really like about this bubak cush
original Haze is it's a great hybrid I
mean it's like right down the middle
it's got great back AG appeal it's got
more of the original Haze high but it's
got the flavor and the look of the Bubba
I mean it looks you know some of looks
like
indoor for a haze of that plant is
amazing and I think Blue Dream yeah as
far as like checking the boxes as from a
Grower's perspective it's absolutely
amazing the Vigor of it is amazing it
has that hybrid Vigor That You Don't See
in a lot of plants and uh it doesn't get
enough credit it gets a lot of hate
um but I think that's because Justin
Bieber said he liked Blue Dream well
because because everybody in their mom
was growing it outside and it's just
like everything you too many people
start to do it and you get too many
watered down versions of it and then you
get people it's too easy to grow good
right Sour Diesel everybody was growing
sour at a point in in somoma and meno
and there was some people in humbled as
well but they tried to blow that out a
little bit but there wasn't a lot of
good sour on the market because it's not
easy to grow yeah and we growing
inferior cuts too I believe that's part
of it yeah I mean I got mine pretty
early on and I got it from the guys that
came out from the East Coast with it
yeah so it wasn't like I got a cut off
of a mom off of a cut off of a mom off
of a back seat off of a cut of a mom
yeah maybe that who knows maybe that's
where my cut came from but as far as I
know that was just like the cut from the
guys that brought the cut out it wasn't
a bag seed and they were growing it in
1999 in honeydew yeah and I remember the
first time I saw that I saw the perss
and the sour both for the first time in
the same week wow and I was showing it
to people and uh I showed this you saw
the perss is in the meno perss or is in
the GDP maybe it was 1999 cuz before the
GDP was called GDP it was called the
perss
or I can't remember the other name for
it but the pers it was the pers it was
just the perss you know uh soon after it
turned into like the GDP and all this
other stuff I mean it was coming from
Humble to Tahoe straight As the pers it
was like nothing else any of us had ever
seen and so I got to see both of those
for the first time in the same week it's
kind of crazy and I show I was like I
was like hey check out this pers I just
got and my buddy was like yo screw that
where's that stuff from last week you
know because we were I got weed every
Sunday that just how my program was and
I was like what I got the pers like you
know and now looking back on it I'm like
damn I had two of like the most
legendary strains in my hands in the
same week and the sour kind of went to
the Wayside until aoup couple years
later I started seeing it again from uh
my buddy introduced me to his guy and so
I you know got to go a little bit more
direct that was in SF I think this was
probably around the same time a lot of
people were getting hip to the sour I
started seeing it 99 2000 2001 was
buying it um and then you know ended up
getting my hands on it those were good
years for sour and the price point was
expensive back I mean flour was just
expensive in general but sour was the
Exotic of its day and it wasn't it
wasn't super accessible for really good
sour anywhere these guys would only let
me buy an ounce at a time you know it's
like for all those people out there that
are like you know just be thankful that
you have access to this stuff now it's
like you know you would get one ounce
one it came around yeah 400 500 bucks
maybe 600 bucks I mean it was what
somebody wanted for it and I've even
still people to this day like oh if you
got sour I'll pay you like name your
price you know yeah um it just commanded
that it was such a different high back
then yeah and I feel like that's maybe
why gravitating towards these pearls and
some of these other flavors now is the
high is different than than everything
else out there you know I find myself
not getting as confused anymore smoking
like you know these pearls they're just
like laser sharp you know really gives
you a Clarity like if you're a um if
you're a computer programmer or you're
an athlete yeah I mean one day they will
consider certain types of herb a uh
performance enhancing drug for sure I
mean it's it's a fact you look I mean
you look at the Diaz brothers the reason
they're such good Fighters I mean they
smoke I mean I would I would say that
there's that contributing factor it's
not the only thing but it's able they're
able to smoke and train and to be
hyperfocused when they train and I feel
like you look at a lot of these
Jiu-Jitsu guys too and these guys smoke
heavy but yeah performance enhancing for
sure I uh I like smoking and doing stuff
even cardio it makes cardio better dude
the African Haze 11 yeah I mean me and
my wife we smoke that and then we out
together you know we got our little like
routine and uh it's it's great for for
athletics you know for creativity um I
mean it's got me I think you you know
we've we've hung out a couple times now
and I feel like people when they hang
out with me they're like kind of look at
me like what's up with this guy he seems
pretty enthusiastic or pretty excited
about a weed industry that is like seems
like it's just dwindling yeah and I hope
that these types of flowers get out to
people they can have the experience and
then can have that kind of passion kind
of put back into their life because
whether you're like a seasoned smoker a
grower a hustler like something that
makes you feel good and just kind of
like brightens up your day like my buddy
Danny from GW he's just like dude every
time I smoke the pearls it like
instantly within five seconds just makes
things brighter you know I haven't done
a lot of psychedelics or really any ever
and I imagine that these pearls are kind
of like at the bottom end of like the
Psychedelic threshold yeah where it's
not quite there but there's these
elements to it mhm that that I can
see could be similar sometimes all it
takes to get someone passionate again is
to remind them why they love the plant
so much and if you can show them a
different side of it man it's it's it's
it's special and to be able to be that
person for me it's I feel like I've been
just trying to figure out what what my
job is on this planet for the longest
time and you know I think I stumbled
upon it with this podcast and then I
mean I've Loved cannabis my whole life
but we can't just do weed anymore we got
to do three other things we we have to
do other things you know and you do
other things as well right so you do you
work with Oaker Dam on some level and
also uh you know with with your wife's a
lawyer and so yeah yeah so I'm an Oaker
Dam instructor um in the horiculture
department yeah and then I'm also an
expert Court witness so an expert Court
witness is basically somebody that um
you know testifies in court on behalf of
a client who maybe has a civil dispute
say you're a cultivator and you have an
investor you had an agreement a contract
you were supposed to produce x amount of
weight you were going to sell it for
this price that doesn't happen now you
have a court case with your investors
because they're saying hey you didn't do
your job or on the flip side these
cultivators are relying on an investor
to put up the money so they can get
their equipment so they get their plants
in the ground so get their clones at the
right time so they can plant at the
right time they have a disagreement I'll
get hired to kind of be like a third
part
unbiased opinion to the situation and so
I'll look at a bunch of court documents
pictures you know photos videos and give
my opinion about what I think about the
situation you get called to the stand
drink trial a lot of times yeah so a lot
of times I I I get a call they say hey
we're interested in hiring you I'm like
cool we do the deal they send me court
documents they send me paperwork I
review them I write a
report then most of the time I get
deposed so the opposing counc gets to
sit me down uh I found out recently for
up to8 hours in one day so I just a
couple weeks ago was deposed for almost
eight hours and it's basically a lawyer
getting to ask you questions about the
report that you wrote I know a lot about
depositions yeah it's rough it can be
rough it you know I mean I feel like
you're basically being interrogated for
eight hours especially by the opposing
side um trying to poke holes in in you
and everything else yeah and they'll
poke holes in every like this guy
recently he pulled up everything I've
ever said anywhere you could actually
find it you know and I was not ready for
it um so you have to be able
to um
respond accurately quickly correctly I
kind of like lawyers I feel are kind of
like uh freestyle rappers yeah you you
have a situation where you have an
outcome maybe you're doing a rap battle
and someone's discs you and you're like
oh I got to come back at them same thing
with the lawyer like the lawyer made a
point now I've got to come back and make
my point so you have to be able to
quickly analyze what somebody said and
then to say something back fact the
better the lawyers the better the battle
you know like some of these lawyers you
know it's it's it's pretty wild so my
wife's an attorney she's specialized in
cannabis for you know around 20 years
she worked with Tony Sarah pufi Law
Offices um and she used to hire Chris
Conrad for most of her criminal cases
because same thing happens for a
criminal case except for it's against
the cops right um and so Chris bless his
heart has been just kind of like passing
cas on to me um you know I don't know
he's done hundreds and hundreds and
hundreds of cases and so I'm kind of
following his footsteps a little bit you
know he was a big proponent of prop 215
really involved with Oaker Dam and and
kind of pioneering a lot of their
curriculum and from a legal standpoint
and so I kind of fell into the whole
expert witness thing through my wife and
him um and you know I started getting a
couple referrals I had an oaksterdam
student that took uh one of my classes
that referred me to a law firm that he
got a job with yeah um so that's been
great um so it's you know it's kind of
my other thing that I've gone into I you
know for five years was trying to figure
out what am I going to do as a
cultivator that now doesn't have a grow
space right like I had my own grow out
in Yuba
County not friendly to cannabis Growers
whatsoever um you know they they raid
every neighborhood about every 10 years
and so I was there on the 10th year they
didn't hit me CU when they did the fly
over I was in between plantings so they
didn't see me plant so they didn't stop
at my place and I was like after they
raided the whole neighborhood I was like
I'm out I'm done um I was already living
in Washington working for a company up
there managing a fairly decent sized
indoor at the time and then I came back
started working for other people and um
you know just like you trying to find my
kind of my place in the industry and um
you know I kind of just fell into this
expert witness thing I kind of just fell
into these hazes my father-in-law has
been doing this his whole life when I
first met him 12 years ago and I started
smoking with him I was like damn this
this guy's like got I was like proud to
show him my Harvest of I had sour I had
Pacific Northwest dog [__] I had Big Sir
holy weed like I had some genetics that
I thought he would be stoked on because
they weren't you know even 15 years ago
10 years ago weren't wasn't blue dream
it wasn't the run-of-the-mill I wasn't
grown gorilla grew and he was just kind
of like that's cool but check this out
and so I was like look at this [__] you
know like he he busts open a a tea a tea
tin y with you know some stuff that
almost looks similar to the
pearls and we went to Hawaii was 12
years ago first family vacation I went
on with with the family and we smoked
his herb the whole entire time I didn't
even smoke my herb because he's like you
know he's kind of an alpha male he's
just like I'm smoking my weed son you
know let me show you what's up youngster
and I'm new to the family he's like you
know maybe testing the waters cuz you
know I'm dating his daughter and she's a
weed attorney she's been smoking weed
her whole life yeah and after that week
I was just like damn there's something
different to this week
and I had just come off of a light Depot
out in Grass Valley and I was like yo I
want to put these hazes these sativas in
a light Depot that's the only re the
only way I thought it could be done yeah
he's now doing it indoors growing I mean
he's got hazes that have gone 22 weeks
inside that's amazing he's growing these
pearls inside um it's just something new
it's something different you know yeah
it's exciting I mean grin spoon the grin
spoon used to stretch out so much they
I've I've seen it stapled to the wall
where they've they've actually stapled
it to the wall because it stretches so
much yeah I thought about growing it
like a like a vine on a vine like you
know just two branches going opposite
directions because I've got 20 in a
greenhouse right now and they hit the
10- foot Mark you know a month ago they
just they're weird because they they
start to weep down at a certain point
almost like a weeping willow so they go
up and then they start to go down and I
mean it's the biggest mess ever like
they just kind of grow into each other
harvesting them handling I mean you saw
like just pulling out this bag is just
messy not a big yield but I love it I'm
I'm stoked that I got onto it yeah I
love unique things so as far as the Big
Sir
holy uh my friend Mojave Richmond used
to GI me Big Sir holy flower along with
sage flower and I believe the Big Sir
holy was one of the page uh parents of
the sage that he created and my thoughts
were always that it was either sister to
like the original Haze or something very
very close because I feel like the
effect the structure all the things the
boxes that it checked were the same
boxes as the original Haze that I've
seen But the funny thing about you know
I'm teaching cul ofar selection at oer
Dam actually in October and part of that
class is like just because you were
given something that's called this does
not mean that it's this I deal with that
in my court cases they're like you know
cuz they're trying to discredit me in
every single way they can so have you
ever grown this strain I'm like no do
you have a genetic stamp for it no then
it's not you can't prove to me that it's
that strain so you can't discredit me
from saying that I haven't grown The
Strain and therefore I don't know
anything about these genetics you're
talking about and then like I shouldn't
be able to test it's like that's not how
it works so I find myself a lot of times
explaining to these lawyers like stop
you don't have any proof of what you're
talking about most people don't and so
yeah it's like it's hard to tell but as
cultivators we our our noses as Growers
I think there's something with us
Growers we have that like memory that
it's just like boom you could smell
something one time and smell it 20 years
later like the sour and you're like boom
that's it you know unmistakably it like
yeah I mean no doubt in my mind and I've
smelled like cat piss if you showed me
the real catpiss and I was able to
actually smoke it I could tell you 100%
with the first hit if it's catpiss or
yeah and I love catpiss that's that's my
desert island if I could smoke anything
the rest of my life it would be the
catpiss and it's interesting because
I've shown the pearls to a few people
yeah and they're like oh this you know
it's some of it's got a terpinolene
dominant kind of like nose to it um some
of it smells like a Christmas tree some
of it smells like seven up I've gotten
OG Kush notes out of it um once one time
and my father-in-law also got that out
of it you know yeah um but like some of
this is a little bit older um that's the
great thing about hazes is they store
really well yeah you know I mean I've
got some like year old IND Bubba cush
original Haze that still looks and
smokes great it's so funny because I
feel like limenine and tpine are the two
dominant tpes in Haze but then you look
at Jack herrer which is super high in
lanine and the Jack herrer I've seen it
has the the least amount of shelf life
of all the flower that I've basically
tried to age and cure and so some stuff
and a lot of these new varieties they
they just don't have a lot of shelf life
to them you know it's like they harvest
they Peak and unless you're keeping them
in optimal conditions it just starts
declining within probably two weeks of
the time where it's it's perfectly cured
and some of these other some varieties
I've been able to keep perfect for four
months you know so it's just so so
strain dependent as well and it's
interesting too because we talk about
the sour and how it can be finicky I
remember when I first started growing it
I was growing it inside and I would keep
a quarter pound of every Harvest so
every two months I had a new quarter
pound and so I had four JS in my closet
had a two a four a 6mon and an 8mon and
I just referred to them as the four
month the six Monon when the 8 month hit
the eighth month it was better than the
two four and the six that's awesome and
it was as good or better than it was
when I first harvested yeah and so I've
heard some people talk recently about
like uh you know the shelf life maybe it
has something to do with the inputs that
it was grown with I believe there's
absolute truth to that and so I think
maybe you know um a lot of people
weren't necessarily growing the sour cuz
they wanted that dank sour I knew guys
that grew hundreds of pounds of sour
because they wanted to make money yeah
and their sour was money sour it wasn't
like love sour you know it wasn't grown
by someone that like wanted some dank
sour to smoke they wanted some Sour to
sell that's always the best when you got
the guy who well I feel like there's
some guys that just they don't smoke and
they grow and that's it's a money thing
and then there's guys my friend Josh
freem used to grow the Sour Diesel and
his Sour Diesel was that kind where it
just stayed on your palette it was the
perfect he was up in cazadero and it was
outdoor and it was you know there's a
banana belt up there and when you grow
the sour in Cass I feel like the sour
from Cass is the best I've seen in my
life and it was like sticky in the bag
you'd open it and it' punch you in the
face and every time he used to grow it
it was like just amazing and but he was
a sour smoke he's a sour smoker now in
fact I was telling him about the sour
he's like man I need to get some Sour
let's just split some so he's one of
those guys he just loves the sour and
every batch he used to grow it was all
all passion you know and people it you
put your energy into that plant and then
that plant gives you back what you put
into it and these guys that aren't
smokers a lot of times it's like maybe
these guys are good at growing at scale
and they can produce good stuff but
there's something special about the
passionate guys that just love it and
they are smoking their own product yeah
I mean these guys they weren't even
smokers they would you know they use
grow more you know I mean I think we all
at some point of used things that have
monop potassium phosphate in them right
um you know I'm I will definitely not
pretend like I'll be the first to admit
that I have um but that was like all
that they grew with you know um you know
a lot of organic guys you know maybe
some syn you know kind of the guys that
do the blend maybe you do like a a
booster mid round and then you know you
finish up with some organic stuff but
when you're doing just hard cams you
know it it seems to like my buddy he was
growing Hydro I was growing in soil we
were both growing sour I was using
botanic air he was using Advanced
Nutrients yeah and the soil beds came
out better you know and that's what he
used to say that's not my opinion he
would just say that when we were out at
shows smoking you know I grew 10 I think
probably 10 pounds of sour the first
time I grew it outdoors and my friends
that saw that Harvest and would like if
they smoked this sour in that bag they
always always say that first one was the
one I was up on Summit in Santa Cruz I
lived like 50 feet into Santa Cruz
County if I went on to the other side of
my street I was in Santa Clara County oh
wow and I was half of a mile from
Highway 17 and that sour and all the
herb I grew up there was some of the
best I mean my father-in-law was grown
in Las Gattis about you know probably
two miles as the crow flies I think even
at the same time yeah and a lot of his
friends a lot of the people I've met met
that know him are like you know that
weed that you were growing in L Gattis
was like super super dank you know and I
feel like that area that pocket not even
like coros because it's drier but that
like Summit pocket the southern end of
of Summit road like it gets just enough
moisture my landlord when I moved in
he's like oh you're growing weed he was
all upset at first he's like oh he's
like this is such a a great spot the the
fog comes in it kisses it and then it
disappears by 9:00 in the morning right
so I didn't deal with as much mold but
that little bit of humidity I mean that
sour was just like I made a name for
myself with that sour you know it was
like that first batch I kept growing it
um it kept coming out relatively similar
yeah and I feel like just having that
consistency you know so then I started
meeting other guys that were a part of
that crew that I got my sour from and
then I started seeing other sour from
the guys in that crew and kind of going
like oh okay this is what you know the
the the subtleties and then I'd be like
yo this the sour is like the Dank you
know and they started taking notes of
like how long they flowed it for you
know because people are like oh the sour
is like this and it takes this many days
well my most recent sour Harvest was 56
days my last one two months ago was 70
something days yeah this most recent
batch is going to be better than the one
before so to say that like you know what
something is how long it flowers for
what the flower structure should be like
is maybe a little little bit more
limited than somebody that has a lot of
experience growing that variety and
maybe has tried different things to
manipulate it to do different things you
know to get like that area sour because
it can be a little stinkier than like
the super dense sour right well indoor I
think there's a lot of reliability and a
lot of consistency and then you start
moving towards like green Greenhouse
whether it's mix light or whether it's
straight Greenhouse or outdoor each step
has a lot more variables and things that
can change conditions right with indoor
I feel like there's a lot of repetition
you're doing the same thing over and
over and getting a very similar result
at the end whereas Greenhouse you can
try but like even with Greenhouse if
you're relying on the sun you're getting
different amounts of light throughout
the year so you're ppfd is going to be
different yeah um that one variable
alone also just the the natural humidity
which you can control humidity to a
degree in a greenhouse but there's so
many little things that change
and then you go outdoor and it's
completely different so outdoor is more
like wine you got one rip a year and
from one year to the next you see it
different and I love that I love seeing
waiting to see what what's new what's
how's this year is going to turn out how
much rain did we have how much how much
did the environment affect it and what
did it what did it do yeah and I think
as Growers you know not necessarily as
much for the consumers but as Growers we
go oh you remember 2005 or whatever that
year was like that was a great year like
this year is going to go down as a great
year you know we're having 100 degree
temperatures in October I personally
have never had a 100 degree October it's
wild so we're going to see a different
outcome so we're going to remember I
mean I remember it was like 2016 there
was like a stretch of like 95 days
temperatures in September and I was like
wow like I don't remember this happening
you know since I've been growing so I
think we have these markers in weather
that produce different outcomes well I
think this year I'm seeing a lot of
a lot of the different genetics a lot of
different cultivars out there finish
earlier uh and I'm sure that's
attributed to the hot days I you know I
think that's one of the attributes uh
I'm seeing stuff that I wouldn't expect
to be early finishers and we got guys
when we were at canopis showing me buds
of finished products and I'm like wow
from From My Seats I was like that's
freaking cool I never expected that to
be an early finisher and it finished in
midt yeah it's interesting how weather
weather affects all that and that's why
outdoor growing is so difficult you know
when I was doing indoor it was like we
were doing the same thing on the same
day every day it was repeatable it was
uh that's really good by the way I know
I'm like I'm like I took like two hits
and I'm really high yeah I did the same
thing I took two hits because I want to
see where I go with it and I'm like I
feel really good I feel like I'm
definitely lifted but I feel
very communicative I guess is the right
word but I feel like I'm you know
sometimes if I get too high like I have
to think about stuff and I feel like it
it just flows so you know and there's a
handful of things that I like to smoke
that that do that and some of this stuff
man it'll get me so high on a show where
I'm like I start talking about just
random stuff instead of staying focused
right and that's the cool thing about
the pearls is it does get you high but
it's like a focused High you know for me
it's like a I don't know I find it's
like in the front of my face in the
front of my head and I find myself going
like damn I'm [__] high yeah but it's
in this really like not a racy way yeah
you know I think sometimes like with the
African Haze that's more of that kind of
like racy side of the high where you're
like feeling that intensity yeah and
that's where sometimes for me the kind
of like um I can kind of like just go
know somewhere else with it right yeah
it's a trip the African Haze you gave me
was really special too but it was pretty
strong it is I mean I find myself I mean
what we both took a couple hits and
we're talking about how high we are yeah
you know I mean to me that's the marker
I got like joints like this and I'm like
you know and I feel like I could smoke
this whole thing and I probably would be
about the same level of high but
different different effect I've tried to
really be like humble in my judging of
the weed that I get yeah um because I
feel like I'm super lucky I'm super
blessed to have been kind of marry into
a family that like has a such a a wide
variety yeah and I've been turned onto
something that I normally wouldn't have
ever found highs that I would have never
experienced mhm that I find myself
enjoying so
much I'm like I just don't really smoke
the other end of the spectrum anymore
because I like it so much that I don't
ever want to go back to that totally but
I try to be objective I try to check
things out so I can check myself you
know so yeah people give me weed
sometimes you know one of my homies like
he grows killer killer outdoor some of
the best outdoor mhm you know I picked
like three or four of his best that he
did one year rolled up a whole entire
joint of it smoked the whole entire
thing with my Dome this is you know I
don't know how long ago a couple months
back and it was like I was just waiting
to get high yeah and it's really good
weed but it didn't get me high you know
and I know that's partially due now to
smoking things like the pearls or the
African Haze where it's like I'm
expecting to get high for a really long
time in an intense way that people were
like yo what did you just smoke cuz
you're like buzzing you know and so a
lot of the weed I smoked now I'm just
kind of sitting there waiting for
something to happen and if something
happens it's like this lethargic feeling
that comes over me for a short amount of
time then afterwards I'm kind of like H
what are your thoughts on Skittles
everybody's gonna laugh at me for this
um I couldn't pick Skittles out of a bag
of 20 different varieties yeah I was
growing the sour heavy up until
2015 left California started growing for
another for a company in Washington
right as the SK Skittles hit yeah when I
came back I was working for other people
that weren't growing the Skittles when I
started doing my own thing the sour was
the first thing I got back so I believe
like I've grown the Dosey dough which I
think has Skittles in it and I always
hear people talk about no Dosey dough
times Skittles is moonbo okay but yes
Dosey Do is its own thing I really like
Dosey Do I mean everything that I've
smelled fits into 1.5 categories and I
say 1.5 because it all fits in the same
category and then there's some stuff
that I've SM that's like just barely
outside of the category for me but I'm
just like it's not far enough away to
get me into the zone of like the African
Haze has a really distinct smell even
for hazes yeah you know it doesn't smell
like a traditional Haze so right I I try
like I said I try to be humble and I try
to be objective and bias and still know
that there's other great weed out there
that can get me super high yeah it's
just not what I prefer to smoke these
days yeah you
know you know my brother he was a really
good grower out the gate and I was
really not a great grower and so slowly
over time I didn't even know that I
wasn't a good grer I thought I was a
good grower and I think a lot of people
don't even know because they haven't
grown long enough to understand and this
is you know the the 90s uh early 90s and
from the early 90s to the 2000s I
learned what good flower was and
even I still feel like I'm learning what
good flower is and it's constantly the
the needles changing right and so I'm
having to re-evaluate and look back at
stuff like this I really like smoking
this for the flavor yeah right and so I
can smoke a whole joint of this I can
just sit back and smoke a big joint and
it might take me 45 minutes to smoke one
of these joints like this right and I
enjoy
that uh meditation right and it's almost
like a meditation for me where I'm
sitting and smoking and just
contemplating maybe contemplating my day
maybe contemplating how much I'm you
know enjoying life right now or how
lucky I am to be alive but I feel like
some of those things where some of the
stuff you can smoke and you could just
sit there and do it I do enjoy the smoke
side of it too totally I mean I that's
you know it's the whole enchilada right
you know break it up smoke it sit there
get high think about it think about some
other stuff um you know and it's that
kind of the the final part of the
process from growing it you know
cracking the seed whatever planting the
Clone to like breaking it up and really
get into like what are your what do your
fingers feel like you know how does it
roll uh you know my father-in-law has
this like crazy criteria if the weed
falls out of the paper when he's rolling
it it's not good weed wow he's like got
he'll like the Skittles then he's got
that far so that Skittles reminds me of
the mango cush yeah um the Sunday driver
reminds me of that the I'm just going to
Rattle them all off because it's
interesting to me the um what is it this
DNA has a sour banana sherbet yeah so we
got the Sunday driver the sour banana
sherbet all remind me of the mango cush
that I used to get from these dudes that
had the sour yeah um not to the tea but
that's what I go back to so that fuess
yeah and there's fru there's a little
bit of gas but this is a special one
because they harvest on day 53 okay if
you go to day 61 or 62 or 63 it ends up
being much gassier much less it's not
fruit forward this when you break it up
you get like when I'm rolling I smell
fresh cantaloupe you know and I love
stuff that's unique like that where I'm
like oh it smells like this or it smells
like that I mean I love complexity and I
feel like this has the right amount of
complexity for something unique it
doesn't it's not the strongest it's
definitely not the stuff where you're
like wow the effect was just amazing it
does it can get you high but it's a
different kind it's more of a relax kind
of like white Thorn uh White Thorn's its
own thing too that has I feel like white
Thorn will get you high but it's more
like Johnny said it best it's like
getting hugged from your ancestors when
you smoke it and every time I smoke it I
think that you know I mean like it's
funny when somebody says something like
that and it triggers this feeling or
this thought like when I smoke it and I
don't know if it's because he said it or
right because that's how it makes you
feel but it's probably a combination of
both um and speaking of white Thorn Rose
Johnny and Jason for they were on the
podcast together Jason from Ridgeland
and that's another one where Terr is so
specific and light and elevation because
Johnny gave Jason the cut of the white
Thorn but it doesn't grow the same on
his property it was selected and own you
know and Johnny's been working for over
30 years on that property and then he
gives the cut to Jason and it doesn't
grow nearly as good yep and so Terre and
you know climate and environment is so
important to different things and and
what performs the best you have to
really try it out yeah in a few
different ways you got to kind of like
put it through the put it through the
test to see you know is it good indoor
strain yeah is a good outdoor strain you
know because some strains can be the
all-in-one and some of them are just
like like the perss back in the day you
did not want to grow that Outdoors you
know I never saw perss that really never
met anybody that was like oh I love
outdoor perss you know it was it was a
really good indoor train I never even
thought about that but you're right I
all the pretty I mean I saw some other
purple stuff that was good outside but
not not the GDP or the perss um yeah
blackberry kush was another one where it
looked beautiful but it didn't get me
high at all I think we had some tested a
while back and it tested at 8% THC the
Blackberry Kush I remember that one I
remember that I thought that was going
to like take over it was like really
white and frosty but had these like
purple and like Maroon kind of Hues to
it on the inside of it looked crazy as a
plant too it would Bush out and it would
get tall they I saw some big Blackberry
fish plants and they would get really
purple and really Frosty but then it was
never the stuff we had was never strong
it was always like borderline
prenda CBD yeah I think there's a lot of
CBD on the market right now that people
are passing off as I mean not that
they're in intally growing CBD flour
right but I feel like some of this flour
is reminiscent of CBD you know it's like
you should be able to take a few hits of
something and feel an effect yeah and if
you don't then you know maybe like
unless it's creeper then you feel an
effect 15 minutes later and some of the
stuff you've given me has done that
where you get that creeper effect where
you we we always used to call it creeper
Bud where you smoke it and then you're
not really high for about 10 to 15
minutes and then you're like oh [__] and
you it's harder to control the effect as
much but that's good too I mean I like
those kind of I feel like those are like
weekend strains just weekend
varieties and uh yeah there's even like
a creeper pheno of
like like my father-in-law sent me a
picture the other day and it was like a
creeper feno where it like grows wide
yeah and so out of all the varieties
that he's grown you know he really likes
the tie he he's he thinks that like a
lot of the more psychedelic type stuff
comes from the Asian regions um and then
he was always like be on the lookout for
the ones that grow sideways like real
long narrow branches the the creeper
ones that grow sideways because he's
like it's kind of how the pearls are
yeah they just like go everywhere they
Vine out yeah yeah um and it's you know
and it's it's a pretty good smoke nice
yeah so what do you think about this
statement
that the high the length of the high is
is in comparison to the length of the
the flowering time I've heard that
before I'd love to have your
father-in-law's opinion on that because
I I believe that I've seen that like
some of the longer like 16 18 weeks
stuff I feel like you some of those
bries that finish in 16 to 18 weeks when
you smoke them the high is super like
you can get a three-hour High out of
some of those I think that's 100%
accurate yeah um it's been my experience
with them you know I've grown 100 120
day varieties uh he's grown 22 weeks I
don't know how many days that is but
it's way too long so wild but I think I
kind of mentioned that earlier and um
you know I get a lot of I get a lot of
this from him but it's like it's
validated by like the stuff that I see
also right um like those pearls you know
is definitely one of the longest
flowering varieties that we continually
grow yeah um and it seems like the
longer the flowering time the longer the
highas um the African Haze 11 the pearls
they're things that you know can have an
hourong effect just off of a h a few
hits yeah so I really think that you
know there there's something to that
correlation with the how long it takes
to flower versus how long you stay high
for right um
and I'm just starting to see that he's
you know he's been grown for a long time
and I don't think really had anybody
that's like done the back and forth that
I have with him about these long flying
varieties because nobody's grown them so
like
you know my younger self even five years
ago I wasn't having the conversations
with him them that I am now yeah and
he's always been like you just got to
grow it just grow it just grow it and I
met someone recently they're like yeah
you know we're trying to like figure out
a way to like reincorporate these like
long flowering varieties back into the
culture and I was like who's we and he
was like just everybody in the community
and I was like well you just got to do
it you know like and that's what he's
been tell me you just got to grow them
you just got to plant the seede you just
but it takes longer so it's this like
it's more daunting it's there's not as
many rewards you know you pop some seeds
and he got the one out of the 10 out of
the Destroyer but that one was
definitely worth the 10 and and like he
said like not all Pearl fenos are good
you know like some of them just aren't
worth growing some of them are
exceptional so I think the amount of
people that are going to be able to
speak to that are very few I think he
would be a very good starting point for
people to start to look at like okay
this is a dude that's been smoking for
60 56 years he's been growing for that
long he's still smoking and he's still
finding things that get him high in
different ways but I don't meet too many
other 70 year olds that are like yo I
just pulled out a 20 weaker here's a
joint you know and it's been like that I
mean ever since I've met him 12 years he
has not slowed down no we got to get him
on the show dude we got to get him on
the show to to lay a good framework for
what I feel is about to happen with this
whole long flowering thing because once
people have access to this once they can
feel how me and you are feeling right
now yeah agreed they're going to want it
um and they're going to want it to a
point where it's going to be like that's
all I want you know because I've had a
few people that I've like given enough
herb for them to smoke for a few days
and they're like yo like you know I can
name a few people um and it's very
enjoyable once there's the access to it
that's when it's going to hit in the bay
there's no access right so you I see it
way more up in humbled and Mendo and as
you get the bay it's all this one thing
now there is a company in the bay and I
don't know their names and I'd love to
have them on the show too but they're
exclusively growing sativas I've I've
heard about them from a couple people
but I don't remember the brand name okay
and I would love to have you know it's
like obviously accessibility is the most
important part we're lucky to have the
access that we have but like it's really
shifted away in the bay from anything
sativa and you might find a dispensary
that has one or two options or a few
options right but they're in my opinion
I haven't seen a lot of good options Haw
spark has some good stuff I'm always apt
to like look at a menu look at their
sativas and then kind of be like you
know and then I ask what makes it a
sativa you know because I'm trying to
understand because I have a company that
specializes in growing these long
flowering or these sativa varieties sure
I want to get somebody else's opinion I
want to get somebody else's gauge of
what they think somebody replied to me
and said the terpinolene is what makes
it a sativa and I said okay interesting
you know that's an interesting thought
on it which I could maybe say yeah there
a lot of varieties that most people have
experienced that have been called
sativas do have a terpinolene dominant
profile in the US for sure but those
aren't what I would consider you would
consider or my father-in-law would
consider a sativa right and so trying to
respectfully
distinguish between a jack a blue dream
a sour a train wreck yeah and most of
these things pearls those are hybrids
those are hybrids that might lean a
little bit towards sativa but those
aren't necessarily really on the sativa
Spectrum especially you know like blue
dream is great but that's not a really t
terpinolene dominant variety either no
it just it has the the traits of the
shorter flowering Inda in terms of the
smell but it's got that Vigor and Bud
size totally and just girth of that
original Haze um oh even the leaves
right it has a thinner Leaf it's not the
thinnest leaf in the world but it does
have a thinner leaf and I think you know
I've seen some nl5 Haze crosses right
people call so you got the nl5 haze and
then you cross that with something else
I love no5 Haze by the way Fort Collins
cough one of my favorite all-time
favorites I love the effect and so I see
like you cross that with something
that's what's obviously indic a dominant
yeah so now how much Haze do we have
left in
that not a lot 25% it depends I mean
with genetic recombination it's
depending on the traits you're looking
at right right but if you take a 50%
indicia yeah and a and a and a 50 and a
5050 sure what is that 50% of the other
two go down to and then to call that a
sativa yeah to me to me is misleading
because now of my what I've learned um
so trying to navigate those terms I
think that's why we've landed on Long
flowering varieties because it lends
itself to like oh it's I do like that
term a lot better actually um I feel
it's more
descriptive of the the growth patterns
of of everything about it right and so
then looking at what people call a
sativa and I go and I ask I say what's
ativa and they point me to something
that has a lot of character istics of
something that looks like a shorter
flowering variety and so I go okay
that's cool like I see OG Kush labeled
as a sativa sometimes in dispensaries
and it's like I mean there's a lot of
stuff that I feel like is mislabeled and
it's so complicated because using
indicia sativa hybrid is just so General
yeah right and then even if we just
started talking about uh tpine profiles
that would be even better in my opinion
but I love the long flowering aspect it
really distinguishes it and makes it
very specific to stuff that flowers long
because I have some gelato times Mexican
Haze that's like a you know less than 60
days that's awesome I mean to if you can
get the effect of a haze in in that
short of flowering time I mean that's
like the golden ticket yeah you know
because like the African Haze 11 is in
flavor and and smell is nothing like the
Band-Aid Haze the Band-Aid Haze is more
of that like traditional Haze smell
right I don't think tur profiles are
really going to do it I think it's a
better conversation though because uh
you know especially if you're trying to
sell flour and you're trying to describe
effect a lot of times flavor and effect
can go similar if we're talking about
like the citrusy varieties as opposed to
the gassy funky or GMO even I feel like
those can kind of describe a fact a
little bit but even you know tpin we
talk about flavorant I don't know if you
know abstract Tech and their their
abstract Tech and their white papers
that they wrote but they go into uh
talking about flavorants and flavorants
are like THS sulfur compounds all these
things that weren't traditionally
discussed in the conversation with tpin
that actually have a lot more to do with
the the aroma and this The Taste than
the actual Turin so in about 2013
2014 I
was I was like what is what nutrient is
most responsible for flavoring smell
right so boom looked it up magnesium
yeah or sorry sulfur so an easy form of
sulfur is magnesium sulfate that's why I
said that so sulfur is most responsible
for flavor turpine and all that so I
started going hard on magnesium sulfate
on sulfur because yeah that's what the
plant wants to like produce those turps
and so now and I think we recently saw a
paper that came out and said these
things about sulfur being that compound
that's responsible for the skunk Aroma
in the sour right and my homie sent me a
message he was like yo he's like you
were right all along you know cuz I just
started doing it out of like nobody
really like talked about it then I I
went to work for a company and my buddy
had a the respect of the owners and so
he was like yo like let's try to
incorporate some sulfur into the feeding
schedule and now I think it's you know a
little more common that people are using
sulfer as something to try and enhance
that even Botanicare started their Suite
which is just magnesium sulfate totally
you know I do like that product I've
used that product I mean I used to use
that product I don't use it anymore but
I used it for a long time yeah um so
yeah all that stuff you know goes into
and I mean even the sour or like I grew
some Band-Aid outdoor a couple years ago
and it looked like crap and it was crap
but it still got me higher than
everything else that I had so it looked
like crap it had a low oil content it
didn't have a lot of Crystal on it but
it was getting me higher than everything
else yeah so I'm still trying to figure
out how is that possible you know
because it's such a complex plant and
we're still learning about it that
there's got to be something else besides
everything else that we've discovered
that would allow an everyday smoker to
smoke that at the end of the day and
take one hit and get so high that like
sometimes you like even recently I was
out somewhere and I smoked a half a
joint of that and I almost got too high
and I mean when I say too high where I'm
like I'm about to trip out you know it's
the only variety out there that makes me
feel like that well I have way that we
can sneak it into the world to where
where they don't have to see what the
flower looks like and pre-rolls I know
that pre pre-rolls right here I think
pre-rolls I've always believed in
pre-rolls because I feel like we're
we're in a world of convenience where
people want something convenient and if
you can take away the way that it looks
and you can just provide them with a
description of the effect and how they
it's going to make them feel good and
they smoke it and they get that they're
going to want to they're going to
gravitate towards that they're going to
want to revisit that and uh I think
pre-rolls are the best in a lot of ways
I think as long as you can get them
fresh and they don't sit on the shelf
for six months I think pre-rolls are
fantastic yeah they're a great way to
Showcase sativa type flowers that may
not look super appealing from a visual
standpoint but we got to get people past
that and you're right pre-rolls are a
great way to get people past that they
can have the experience the effect and
then they're going to be more receptive
to looking at the flower and thinking
damn that's what's getting me so high
yeah and I hope we get to a point as a
culture where we look at stuff like this
and we're like damn I can't wait to see
how that's going to make me feel right
not this prejudgment of looks like
oregano you K me I mean I think a lot of
people the first thing that would come
to mind is that that doesn't look like
weed I mean how do you feel right now I
feel great I feel good I feel uplifted I
feel energetic I feel like I could go
exercise that's for sure but I I feel
great I feel like uh I smoke just the
right amount to where we're having an
amazing conversation and time just I I
feel like there's this thing and I get
it from micro doing mushrooms and also
from smoking the right amount of weed of
the right cultivar where I don't have
the like there's this connection between
when I when I talk and when I have to
think about stuff and it just sometimes
flows and it'll like when I exercise I'm
not thinking about it I'm just doing it
and there's handful of things that can
get me into that that mode and and you
know this is definitely one of them it's
like I feel like I could pretty much do
anything on this and have a great time
doing it yeah yeah I like to tell you it
just makes you feel great you know I
mean that's really one of the I best
ways to describe it you know because
it's making you feel all these different
ways all which are just great yeah you
know the
aeno is 16 weeks unfortunately because
it's the best one um but I recently got
into a new greenhouse and and we were
doing some planting my father-in-law was
there it was pretty cool like he got to
come in and water the first set of
transplants on a greenhouse that was
like kind of you know first try with all
these genetics and I smoked some of the
A and I was just like D I was like
running through the greenhouse like
flapping my arms yeah you know I mean
it's like going on a Magic Carpet Ride
you know um and it's like it takes you
somewhere you know and and I think part
of what what I'm trying to do is bring
people back to like when your uncles
your aunts your mom and dad used to talk
about smoking weed back in the 60s and
70s and how good it made him feel you
don't ever hear him talk about like oh I
used to smoke all this weed and like
fall asleep it's always like we used to
giggle we used to have a good time we to
go out and do stuff yeah for sure yeah I
want to I want people to have that
experience you know and to like kind of
take it back to that I know a lot of old
school people that don't smoke anymore
anymore because the weed is too strong
and uh it's strong and pro and they
probably think it's too strong but maybe
it's just strong in a different way
maybe they like the stuff that was more
uplifting and not the stuff that was so
narcotic but I think there's probably a
lot of Truth to that yeah and I even for
younger people you know it's like you
may say oh like my grandpa used to smoke
that [__] back in the day and it's like
for good reason and I think it's also
going to be appealing to Young
professionals young Entre entrepreneurs
Athletic kids I mean I have uh of a
family member they're Engineers they
smoke some pearls and they're just like
instantly like know we wanted to start
solving these problems that we had at
work you know and they're in their late
20s early 30s yeah so I think it's going
to go past like oh this is like you know
this is my father-in-law on the shirt
Tony budo it's kind of an old school
looking image yeah um but it's classic
it's Timeless these varieties it's
Timeless weed it's going to make you
feel so good people are going to be
talking about this in to the next couple
of generations and be like dude my great
grandparents were smoking on that [__]
that made them feel good and then all of
a sudden this like weird like Divergence
came and people kind of like took this
Sid step like you know who Tom Hill is
of course good friend of my
father-in-law and he sent me a message
one day um and he was just like yo he's
like Tony Tony got off track with those
OG ladies you know um and and now he's
kind of like back on track and like for
the record Tony never fell off he just
maybe went a little bit more of a
direction than Tom did yeah in like
sticking with these crazy 20 weers and
so I feel like it's going to be comes
something that's appealing to everybody
because the effect the way it makes you
feel the creativity the problem solving
aspects the performance enhancing um I
mean the Band-Aid Haze is a great
anti-depressant like I just heard
somebody talking recently about like
there's no medicine yeah anymore the
Band-Aid Haze is an anti-depressant dude
if you were get that you memory recall
is what I was trying to think of but I
like the memory recall aspect of it
because then you don't have to think you
can just flow and that flow you know it
makes you feel comfortable when you're
in conversations a lot and and stuff
like that I feel like there's so many
benefits to it and somebody said that
the other day one of my buddies I think
Danny was smoking he was just like you
know I don't forget as much yeah and I
was like a light went off because I've
been on this sativa kick for a couple
years now like really only smoking long
fling varieties right and like I said a
light went off I was like when I smoke
even the sour I'm forgetting all kinds
of stuff like my homie Danny from GW he
every time he's just like I feel focused
he's like he's like I'm dangerous with
this weed he's like I feel like I could
do anything I have a laser sharp Clarity
yeah and it made me realize that my
memory recall has gotten better with
smoking these types of varieties so I
really believe people will find that
there's a lot of benefits to it not just
the how long the high get you know lasts
for how high it gets you but there's all
these psychological factors that go into
it right that went harnessed the tech
world is going to be like yo we want you
to micro do and we want you to smoke
this hay [__] from budo because it's
like the two ends of the like Focus
Spectrum right right that keep you
focused keep you clear but so creative
that PE like some of the biggest
companies in the world I me even Steve
Jobs has reported to have kind of gotten
a lot of these ideas for Apple after
tripping on l a few times you know and I
could totally see it for sure you know
Visionary yeah I mean and that can open
up parts of your brain that you didn't
have open before for sure and give you
perspective and I mean life is all about
perspective anyway feel like we have
these lenses that go over our eyes every
time we experience anything uh and
everything and to be able to pull some
of those lenses off and to see the world
from a different
perspective really puts the the grander
scheme and all these other things into
perspective um you know I feel like it's
it's always great to see something from
a different perspective and some people
just do it naturally and other people
they need they need that assistance
whether it's l or whether it's smoking a
little bit of really good stuff or
whatever yeah and you can get that with
anything you know I'm I'm real heavy on
the long flowering stuff because that's
what I like you know it's like it's like
Tony says you know it's all good just
different you know I believe that even
like the the worst grown weed you could
ever imagine like sprayed with with the
worst chemicals the most dangerous
harmful chemicals can still save and
change somebody's life so I'm not
promoting to grow anything like that but
I believe plant is so powerful that even
if you try and make it into this toxic
thing yeah it has this innate ability to
bring out the good in it itself and
reveal to you something that is amazing
out of something that somebody else
didn't give a [__] about and was
treating as a dollar sign to the extent
that they were willing we used to smoke
Mexican a lot of that Mexican brick weed
you know and that still had its I mean
it would give you a headache if you
smoke too much but it still had a spin
but that was really good weed just not
cured in process really
you know Mexican weed is some of the
like the strongest weed out there and
you get a good batch of Mexican in
Mexico right off the vine like we do
everywhere else in the world yeah I mean
you know like the pearls we put the
pearls in somewhat of a a loose brick
yeah you know it's like highgrade brick
weed yeah you know somebody could really
say that and I mean when I look at it
first time I was just like what the [__]
dude like really this is this is what
we're on this is where we landed this is
what we're on now you know you showing
me all this other stuff I seen all this
other stuff in this is what is driving
conversations now you know um so it's
really cool um I'm really stoked to to
be a part of it and I hope that I can
you know just continue to you know get
these hands on some of these genetics um
I know you got some St breeding projects
and potential I mean I I feel like I I'm
a I'm in it for the long game and I
realize how much is actually ahead of me
with the rest of my life to be able to
do some of this stuff and it really
really is a a a commitment to the plant
a commitment to yourself and a
commitment to the plant and it's
something that takes a lifetime right a
lot of this stuff we talk about what we
can do in five years and that's great
but like to really make a difference it
could take a lifetime this is a
lifetimes worth of searching for Tony
yeah and now he's made a difference in
my life and it's made difference in
other people's lives and he didn't breed
this right he just stumbled upon it from
the sea that he pop but you know but
we're all in the shoulders of giants at
the same time including ining him right
so somebody else did some work he found
it now you have the opportunity to
really be able to pass this on to
somebody else someday and I feel like
that's the beauty of the plant it is you
know and I feel like for me I always
like to share you know I I had my first
my first PL I harvested because I
couldn't afford to buy wheed yeah and
so hey got some weed cool shared it with
my friends and then you know I kind of
continued to grow and I found that that
was one of the things that I really
enjoyed was sharing herb yeah because I
knew how profound of an effect it could
have on somebody's life so I knew that
if I could give enough weed to one
person yeah that weed would end up in
two or three people's hands yeah so I
could affect a few people with one share
and then now we get the person that I
shared it with is having an experience
with the next person down the line so
you talk about like five six maybe 10
people having hopefully a positive
experience off of the few nugs that I
shared with them right and to me
that is like if you're going to be
growing a lot of herb and you're doing
it as a living please give them some
Away share it with other people that
don't have a lot of it share it with
your friends that maybe have a tighter
budget you know um share it with people
that need it and and get into their
hands and I feel like that has been
something that I've really enjoyed out
of all of it is being able to share I
agree and I feel like when like like for
me from a breeding perspective like
where I've taken and crossed two things
whether I created the parents or not but
where I've crossed two things I've grown
that out I have the finished product and
I'm able to share it with people it's
like you're sharing part of yourself
right and that's that's the beauty and
they're like you know and they're
getting to experience a part of you
right and then when I get other people
that grow out my seeds there's just
another amazing feeling where you're
like I got to smoke some of my flour
that somebody else imparted part of them
into and you know I'm that's why the
plan is so beautiful because it all it
brings us together in such a unique way
you know food can bring us together in a
great way too if you're a chef you cook
some stuff or if you grew vegetables
it's kind of similar but it's really
amazing like the full circle that goes
on with cannabis yeah there's a lot of
amazing totally different things that
stem from the one interaction I mean
like with the sour you know um the chem
you know that one interaction or maybe
whatever however many few interactions
it was we talk about the butterfly
effect you know what I mean and that
like that one interaction had it not
happened like that who knows where it'd
be with you you know and all these these
amazing coincidences potentially I guess
we can call them but like it depends on
how you look at life too well it's like
when we met you know I had recognized
you and uh I had no intentions yeah when
I approached you other than like I know
you like weed yeah and we had a
conversation and and it kind of led us
to this you know um and so so I think
there's that type of opportunity with
every conversation and I've been seeing
that a lot lately um because I set out
on this journey to bring these long
flowering varieties to the market 12
years ago when I first met my
father-in-law and I was like dude this
is the only way to do it you can't do it
indoor even though we both now have now
it's been you know really recent that
I've kind of like really put it out
there that this is what I'm doing this
is who I am this is what I'm all about
and I don't know if it's because I've
been preparing for so many years you
know like on a I mean I worked on the
name of the company for two and a half
years you know I got a trade mic lawyer
and he was just like he said yes to this
one and no to the other ones and so
because you can protect it right and you
know other people might say oh that's a
waste of money X Y and Z but I'm not
going to let anybody tell me that I
can't use this I probably I don't give a
[__] somebody tries to use my name like
everybody's going to know who the real
budo is that's my father-in-law Tony
that's who this is all about but this is
the brand that started together but
nobody else is going to tell me I don't
have the right to use this word and
that's a powerful thing when we're
talking about protecting our genetics
you know because the uh the loss of
ability to operate could put a business
out of business yeah and so if you have
genetics that you are holding that are
special to you or need to be saved your
loss of ability to operate can now make
all that disappear and we've all spent a
lifetime building up whatever we've
built up and I'm not going to let
anybody or anything
jeopardize that you know my wife's a
weed attorney she's like here's your box
don't go outside of it if you go outside
of that box we're liable to ask for
trouble great having a lawyer in the
family it is man it's funny though
because in the 215 days like when we got
together I was like oh everybody's like
oh you got a we we lawyer for your
girlfriend that must be great and I
thought I was going to be able to do
whatever I wanted yeah it was the exact
opposite she was just like well if you
do it like this then when you go to
court then I can cover your ass but if
you don't then here's going to be our
problem so I just looked at it like this
is kind of a common sensing if I'm going
to be doing it I might as well do it in
a way and she has an amazing track
record for getting people out of trouble
even people that hadn't kind of followed
the guidelines I mean she's gotten
pretty much every time she's had a case
like it's gone in the client's favor you
know um so I was like I better just take
if there's one thing I've learned listen
to your lawyer take your lawyer's advice
like whatever they tell you to do
they're if they're a good one they're
just trying to look after and you
protect you so yeah I was like oh I
can't do all this crazy stuff that kind
of sucks but it kept me in line it
probably prohibited me from doing a lot
of stupid stuff right and it gave you
guidelines to operate by that that made
sense for everybody and now I'm an
expert Court witness so it kind of like
comes full circle of like understanding
these things being like you know knowing
laws being able to interpret them and
just you know kind of being a little bit
in that world also right um so yeah it's
it's definitely been a crazy Journey um
but I think really really from a
breeding standpoint you know the AF or
the Bubba cush original Haze it's a
great hybrid you know it's a real solid
50/50 and so being able to take those
things and match them up with something
new that's where there's going to be
some really awesome magic and we're
going to see some really good
traditional looking weed that has a
totally different profile and maybe we
can get out of this predominant turp
this dominant gene that keeps on
infiltrating all the different crosses
and get some other stuff in there and
kind of start a new chapter in like okay
well we we got it to tweak a little bit
and now it's like when the cookies hit
they hit a profile that nobody had
really ever seen yeah and so it like it
changed a lot of stuff and it and it and
it took everything in a totally
different direction right you know and
we're going to see that happen time and
time again it's just when you know how
many times it's going to repeat itself
in every 10 years I mean we're on
thousands of years of this cannabis
stuff you know and in the last 30 years
we've had a handful of those OG sour
cookies train wreck you know those types
of things that have left a longlasting
impression with all of the generations
right all the generations know cookie
sour and train wre you know so it's
going to change again and people like
you like my father-in-law that have been
you know going this direction that
direction when we kind of come together
and we fuse those two
together that's where the Magic's at you
know yeah there's potential for some
really cool things to happen you I feel
like the the more the more people you
have that are skilled and are really
strong with their skill set that's
different from the other partner skill
set or the other people it always
complements the group and I feel like
especially two people going two
directions if you can put two people
going two different directions that are
on the same path and you have those
Collide then you have this amazing
opportunity for really cool things to
happen yeah that was kind of like when I
was growing the sour you know my buddy
was doing it more you know synthetic I
was doing it more organic yeah and we
were growing other stuff at the same
time but he had a spot I had a spot he
had another spot I had another spot we
had a spot together so we had five spots
and we were just like and we saw we were
at each other's house all the time we
were at each other's spots we were
helping each other out and so we didn't
even get a chance to include the ego
because it was just like we see what's
going on at each spot and really we both
just wanted good weed right but it
allowed us to really like see the
differences you know so we knew that the
way that he was growing the sour was
different in a way that I was growing
the sour and we both liked the way that
that I was doing it and I grew the sour
for long enough over and over and over
to learn how to grow weed in general and
that's would be my advice to anybody
that's just starting out just take one
genetic and grow it 10 times because
you're going to be able to identify a
nutrient deficiency after those mult
multiple times of growing it as opposed
to well maybe what you're seeing in
another plant isn't a nutrient
deficiency maybe that's its signal for
over or underwatering or X Y or Z so if
you really want to be good at growing
grow the same plant for a couple years
and try and harvest it as many times as
you can yeah I grew the sour still I
mean I've been growing it since 2001 so
we're on 23
years that I've been trying to like play
with it and it's pretty amazing you know
it's pretty amazing that long with the
same thing I mean I've lost the hour six
times and had to go back up to
Washington to my family up there and get
it back six different times because we
had a hard time keeping stuff alive yeah
I've gone to Great Lengths to keep it
around um I've really put trust in a few
people to keep it around um you know I
would call my buddy every six months and
be like do you still have it and I would
for a couple of days I would start to
stress really really hard when it was
out of my possession
because at a certain point people just
stopped growing it you know um that's
what happened in Washington eventually
they stopped growing it right that's why
I don't have that exact sourer cutmore
and so I would get really stressed I'd
call my buddy all right cool you got it
and then it was like as soon it was like
the day that I could get it back in my
possession and I could do it without
having a landlord messing anything up
boom I was like I need that back and
then I started growing it under LEDs and
it was not the sour that I remember from
the HPS that all my homies had grown the
outdoor I had grown um and so I gave up
on it I like literally and that was
honestly was interesting time me though
that was about the time I started
growing the hazes and the long flowering
stuff it kind of like filled that void
for me because I would have been jazzed
for like four or five years I was like
you know I finally get my chance to grow
the sour again it didn't come out that
great and I was like man I was bummed
you know this is something that like you
know people used to call me Diesel Dave
when I would like take into this one to
you know um and I had this like really
strong connection with the plant and I
was really let down and then I gave it
to a buddy and he grew it out last year
Outdoors out in Mendo and I was like yes
it still has it like you know because
you what you smelled what I what I knew
you were going to smell was very
particular yeah and when you smell that
you're just like f yeah it's there I got
it exact you know and when it's not
there you're just kind of like it's like
I was a serious bummer yeah um and so I
saw it last year and I was like cuz I
hadn't grown it for like five years
myself and i' given it to a few people
that had tried it out um you know some
of my friends that had seen it grow when
I was growing down in Santa Cruz and so
I was like all right I'm G to try it
again and uh you know thankfully it came
out good enough to run a second time and
now I'm definitely gonna be running
quite a bit more of it as I kind of get
back into the swing of things it's funny
because with sour before I saw your sour
I was kind of second guessing my own
memory and and thinking did I really
remember it right because so many people
have been giving me sour I got some from
some really reputable people that have
been on the show that gave me you know
nice flow but not the sour that I
remember so in my the back of my mind
for the last at least the last year I've
been like was my mind playing tricks on
me right and turns out obviously it
wasn't but it's great having that
reinforcement because there's things
like cat piss that I haven't seen in so
long and I believe that's probably still
out there with the right person I just
haven't found the cat piss that I
remember there's a lot of people with
cat piss but it's not necessarily the
cat piss that I remember and maybe it's
named something different exactly or
maybe it was never ciss but it has that
same turp Pro profile because there's
been a few varieties like um that
Skittles you showed me the Mango Kush
and the sour banana sherbet all have
that similar kind of dominant turp right
three different names um you know
there's another some other genetics out
there uh
that it's the root beer from mean jeene
um I oddly enough within a few month
time frame saw two other genetics
totally unrelated some of them from out
of the state that have that same profile
wow you know from people that didn't
even know each other or didn't even know
that there was multiple varieties of
herb out there that had that same tur
profile yeah I really like the black
lime reserve the number three and the
number five from Jackson yeah mean jeene
freeorn gotta love the the Freeborn
stuff he's one of my favorite breeders
yeah he's awesome let's smoke some of
this sour before yeah so you brought a
little present right here in this paper
bag yeah it's really
fresh um but you know um I didn't know I
love it this is a little different
structure than the last
stuff but this is real Sour like this is
even better of a nose than last time
like that is and it's a little denser um
and it's not really this maybe the other
buds are different but it's not foxed
quite Fox tailed as the last so I'm
going to be I'm gonna be honest in an
attempt to hope that someone else
doesn't make a similar mistake that I
did and I'm not going to go into a lot
of the details but the last batch had a
lot of pottassium yeah and what I
learned about potassium too late is that
it can have some negative effects on bud
formation yeah and so that last round
really didn't like fill out or do what
it normally does it was like totally
weird so that one is a little bit more
representative of the typical bud
structure yeah um you know those ones
got bigger you know they kind of get
that those like big wide classic sour
buds yeah um but this location has a lot
of sun you know it's up on top of a hill
so it gets sun up to sundown I mean it's
like you know Sun's doing sideways [__]
and so you're going to see it lean a
little bit more towards the den size but
not as dense as like the Bubba cush
original Haze you know so I think
there's those variations of most sour
isn't getting a ton of unobstructed
light at the end of the year you know
I've grown in spots where it got less
light and more light and I saw fluffier
versus dense I love the southern facing
hillsides that get real good good light
you know and I think that's that was
cazadera that's why it was so special it
was Southern facing and it did get a
little bit it was like it didn't get a
lot of fog but it definitely would get a
little bit more humidity and it wasn't
nearly as hot as more Inland and so for
the sour always had the the best nose
that was growing that growing up that
was where we used to get it and it was
amazing so but the flavor of this you
know I'm sure the will have to smoke it
I mean that's that's special so yeah
with all these L I have 70 L race
varieties and then I have more from Dave
mesford that I want a feno hunt and he
has some Nigerian black cross with uh
Blue 13 which is uh the the blueberry
Haze times
jre's uh Louis the 13th okay and I think
there's some really special stuff so
we'll have to go through all this stuff
and figure out what you're I mean
there's just so much so it's like okay
well we got to pick and choose the
starting point yeah and I mean you know
it's time and space that really as you
know that depicts everything but I think
there's there's a very good reason to
dedicate time and space towards pulling
out some of these longer flowering
varieties keeping them separated and
then remix them into new stuff yeah um
and then being able to say like I got
two new things right you know I think
that's a a big advantage in the market
um and
then yeah doing that work you know
because it's like you talk about normal
breeding projects how it can take you
know you flower plant out two months
later you make your selection well you
know four months goes by and you get
maybe
two breeding projects in a year because
of the amount of time it takes to flower
yeah you
know that can really
really slow the amount of progress you
can make and it can also be um
discouraging when you wait 20 weeks and
you don't get something worth keeping
you know a lot of the guys that are
still growing these long flowering
varieties seem to be like older retired
dudes you know and they're doing it
because they love the smoke and it's
like how do you how do you take
something that takes 16 to 20 weeks
that's like so good that you have to
share it with everybody right how do you
bring that out how put that out in the
market you know it's like my Band-Aid
Haze has seven more weeks to go you know
it's a week nine yeah it's not going to
be done until the end of November and I
started flowering in the beginning of
August you know you want to breed with
something like that it takes a whole
another level of passion and dedication
and I think that's why a lot of people
aren't doing it but um you know it's
like I we're here to deal with the plant
I feel like I'm here to to to do this
long flowering thing and try try and
bring it to you know the the older
Generations the younger generations to
us everybody you know yeah oh it's
really cool and I feel like I I love
Innovation within the pl even if it's
going backwards in a sense I feel like
sometimes we have to go backwards to go
forwards you know there's so many things
that are counterintuitive and I think a
lot of
people think they know what they like
until they've experienced something
that's outside the box that they really
enjoy yeah you got to be open-minded you
got to take the ego sometimes the ego
just has to go away for a little bit so
you can try something that's different
that maybe you know and I feel like a
there's a lot of ego out there too
especially with Growers and people who
they believe they're connoisseurs they
know everything about it and then they
would look at this and you know probably
give give it a thumbs down before even
trying it that's why the pre-rolls are
so perfect I thought I knew a lot about
weed until I smoke this you know I've
been smoking for you know since 99 I've
been growing since 2001 totally um and
I've had you know had a lot of harvest
too I think there's a sometimes I like
in my own ego I guess makes a
distinction between like growing for 20
years versus how many Harvest you had
right because when you're cranking out
you know like nowadays like some
companies are they're harvesting 100
pounds every three days like you learn a
lot quick so you could take a five-year
grower could actually be way way way way
more skilled than a 20-year grower just
because they've been harvesting every
three days for five years it's a lot of
insight knowledge in a very short amount
of time you can learn a lot of knowledge
but a lot of stuff is super automated
too so sometimes you might miss the
nuances of of growing Boutique flower
where it's like it becomes a commodity
and so you're growing at such scale
that I think when you're growing at
scale you have to grow you have to look
at it
differently uh whereas if you're growing
Boutique flower you can really get to
know a cultivar growing it over and over
and over on a small scale you can do
that with a large scale too and I think
that's still like Tri and air at a
larger scale but but when you're handw
watering and you're looking at a plan
every day there's something special
about that too that you get a different
experience of growing at scale totally I
agree I mean the difference
between having to make sure that a 500
life facility is producing enough weed
so that the facility can stay open is
different than growing weed that
like you want to show to someone you
really expect that you think likes good
weed yeah um and that that was always
the challenge for me was you know cuz I
had an instance where I was growing
Gorilla Glue for a company in a 400
light facility yeah somebody that had a
four lighter brought their Gorilla Glue
and I wanted to take it to work and be
like guys like this is what we need to
be going for you know and there were
things that that company was doing that
we kind of switched up um that improved
you know the quality a little bit um but
it's hard I mean we grew good it was
good herb but was it the kind of stuff
that I grew at home
no I think we could have gotten a little
bit better had we not done certain
things that they were doing they were
really worried about failing tests and
so we were spraying um oxidate at the
end of like the day of harvest wow and
then kill off any mold basically yep and
we stopped spraying it and I was like we
had this one variety that just didn't
taste very good and then after the
Harvest after we stopped spraying I was
like dude this stuff has some flavor to
it you know and we're not failing test
like just stop this I prefer not spray
at all and so grandm I mean that's
obviously the best right like if you can
not spray at all and like even my
outdoor at home I'd rather deal with
picking out uh caterpillars by hand then
spraying them with anything even though
it's for seed I'm GNA get a little bit
of hash out of it you know I do this
little seed crop at home every year
couple years back I did huge seed crop
but Grandmaster lighting has these uh
new UVC lights bug lights and I'm super
excited about testing them out and
basically so you don't have to spray uh
we're running a couple of my friends
facilities we don't have bugs here
because we're a closed circuit right but
still as a redundancy and in between
rounds and just to be safe they have
these UVC bug lights and I'm really
curious as to how they work with all my
friends and you know it's they're new on
the market they're available and they're
very affordable and to be able to not
spray anything makes makes the most
sense to me if I could if if I could
grow and I was a cultivator and I was
you know I was growing throwing lot a
lot of lights I would want a product
that could prevent me or at least assist
me in the
IPM uh model to where you're not
spraying stuff all the time and there's
not the rotation because a lot of guys
they rotate through stuff so that they
don't have problems they're being
preventative and I like preventative but
if you were able to do it without
spraying that'd be the best yeah I've
gotten on this uh this new uh bug
identification system that I really like
cuz it speeds up the amount of time that
you can find a bug in the room y um you
know I've got a smaller Greenhouse so I
still walk every aisle at least three
times a week yeah you know and I do a
pretty hard stare um sure you know I've
had a couple things pop up that were
like small little issues uh nutrient
wise right they can detect also um and
so it'll basically notify you through
this camera that has AI like hey you got
a nutrient deficiency what's the name of
it um the company that I'm working with
is called formada nice and they're kind
of I think they're based out of Israel
um and yeah like I said I mean it'll you
know if you got spidermites it'll
identify the spidermite send you a
notification and then you can like make
you know a change accordingly it'll show
you a graph it'll shoot yeah I mean I
can look at my greenhouse and it'll
pinpoint the plant that the issue is at
and so really and I think they've been
using this technology for a while uh I
remember back in the day I heard like
you could there's a company that could
find uh one specific plant in the Amazon
with this like detection system right
and I think that's what they do is they
get like the the the footprint you know
of a spidermite the footprint of an aid
or whatever right they see the damage it
makes and they can just like hone in on
it and identify it and it's you know
it's down to like it'll be it'll show
you everywhere it's at so yeah if you
have one plant that is starting a
nitrogen deficiency it's going to Ping
for that one plant wow and it'll show
you EXA where it's at and then if you
have a you know large cultivation site
and maybe you can't have people walking
up and down the rows yeah or whatever
this is something that you just boom it
and it's you know it's pretty quick to
identify it um I can't wait till they
can
identify uh I I think using ethylene
they'll be able to identify Herms very
easily if they haven't done it already
I've heard about trials being done with
infrared and some other tech technology
so I asked this company I was like can
you detect male flowers from aphrodites
with this software because if you can
that'll be a game Cher for breeders and
they said it's a different camera um you
know they the the camera they have is
they chose for a specific reason it
works for a lot of applications and it's
scalable right there's other things that
you could do maybe with other cameras
that might be outside of the scope of
their focus infrared drones let's do it
I'm excited but yeah so yeah you can put
these cameras on a field mount in an
outdoor spot and just put it on a post
so you can do indoors Outdoors green
houses um it's pretty cool you know good
sour good sour it's fresh it's like
super fresh still has the sour taste but
it's super Super Fresh I feel like I and
I still like the Skittles when I got it
the other day I Still Smoked it Super
Fresh just because I love the flavor but
this one it's like I really want to cure
that out for another week put them in
some tur blocks and let them go I did I
did I give you turp blocks last time
yeah did you try those out at all for
curing um you know I haven't cuz it's
kind of been in between but I have them
now yeah and I got some freshy it's
great to do side by sides too put some
in a a jar put them in a mason jar put
them in a turkey bag put some in the tur
lock and then really do side by sides
and take a little butt out and smoke it
like once a week and you'll really be
able to see the difference of okay I I
feel like the turkey bag goes first then
it's the Mason jar and then it's the
turp blck I'm well I got a fresh bat of
sour I'm gonna have to try it out nice
but yeah that stuff um you know wasn't
even really snapping on the stem i'
probably let it go you know another five
or six days before I even like take it
off but yeah yeah um you know one of my
measures of good sour is it when it
burns it should taste like good sour
even if it's two days after it's been
harvested you know it should have that
dank sour smell the whole entire way
through drying and if you can smoke it
at day five when it's obviously not
ready to be smoked and it still tastes
balm yeah and sour is a real greasy one
anyway so like it's sometimes when it's
grown perfectly it doesn't feel like
it's dry cuz it's so greasy
and then uh you know you can still smoke
it it's amazing yeah yeah uh I like to
say uh squishy squishy Bud Snappy stem
yeah you know that's like that's what
you want you know you can just crack
that stem and it's like just bounces
back to where the bud was yeah I love
that well so if people are trying to
find out more about you or they want to
buy some of your flour where can they go
um you can check me out on Instagram
head grower
uh you can check out budo humble on
Instagram and uh that's where we have a
lot of the flowers showcased and then
we're about to launch the brand budo
into California stores in the next
couple of months uh just ironing out the
last couple details so if anybody is
interested in this type of herb if
you're a buyer or you're a consumer um
just have you know just reach out to me
at head grower you can find me on there
one of the coolest Instagram names ever
you must to got in on Instagram really
early on it was uh
2016 wow yeah a good name I was very
hesitant at doing it because I was
working for a company at the time and I
was like you know I don't know how
they're going to view this um and I was
really hesitant about just like even
having an Instagram page I have never
been somebody to like show my face
anywhere so to speak you know so this is
definitely um I'm embracing the changes
necessary to kind of like move forward I
was always like a super behind the
scenes guy now is the time to do it yep
definitely thank you so much for coming
on the show today man it's been a lot of
fun um yeah we have to do this again
sometime soon yeah thanks for having me
I appreciate it
absolutely thank you guys for watching
please like And subscribe down below