[Music]
[Applause]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James loud
podcast and today our special guest is
Taran buckon from Oakland extracts how
are you doing today I'm doing excellent
very excited to be here yeah I'm glad
you're here too man I met you a few
weeks ago like it's it seems like a few
weeks but it was a little over a month
ago over at The Harborside reunion party
great event uh you know a lot of great
people coming together for a great cause
and uh yeah it's like a high school
reunion it was great yeah it's wild you
know and seeing some people that I had
no idea that were even going to be there
um you know because I'm as an outsider I
was a vendor you know knowing Steve and
Andrew pretty well uh doing some filming
with them especially over the last
couple years they're great guys and then
everybody that works at Harbor Side it
was like very family oriented company
yeah it was a beautiful space to be in
um I was lucky to be there uh early when
they opened I worked there from 09 to
2012 and so I got to know a lot of the
original staff that first open the store
and just when the staff was a little bit
smaller as it was starting to grow those
were the best years too in my opinion
those were the best years of Harbor Side
going there as a consumer going there as
a vendor someone who went there to buy
clones they had the best clones like
literally they set the standard for
clones the same standard that we have
today was set at Harbor Side back then
and the world had never seen anything
quite like it yes there was you know
there was clone vending going on before
Harbor Side there's clone vending going
on now but right you know when they when
they brought out we had Dan Grace who
really rocked him out uh from darkheart
Nursery man just really killing it on a
whole another level and you know scaling
and as they
scaled uh they maintained quality and
very even clones you know I haven't seen
very many companies that have competed
with those kind of clones even today
yeah I don't I mean I'm not in as in
touch with the Clone Market as I used to
be but I had never seen a clone company
grow to that scale that size that well
branded and still people come came back
loving the cuts even years into them
being popular a lot of Brands will kind
of get big and the quality kind of
starts to waiver as they scale up and
they always maintain that quality so
that was awesome I feel like at the end
they had problems they had hop plate and
verid was a big problem and so that
really I think affected them more than
anybody that I've ever seen uh but yeah
and as you scale it gets difficult and
the scale that they went to was pretty
phenomenal
and Po and then just gr and then
providing good genetics and I feel like
they were very they had good Integrity
with the the genetics the names of the
genetics everything was tested they they
weren't just throwing stuff out there no
we really liked working with them when I
was there there's a lot of the there's a
lot of small clone companies are kind of
popping up out of nowhere and then you
really couldn't trust where the genetics
were they say it was one thing but it
was often something else and dark heart
you really felt like yeah you could you
could really trust what they were doing
and just that era I mean I remember
before there really was a clone
department at Harborside and then once
there was and once it got rocking I mean
there'd be a line when it was the season
the line there's a line outside the door
two hours before we opened that was down
the block and that line existed until we
were closed and there's still a line out
the door well after we were closed
people coming and getting those clones
and they were selling them by the truck
full yeah just you know it was funny
because you would go uh it you would go
online and I believe it was Twitter back
in the day um you know when Twitter
first became a thing you would go and
get the menu and hopefully you could get
what you wanted to get there it was like
published the day you know the day of or
the day before and you go there and get
in line and hopefully it was there maybe
it was maybe it wasn't but there was
always a diverse menu too of all kinds
of good stuff you know and it really
impressive you know looking back uh
looking in hindsight you know the stuff
that these dispensaries went to to get
to the points the places they're at now
yeah well it was beautiful working there
because before there most of the
dispensaries they're a lot smaller a lot
darker um security was kind of big
scalling guys up front and just the
entire experience it kind of felt like
going to a used record store if you
didn't really know the cool thing you
kind of got a certain kind of vibe from
people where was Harborside all the
security they refer the security as
safety it was wide open it was beautiful
it was well lit and it was very
welcoming and inviting for people who
weren't necessarily from the Cannabis
community and they really made a point
as someone who worked there that you had
to be smiling all day if one if one of
the managers walked through and then saw
you not smiling they jumped on you
because they didn't want you just
sitting there looking stoned they wanted
you to look aware and engag so when
someone came up to you talking about
cancer or talking about some kind of
issue they had you weren't just some
Stone kid in the back they really wanted
to make it clear that this was about
medical and about servicing the
community yeah it was cool and they they
had a lot of money to yeah harbor side
was very successful so they had massages
and they had programs and they had you
know classes and all kinds of stuff they
spent a lot of money on that even when
they weren't making money that was
always a priority of them to make sure
that there's free health services
available to the community and that was
something that no matter what what was
going on with them financially they
always maintained through all the
lawsuits with the feds through the tax
bills that came in they always made sure
and all those people were paid by harbor
side these people weren't just giving it
away for free so it was really beautiful
thing that they committed to yeah they
had a big Target on their backs being
the biggest and being the first to do
what they did and then to scale people
wanted to make an example of them it
they were always in court it was always
someone trying to come after them it was
it was wild yeah our monthly staff
meetings were just Court updates usually
what's going on with this case this feds
might come in different trainings for
the cops coming in the feds coming in
how that might look different and it was
it was a lot yeah so how did you get
your start in cannabis um as a consumer
you know love the plant grew up loving
the plant uh all through high school and
in college I was always a big big fan of
the plant it was a big part of my life
and um I kind of inadvertently started
growing a friend of mine was started had
had a little grow at his house and I
would just kind of help him out he had
helped me out on a project previously so
I kind of owed him a little bit of Labor
and then so I started help helped him
build out his grow helped take care of
his plants and didn't realize I had a
green thumb before them and like really
got into taking care of the plants and
all this time I was working in different
nonprofit organizations so I had a kind
of a square day job and then doing this
in the evening I really really got into
it and I got so into it I wind up having
my own grow at my house and then I
stopped working in nonprofits and I was
just growing and I I lived right near
Harborside nice and I would um I would
go by there like every other day right
before closing just to kind of come in
get a gr but really just to hang out and
shoot the [ __ ] because when you're
growing it's a very insell activity like
I'm by myself in a basement all hours of
the night and so it was just kind of
nice to go there to hang out and they
just started joking like you come here
so often you should just work here and
um and I honestly I got more good advice
about growing from the people that work
there than even the original people that
kind of put me on to growing and so it
just a great knowledge resource and I
had the time and so I just started
working there kind of for fun when so
many good Growers going in there it was
and and vendors too like the quality of
the flower there was really amazing
flower uh diverse you know there was
something for everybody too it wasn't
like there was only top shelf there was
top shelf and there was the bottom and
there was stuff that was was affordable
that was good um you know and good
healthy clean medicine I think that was
always the agenda was to have good
healthy clean medicine yeah that was the
focus Rick the original buyer there was
like really really strong on that before
we had any kind of um lab testing they
were very clear about what kind of
growing practices they wanted to see The
Growers have and as a vendor before I
started working there people would be in
that vending room they were getting
their hearts broken because everyone
thinks they just have the most beautiful
plants and they go back there oh and
they would get uh they would get long
explanations of what can do better next
time and you see people coming out just
Crest falling but it just increased the
amount of effort and energy put in
towards their plants and making it
better it just improved the quality for
everybody so what was your favorite
flour from back in the day I know mine I
mean there's so many we we had a cut of
super silver haze that Steve insisted
was not super silver haze because it
smelled nothing like Haze he was like
stop calling it super silver haze he got
really mad he came in one day he smelled
it and he's he went off and he's like
just call it super silver it's too
cheesy and we're like the We're Young we
don't know what you're talking about
this is just the best sativa ever so I
used to love that we had it was that 97
cut I believe it was that 97 cut that
was extra funky it wasn't as terpinolene
dominant or terpinolene dominant yeah I
used to love that one I love the old
school ciny star yeah C it was so good
back and I miss real indas that tasted
amazing I don't care what they tested at
but like like Romulan yeah Romulan
Romulan Romulan um and pure Afghani umgh
everything before the pers took over
there was it felt like there's a lot of
more variety with around the indas and
it was really interesting you could
really feel them then when purple
started to dominate that everyone kind
of went that direction Purple Kush that
was out for a while I like the old one
when it was ugly little nugs that were
just dense and they actually did
something to you as opposed to whatever
came out later that I think was just
another version of Grape Ape they just
look good but didn't really do much I
like purples used to actually have an
impact and then they started TR of focus
on were some strong ones for sure but
then then there was like the Blackberry
Kush right and that was like the weakest
of the week it was like CBD we didn't
even test it back in the day but I'm
pretty sure it would be super high in
CBD and super low in THC yeah yeah but I
missed a variety I I missed that variety
oh yeah and all the different long
flowering varieties uh you know it's
like there was some really special stuff
power plant I didn't like back in the
day but I like now I was always a big
fan of red Congo still am but I I like
red Congo more than than I do now and
then I like red Congo more than the
Durban and more than the Mala although I
like all three of those a lot the red
Congo makes me like laugh and smile and
the Durban just takes me out same thing
with the Malo is one of those ones in
small doses it's great but like you can
overdo it with that one for sure you
really got be climbing the walls oh yeah
yeah good stuff yeah my favorite my
favorite thing at Harbor Side back in
the day was the sage and sour I believe
it was from Santa Cruz yeah yeah that
was special I had my friends were
growing that for a long time so I got
really close with that plant that was
one of the original plants that we
started extracting when we started oen
extracts um that that was phenomenal the
San hard this that whole crew they're
all indoor organic soil soil grown was
that was that in my opinion that was the
best thing that came out of Harbor Side
the chem 91 was really good too the you
there was a bunch of amazing amazing
things that came out of that uh era but
that sage and sour was something special
because it was like if you like sour it
was great if you likeed Haze it was
great it would it would just check so
many boxes it was gassy it was it was
really nose burning pungent and the
structure was amazing it had a lot of
structure to it I miss the same crew
that that worked with the sage they
didn't create the sage but they had the
sage for a long time at Harborside they
did a Kyle kushman strawberry cough and
there was a couple runs of that that was
the best smoke I've ever had in my life
where it was like a psychedelic
experience it was so amazing but what's
interesting about growing is like they
had the cut the cut didn't change but it
was really just they it was great for
like a year and a half and then it kind
of whatever happened it kind of
deteriorated or their ability to get the
most out of it changed and it just was
just never the same yeah I like
strawberry cuff I feel like blue dream
is great it's like you know like blue
dream is very functional but Strawberry
Cough is a stronger Blue Dream It's like
it turn it's like blue dream turned up
yeah I was a big fan a big fan yeah yeah
good stuff I mean yeah I love talking
about genetics from the back you and
there's stuff that I haven't heard of in
a long time and somebody brings it up
and I'm like wow I remember that that
was amazing I just miss basic stuff like
UK cheese yeah like I don't understand
why that's still not around that was
loud you cross it into to know the right
people Nick has some okay so nickes got
some but uh it's not common to see
cheese right like cheese or even like
strong cheese derivatives I you know
there are some of these chemi things
they're like so I smell in extracts too
like when you're smelling raos and
you're like that smells cheesy and
people like I don't know that smells
like the cheese The Strain you know I
mean real UK or Exodus cheese that's
phenomenal yeah I just missed the
variety like I it like I I I mean gelato
is cool yeah you know all that all
what's happening now is cool but I just
miss a variety that we used to have and
there was just so many different and
there so many different types of St
strains coming from so many different
mom and pop grows yeah and the the best
I've ever smoked in my life were coming
from people that had like two four six
eight lights I mean literally all the
craft all the craft grown stuff that it
would come out different every time or
somebody had mastered its variety right
they had taken one cultivar and that's
all they grew for years and they' really
dialed it in I know some old hippies
that still do that you know it's like
that that's in my opinion is the best
like where you've mastered that because
the thing is is like everything requires
uh different inputs to a degree or or
different variables you know whether
it's harvesting on a certain date and
playing around with that or whether you
need to push it harder in the beginning
or at the end you know I think there's
there's so much to cultivation and
learning the cultivar yeah U and then
there's something special Bubba Kush was
good back in the day yeah Bubba was
amazing the Master Kush the Bubba Kush
the Hindu Kush yeah I I was not a fan of
that cuz my friends grew way too much of
it but like when I first got my hands on
it it was amazing and and like they
crossed it into so many different things
that really really really great great
plant I really um like I said I miss the
variety that we used to have um I like
the access that people have now I like I
like going I do demos at stores seeing
all these people coming just buying
gummies who like five years ago wouldn't
have even gone near a cannabis shop so I
love like how open it is but I do I do
miss the old the old guard I do miss the
old Farmers I do miss the old quality
and then I miss people just appreciating
flour like extracts are cool I I like it
dab but I'd rather have a joint any day
of the week I love flower I miss an
appreciation of sungrown it's like it's
like people so much so much
mass-produced like stuff they don't
understand that the best stuff on Earth
comes off of some Mountain somewhere
that someone picked you know and they've
probably never experienced it that's the
thing is like there's so much people
think oh well I know weed I smoke weed
all the time I go to the dispensary I go
to this guy and he's you know I go to my
plug and he's got the weed like I've
tried they think they've tried a lot of
it but they don't think sunr is great or
better or Superior and it's a different
product right like especially the effect
like we've gone away from talking about
effect which I feel like we need to go
back in that direction to like okay so
how does it make you feel yeah exactly
yeah and there's a handful of us that
are really kind of trying to push that
agenda and I think it's it's going to
catch on because at the end of the day
that's why we're all attracted to this
plan it's not because the way it looks
the way it tastes is may be cool but
it's really the effect it's the feeling
like I I miss being able to smoke
something and go to sleep like I miss
when indas actually put you to sleep cuz
that's really how I got GDP that gives
you the munchies yeah I mean that's how
I really got into can because I had
trouble sleeping when I was a kid like
all throughout my childhood I couldn't
sleep at all and the first time I not
the first time but but when I really
started being able to get regular sleep
was when in high school I discovered
cannabis and so over the first few years
I had cannabis a lot of times I wouldn't
smoke throughout the day but I always
made sure I had a bedtime Bowl because I
knew I would actually be able to go to
sleep that night and then actually work
in medical cannabis and realize there's
all these different types of cannabis
for all these different things and you
experiment with all that and you kind of
kind of fall in love with that and then
you see now wreck has taken over and
we've walked away from it being
experiential base we're being about
health and medicine and things like that
now it's just like pretty colors high
THC scores we really lost a lot I mean
Instagram weed will only get you so far
yeah you know but I think Instagram and
social media has they've changed the way
we look at at cannabis in general you
know but I think there's no no time like
the present to change you know I think
like podcasts you have your own podcast
too yes sir absolutely you know I think
podcasts are a great way to influence
people to change telling your story
telling the the world about the effects
of cannabis and how you know it's not
just about getting high um and I think
people can relate to that too cuz you
know it's like people have taken that
edible dose that's like 500 milligrams
and it's like some people never want to
take Edibles again because they've taken
too big of a dose yeah we used to scare
a lot of people off now that's actually
the one Improvement about what's going
on in the market is back in the day so
many of the Edibles were really really
strong that when someone came in we
would just absent mindly give them 100
milligram cookie not realizing that 5
milligrams would have been perfect for
them and now it's the opposite like it's
hard to find something that has a lot of
milligrams in it and that's safer for so
many people and so many more people do
have like a gentle experience with
Edibles which is really nice to see I
think it's good I think cuz that's a
great way to turn someone off from the
very beginning from their first
experience they're like oh I'm going to
go get 100 milligram edible and then
it's like okay well I never want to do
that again because I don't want to feel
like that but the thing is is like if
You' eaten 5 milligrams or 10 milligrams
or maybe even 20 you would have had a
much different experience yeah it's
interesting because it's it's it's so
important that people have a great
proper introduction to cannabis because
again having um having edible that's too
strong is going to really turn you off
and kind of turn you away from
everything
in the same way a really good topical
can be great to get people involved in
it I love giving topicals to older folks
realizing that they can deal with pain
relief without going to the medicine
cabinet having something safer more more
holistic and that opens them cannabis in
general you can start with the topical
move over to a small gumy and kind of
just get them deeply they got bath bombs
they they got all kinds of stuff it's so
wild and we live in this world of
convenience it's like uh before we had
to really worked to do it you know like
roll a joint now there's pre-rolls or
hand rolls you know before dabbing it
was like there there was a lot of
different ways we smoked like Adam
Smashers smoking on coal and you know so
hot knives I still miss the hot knife
the hot knife was great there was like
these weird little eras where like I
remember hot knives in high school I
went to high school in the 90s so I
remember had a friend that lived in
Spain and so he would he would go out he
visit his dad every year and they would
come back with hash and they would put a
little bit of hash in the hot knife and
it completely blew my mind oh yeah and
then seeing them they started making
like glass hot knives like like little
glass like spoons they had like a little
divot in it with the knob on the other
end so you could really get it in there
and I remember a friend of mine he had a
um like a glass little thing that you
inhale through that had a a big hole in
the middle that you could put ice in it
and you put a cork in it so it cooled
the middle of this this little Flume
that you kind of hit this like the [ __ ]
and that's all G so creative yeah and I
think you can attribute some of that to
the plant right like the the creative
side of it you're like okay well how can
I make this experience better you know
so I got some guys that are for my
friends Asher introduced me to catch a
fire and those guys are from New Zealand
and in New Zealand they have their own
version of hot knives it's a torch that
has the knives on the end of it it heats
the knife up and you push the button you
you put the butt in there and you
squeeze it and you hit it out of a tube
oh that's awesome I got to try that oh
yeah it's it's wild and like I would
never have normally done it but I was
backstage uh at a show and Marlin's like
oh yeah we got to smoke with these guys
and they were like dude you have to hit
this and I normally would have been like
I don't know but I was like okay I'll do
it yeah it got totally ripped yeah you
got to try it where however people
present it where they're from like this
is what we do at home you you want to
try that you want to get a taste of it
yeah it's a different experience you
know there's so many different ways you
can smoke I mean you got your puff Co I
got my focus V yeah uh ways of
convenience and it's just so easy right
so and then we have all these flavors
too I mean I got a variety of stuff I
got some uh long flowering varieties I
got some really short flowering
varieties I got the Skittles candy candy
it's really got candy yeah you know more
than anything especially with extracts
is candy candy candy flour too M but uh
you know and then but we're missing out
on some of these amazing long flowering
varieties when it comes to flour I
prefer a sativa I prefer things that
they grow like that but when it does
come and and in in flour I'm not a big
candy fan but when it comes to dabbing I
like the candy stuff all day and I don't
like it when they press anything else is
really interesting I mean I'll sit there
watching TV and I'll just smell too I
I'll dab but I'll also just smell the
xjack because I just love the way it
smells I do that with bud but more so
with little jars because it's just I I
have these little jars it's
concentrated oh wow there's some uh long
flowering yeah very
Jackie yeah super silver yeah super
silver yeah yeah Super Silver and uh
miss that Flor flame Flor flame those
guys are good another Oakland company so
we're all practically neighbors that's
great I didn't I was under the
impression that sativas don't press very
well and that's why we don't see a lot
of sativa in the Rosen Market but to
know that Sil super silver does like
could just have that as my sativ and
just be happy right there it'll do it
for you and the thing is is it's one of
those ones where you don't need a big
dab of it right like it's super strong I
feel like uh palpitations yeah whatever
like if you do too much like for me I I
enjoy it it's a good daytime thing it's
like uh or or morning I go to the gym
you know and it's like now rosin carts
it's like these are great for rosin
carts and I get in trouble I I work out
a lot and I definitely smoke before I go
in the gym but I I can't use the cart
cuz I'll like keep hitting it the whole
time I'm like in the car or at least if
it's a joint it's a beginning middle and
end so I don't over consume because if I
hit a cart for 45 minutes then go in the
cardio is not so good yeah for sure so I
just do the two hits right like I'll do
one or two hits the two hits is the most
in moderation it helps me focus it helps
me get through cardio if I have to go do
cardio if it's a cardio day I I do enjoy
smoking a pen and it's like depending on
the day and the mood some things I don't
I cannot smoke and go to the gym and
I'll be like no I got to get out of here
but other things it's like Skittles too
Skittles is one of those ones that the
the extract of Skittles is super mild
compared to other ones but it leaves
that taste in your mouth too so when
you're working out you're like yeah I've
smoking Skittles yeah I've really uh
this year I've been stuck on the white
Thorn Rose yeah yeah over we talk about
it on almost every episode of the
podcast I'm disgusted with myself how
much I like it and because I'll still
like I go out I buy a lot I buy from a
lot of different brands just kind of see
what's current see what people are doing
and the amount of times I'm just go back
to the white Thorn this is my favorite
thing of all these things that I bought
I'm almost embarrassed well you
shouldn't be because I'm that same way
and I feel like it's good old Feelgood
weed and we need to get back to more of
that stuff that the effect is so
important like with white Thorn Rose it
just makes you feel good like you smoke
it you can do anything you conquer the
world uh blue dream does that to a
degree but it's different yeah uh and my
buddy Dave mesford passed away on 420
his Blue 13 has the exact same effect as
white Thorn Weare okay you can smoke in
the morning you feel great you smoke in
the afternoon you feel great you smoke
it in in the evening you feel great
doesn't matter when you smoke it what
you're doing you just feel really good
and I feel like those people that
haven't experienced that with cannabis
that are like I don't know I don't think
cannabis is for me they should probably
try way throwing row yeah and it's just
it's it's one of those profound effects
where it's like it just makes you feel
whole or complete you know like that's
that's what I love about it I love
giving people their first dab or even
their second dab because I do a dab bar
as like cuz I'd rather do a dab bar than
a demo I don't want just sit in the
corner of a club I'd rather go to
there's a lounge where people can try
things that can sample things that's
where we met was your dab exactly and
just being able to offer something that
tastes delicious and then also I'm very
keen on low temp small dabs in the
beginning so you can kind of just get
the flavor of it and not overwhelm them
and so many people their first dab was
red hot and just burning screaming kind
of experience that I like 900 de yeah
give them something gentle something
that tastes amazing and just kind of
seeing their eyes light up and like I
had no idea it could be this good I had
no idea this experience could be like
that what's the perfect temp for you for
low temp o um it's going to depend on
the consistency of the concentrate 100%
um I always go for it as low as possible
but certain things like I mean I don't
like to dab diamonds but if you're
dabbing diamonds they want more heat
than like a nice rosin yeah um usually I
mean I guess I could open up the app on
my puff Co I can tell you exactly I
think for um my normal puff Co my my low
temp on the puff Co is around 450
sometimes 475 um Roger from puffco he
says he does 530 so I started doing and
he has access to everything so I started
so I started cranking mine up just to
like well I guess it's okay and it's
just a little hotter than I like but
definitely you feel it so much more when
it is a little bit hotter but I like the
high fours low fives yeah this because I
want to taste it CU my thing is like I'm
going to keep hitting it like I don't
need to just get wasted I don't need to
get loaded immediately i' rather just
dab I'm I mean I'm going to dab for a
long period of time anyway so I'd rather
just kind of savor the flavor of it
mine's a 420 I like that four that load
it's easy to remember too it's like okay
what's your temp it's 420 so and low low
temp I think so some people go even
lower than that but I feel like that 420
is about where you get a lot of flavor
it also depends on the device too cuz
each one calls a little bit differently
definitely on my on my focus V I have it
dialed lower because it's hotter for
real for I don't know which one's more
accurate than the other but I know on my
um on my focus I should have brought it
because I have it on the counter sitting
right next to my puffco it'sif it might
be 375 or like low fours you got to try
this this is the this is the Rover you
can you can change the temp of that as
well excellent excellent and uh yeah and
it's convenient you can watch the smoke
I I love the convenience of it and I
love the price point they're $80 oh it's
perfect you know and I'm not getting
paid to advertise this at all I love
these guys uh yeah they they do a great
job I just love all the devices out
there I just love the [ __ ] toys like
I always have well yeah and I love the
guys that are pushing the envelope on
stuff and trying out new stuff and they
might not hit it out of the park every
time but like dip device they had a the
the uh the or original Little Dipper is
like the straw like the E straw right
where you can just dip it in and I was
like oh whatever I like my nectar
collector I'm a big nectar collector guy
I've always like the a bu I've got a
drawer full of them yeah and they're fun
they're easy to use and then they had
this e version of it I'm like e it's the
drawer for six months honey bger yeah
there I every time they get I got one I
wound up giving it away immediately
because it was just like just be the
torch yeah yeah and so I I used it after
six months I'm like oh this is great for
events where I go to and I want to try
everybody's stuff but I don't have time
to take you know like it's there's a
process there's time and I want
convenience it's the most convenient you
just open the jar up uh yeah and
hopefully you don't burn their extract
inar ex that's my thing CU I I never
whenever someone brings it out I'm like
I'm not just giving you my jar because
you'll just manhandle big old mason jar
they're like putting a big old Mark in
it you know like no good yeah but this
is this is what I love about our
industry that there's just so much
variety there's so many options just
seeing all the merch you have when I
walked in here just reminded me of how
much of an exciting space that we're in
right now yeah we're we're about launch
loud times it's our brand uh our our
clothing Lifestyle brand that we're
about to do and you know it's Oakland
rooted in Oakland just like everything
else we're doing I feel like yeah this
this community is great you know and
it's like uh very supportive of other
small
businesses uh that are still around
because it's tough these days you know
it's very tough very tough so yeah and
then the Lifestyle brand it's like
cookies does really well with theirs
backpack boys is doing well with theirs
you know we're we're a little bit
different than those guys we have our
own style and well makes sense you just
I mean I think the key with
merchandising is like you speak to your
community yeah I mean cookies is cookies
I mean that's that's that's who burner
is there's four-year-olds wearing
cookies t-shirts and then with with bre
backpack boys like if you know them like
they are very much in tune with their
community and is in tune with them and
it's very organic and all that and I
feel like your brand has that can do
that as well because you're you're
speaking to a certain group of folks
that are out there that like want cool
stuff so yeah and everybody wants cool
stuff to a degree you just have to find
you you got to get in where you fit in
you know at the end of the day and it's
like and authenticity just goes so far
with this industry you know it's like
you can spot it a mile away there's a
lot of there's a lot of uh people that
have come in from other Industries and
they weren't cannabis guys but they're
like I'm going to make money in cannabis
and and you might be successful but most
of the time you're not no they're never
they never really are now I mean they
think they're going to be and it's funny
because I've been in legal cannabis
since 06 yeah I think and then I was on
the oak Canabis Regulatory Commission
for a while like I was doing like a lot
of stuff and then I wound up I guess
Consulting with various people that were
coming into this coming into Oakland
trying to start businesses right and it
was always these investment bankers and
they were just like yeah we're gonna
have a brownie and I'm like no you're
not like you're not they they think they
can come in and revent the wheel like
you guys just didn't know how to do it
right and it's like no you don't you
don't want to learn the lessons of all
these businesses that have tried and
failed around us from people who've
actually been here in this community not
like Oakland but in the Cannabis
community and understand like what's
going on with these products and they're
just like no we know better and we're
going to come in with our money
spreads and we're going to show you we
got someone from Nestle and they know
how to make the amount of times we have
this choler from so and so and I'm like
bro Christy at ke is going to kill you
like you're not going to survive like
you can have all these people you want
but we have products that already exist
that have been doing really well for a
good reason and you're not just going to
come and replicate that or do yeah
improve on that it's like yeah it's in
that that that space is so different
than cultivation in in the regard that
the companies that are doing really well
well it's not easy to just go in and
like I got a good product and it's going
to sell it's like there's so much more
to it and just cuz you think you have a
good product doesn't mean that it's
necessarily going to fit into what the
world wants yeah I love just seeing the
some of the older brands that are
hanging on I mean like like ke was like
one of them I mean we were selling k
When I was a bud tender like I can't
think of any products that are on the
Shelf today that were on the Shelf in '
08 kind of a thing you know and there's
a handful of brands that have been
around like Maya is somehow still here
with om bath bomb they crush the bath
bomb I love just everything I mean and I
always felt like she I mean her whole
movement was dope she always had an
amazing team she always had great
products and they always just I loved
what they did for the community and our
culture and I love to see the few brands
that are kind of still hanging around
from them totally yeah yeah there's a
handful of Brands still hanging on that
are doing their thing and yeah oh makes
yeah great products their gummies are
amazing Rosen gummies can't go wrong
with Rosen gummies I love them and I
just I I like I love edibles actually
when I started the Oakland extracts uh I
started I was working at Harborside and
I met my my business partner now Aon
Tran he worked there with me yeah and
he's a former chef and we really wanted
to make edibles like we're eating
Edibles all day at work talking about
Edibles all the time so the plan like
we're going to do some edibles and then
he learned how to make some hash with
some of our friends and next thing you
know we have a hash company instead and
every time we have a meeting it's like
when are we doing Edibles like we we
love edibles and there's just a lot of
other corners of the industry that are a
lot of fun but everything is so
treacherous now it's like you got to
have a firm footing in what you do
before you start expanding too fast
especially in edible but you know Ros
and gummies are a great way to go
especially with the extract company I
feel like that's the most authentic way
to do it is extract it yourself put some
white Thorn Rose in a gummy those are
those are my favorite that I've had so
far in my whole life the white Thorn
Rose gummy yeah I don't know who did it
but I've had a couple this year and they
were amazing they were beautiful yeah I
believe uh rosin did some and but
there's a couple other companies that
have done them as well I've have always
had trouble with sugar-based Edibles
yeah I mean I come from cannabis's
medicine mhm it's like I'm not going to
give someone who has cancer and tell
them eat sugar every day to fight your
cancer kind of thing it's like even if
like when when I was at Harbor when
there wasn't proliferation of gummies
there were just a lot of cookies a lot
of brownies and just everything in the
sweet category and there were a few
savories back then and I really feel
like creating Edibles that are actually
healthy are are a good wave and there's
enough candy out there there's enough
cookies out there I guess know
everyone's gone except for Peete but I
mean there's enough of the sweet things
that are out there on the market that is
time to kind of like diversify that up
so I'd like to do something kind of
other than the gummy something that
isn't sugar based the ures were good but
it's not edible right but but tinctures
were good Amber Alchemy she's uh we had
her on the show uh Rachel yeah she's
amazing and I love for for medicine I
think tinctures are probably the best
but there are food options that you can
do yeah absolutely I I'm a big fan of
Jade nectar yeah they really strong um
sativa tinctures that are just just
amazing it's eye opening I consume a lot
of Uncle Ares I'd probably consume more
Uncle Ares than my own product I just
love beverages I love the beverage space
that's another space I kind of wanted to
get into but I see how difficult that is
and I'm staying far away so much it's
just a lot of money to get involved in
Bev but it's like I feel like for sure
like that is the space to be in in the
future in cannabis I think like when you
go into a 7-Eleven when you go into a
grocery store we devote so much more
space to beverage than any other type of
snack food out there that clearly
Americans know how to drink their
calories they like drinking their
calories and so I think the beverage
space is just going to keep expanding
for sure and then got Coca-Cola and big
companies eyeing it too they're like
okay well there's money there how are we
going to approach this yeah yeah I mean
we already have the alcohol people we
got Lonas paps say eyes I'm which I'm
not a big fan of I'm I'm okay with
lagunas because it's like that small
time that like there's our local Stoners
kind of they are a big company now but
they weren't they're on by hinek now but
they were Tony McGee J I used to work
with Okay so they're real people right
whereas when I see like paps are really
Sane eyeses I'm like you contributed to
so much negativity in our culture with
Malt Liquor not paps more St eyeses that
now that you're going to come you're
going to come into our space now like
like stay over there you're liquor like
we don't need you over here but we don't
need you yeah we don't like we we can do
our own thing like we we we have our own
message to we have our own story to tell
and you had your time you told a story
and you had an impact on the community
and now it's over there and now this is
something else that we're doing but this
America everyone's free to do what they
want but I'm never that excited to see
them in our space yeah good luck you
know coming in with that model into our
space like that you know that's why I
love the uncle AR like I love the people
that that's cannabis this is a owner
like I want to be in this space how what
do I make and then he made something
organically cuz he wanted to be in
cannabis like I like that story better
yeah yeah TOA colola I don't know if you
remember the toaa back in so I think
before 2005 TOA colola was a big thing
okay uh there was a couple beverages
they the beverages the companies all got
taken down by the feds guys did years in
prison damn uh yeah Beyond bomb best
edible company to exist ever one of my
good friends he did five years for
edibles doing it legally in California
but we had a beverage at Harbor Side I
forgot I don't know I think it was THC
designs was the name of the guys company
he had these little cheesecakes where
they medicated the graham cracker crust
in the bottom that were strong and
delicious and then he had a mango lossi
a chai and iced coffee and then I think
one other bever eggnog around the
holidays and each of those little those
little like little milk carton bottles I
think they're about about 80 milligrams
a piece and then at work we just take
pour two or three of them in the blender
with one of the brownies and just
sounds amazing oh good times good times
I bet I bet yeah and I love edibles I
and I I love edibles in that sense I
don't eat Edibles as much especially you
so Edibles affect me so they're so
strong for me I smoke I can smoke joints
I can smoke big three gram joints and
sit there for an hour and puff on a
joint no problem but then I go for like
a 20 Mill 20 milligrams two gummies you
know because California is 10 milligrams
per gummy is the maximum dose although
they are selling 100 milligram packages
it's supposed to be 10 doses but yeah 20
milligrams will get me now but back in
the day we never measured anything so we
would eat cookies and brownies and it
was like okay how strong can we make it
yeah I remember I used to make cupcakes
that's how a lot of people like back in
the day no man used to make these
cupcakes I use because I I was working
with the people that are growing
strawberry cough and this was they were
just throwing away their trim so they
would just give me bucket loads of fresh
indoor trim and I'd make this butter and
make these Strawberry Cough cupcakes and
they were like electric there were just
a psychedelic experience eating those so
we were mega dosing and then when I
worked at Harborside we had crov we had
the th000 migr black bars and then like
it was there was like hazing when I was
a bud tender about like how many Edibles
that you could eat on shift and like can
hold your [ __ ] together cuz you still if
you look too inated you're going to get
in trouble so you can't like sit there
looking wasted although sometimes we did
and so there was a race to get to how
many people could eat 100 milligrams on
empty stomach first thing in the morning
and clear through your shift without
making mistake there's like that going
on but I can't do that now and I mean if
I eat Edibles now I'll do the uncle Arn
I'll smash that 100 milligrams but if I
get too much beyond that I'm in trouble
and when I I used to be over to do 1,200
without thinking about it so what's the
secret to making butter cuz I got my own
recipe everyone has their own recipe I
did I did a crock poot and I always cut
it with water yeah and so I would do um
a couple pounds of butter really fresh
even then I was I was I was freezing the
trim even though people kept telling me
you didn't it didn't matter but I was
like yes it does [ __ ] I mean I grew
like I we had it everywhere and so I I
would freeze the trim even when we
weren't supposed to only use sugar trim
never use the fans or the any of the
other stuff that put it in a crock pot I
would do 12 to 16 hours in a crock pot
with a couple pounds of butter couple
cups of water and then I keep it at a
low rolling boil and then I would keep
refilling it with water so I keep a
certain amount of water in it yeah and
then um then like strain it into a
through a cheesecloth into a metal Bowl
put it in the refrigerator let the water
and the butter separate it and then dump
out that dirty water or save it for
something else and then I would take
that hockey puck of butter and then I
would melt it down and kind of do a
clarified butter thing where I kind of
pour off the top where it was just it
was just almost clear it was just
perfect whereas the lower part was a
little bit sludger um and that kind of
had more of like I feel like it had more
of the indicia stuff in it that but that
might have been all psychosomatic and um
and when I would make my cupcakes I
would use an Indica for the cake and I
would use a sativa for the icing and so
people would lick the icing and that and
because you're licking it it's kind of
sublingual so you're you get lit quick
you know especially when like you're
Mega doing the the icing and so they
have a certain kind of a high then they
eat the cake and that doesn't kick in
for like another 20 30 minutes takes
them a completely different direction
I used to do damage I used to do damage
oh we had so much fun sounds like fun
yeah really exciting yeah we so I was
told the Native Americans would boil it
you know this is when I was in high
school so people were like oh yeah you
do the cheesecloth you wrap it in
cheesecloth with a rock use a big pot
and you boil it you let it cool if it's
cold outside you just put it out
overnight and then you set you cover it
and then you go out the next day and you
got a disc on the top you know and then
the more weed you put in and I feel like
that's the most that's the best way to
make it super super super concentrated
because you can put a [ __ ] ton of Trim
in there and it's the best but butter is
the best fat is the best carrier like I
don't care what science is happening I
don't care about Nano anything you give
me a butter based edible and it's just
going to be stronger than the rest of
them and I love that's why again I still
mess with big pets I mean because it's
like those cookies make some cookies
with butter I love that you know just
the old Tech is always better and they
got to taste good back in the day we
didn't care as much they tasted like
weed back wanted it to be green oh my
God it's strong I remember we used to
eat brownies where they just put the
weed in the brownies it would burn the
back of your throat I don't think I'm
supposed to be pulling weed in between
my teeth pulling little Twigs out but it
was great figuring it out it's just that
that culture and I just remember like
growing up and then people like giving
you brownies in the hate yeah like brown
to cooking I mean there were people
selling it I guess they were selling it
to like the tourists and like the older
people and like the yuppies or whatever
but just being like a teenager they just
give it to you so you just get cookies
and brownies and sharing brownies oh
yeah we're g get into that 100% would
cut school go to Telegraph half in
Berkeley get as a 250 of pop go to
Blondies get a slice of pizza and the
soda be in people's Park and that was
the day so we grew up in the same era
right because that's what we used to do
totally the park over there was amazing
destroyed it yeah before they old Cody
before they moved Cody down to fourth
with the yuppies beautiful blondies
Cody's books and Mo's books that was
like my triangle in Berkeley but that's
the beauty of the bay what's the beauty
of I guess living anywhere but I do
appreciate the bay I do love San
Francisco I love Oakland I love the Bay
Area I love the uh the diversity culture
we have oh yeah culture it's the best
culture in the world in my opinion and
there's a lot of great culture in other
places but there's so much diversity
here on all levels it doesn't matter
what you like or what you're into
there's something for you here in the
Bay Area yeah we're definitely blessed
foodwise you know you can go to the
ocean it's like right there you can go
up to the mountains during the winter
it's like everything is so close we got
the Redwoods we've got great hiking
camping we're blessed blessed I mean
it's California the weather I still miss
going I used to my my uncle had um some
weed shops in La when I was younger and
he wasn't really smoking at this point
so I would go with him up to humble to
get packs yeah and just going up on the
mountain and just seeing all the
different types of flowers coming down
and seeing all the variety and stuff
that like never left the mountain like
we took a lot of stuff that back to LA
but the Brokers always were like cuz I
smoked and he didn't and they're like
we're never selling him this but you
want to smoke a little bit like this is
just doesn't leave the mountain kind of
a thing and just trying sampling that
and then realizing again like if you're
not up there or going up there you
really don't know how good it can get
kind of a thing like what we get down
here is just is just what we get down
here kind of a thing and I love that
about this plant in our culture and I
guess it's the beauty of California
because we have that about produce we
have phenomenal produce top and bottom
but oh yeah some of the best produce in
the world and I think the abundance of
produce yeah I love seeing that we're
starting to see uh cannabis farms grow
food again like because the Mom and Pops
kind of went away but some of the bigger
ones are kind of trying to build that
back into what they're doing so they're
offering food and cannabis from the same
place and kind of pairing it I know
Happy Day farms does a really good job
with that and there's a bunch of other
places that people I popped up recently
they've been doing events I think it's
uh I don't want to say the wrong name
but there's other folks out there doing
this and I really like the idea of like
people being able to understand that
this is an Agricultural Product and it
doesn't have to be separate from this
this can be part of your experience of
going to Farmers Market buying good
fruits buying veggies buying this kind
of produce as well and having it all
together I like that totally so tell me
about Oakland extracts I know you
touched on it a little bit about uh
edibles but let's let's dive into
Oakland xtrax how that came about and uh
where it's going um started it in 2013
uh with my buddy Aaron Tran we both
worked at Harborside um like I said we
had been talking about making Edibles we
kind of wanted to do that and part we
knew part of that process was hash you
have to learn how to make great hash
especially back then you really need to
learn how to make great hash to make
great Edibles and I left Harborside to
work on a farm and he started working
with some guys at Harborside learning
how to make some hash I started coming
back from the farm and we kind of
reconnected and we're like okay let's
let's do this I started bringing him
like a lot of really really good product
because I was working on a farm and no
one was doing they're throwing it away
and piles of trim were sitting on this
Farm just rotting in the sun kind of a
thing and um this is back when
everyone's just giving trim away so I'd
bring it home and he would make this
just phenomenal phenomenal wax and
shatter and we were just kind of giving
it away to our friends and all that and
then one of our friends who's a buyer at
Harbor Side is's like you need to stop
just giving this away you need to sell
this for real and um start selling it in
stores and um and it was this was back
when they would not accept branded
product when you're just bringing in
slabs of shatter Weare full of wax and
um and I I remember one of the one of
the stores is like you we actually need
you to name it because it's so much
better than the other stuff that we're
bringing in it's confusing the customers
they want to know how to ask for yours
and again it was because I was just
doing I was just getting really good
material I kind of didn't have the
capitalist sense of if you're selling it
as fast as you can make it you should
just get more trim and make more of it I
was just getting what I got from these
guys who was giving me phenomenal trim
and so the product was super super high
level at all time
and um and that that then we we needed
to have a name and we're from Oakland
and then I I grew up around Oakland so
grew up watching the crane and all that
kind of stuff and then and also you know
it was it was so good and so affordable
and like we could sell it in a really
affordable way this was back when most
of the good wax and shatter was $80 $100
a gram for no reason like we didn't just
I remember working at Harbor Side when
there was no BHO there was only water
hash cuz Steve and them weren't messing
with butane they didn't like the idea of
that and I remember when they started
started selling it it went from4 to $60
to $70 a gram like in a couple of months
cuz it was selling so fast and the you
know Market forces and the people
producing it started wanting to sell it
for more so when we started making it we
realized that because we had access to
this phenomenal Farm it was basically
giving us whatever we wanted we could
have product out there that was good as
a $60 or $70 stuff for only like 30
bucks yeah and that was kind of our
thing top shelf quality at everyday
price we wanted to have this phenomenal
product but it not be super expensive
and that really came from working at
Harborside in Oakland when all of a we
went from not really having a lot of
hash to all of a sudden there was a
bunch of 80 to $100 grams and people
would be like they didn't even they
didn't know what it was like they they
called it super milk yeah and so I was
like why is this supermel $100 a gram
who no one's paying $100 a gram and the
customer [ __ ] that this is Oakland ain't
nobody paying $100 a gram and they would
storm out and us as staff we laugh
because we smoke it we know how good it
is we also knew how expensive their
price was and it became like this
running joke like this is Oakland ain't
nobody paying for all that and so when
Tran and I started making it and we it
was like it was really good and it was
yielding a lot and we had it at a really
low price so like Oak xtrax is
Affordable inapproachable and um that
was really kind of like our initial idea
was that we just wanted to have really
good hash and we're making shatter and
um and some wax and we kept having
people like no none of my friends were
dabbing this is blowtorch era yeah so
dabbing was like something that you had
to be really comfortable with the torch
so no one in my community I want to say
no one but I didn't know any brown
people that were dabbing it looked like
free based people weren't going for it
and I kept telling TR like I'm selling
all this shatter but it's like our folks
really AR buying it and people keep
asking for something they can roll up
and the wax was inconsistent and um
sometimes it's gooey sometimes it's dry
and it's it's not for someone who's
trying to roll something up it's not
convenient for all them always to buy it
to roll and I kept telling about that
and he's like well I can make the wax in
these little one G Wafers that are
really really dry so it be like a little
vanilla wafer and they can just crumble
it up over a joint blender bowl and
that's really kind of what put us on the
map so most of people that know openland
extracts from 10 years ago they know
it's from these little one G Wafers that
look like vanilla wafers actually like a
very small version of this this is this
is a larger one that he he made with
rosin oh nice and so we're going to
re-release the we call them coins for a
minute we're going to re-release them
but we've been really slow about it
because we we wanted to make it from
rosin as opposed to wax and not every
type of rosin can you like kind of get
that dry and that that stable really
cool and so we've really been kind of
trying to refocus on that she microplane
that right over your exactly or really
my thought was like I got I have lots of
friends in Oakland who stand around on
various street corners they're kind of
rolling Blunts and they do it
everything's in their hand they take it
they bust up the wied in their hand
there's no Grinder like everything is
just two hands going and this is
something that they can just kind of mix
right in the go with it and just be
really on the go oh yeah and um that was
kind of well hash holes are trending
really hard right now yeah that's
actually what what kind of got us
[Music]
reinspection want to have something
that's easier for people that are out
there mobile like most people are with
they're smoking nice um but anyway so we
we started doing that we did that
through the medical era when there's no
rules no taxes everything was great
backyard blasting all that kind of stuff
and then with prop 215 and then when
prop 64 happened we actually had like
serious regulations everything had to
come out of a licensed facility we had
to kind of change everything we were
doing because previously like I said
blasting outside we had you know ovens
in the the basement kind of a thing so
we had to actually find a real licensed
facility to work out of and I spent a
year and a trying to raise the money um
this is back when you kind of could
raise money without having real receipts
it was that weird transition period
where there's a lot of people coming
into California trying to invest in
companies that were in 215 trying to get
to 64 but people were being offered
really raw deals and so there's a bunch
of different times where I got offered
deals that I thought were okay and then
I had someone read it later and they're
like no you almost sold your life you
know you gave your life away a lot yeah
and so I'm lucky that I didn't do that
but it kind of created issue where we
didn't really have startup money that
was a hassle for a long time and I um I
have know the guys at Jetty since they
moved up here from San Diego yeah Nate
Nate's one of my friends yeah I love
Nate Ron the whole crew and um and Ron
kept saying because I Ron used to go to
all these events I'd see him at any
random Oakland event it wasn't just
cannabis events like when they first
came up here like he made sure they were
in like going to community events too
you kind of really understand the
community he was coming into and I kept
running into him and we kind of
developed a cool little friendship and
he's like you know you can just make
your stuff here but I didn't like the
idea of I don't I really didn't like the
idea of white labeling I didn't like the
idea of just like someone else making
your stuff right and um they knew Tran
they knew Tran was really a good guy so
like okay we'll hire Tran or your your
partner who makes everything he can
physically work at our facility and make
your products but it can still come
through our license facility so we kind
of found a way to be able to get our
stuff through a license Channel but
actually still have our hands in the mix
of it because again I want to make
because Transformer Chef like he knows
the flavors that we want he knows how we
want things to be absolutely and so he's
able to kind of pick and choose things
that are there and kind of make it up to
our specifications and we've been doing
that ever since
nice so what were some of the
difficulties you went through with
starting your own business in Oakland
you know we have the equity program and
all that um the equity program is
complicated I was actually on the
Oakland cannabis Regulatory Commission
when they created or when we created the
equity program desay Brooks councilwoman
desay Brooks was the one who created
that and it was born from a good idea
that like there's definitely a bunch of
people who have been in the Cannabis
business for 20 30 40 years and have
dealt with all the the punishments and
repercussions of that and then when
legalization happened there there was an
opportunity for them to jump straight in
and so there was definitely a need to
create some kind of system to address
that the system we have is uh doesn't
work very well for a variety of reasons
um and so I I stayed out of that program
although I I really probably wasn't
eligible for the program anyway because
you had to come from a certain zip code
and I've never been to jail and all that
kind of stuff but there was people
finding their ways into the program but
I was really uncomfortable about the
program because I didn't like the
relationship that it created between you
and the person incubating you right and
it was it and in certain cases it was
predatory but consistently it was
condescending and I kept seeing these
people it's like I know this does dude
doesn't know how to do a business plan
or performa or doesn't know what to Roi
doesn't know all that stuff but they
know miles more than you about how to
Market a product in this community so
you're just assuming because they don't
know how to do these certain things that
they don't have all this other value
that's that's that they can bring in to
that always made me really uncomfortable
so I never wanted anything to do with
that personally in terms of kind of
signing up for it but I do um but I was
I have been involved in the program I've
advised a lot of people who've been in
the equity program kind of on both sides
of it and um done some Consulting with
some of the different cities that are
have like training programs and all that
and I I appreciate the need for that um
we came in when it was medical so we we
were making money before we knew what we
were doing kind of a thing and it
quickly turned into like oh I have to
now buy a safe there's stacks of cash I
mean it was just like we didn't we were
just it just kind of erupted in front of
us you know old school medical cannabis
um when 64 happened all that went away
um I've been Broker Than Ever the past
couple of years definitely the brokest
I've been since I've been in cannabis
have been the last three years like
without question um I feel lucky that
we're still here there's so many brands
that were like bigger and better brands
that are gone they took money from the
wrong person or they just they the AR
got ahead of them and they just they're
just they don't exist and so I feel
lucky this like when I see like I'll see
Dorian from bezel like bro how are you
still here like you know I just want to
talk to these guys who've been here
longer than me and then luckily like old
school cannabis people are really cool
about sharing and so I have a lot of
great relationships with people who've
been in the business longer than me
who've normally been open about hey
maybe you should try this or this is the
pivot I ran into Dorian in Maryland a
month ago I was visiting my family and
he was out there and he was trying to
put me on game about this is how you can
get into this state this is the
opportunities that are here yeah those
guys know their [ __ ] you know Mike Mike
and Dorian but it's a beautiful thing
where someone's like oh I have an
opportunity let me show you let me let
me show you how to access this and as
are so many other Industries it's like
oh I'm not going to tell anyone anything
the trade secrets and all that I still
feel the old school the Legacy people in
Canada Legacy people will share with
other Legacy people that's for sure
because we want to see each every
succeed like I'll I'll give anyone
advice even if you're some corporate
jump it's like if you ask me a solid
question I'm gonna give you an honest
answer like it's just like it's just
telling the truth you know for sure
we're all gonna make it if we guess well
I think the ones that are persistent are
going to make it like the ones that
aren't taking no for an answer it's like
at the end of the day it's like I I
don't want to be in any other space I
love this space I'm on the genetic side
so it's a little bit different you know
I feel like I'm more picks and shovels
in regards to that uh where I work with
cultivation Partners I work with Nursery
Partners we work with we have Partners
in all these different spaces but we can
have Partners in every state working
with the genetic side and it's like uh I
think there's more longevity for us in
in this space doing that than
cultivation it's just so difficult and
hats off to my friends that are
cultivators dude you guys crushing it
you it's like the ones that are doing it
now growing super fire I mean top shelf
flower the only game there is now to be
successful at is growing top shell
flower if you're in cultivation the mids
you're you're done you can't grow mids
and survive anymore the price is too low
yeah now the corporate jums just doing
it for dirt oh yeah oops it's wild we're
we're in Wild times but it is
interesting I will agree that like when
64 first happened the Cannabis that we
had on our shows was a mess it was like
the people that were doing good work
were not ready to flip the people that
were ready to flip into the new
regulations were just growing scaled up
trash and I felt like we didn't have
good weed for a couple years and it was
so hard though cuz the thing is the
product would sit on the shelf for so
long or it would sit in some some
Warehouse somewhere everyone tried to
figure out metric yeah people trying to
figure out metric and some of my
favorite
Brands like pre uh pre wre when they
went into wreck it's like all of a
sudden their product is [ __ ] now and I'm
like how is this possible you've always
been amazing what the best you were so
like you were the one and I'm not going
to name any names because I feel so bad
because it was like my favorite product
in
2017 come 2018 2019 you go to the
shelves and I went to go buy it and I'm
like I can't believe this is the same
company and it's not really their fault
because it was so difficult to navigate
and props to them for for trying and
doing it you know what I mean it's like
but there was so many things to navigate
with metric and it wasn't easy a lot of
the stuff with metric was these
companies with lots of money they were
the first ones to the table because they
had so much money and so then they have
this product out there that's [ __ ] or
they acquire brand so you know that that
happened a lot too and they not want to
hire the the head grower what they
should lose the head grower and then
destroy the brand because you have some
amateur and they're trying to follow a
formula oh yeah some guy from uh
wherever that that like had a had a
garage girl that's now in charge of 300
lights or or whatever I've seen a lot of
that a lot of that yeah scary but it's
gotten so much better like I really the
past two years particular the top shelf
has just gotten so much better like fig
has always been fig but they're amazing
is great dude you can't go wrong with
North uh sense I mean I love though that
cluster of Brands and there's like Ember
Valley there's just so many good top
shelf Brands I do I remember distinctly
like right in the beginning of covid it
was just like it I was like had to who
am I going to buy where am I going to be
able to find anything good on the
shelves I mean I didn't need to be in
the store because I have a bunch of
friends that grow but I still like I
still like the retail experience I still
want to know what's current and I just
like that that part of it and it was
like slim pickings for a while where now
it's like there's just a glut of good
stuff and then there's in the mids
there's good mids I mean I really love
midzotics I mean he's crazy I love that
dude mat Matt I mean the product's good
for the dollar you know for what it is
and he he's not he's trying to be
authentic in his own way I love I love
that he's 100 like I've told him because
we've done events where he's been at the
same event like I will do any event that
you're at cuz you come with so much
energy and you don't care you're getting
your name out there he believes in his
product
yeah I love that the car like the yeah I
love all the all the little brand stuff
I love that he's my favorite every time
I see him I give him a big hug and I'm
like okay this is where I want to be I
love him I love the rise of the lounges
I go like I said instead of doing demos
I can't wait for the lounges in the next
year they're going to pop up everywhere
too right so finally we can have smoking
lounges if you guys don't know
California just recently passed the law
that is going to allow smoking lounges
it's it's about time we've had some the
cafe part the cafe we can actually sell
F and make money where we yeah I mean I
think that's going to be a big game
changer for California you know we've
had like there there's a couple in San
Francisco smoking lounges is yet to get
some Oakland has rooted in the 510 on
Tim mcow they actually have the biggest
Lounge in nor in California period is is
[ __ ] huge it's still being built out
so it's it's more big than it is uh
ready to go and um and Urbana in Oakland
is opening up in a couple weeks and
that'll have a really nice Lounge area
but yeah I go to the city I go to m
greens I go to I just anywhere there's a
lounge like I where I want my product to
be because I'd rather do a demo there
and actually be able to share things
with people part of experience old
school Urban Farm we had epic demo but U
dab bars going on there and it was just
fun I miss the deli style with the tooth
the Chopsticks you know I mean the deli
style pick your
bud the bud you was I think it was uh
the Divinity tree it was some club that
was back in the day in San Francisco I
used to go and I oh it was the and it
was like all experience all the a were
like four grams or whatever they didn't
it's over it's fine you can just take it
here take this gummy to go or take this
this the old the old stuff the good
stuff I I love that but I just love the
industry in general I don't like there's
bad things about it but again I like
there that there's more access than ever
and if we could just stop locking people
up and getting free the people who are
locked battle you know because it's just
not right no matter how you look at it
you know what however you feel about
legalization the most important part is
that we're not locking people up uh
we're not locking users up especially
it's like it's so crazy to think that
for the last 40 years we've been putting
people in jail for cannabis for a plant
for a plant that only makes the world a
better place in my opinion yeah
absolutely you know it's it's sad and
it's sad that how much of that
conversation has gone away again now
that we're in 6 prop 64 we're in the
recreational era it's all about making
money making money and then a lot of the
conversation with us who' have been
around for a while is just we're going
out of business how do we stay afloat
but how do how do we deal with the fact
that there's still people being locked
up there's still people going to prison
over having a couple plants right it's
not good yeah it's a strange world we
live in you know I think a lot of the
stuff is
backwards you know but we're wild times
you know postco good times there's
there's good times and there's good if
you look in every situation there's
there is some good I love the the the
the rise of new new cannabis media yeah
like this podcast first smoke of the day
there's all these there's all these
other podcasts stuff going on on Twitch
that I can't keep up with and I don't
know what the hell's going on with Tik
Tok I'm too old to know but I just love
the idea that people are using media to
be able to push different messages and
create community in that way because I
feel like outside of lounges it's hard
to create Community but the spaces like
this are a place to create community and
that's really awesome well and we're
we're able to tell a story that's so
much bigger than ourselves it's one
thing if I was to write my story but now
we're on episode 80 something right and
so going in on episode 80s something uh
we have this story that's told by 80
other people and if we go to a thousand
someday which I hope we do of course he
will keep knocking them imagine a
thousand different stories over time and
and the impact that that potentially has
on the future which I think to me that's
kind of what it's all about I enjoy
sitting here talking to everybody but
it's like uh we're we're telling a
bigger story yeah you know and it's one
I'm getting your perspective today and
then next we got Maya from home and then
we got this person here who's a Works in
genetics you know so we get these
different stories about the industry and
it really Paints the true picture of
what's going on because with the media
as a lot of people
know uh we're we're given one story
whether it's agenda based uh or whatever
but it's the perspective of somebody who
has one opinion right whereas you can go
and watch podcasts and then you can
align with different people and their
stories and you can kind of pick and
choose what you want to hear but it's
all for the most part authentic well I
think it's important because it's it's
like there's so many Brands out there
they are just kind of faceless and
there's Brands out there that like I
recognize that name but I really don't
know who that's who that person is I
don't know that their story but once I'm
able to hear their stories like oh I
want to support them like I want to be a
part of their movement because I hear
where they're coming from like I love
that element of the podcast and just
cannabis media the ability to meet the
farmer or meet the people where this is
coming from and really kind of have a
better appreciation of their story and
again realize these aren't faceless
Brands these often most of these the
good brands just they're just a couple
friends that kind of got together
because they liked doing one thing and
they built this world around them and
they're worth supporting they're small
business owners yeah you know in
California and it's not easy to be a
small business owner in California it's
very difficult you know we're taxed a
lot heavier than other places uh the tax
burden's much higher uh but it's just
it's difficult to be a small business
owner in general yeah it is it's tough
it's tough you get very used to not
paying yourself much like I'm I'm good
at paying other people but not so great
at paying myself but I'll Pat myself on
yeah exactly but but what you need is
less it's like I just want this I want
my baby to succeed I want this to get to
the next year and so it's easy got level
up yeah it's easy not to do things for
yourself when you're like cuz I want
this other thing to be able to happen
and so it's exciting yeah one of the
things I'm the most excited about is the
farm to take a model of in the winery
model where you get to go to the
grow uh whether it's indoor outdoor
Greenhouse extract company and you get
to talk to the people that work for the
company and go on a tour potentially and
get to try the product there yeah and I
feel like that's the one big thing that
we're missing and it's slowly starting
to happen and it's it's just going to
eventually snowball and it's just going
to be like the micro brew model or you
know like Lanas you want to get you want
to get a sense of of what the Cannabis
industry is going to be like in 10 years
go get a tour loggan is because that's
the future it's really frustrating that
we're not there yet I've just I've had
so many friends that had grows on
wineries or next to wineries you know
I've uh there's a club in Livermore that
opened up recently that like it's
there's a winery on the same property
yeah and so like you're at the you're at
the dispensary then you see this
beautiful Winery and they hear about all
the events they have at the winery and
like what are your events well you can
come hang out you know it's but you
can't smoke you can't consume but we can
go to a winery and do all that and it's
like as if it's not so much more
dangerous to go somewhere drive
somewhere drink and then drive away I
mean can't if you can if we can justify
that activity and say that we created
safety measures around that we can
certainly do that around cannabis and I
think that's again that's a way to save
small mom and park Farms there's a bunch
of people have small pieces of property
where they love to be part of a network
of small farms where people could come
visit them on Sundays and see how they
operate and buy directly from the farm
and have that relationship because it's
it's so much better when you know the
person who's either growing your food or
your cannabis having that direct
one-on-one it's the best totally yeah
are you guys planning on expanding to
other states are you guys just really
focusing
on I'd like to expand to other states so
this has been the conversation I mean
for those of you who don't know if you
want to succeed in California you get
out of California um like every everyone
that I've talked to the only way to stay
solvent is to have a presence in another
state California you can build your name
you can learn you can be part of the
culture but if you actually need to make
money you need to go somewhere else so
we've been talking about that we've been
really slow with it just because were're
not anywhere near where we want to be in
California those last two years have
been extremely difficult for us and I I
feel super lucky to still be here but I
have talked to some people back East um
talked to um some people in Vegas too
actually like I'm not a Vegas person but
even before the Raiders went to Vegas
there was always a huge Oakland
contingent in Vegas and people would
always send me pictures of our stickers
like around Vegas randomly like oh
that's cute and then um now that the
Raiders are there there's even more
series and I went out to MJ Biz a couple
years ago and it was interesting like
the dispensary owners who have the
option to open lounges were like not
sure what to do with it yeah they're
like I have I talked to this one guy
some policy thing he's like I don't even
know if I want to do it it's like are
you [ __ ] kidding you don't want to
have a lounge in Vegas like like but
they didn't they kind of didn't see all
the what could be done with it and we
have so much experience here in
California it'd be crazy not to try to
take out to the rest of the country and
do things out the rest of the country
and so I'd love to eventually be able to
do that but um I got a short up our our
current business we do a lot of have a
lot of cartrid we sell a lot of
cartridges that's probably like 85% of
our business currently um we've always
had live resent jars we've gotten into
rosin recently and then we're going to
get into Edibles and I really want to
launch Edibles here and get that going
sooner than later and then kind of
Branch out to other states um I love to
do a beverage and I think beverages will
work better in other states as well I'm
excited about beverages I just love the
beverage model too yeah I I'm just
excited but there's so much additional
product development that we're that's
going to be able to happen or not happen
we have the product development so as
the market expands there'll be more
opportunity to create Niche products and
so things that can't necessarily survive
in a brutal market like here but can
survive acrossing like state lines and
people are shipping things I'm I'm
talking to brands are like with the hemp
thing it's just like it's crazy to me
I'm like you're doing what like you're
you're making what selling it in
Tennessee it's just oh Texas Tennessee
all over yeah I mean we're talking to a
company out of Tennessee flow Gardens he
was just on the podcast uh getting our
product out so that you basically he
will be our cultivation partner and
doing it as hemp yeah and I think that's
a it's a great thing it's a beautiful
thing it's this beautiful loophole and
you know and it's great because access
is important I think and honestly like
when I the reason I like going to MJ Biz
or just other events like that is
talking to people in other states
because they're so excited like here
we're kind of jaded we're exhausted
we're burnt out you talk to people I
talk to these guys from Jersey they made
me want to move to Jersey they were so
excited about opening their Club they
had all these plans that may or may not
work but just the excitement that they
had and it was like I would love to be
able to feel that again and be a part of
something like that again so that's part
of the drive to go to out ofate is just
to be around people who have that level
of excitement and energy around it I
think they only had six licenses in
Jersey originally so yeah we might have
been talking to the same
group yeah I was talking to some strange
characters but um a lot of that really
comes from being part of the equity
Trade Network uh this one of the The Dr
Distribution Center I work with Equity
trade drro is a Dro that's made up of a
bunch of small Equity businesses and and
some Legacy businesses as well and they
they've kind of gone National so now
they kind of have a a national trademark
that's they're kind of collecting Equity
brands from around the country under
this one umbrella and through them I've
been able to meet all these people in
these different states and it's been
really interesting because our um the
Cannabis in the black community it's
accepted and not at the same time I mean
a lot of folks obviously are my
community are involved in the Cannabis
industry but there's still a lot of
reticence because of the War on Drugs I
know that was my parents were against me
being in cannabis and I've met a lot of
other folks who their family are having
having issues around that same thing so
the idea of being able to work with
other folks that kind of look like you
and kind of work together has been like
really advantageous and it's been a huge
opportunity and so the folks I met in
Jersey were were folks that had access
to equity licenses out there and they're
trying to figure out how to actually get
it off the ground and there's so many of
the equity businesses particularly the
ones in La they didn't have the best
partners and the partners made bad
decisions for them and so those clubs
are really really struggling and then
seeing like just simple little advice
you can give people can go a long way so
I'd love opportunity through the equity
Trade Network to kind of work with these
other brands in other parts of the
country and just trying to share the
knowledge that we do have so we can kind
of all work together which is that's
where the the podcast came from um the
color in the color in cannabis podcast
which I should probably be able to say a
little bit easier I've been working on
for the past year and the idea behind
the podcast was just interviewing other
just folks from different communities
about their experience in cannabis um I
think cuz so many of my friends I have
like a a bunch of Arab friends and their
the pressure they were under from their
family looks very different than my
Asian friends or looks very different
than some of my white friends like each
Community kind of has their own
relationship to cannabis I have a friend
that's a her family from Nicaragua and
they're like they're not tripping about
the plant it's just a plant to them it's
a plant it's plant medicine it's
recreational whatever it is there isn't
the Judgment attached to it whereas my
Persian friend it's Haram I mean it's
all this heavy [ __ ] within his family
about this being a sin and um and so the
idea of being able to have all these
different people from these different
backgrounds kind of tell their stories
and talk about how entrance into
cannabis how their family and their
their uh their background their ethnic
background has impacted that that's been
kind of really interesting and then I
agree with what you're saying about the
talking to people hearing all these
different stories and how it gives you
such a fuller view of kind of what
you're doing and the connections with
other people and is completely inspired
my business re-inspired my business this
past year working on the podcast just
again talking to people where they're so
excited about their corner of the
industry and you're like yeah I do like
it over here I do want to do more of
this and so that's that's been really a
lot of fun I get re-inspired weekly you
know guys like yourself coming on the
show it's it's always great and you're
so you're on episode number 10 yeah yeah
we just we just launched or just
released episode 10 uh last week it's
going to be the end of season one we
have kind of season two lined up have 10
more guests we want to interview and um
and I have another podcast that's that's
not just about this as kind of a broader
talking to kind of everyone I know in
the industry kind of a thing right and
um I I'm more excited kind of about
creating content and media around
cannabis than maybe just selling a
product right now selling a product is
really tough and I've talked to so many
people in other parts of the country who
just have no idea how any of this works
and there's a hunger to know and again
MJ Biz is one of the things that kind of
really highlighted that to me there's
things that we kind of take for granted
we're in California like everyone knows
these things but when you talk to these
people in different states or in
different countries they they don't have
the experience that we have they haven't
seen 50 other businesses fail going down
the same road so that we do have
something that's really important to
share with all these other people and
again there's a hunger to know and so
it's been really exciting being able to
offer that or deliver that and just get
to know people better and now I'm
talking to people on the other side of
the country because they've been
watching it it's just increased the
conversations I'm had and the networking
I've been having so it's been it's been
amazing you got to go to spanis got to
go Mary Jane I want to go to Spain it
been so bad like I I've Been to Spain
separately when I was younger and I I
love Spain I love traveling in general
and going to Spain I went to Barcelona
10 years ago and it was one of the best
experiences of my life 10 years ago was
the best time to go too I just want to
go to span I just I just want to see I
mean I want to go to the conference in
Germany yeah yeah that's Mary Jane so
you got to go to yeah I got friends who
go I see these pictures I'm like [ __ ] I
love being in spaces where the English
isn't the primary Lang language spoken
and I'd love to be able to do that
around cannabis like just be it's it's
so wonderful that we can do that you
know it's like CU because it's the one
thing that brings us together and people
from all different walks of life getting
together around a plant yeah and having
that same conversation because they love
the plant I I I have several times I
have some friends in in the device space
and I've often been like maybe I should
just get a job with you because you guys
get to go everywhere and you guys get to
do all the cool stuff and I'm stuck here
in [ __ ] Cali I I love California but
like I want to go to Germany I want to
go to Argentina there's all these
amazing places to go so Brazil just in
Brazil yeah but again that's actually
part of the motivation with that podcast
too is realizing that there's all these
Amazing Stories here but around the
world I mean cannabis is a multicultural
activity and I'd love to talk to people
in Thailand about what their
relationship to cannabis is and people
have been farming like multiple
Generations in other countries and what
that looks like India that got go that's
the home of it you know I mean to be be
able to see something that far back I I
very um I enjoy Indian culture I
appreciate Indian culture I went to a
Buddhist school for a long time and so
like I really resonate with a lot of
things that are happening over there and
so I'd love to actually be able to try
like the native products and just be
able to try like like real hash and like
real cannabis and just uh bong the drink
that they make on the the pronounce bang
bang b b h a n g yeah I've always want
to try like the real version of that oh
I've had some and it's wild yeah I bet I
bet Beyond bomb xra it's so funny how
everything comes full circle but the guy
from Beyond bomb good friend he used to
make the craziest bang like it's milk
right so you like fat and that's how you
get it yeah it'll get you good yeah
making I miss I miss tainted I was just
talking to somebody about Mickey Martin
the other day and just all the old
school products and just him yeah
tainted and Beyond bomb were the two big
companies that yeah that are off the you
I I think 2005 they were done that's sad
but you know Trailblazers often
Trailblazers pushing the envelope
someone has to do it yeah they do and
they do good work and so I'm just
excited about where things are are going
I um excited about new products excited
to be in the space yeah I mean it's
exciting times and you know when it's
volatile is when it's exciting you know
once it's stabilizes it's not going to
be it'll be exciting in other ways but
the volatility yeah you know well that's
where the real money is I think if you
want to make a lot of money you go into
that state that has an emerging market
and you just kind of explode in there
and be the risk taker but we both know a
lot of people who were that person they
went to jail like I know several people
and it's really it's uh it's like I like
opportunity but I don't like the sound
of federal prison no we've had we've had
Luke scarmazzo and rich delisi on the
show Uncle Rick and you know Uncle Rick
did 32 years for a plant yeah that's
insane that's insan circumstantial
evidence yeah one of the guys I talked
to Jason uh Washington who owns plants
over pills he um he was in Montana had a
bunch of dispensaries was legal
successful doing really well the feds
didn't like him over that space doing
that and he um they tried to give him 20
years and he fought it and he fought it
he got out he got I think he got off
like 6 months which is that doesn't ever
happen with the feds right but just um
but just talking to him and Evelyn both
people have interviewed and hearing how
they were doing everything right and
then you still wind up in jail like I
don't think people realize when they
hear about like how important de
criminalization is that it's not just
like some Street dealer that got busted
doing something they shouldn't have been
doing people have done everything right
and they still get persecuted by the
feds and they still wind up going to
prison and it's just just not right yeah
we live in a backwards World in a lot of
ways yeah but there's there's time for
change and then we're here now I mean
like yeah you know I remember like
hearing about don't drive through Texas
because if they catch it with one seed
you're going toison I'm saying this we'd
be in jail for next thousand years over
here so I'm just seeing like and I love
all seeing all these Brands like I'm
familiar with so many people up here
love them to death I I I was second
graduating class out of oaksterdam
prophet luk my peeps Love David DS with
hash week just the idea that all of
these things can be successful and
thriving in this but not all thriving
but that we can be here and be doing is
be working with this plant it's an
amazing treat I just love it so you got
some extract here today I think we got
to try some of your extract you can try
some of the stuff I got here we got all
kinds of good stuff all right I have I
brought some of the Zava some live rosin
that we just did um I wasn't thinking
when I left and and then like oh yeah I
should have product with me so I there's
not a lot OFA in there and um and then I
just brought I had some random stuff
around the house but I have a lot of
goodies I've been working with uh the
folks at Kalia yeah recently and so I've
been getting some goodies from Mark up
there that's actually where we got our
rosin from recently and then we're going
to we're we're thinking about opening up
manufacturing from different places I've
always wanted Tran to have his hand on
it kind of a thing but the opportunity
to get things from Kalia is like
unbelievable and the fact that Mark and
his team have been so generous with just
here this is amazing you thinking people
like it and giving it to us at a number
that we can still deliver it at our
normal like super cheap price is [ __ ]
awesome right and so um I still like
good BHO I I'm
sorry uh but really good uh you know
live resin yeah good B is phenomenal
just most people haven't had it yeah
exactly at various points I've because
the market for it got crumbled because
there's cured resin which is cheaper and
whatever and so I keep thinking about
like not not putting out live resin
anymore at all just because we're
competing against people that are
selling it for $5 a gram like what are
we really doing oh yeah but then every
once in a while I'll run into someone
and it'll be like oh my God that's so
good that's that's why we we got excited
about this thing like I I for a while I
thought it was it was the fact that
everything was coming through the Clos
Loop systems and maybe the Clos Loop
systems couldn't replicate open blasting
but recently from Mark he gave me some
live resin that I would have swore was
rosin like there's no way that that was
that was B so turpy it and it was so
100% the plant like 100% plant and it
was kind of creamy and [ __ ] I'm like
what are you guys doing but they tweaked
the machines and they're doing us
Alchemy in the back and so anytime I
think I don't like a class of products
like backup weight cuz actually I do
that with it happens with rosin all the
time because I like flour I like smoking
joints I'm about to Smoke Joint and I
have a friend of mine Jess she's a buyer
at Pharmacy she's like are you dabbing
like I'm like [ __ ] a dab I'm smoking my
joint she like shut up Taran and she'll
put something in my little rig and I'll
be like okay you're right I forgot how
good it can really be oh yeah be
reminded yeah candy yeah Jesus zle is
the real thing here's some of the white
Thorns Z I got some of that from Mark
the other day my absolute favorite so so
I got an idea with the white Thorn for
cream soda would be amazing yeah it
really love try yeah yeah and then the
second I think that something isn't good
they figure out how to make it better it
doesn't matter with LED lights I can't
believe that shit's working I mean
because I used I used to grow 10 years
ago and LED lights were a joke and they
someone would always come around BL
right so the blurp sucked yeah and we've
come a long way since the
blurp uh big shout out to all these
lighting companies you know I think
there's 80 big lighting companies or I
wouldn't say big but there's 80 lighting
companies and there's only four
factories or something like that but
yeah LED has come a long way Spectrum
tuning now you can dial in your own
Spectrum you can screw up your plants
that way too which is a great way to
screw up your plants having relearn from
scratch oh yeah okay so you're asking me
about my my temps so 451 is my low that
I do for really really nice rosin yeah
475 is my general use and then I do 531
cuz that's what Roger does and every
once in a while if I'm doing diamonds
I'll do 550 but again that's just for
this device on my focus V at home I
think it's at 375 or four something
really really low on the one on it at
home we're gonna have to get Rog on here
to explain all this stuff yeah I I I was
I wish we could just get all the device
guys together in one room and just talk
about all these devices at one time cuz
there's no egos there yeah was like come
on we were these are such great toys but
like [ __ ] like this works well and this
doesn't can't we just all but whatever
we're getting there and everybody's got
their own version of a saber you know
Puff's got their
pen yeah I mean they've got one for
Focus V dip device has their own version
I love I love the saber I love the light
on the saber I love the light on the
saber the hot knife is convenient you
know honestly like cuz I do da bars and
I have everybody's equipment not
everybody I have a lot of equipment at
home I buy lot of stuff people will give
me stuff
damn that white Thorn is good yeah so is
that Skittles yeah it's funny like
there's a reason why the pop popular
things are so popular and it's easy to
turn your nose up like like blue dreams
classic [ __ ] Blue Dream really good Blue
Dream will sit you down and shut you up
just shut up I mean you've had it 10
million times but I enjoyed really good
Blue Dream but I mean I used to there
was a time where I sold Blue Dream to
harbers side yeah I sold it yeah Harbor
Side
PCC uh purple heart I love all those
places yeah rip purple heart that were a
great place you know was like keep
thinking he's gonna come back Keith man
come back we miss you Keith I'm telling
you they had something special there and
I feel like they were this small little
hole-in-the-wall place with tons of
passion like real passion real good
medicine real good product they like my
product so it was always but but just
really good people uh you know in in the
Bay Area we just had some you know even
even the guys over uh at BPG you know I
mean they they were really passionate
about PL it's like I love I missed their
old location when they had their Lounge
they had the first little Lou went into
I still go over there a lot to the um to
BPG they still take good care of me and
then um that was the one with the the
the driveway that and then I still go to
cbcb I mean like Beyond just like as a
so and selling product yeah each Club
has some great cbcv has some great
prices on the outdoor that they're their
house outdoor phenomenal and it's like
it's just pennies you know PCC had top
shelf that was match back in the day
Eric and Dave they're gone they sold but
uh dude the the product at PCC was
phenomenal off Telegraph that was a
great Telegraph spot I had the hat shops
right there so we get the Hat go get
some freaking I spent a lot of time in
there cuz I I knew those folks and they
um is again was one of the when we first
started it was like one of our first
five or six accounts and then like uh
the telegraph Health Center THC when
they were there I mean just B this the
network of old clubs people were so
dedicated and they spent so much time
and energy and it was a time of such
fear you're worried about the feds
coming in you're getting robbed like you
didn't know what was going on right the
people were pioneers and I just I really
appreciate them well and people think of
quality being like it is today like the
quality this quality that but back in
the
day there was some fire yeah like some
really special stuff too and stuff where
you would only see at one time in your
life we had some stuff called the
spaceship that we had for a while that
was really really phenomenal and the
shaman okay the shaman in in fact the
shaman was one of the things that really
got me excited about breeding CU my
friend bred the shaman it was a shaman
it should have been called the shaman
because it was Shaman times the Romulan
back to the shaman was a back cross and
it was just so good and it was purple
and it was strong and it was Hey and it
was turpy
mhm um here some Ray Congo batter or Ray
cono oil at this point it's been around
way too long but anything Congo we hold
on to it think for that's stuff that I
would put in my freezer you know I have
a little freezer stash and that has I
don't know a few different kinds we got
we got jars in there yeah yeah oh
wow I love the Congo I love the Congo
this smells like tree sap it's so good
it's got its own unique and those things
have their it's not like the terpinolene
limine or terpinolene line that most
people think of as Haze it's like it's
got its own Funk like real good Durban
it wasn't super hazy it was real funky
and musky
and you know it has its own thing with
like the anise in it the current one is
really like I love Durban it's one of my
favorite strains but like I know the
Durban I'm smoking now is not the Durban
that I I smoked like 10 years ago no
same thing with Lamb's bread like I
don't see it that often and but Lambs
bread L is the most unique thing though
it's that's a Musky one right I feel
like Lambs bread is extremely mus mus
funky and mus almost cheesy but yeah
definitely almost cheesy for sure and
the real one it's like I've smelled it
in other other people's crosses where
they have that expression on the nose
where you're like Lamb's bread yeah
Shane Sunny chba my my buddy he was at
Harbor Side and he they were pheno
hunting 20,000 plants and he took me
over to the Lamb's bread crosses and
they all smelled like Lambs bread like
they had that distinct musky nose
funkiness like you know it's like and
it's really hard to describe if you've
never spelled it but it's one of those
things if you smelled it and you smell
it again you'll remember that the rest
of your life yeah I missed that I feel
like just the way the Advent of purples
really kind of hurt indicas in general
because people started obsessing about
color I feel like uh the same thing has
happened with this candy gas Obsession
like it's great but it's like we're
losing so many things because that's the
wave and again as quickly as I say that
I will admit every single time somebody
hands me a Lemon Cherry gelato I'm like
damn that tastes good so I'm embarrassed
just like the white Thorn I'm
embarrassed that I'd like something like
that's so common and so pedestrian but
great flavor profiles are great for a
reason well it's funny cuz if the if
white Thorn wasn't popular you would
still like it the same oh yeah for sure
I don't care yeah with lcg if it was I
don't care what you call it I just like
it yeah Sunset sherbet some people were
like hating on Sunset sherbet last week
and I'm like dude how can you hate on
like real good Sunset sherbet I think
they haven't had it is the issue I feel
like you don't know what you're talking
about if if you hate on Sunset sherbet
like it it never got its day but it's
just as good if not better I like it
better than the
gelato but it's its own unique thing and
it's like really good [ __ ] Sunset
sherbet is some of the best stuff out
there yeah and it's it's so like it's
grower by grower is batch by batch I
think when people I hear people hate on
a classic I just like you probably
haven't had the real version like you
had some water down BS where it Jack I
get hating on Jack because so much Jack
bad Jack went around but if you only
think Jack is like something that's very
linear you didn't get really good Jack
because the Jack back in the day was
strong complex had amazing flavor uh but
it's not the jack that most people think
of as Jack today and I think there's so
many things like that train wreck real
train wreck is phenomenal strong real
train record that's one of the few
strains where I've smoked it where it
was like too strong like I had to put it
down and kind of relax a little bit like
the true vers like there's a reason why
it was called train wreck like people
think these things are games like a real
AK-47 would do something to you and
people just again they got the watered
down version of it and they don't know
the real expression yeah I like a lot of
the old stuff I just it's you don't see
people growing it to the full capability
you know I feel like people aren't
pushing it as hard as they used to and
there was there was more of it but I
feel like there was also less Growers
and there was more passionate people it
was illegal for one thing you're taking
big risks and so you had to have bigger
balls yeah and also there was mids back
then yeah absolutely there was
absolutely mids you know besides the
Mexican dirt weed there was people that
grew mids that thought it was amazing a
lot everyone thought there we yeah yeah
yeah I mean everything that not
everything but so much what came out of
BC for us was mids although I was when I
lived in Seattle I had phenomenal things
coming out of Vancouver that would just
m your face then by the time you get it
get got down to here it was BC Buds and
it was just it was a dirty work yeah it
was a pound that was this big you can
play football with it you know it's not
you know I I think they would Smash It
and they would use O3 to get rid of the
smell so it all smelled kind of like hey
um but that wasn't necessarily the good
stuff that was just the stuff that was
floating around yeah I would uh when I
lived I lived in uh I went to Evergreen
State College for my last year of uh
College last couple years of college and
we spent a lot of time in Seattle and um
I remember getting weed from people like
kind of like I guess like humble I'd
find people they'd still weed out of a
duffel bag but it would be like
phenomenal it would be this phenomenal
indoor I don't know where the hell this
[ __ ] came from and they're just like
stick your hand in and take whatever you
want and I'm just like I'm from Oakland
I'm like I'm not sticking my hand in
[ __ ] like I don't I I can't wrap my
brain around this but we would get such
amazing weed and it was from these
little weed nerds like I got weed up
there that it I didn't I'm this is uh
9798 99 there's weed that I got randomly
from dudes at this this one particular
coffee shop in Seattle that's probably
still not not there anymore like and it
was better than anything I've had
probably since I mean it was just
phenomenal I work in Seattle I love
Seattle always been weed nerds up there
and those kids are geniuses this some
[ __ ] supposedly the [ __ ] that came from
udubb or whatever all the stories about
all that nonsense and all that and all
the stuff coming down from Alaska and
all the stories about that and all that
stuff it was it was phenomenal
permafrost I don't know if you remember
permafrost from up there but ATF ATF ATF
and then before is ATF I mean when I
first heard ATF it was matusan Thunder
[ __ ] there was yeah they had both I I
think I remember Alaskan first but then
I remember both the matusa and the
Alaskan Thunder I wasn't sure what came
I just remember just like and then you
found it and you're like okay this is
why this is the thing yeah Seattle had
good flower it was just really hard if
you lived in Seattle and you were
cultivating it was hard to keep your bud
nice because of the humidity yeah and it
was always super humid during the winter
especially and I mean I think their
summers are drier now than I think they
typically were but higher humidity
environments it
requires uh indoor trimming indoor uh
basically storage and then if you're
like dispensing it you need to have some
sort of bag or seal on it and then every
time you open the jar you got to shut it
right away otherwise your Bud's going to
get soggy right because it'll absorb all
that moisture and humidity plays a huge
role in the quality of your flour
chirpin are volatile they'll go away as
soon as it gets humid again and you dry
it out then get it humid it's even worse
yeah I had a lot of wet weed up there
not even just wet just not not dry
exactly it wasn't dry and crispy it was
just soft I think it was pretty part of
the it was part of like how it was it
was just most people had spongy flour
they trying to roll a joint with it of
the shitty little papers because it
wasn't a good paper selection back in
the day
either good stuff yeah well so if people
are interested in finding out more about
you where's the best place to go um
oakland. extracts is our IG our
Instagram so that's probably the best
place um we also have a website Oak
extract.com that I do not update at all
so that's probably not but but if they
go to our IG I'm it's just me and my
buddy so I answer all the DMS there so
I'm really big on any people have any
questions comments thoughts whatever I
respond to folks on there um and check
out the podcast the coloring cannabis
podcast look out for a couple more
podcasts coming and um if they're
interested in Oak extracts and they in
California we're on navis I guess you
know awesome but um but really just uh
yeah the Instagram got to love Instagram
smoke more hash yeah well cheers thank
you so much for coming on the show look
forward to having you again one of these
days it's an honor to be here thank you
appreciate you brother
[Music]
cheers thank you guys for watching
please like And subscribe down below
[Music]