[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James loud
podcast and today our special guest is
Thomas from Grandmaster LEDs how are you
doing today awesome man happy to be here
it's nice definitely feeling the weather
on this side of the bridge versus San
Francisco totally yeah it warms up it
totally warms up over here it gets
really hot so yeah so where are you from
exactly I'm based at aqu Qualicum Beach
Vancouver Island so we're basically as
far west coast and South as you can go
in Canada pretty much the nicest weather
right across from squim yeah yeah so
yeah no I I absolutely love it out there
I've been all over the mainland but um
well about I think about nine years ago
I had like a really bad home invasion
and I was just like screw this man I'm
moving to the island like it just I
lived in this area in chillak um British
Columbia where there were just like
people for a living were just going
around it's just like the home invasions
were so bad and these guys were like
pros too where they they come and they
drill a tiny hole through your you know
to figure out where you're at with like
little bullet cameras and come back at
the right time oh that's straight
Oakland style that that's been happening
in Oakland for 20 years and now it's
gone it's gone viral and gone all over
that's crazy yeah like pretty ruthless
too and violent too but I'm sure that's
like that here too I hear it's a bit of
an issue too Oakland now they'll just
crashing through the front door with a
vehicle with a stolen car stolen truck
and uh going through the front and
freaking empty you out and do whatever
and the cops don't come they don't do
much they don't do anything they they
don't do much and there's not much they
can do in a lot of instances you know
it's like uh the the laws are kind of
against all of us right now it's like
anything less than $900 you don't even
get arrested for it's not you know theft
is you know cited and released yeah
that's insane man yeah I know
everybody's been Waring me about don't
put anything in or just be so careful
it's that bad you really have to be
careful in San Francisco and Oakland you
don't want to have anything in your
vehicle in plain sight uh yeah it's it's
pretty rough are you guys allowed to
conceal or you're not you some people
have concealed but it's not it's not
very common hard to get it's hard to get
so it's harder to get it's still
possible but yeah it's not it's not a
normal thing for most people to have
conceal carries like Texas you don't see
that stuff happening yeah I was just
going to say if everybody's packing it's
like it's obviously got to change a lot
of stuff but it's like the wild West out
here and I guess with the value um like
in Canada the price of cannabis has just
gone down like we've seen areas that you
guys or territory that you guys haven't
seen yet because you guys still have red
States and obviously there's still
thriving markets of people pushing stuff
everywhere right I mean we're seeing the
race to the bottom uh it's it's
interesting though I I see stability
happening too because we've just in
California was 2018 they went
recreational right so we had medical
first before anybody in 1996
and then prop
215 and then 2018 we passed for
recreational and a market that was
completely unstable when you have a
market that's unstable the thing is is
going from the traditional Market the
medical Market which I feel was much
more stable we had better product that
was fresher and then it was the first
person to get in or the first people to
get into the wreck were the people that
had the most money not the people with
the best quality not the people who
understood quality
and sometimes people scaled too quickly
they had quality and so what's on the
shelves is [ __ ] product right
unfortunately and so it's slowly
correcting I see good product on the
shelves sometimes I see good brands with
good product and their product is bad
because it sits on the shelf for too
long that happens a lot yeah it's a real
problem in Canada going from once it's
finished to getting it on the shelves
like having the skew um you have to have
it registered and and some it's only
supposed to only take a month or two and
I've seen it take up to four months so
if you have a product that doesn't have
it it's like you have to wait for this
registration I've seen a lot of times
that taking six months to have finished
product to actually get it on the
shelves and it's like I know some people
like doing a six-month care but not for
me like I like it when it's still sticky
like it burns everything is snapping but
sticky I like that flavor like ex I like
it fresh yeah I like you know and it has
like a six week window of when it like
it's only going to go downhill after
that six weeks where you know
we have products like TPL loock which
help you know and storing it in cold
temperatures help uh but nothing beats a
fresh sticky Pro especially if you get
that sticky where it's not like sticky
from it being wet but sticky from resin
exactly every stem will snap but the
whole half pound sticks together like
that's my trademark for any half pound
that I've grown you can pick it up it's
almost hard to roll joints with it but
it rolls in a perfect yeah it looks like
you've been trimming after you've rolled
one joint and your hands are all [ __ ]
up butt where you can't even really use
the ERS yeah yeah that's that's my style
too if I am going to be smoking for sure
so you have a lighting company yes yes
so I've been in the lighting business I
was with another company for four and a
half years and then um I branched off on
my own nice wasn't kind of planned it
was kind of I kind of got thrown out um
thrown out to to dry basically right but
uh it was for the better or else
Grandmaster LEDs would have never
started so yeah I mean it's funny how
that works out sometimes the things that
at the at the time in the moment they
seem like these terrible things and it
it ends up being a blessing in disguise
well I'd stayed my whole life Anonymous
too so I've been on YouTube for like
years making videos I had to remove
hundreds of videos when they were doing
The Purge but I've always stayed
Anonymous until when I broke left that
company they doxed me on this roll it up
Forum so now like I've been public ever
since then wow yeah nice yeah you're
extremely public I see your Instagram
that's that's actually how we connected
was through Instagram yes and you are
very
opinionated uh like our friend Alex
Miami mango I feel like you guys are
think unprofessional is a better
unprofessional ter that's a great term
but yeah I mean I feel like you guys
speak your mind you're not afraid to
speak your mind and uh you know the the
world needs people like that that are
you know willing to argue and stand up
I'm not one of those people who likes to
argue I just rather not argue about
stuff I just put my content out there
but I love the fact that you guys do it
yeah know I can I totally understand
like I could have probably taken my
career a lot further by just keep keep
my moue shut and saying hi to everybody
and even if I saw something that doesn't
isn't right keeping my moue shut like
for example like just this week I bought
another competitor's light because
something didn't smell right and what I
I sent it to light laboratory in
California here and they're pretty much
the most reputable spear testing place
and then it's like all of a sudden I was
right you know the efficiency is lower
than what they're saying and like you
know I I post that kind of stuff and I
guess you could say expose it or if I
see another company just miss leading
people in a really bad way I'll say
something even you know and sometimes it
is going to cost me customers but at the
same time I think for everybody it cost
me there are people that respect that
I'm willing to do that right and we're
like it's growing at a really fast rate
um I think anybody that started at the
same time of us it's probably out of
business by now yeah you know what I
mean and we're every single month doing
better well how it comes across to me is
authentic right I feel like I'm
authentic in my own way and I feel like
you're doing the same thing you're
authentic in your own way and there's
nothing wrong with exposing people for
[ __ ] right absolutely this whole
industry there's a lot of [ __ ] that
goes on within the industry Within
products within testing and all these
things I think they need to change so
many white papers have been faked and
like uh I really believe video evidence
is better like like when you can see it
firsthand like so many times everything
has been faked and it's like we've been
LED down these wrong paths because of it
and like anytime where I see a study
that's been done in the later 2000s and
it doesn't have video with it are
pictures I always have to question it
because why couldn't you be snapping
pictures and showing what you're
describing but only putting it in words
right you know and like um well just
even with some of the stuff we've done
we've discovered other people were
faking their research yeah and it it's
just such a big problem like everything
we do is for the grower like I've been
doing this my whole life so like even
we've designed it when we started we've
designed over 30s something lights and
in the first year I learned some really
big lessons like there was a big
efficiency War originally and we you
know I learned
um diversity is more important than
efficiency and it's like um so we and
same with other things like discovering
far red and having far red into your
lights and seeing the results like we
made lots of mistakes and had to you
know re-register and redesign everything
to make it the best um so like I'm not
afraid to make a mistake and admit that
I've done it and then correct it and
kind of move forward right I mean I
think those are the best ways because if
you look at LED in the beginning it
sucked it was [ __ ] terrible 100% it
was awful and it was something I said
I'd never use but I've learned from
experience that I don't use that I'm
never gonna try that again because I
feel like a lot of times we can dial
stuff in we can make it better Spectrum
tuning ex stuff like that I mean we we
use science here and we have Spectrum
tuning and I feel like if you know what
you're doing Spectrum tuning can be
amazing absolutely well to be quite
honest science um is what gave me the
direction that I went with our company
when it went in the Spectrum tuning
because they were the real first company
that had the first concept that had that
we just kind of took it to another level
um to be able to do stuff that their
lights can't do and that you know other
lights can't do and I I think one of the
biggest things with HPS and led that
people don't really realize it's just
like they want L HPS results from an LED
but you know the the spectrum is so much
different like I know a lot of people
try to say oh it's the radiant heat yeah
from it but I I do not agree with that
it is the temperature of the light is so
much different and so it's like the
second um we're seeing people that have
been using we've developed the very
first HPS Spectrum so there's no other
lights that they can mimic a HPS yeah so
like there's a lot of other companies
that have far red in their lights and
they're usually like 2 to 3% at maximum
while at double-ended HPS have 10.4% wow
well ours have the ability to go up to
15% if you really want like they have
the ability to cuz far red can be used
to stretch the plant like I know it's a
re really rare situation but sometimes
like you could have an area or a strain
that you want to catch up with the rest
of the room so you can manipulate it uh
to stretch I think some genetics work
better when you stretch them too as far
as like giving it more node spacing yeah
you can get chunkier buds that way
absolutely having the ability to also
limit the stretch if you want to by
adding blue is such another huge thing
uh that's another thing that our blue
that we use well it's just kind of a
wider blue wavelength most lights like
science and you could say almost you 98%
of companies have just a 450 nmet blue
Spike where we have a 450 and a 437 and
you get those from using the Samsung Evo
mint diodes and they just um you know
when I was testing them up against each
other we did lots of side by sides like
two spikes versus one and I couldn't see
any type of difference really because
it's the same percentage of blue but um
it just gives you the ability to have
more blue so like anytime when we're
doing lots of different side by sides
I've seen lots of tests where like when
we only had one to 2% difference it's
literally identical like if there's a 2%
difference in a spectrum you're not
seeing anything but you get up to 10 to
15% and all of a sudden you can really
see some crazy different Expressions you
can have one piece of flower look like
it's from a different planet and it's
the same cut yeah it's amazing yeah
that's you can also completely fluck
your crop up by using uh some you know
by tuning it incorrectly by adding too
much of this or too much of that or
playing around if you don't know what
you're doing and I've seen that happen
before and I'm one of those tinkerers
where I like messing around but I I
gotta my buddy Justin he's really worked
with the science lights and so he knows
the recipe and so I'd listen to him
instead of playing around with it I'm
like like okay this is you could totally
screw things up or like yeah I I worry
about that too and we got a lot of
people after buying them because we have
like 60 preset spectrums you can choose
from and they're like well what do you
use yeah and I I try to tell people I
don't even actually pay attention to the
different set spectrums I just kind of
think is warm white almost as a HPS and
cool white is a metal highlight right
and then you can you know you can add
the other Reds in I'm not the biggest
fan like a lot of companies have gone in
this direction where they have this big
red Spike it's 660 NM it's a 660 Peak
and a lot of companies use like over
double the amount that they should be
using and it's strictly to get a higher
efficacy number to like look more
efficient on paper it's not for the
plant it's like they're doing it and
specifically yeah and what happens is
when you add that extra red it actually
suppresses green that's like really
important I think that's pretty
essential um when you look at HPS like a
double-ended HPS it roughly has about
almost I think it's like around 58% red
and around like 38%
um green and then the rest I think it's
like four to 5% blue they just don't
have nearly as much I really think it's
just the wrong route like if you look at
um an actual double-ended HPS you'll see
that like it goes from 600 to about 630
is where you see it you don't doesn't
even really have any 660 if it does it's
just at the very bottom right and like I
I've just seen people having better
results with the Fuller Spectrum um I
had a crop where I did three different
spectrums with a cut where I've got over
a hundred runs in with it it's called
Death Bubba everybody has seen my death
Bubba videos and when I still got three
different results like one of the buds
was almost like 15 to 20% bigger
different triome density different bud
structure it's like as soon as I saw
that I'm like this is the future yeah
100% like everything we're doing moving
forward as Spectrum tuning yeah I agree
yeah I mean it's just another level you
can just take it to a different level
and the more you can tune in your room
the better you know and it's it then you
can get really specific with genetics
and you're like okay well this variety
well under this spectrum and this one
under this and you know it's like that's
the future right well having that test
room with the four lights a bare minimum
two but we um we're working with this
company in Missouri that they have a
test room with four different ones they
put curtains in between it and they make
it like totally different and man
they're really seeing a a big
Competitive Edge because whichever one
does the best then they Implement that
as their base Spectrum but then they can
also use it like with adding blues and
different stuff to manipulate it but
know what base Spectrum it's going to
work the best and most people have one
Spectrum right so they're like you know
it's such a Competitive Edge to have oh
yeah and it's a beautiful thing like as
a breeder now coming in now you're
breeding these things and you're
starting to understand how the Spectrum
works with the genetics that you're
breeding and then right out the gate you
can kind of get a good understanding of
what's going to work well with what and
yeah especially for your own crew or
like coming up with your own proprietary
light recipes that you can license out
for those different genetics because
like what's when everybody's using the
same spectrum and the same genetics and
the same food
it's like you really need to give
something that's
that have an edge yeah I mean it's it's
really interesting the direction the
world is going in it's like right when
you think they figured it all out boom
we got this this isn't even the tip of
the iceberg yet you know I feel like
there's so much more you know with
nutrition with everything else and
everybody there's a handful of companies
that make good product as far as
nutrition is concerned absolutely but uh
it's like we're still dialing it in so
dialing in yields under canopy inner
canopy all this stuffff yeah we've been
working on we're we're probably about a
month from releasing their under canopy
we we ran into a little hiccup like I
had everything ready to go and then I
well ARS isn't just under canopy it's
Lower Side lighting too and upper side
if you want and I what I didn't I
overlooked is the different distance and
trellis bars between different tables
yeah and because you know they there
could be anywhere from four feet five
feet six feet or even more and we had to
you know come up with a waai to make the
lights Mount to those bars so I like I
same with our under canopy they kind of
they float they don't sit on different
structures so oh wow yeah we actually
have a Utility Patent for it actually
yeah I'm excited for all this under
canopy and inner canopy and side
lighting I think that it's it's really
cool and I think you know some of these
guys are like ah you don't need that if
you have the proper light at the proper
distance you're going to get the
penetration and I have yet to see that
and and you we're working with faven
we've done some faven trials and yeah
I'm excited for the stuff that uh we're
doing now and it's like the poten so
huge for that and same thing with
breeding right so if you make seeds
you're doing seed production oh You' get
so much more underneath all those all
those white yellow seeds those now I
didn't even think of that that's dud
it's a game changer and so we're
actually I'm actually trying in my seed
production room we're going to be able
to tell you whether it's the under
canopy the Light Lift or the combination
of the Light Lift with the under canopy
that yields the most seeds so I'm I'm
very confident that one of those if not
all of them are going to be extremely
beneficial I I think it yeah it's going
to play a huge Factor well just having I
like I really recommend people if they
can to build a light lifting system I
even have a DIY video that shows how to
do it with pulley and using a winch
system if you can't don't want to buy
like a I know think growed has an option
for doing it and there's a few different
options we got a horizon light but yeah
think has a cool one we got the hor nice
like well even so even going back for my
whole commercial growing career yeah um
going back to almost the earliest days
well after about 2004 we would always
have like I'd build it on a crank system
yeah so you can always lift like I was I
was never a double-ended HPS I was a
single-ended HPS guy I went from I hate
yo-yos I absolutely hate I went from
that to then like I went and got into
LED lighting and like um so yeah my
experience like I didn't ever get like
the most to be quite honest that I ever
yielded on a single ended HPS was 2.85
pounds per light like with a a cush
strain and that's still really really
good I did many times between 2.5 and
2.65 and you know went for half a decade
over averaging over two when that was
way above the average back then like
breaking two was a big deal 1.5 was the
average just so you guys know back in
the day if you hit 1.5 you know 15 years
ago that was it like you were you were
killing it and then sour and blue dream
they would get around two maybe 2.2 like
the first time I hit 2.2 was with sour
did you ever grow Juicy Fruit like we
were I was growing juicy fruit from like
about 98 to about 2002 and I know that
majority of it all came to here too did
we saw that juicy for here it was such
like that was the really good stuff that
came from Canada I believe was Juicy
Fruit but uh we had a lot of the beers
that W weren't so great that you know
it's like they were all footballs
football pounds that were like that big
where they had smashed them in and I
think they ran 03 to kill the smell oh
yeah there were just so many so much
crazy stuff that we used to see but yeah
it was such a popular one for years I
don't know if you guys ever had the old
school plant that was like from the '90s
to the early 2000s that's gone now yeah
I mean we we've had some hash plants
I've seen a couple different varieties
of hash plant coming down so some uh
like AFU was also a hash plant yeah like
I this would have been I I don't like I
would have made it at some point but it
would have been in the late 90s it
wouldn't have been that popular but it
was like a biker strain like and it was
it was just a super killer strain I've
been searching for it forever like just
to get it back and with no luck tried
well people have given it to said hey
I've got a cut of it but holding on to
it for two decades and every time I grow
it it's not even close that happens all
the time I mean I think that that's the
same thing with cat piss there's a lot
of people that say they have cat piss
but it's like it's not the cat piss that
I remember oh man I sure remember a lot
of cat piss strains yeah we also there
was a strain called Master Kush I don't
like I don't even know if that's what
the real n uh strain I used to Mono it
with death Bubba um it had the highest
thcv that we' ever seen by far W like it
got almost 7% it was just under 7% it
more than anything we'd ever seen and I
was one of them I grew it um up until
the point where death Bubba was yielding
more for me and I was getting the same
money for him and then I dropped it and
then I I got it years later about four
years ago guy gives me four cuts and
says if this is it for sure well out of
the four Cuts one of them was the real
cut one of them was a cross and one of
them was like this other PK strain that
I absolutely hate and it was just
incredible so after I got it grew it out
I somehow managed to mark it wrong
so like or somehow like the person I was
working with didn't mark it correctly it
wasn't me personally so I had to grow
out again and then on the next crop as
soon as it was done somehow my buddy
must have while he was walking out of
the room swapped the Clones so I threw
out like this is after I lost it I the
other one was across of it though I was
like the S like it grew small buds and
had the smell that was different but
anyway so I threw it out sent it to like
five different people across Canada to
like secure it for me me then they
started growing it out and the strain
didn't like light like it couldn't take
very much light and all of a sudden I
was like I just couldn't believe that I
got it back and then threw it lost it
never will I let some I'll let someone
else deal with it I'll deal with it
myself right or trust someone I've lost
so many different things that I really
loved over the years you know there's
been so many great things that we didn't
have tissue culture back then we didn't
have big places to keep our stuff alive
and we shared it with the wrong person
and they lost it oh yeah I mean I used
to bring stuff up to Washington just so
they could secure it for me so I could
go back at I lost sard isil like maybe
six times and had to go to Washington
six different times to get it back nice
that in the cam we had the cam that's
such a popular strain on the East Coast
on the sour d it was all grown here oh
yeah but I mean like every I always hear
people on the East Coast talking about
what people from New York just freak
they loved it and it was top you know
$6,000 a pound or whatever uh top top
and the but the thing is is like again
with sour it's like I have not seen the
most amazing sour like it used to be on
average we used to see a lot of good
sour where it you open the bag it
punches you in the face it's so loud it
just you know and the buds were so
sticky and I mean the outdoor was nuts
too like the outdoor was just as good as
the indoor yeah your guys's outdoor
Market it's well like it's so different
than how ours well we don't have an
outdoor Market we never have like no
like I'm not saying that people didn't
grow but it never affected our markets
what was so crazy for um a I'm going to
say up until potentially
2014 I would watch every single year at
the end of August September the prices
of indor with Skyrocket yeah it happened
for I watched it for about 15 years in a
row and then finally I remember talking
to my buddy just a few years before the
15 years be like hey man you could just
make a career buying stuff at cheap and
selling it you know months later when
it's like careers and retirements have
been made on that for sure D out there I
mean that's that's it like you
if you have the if you have the funds
the capital to do that I mean there's
been people throughout the last 20 years
that they Brokers that didn't even grow
it they can go buy for dirt cheap hold
on to it for four months put it in some
cold storage and then unload it for two
three four or five times as much as they
paid for it yeah it's insane so the
first year that I tried it buying 50
pounds was the first year there was a
gap in the market where we hit Uncharted
Territory well it's funny cuz I think I
had gotten it for like 17 and you know
at 24 was the peak like we're used to we
were used to seeing at least go up to 28
to 29 every single year and then it went
down to 24 and then you know I still did
all right with it but I it was the very
first year and then it's like we got in
Uncharted Territory ever since that
point on and like we've just seen well
like for our outdoor it's just so
different we don't have like that
outdoor crop it's we don't I've in my
whole life I've ever seen anything I've
never seen it flooded with outdoor packs
like no one's interested like that
doesn't we're like a hub where
everything is going out you know what I
mean from all over the place so for sure
yeah well now Canada is exporting all
over the world I heard I've got like a
good friend of mine that exports about
three to 5,000 pounds a month and it's
he's all over the place you name it he's
in like 16 he even he was the first
person to export to Jamaica and I don't
know why they're exporting but one of my
a guy that I dealt with for years set up
a chain of dispensaries across there
yeah called the canic clinics but nice
but uh yeah it's just insane um like I I
think there's still people that do it on
the black market that bring it to the
states just because of the Gap in our
pricing I know it sounds crazy but
there's people that will take it from
the West Coast that bring it to the east
coast and going across to the states
it's just well like it right now like if
you know you can get really nice stuff
for like say 500 Canadian a pound I
probably wouldn't even recognize it
because I think when I think of Canadian
I think of this super dense stuff that
like doesn't have you know what I mean
so probably if he comes down here they
don't call it Canadian they just call
you wouldn't have a clue you'd be
surprised on like uh just how horrible
our Market is like I I can remember a
while ago couple years ago one of my
buddies was bugging me like crazy he's
like I know you can help me so I phoned
a store for him to try to I'm like can
you can you get him some picks and uh I
happen to be in town and like I'm I'm
not involved in anything like that but I
was I happened to go by the store and I
saw these were the nicest picks I've
ever seen in my life not one small piece
like I'm talking they were absolutely
freaking beautiful I've never in myen
that were just spectacular like and they
want end I think they said it was going
for like 800 Canadian and they didn't
even want to come down and look at it I
was like holy [ __ ] what is wrong with
you guys I've never seen that in my life
like I've seen a lot of packs and yeah
never seen anything even close to that
wow well and you guys are big into rosin
I mean I got some friends from Canada
and they they have amazing rosin so you
guys are producing amazing rosin and
xtract up there as well and yeah well
you know um BC bubble man marus yeah
he's on our team so yeah he's uh he's
got the fire he's always had the fire
yeah he's I was just going to say he
kind of RI the wrote the rules wrot the
fire he wrote the rules for the fire
yeah exactly I'm friends with Dave from
Gast town he was on the show okay yeah
he's right he's from Vancouver Island
also too yeah he's he's got the killer
he's absolutely no he's in a really nice
area in Tofino nice yeah it's a
beautiful spot on the island yeah I
gotta come back up to Canada are you
allowed in maybe maybe we'll see nice
let's see I got kicked out of Canada for
a joint driving across the border I only
had a joint in the car but it was in a
tackle box and they decided to search
the car and I was so upset that they
were searching the car I talked [ __ ]
because I didn't think there was
anything in the car and so the whole
time the guyyy searching I'm like you
find anything blah blah blah and then
he's like no we're going to find
something and sure enough there was a
tackle box in the trunk that had like a
four-year-old joint that had a little
Bend to it oh [ __ ] pulls it up like we
got him guys and then I I had paperwork
in my back pocket I'm like I have a
recommendation from California that's
medicine
and they're like no it's not you're
you're going across uh International
borders with drugs I'm like no I'm not
I'm that's a joint and it's it's
medicine it wasn't even mine that's the
funny thing but I did have a script on
me and so I ended up having to pay a
$550 fine and got kicked out of the
country for five years okay when was
that what year was that a long time ago
that was
200 S maybe six so I'm okay I mean I got
a felony but we'll see nice renthal he's
he goes across he seems to be okay doing
going over there yeah I you know what I
think they're you know they're going to
let you like if you broke somebody's
face with their legs I think that you
have a better chance of getting across
than if you're selling or got caught
with like a trafficking charge or
something yeah like something like that
they just hate that [ __ ] right or I'm
sure stolen property too probably
doesn't go over doesn't fly very well
anything like that but DUI I think if
you have a DUI you can't even get in
Canada but the United States stupid
silly yeah well it's just especially I
don't know how they well 24 I don't know
like they have a 24-hour here that's
like a step down from a DUI or is there
is it only DUI only DUI yeah for us you
can get like a 24hour where it's like uh
you just lose your license for 24 hours
and you get it back or whatever they
need to do that here that's a that's a
good one yeah like I I I you know I've
got I've got them for [ __ ] when I
wasn't even on anything and the only
shitty thing about it is I can't dispute
it or anything and like if for weed like
it's happened to me like remember uh get
going for a drive to pick something up
from the store and like my ride smelling
like it and I got taken down and I'm
arrested for 24 hours I remember like I
was just picking something up from the
store my wife is like where are you yeah
like uh so yeah it's pretty crazy wow
but yeah so I mean they do need that
here if it's you know a DUI I guess it's
a pretty serious charger you can well
it's big money right and so at the end
of the day they're not going to change
it because they like the money that they
get from the DUIs I think it's you know
and and 08 is the percentage oh so you
are allowed some you can have up to 08
in your system and then anything over
that you go you pretty much go to jail
pretty sure Canada it's zero tolerance
now at this point zero tolerance for
driving yeah I'm pretty sure it's like
you're not allowed anything anymore wow
yeah you guys are drinkers too a lot
most of the Canadians actually Dave not
a drinker bubble man's not really a
drinker yeah no no definitely not bubble
man like I don't like I when I drink I'm
not a quitter yeah so like I I drink but
like I only maybe have drinks maybe one
or two times a year it's not not a very
you ever see the movie Strange Brew not
sure like I I I'm it's not ringing the
name sounds familiar but it's not
ringing a bell what's that was like my
first experience with Canadians in beer
but it was so long ago but I remember
the the a they said a a lot yeah no I
spent my 20s doing a lot of drinking
yeah a lot of club scene and stuff and
got out of that well I've got three
daughters now yeah nice prefer Edibles
and cannabis over drinking like I like
the Edibles is actually
nice yeah I'm not big on the Edibles I
smoke joints uh Edibles just don't sit
well with me I mean the thing is is like
I'll do the the micro do weed edibles
like I'll do like two mic or two two
milligram yeah you know and then all
yeah I do the mushrooms too I like the
mushroom micro does too um but like
mushrooms I can handle more than I can
handle Edibles for whatever reason but I
can smoke a big fat joint and be totally
happy it man if you don't have a
tolerance like even for me I just quit
for a while and then took it and it's
like I was getting way too [ __ ] high
like yeah uncomfortably High man like
where I can't go out and do stuff like I
can smoke and then go to work or go
whatever you know what I mean I can go
hang out it's not fun if you're like my
heart my breathing okay just normal
you're get I've given them to these guy
I've given them to a few people where
they phone straight up 911 and got an
ambulance there cuz they think they're
having a heart attack this one guy I
gave it to like I have these gel caps
that are like 3 50 milligram yeah I gave
one to him and I took it he fell asleep
woke up forgot he took it and he's just
thinks something was going on with this
hard paramedics and everything come down
there they're like no any [ __ ] drugs
he's like uh oh [ __ ] yeah I took it but
I've seen a few people where this
happens to if you take too much it's
just not fun I mean I've curled up in
the bed before I wanted to go to the
hospital for sure yeah but uh yeah well
here so in wreck you're limited to 10
milligram doses and 100 milligrams per
package that's what I've been seeing
I've been buying them I've been eating
like a few hundred at night time just
yeah yeah do you know what it's better
than Canada I think in Canada we have
five I've never even truly been in a
legal dispensary in Canada never really
never like it well there I personally
it's just not my thing there'd be
nothing for me to there and right and
well first of all the Edibles are just
like baby baby doses too right totally
five milligrams but you got to eat a lot
yeah like kind I don't like having to
suck on a bunch of sugar or eat a bunch
of sugar either if I'm going to like
once in a while but I don't want to be
eating a bunch of sugar every single
night so I always have them in gel caps
yeah yeah that's the way to go for sure
MCT oil yeah definitely good stuff I
like making like high-end rosin that
people would be smoking and using it for
Edibles I think rosin's the best for
Edibles yeah I think absolutely well
like I normally was making it from flour
and just recently like I I I'm just
getting into water hash cuz of bubble
and like I'm making it all and a man the
difference in potency is so [ __ ] kick
you it's so much different like same
milligram but it's way more but but so I
like the the gummies that are made from
rosin yeah oh definitely like anything
that's made from Rosen like I for
whatever reason I would always notice
that when if you have Edibles that were
made from BHO yeah after I would you get
like these nasty burps totally from like
the taste of it like and you know when
people are making distillate that stuff
there's like some pretty stinky stuff
that comes out of it some of the crude
yeah I forget what they call my buddy
nicknamed it the fish stuff but that
gross stuff yeah is like uh what you're
burp it's that that you're burping that
stuff like
it's yeah when I when I take it from
rosin I don't have those burps at all
it's completely gone you don't so it's
like um it filters that out when from
the Heat or whatever the lipids or
whatever the fats aren't in it it's like
the hot dog water in the carts yeah yeah
that's nasty uh but yeah I like I like
the Rosen yies rosin Tech makes these
amazing ones I don't remember the
flavors but they had some like I feel
like you get the the taste of the rosin
is also good you get the chirps yeah and
it's complimentary a lot of times
especially with sweet stuff yeah I was
noticing like it's the pricing here like
on well the stuff for 20 bucks for 100
milligrams with really tasty really nice
high-end gummies though stuff for $10
I'm surprised it's not that bad but you
can definitely taste taste taste the
difference well taste the difference in
it I'm thinking in my head why did I buy
the cheap [ __ ] I well first of all I
don't want any cheap [ __ ] there's a
reason why they're selling it [ __ ] so
cheap and I like I I know that you guys
are it's I think it's from what my
understanding it's like the wild west
for your guys's dispensary like
pesticide testing and stuff like in
Canada it's so like everything is tested
so thoroughly there's no way you're
walking into a dispensary and getting
stuff with pesticides like it could
happen I would say here it's the same
way too I mean there's some people that
have circumvented and cheated and got
gone around it but like in the
dispensary
in
California I can't speak for every state
but I would say that it it's pretty
heavily tested and they're coming down
on the labs that are you know oh really
oh yeah because like I I I kind of
thought it was still kind of like the
wild west with the dispensaries like up
until like Canada be there used to be
like in downtown Vancouver like over a
hundred like black market dispensaries
they were accepted by the police they're
paying you know licenses but then every
single one got wiped out like they were
completely gone and there's no more
black market dispensaries it's only
legal dispens New York has the Bas right
so like you can do in New York but
California doesn't have the BEDA model
really but we have thca and so thca you
can find that in gas gas stations liquor
stores uh CBD shops and it's thca flower
that's grown under hemp license a lot of
times and you know so these guys are
there's just loophole right now it's
going to get sealed up but I've been
hearing about it yeah I didn't fully
understand it like say Ser wild yeah
like cuz like I remember I was speaking
to this guy in Colorado that was like he
was so happy because he was allowed to
like sell thca now yeah to some other
state he's like my bank just accepted me
like he was all excited about it yeah
because I guess that's well I already
know it's the issue here like I like I'm
with Chase and I I had an issue like
when we got paid by a cannabis company
like I we can't even be paid by from
Chase yeah I don't like Chase Chase is
the worst is are they yeah I can't even
have an account there they they blocked
me from having an account but oh yeah
but yeah like in cannabis like Chase is
Chase is not cool with any of it uh thca
is considered hemp under the farm bill
that was passed it falls under the
category unless it it's converted to a
Delta 9 then that would be considered
THC but it has to be above. 3% so you
could have Delta 9 at 0.
2% uh and it could have 27% thca and
it's considered hemp you you smoke it it
still gets you high still tastes amazing
still that same plant but it's it's it's
categorized
differently wild yeah yeah we're in an
interesting I mean you know this is an
interesting day in time that's evolving
and it's not going to stay this way
forever things are changing I I still
think though like with all the damn red
States like it's got to be so thriving
there's got to be so many people just
crushing it that's all like dude the
thca people are people that are selling
you working under the hemp are crushing
it and Texas because Texas isn't legal
for cannabis it's it's not it's not it's
recreational who knows if it'll ever
past Recreation I would hope it would
someday but it's not right now but thca
is in all the CBD shops so they have
jars you know and they have jars from
Oregon and from wherever and you can
find your popular brands and all of it's
there you can go online though you can
go online and you can type in thca and
your favorite company cookies is selling
theirs you know even cookies has their C
is
but yeah so you have a pretty big
Instagram following so tell us about
Instagram and your history with social
media you've been on YouTube for a long
time yeah so I was on I had hundreds of
videos on YouTube so I at any given time
I would be documenting anywhere from
like two to six to seven operations so
like I was a commercial well commercial
sized medical gross for a long time like
for about 15 years where I would have
anywhere from I don't know 150 to 500
lights going really depending on what's
going on so I used to yeah I used to
make like um in some weeks I would put
out 10 videos like I I literally did it
besides the growing it was almost full
time where I'm like I'd have crops where
I would have over 50 videos out just for
one crop where each video is anywhere
from you know five to 20 minutes where
I'm covering every last part of it um
and it you know it was like a passion
for me I just and I helped a lot of
different people all over the world with
it and then they had this YouTube Purge
I don't know if you ever remember about
it where it's like all of a sudden
YouTube channel half of everybody I knew
was taken out and so at that point we
were like I I removed like I had over
700 grow videos and like a couple
hundred live streams I removed
everything and I opened up a zoom
account and we started taking everything
to zoom you know we have like at one
point it was like a 500 to 600 person
live audience we had built up every
single week soon as we went to zoom we
were down to like 200 we did that for
like about a year and then I felt
YouTube like some channels were coming
back and the tide was changing and I
just felt like I came back to YouTube
and then um obviously the algorithms
changed like it used to be well and it
keeps changing I feel like the one thing
now that's the constant is that it's
going to keep changing same thing
Instagram it's constantly changing sucks
you can never catch up to it because
it's constantly changing it's so
complicated and they use so many data
points uh that they're they're pulling
from and there's so many qualifications
for videos and they use AI so if there's
a weed leaf on your shirt you're not
going to get subscribers you're not
going to get viewers on on any of the
platforms except for maybe Twitter
Twitter's been more open about that yeah
but Twitter doesn't have the same for me
Twitter doesn't have the same results as
Instagram or YouTube yeah like at at one
point if you had a title whoever had the
most views and it's the same title came
to the top that was like the ultimate
and um X is supposed to be like that
right but I'm Just a Nobody on X like I
can't I'm trying to give away a light to
get over a th followers and it's been a
month like I haven't been plugging it
every day but it's like yeah it's so
hard to get to that point like I'm sure
if I had 20,000 people I could totally
grow from that point on but because I'm
being seen by so little it's like yeah
it's the same thing for like YouTube
like try to start a YouTube channel from
scratch and try to make it it's
impossible you would need a big break
yeah you know what I mean like you
that's what we had we I mean we we grew
we have now 12,000 subscribers and I
feel like Ricky Palamino when he was
talking about Snoop Dogg it went viral
and I think those when you're talking
about celebrities or popular things
popular search topics those you know we
got six million views on one short on
YouTube that's insane yeah yeah it just
kept growing and I'm like is it gonna
stop and Ryan is it gonna stop and he's
like I don't know you think it's gonna
stop and I'm like I don't know and uh
you know we went on for eight weeks and
it just kept growing and growing and
growing yeah it's just really it's crazy
and like uh one of the strategies for us
was like cross um cross crossing traffic
with other people and
collaborations like we're actually do
you know who mercules is with Death Row
Records he actually pering for Snoop Dog
right now on their tour that they're
doing um we're doing a collaboration
with him and we're making mercs so we're
making some really pimp ass glasses that
are going to come with our lights and
he's also going to be selling them what
is the best Spectrum for Led glasses
what is the best color well here's the
thing is uh like there's some companies
that make them that claim protection but
I'll tell you you can put it on and it's
like blinding so we have already have
our own glasses when you put them on
it's like a green color but it gives you
almost I'm going to say 99% protection
like I can turn the lights at full power
and look at them and I have like actual
protection the only issue is it's like a
green color but after about five minutes
it adjusts right so your eyes do adjust
have green ones too yeah we're we're
we're working on a few we're going to
have a few different lenses and um but
we're definitely going to keep on
working on till we have something so
like we haven't finished our lens but
we've just finished the design of the
glasses so yeah you need a tunable
glasses that can tune to the different
spectrums yeah Auto Tune on the glass
you just push a button and it Tunes with
the light yeah yeah being able to the
eye protection it's I think it's
something that's overlooked like oh man
your eyes can oh like after working in
they trying to work in Far red or like
too much it's so bad yeah just like when
you walk out of a room after you've
doing it like you're so blinded too so
yeah it's like it's something for the
it's some people should be paying
attention to and yeah I mean these are
the type of things I think about for
employees like I don't I don't it's not
even the liability aspect of it it's
more so that their health and their Eye
Health I'm getting older myself so my
eyes have gotten worse the second you I
was fine everyone's like when you turn
40 and the truth is is when I turned 43
is when my eyes got [ __ ] I'm 47 now
but like my eyes went to where I needed
bifocals I didn't get bifocals but um
now I have two different lenses so I
have one more concentrated that's that's
for distance than one that's for
nearsighted I could I could see that
yeah you have to be it's yeah my I've
had really good eye vision but I like my
whole life and stuff but I kind of feel
like they've taken a toll from the years
of the lighting and every like being
around it like crazy well we're in a
beautiful time too they have lens
surgery to where they can pull the lens
off your eye and put a new lens on and
they be better than 2020 Vision as long
as your vision's stable yeah so let's
dive into talking about genetics because
I know you're a big genetics guy you
love genetics you love cannabis at least
from what I get to see yeah um yeah to
be quite honest like I I'm all the stuff
majority of the stuff I have is really
old school well like old school OG
lineage and there's a big problem in
Canada I don't know if it's as bad in
the United States with just renaming and
like so much stuff just gets the wor it
just like in BC alone like when Purple
Kush hit it just there must have been a
hundred different names for it you know
what I mean and uh so yeah it's a big
big problem um I've had this strain it's
kind of funny it's quite a funny story
if you even Google it it will lead you
down the wrong path called Death Bubba
and like the the death Bubba name came
from us getting it into a dispensary
like and it was just an an accident like
everything like growing up in the 990s
we'd call like if it was something was
really good we'd describe it as the
death I got the death yeah you know what
I mean so we don't with the kill the
kill the kills I got the kills I got the
death that killer yeah exactly so and
then like um after PK like different
types of Bubba started coming on the
scene and they be started becoming
really popular like and they were killer
like and uh like I we how the name
actually happened there was a buddy of
mine took it to this dispensary Eden in
Vancouver and it was one of the biggest
chains and I I remember just saying to
him just just show it to him get him to
smoke it look at the death yeah it's the
death man it's and then like my buddy's
like it's death it's Bubba and then like
somehow he said it's death Bubba and
that's how the how the name got started
and what's what's kind of funny is I
dealt with a lot of people but I didn't
deal with the main guy and the main guy
just I got put in touch with him by
bubble man just like a couple weeks ago
like I have to ask you about this
because he was the person in charge of
it and yeah they they absolutely loved
it it was their number one seller for
until we stopped giving it to them and
same with the MK W it got so popular
that other dispensaries just started
copying the name like there' be lineups
outside the door for people to get it
right so people would just rename it
yeah such BS but yeah happens all the
time the MK Ultra was that yeah well
that's what H with those were the two
strains we had death Bubba and MK but
they decided just to call it
mku like that Eden made this decision to
call it mku like we never said that and
we just called it MK and um then
everybody just copied it and like there
is a really good mku string but it's
it's nothing like this like the Master
Kush that I was growing or even related
oh yours was the yes so mku is MK Ultra
and but they called it
your MK and then people just started
stealing the name and because like the
strain became so popular there was
another really good mku strain so you
know unless you're from like the early
2000s and you bought that and stuff most
people don't know the difference because
like mku is like a really popular strain
that a lot of people die hard grow and
like it which in my opinion is more like
the Bubba strains like there were all
these different Bubba strains that I
felt were somewhat related even though
they had different flavors but and like
they all had OG in them soapy OG yeah
I I love Bubba you know I think uh Bubba
got bastardized in the Bay Area so what
happened is it became the commercial
strain because you could harvest in 54
days and so the Asian Community blew it
out I mean blew it out like no tomorrow
this is before runs and before lcg
Bubbas were the big thing and I grew up
with the different Bubba same thing with
Master Kush we had a Master Kush that
would it would Branch out laterally so
you'd get lateral uh so the BRS would
grow sideways almost like a Christmas
tree so the buds they they were ugly
looking or weird looking I wouldn't say
ugly but they were almost Chris like
Charlie Bown Christmas tree looking buds
okay and then we had the Bubba and the
Bubba was like this soapy smelled like
Irish Springs OG gassy both of them were
extremely gassy extremely pungent and
those were for me those were the Exotics
of my day back in the '90s and early
2000s yeah one one thing about the two
that I um really big difference that I
would notice like death Bubba and bubas
could go purple yeah and lighter color
with yellow leaves where that the master
cush strain that we had no purple it
goes completely only yellow yellow in
the yellow and lime green like somewhere
in there yeah yeah but no purple at all
and it was um the death Bubba was also a
lot more forgiving of a strain where you
like you make a little mistake or feed
it too much food you could kind of
recover and go a little bit longer
Master Kush it's like you give it too
much food or do anything or you lock it
out you're [ __ ] it just shuts down
yeah so that was my experience too with
OG Kush back in the day was like it was
a finicky strain it was totally worth it
but I never got really big yields with
OG but it was like the best smoke ever
and everyone wanted me to grow it but I
didn't want to grow it because the
yields were so bad yeah and I mean I
grew it for myself for smoke same thing
with cookies I grew that for myself for
smoke back in the day but it wasn't like
the big producer and I grew a
combination of different I always like
having different flavor oh totally but I
also like mastering flavors and
mastering growing one thing like we've
tried multiple breeding projects like
anybody that ever got the death Bubba
could never get it to produce pollen
it's kind of weird like before different
people attempted it and they' get pollen
sacks um but no one ever got any pollen
out of it but I'm still yet s is like
that okay you know I think SF uh Mac one
is a partial triploid like a natural
partial triplo and so that's what I
think it might be naturally or not I'd
be interested to see someone cross it
yeah see how
see what happens when you yeah I mean
reverse it you make some pollen see if
you can reverse it even yeah well if
even if you can't reverse it you could
still cross it though no you can still
you could still pollinate it yeah you
could still pollinate it and I like it
the thing I like about it is the
stability of it yeah like well like it
would what's really weird is I would get
over the 20 years of growing it like I
could get it to produce seeds yeah but
only like a few like uh my cousin he
could barely fit through the aisle of
the room and I remember when he's
walking through the plants are like
shaking like crazy well that say out of
40 PBS well we might have got 30 seeds
wow like you know found 30 seeds
throughout the crop all fully mature and
on one of them I remember um sprouting
them and they were literally the fenos
were identical like they you couldn't
tell the difference but I didn't back
then we didn't have like I wasn't COA
getting them tested but like I didn't
even keep them because they just looked
identical I kind of regret and not it w
but yeah yeah totally I mean that's when
you have stable genetics right like
that's that's a good sign of stability
when the seeds come out exact like the
parent especially s1's I've never seen
any type of male flower or anything on
it like so it must be internally that it
does it and it pollinates itself like
for it to produce the seed well that's a
survival mechanism that the plants have
and like typically a plant all if
they're under any sort of stress will
produce a seed you know sometimes it's
only one seed and I mean even the most
stable varieties will produce a seed
gotcha yeah so and it like you know
almost every other crop I would also see
like and this is I can remember it for
10 years like out of nowhere you'd see
like this weird growth coming out of it
like where you'd be six weeks in flower
but then you all of a sudden like a
lower Branch would have this like three
week old growth kind of weird and I
would always cut it out and not but I
never ever see it just it clearly always
stuck out because hey why is it doing
that you know and it also another cool
thing about the strain is it will have
round tops and pointy tops and like for
whatever reason like lately it's just
all pointy but like on the last person I
saw grow it we were seeing a bunch of
round tops again and I can't explain why
it does that light spectrum yeah I guess
so huh probably light spectrum something
like that I would say it's environmental
but I'm saying even in like the same
room even in the same room on the same
plant yeah like in the same room with
multiple plants like you'll see some
that are pointy and then some are around
interesting like under the same Spectrum
you can get different results that's why
I wasn't sure like I saw it for a year
like you know all my crops are were well
I've got two under LED with death Bubba
and I've got probably like 100 plus
under HPS with it nice yeah well it's
just like I monocropped it because for a
decade yeah well it when people love it
though and you never get sick of it like
that's the true sign that it's amazing
too is when people never get sick of it
you never get sick of it yeah because
like something like green crack I love
grow I loved growing green crack and
then I would smoke it and it would be
cool for like the first first couple
days yeah I mean even the first couple
weeks like it gets you really the first
couple days and then you build a
tolerance to it and then after a couple
weeks you're like nah I don't want to
ever grow this again I might grow it
again a couple years later yeah I've
definitely grown up before too and feel
the same way about it nitrous oxide and
beef jerky those are the turps so yeah
that's what I get on the nose with that
stuff and I didn't actually make that up
I read that online somebody else wrote
that but I was like [ __ ] you smell it
it smells like nitrous oxide beef jerky
and uh but yeah that's the one where
it's like in the beginning it gets you
super high and then by the time you're
building a tolerance to it you start
sharing with your friends you're like
why are you guys [ __ ] so hot but yeah
this a good one yeah these days I like
to just obviously selection is key like
having so many different flavors and
stuff to pick from yeah well I like like
you know I like six-star hash or like
really highend rosin and like having a
bunch of different flavors and what I
like about it is um being able to have
it put it in the freezer and 6 months
later it's still nice and yeah that's
like you can't beat that that's where
it's like I do that with flour too right
so I feel like flour I can come out a
year later and it's still PR by just
sticking it in the yeah so I you cure it
properly so you dry it you cure it
properly and then you put it in a
sandwich bag Loosely and then you vacuum
seal and then in the freezer and then in
the freezer and you want a stable
freezer that doesn't have ice or
anything like that and you label and
date it and you're good to go uh the
first person that ever showed me that
was a guy named Ben from IC Collective
okay and you know it's like Game Changer
i've smoked stuff that was 2 and a half
years old that was pretty [ __ ]
amazing cool man so yeah like uh so that
that's kind of one of the biggest things
why I like it and like also with water
hash to and making everything fresh
which I like I'm about to start doing
yeah I just like the idea that you're
getting every last bit of resin like how
much are you losing when you're
harvesting and like and trimming and
like what's a fair number 25% by the
time everything is shaking and
everything is moving versus if you're
washing it and it or if it's going right
into the freezer Frozen I just smoked
some bubble house that was like four
years old in my freezer because I'm
moving and BR in it tasted amazing yeah
well that's that's exactly like I I have
a little six light medical where I can
also test um different you know lighting
and use it for R&amp;D but my I've been
growing three strains but I plan on
doing it to like six strains so that I
can you know have six flavers wash them
and then have just keep on storing them
in my freezer so like after a few years
I'm going to have it just a shitload of
flavors for when people come over right
yeah variety is always nice absolutely
just having that selection and also just
for if you're doing Edibles or
everything it's yeah yeah and they all
have different effects too like so I'm
big on the effects like I'm more
recently since my buddy Dave has passed
I've really been thinking a lot about
what's important at the end of the day
the effect and the flavor I mean but
there's there I I kind of went away from
putting an emphasis on effect and was so
heavily focused on Flavor for a long
time I'm also a chef also get excited
about flavors and excited about effect
too but like I like the effect of
cannabis in general but like there are
certain uh cultivars and certain
varieties that you smoke that are like
wow I feel [ __ ] great or wow I'm
[ __ ] awake first thing in the morning
or wow [ __ ] I can go to bed
absolutely and being able to just have
those when you want them it's kind of
nice or even the combination of
combining them um really like tolerance
breaks like well I don't like
necessarily like I because I use it to
sleep and I kind of have serious
insomnia without but at the same time
it's like your tolerance just gets so
strong and it's like you're take like
every now and again I like to take like
a full month off it's kind of hard for
me to do yeah getting through the first
week like I I literally when I quit
Edibles like and after I built my
tolerance I literally withdraw like my
body physically addicted I need it to
sleep right and so like I go through
hell for about a week but after that
week and then like on the 30 day Mark
it's just like you get so high when you
try smoking something or like for or
edibles is almost too strong I have to
go so light afterwards but it's just
kind of nice to have that tolerance
break and really feel the feel what it
can do yeah yeah yeah I think it's good
I you know I I have a tough time with
tolerance breaks like real tolerance
breaks going to shows going to events
you know it's like the majority of my
friends smoke and exactly and we're
always excited to dude you got try this
you got oh dude like yeah this white
Thorn Rose I got some of that and I was
sharing it with all my friends and it's
like oh it's [ __ ] feel good weed yeah
I like you know and I'm back to I I like
some of those Feelgood ones where it's
not really an indicia it's not really a
sativa where they would classify it as
narcotic or you know uh stimulant it's
somewhere in the middle where you smoke
it and you're just like you got a big
smile on your face every time you smoke
it every time I smoke that white Thorn
Rose my buddy's Blue 13 it puts a smile
on my face and I feel feel good like I
just feel it doesn't matter whether it's
in the morning whether it's at night
it's just feel good weed and there's
just something about those where it has
just those effects where it's like you
feel great yeah so yeah and I haven't
tried I mean I've tried the rosin of the
white Thorn that same thing I but the
problem is is when it's good like that
and I only had a gram I just smoked it
all because yeah it's easy to smoke a
gram when it makes you feel good oh
absolutely so yeah so how did you get
your start in the industry you've been
do at this a while right yeah yeah well
um I remember like well 90
1994 guy I knew he's like running some
from some people from a park and he's
just running through property after
property and runs into like this crazy
ass field like hundreds of plants in
full of flower so um that was kind of my
start well like he just started telling
everybody and we had pound we had
garbage bags and pounds the biggest
problem was trying to dry it yeah I bet
and then um yeah I like you know ever
since then and like I got in a lot of
trouble as a teenager lucky for the
young Offenders Act in Canada because
anything you do gets sealed when you're
19 or whatever so I'm definitely had a
lot of ups and downs and just got in a
lot of trouble um once I was about 17
years old I kind of figured out the
right path or became pretty good at what
I was doing yeah and then just kind of
stuck with it my whole life like well 96
was the very first indoor that we I got
into it was kind of funny I remember I
was walking through a path um in my
neighborhood and I just happen to be
walking by and this guy opens his door
and the light just comes blaring out I
see it like you can't hide it yeah and
he sees that I I saw it he tells me to
come over and then we ended I'm like no
don't worry I'm cool we ended up started
talking and it was just a four lighter
but he didn't have any money for
nutrients I was funny I remember buying
General Hydroponics and that was our
very first uh four lighter and so three
part was good back in the day I remember
three part and I never had a problem
with it back in the day I never hated on
it oh no that's what that's what
everybody like let's be honest in the
mid 90s like that's what everybody used
and I remember was O aonic was that what
it called it said for bigger bank
accounts and larger yields there was
this other product I used a couple other
products um cool Bloom and just a few
other things that we used back then yeah
and um you know I had like lots of um
success and then like by the time I was
in like my like the early 2000s I was
more like the person in charge it wasn't
me really growing yeah and um you know I
went on a pretty nice run with that for
quite a while and um I actually had
gotten into out of it for almost like a
couple years because I was playing poker
like I evolved into playing online poker
and then um I'd done really really well
like I was playing 16 tables at a time
and a couple hundred thousand hands or
over a couple hundred thousand hands a
year and doing a really successful at it
just killing it and then one day um
everything got seized by the FBI like
poker stars in Full Tilt got shut down
and They seized all the money and that
put me yeah like it was crazy like and
it was I ended up getting my money back
like a year and a bit later whatever but
I was like relying on that and like I
was doing you know I had I thought okay
well this is my career what I'm going to
do I'm really good at this and I can
make money and but then that happened
and that like pushed me back into
growing and I remember um I bought these
uh cuz like this isn't legal these are
still the wild west and uh we bought
these cargo trailers that were like
portable so that like you can just hook
up the power and water if there's an
issue you can get them out of there
right right so I I hook I bought like a
well I set them up like a 10 lighter and
an eight lighter and on the very first
crop like I've been so out of touch with
growing like because it wasn't me the
one that was doing it and I like this is
hilarious but on the 10 lighter I did I
got two and a half pounds a total crop
and the eight lighter like a pound and a
half and I literally locked them out
like totally and like I I remember my
buddy being like how does it feel to be
like the worst grower in the world like
the couple people were just riding me I
was like going crazy I was like
frustrated because I needed the money
too and it's was like then I just went
and I talked to every last OG I know
picked their brain you know like that's
growing the true kills and it's like on
the next crop I just knocked it out of
the freaking Park and then like just
from that point on it just kind of got
better and better and better and then
the medical licensing came out and that
was just just like so nice when it came
out having an actual medical license and
having that security I remember when it
first got issued you actually get like a
government ID oh wow and I remember
remember getting stopped and the cops
are like oh [ __ ] like they could smelled
and everything I remember showing it to
them the cop had never even seen it or
even heard of it like what the [ __ ] I
remember just having that card being
like Oh literally your get out of jail
card yeah it's just like such a relief
on the cops weren't you know weren't
used to it either so then yeah I just
went on a a really nice run doing that
and then um I started making YouTube
videos and then um like one day I made a
video saying like hey is there's any LED
companies out there send me an LED and
uh I'll prove that it works because I I
was an HPS guy and didn't believe in
them at all yeah then finally a company
reached out to me and you know I tried
it and like I could see that hey this is
this is working pretty nice and like
halfway through the crop I was like hey
if this goes well can I get the Canadian
distribution rights and they were like
sure at the time they they were nothing
and didn't have any money anyways and
they were happy to be working with me
and they were like sure yeah so then
that went on and then um it just it was
kind of crazy how fast things happened
like and then yeah and then um four and
a half years later I ended up just
starting my own company nice yeah it's
amazing how stuff can snowball you know
yeah well it's like the power of um I
always try to tell people that anything
can happen so fast like what can happen
in one year if you work on it every
single day and don't give up it's pretty
crazy like the power of doubling too
like of yeah you know having one
facility and going to two facilities and
then going to four three or so on
scaling is an art too that's yeah but
while having work ethic and also knowing
about I think it's also a skill to be
able to pull the be able to pull the
plug too when you need to like not every
idea I've had like even with the LED
lighting like we've made plenty of
mistakes and had to change direction or
change what we're doing or you have to
be able to identify hey this isn't
working I got to pull the plug and
change something or adjust or adapt
being okay with making mistakes is one
of the biggest things in business yeah
if you can learn how to be okay with
making mistakes then you have no fear
and also recognizing that it's a mistake
take responsibility take responsibility
yeah you know because I feel like I've
made over the last two years especially
with James L genetics I made a bunch of
mistakes but I learned from them and
they made me smarter they made me better
at what I do uh you know I'm focused on
the plants now and being the one that's
making the decision absolutely like I
I've always kind of said that like you
have to take responsibility if you can't
admit it or try to blame it on somebody
else you're not going anywhere fast well
and sometimes there's like I've had to
come to Jesus moments where I realize
that nobody's gonna come there to save
me I got to save myself right absolutely
and those are some those are some great
experiences I think that we all need to
go through because a lot of times in
life even when it's talking about I've
been going to the gym lately by myself
and I've had workout Partners I like
workout Partners to a degree but I also
just like going and doing the work and
nobody's going to come save you you want
to get in shape you got to do it
yourself if your friends can't go work
out with you you need to go to the gym
you know if you want to be in shape you
if or maybe you don't maybe you can go
for a run maybe you can go for a walk
but same thing with the plants if
nobody's gonna you know if you you don't
have anybody that's going to go thin the
plants out you got to thin them out
yourself and that's just the truth
reality of it and the sooner you can get
over that kind of stuff and just suck it
up and say [ __ ] it this is what I got to
do I want to be successful I want to be
the best person that I can be you know I
think those are those are the important
things funny you said the gym because
like that is one thing like I've been
trying to brace myself I haven't done
any real physical workout or like work
been at a gym since my early 20s but in
the last month I've been doing a couple
hundred push-ups a day trying to embrace
myself and it's like yeah like you said
like no one's going to do it unless you
do it yourself no one's going to come
save you no one's going to come Force
you go to the gym yeah I mean and it's
so hard like I just even remember like
it's kind of motivating now CU I can do
it so easy but in after the first day of
just doing a couple days I was like you
just get so sore and getting it over
that hump of being able to just have the
motivation to do it to and want to do it
well I think there's there's showing up
and I think that's important because
that's repetition and that's you know
you there it requires a a a certain
amount of discipline right just showing
up right just getting there and showing
up that's great but then when it comes
to working out like putting the effort
in because I look around the gym and
they all look the [ __ ] same as when I
was going to the gym two years ago and
I'm getting really good results right
now because I'm putting the effort in
and when I go I make each rep count I
don't do long workouts I do shorter
workouts but I go there and I'm there
for a purpose and I'm there I'm not
there to socialize I'm there to get [ __ ]
done just like I am at work exactly so
uh let's talk about the Emerson effect
the Emerson effect okay yeah there's a
lot of talk about that lately just like
online and stuff and I I think it's a
little bit confusing because people
think the Emerson effect that means a
lot of people think that's like putting
your plants to sleep right and it's not
it's just really the combination of 680
nanometer and or lower and
720 nanometer and higher so basically
it's just having deep red and far red
combined together um it allows the
photosynthesis of the plant to be more
efficiently and like we've seen lots of
people just without even like using it
to put the plants to sleep um have
faster crops by anywhere from like two
to five days can you explain the
difference between deep red and far red
um so deep red is like 660 nanometer
like if you're looking at it on a scale
and and far red is 730 so it's just um
yeah like they're they're right next to
each other deep red like too much far
red also is not good for your plants
like um far red like in double-ended HPS
a lot of people criticize it too because
they don't understand it and they're all
like oh you it's got way too much far
red if it's got 6% but then like a lot
of people blame stuff on Far red but
then I always argue back well HPS has
10.4% and it's never turned off yeah you
know so I always come back to that and
say it's another variable that you're
blaming it on Far red um we find I find
far red um just so beneficial like when
we were adding like we have lights that
can control it independently or that
have it fixed in and we could just see
that having it in the Spectrum um the
plants like it better they prey better
just everything about it they like
better they get better color if you're
going for color which color is such a
big qualifier now it's it's one of the
boxes that needs to get checked with a
lot of people yeah you know and I think
what I've seen with the favin is you're
getting with their their under canopy
they have far red and does it have far
red in it it does okay it does and it
also gets purple purple buds on the
bottom that are big yes and so I think
that's just you know I think the
potential for that so I'm excited to see
you're under your your abs absolutely
well we've um we've we've kind of
designed it to have more light peratt
than everybody else and we're going to
be coming in with a cheaper price so
we're kind of going to shake up the
industry like we've done with a lot of
our other lighting um but we've what
we've really done well we've really
shaken up the industry just with some of
our lighting with the value um in it and
the reason why we're able to do that is
because we're extremely efficient like
I've been well we've been at this for a
while and it's like everything we've
done we're setting up where like our
competitors are spending tens of
thousands of dollars a month on rent
where we don't pay rent like we're just
we you know for our Michigan
distribution we just bought our building
like and we're just every like in that
aspect we're just set up um so much more
efficiently like a lot of I built an
army of people working on commission you
know over 50 people and you don't get
paid unless you actually make a sale and
it's just a lot more motivating for
people I've always tried to do that too
with grows like of all the grows over my
years like I didn't like having workers
like I like having partners make someone
a partner we bleed together if we're
gonna bleed and it's you know it's
motivation and like I've always trying
to you know doesn't always work out and
I've had a I've broken so many people
trying to do that yeah you know what I
mean but I like trying to start a
business I remember like I've had we
could just say other businesses on the
distribution and people think oh I'm
gonna start that and it's like good luck
buddy like trying to start something
like that yeah try working it every
single day yourself for a year yeah
before you're even gonna think about
hiring it's almost like any business
like I I had a really I had a Don like I
I owned a Donaire business I didn't work
I didn't work it but I had like a really
good this girl that was a employee and
she was just an incredible worker and we
did so well and it's like the second you
get to somebody that's doing the bare
minimum it's just like the place fails
yeah well it's it's such it's it's such
a challenge a lot of times because of
the balance you know it's like hard to
find someone that complimentary that
that's willing to put in the work for me
it's always like I'm the Workhorse I
don't mind being the Workhorse I love
that part of it yeah and then you need
to have someone that's complimentary
that's able to Bal be the balance right
at the end of the day you don't need an
exact duplicate of yourself you need
someone that's the complimentary version
of yourself that adds the things that
you don't contribute and I feel like
I've gone through enough relationships
and Partnerships I love Partnerships I
love Partnerships working with people
people bleeding together winning
together and losing together you know
and it's like it makes losing not as bad
and it makes winning even better and the
right partner can make it amazing and
the wrong partner can just make it hell
absolutely yeah like I I almost like
I've had to make deals in my life where
I almost felt like I made a poor
decision well like a poor deal on my
let's just say for example it's a 50/50
partnership except for I'm doing all the
work and the other person put up the
money and a lot of people criticize that
but I always you know I'm the one that
made the deal and yeah it sucked and it
wasn't really fair but guess what at the
end of our five years we got that was
the reason why I got way ahead you know
what I mean like and having that and
being able to recognize that so like I
know a lot of people don't think it's
fair well if you don't have the money to
start sometimes you have to you have to
sacrifice something yeah you have to
sacrifice something and like I I can
remember like I had a 5-year deal on a
place and I I hated it like I I like
after a few years and we were doing well
and um like I used to I didn't bring
this up but on YouTube I was probably
the first person in the world that put
the most aggressive Leaf strip online
and uh like before three of light and I
just like I would bring in a crew and I
would strip my plants naked in the
middle of the crop and I remember day 21
you just oh I actually would do it on
day 15 oh wow for for me if I can unless
I needed the plants to fill out more
yeah so and like we we would get like
crazy aggressive but the reason why I
brought this up is I'm 50/50 partner but
I'm responsible for it so I'm bringing
people in to do it in pain and it's
coming out of my side right you know and
like I you know deals like that I would
be frustrated with but at the same time
well hey I ended up like I'm not
complaining about on the money I made on
owning the host House at the End of the
five years and everything like you know
what I mean and I sometimes you just
have to you could say make a deal with
the devil if you have to or makes an
unfair situ deal to get ahead and
sometimes they're unfair in a certain
perspective perspective and it's just
all about life is all about perspective
any yeah well like exactly a perspective
it's not in the bigger picture unfair
because like they put up like how hard
is it to save up six digits plus of
money and and also have the balls to
invest it and do it without securing it
having that kind of stuff right yeah I
mean a lot of it comes down to balls too
absolutely like I've had a pretty good
track record for when it comes to like
investing in stuff or like getting
people to come or like if I come to
someone for money so it's like I've
never really had too much of a problem
but I can like I've had a lot of other
people that that have said no you know
what I mean that just because they're
afraid of it or whatever but yeah if you
have a pretty solid business plan and a
track record it's a lot easier well and
it's not all money is good money yeah
and so it's about finding the right
partner the right person it's like
that's I've seen that happen before you
know myself and you myself too yeah yeah
where I wasn't yeah happy with my
partner or who I'm associated with
I mean I'm in the perfect situation now
with my partner and we're the balance
with each other yeah you know and we we
contribute both of us contribute a lot
to the business and different things and
it's just you know I wake up in the
morning and I'm excited to come to work
and those are the you know you know it's
good when you wake up at 5: in the
morning you're like I'm going to the gym
and then I get to go to work yeah
exactly and just enjoy everything youve
built and just everybody that you're
working with and I kind of feel the same
way even though I'm busier than I've
ever been in my Whole Life by far I
enjoy it and it's like I I enjoy that
like I have late nights in China you
know four to five times a week you know
just and I enjoy it though I enjoy the
hustle I've been and it's rewarding to
see where we're at too it's like in the
last two and a half years so much has
changed like even when I go back a year
from now and it's like it's it's such a
rewarding feeling of like I put I was in
the craziest fight of my life and just
every single day I just wouldn't stop
and it's like we're really reaping the
rewards and we're not slow
at now we can really we' brought things
to the market and we can innovate in
other ways or do anything at this point
and that's what it takes is just not
getting up and even when it's tough
putting the left foot in front of the
right and the right foot in front of the
left and just keep on moving forward
yeah like we got killed in our very
first year in Juice you could say
because like I like I didn't borrow from
a bank or anything you could say so it's
just like I I did everything myself
without having to bring anybody in and
then after about a year one of my
friends kind of jumped in and helped
just because they could see how well
things were going but yeah we haven't
taken on any money it's just been us and
exactly I think those are the best but
also we've struggled you know it's like
it's a struggle people everybody thinks
like you're doing it you're killing it
you're you know it's like yes but it's
been a struggle it hasn't been easy good
things are never easy at least in my
experience most of the good things are
challenging and I get reward and a lot
of gratitude for everything that's gone
on absolutely like we caught a really
big break about a little over a year ago
with a client from Dubai and we just did
like a was 166,000 light deal wow yeah
so it was like we designed a we designed
a custom light from them and it was just
like a massive break for us that just
allowed us to kind of get into another
league and was it for indoor cultivation
yes it's for growing lettuce wow yeah
it's in like three tier two tier oh more
than that like a insane tier like I
don't even remember how many but like
just the most ridiculous setup and they
they originally had come to us with a
design that was horrible and we
redesigned everything and just improved
their uniformity and we have them as a
client too for like we're going to be
doing another massive project with them
and um that really just changed things
for us that's awesome yeah so yeah and
you never know like when you start a
business you never know how long it's
going to take usually with if you do
build outs it takes twice as long and
twice as much money but like oh just
because you have an idea that's good
doesn't mean you're necessar going to be
successful with it so like there is risk
involved but once you once you start
seeing the signs it's like you know
you're onest stuff and figuring out just
how to do everything like we had so many
learning experiences like even from with
someone saying they're moving forward
and not taking a deposit like there was
someone that I thought was as good as
gold before that told me and I made 500
lights for them and then they backed out
and it wasn't a model that like was
popular selling and like it it to be
quite Hest it tied it up for almost six
months for me and like it was just a
learning mistake and those typee of
things of we had some crazy Financial
challenges with just everything we're
doing and then having so many lights and
then figuring out which ones perform the
best and then having stock and yeah it
was extremely challenging but it's you
know like I said it's a rewarding
feeling getting to hear totally the
whole research and development aspect of
it it's pretty wild especially with
lighting it's like to well because you
don't want to just make another light
you have to make a light that's
different that's better that has
something that makes it stand out
because there's gilan lights and then
there's knockoff lights because it's
like there's stuff coming out of China
they're knocking off stuff and
absolutely it's such a it's such a crazy
market and we you know we wanted to do
something different and that's where we
came in and it's like we like I always
say to people it's like name any company
and compare it to one of our lights and
let's like break it down in a lot of
cases you're getting double the value
with us so that means like if a the
light cost double the cost to make but
it's retailing for the same price yeah
you know what I mean and that's where
people that like when they start going
down that rabbit hole it leads them to
us right like if they want if they want
to have the best value they want to have
the most efficient they want to have the
most diversity they want it to run the
coolest they're coming to us yeah yeah
really cool so let's talk about your bug
Light okay so yeah we have the very
first registered pesticide light in
United States yeah so um like about two
years ago my father-in-law came across
an abandoned patent from like the early
2000s that gave us the right concept and
we kind of started going down this
rabbit hole and then well we started
doing research on UVC and it's not like
UVC is it's been common it's been used
for years to like kill bugs and labs and
all different types of stuff um it just
hasn't been used the same way so we
developed a we came up with a concept
and there was one other company that was
on the right track they had the right
idea
and the reason why you don't know who
they are is they started well I'm
positive that they started faking the
research really yeah so like saying that
the light is runs for this long and it
will wipe out and do all the stuff and
they started doing even studies showing
pictures before and after and like you
know you would think if it was truly
true they would have [ __ ] blown up
and then we realized like for the amount
of time that they were using it like I
started doing I bought their light I
even tested it absolutely doesn't work
what they were saying so we started um
going down this rabbit hole and it's
like it's a really it took us like a
year of R&amp;D of trying all different
types of diodes different wavelengths
and all of a sudden on one of the tests
that we did it was just stupid well we
started um I used to I don't know if you
saw those posts we'd be making posts I'd
be like anyone got spidermites who's got
like I want spidermites I'd make post
saying I want spidermites or I want
thrips yeah and I started even working
with someone that was even breeding them
and we were introducing I had four
different people that were partic
participating with us H was one of the
people that you know floor that came on
the showt he's awesome and then I was
doing it with another lab um too that
was participating so we we were
introducing five to seven spider mites
and we were beating them in seven days
then we started introducing so like
after the very first test I thought okay
well we can beat spider mites I thought
we could because you introduced five to
seven mites and we're beating them in
within a week and then we started adding
well on the very first test I added like
over 200 and I've got this all Doc the
footage document I'll be able to show
show you here cuz I'm about to start
releasing this stuff yeah um and that we
had like it had hundreds of eggs and
after about 36 hours of them being
established we started trading them we
couldn't beat them but we could reduce
their spread by over 95% and by like day
21 they were still weren't even webbing
and uh so it was just like a GameChanger
for spidermites but at this point we
we've evolved a lot since then like
we're about to start doing a whole bunch
of testing but I would still say it's
like one like with what we were doing it
was a straight up 95% protection like so
basically if spidermites come in your
room you're going to be in a 95% better
situation if you don't beat them in the
first week like if it's a serious
infestation and then with um thrips um
the same thing I had well we were doing
like I I happen to have the very first
day I got him I happen to get an
unplanned infestation of thrips so it
was just like the best uh thing and like
I documented it and you know we're
beating them by 97 to 98% and I'm like
thinking hey this is absolutely
incredible you in the top 30 plus inches
like we cannot see a thrip and any of
the thrips or anything you see is like
out where the light is int treating so I
thought this is incredible um now let's
try using it to stress out the plant to
get higher THC and tpping so we started
doing two 15minute treatments six days
later there were no [ __ ] thrips in
the room completely [ __ ] gone and um
there was a fellow from California
Matthew Gates do you know who he is sink
angel or I know that name yeah he's like
I I consider him like he's just a really
smart guy really knows IPM
really well and uh we flew him out to
see like hey can you to find a thri
because I had been talking to him and he
had seen what we were doing and like I
just wanted him to see it and stuff and
you know he can't he didn't see the
whole crop but he could see the footage
before and then to like while the thrips
were alive and he came down for the end
and they're not a living thrip and then
we've done multiple tests by now and um
it's yeah conclusive like thrips are a
problem of the past we can beat him
without pesticides or any type of
Predator bug so in the light work you do
treatments couple treatments a day it
runs in the middle of Darkness oh wow it
doesn't have to run in the middle of
Darkness but um everything that I had
done like for their research shows like
bugs are attracted to light in the
middle of darkness and it's not enough
to wake it up so we we like we even have
like over a year of using it like longer
times at night time but you can
definitely use it in the middle of the
darkness is when we recommended if
someone was nervous about it they could
do it right after the light squo or
right after after sure but yeah so it um
so it also works to kill mildew and
enhance THC and turpins really it's like
it's like the ultimate you know what I
mean it's sounds too good to be true
sounds too good to be true I can't wait
to see it yeah so like a lot of people
use UVA and they put UVA in their lights
we would never do it well first of all
UVA the diodes don't last nearly as long
right so when we have these souped out
lights with all these fiveyear life
dials we would never put UVA in the same
fixture that doesn't last nearly as long
next to that I've seen tons of side by
sides Over The Last 5 Years UVA versus
not mhm at most we ever saw was a little
over a 1% increase in THC with
sacrificing turpins yeah so like it was
never really that big I didn't think
very much of it and then UVB on the
other hand has a much higher efficacy
than UVA so UVB is from 280 nanometer to
3150 nanometer though any of those
side-by-side tests that we saw there was
a huge gain of 2 to 3% in tpin and 1 to
2% or sorry 2 to 3% in THC and 1 to 2%
inter turpine so um like you got UVA and
then you've got UVB which has you know a
way higher efficacy and then you got UVC
100 to 280 this stuff causes cancer by
the way like this that was why it was
such a big deal to get this registered
in the states right because you had to
go through all this different stuff with
the EPA and uh which is not not an easy
thing to do but um anyway so UVC has a
much higher efficacy we also made an
accidental Discovery when we had it on
we had a room where a timer failed and
the light was on for 12 hours and it it
[ __ ] up every part of the plant like
so the the light was down by the stem
and this is when we discovered that hey
it's affected every part of the [ __ ]
plant we can admit UV systemically into
the plant through the bottom of the
plant to enhance THC and tpes nice and
we couldn't there's no literature on
this so we're going to be like it was an
accidental Discovery I'm sure there's a
lot of people are going to be messing
around with this but uh it's it's pretty
incredible um so we don't even like with
our lights and having our we call it the
tantula Predator you don't need any UV
supplement you have the ultimate UV
that's working underneath your canopy
that also protects you from mildew it's
not going to like be a cure for mildew
because like you could technically kill
mildew if you put it within like a
certain distance sure but if you have
something that's causing mildew right
this Airborne it's like Well yeah if you
got a problem it's not going to be a k
like I've seen a mildew happen two two
major reasons why it happens is like I
see if someone doesn't have a room
properly insulated and it gets cold and
then hot and then it starts rotting in
the wall or it just simply getting too
cold with the humidity too high at night
time right so like if you're doing that
every single night we can't cure that
problem if your VPD is not it correct
but um but it definitely does work it
just overall it's just such a
Competitive Edge
nice yeah and what kind of price are we
looking at um to do a 4x4 area it's
going to be 225 us nice yeah super
competitive yeah it's it's super
reasonable um like we were working on a
UVA UVA bar wall it's like already done
uh just working on the certification but
I was ready to abort it like we didn't
it's a fluorescent bar that will attach
to any fixture and we like we didn't use
UVB diodes like there's a lot of other
companies that are but the technology
isn't really there yet when I say that
like in a fluorescent bar it was 80%
more efficient yeah so you're getting
80% more light per watt because I'm
using in a fluorescent so that's why we
went in that direction but with the UVC
in our Predator like I'm pretty much
going to abort it because what's the
point of having UVB and UVA when you got
UVC right and what's also cool about it
you can get it anywhere in your canopy
like the lights they float but they spin
360° and you could move them up anywhere
in your canopy if you wanted it up by
your upper flower and like um I know
it's kind of hard to visualize but
basically when you have clones they go
above pointing down mhm at your clones
nice and it's also for like someone like
you that has genetics yeah it's a
[ __ ] GameChanger for your mother
rooms like because you can't have to the
more you have the better the more
coverage you have so like for me
personally if I had any type of genetics
or any type of breeding my mother rooms
would be covered in them just because
it's the ultimate protection like can't
um like we haven't got to test it like
we're working with a major you
University um with like a with the dean
of a major university I I can't say yet
but once it's everything is published
they're assisting with the white papers
and uh we're so we're going to have all
the science behind it and like I believe
it's going to work on everything to be
quite honest like russet mes I broad
mites I think it will work on everything
like it's so effective that's such a
game changer too because russed mites
and Broad mites is they're a pain in the
ass I mean you can use M microle
disperse and sulfur for Russ mites and
Broad Ms to a degree but there it's not
easy to get rid of and then all of a
sudden you're spraying sulfur on your
plant now you can't use it for extra
right smoking sulfur you don't want to
smoke sulfur oh it's so yeah sulfur is
such a yeah it's it's such a like we see
it with the potential to end pesticides
on food crops well it's like the
ultimate IPM right so like really it's
the most safe method of uh Pest
Management on the planet yeah and like I
said we were doing well against spider
mins but that was a 10-minute treatment
I haven't tried two 15minute treatments
yet on them so like we might be able to
beat spider mites the same way we might
be able to beat thrips um but we already
know it's so effective there's no we
can't hold it back anymore like it's and
it's well it's right like we literally
have it leaving for the USA at the end
of this week um really cool yeah so
anyways yeah have to get some of them
for the facility oh definitely like I
said it's a a game changer especially
for someone like you that's got genetics
yeah no that sounds awesome yeah good
stuff well if you had one piece of
advice for your younger self coming into
the industry with all the experience
that you have now what would that
be um well I definitely would like I
definitely wouldn't have acted as
unprofessional as I did in some cases
like going back like uh like this is CRA
I'm crazy conservative the last two
years that you've known me go back like
a couple more years and I what you could
consider me as a hotthead or would speak
out or I'd be canceled for sure yeah you
know just like like uh so I would say
being conservative like never um well I
think the ability to know if you have a
bad if something's not working out you
have to abort or reconfigure and move
forward and I'm being able to see that
or pull the plug and start something new
I think is a one of my biggest pieces of
advice I could have nice yeah people are
trying to get a hold of you want to know
more about your
lights where can they go um either like
Grandmaster level on Instagram Grand
Master
LEDs just type in Grandmaster LEDs on
Google in our website they'll be able to
we have a chat contact form I'm we're
super easy to get a hold of yeah awesome
yeah really cool thank you so much for
coming on the show look forward to doing
it again checking out your lights but
thank you very much awesome
[Music]
n