[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James loud
podcast and today our special guest is
Tracy the founder of the lotus Church in
Oakland how are you doing today Tracy
great thank you for having me thank you
for coming on the show we met on 420
this year which was a serendipitous day
for me because my friend passed and 420
being what it was it was like a really
special day uh so it was really nice
meeting you on 420 and I'm so glad you
finally made it on the show thank you
thank you for having me yeah SF weed
week that was a really cool day I mean
we got to meet a lot of people um new
people um see familiar faces that we've
known in the industry just for the past
years that we've been a part of it it
was a really great event David DS did an
exceptional
job I just I had a really good time
there and and I think it was set up well
there was the perfect amount of people
it wasn't too crazy it wasn't too mellow
it was just just right it was the right
blend of people too I feel like there
was a little bit of everybody from
everywhere right and it was a lot of fun
yeah I liked that he brought in um other
companies maybe not so well known and
mixed it in with you know yeah some of
the more familiar yeah it was like the
big guys with the little guys and a
little blend of everybody in between and
everybody that was there was there to
party and celebrate and have a good time
and there was just Good Vibes it was a
great Vibe it was a great Vibe I had a
good time there so tell us about the
Psychedelic church and what you guys do
I mean I started doing psychedelics when
I was 14 15 not something that I suggest
14 15 year olds do but um being a punk
in Olympia at the time that's kind of
what we did was forage for mushrooms
yeah it's mostly blue ringers and
liberty caps Olympia Washington Olympia
Washington so Dave was from Lynwood oh
was he yeah and I I was born in Portland
Oregon oh awesome so yeah we're all West
Coast
neighbors yeah and um I ended up doing
some mushrooms with the best friend of
mine um for a birthday and we did far
too many yeah and had an amazing
experience um went to a concert danc
like it was
1992 and he was just like you know I I
remember like you grew weed in the 90s I
was like I did like I bet you gr
mushrooms so it was like a dare yeah I
was like take that challenge all right
so I read I studied micology for a year
and then finally did it and um then the
pandemic hit and up until that point I'd
been working um for billionaires as a
newborn care specialist in private Chef
oh wow so that work kind of died right
in that moment even the wealthiest of
the wealthy were not having anybody in
their homes right so I was like well I
just learned the skill of growing
mushrooms let me let's do this
and um one of the ladies that I was
working with she's um one of the
original Black Panthers and she said you
know your medicine is the cleanest
medicine I've come across in Oakland wow
you what a great time to be in Oakland
you know cuz they had decriminalized
mushrooms yes and psychedelics uh most
psychedelics um not most but selective
ones and um she was like I'm going to
take you into the streets of Oakland and
we're going to get this medicine out
there so she took me into debast Oakland
I'd never been out that far wow and
started doing
sashes yes and it just bloomed from
there it was just a word of mouth spread
around the country I was going to
national conferences letting people know
that um you know the benefits of
psilocybin and the healing properties
right and um so many people came back to
me with the Positive immediate results
of their use of psilocybin and I started
doing more research and I realized this
is something that's going to be
transformative for everybody and it
shouldn't be relegated to just a select
few people that can afford it yeah and
so that's when I started to think about
paths to getting medicine to people and
um doing it in a legal way in a way that
um celebrates the medicine and a church
seems like the best path totally so it's
a community space
it's a space where people can come and
get education celebrate the medicine
find Spiritual Awakening and in an
autonomous way yeah that's beautiful
yeah I'm a big proponent of psychedelics
I actually took psychedelics before I
smoked cannabis I was afraid of cannabis
when I was 14 but there is this little
paper in my friend ad them they said you
know the Ki it was LSD right and these
little tabs uh
and I'd done that probably 10 times
before I smoked and I'm like that's an
opposite way such the opposite of most
people uh I was running cross country I
was worried about my lungs okay and
smoke okay and I was I mean I guess I
wasn't that smart as a kid but uh you
know I tried different things and uh
that was definitely like the the
psychedelics opened me up to everything
else uh and the possibilities of other
stuff and I just it's an amazing thing
and I think used correctly it can be a
life-changing experience and siloc cybin
and the thing is is especially siloc
cybin and LSD and some of these other uh
compounds I feel like it's
transformative right away like you get
direct effect that can be life-changing
once you go there you can never go back
right and I think that can be a really
amazing thing especially fear and
anxiety and some of the things that you
can get over with it uh 100% especially
with people with s depression yeah um
I've had multiple people come to me and
just cry at the table and like you saved
my life like I literally wanted to die
that day and someone gave me some of
your capsules and It reversed my entire
way of thinking yeah and when you have
something that transformative and that
immediate um there are so many people I
mean we see it here in the streets of
Oakland every day the level of
desperation um the lack of mental health
treatment for a lot of people how can
you look at that and just turn your head
and when you come to the realization
that soloc cybin is something that's
going to heal a lot of people why would
you deny that absolutely I mean I feel
like it was just like you know all this
stuff we even CBD was kind of looked at
negatively uhuh you know until sanj
Gupta came up and said look these kids
are getting cured but for for instance
mushrooms I have a friend he has severe
migraines and the only cure is
psilocybin mushrooms right literally the
only cure and he has to take a pretty
big dose but he he does it he he
actually knows how to regulate it so
when it's coming on he takes it before
it hits him hard and then he doesn't get
the severe migraines and how can you say
that's wrong you know that's that's my
big argument is how can you say that
somebody's Health shouldn't be in their
own hands if it's not hurting anybody
else right and it's beneficial how can
you say that's bad right right right and
there's studies that now I mean from ivy
league institutions and other reputable
universities around the world that it
regenerates neuron growth and so we live
in like this fear-based culture of like
don't you know don't hurt yourself by
doing just anything anything can do that
so finding out that psilocybin reverses
it and actually um regenerates neuron
growth it's huge it's huge for people
with um CTE and NFL ERS with brain
damage right um people with Alzheimer's
people with postpartum depression people
with you know I mean it and we're just
scratching the surface no I mean then
that's the thing it's like it's it's
incredible like we still have so much to
learn y there's so much potential for it
and so what we do know is that it helps
people with addictions and it helps
people with um depression and that's the
main thing that we're dealing with in
the United States right now right so
well we live in a fear-based society and
I think a lot of religions are uh
founded around fear and uh unfortunately
right and so we live in this fear-based
society that you got to be AF you should
be afraid of stuff and you should be
Afra you know I think well D Western
Western religions Western religion yeah
for sure Western
religions um unfortunately yeah and so
and I don't think all of those religions
were founded and meant to be like that I
think that it evolved to be like that
over time mhm cuz it's a control
mechanism it's a control mechanism for
the masses right and the same with you
know government control over plant
medicine period yeah because they want
to push their own agenda right and so
they they ins still fear into people
fear for profit right 100% And so I've
made it my mission to create this safe
space where um I don't push an agenda I
don't push um a
Dogma um I'm not um pushing a specific
you know philosophy um it's a space
where people can come and find their own
spiritual path where they can find their
own um healing uh we just provide the
cleanest medicine for you to do that and
we also have Avenues if you're looking
for a therapist or if you're looking for
um a ceremony I I love the fact that
it's self exploration right at the end
of the day we all need to explore what
works for us because our body
chemistries are so uniquely different
and I feel like there's no one-sized
fits-all solution for any of our
problems because we're all so uniquely
different and it's beautiful if you can
go and start exploring what works for
you and find you know finding out what
doesn't work is a great way to find out
what works process of
elimination but with that you have to be
careful too extremely careful but that's
why you know having a guide or having
somebody who can help help show you the
way and you know I think micro do is now
a thing and when I was a kid there was
no micro do we used to eat e of
mushrooms pretty regularly yeah and
quarters of yeah the most it was a
quarter when I was a kid we didn't weigh
it we just picked them and made tea and
drank it or we just eat it right out out
Forest tea I I like tea the best though
for me personally I like the tea because
it doesn't mess up my stomach as much
whereas if certain types of mushrooms
really mess my stomach but I like
mushrooms for public speaking believe it
or not I think it's a great way you know
I've done micro do and I've done a
little bit more than micro do and I
learned that you know you got to tone it
back um I got a little religious at MJ
Biz one the time talking so well you
know I get really excited about stuff
but what I like about psychedelics is
specifically mushrooms for public
speaking is I don't have to use memory
recall uh that goes away and I start
talking from the heart where it just
flows and I'm able to get my point
across and I'm not really thinking or
trying to process what I should say next
I'm just saying it right it's like a
very clear stream of Consciousness where
it's not um disconnected it just kind of
flows well and then I feel like it comes
across as more authentic and so some of
these shows I take micro does some of
them I don't it just depends on the
individual show right so and I love that
and that's you know the self-exploration
side where I'm like exploring what works
for me and what doesn't and there's so
many compounds now before we had like
three or four right and now there's 50
yeah yeah so yeah it's we're in a
beautiful time we are I mean we really
are and I think um with the church and
allowing people to keep that control
within the individual is so important
it's it's sacred that you have your own
ability to choose your own path of
healing and the mode of and speed that
you want to do it yeah as is so
important um I don't really agree with
the
um the therapeutic like the the the
whole model of people sitting in a room
with eye masks on and a blanket and
holding the hand of a therapist um that
to me
is isolating and also borderline in
appropriate in my opinion um I I can't
think of a time in my personal
experience in therapist office where
anyone would ever touch you so I don't
see how that is appropriate especially
when someone's under the influence and
you've opened someone's mind completely
right if they're going to do it certain
ways and there has to be very strict
protocols and um unfortunately I think
they kind of failed on that aspect yeah
um they don't even do background checks
on people wow I spoke at a at a
conference and
they didn't even
know where you would look for somebody
that's like where you would look up
someone's name that was sex offender and
I'm like that's okay well and it's
because it's been gray area and it's not
accepted by the masses I mean it's
starting to be right I think there's
been you know it's Leaps and Bounds from
where it used to be you know and and
same thing with cannabis cannabis was
very much against the ma the majority of
people were against cannabis right and
now than 50% I think it's closer to 70%
now or Pro cannabis especially for
medical use and I think Dennis prone
said it's medical whether you believe in
it or not but I feel like psychedelics
are the same way like they can be
therapeutic and and medically beneficial
especially you know for your psyche
right right right just for your whole
feeling of connectedness to the world
and and Trauma right we have so as we
you know we talk about filters I talk
about this on my show quite often but
the filters that go over from every
experience you have you have a filter
that goes over your eyes and that's how
you see the world from the time you're
born you develop these filters and it's
great to take some of those filters off
and see the world how it really is again
right and that's almost the only way I
think there's you know meditation and
there's Buddhist monks were you know
they were able to tap in to their inner
DMT too right right right so but I think
that stuff it's it's amazing and I feel
like it's gaining momentum the fact that
it's decriminalized in several States or
places uh cities I guess more than
States but it's going in the right
direction oh it is absolutely I mean
when you have um articles in Vanity Fair
and you have mothers talking about
starting Market Rosen groups in the
midwest I mean you've kind of touched
the spots that really needed it's
spreading it's spreading really quickly
when people take it and they realize
that they're not going to be tripping
out that it's actually like um it's
almost like a what how I describe it is
like a natural volume yeah without the
fogginess without saying yes to
everything you're just calm and you're
in a place of Zen and you can navigate
the world from a place of just more um
grounded thinking and just
feeling yeah I think the awareness
aspect of it is so
amazing U because a lot of us aren't
aware and we're not living in the moment
either and I kind of feel like a lot of
us either live in the past or they live
in the future or both at different
moments in time and with psychedelics
you can really go into the moment
without even having to think about it
you're in the moment right you know
we're all in the moment all the time but
to put us there
mentally uh it's an amazing thing and
for a lot of people it's a big breath of
relief yeah yeah yeah and that's that's
that's kind of the the danger with it I
won't say danger but things that we need
to be cognizant of is that you shouldn't
be using psychedelics as just an escape
from your current sit current reality um
it should be used in a way that um opens
you up and so that when you do come back
to reality you have a better
understanding of it yeah and um I do see
some people in the community that use it
as a way of escape and um I don't
necessarily agree with that but at the
same time like I don't judge people and
I don't dictate how people use it right
um because everyone has their own path
yeah we all make mistakes and we
hopefully learn from them you know I
think that's the beauty of life too is
like making mistakes so you can learn
from them and the beauty of psychedelics
especially like mushrooms is it's a lot
safer than even cannabis to where you
can take a heavy dose and you can feel
pretty scared but you're going to be
okay yeah yeah and and there's no level
of addiction to it none um and once
you've done a heavy toast you know that
there's no level of addiction you know
it's like that's all you need is one
good heavy do yeah true during Co I was
with Marlon and we ate 16 grams of some
golden
teachers that's a lot I don't recommend
that and I don't recommend that to
anybody either and and Marlin is a yeah
he's a mushroom
connoisseur and we had maybe was over 16
Gams it might have been 17 or 18 but
either way it was it was a still it
still Beyond a heroic do yeah and it was
over a period of a good amount of time
and we were at like the worst ree show
that I felt so bad and he we started
eating mushrooms then we mov back to the
house and uh we hung out and we were
laughing so hard but we we put on TV and
the first thing that came on was UFC and
both of us looked at each other like no
we can't watch this this has to go and
so we were trying to like we were
probably spent like minutes trying to
find something to watch and I'm like
Disney has to have something that we can
watch and we stumbled on this show
called pickle and peanut and pickle and
peanut was designed and must have been
written by somebody who uses lots of
psychedelics Na weed definitely
psychedelics they incorporate animation
with like a live video of like animals
and people and and we laughed so hard we
probably laugh for four or five hours
straight I believe it where I would look
at him and I would start laughing and
then he would start laughing and then I
try to stop laughing but he was laughing
so I couldn't stop and both of us just
we were on the floor and literally my
stomach hurt and my cheeks hurt from
laughing so hard and then I had a
hangover the next day from it and you
can get hangovers from psychedelics from
from mushrooms if you eat too much you
have physical feelings of just like you
did a thousand crunches yeah like you
probably did you know in that same
notion you probably did equivalent to
so but those are good experiences
they're fun stories and yeah you know
and it's like it's not like alcohol you
drink too much alcohol you're in the
hospital you could die right right so
the worst thing that happens usually I
mean you see God and some aliens yeah
you see God and some aliens hopefully
you don't take your clothes off and run
naked through the streets but that I
don't find that to be the case with
mushrooms with most LSD LSD yeah
possibility I've seen it happen with
mushrooms once okay but usually it's the
LSD and I think it was a combination of
mushrooms at alcohol that maybe had you
know pushed somebody over the limit one
of my friends when we were younger yeah
but yeah there's always great stories
about people on psychedelics and yeah so
yeah I I just I think there're such an
amazing thing and I wish everybody had
the opportunity in their life to
experience them yeah so um I it's not
for everybody though you're right it's
not for everybody it's not um like if if
you
have been diagnosed with schizophrenia
or if your family like one of your
immediate family members has
schizophrenia yeah you should never do
psilocybin um because if you don't have
the symptoms of it and you do psilocybin
it could trigger that well I think
cannabis can also do that I'm not sure
about that but yeah I think cannabis so
yeah I mean there's there's a you know I
think there's something for everybody
and maybe it's not psychedelics for
everybody and maybe marijuana can't
cannabis isn't for everybody either
right but the fact is that there's only
a few people that can't do that I mean
yeah schizophrenia um
epilepsy and um high blood pressure
diabetes yeah and everyone that that
leaves a wide range of other people that
can do it and should yeah and people
that have had trauma it's a great way to
see if it can help with your trauma I
think it's you know yeah I agree I agree
under certain circumstances yes um
directly after a traumatic experience
probably not the best no I mean
childhood trauma it's good I think
childhood trauma is good and we all have
childhood trauma everybody does you
don't think you have childhood trauma
you're probably wrong yeah you do you
know there's very few people I know that
don't I mean I don't know anybody
actually that doesn't have some form of
childhood trauma right right right and
everyone's um idea of what is traumatic
is different so um I don't think you can
you can judge like oh your trauma wasn't
as as you know severe as mine whatever
it's all individual and I think that
soloc Simon is super healing on whatever
range of trauma it is yeah so do you
guys do any form of like me mesculin or
anything else like Cactus uh no we don't
um s Pedro those who we do have it from
time to time like we do have vendors
that come through that do have um cacti
plant medicine but um it's not something
that we regularly offer there yeah yeah
I'm a big fan of all of
it sounds like it yeah I mean I know my
stuff to a degree but I I just I enjoy
it and the thing is is when I saw the
legal pathway for uh
cybin coming down I I had friends that
are like you should breed cybin because
you know you can you can do breeding and
selection to a degree with cybin and I
said no thank you that's not my thing
that's my thing I'm I'm a cannabis guy
I've been fighting for cannabis my whole
life right and believing in the plant
and I believe that that's my plant uh
and I love being on the sidelines and
watching all my other friends win and
you know all seeing the trials and
tribulations going on because it's not
easy it's not as easy as people thought
in the beginning I saw a lot of people
dive in invest a lot of money lose a lot
of
money and I'm just excited being on the
sidelines and being able to try these
things so now there's like mushroom
gummies there was never mushroom gummies
growing up we had like maybe mushroom
chocolate somebody would make some
chocolates out of in there or they
ground up you know and but the level
of uh quality is just amazing how far
it's come and the different varieties of
stuff that you can get I mean I think
they have sprays now they have uh yeah
sublingual they have gummies they have
chocolate they have all kinds of stuff
and you name it they probably got it you
know as far as whatever you can think of
just like cannabis edals I haven't seen
a beverage yet but I bet it's either
coming or it's already there's a
beverage already yeah yeah yeah we have
a beverage at our at our location I know
where I'm coming
from it's a powder drink but yeah yeah
is it in the cap and then you we it
comes in two tubes and then you mix it
oh nice yeah really
cool yeah and I I love it because I feel
like eating mushrooms is it for
everybody because it's like cardboard
and sunflower seeds that's that's how I
describe eating Act ual dry mushrooms M
uh some of them taste shitty some of
them don't but like they shouldn't taste
shitty they
shouldn't some of them back in the when
I was a kid did there was actual on
it there was actual they were
pulled out of out of cow manure
specifically right right but yeah I
think that uh it's amazing because
people are more inclined to try stuff if
it's a gummy or if it's you know
something appealing
right cand taste good like they they do
not tast to very few people they're like
this I like the taste of it but
typically people are like I don't want
to go sit and eat a bunch of dried
mushrooms rather drink tea like if I was
going to do it that way and I feel like
tea is the one that hits you right away
it's the most effective in my opinion
but yeah there's the chocolates are good
too I like chocolate I think that the
interesting thing between now and 20
years ago for me with mushrooms
especially is I used to get stomach
aches from it and I had this thing where
I'd eat green M&amp;M's and so so
psychologically the green you know they
have very little actual chocolate in
M&amp;M's but psychologically they were very
helpful and uh yeah I really liked uh
green M&amp;M's with stuff now a lot of the
stuff doesn't give me the stomach aches
like it used to um and I think different
varieties too it's not the varieties
that give you the stomach ache and this
is something that is really missing from
the
Psychedelic uh education right now is
food safety huh food safety you should
never be getting sick on mushrooms you
should never be vomiting you should
never have diarrhea it's not iasa you're
not purging right so if you are getting
sick from
mushrooms it's because of food poisoning
so I heard some of the ones that like uh
the penis envies they they don't have
like they they're open caps and so they
don't have spores spores and so I heard
that the spores are actually what would
cause stomach like I never got like sick
to where I was thrown up typically but
it would give me that twisting in my
stomach and nobody wants to have that
feeling when they're feeling the effects
psychedelics so there's another reason
that it may be as well and there's a
very small subset of people that have an
aversion to kiten and kiten is a protein
that's in the mushroom it's also a
protein that's in the exoskeleton of
insects and some people find that hard
to digest wow and so you for those folks
tea is tea or extract is the only only
way that you're going to be able to do
it without getting a stomach ache um but
it's a very small percentage that have
that aversion it's possible that you
have that totally possible but all the
stuff today does none of it gives me
stomach aches then it was food poisoning
100% probably food poisoning 100% when
people come to me and they're like oh
man I took this I ate this chocolate bar
and I was vomiting and oh I had the runs
I'm like that's because you ate a really
disgusting chocolate that was not made
properly y um people handle mushrooms if
you see people handling mushrooms with
their hands after handling money after
it falling on the floor it's not weed
we're not putting it in a pipe and
burning it you're eating it would you
eat french fries that fell on the floor
no why would you eat mushrooms that fell
on the floor it's the same thing like
then food safety still in for I used to
be Chef as well right so I I think food
safety is so important and a lot of
people look past it and a lot of the
early mushroom things were made by
people in their houses yeah yeah or
wherever yeah hotel rooms whatever not
sanitary not sanitary not thinking about
no Health Department no not thinking
about like how you handle the mushrooms
you know you put them in a bag and it's
rolling around with manure in there and
then you take it home and you eat it
like yeah you just ate manure like yeah
would you you with hand no and
that's another thing is like I I see a
lot of people posting photos of
mushrooms dried and they're covered with
brown on the bottom yeah and I'm just
like that is unnecessary unnecessary and
it just took day age anyway no I mean
and the knowledge is there it's just
laziness well I think yeah I mean really
what they should be doing is cutting off
the tops baging those and then
extracting what's left in the subst we
cutting it before you dehydrate it it's
one step it's one step but but people
are think thinking too far ahead with um
oh I don't want to lose weight yeah
they're worried with their yields so
they leave it on there and they think oh
I'll brush it after it's dehydrated
right number one it's super timec
consuming to do that and the amount of
substrate that you leave on it is
negligible yeah so just cut it and
dehydrate it like it doesn't have to be
so dirty it's so dirty yeah it's gross
it's so gross and then for the um the
people who don't know and are consuming
it they're like Oh I thought the brown
stuff was supposed to be there I'm like
no no no I'm like would you take would
you take a salt shaker yeah and and put
that all into a little salt shaker and
sprinkle it on your eggs and eat it no
probably not so then don't eat it off
the bottom of a mushroom yeah it's it's
interesting the world and this is
because we're just in the infancy of
legalization I think a lot yeah you look
at where cannabis is now especially with
packaging and with safety standards in
wreck right and I'm not saying it's
perfect but it's you it's safer than any
other egg product actually it's tested
heavier uh in some ways that's
unfortunate in other ways it's great do
you feel like it's fail proof do you
think stuff slips through the cracks
absolutely stuff slips through the
cracks and you can spray stuff that is
not necessarily good uh right even
though it's omry listed does not
necessarily mean it's good especially if
you spray at the end and yeah you might
be able to pass testing but that doesn't
mean you're creating a product that's
still good for people to consume just
because it's omy listed right and I
think people need to get out of that
mindset you know and I think there's a
lot of preventative stuff people can do
especially with cannabis that so they
don't have to spray or they have to
spray in a very minimum amount and you
know the less you spray especially if
you're making extract from it the less
you spray the better uh so but we we do
have a safe product I think that the
product and I think a lot of people that
were using things like Avid most of
those people are gone they don't have
businesses anymore they're I'm not
familiar with it at all I grew in 96 to
06 and then I got out so all this new
stuff like I'm just getting
re-educated yeah so there's all kinds of
stuff that you can spray to you know
it's like spraying Roundup on your
plants yeah nasty yeah so but you know
you can't spray round up on
cannabis thank God you can't put it on
mushroom
no no no there's not a lot that you can
do because you have to grow in a sterile
environment right so technically you're
growing in a sterile environment you
should have a sterile product it doesn't
always happen that way no and then you
get contamination oh everyone gets
contamination you growing mushrooms
you're never going to not have
contamination at some point yeah because
all it takes is one molecule of mold mhm
and the whole thing's ruined and I think
a lot of the cannabis FKS that switched
over to mushrooms thought it was going
to be so super easy absolutely and it's
like no no it's actually much more
complicated yeah and it's labor
intensive believe it or not it's super
labor intensive um making the grain
harvesting all of it well there's now
there's shops you can buy the grain you
can buy whatever substrate you want
there's multiple types of substrate you
can buy them it gets costly if you're
doing it on a regular basis though I bet
I bet it gets I mean and the thing is is
the price of mushrooms
since uh decriminalization has changed a
lot oh yeah it's gone down way down the
market got flooded just like cannabis
but I also see like a lot of these
commercial varieties and strains of
mushrooms uhuh and I think that I'm very
particular on what I like uhuh uh
especially if I'm making te's I I like
specifically golden teachers in larger
amounts because I always feel so good
but like the penis mvy is not my cup of
tea not M but it's a very yeah there's a
few there's like some turkey uh these
these big giant ones and it's like
they're they're made for yield and I
think they're made for commercial
production uhuh and they're as far as
like I'm all about effect with mushrooms
at the end of the day it's for me it's
all about effect how does it make me
feel does it make me feel better do I
feel clear do I feel introverted right
because sometimes I'll feel introverted
and not social at all and I want to be
alone and not want to talk to people or
like I can't talk to people do you want
to talk to me and I can't like talk
you've taken too much taken too much or
taking the right amount and you're in
the wrong environment exactly that too
that too um there are so many varieties
of mushrooms um psilocybin uh there used
to be believed that a cube is a cube is
a cube like no matter what it is it's
all just going to give you the same
experience and that's just not the case
no um what I've noticed is that there
are some that are that don't give you
visuals just mod high and you just feel
like Zen just calm right and then there
are other ones that are hyper Visual and
um not social so it's more for like
somebody that's trying to do meditation
and then like penis envy is like natural
LSD it's not for everybody no it's like
uh it's 5x strengthwise three three two
to three yeah yeah I feel like for
Golden teachers it's like a 5x oh yeah
no golden teachers is like it's like the
beginners like the training wheel but I
just love so for me it's like I like I
like uh Tai cenzi those are great too I
I like those a lot but the golden
teachers just always make me feel good
right so like I I go back to that a lot
of times because I love the good feeling
and I think the penis EnV is like you
know even though 0.1 micro do doesn't
feel like a micro do it's not it's
genuinely not yeah I I I find it hard to
believe when people are like I'm going
to micro do on penis ENB I'm like that's
just very rare yeah um we have some
gummies from micel Oakland and they were
like oh there's 250 milligrams in each
gummy I was like okay I took one and it
was the beginning of a journey I was
like that's not a micro do no that's not
a micro do no and it's like a gram so
like a gram of penis envy feels like an
eighth of a lot of other mushrooms yes
and an eighth of penis envy feels like
the craziest hero You' been taken no
that's like 9 to 12 grams of a regular
one yeah I had one guy come to me and I
warned him I warned him I said don't
take more than a gram start there always
start small because you can always take
more you can't take less you can
staircase it but just feel it out his
friends were like no she's just she's
pumping you up like take the whole thing
like it's just like any other mushroom
yeah he took the whole 3.5 grams little
get and sat on the couch and they said
the only thing he could say for hours
was the entities the entities that
identities and I'm like well yeah of
course yeah that's that's a lot so he
came back and told me about it and he
said you know it was honestly the most
beautiful experience in my life but
it'll be a while before I do my shs
again I was like I don't blame you yeah
I don't blame you at that level well and
so I call it the full melt experience
where like you get it from DMT actually
the first time I had it was from nitrous
oxide which is very different you know
I've had I've gone down different paths
than a lot of people very different U I
was so in Oakland off 8 there's a
Pottery Shop everybody knows the Pottery
Shop well there was a rave back in maybe
90 something uhhuh and someone had a
tank in the VIP room and my friend was
the one throwing in the party and so I
got a big punching ball thing of nitrous
and there was a big like uh bean bag
chair and I decided to go I was like
that looks like a big perfect chair to
go sit and suck on this balloon and I'm
not a big nous guy now or anything but I
I did it then and I got this full melt
experience and I don't know how long I
was gone just like very DMT very DMT
like don't know how long I was gone I
came back tried to gather all my friends
around because I want to explain
everything because I understood
everything and the second I tried to
start putting it into words I you you
can't
verbalize where you go or what happened
but at the end all I could say is we're
all going to be okay and that's stuck
with me through life and that's like one
of those life-changing things where it's
like we're all going to be okay no
matter what whatever happens here
whatever happens to us on this plane
we're all going to be okay and that was
my big takeaway and I'm lucky I got that
at a very young age because I've always
felt like you know I've been a up
part of my life and I've done stupid
stuff and I've done a lot of great stuff
but the one takeaway is that we're all
going to be okay yeah yeah and if
everybody felt that way how much better
could the world be it's just I it's it's
it's a different mindset you know I
think I felt that in Cuba when I was
there m times that it was um a feeling
of just living day by day y because you
didn't have any worries about where your
food's coming from where you're you know
it's just very by the day right I've
never experienced that anywhere else
Barcelona is the same way Florence is
too I believe it I believe it yeah my
parents were in Florence this last
couple months ago it's cra
every place in the world there's like
something I I know I want to try
foodwise like the Roman Pizza that's
Square oh those're so good yeah they are
so good I like Detroit pizza so I'm like
Roman Pizza you know and I've had it's
so good yeah it's delicious and the
ingredients they use are just well the
bread in Europe is so different I feel
like it agrees with my stomach more like
that's another one I I don't the the the
grain here doesn't agree with me like
over in Europe I'm fine but but not here
same with the tomatoes for me yeah I had
acid reflux so bad couldn't eat tomato
sauce go to Italy I can eat tomato sauce
every day no problems yeah I yeah they
use a lot of tomatoes in Italy so and
tomatoes are great I I love tomatoes
they do even I like growing my own
Tomatoes it's one of my favorite things
to grow besides cannabis right
interesting yeah well they and they grow
similar in a lot of ways that's what we
used to tell the the hydro stores we
were growing totally we had to come talk
about tomatoes tomatoes and they'd be
like tomatoes right Berkeley in our
garden you could not go in there to talk
it to somebody unless you talked about
tomatoes and vegetables you could not
you had to be in code in the 90s it was
like such a big deal and uh you'd get
it'd be funny because you'd be in the
store and then every once in a while
someone would come in and they'd slip
yeah and you'd have angry people working
at the place that wouldn't want to talk
to you get out of here get out of here
yeah we don't talk to people like that
blah blah blah and it's like oh my God
100% there was a I can't remember the
name of the gr shop in North Hollywood
but they would get so mad the old guys
back there yeah don't say that grown
tomatoes like okay I got you got you
right and then um All Seasons opened up
in uh
Chatsworth and those guys are still
around I mean they were my go-to they
they're amazing yeah we didn't have to
talk about it we all know what was going
on you justed have to go in a black
hoodie park down the street so that your
licensed place wouldn't get photographed
by law enforcement but with their the uh
their binoculars recording everyone's
license PLS back in the day it was funny
yeah we were so separated from that
world and I think there's a lot of
people that are involved with
today's cannabis economy that have no
idea really what went on no uh and how
illegal it was for for even small
amounts for a six lighter you could get
in big trouble and I mean I just had one
I had one light but I grew 100 to 200
colas wow sea green sea of green real
small Forest you basically would flip
right when you got the Clones yeah did
you go I well I Grew From seed so I got
seeds from markam and then had mothers
because it was really difficult to get
seeds back then yeah so we had to get
them from Canada sometimes they would
make it and sometimes they wouldn't yeah
so then I had mothers always in the
Times magazine you got his number from
there and then oh yeah yeah this is
before email even this is before email
yeah like you had to send an SAE yeah
yeah crazy yeah it's so funny s yeah s
yeah Strange World you know it's like
people they like before email how would
you communicate it's like well there was
addresses you could if you didn't have a
phone number you could write someone a
letter you you get the phone book The
Yellow Pages are Yellow Pages what's
that it's a book that had all
everybody's phone number that and now I
don't even know what the Yellow Pages
look like I mean everything is on I do
know what it looks like it's
yellowpages.com it is so yeah save some
paper it's funny it's funny yeah it was
it was a scary great time growing in the
9s especially in La I lived in um San
Fernando Valley and I grew in apartment
buildings like one or two bedrooms just
blow them out and slept in the living
room did they have carbon filters back
then MH yeah they had like I think they
just come out yeah they had just come
out in the 90s I mean I remember when
they first came out and they didn't
really work all that well in my garage
they didn't work that well back then
either the whole apartment complex
smelled like weed multiple people were
growing
no just you just me but I kept my day
job right you know I was a nanny or I
was working at the preschool and my ex
was in construction so we didn't drive
flashy cars right you blame it on the
weird neighbor you're like just them no
no but nobody knew it was us yeah
because we would come and go tot not fit
the profile no no and they're like maybe
it's the Russians oh maybe it's kids
down there maybe C is on the top flooor
yeah like never assumed that it was us I
mean serbs definitely the serbs yeah I
mean it's so crazy how people but it was
dangerous it was absolutely dangerous
and nobody would dare call the police or
anything because the only people that
were really growing were people that
were really ready to die for it yeah and
so it was super dangerous I mean there
was a time where um one of the gangs
found out that we were growing and
luckily we were on the other side of the
street so our ZIP code was not in their
territory yeah but we had to stay up
every night with a loaded 45 wow waiting
to get executed by some gang that may
come through the door right and that's
when you realize like over a on lighter
yeah over over over a one lighter yeah I
had a one I had a Phototron that was my
first indoor was with a
Phototron from from High Times magazine
that were in the back of High Times High
Times magazine was really cool I mean
that
was where I got my inspiration from as a
kid
uh at a very young age probably too
young for some some parents to want
their kids to be into that kind of stuff
but uh I think there was worse things to
inspire to do oh gosh we we're the
generation of um Faces of Death BHS
going around you know what I mean like
there's so much stuff that was worse
Faces of Death and there was the bum
fights oh my god I've been accused of oh
this is a funny this is a funny rumor
there's been not about bum fight
shouldn't laugh because me either I it's
ter hor but but there so there's been
funny rumors that have been spread about
me over the years right so one of the
rumors was I got my money from bumfights
that I was the original investor in
bumfights that's not true guys oh my God
and uh so but but it's funny hearing
these rumors and then people were like
oh yeah I remember hearing that about
you and it's like had nothing to do with
bum fights whatsoever and whoever came
up with that is super creative I think
it's funny but you know but not true at
all so there's always rumors about
people and it's like oh yeah oh yeah
yeah yeah people told a rer that I in
high school that I died at one point and
it was only because I'd gone off the
radar and I was living in La growing
weed yeah they thought I they said that
I got run over by a train I was like oh
that's great yeah no I'm still alive
yeah I had a friend that I thought he
died in Desert Storm and for 20 years I
thought he was dead and then he appeared
on Facebook I'm like well he's not
dead so yeah I used to party his house
all the time I can't believe it like I'd
been feeling bad about this guy like you
know not to laugh or anything again but
like it's funny how rumors happen and
then social media exacerbates social
media is so gross I mean the level of
egos that we get out of the Cannabis
industry over a couple tens of thousands
of followers is just wild to me it's
just it's wild yeah I mean let's spend a
lot of our I I just posted the other day
but let's spend a lot of our time every
day arguing with people we know about
stuff that doesn't even matter yeah you
know and that's pretty much what it is I
mean the thing is it's the most amazing
beautiful and disgusting thing all at
the same time and it's really how you
use it and I feel like it can be used
it's a tool just like anything else but
it can be abused it can be used
incorrectly and it can it can basically
feed your ego and make you think that
you're whatever yeah God or whatever
think you're different than who you
really are and sometimes we just need to
be grounded and realize that we're all
you know one guy I told them that we're
all equal we're all the same and that
that's in my opinion we're all equal and
I don't care who you are and he said
well that that's like giving
participation Awards and I'm like that's
not what I mean it's very different you
know I mean I mean we're all equal on a
spiritual level we're all equal on a
physical level I mean you can talk
about uh you know as far as like
participation Awards being a bad thing
and I think they are I think that we
live in this world where participation
Awards but as far as us being equal men
and women being equal
it doesn't matter what race what color
what sex any of that stuff I mean I
think that we are we should all be
treated equal we all have a right to be
here we were all born here we didn't
have a choice nobody better than anybody
and so I think that's a big problem is a
lot of people start thinking they're
better well I'm a better grower or I'm a
better this right but it's it's all
subjective and none of that stuff really
matters it's at the same time it doesn't
I better than anybody and nobody's
better than me and as long as you can go
and that's something my father really
instilled from a young age is you're not
better than anybody right but also
nobody's better than you right and so
the more you can think like that and I
think we we want to strive to be better
we want to strive to be better than
ourselves not better than other people
and I think that's where it gets lost
right is like even though you're
competing in whatever you're competing
really you're just competing against
yourself even if you're on a team you're
just trying to do the best you can do to
be a better person every day so
hopefully over time you become a lot
better there needs to be a lot of
humbling in the Cannabis Community
psychedelics will do that psychedelics
will do that I hope they do more
mushrooms um the last like year and a
half like with being a fly on thewall
and doing some networking in the
Cannabis industry I was really kind of
appalled um the level of
misogyny um just the bullying the online
bullying the online bullying is silly do
it's ridiculous or this isn't Middle
School guys no but but the the thing is
is so I mean I try to look at it from
the outside right because there is a lot
of bullying there's people that try to
bully me around and it's like I'm a big
guy like in the real world you'd never
bully me but you want to try to do it
online go ahead right but the thing is
is like I understand that those people
have trauma that they've gone through
most of those people were probably
bullied when they were in school and so
now they're online and they're like I'm
gonna get this guy but it doesn't really
matter yeah I care I'm not the stuff
doesn't affect me I I think that
sometimes it does actually to be honest
sometimes it bothers me a little bit
well we're human yeah we're human but I
just I try to be grateful for all I have
I think that I I try to live in
gratitude and I think that's so
important is living in gratitude to be
grateful for what you have and not worry
about what you don't have as much right
you know I think we can strive to be
better or we can strive to do amazing
things uh and there's nothing Out Of
Reach if we want it but we really have
to be grateful for what we have because
we don't know how long we're going to be
here and we don't
know how long we have to do all these
great things it's all this stuff is
finite right and so and psychedelics
kind of really have opened me up to that
to where I realize that like we have a
limited time to do great things we have
a limited time to tell the people that
we care about that we love them you know
little things like that yeah but those
are the beautiful things in life when
you can be grateful for what you have
and and wake up and go this is
pretty great and it could all be gone in
the heartbeat but right now it's amazing
yeah yeah I if people would spend more
time um focused on their own projects
yeah and pushing out the best that they
can with their own projects instead of
um creating unnecessary drama and being
worried about other people working
together working together is a
collaborative you know effort in the
community they would get so much further
as opposed to just this race to the
bottom well that's the future right so
there will be the in the Cannabis uh
scene especially there is the race to
the bottom but along that line where we
have this race to the bottom where it's
going down we have collaboration coming
in right and so the ones who collaborate
are going to be successful and it takes
a but but it also it's just the next
Evolution because when we were growers
in the 9s and in the early 2000s we had
to do everything you were an electrician
you were a carpenter
you made extract a lot like I made
extract I did Growing I did a I did
trimming I did it all well then you
start getting into a more advanced uh
situation where okay well I can just
focus on this and then I can have an
extractor and I can have trimmers and I
can all these things over time change
and evolve right and so I just feel like
the next evolution is going to be
collaboration especially because you can
work within a network of good people and
whether it's companies finding those
good people it is but if you're in the
industry long enough you start finding
people that you can attach yourself to
that have a good reputation that do good
work because although I feel like we've
weeded all the bad people out that's
never the case there's always going to
be bad people that somehow are able to
get in right right I feel like I weeded
most of them out a long time ago but
still we get Snakes in the Grass coming
in posing is something else and then you
realize oh man that person isn't who you
perceive them to be yeah a lot of what
we see in this reality is just
perception oh yeah 100% so it's not
always reality it's not it's not because
what you perceive is an individual
experience it's not a shared experience
it's not a shared reality and once
people realize that then you start to
share your perceptions and you can come
to an understanding and you communicate
then you can share your different
perceptions and come together in
community that way and Community is so
powerful it really genuinely is um and
I've been blessed to find a lot of
really great people in the Cannabis
industry people that are passionate
about the plant people that want to push
it forward in a positive way for the
right reasons for the right reasons like
the regenerative Farmers Guild event
that we're doing on June TW 22nd um it's
going to be a monthly event and we're
pulling the best Farmers from the
mountain that are just about the plant
about preserving the plant about pushing
the best genetics forward about you know
creating a future
for their children for themselves and
for people around them right and that's
important it's not about an ego it's not
about um I did this or that or the other
thing like right what what does that
matter 10 years from now 20 years from
now 30 years from now like who cares
yeah there are 8 billion people in this
world how many people know you by name
like you're insignificant in the grand
scheme of things yeah but as a
collective effort as a collective
Consciousness that's the beauty of all
of this is the collective Consciousness
cuz we all just play a role in the
greater Collective consciousness of
existence is how I feel um from what
I've seen and what I've experienced and
that's the beauty of it if we can get
rid of ego and realize that we're all
just a part of something so much bigger
than ourselves that we can't even fully
comprehend it's amazing it really is it
really is I think when people grasp that
and fully um you know delve into that
experience um it humbles people and when
you get humbled on that level then you
start to see that you have a lot of work
to do within yourself yeah and once you
start working on yourself then you can
help other people yeah and it's never
over I feel like it's a it's something
you strive for and it's something that
you have to work out on a daily basis
100% because the second you feel like
you know it all you're so far away from
any sort of like understanding of it I'm
scared of people who say they know
everything yeah I have yeah I have
friends that think they know everything
too and it's like but they need more
psychedelics for one thing they need
more psychedelics and they need to read
more yeah but it's like no no one person
can understand all of it no you can't be
good at everything but if you work hard
at one thing you can be really good at
that you can be a master oh you can be a
master absolutely and and it doesn't
take Natural Born skill always a lot of
times repetition is what's going to make
you successful showing up for yourself
yeah yeah the consistency repetition the
practice I mean and that's what I
learned as a child my mom's Korean so
talk about piano lessons violin lessons
like yeah repetition repetition every
day every day to get better and better
um and that's with anything and that's
what life's all about yeah 100% so tell
me more about the church so I founded
this church to create a safe space and a
Haven for plant medicine and under that
umbrella it it um includes
um
psilocybin DMT cacti outside of
peyote and cannabis people use these
products to or sacraments to heal
themselves um for Spiritual
purposes and um my goal is to have the
cleanest plant medicine available to
people so that they can find that path
wow and um
ultimately um I would like to be able to
get to a position where we can subsidize
medicine for people in the streets of
Oakland to help them get off opioids and
methamp fetamines and hard drugs in the
street so that they can you know reverse
their lives back to you know a path that
is um one that they got derailed from
well most of the psychedelics are still
a schedule one
yes but I think that's going to change I
think so I think so I especially
mushrooms Sol side specifically cin
because um the VA is working with um
Veterans for PTSD for PTSD um you have
people in the pharmaceutical industry
that are working on it um you have
Academia that's working on it so um
there's a lot of research that's going
into it that is behind it right so it's
not just a party drug it's it's a
healing mechanism for a lot of people so
with the church do you guys have uh
Church sessions throughout the week is
there a different I mean I I you were
telling me about an event that's going
on on the 22nd right so we have the
regenerative Farmers Guild coming yeah
um we have 30 Farmers that are coming
down from Humble and mesino to share uh
seeds clones uh flow and um education so
loud speakers uh Tim Blake is coming to
speak nice um we have some hash makers
that are joining as well um to talk
about the benefits of hash
and um educate people on the different
qualities but mainly like we support
plant medicine in all different
communities uh I have a woman who comes
to do um uh 5 Meo ceremony so um that
and we have uh neuroscientists and
psychiatrists and psychologists that
come through to do integration and they
teach people how to take the medicine on
a micro do and ated into their lives and
talk about like the the science behind
it so when you're talking 5 Meo for
people that aren't familiar that are
watching the podcast and they're hearing
it for the first time are we talking
about
buffo uh toad Venom yes specifically yes
and so she's a spiritual healer she's a
ceremony holder um she has extensive
experience in that so that's I I'm not a
spiritual healer so I pass that off to
people who have the expertise in that
but the San Pedro that's a great one it
is yeah that's that's another one that
will get your stomach
turning so we have a guy who's who's a
cacti expert who comes through and does
vending and and he wants to do a class
on grafting and talk about um extraction
and all the benefits of it as well wow
that's really cool yeah and the funny
thing is San Pedra is one of those ones
where you see it growing random in
Berkeley and Oakland you know like
driving by people's houses there's these
big San Pedro cactus so all over the US
it's get in at Home Depot yeah so it's
very common yeah yeah so yeah people
don't even know they have it going and
oh they got that magic grown right in
their front yard right it was just a
cool looking plant
yeah yeah it's it's really beautiful I
mean Cactus just in general is
amazing yeah I mean our main focus is
mushrooms just because that's where my
is right we do provide genetics and grow
kits and teach people how to grow their
own medicine because it's not just about
being a dispensary model you know we're
more of like a community space where we
give education and we want people to be
able to do it on their own so if someone
wants to come to church on
Sunday um we all have events typically
is it every day or you guys not every
day we have like two or three days a
week we have events um we do have an
event called um dabs and doodles which
is we we open up the doors for free to
Street artists graffiti artists they
come and share hash and we'll have a
couple vendors and it's just a very
chill environment those graffiti artists
those writers all like smoking hash yes
it seems not all of them because we had
The Luminaries and only one out of the
three guys actually smoked but the ones
I know a lot of them like hash they like
hash they like mushrooms Ros and and
mushrooms St yeah we just had an event
with um the Lord's crew and so they
painted the auxiliary building we did an
art show so we do a lot of things that
are um Community Based right right and
so church is counter cultur Community
Based gota love it yes just getting the
the message of what mushrooms do out
there in maybe a less than Orthodox way
but um I don't focus on just one subset
of people but this isn't just for the
one % that can afford like a
$155,000 ceremony this is this is for
everybody and we're losing people in all
communities well it's sad that it's been
commercialized right that at least
that's my feeling is that part of part
of it is sad that it's been
commercialized to where people feel they
have to go away for the healing and and
maybe there is benefit to that and I
think it's great right but uh you know I
think burning man has kind of changed
too over the years I went a long long
time ago and it was completely different
not that there's anything wrong I don't
know because I haven't gone but I see
people flying in Jets and helicopters
like especially helicopters and it's
like that was never a thing 20 years ago
right uh and then iasa ceremonies were
probably you know your your flight
that's all you pretty much had to pay
for because everything else was so
inexpensive and now it's a commercial
business and so they've commercialized
the
healing and not that there's anything
wrong with Comm izing stuff but I feel
like you take away part of the magic too
with it and and it it makes it so that
only very few people have access to it
and then you take away access and that's
where you lose the
magic because it's for everybody it is
for everybody and that's why I think
it's awesome that uh Oregon
decriminalized Statewide I don't think I
heard reversing that by the way I I bet
they are I bet they are I think it's
crazy that they did did that to be I
think it's great that they did it in
some ways but meth being able to possess
drugs like meth or even small amounts
like I think th those things need to be
off the streets personally no 100% it
there's I don't see any value in meth
heroin fentanyl F there's no value in
and it it takes away from society it
doesn't help people it destroys
lives uh it's not positive no it's not
it's not and soloc cybin is proven to
help reverse that crisis I think it
makes the world a better place to be
honest yeah um I think there's a handful
cannabis makes the world a better place
that's why I'm doing what I do that's
what I love about it is it it makes the
world a better place and there's things
that contribute to making Society better
and there's things that take away from
it right and I think that these hard
drugs uh they take away from it and you
know the fact that Oregon just went
across the bort and said we're going to
do everything for possession is okay I
think that's a little crazy I think we
need c like I don't know about putting
people in jail that are that are addicts
I think maybe that's not the solution
but I treatment therapy and treatment
and uh Solutions we need solutions for
those people Homeless Solutions I think
one of the biggest problems is our
homeless problem right solving that I
don't know what the answer is because
everybody's like oh it's a bad thing and
it's like what's the solution I think
it's so complicated that there's not
just one answer it's it's over a long
period of time it took us a long time to
get to this point where we have tents in
Oakland on on Bridges there's
communities of homeless people it took
us a long time to get to this point uh
my parents were friends with a guy who
basically starved himself to make a
point for for months and months and
months to bring attention to the fact
that we weren't taking care it was all
mentally ill people the majority of
people that are homeless are mentally
ill and I would say that that's still
the case case but it's not all the case
I mean it's California it's it's a rough
time out there it's expensive and we
don't have enough Solutions and you know
there's a lot of countries that have
solutions for homeless you were talking
about Cuba yeah you know you don't see
homeless people in Cuba uh Scandinavian
countries you know they have solutions
for these things and they're thought of
because the government cares about their
people I'd like to think that people in
our government care about people but as
a whole it's it's tough it's tough to
look at our government saying that they
care about people people and then you
see people homeless in Oakland and San
Francisco and I do think there's
politicians that care I honestly do
think there are good politicians and bad
politicians and it's not just bad across
the board but it's perception I mean
when you're going down the street in
Oakland it's hard to think good about
anybody uh that has any sort of say on
anything when there's people living in
tents and communities and there's people
getting robbed and beaten and killed in
Oakland in the streets and Oakland's the
worst it's ever been that I that I
remember at least in my lifetime as an
adult it's it's honestly the roughest
it's ever been yeah I I volunteered for
two years with um punks with lunch which
is a nonprofit that my friend Alandra
started um almost eight years ago nice
and every Sunday we would go out and do
harm reduction um meals and clothing and
hygiene and um two years it it took a
toll on me uh when you when it started
when I started volunteering um it was at
the beginning of gentrification in West
Oakland so in the beginning you would
just see mostly people addicted to drugs
mental health issues
runaways uh kids that got misplaced
after the foster care system let them go
um and then over those two years you
started seeing families you started
seeing like working parents with kids
living in tents because they got evicted
um it's the economy that's that's the
that's the Catalyst to all of this um
the lack of Health Care the lack of
Education the lack of um just living
just a a living wage nobody can live off
of $15 an hour in Oakland or no in 15
isn't worth what 15 was before no you
know you look you look at the the value
of the dollar is depreciated so much
over the period it's not houses are more
I mean they're more expensive right but
it's not like they're worth more no it's
because the value of the dollar is much
less yeah and we haven't matched the
salaries because you used to be able to
be a janitor the 50s and 60s and you
could still earn a living wage and buy a
house off of that salary right and it's
it's just changed so much and I like to
think that it's getting better but I
feel like it's still going to get worse
before it gets better yeah I think um
the economy has to change first and um
we need to provide basic services for
people well and I feel like the economy
goes up and down no matter what we're
going to have a better economy and then
we're going to have a worse economy and
that's just going to fluctuate
throughout time I just there's not
enough awareness of reality and what
happened over the last 20 years is the
middle class has gone away yeah and so
we look at where we're at right now and
you're on one spectrum of the other
there's not a lot of people that are
just happily living in the middle you're
either pushed towards the upper or
you're pushed towards the lower and it's
a big struggle it's a big struggle for a
lot of people I mean you can't blame
people for robbing and stealing when
they can't provide for their families
off of a basic wage like what would you
do well I think there's opportunist
there there's a difference though right
so there's there I see the if if you're
stealing CU you're hungry and you're
stealing food uh that's very different
than if you're an opportunist and you're
going with your friends to Rob Nordstrom
and steal as much clothes as you can so
you can steal them off the streets or
you're breaking into people's cars you
know it's just so there's very for me
it's like I there's a separation here
like the opportunist I I think those
people are not doing the right thing and
if my family was starving I would do
whatever it took to feed them and I
think that's a very different situation
and I think it it depends it's not a one
siiz fits also and that's why it's so
hard to deal with it's like well what's
the solution well it's not one thing
there's so many steps and so many things
that have to happen over time right I
mean even when I was volunteering like
trying to think of like what's the
solution yeah it's daunting like where
do you begin yeah where do you even
began it's it starts with people just
helping each other in the streets yeah
it starts with people who have to start
chch was compassion yeah totally I agree
compassion and empathy and just
understanding that it's very Poss POS
for you to end up in their shoes it
doesn't take that much no you know it
really doesn't and when people get that
into perspective and you start
humanizing the people on the street as
opposed to seeing them as throwaway
people and understanding that they are
people's family they are people's loved
ones and start to treat them that way
yeah then it changes it changes
yeah yeah I mean that's I guess that's
the beauty of living in Oakland is the
exposure too I mean puts the world into
perspective unfortunately and I don't
know what what's going to happen I I
really all I know is that uh the one
thing Coston is change uhuh and so if
it's not going to stay the same no
matter what we're changing and evolving
people thought I was going to be easy
money in the Cannabis industry forever
they thought it was easy money in the
mushroom PCT they thought it was going
to be easy money and it was for the
people in the beginning there was some
people that crushed it but that was a
very short window and I would say the
real reason why I wasn't excited to get
into mushrooms is because I realized
like when I take mushrooms I don't want
if I take a big dose I don't want to
take it for a long time I smoke weed
every day right right I I'll puff on
some when I go home my smoke and wear as
mushrooms I do selectively and over the
period of the last 33 years uh I've done
it in waves throughout my life right
it's never been a constant even when I
did the micro doing and so it has a
ceiling to it whereas cannabis can at
least keep grow there's definitely a
ceiling to to the amount of mushrooms I
mean we still haven't reached that
ceiling it's going to be a long time
before we reach it but there is a
ceiling and it's because of awareness
like the more people that are aware of
it the more people that will try it and
benefit from it yeah and when you tap
into um what those you know outcomes are
as far as like PTSD and um brain trauma
and those you know physical things that
are going on in your brain and knowing
that the medicine really helps you in
that way
getting that word out to more and more
people I mean there 273 275 million
people in the world or in the US in the
US um 2 I think it's 273 last time I
checked but it's been a it's been a
little minute I think it's 350 million
is it really now I'm not sure we'll
we'll uh check that one we'll fact check
that one we'll fact check that one
totally but that's a lot of people it's
a lot of people that's a lot of people
who would take mushrooms and not take
and not swep weed right you know because
if you're take it like a vitamin medic
for medicine yeah as a vitamin I mean I
think that but also cannabis we we're
still exploring the use for that so I
think plant medicine is we're just
scratching the surface of it and we're
going back you know and this
is a long time coming yeah and and I
think it's going to go back to a lot of
plant-based medicine we're going to look
at stuff and go this is actually better
and more suitable and has less side
effects way less dangerous right and you
know I think it'll be custom tailored
too just we we know of all these canono
and we know of all these tpin and we're
talking about flavorants and other
things and how they work with the
Entourage effect together and so we're
just scratching the surface on how do we
apply this medicine and there the best
part of changing the scheduling to
schedule three is now we can do more
research and so once they go from
schedule one with siloc cybin to
schedule two or three or four or
whatever they change it to will be bble
to do even more research and clinical
trials and that's where they start
finding the magic that's where they
start finding okay well this works great
for this and now we've solved the
problem my fear with that though is that
pharmaceutical companies will take over
and control it all I agree it I mean
it's but I try not to live in fear right
so so my biggest thing is like because
I'm always scared of that with the
Cannabis industry that I know what's
coming I see what's coming I see what's
coming with plant patents I see what's
coming with uh pharmaceutical standards
and not just GMP but like ISO standards
and stuff like that they especially when
we're talking about labs and stuff like
that uh but but even just standard uh
GMP
process uh most people aren't ready for
it right and so there will be people
that lose but there it's still an
Agricultural Product and there's still
going to have Farmers farming and I
think that the ones that are in now I
feel like they we had uh Ridgeline farms
and we had Huckleberry Hill Farms and
those guys are great examples of two of
the several companies that I see moving
into the market in the future and
expanding and once interstate commerce
goes they can start growing and sharing
their product with people all around the
United States because we're so limited
with wreck in that regard and that's
going to change and that excites me yeah
and so even though there is like a
little bit of fear of the pharmaceutical
takeover and that's going to impact us
I'm not as worried about that when I see
guys like Johnny from Huckleberry Hill
Farm who has a a cult ofar that makes
you feel absolutely
amazing um and then we got Jason from
Ridgeline he's got he's the he's got the
latest and greatest and he's doing mixed
light he's also doing outdoor but but
his mixed light stuff is comparable to
indoor and it's the future and so we're
evolving and what happens with the
pharmaceutical IND industry yeah they're
going to try to take they want to take
people want to take over that's how it's
it's it's the human nature to want to
own it to want to to want to take it all
right for it to all be mine that's the
human nature in people and we need to
get away from that a little bit and try
to share more it's American it's just
it's it's very American very American
it's very American I gota have very
Texan I want to have the I want have the
biggest the best right all this stuff
and and a lot of that is ego if we could
kill a little bit of that ego the world
would be a better place I think
100 you know I think the other thing is
we live in excess in in the United
States especially in the United States
you don't see it in Europe quite as much
although we are definitely influencing
them there's more overweight people in
Europe than there ever has been and
there's fast food restaurants all over
Europe too now and uh you know we got
the Nikes and they got the
influence uh but I feel like everything
goes in waves so we're going to go
through this and then we're going to go
through good periods and
you know I think a lot of stuff skips
Generations too so like hard workers the
sometimes uh parents are really hard
workers they want to work so hard that
their kids have an easy life yeah right
and that's not necessarily the good way
because then their kids are going to
have an easy life but they might not
have money for their kids so their kids
are going to have to suffer so it skips
a generation and then their kids become
hard workers and so on and so forth
forever and so yeah what is this saying
tough men create
uh easy times and then EAS and then easy
times create weak men and then weak men
create hard times and hard times create
tough men and so that
pattern uh like many things it's it's a
pattern that goes on we go through these
fluctuations and just like the economy
going up and down right and so we went
away from PL medicine I I we went away
from hemp which is the silliest thing in
the whole world that we went away from
hemp as a society and hemp is so
valuable and we turn it onto things like
cotton you know which is not nearly as
eco-friendly nearly as strong and
durable and we as a society went away
from that and that's to me that's so
crazy because if you look a 100 years in
the past or 100 years in the future
they'd be like you guys were nuts right
you guys really screwed up on that one
among other things among other things
but that one by itself is just like wow
we really sced up on the hemp and I
think we fed corn or not now now we feed
all the cattle corn and I think before
we were feeding a lot of hemp and so
we're talking about canabo possibly
being in the milk that we drank and we
have all these autoimmune diseases maybe
there's a relation maybe there's not but
there's definitely something going on
with the nutrition that we get oh the
nutrition has dropped significantly oh
yeah with all the produce because of
them you know the the
companies that have been patenting just
corn and and soybeans and all of you
know our basic putting seed oils and
everything and and just uh you know with
the patents came control and um lack of
biodiversity yeah and so we've lost a
lot of species of corn lot everything
Tomatoes it's we have we have a what
four types of tomatoes in theore it's
crazy if that bananas we have we have
two so that's that's a huge contributing
factor to the lack of nutrition in the
food um and it's scary it's scary I I
try not to talk about you know scary
things or fear-based
models but when you have the knowledge
of the biopiracy that's going on and um
the patenting of life um and and the
that control being in the hands of very
few people um you need to have people
with boots on the ground that are
working against that and preserving
genetics and preserving um the diversity
of all different kinds of plants and
species because um that's the future of
life on Earth future of our children and
our children's children and their
children and that's what Americans don't
genuinely think about is generational
they think of right me right now and
when I die or who's going to take care
me when I die and there is generational
wealth to a small percentage but if you
look in other countries the generational
wealth is much bigger where stuff has
passed down through multiple Generations
Asia especially like Italy too you don't
have a lot of homeless people in Italy
because those the properties are all
passed to their children and home stay
in the family um it's not how it happens
here in the US
unfortunately bass
Awards yep seriously Common Sense isn't
common
anymore but I think there's people we're
talking about it today so at least
there's that at least we recognize it we
can talk about it I think uh the fact
that we're talking about it our
ancestors would be they would be proud
of us but I guess the the two people
that you really need to make proud in
your life are your 18y old self and your
80y old self you can do that you're
doing okay that's a good that's a good
way to live yeah that makes sense so my
18-year- old self is super stoked on
everything I've done my 80y old self
we're working on that one we'll see but
if I make it to you
know my my 18-year-old self is like yeah
makes sense what you're doing right now
totally when I was 18 I had like tons of
High Times magazines and I was all about
it yeah and the fact that I'm here now
is just a blessing yeah so yeah so one
last question before you go if there was
one piece of advice for your younger
self that you would give your younger
self now after all you've experienced
what would that one thing be don't trust
everyone so easily and go with your
intuition and don't stop being generous
despite
people being negative or I don't know
being bad yeah I guess my 18-year-old
self would just say to to be careful who
you trust and um you know choose your
friends
wisely nice that's all I can say because
that I I feel like that's great and
everybody has different answers and we
get so much stuff and I feel like we're
have a show of just the answers of what
people would tell their younger selves
and it's like it's it's so great you
know especially the collective
Consciousness right I'm sure people have
said some like I don't know I can't even
imagine what other people would think
yeah save your money you got to see
that's a big one save your money don't
do so many drugs so fast or so much it's
all going to be okay all going to be
okay
um yeah we always bounce back yeah
humans are resilient you always back you
will always bounce back and usually when
you bounce back you bounce back higher
than where you you were before life is
about lessons don't be afraid to fail
that's that's one of the biggest for me
I think that's the biggest is don't ever
be afraid to fail because you're going
to keep fa if you want to be successful
you're going to keep failing and you're
going to keep getting up and and doing
it and then show up for yourself I think
that's the other big one is show up for
yourself and and I wish more kids could
hear that
that sometimes you don't like doing
stuff uh but to be good at something you
have to do it a lot you have to practice
over and over a natural born Talent it's
not always going to get you there uhuh
but uh dedication to something is what
it's all about okay and commitment so if
people are interested in finding out
more about you where can they go Lotus
church.com awesome become a member and
um I just have a couple criteria which
is I make sure you're 21 and over and
you're not on a sex offender registry
nice and um then you're welcome to come
excellent M what about social media do
you have social media yet we do we have
an Instagram it's Lotus entheogenic
church and um you can find that on the
website because it's kind of hard for
some people to spell so go to the
website Lotus church.com and the
Facebook and the Instagram are there and
um we have events all the time we
welcome the community to come out and
check it out it's pretty cool it's
pretty cool we back going on yeah it
sounds really I can't wait to check it
out I'll try to be there on the 22nd
yeah so yeah well thank you very much
for coming on the show it's been a blast
thank you for having me it was fun it
was fun we'll have to do this again
sometime yes at the church yeah come by
the church on mushrooms mushrooms I'll
do it on mushrooms I'll be laughing the
whole time yeah yeah I'll do I'll be on
musroom you don't have to be on
mushrooms I'll do the mushrooms we'll do
it though all right that sounds good
that sounds good thank you very much
[Music]