[Music]
oh
[Applause]
[Music]
how's it going welcome to another
episode of the James loud podcast and
today we have turtle from Turtle pie how
are you doing today I'm doing great dude
thanks for having me man it's really
killer thank you so much for coming on
the show we've been talking about this
for a minute we uh have run with similar
the same group of friends but not really
known each other for quite a while when
I saw you uh chefing at the birthday
party I was like wait a minute like how
how close are you I had no idea so the
fact that we're on the show and we're uh
getting to know more about each other is
great seems like it's long overdue
totally yeah and I've known about Turtle
pie for quite a while Turtle Magnum it
made the made the circuit you know a
while back and that was super popular
and I feel like it was a hype strain for
a minute it was the thing to have yeah
that magum Turtle definitely had its
little spotlight it was it was
challenged heavily by the lcgs cuz it
looked it looked the same but it
definitely had its own tarpine profile
its own taste it was so great though
honestly that's exactly why it was so
great cuz it wasn't just lcg it was
different no lcg just looked similar
there was no lcg yeah it did it had a
similar look but the tpine profile was
completely different the effect was
really good I feel like it was pretty
strong anecdotally do you remember
cherry pie I do was there any tarpine
profile similar ities between Magnum
turtle and cherry pie cuz the the first
time I smelled it the only thing that
came I'm like I've never maybe this is
what Cherry cuz I haven't seen cherry
pie since you Cherry Pie was like
straight anise and I mean okay I would
say cherry pie was like anise gas like a
GDP with more
cherry okay so that's that's how I
remember Cherry Pie and Cherry Pie hmed
a little bit when you grew it and but
like cherry pie was amazing like I think
that was another one but I think that
that lost uh momentum because it had
intersex traits and people didn't want
[ __ ] that hmed but GDP was like the real
the real real back in the day cherry pie
was if you thought about opening the
door with the lights off it was going to
get seeds yeah cherry pie was special it
was extremely special and I mean that
came out of like the GDP era and was
like the new GDP and it was it checked
those boxes for those people that really
like GDP but it wasn't GDP and that's
what I liked about it you know and the
whole that that was like the beginning
of like the cookies are era absolutely
and it was the beginning of like back
then you had Jack TPS yeah you had sour
and OG turps and you had per turps and
there was you know there was other uh I
used to get this stuff called Orange
Crush so you had your citrus turps too
but there wasn't a ton of stuff outside
that box that was readily available so
when cherry pie came along I was like oh
wow this thing tastes way different it
was an early zah pre candy yeah for sure
for sure some of the I smoked funny uh
old friend of mine grew it in his
backyard in like half a whiskey barrel
or some [ __ ] and and it was it didn't
HTM at all it was one plan it was huge
and it was just the firest outdoor I've
ever smoked growing in noi Valley uh uh
in early 2000s yeah it was like you know
I mean I feel like cookies was its own
thing and it was like a
sweeter something that definitely tied
into the cookies and and you know I
really enjoyed it I the wild life was
around back then I was super excited
about the I have not seen the Y since
2014 used to get it from my buddy gold
member and Dude that [ __ ] why life
was down to the road tasted just as
intense as Skittles it was the you know
before Skittles that was the candy that
was the one it was floral too it was
super floral super sweet really amazing
that was one of those unobtainable
strains for me like I was lucky to find
an eth every once in a while or someone
would part with one because it was like
no I only got a zip I'm you know I'll
give you an eth cuz I'm going to keep
the rest this [ __ ] right uh but I
definitely it was day it definitely had
his time in the sun I remember paying 60
bucks an e that we could get it straight
up 60 bucks an eth and that was it you
it didn't matter not 3.0 no we actually
got 3.5 might be a little wet but you
know it was okay I mean can't wait to
sell it you're not going to wait for it
to dry I remember the time yeah people
were so excited about certain things you
would buy it wet and you would lose a
little bit of weight but if you didn't
get it wet you wouldn't get it at all
you wouldn't get it yep so yeah so how
did you get your start uh in cannabis or
when did you start I started I was
seventh grade I went to private school
as a youngster uh first through sixth
grade and cannabis was something my dad
and his friends did uh there was always
a tray of cookies at the Christmas
events was like these aren't for the
kids don't eat these and we didn't think
anything they were smoking doobies back
then and yeah uh you know black hash
finger hat you know whatever nepes
traditional hash yeah um and I went to
public school and after a couple of
months after coming from private school
you know 200 kids to go to public school
in seventh grade like a thousand kids or
whatever I find myself in a group of
kids and they all smoked weed and before
long I'm like oh you know my dad's got
some of this you guys oh yeah [ __ ]
bring to school tomorrow like okay sure
and then when we'd run out of our
parents weed that we were boosting we'd
uh walk a couple blocks down to Dolores
Park and get a oo from
the the dudes in dores park we'd have a
little flap of grass they'd pull up with
a bunch of tinf bindles of uh straight
Brown burnt Mexican Brown weed [ __ ]
seeds and all and 60% seeds 40% weed
that's why we called them oills CU we
didn't want to give them 10 bucks we're
only giving you eight for all them damn
seeds seriously uh because I had it you
know because it kind of just took off me
it fit you know my dad grew it he didn't
really introduce me to it until I
introduced him to me doing it it wasn't
like he was like all right it's time now
he never shared the family business with
me until way after the fact now you got
yeah he beat my ass it was funny like I
remember he left on Hawaii he went to
Hawaii one time and I was maybe a
freshman in high school and he left like
an ounce of weed in his weed drawer and
every day I took a little bit thinking
he wouldn't he wouldn't notice right but
the eth turned into like less than a
half ounce or the the ounce turned into
less than a half oun so to me it didn't
look like much was missing because I was
taking you know bowl or two every day
not a big deal right home he's like all
right this has got to [ __ ] stop
you're you know you're a freshman in
high school you're not supposed to be
smoking weed I don't stop stealing my
weed get your own which I did and that's
kind of how this all started yeah had a
guy who would sell actual Ace for 60
bucks and bought an eighth one day broke
down three dubs sold them the next day
bought another eighth the day after that
broke down three dubs sold him the next
day now I had a dub it was like I saved
the0 five from the from the ace I did
didn't smoke it and for once and then I
just kept reinvesting and you know kind
of always always like being the plug to
a certain extent definitely has his
pitfalls being a plug plenty yeah um you
attract a lot of attention a lot of it
good A lot of it Sinister a lot of uh
multi- intention people hang out with
the plug yeah uh and so learned a lot of
hard expensive lessons lost a lot of
people I thought were friends that
really weren't friends they were just
hanging out the plug um but at the end
of the day I don't know that I would
change too much maybe some of the dumb
decision decisions I made but you know
who wouldn't yeah you really know who
your friends are when [ __ ] hits the fan
you know I mean like when you go through
hell when you bad [ __ ] happens then you
really find out who your friends are
it's happened to me I've learned you
people that I thought were my best
friends or my close friends and then the
people that actually came out and that
were there for me it's like those were
my real friends you only got a couple of
flat tire rainy day on the freeway
friends you know I mean if if you got
three then you're probably in good shape
you know most people got one if it's not
their wife or partner you know what I
mean so uh and if you got more than that
then you're obviously running [ __ ] the
right way you're running your life and
you're making sure everybody else is
eating and taking care of everybody and
uh you're you're not wrong about about
the the how you find out what where you
are in their life they may be hold a
certain position in your life but you
don't really know where you hold what
position you hold in their life until
that day comes and then it's like oh how
did I not see that well the bad times
make you appreciate the good times even
more so I feel like you can't have the
bad without the good I mean there's that
contrast that really uh you know it
shows you who you are too and you know
the tough times the test you show you
what you're made of and then when you
have good times it you know it it allows
you to appreciate those those bad times
even more because they gave you that
contrast 100% it I heard the saying you
don't know happiness if you don't know
sadness and I kind of chuckled it off at
first and you're like no actually it's
really deep and it kind of they kind of
coexist like you can't have one without
the other you can't just be happy all
the time cuz then you won't know what
being happy is you don't actually
experience the opposite of that if
you've never been broke you won't really
appreciate what it's like to have money
and vice versa I think you got to be
broke
twice I agree I agree you really before
you really start to get it yeah you need
to make that and then if you're dumb and
you trick it all off and then you make
it again you're like I'm never going
back like I really get it now like I'm
going to save every penny or I'm going
to invested correctly or yeah but also
you know that you can if you have to
right that's the other thing is like
then you you don't have the fear because
I think a lot of people they move
through life with fear but if you can
take that fear away and you can just
move and do things the right way you
know I mean there's so many way you know
the right way is so many different
things but there is the right way
everybody's version of the right way
yeah you know that's how your version of
the truth your version of how you look
at things your exactly am I normal I
don't know what your vision or version
of being normal is seem pretty normal to
me you know but yeah so it's perspective
it's all the balance for sure for sure
so yeah so and then you grew up in
California bone and raisin SF yeah first
go as I like to call it yeah freshman
year high school I mean senior year of
high school I started raving a lot it
was huge in '92 dude yeah so i' I've
went through the same thing I mean I'm I
class in 95 but 92 is when it started
popping how' you hold on yeah I mean the
Rave scene in California
especially San Francisco was the
epicenter but there was like the home
base parties in Oakland there was like
crazy CRA I mean it was it was a whole
different world and it was like disco
once it was gone it was gone forever I
considered it it was all kind of the SF
scene yeah but it didn't you weren't
beholden to hold it in SF like I went to
Bonnie dun several times the home bases
or Freedom that was out you know in
Antioch not it was out past Antioch
Oakley you know there was some amazing
parties out in Sacramento oh they right
but it wasn't like the majority of them
I went to in the city you know Monday
night Tuesday nights Saturday absolutely
Wicked all the W all the wickets I could
sneak into till I was old enough to get
into because for me and all my friends
we all RAV together but I was 19 and 20
and they were all 21 and 22 so it was
like I would be so butt hurt when I
couldn't get into party I promoted a lot
so I had even some parties I was able to
get into cuz I knew the dude throwing it
or you know I mean I did some work for
them funky techno tribe that was those
were my boys yeah Johnny Karan he's one
of my good friends that's funny yeah
Johnny knows me I go back him and I he's
a little bit younger but we were right
there together with Kevin and Jerry and
yeah funky techno tribe was those
parties were insane yeah they were it
was awesome so the bay are is amazing
for culture and amazing you know I feel
like we're all carrying on these
legacies for people were on the
shoulders of giants you know cannabis
industry well said I mean can't ride it
without the Bay Area without California
Northern California does almost doesn't
exist without that you know totally
Northern California their influence
humble medino I mean humble's known all
around the world they might not even
know what humble is but they know it's
in California they know it's a place
where the good weed came from the good
weed came from exactly and it can't be
duplicated our climate can't be
duplicated and not in authentic way
right like that's the thing is like you
can duplicate stuff but can you
duplicate it authentically it's really
hard to you know try to take a carbon
copy and put it somewhere else sure uh
yeah you can grow amazing flower in
other places you can anywhere anywhere
in the world that you have someone
that's super passionate you can grow
good flower does Antarctica you sent
some guys that are super passionate down
there they can grow good flower in
Antarctica I guarantee you you know in
space whatever but uh you know so
there's that passion that drives see
them grow some weed in space that is
dude I don't know how far that is away
but I'm ready space weed come on Elon
yeah grow some weed on
SpaceX yep
seriously yeah AI grown flower a AI
grown flower completely hydroponic
obviously that's hilarious yeah know the
the future is bright you know I think in
a lot of ways and uh you know our
industry is challenged in its own right
you know going into recreational we've
had our setbacks in our challenges and
uh you know I've seen a lot of people
fall off U some good some bad in a mix
of everything uh
genetics genetics is kind of all over
the place but we're still holding on to
that gelato model um you know know
strains
have decade blocks yeah you know Sour
Diesel was all anybody wanted for the
2000s oh yeah that or OG Kush depending
on which coast you the circles that we
were in for sure it was Sour Diesel you
had some chem dogs some Sour Diesel some
OG those were the Exotics of its time
and it's like I still love good sour
good OG good chem dog chem D grown right
amazing yeah absolutely I'm actually
pumped because the green dog team has
been scouring their resources to come up
with the diesel they grew up with in uh
in Vermont and one of the posts I read
the other day from the cultivator Keegan
shout out dirt lore buddy I love you
dude uh he was though just the passion
and the way he was describing the flower
of it being so reminiscent you could
kind of see like I could see it because
it was still wet but like the the
outside was really bright green but
light light bright green a lime like a
like a line that you almost peeled some
of the [ __ ] skin off of like it was
super light and then it had these bright
pink salmon colored hairs and then the
inside was almost like white and
blinding yellow and I was like that's
what old wet diesel used to look like so
I haven't been up the sack in a couple
weeks but I'm going to go up and
hopefully get to smokes I don't I should
have don't we' had access since R the
river uh Dave from uh buero he grows the
real Sour and he gave me some of ree
we've had we done a podcast with them
I've been friends with them ever since
and amazing amazing and then it made me
think that really there's probably only
one sour I feel like we have the AJ sour
and we have the weasel Diesel and all
these things and for me the sour that I
remember it was just one thing like
there was this one amazing open the bag
punches you in the face with TPS and
it's not super chemy it's got the gas
but it's definitely the gas on the
bottom and it has loud lime Citrus funk
and it just you open it up and it's
unmistakable the thing is is like with
certain things you smell enough times
where it's not what you remember and
then you start wondering if your mind is
like playing tricks on you and maybe you
just didn't remember it right the funny
thing is is once you smell it you'll go
oh that's it that is the one it's
unmistakable there's no other ones that
I remember that are quite like that I've
recently come across that we smoke what
we called Nate yeah BC weed Canada weed
we short we shortened Canada or Canadian
into Nate Anders n n and the nade and we
had we had what we called nade or we had
glue or glue there was wasn't really too
many other variations if there was I
don't remember it well our friend
brought me some and I was like this the
[ __ ] n dude it's like no it's
whatever he's calling it I'm like
looking at it and I'm
like way I'm smelling it and I'm like oh
my God and then I touch it man like like
a [ __ ] reaching back into history
reaching back into the 2000s I'm like
I'm like this is it like holy [ __ ] it's
a
2024 version you know grown differently
to today's standards and and if it's an
identical twin this is our mutually
favorite genetic right you know that
right both the second I I smelled it I
was like oh this is the one dude this is
the [ __ ] so what do you remember it as
because you have yeah I mean so I so the
funny thing is I I was so excited when
he gave it to me CU it's so loud and
it's like the OG that punches you in the
face it's got that OG gas that burns
your nose right and but it's not heavy
on the pine like like like Josh D and
some of these other ones have more of
that earthy Pine this one is like nose
burning and it's more on the sativa
leaning smaller buds uh longer flowering
and it has that nose burning punch like
the gas like you wouldn't believe it has
the most gas of anything out right now
and I showed it to a whole bunch of
people from New York and a whole bunch
of people from Miami and the thing is is
the first thing they're like d That's
crippy I'm like crippy uh yeah and so
their opinion was crippy I remember
getting that in the Bay Area as OG or
like we had an OG that was just like
that where it was like what the [ __ ] is
this you don't see gassy OG Brian from
vital soil hit me with some OG like an
ounce of OG that was it was the real OG
like unmistaken he's had the cut for 20
years it was the sh out to Brian living
soil yeah Brian from vital thank you
Brian it is you know he has it every
time I see him he usually givs me a
little bit and uh they do you know they
do the infinity jars and I think he has
some friends that are also he's working
with that are doing it and it's like
that is the real cut of OG like it's so
for me it it's not it's it's different
than the OG I grew yeah it's it's
feeling and effect wise it's there but
like I get in my nasal I get and I don't
I hate saying this cuz I don't want to
diminish it in any way but back then I
get Gorilla glue Vibes off it to a
certain extent Gorilla Glue was the [ __ ]
for years like that was a really killer
strain for a light you know it did well
for itself but like I get I get like the
merger of OG and Gorilla Glue not really
a GMO kind of stank but like that that
pungent that loud up there in the in the
in the simar structure to the glue too
the way it fingers out so I definitely
get what you're saying with the
structure also just the loudness it's
extremely loud uh you know and the first
thing like do you do you have any I
don't but our our mutual friend is
supposed to be bringing some soon I
think they're in they're they're in like
week six right now so it's a 10 weer so
we got four weeks he's splitting it with
you and I we get the the tester lights
so that's that's the you know that's the
dream and I love that stuff and it is so
loud right so that's the one where you
don't see you don't get the same effect
from gelados or cookies or any of these
things where you open the bag and it
burns your nose like you get hit it's
like how sour would hit your face right
Sour's different but also when you open
the bag and it punches you in the face
with smell with the aroma it's just like
unmistakable cat piss is what started
for me where it had that that nose burn
where you open the bag you don't even
have to open the bag it would smell
through bags you know and I guarantee
you even today's standards the TPL locks
like it would it would go through TPL
locks cap his I miss some good cap his
man you're from the Bay Area so you
probably remember good ciss in the 90s
you know and it's like that's another
one where if I knew what my dad was
growing I'm sorry I cut you off but like
my dad always grew he only he only grew
green weed once and it was the [ __ ]
best [ __ ] he ever grew but all the other
ties and mexies that he grew that he
took care of and manicured and and it
was all fire like weed I've never seen
since you know se you know seeds that I
don't know if he went and where where
they came from out of a lid back in the
day uh but as as a freshman in high
school that the strain you're talking
about was for me was skunk yeah because
it was like you had to have seven bag it
had to be in seven fold over sandwich
bags or film canister when we used to
have 35mm because if you didn't you get
busted at school it would smell out of
your backpack and it'd be like a
thumb-sized bright green marble with one
Crown Royal bag purple leaf just laying
on it and it would just be like what the
[ __ ] and then we moved from that
disappeared it was probably so strong
that people didn't want to grow it I
think that has a lot to do with it it
was so intense CU we had skunk weed we
didn't even call it skunk though it was
you know it was green but it was
extremely skunky we got some from Santa
Cruz I've told the story of my podcast a
few times it was called the strawberry
because the nugs were strawberry shaped
right so the you get three or four
usually three nugs in a bag and each nug
was you know like 1.2 grams or whatever
but it was strawberry shaped and it was
as skunky as anything I've ever smelled
we never had stuff called the roadkill
skunk that wasn't until the 2000s that
I've heard that name kind of being
thrown around but like 90s we didn't
have a roadkill skunk we had heard the
term skunk for sure like skunk or skunk
one was basically it yeah skunk one was
a sweet skunk that was like totally like
the skunk that I skunk one that I
experienced uh there was a Michigan
skunk too that was really good but that
was like on the sweeter side of the
skunk and not on like the nose bur side
I don't remember the sweet skunk I just
remember that stanky yeah loud in yourr
pocket on you it told on you it told on
you told on you for sure yeah well a
tenth of a gram if you just had a tenth
of a gram that accidentally fell in your
you know pocket you're you're done it
would smell it would smell a whole room
yep and you just don't get stuff like
that anymore more and some stuff like
Skittles doesn't even really smell like
weed it smells like candy you know I
mean 90% of the stuff that's out there
right now is a trip down through the
Gummy Bear Aisle yeah you know or the
the the high chew aisle or whatever with
n you know insert whatever fruit
flavored ice cream candy com you know
combination you want to come up with
which is cool I like it but you know for
me it's
like so I just did a breeding project
myself yeah and I did half of it for me
and the other half for everybody else
yeah right and I know I'm going to like
it all but like I made sure I hit some
turtle pie with some stuff I want yeah
just because it's time it's time to
catch Turtle up give Turtle bit a little
bit of for me I I still love it to this
day because it the way it makes me feel
but other people don't like it because
it's too strong I'll fire up a joint
they'll take a hitter to me be like I'm
cool bro I it's just not my [ __ ] you
know they smoke Skittles all day long
you know Skittles is over here Turtle
pie is over here yeah no similarities in
the way it makes you feel um so I
definitely got I'm super pumped I took I
didn't just mean to jump into this right
here but like I'm chomping at the bit uh
because I can't I can't wait to start
popping these seeds and see um what I
come up with i a friend of mine uh shout
out Adrien Sky he created zetopia which
I love zetopia okay I do too I do too
and a lot of people don't really notice
the difference than a regular lcg but I
get the Z twang in the back it's totally
different if you're a smoker I totally
get in the background and it's for me I
I really dig the strain for being in the
in the realm that it's in I dig that one
a lot we worked together way back in the
day and then we just you know Frisco do
went our separate ways well he ended up
Lon with the group or I don't know what
he was a main part of a group I don't
know the middle of 2000s and he ended up
developing the zetopia and we got
reconnected he he was working I believe
with the jokes up and uh Society right
and working with them and I had no idea
it was a friend of mine and I I said
something I was like I did a post like
February is love month I'm looking to
you know get my ladies pregnant and he
hit me up like yo I got you and I'm like
what do you mean and he's like yo I did
this I did that I did the Obama runs I
think I think he said the Obama runs I
hope I'm not I hope I'm quoting him
correctly yeah but uh like no [ __ ]
way like all right let's talk so um
after a few unsuccessful breeding
projects I tried to do
um I just said [ __ ] it I I need some new
genetics I got to get some new stuff
pumping through the pipeline um and so I
did a little project in my basement and
I've got a couple hundred seats to start
rifling through I
took six seven of my strains and then
one other strain was gifted to me by a
friend and I just dosed them uh I got
some I got with purple sticky rice some
I got with zetopia and some I got with
the belts
and so I'm pumped to see some of these
combos I got grits and jam combos I got
strawberry melon combos I got prickly
pear SUNY paper like I'm super pumped
it's my first intentional breeding
program I got a lot to learn I don't
know if becoming a breeder per se is
something like internally for my own
[ __ ] absolutely but like to turn to make
that external I'm probably not organized
enough uh to do that I it seem it's
still a great progression for for sure
it's not it's not pounds of weed it's
not triming flour it's a completely
different everything um from I guess
from the day you flip the lights you got
to treat them differently to a certain
extent yeah I'm pumped to start popping
beans I'm pumped to get some new Jenni
out and and see the
feedback I have a new strain now that a
friend of mine did it's it hasn't
released it's about to release I'm super
excited about it it's purple sticky I'm
calling it original sin it's purple
sticky rice time Sher Banger and it's
[ __ ] great it's got Banger I've worked
with the sh Banger too I love it too
it's got everything you want from the
purple sticky rise but then it's got
that from the sh Banger it's got that
Banger from the sh Banger soch yeah I'm
super sto again every time I talk about
weed it's all about the feeling for me
and I like those weeds that make that
that punch hard the turtles the Sher
bangers the nade or whatever you know
those those GMO I love the way GMO makes
that stuff is so strong great yeah GMO
is super strong too but yeah the the
nade or the crippy or whatever whatever
you're going to call it I'm going to
call it it's so amazing right but it's
so strong right like that stuff is like
it's not for the faint of heart right
it's not for the it's not for the new
smoker that wants to see if they like
weed it's for the guys who really smoke
that's what I love about it too CU all
the old school guys that smell are like
yeah that's the one I want that it's
people with either too much anxiety and
they need less or people or if you get
anxiety hella easy it's not for you it's
not for you yeah yeah it's not for you
if you roll with anxiety and you want
less smoke some turtle if you if you get
anxiety easy definitely stay away from
it cuz your heart will be beaten you'll
hear your I can hear it in my ears who's
got the food it also makes you eat like
crazy but uh yeah I'm pumped about the
original sin because that's it like as
soon as it came out I'm like oh I got
something here this tastes so good and
it has the looks and then as it sinks in
seven or eight minutes after smoking and
it's just like big heavy warm coat
laying on your shoulders I'm like oh
this is the [ __ ] right here thr Call of
Duty or a movie and I just [ __ ] veg
out for a little while I like it so be
on the lookout for original sin I know
you guys are going to [ __ ] like it
it's got it hits everything uh so and
that's going to be coming in the next
couple of weeks just got my packaging
figured out and that's what I forgot to
bring the damn jar for the original then
yeah but uh yeah I'm pumped off that and
then I'm gonna start popping six to 12
ceds at a time and see what I can get
and just you know just do some fact
finding and see see how some of the
genetics laid out and and where I'm
going to end up with them so nice yeah
yeah and I I'm in the right place I know
I'm in the right place to talk seeds all
day off camera well the thing I like
about someone like yourself who's going
into breeding is you already know what
you're looking for as far as quality
right so like if you just start growing
and then you're in like a year or six
six months to a year and you're like I
want to start breeding I don't feel like
you have enough data points collected
over the period of your life to really
go you know you might say this is what I
like is what I don't like but if you
have a huge collection of things that
you've tried and you can go okay 80% of
the stuff I don't like I really like 20%
I like the way this makes me feel I like
this the way this tastes I like these
traits and you can start period I like
the color I like the yield you know what
I mean you start listing these boxes
that have to be checked and it's like as
you have experience that's when you
really should go into breeding and I
feel like it's it's a great way to
prevent yourself from getting bored with
just growing for one thing but also you
have this knowledge that you can pass
down and you can share with the world
through your breeding I completely agree
I think there's 15 jobs you should have
before you're [ __ ] breeding from from
building a room or or watching a room
being built to learning how to line the
trays or set your trays up and run run
feed to De leafing to harvesting to
trimming to all those things come away
then then maybe you get to learn how to
make the batches you know maybe curing
and drawing I feel like that's a huge
one like learning how to
you can watch every day but it's still
on me I'm not going to unless I'm gone
you're not doing that until I'm
confident with you it's one of the
hardest parts 100% you can ruin all your
work in one [ __ ] day that you spent
three months doing so many people do
they ruin it they grow it and it's
amazing and then they go to or they
don't flush right and then you know they
don't do that last week or that last two
weeks or whatever you flush for but they
screw that part up and then the drawing
and the curing they just major fail and
then they have some Booth right and Y
boof that should have been amazing they
had a good starting point with genetics
like if you start with good genetics you
have your room set up properly you dial
it in and you go all that time do is
don't [ __ ] up yeah you don't even have
to be great you just don't [ __ ] up right
like you know keep it simple until you
actually learn what you're doing and
then you know I would an early mistake I
made and maybe you did is I had two or
three other people who were really good
Growers yeah and I'd ask them all the
same [ __ ] question but and I would
take some of what he said and some what
he said and some wor yeah it was the
worst [ __ ] idea because then you
don't know what's actually working and
not working so then I was like you know
what I'm just going to listen to this
dude and then I take his advice and if
that doesn't work out after three
Harvest then I'll you know I mean for
whatever reason I'll take the one
problem or two problems over to this
dude and see if he can help me Square
them away and that need trial and error
but cannabis is a [ __ ] up business to
have a lot of trial and error like one
lost Harvest might mean lost rent you
know especially if that's how you're
supporting might be a bad Christmas it
might be a Christmas with no presents it
might be a yeah you can't afford
electricity there's all kind of bad
stuff Christmas was always hard in the
weed game unless unless you saved money
from summertime cuz no one was spending
money I like I'd be like don't you want
to buy weed for Christmas like give
quarters away like who the [ __ ] wants an
album they want a quarter of this
OG here best Christmas gift of all time
for sure yeah but Christmas money was
hard to make October to January yeah
that was when it was flooded because we
had floods and we had droughts and there
was a lot of yeah and it was up in waves
and you know the summer it'd be hard to
get stuff people don't even understand
there was times where you couldn't get
weed to save your life when I was a kid
you know I was like you know not kid kid
even in 1819 it was like we might be
able to get some brown weed but nobody
wanted to smoke Brown weed like I I
would rather not smoke at a certain
point when I was younger I was like
whatever but there was a point where I'm
like I'm not smoking that stuff because
it gives me headaches I just want the
good stuff and once you really get a
taste for the good stuff and you've
smoked it long enough you just can't you
can't do the bad stuff you know and it's
like I think I've smoked Brown weed like
three times since I started smoking
green weed yeah once was in Thailand
once was I let my buddy convince me that
his brain was phenomenal cuz it was
green but it was brown weed like you
could tell I mean for for being brain it
was good but it's like you did like once
you fly first class you don't try to go
back to the no that's the truth I'm
experiencing that you know it's like
it's hard you know it is what it is but
uh you know we live in this amazing
world where we have access to a lot of
good stuff like you the access that you
have and the access that I have it's
like we get to smoke the really good
stuff but not everybody I always have to
remind myself this not everybody gets to
smoke like we get smoke or experience
whether it's you know it doesn't matter
with extract we can smoke pens or
whatever most people don't really get to
experience stuff on that level because
that's the 1% right so like it's just
like with money and everything else most
people don't have it there's there's a
reason it's the 1% and not the 99 I
definitely
know the groups of weed I smoke with I'm
smoking the if not the best TI for the
best weed around it's yeah it's at that
point you can't really that 1% area and
it it kind of like I'm 50 almost 51 yeah
I've been smoking
weed you know 80% of my life at this
point I don't have space in my lungs for
shitty weed I I can't and
it's and and I it comes off totally weed
snobby and it might be a little bit but
I would prefer you step your game up and
get better you know what I mean
so I don't have to about that like
people want to hand me their joints all
the time first of all with and being
sick like I'm like I'm getting the point
now where I like go to an event and
light a do can be like I'm not I don't
want to hit your weed I love you give
you bro hug give you D but I don't want
to hit your weed and I don't really want
you to hit mine cuz I don't know what
you're giving me I don't know how it was
taken care of I know who grew and rolled
whatever's in my hand and I know their
standards right and and then nor do I
want to swap spit like I would always
get sick coming on from Emerald cup or
any you know you get cup cough right all
these all these events Amsterdam High
Times cups all these things you would
get the cup cough you know because
everybody's sharing joints and they got
germs coming in from all around the
world and we're all mixing it up and oh
especially I I haven't been to that I'm
going in fact I thought about like I got
to get my passport taking care of
because I want to go to spanis have to
go to spannabis and then Germany has to
be on the is it right is it right after
Germany is in June and span is in March
okay Y and so so I get and then there's
420 in between [ __ ] that's a busy three
months right there well that's the
industry for you yeah for sure but
spannabis is the one you got to go to
for sure our mutual friends are all
going to spannabis I hope this year
we're doing a big uh every year is Big
when I have fomo on IG and I'm watching
everyone I know there [ __ ] I'm like
why have I not going I'm a family man
first you know what I mean my wife works
her ass off she has a full-time job
taking care of my dog my two cats and my
daughter completely for a week and a
half is a huge stress on her right shout
out babe love you uh and so like there's
part of me that's like I can't [ __ ] but
and then at the same time I'm like look
yeah you don't want to live in this
house
forever I need to go do some of these
things and she's like I get it just the
big deal happen you know all the all the
big meetings happen at spannabis at
mjbiz at these bigger events that's you
know those are where you you bond with
other guys in the industry too that are
on your level right that's the beauty of
it and yeah my wife's very supportive of
the industry she works with me she's my
business partner and my wife and she
does a lot of the [ __ ] hard stuff you
know so that that I can do the stuff
that I do right so yeah it's a team
effort oh 100% I I my wife is so busy
she doesn't help help me with my job but
I got my two team members and without
them I'm
I like what's the address for today's
event again can't find it in my emails
okay Boomer I got you on yeah shout out
to Le and John Henry you guys have are
clutch and come through for me all the
time totally I I like to give people
their respect I got I have a very small
group of people who help me be Turtle
pie and allow me to be Turtle pie um my
sack craft team my personal team and
then do you know Barney do you know of
Barney Barney has a green dog formerly
Barney has a blueprint I know blueprint
okay blueprint I mean Jordan's another
homie totally um but Barney Barney is uh
he he's like a weed celebrity without a
brand yeah like everybody in SoCal knows
who the [ __ ] he is and he represents Our
Brands down in in in the Southern
California area with the the most
enthusiasm and dude is just [ __ ]
awesome like uh but uh the the team like
I said my team the green dog team and
him and a couple other you know tight
Jace tight family members I don't want
to leave anybody out um you know we
can't do this [ __ ] without you you and
it's so much [ __ ] fun doing it with
y'all I love it thank you guys for all
being [ __ ] awesome showing up to work
motivating me to do more every day
because I can get lazy you I can get
complacent I've been doing this for so
long like I haven't been up excited
about anything really except for the new
strains that I drop and the seed like
this new seed project I'm excited about
that because it's new for me it's it's
you know I did it myself you know I did
I was given the pollen but I got my
little paint rushes out and went in
there and dusted each plan and you know
did I haven't grown in years because
other people been doing it for me so I
got to grow a harvest again uh I know
why I [ __ ] up at the end and if I
decide to do it again I won't make that
mistake when with seeds it's like you go
for me I go a lot longer than I would
like if I harvest something a day or 63
in flour I go an extra month because I
want the darkest best looking seeds sure
so it's a lot more work and you got to
keep them as healthy and happy as long
as possible with seeds it's always a
challenge we can talk on air off air
about that like I definitely would like
I'd like a a a a a longer recipe cuz I
got a bunch of great seeds but they're I
wouldn't say any of them are huge um
they're going to pop and I'm going to
get some fire as genetics out of it it's
not the size not the size of the seed
it's not the size of the seed that
counts yeah okay I was I guess I was
just making the extra month would make
them girth out a little bit not
necessarily but it'll definitely make
them darker uh outdoor seats come out
bigger typically than indoor but also
that's very specific to the genetics
you're working with um you know you can
but but I've seen bigger seeds come from
the same cross outside as opposed to
inside okay so you know but I feel like
there's all kinds of benefits but yeah I
got a book too you've seen my right I I
haven't given you a book yet so we'll
give you a book today [ __ ] will you sign
it oh yeah of course go yeah it's it's a
lot of fun and I mean I think it's all
about finding those exciting things
where it you know I mean some people are
barracudas right they're chasing the
next shiny object in the ocean right I
try not to be that I try to do stuff
that keeps me excited that's aligned
with my main focus so we got a breeding
book we got a podcast we got a new
podcast uh we got our website we got all
these things it's all genetics right
everything comes back to genetics I'm
not trying to be the flower guy I want
to be the gortex I want to be the velcro
I want to be the guy that helps you make
your genetics better or your brand
better I like that and proves you know
and the beauty of where I'm at with that
is I can work with everybody I don't I
feel like I don't have enemies in the
industry there might be people that
don't like me but I don't care I like
everybody for the most part and if you
want people that don't like you you're
not doing [ __ ] right exactly exactly
there's always going to be haters dude
it's like look at the environment we
live in currently right like half the
country sees things one way the other
half sees things the other way AB you
guarantee if you got both of those
people paying attention to you some of
them are not going to be like it just is
what it is it's okay negative energy
still energy yeah you know what I mean
if that's what you got you got negative
energy for me [ __ ] it it's better than
none energy as long as you're not
pointing a gun at me you know we're good
sure you know hate all you want I laugh
at that [ __ ] it's like cool you could
have spent your time hanging out with
your kid but you chose to [ __ ] rage
on me okay thanks but yeah like our our
friends our mutual friends at SF Canada
it's like them and a handful of other
people I feel like we the industry is so
small within our community like
everybody knows everybody and we all
kind of lift each other up and it's like
you know who the Bad actors are and who
the bad guys are it's like you've done
it long enough and I've done it long
enough it's like we know who the bad
guys are and they they stay at a
distance right and so they might still
exist and I know there's bad guys out
there but like I work within the people
that help lift me up and I help lift
them up and it's like this community of
good people and it's like we all have
the same kind of vision about what
quality is we have the same kind of
vision about what ethics are because I
think that's important uh and it's it's
it's teamwork at the end of the day not
one person can do it all and I don't
want to do everything I want to stay
focused on what I do and then you know
we got SF Canada that grows amazing
flower y we've got all these guys in the
Bay Area there's a handful of guys to
grow really amazing flour and then
there's everybody else and I've always
wanted to be aligned with the best
whatever the best quality-wise the best
flour I fell in love with good weed and
I just have never gone back and I always
attached myself to that that's what I
want because that's what I want to
consume for myself when at the end of
the day I want to smoke the best stuff I
can possibly get life's short I mean you
know when do you pick the old steak Yeah
you know when you don't you know when do
you drink the mold milk don't do that
dry yes but not the one that's 99 Cents
Brown I don't go for the discount [ __ ]
no so why would you not be wanting to
smoke the best unfortunately you and I
are in that in within arms R length if
we're not doing it ourselves to do to do
just that all the time well it's always
the latest and greatest I'm seeing
you're seeing stuff I mean that
zetopia you know I feel like it hasn't
made it fully on the scene like some of
these other things but it is special
it's just as special as anything else it
smokes good down to the roach and it's
got it you know it definitely has its
own thing I
think back to the actual pallette and
connoisseur and understanding of what
you're smoking yeah if you're not
looking for it it goes right over your
head yeah if you don't if you know if
you're not familiar with zps if you're
not familiar with how zps affect other
plants and other genetics like I don't
even know that I get a ton of Z in the
smell like there's there's something
different about it it's am I lcg right
in my opinion it's just not visually
visually it looks very similar even on
the nose it's pretty dang
close to your run-of-the-mill lcg but
yeah you exhale you're like oh there it
is I got that and you smoke it down to
the roach it just tastes good all the
way down and and it has a really good
effect too like I feel like it's all
about effect with that U and it's not as
strong as lcg right but it is the Z
somewhere in the middle because of the Z
but uh you know it's not a diet Skittles
either that's what I I hate diet
Skittles I hate stuff that's a diet
version of the original there's nothing
better than Skittles as far as on the
candy where it's like straight candy but
there's things like moonbow and I've
talked about this on my show a lot with
moonbow where it's like it's complex
enough to where it's not just straight
Skittles but it's Skitty it's got that
doy dough and it's like complex and you
smoke it you're like wow down to the
roach it tastes amazing and that's what
I'm really looking for tastes amazing
makes me feel great makes me want to
smoke another joint it
that's okay so when you go to get high
yeah and you open your toolbox with 200
[ __ ] flavors in there do you open it
how often do you open it with a
conscious decision prior to opening it
what you're going for or how or how many
times you open you're just like I'm
feeling like this one right here because
I get that with the zetopia like I I
love I love that tur like I love smoking
my Sunday paper yeah but I don't want to
smoke it all the time I I smoke it
intermittently I don't I don't want to
smoke the zetopia all the time but I
find myself maybe because it's new right
like lately I've been like papers Utopia
my other strains like I'm going to lean
this way and for me it's so often an un
not an unconscious Choice yeah but you
know what I'm saying it's like if I want
to go if I'm like I'm [ __ ] pissed or
I need to go to sleep and I need to be
this high I'll go smoke some turtle yeah
the rest of the time I'm like you know
it's shades of the same color but you
have some that are heavy over here and
some that are heavy over here and I find
myself gravitating towards that zetopia
lately as it as opposed to some of my
other routine strains the ones I line
jar test you know it's like the first
thing gone that's the one you it's like
there you go and and I have so many like
exactly what I'm talking about yeah and
I have options I can smoke 50 different
things right I have a jar of this and a
jar of that and a jar of this and I have
that you know I have 20 jars of extract
or more than that actually probably like
40 or 50 different types of raw in right
now and I can pick from any of them but
you know the the one that goes first is
usually the best and I I gravitate
towards Skittles even though that's not
the strongest but a lot of times that's
my daytime just
yeah I mean other than the one that
we're about to try in a little bit that
so on my last podcast we did it you know
we we took dry hits uh and then we
smoked and tried the soil grown versus
the cocoa right actually I think I did
the dry hits and she did not hie from
humbled seed company and we got really
high on the podcast and you know I'm not
used to getting high like that from
Skittles Skittles is usually you go up
to about here and I can maintain that
here all day long where it's it doesn't
get me over the top I can super
functional I can do pretty much anything
on it but that soil grown it was more it
was almost perfumey it was Candy Perfume
like TPS up here as opposed to down yeah
he get here no we have we have the the
refires we're we're going to test refire
dude so I feel like that's the true test
right that's funny I was just going to
say the same [ __ ] thing so we're
going to see if you know which one is
you know after hearing all this you
should be able to tell the difference on
the refire I'm excited to see how much
of a difference it was from the last
podcast to this podcast on the refire
I'm C I'm curious in the comments after
I watch this episode and I read the
comments what is The public's opinion on
refire because I have so much weed like
I give it to my family and friends or
whatnot my mother-in-law my pops my you
know my my close homies where I can roll
a fresh joint all the time but if the
weed for me if the weed is so I I always
after I take 10 or 15 hits I do a tiny
Puff out so anything left in the paper
goes out and then I never extinguish it
I like put it in the end of a glass tube
or something so it just stop smoking
right and then 30 40 minutes later when
it's time to reup I go back outside and
I do the same thing and as you said that
is the true test especially if you can
light it three times and you're like
this [ __ ] still tastes H that's like the
old school py Old School Champagne like
the roach tasted almost damn if not
better than the front because you're
getting that [ __ ] resinous gluey [ __ ]
it's funny full circle Johnny Karan
uh-huh that's where I used to get the
real champagne from that's funny small
world right like but the real champagne
was like that you would put it out and
champelli is the man I I'm I'm good
friends with champelli we've been
friends a while um and yeah there's a
long story with that too but like d that
champagne was got lot long stories that
there's so many long stories yeah for
sure Bay Area is just such a small you
know ni Community the amount
of if not now at one time influential
Canabis people that went to [ __ ]
mcateer high school you know if the book
of cannabis is written and they have a
map with little you know hot spots like
mcer High School 89 to 92 is going to
it's going to be blinking on the map
because there was quite a few people who
have have had a hand in the Cannabis
industry and forming and the shaping uh
at that place at one time was kind of
funny right and all the high schools
that really all the high schools
Berkeley you know East Bay you can go
out into conquered and you go Walnut
Creek conquered Pleasant Hill area you
know that's kind of where I was at and
it's like cat piss a lot of guys from
there remember the cat piss you know
there's there was a lot of legendary cat
piss going around that conquered area
all the way into Antioch you know making
it into the bay yeah [ __ ] ay yeah
crazy it's I
mean the the F the fact that we have run
such parallel lives and are only three
years apart and really haven't come
across each other at all until happen
stance recently it's it's kind of weird
because people with your resume and your
longevity like I feel like I know most
of them especially if they're from the
city you know whether they're good
friends or acquaintances or somebody
I've met once or twice um so like I said
before this is long overdue uh and I
like I definitely I definitely like
talking we I'm telling because we don't
really talk it too much we haven't hung
out before too many times you know a few
minutes here and there this is the
longest conversation I've ever had with
you but to know how many similarities we
already share without you know without
knowing that ahead of time it's pretty
[ __ ] cool like we we can sit here and
think the same [ __ ] you know without
having to verbalize it and then we're
like oh yeah that's F damn s with the
that's the true test of weed that when
you can relight it and tell how good it
is for sure but I am curious if so if
after you watch this I do Wonder because
I already l a [ __ ] hash hole like who
I can't face a hash hole you can't just
throw that out no who [ __ ] know but even
I am not throwing out anything but if
it's a stew doinks the last part is
that's it because it gets too harsh but
I'm definitely not throwing any none of
my cash packs none of my stew dinks out
none of my homies doinks out I'll
already light that [ __ ] three times if
I can if I know there's no more hash
left okay because I can go fire up
another one but like who can face a hash
hole you know seriously I have one
friend that comes over and takes my half
joints and it's you know he comes over I
don't like I don't mind like I don't
want him to go to waste either you know
what I mean but like if I showed
the bag of half people would be like
what the [ __ ] is wrong with you like I
can be wasteful but I don't smoke I
don't do the relight longer than the
next day yeah I won't leave it outside
for three days and then go Rel it
because that's never good sour you could
do that with and catpiss you can do that
with and I can't really name other ones
where catpiss you can smoke it a week
later and you're like [ __ ] that's CET
okay so I I don't that I'll roll a joint
at like noon and if I don't finish it
that night I'll smoke at the next day
but I also don't smoke flour every day
yeah I smoke a ton of cold fire and uh
flavor Aid uh and I I dab a little bit
it's it's definitely my least it's
definitely my least form of consumption
yeah um but I went through a phase where
all I did was dab and it just [ __ ] up
my tolerance in general so if I want to
enjoy any FL you appreciate flower as
much I still dab quite a bit and well I
mean I've been like so the the ays from
Focus V is like my go-to but then I got
this Rover and I've been on the Rover
kick and it's like you can see the smoke
yeah it's wild like I mean it's that's
so reminiscent of the glass domes and
the the little uh the what is it called
the the castle from a chest piece they
used to go a little metal thing like
with you I'd always get to the party
like 15 minutes into the party the glass
Dome would be busted in my pocket and
I'm oh yeah that's the I broke in two of
these now with the glass and and uh dude
they these guys are great uh so dip
device makes these so dip device made
these straws right and so I got this
straw from this dude named Uncle Stoner
he's a character dip device they they
make the straw right and so you can just
it's the same idea but it's electric
nectar collector I love neor I have I
have they gave me a couple pieces I
really liked I think I used them up but
they worked pretty good I didn't know
they had a new product you gave me one
hit off that and it [ __ ] tastes a
great and yeah and so it's a quartz
bucket right and the inside it's got the
beads for TPS and I I I really so for
the price point is 80 bucks oh [ __ ] and
I think it's amazing for that you know
and this is not you know they sent sent
me some they didn't pay me anything to
talk good about their yeah and I mean a
lot of these products are expensive but
for the price this is a great product
it's simple and easy to use you know and
you know it's like I feel like taking it
around other than breaking the glass I
feel like if I had a container to store
it in but it's simple they have a bunch
they have a flower pen too that it's
like a volcano that's pocket size so
pretty cool and they sent them for the
dab AO and I I didn't get them in time
and so I've been using them and I you
know I
anyway yeah um what's it called a ro
this is a Rover that bowl you passed the
hit you passed me earlier was [ __ ]
great that whatever it was tasted great
that thing hit really nice so yeah yeah
not bad and it's it's convenient sounds
like that's a good walk away price yeah
and then smoking before I go to the gym
I usually dab because flower I don't
like smelling like flower everywhere not
that it's that big of a deal but I go to
the gym and I know everybody there not
that it matters but like I feel like
weed basically when I smoke a fat joint
it it makes me a little more tired
whereas I take a dab it it wakes me up
we also if if you're doing any kind of
cardio yeah I'm not trying to smoke
don't a flower before I go do cardio I'm
going to take one fat dab or hit my pen
twice and my lungs are still going to be
tight but if I sit there and so it'll
open me up if I just do one nice big hit
and it'll make me not have to think
about what I'm doing so like cardio is
great like or even lifting weight every
hit [ __ ] closes my [ __ ] up I need
like a
ibol hit the Dewey and then take a nice
[ __ ] hit some inhalers so I can open
my chest again some caffeine yeah some
aerosol caffeine I love smoking weed and
drinking coffee yeah that's the best
combo ever that's I I would say most
Stoners do that if you smoke a lot I
feel like coffee is the balance for me
so like throughout the day I don't drink
a ton of coffee but I definitely drink
coffee in the morning and then I'll
drink it around one or two if I if I
drink coffee at five or six it's no good
I can't sleep yeah if I drink it three
times a day I just don't enjoy it the
next morning like I love my morning cup
of coffee yeah I like that take my dog
to the park rip my pen a few times drink
my coffee and [ __ ] yep I like that's
a good morning for sure before I [ __ ]
tackle emails and phone calls and all
the other [ __ ] that comes along yeah
it's it's easy and I just feel like it
makes especially with with the extract
in the morning if I'm smoking some good
rosin if I take a hit of that and I
drink some coffee I'm I'm just super
clear-headed right if I smoke a huge
joint I save that for
like afternoon yeah evening for sure
evening evening evening and then usually
in the afternoon podcast we usually
smoke joints on the podcast but I like I
like the extract too I like all there's
so many different types of raas in now
and you can kind of get different
effects from just so many different
things so we we not too long ago
released a BHO line which has been
[ __ ] doing great so thank you guys
for so much for grabbing it because it's
it's fire um I asked for when possible
Butters so I can get the doughnut hole
because I smoke them and I can't offer
rosin as a product none of my stuff
really hashes which is another reason I
did the feno hunt that I did the reading
project that I did so I could hopefully
you know I'm looking for six to 10
strains Max um which I think is doable
considering the genetics I put together
I think I should be able to get that um
but one or two of those really needs to
give me two plus 3% yield so that I can
offer you know a quality rosin in the PO
because I smoke hash holes I really love
it and I do kind of feel on the outside
CU I don't have a product that can
really my Butters do it and for people
that you know it's a really cost
effective way to roll some donut is a
really clean way to smoke BHO um yeah I
mean if you Ian it gives you the hole
too like it it works it smokes a hash
hole just fine the end can be this much
l there's a lot of people that hate on
on BHO but like BHO you're not losing
those water soluble turps that's all I
got to say again I'm offering it I'm
offering it to offer it yeah because I
can't I've tried all my [ __ ] and 2% is
not a reason to stop growing flour and
make rosin it's got to be better than
that well you're going to have hash
makers that hate you at 2% yeah 100%
well I mean just to get them to do it
you're going to be twisting arms well my
flower does too well that take a a 2%
return on hash would be just a huge L
you know aside from the amount of work
to get nothing it would just it wouldn't
it'd be G it wouldn't be cost effective
no so hopefully with some of these new
crosses I'm going to get find something
that washes like the the the turtle's a
dumper she's dumped 5% a few times um
what is the turtle crossup the first
time when jiga gave me and my old
partner cookies yeah we grew one tray of
cookies in a room in a building full of
OG the cookies early on I [ __ ] miss
cookies I would love some form cut or
some cookies friend has I haven't smok
cookies I'm so ready a long story about
Platinum cook we call him the zebra but
uh it was weird my partner and I were
harvesting the room and like there was
one OG Kush plant that was like
abnormally large it was a foot and a
half two feet taller than any other
plant in the room we're like what this
plant's special we just cut it off and
put it to the side you know we did dealt
with the rest what we had to do with the
rest couple weeks later he's like bro I
got a [ __ ] seed off that OG plant I'm
like the big one he's like yeah and
[ __ ] thing was I mean I tell it it
was a size of a marble it wasn't but it
was [ __ ] huge and it was beautiful
and it was just Stripes all over it and
we were so disappointed in the yield of
the cookies and also OG was still King
at that time so finding OG adjacent
things which was never possible
everything was Sub sub OG I never made
anything I never got better crosses
making OG I always got wor there was
some good [ __ ] but it was Never As Good
As OG well so it has the the quality
traits that everybody loves are
recessive so it's like you typically
it's hard to get get you're not getting
them in the crosses not not right away
you know it takes some work it was a
long time before people had good OG
seeds for sure oh I never saw OG from
seed it was all it was cut you know my
old friend was the dude in from bring
from Florida in his [ __ ] sock diet OG
diet Skittles diet OG a lot of you know
so uh yeah it was a it was unbeknownst
to us at the time we thought we had new
OG yeah um but it was the plant the girl
the cookie girl next to her was freaky
back then and she just and and puffed on
the OG leaned heavy on so we got this
everything about it was cookie dominant
aside from the effect and the effect it
was like it really got me stoned in
comparison to what that was the only
thing I didn't like about well I didn't
like the yield and I didn't like the
potency in compared to OG um it was
tasty everybody wanted it you know it
was [ __ ] it was the [ __ ] for a long
time right um but it it missed what I
appreciated about smoking weed well the
strain we got we called it sweet cooks
and it really I always think we misnamed
it we should have called it sour Cooks
uh that would have taken off much better
because it was it was cookies times gas
times sour gas and that strain my my old
partner at turtle pie ended up Crossing
that with the original sfv cut and
that's where turtle pie came from nice
um so it was cookie to OG that shame was
crossed back to OG and again if you see
her and smell her like she there's not a
ton of OG visuals or nose to it but then
when you smoke you're like you got the
strength you get the strength just like
you get I mean cookies was strong too
that's why cookies right big noes big
old cookie noes they like four fingers
or more yeah and it's like then it
spaghetti's out yep that was the problem
that I had with cookies was and same
thing with the old OG that we got that
was just OG cush it was like it would
spaghetti out where you had to Trellis
it you had to support it there was no
way to grow it unless you wanted a bush
that ran along the ground because it
would literally grow up and flop over
4inch node spacing little buds you know
um thin mint was different thin mint got
dud that was a freaking amazing plant
Spears do you mean if I didn't grow OG I
didn't have to Triple trellis yeah
exactly [ __ ] like I didn't know that BL
dream you don't need trellis what are
you talking about trellis yeah it was
like it only took me like three Harvest
to be like okay they're This Tall put a
[ __ ] it I also wasn't I didn't use to
clean my plants like when I first
started I didn't rip everything
underneath the canopy off yeah like I
didn't I didn't know I was learning you
know my buddy my buddy came over and
taught me how to De Leaf the first time
I'm like what the you just ruined my
garden yeah there's no solar panels left
he's like just [ __ ] wait and sure
enough I was like oh wow
I see some people and they just pull it
so hard they strip it so hard where I'm
like what are you doing but they they
get crazy yields and I I've never been
one to completely pull off every leaf to
where I'm like but everybody has their
own way sure well and now with underc
you have what are you getting paid for
yeah leaf or Bud totally so grow less
leaf and more Bud the energy is going
somewhere it can go to your leaf or you
can go to the bud and I'm like okay that
makes sense okay yeah so the under
canopy lighting you don't have to clean
the under
canopy the faens are crushing it all our
friends use favin it's like [ __ ] dude
well when you're getting 30 to 50% more
yield and you're getting more purple
buds on the bottom than you're on the
top it's hard to argue with that you
know I did that years ago I hung t5s
around my room like so I mean it was it
wasn't under canopy but I got full side
canopy and I had crossover light you
know t5s don't really get that far but I
definitely noticed the [ __ ]
difference in yield yeah I also notice
the huge difference in power but a
little Phototron you photron same idea I
had I tried growing a Phototron in a San
Jose and it just was miserable you know
how I know you're old you grew the photo
tron yeah that's I agree with theot that
was where I got my start too did you
ever try the Octagon yeah yeah so I
that's so funny so that was the sickest
[ __ ] I could never Im so dope so we had
the wooden octagon my friend yeah Micah
my good friend in business partner for a
long time he came over to the house one
day and was like he had the recipe you
know he had okay this is the we have
these Ang we have to cut we had to go
all the way to Willets to the Garden
spout and buy these Dutch pots which
were 5 Gall Square pots with little
holes in the back and they were five
bucks a piece and it was 13 plants per
row and per light there was 26 plants
per light growing toward thousands or
the 600s one we had thousand so we did 2
thousands some people with three 600s we
had the cool tubes that ran in the
middle so the cool tubes then there was
with light on chains right and uh some
people just used to hang them but we put
the cool tubes in there to keep it
cooler yeah but it was very strain
depending on what would work you had to
grow something that you could veg just
for very shortly and you would still get
nice buds you grow some chem 91 like I
did and we got walls of lar it was
straight it was it was chem dog it was
the West Coast dog we got we got it as
the dog so my buddy had I think he had
three in the room but he also had room
lights yeah so all the backsides
flowered out too like he end up having
to hang trellises on the back that's
crazy like he was like you know there's
so much [ __ ] like it all Grows Right
towards the light that was another
triple trellis like you had to hang
trellis after cuz he was growing cush
and sour so it was just you know was
getting super long and then it would
even if it touched the Cool Tube it was
getting burnt even you know what I mean
it wasn't that damn cool GDP was the
best thing to go in octagon because
short they would short and it would
really chunk out yeah eight weeks and
you yeah I like GDP still [ __ ] I
don't see anybody growing it CU it's a
pain in the ass to grow same thing good
bubba I haven't seen a lot of good bubba
like I have this philosophical
conversation with people like what I
like and what sells yeah you know I try
to sell people what I think they will
what I of course I have what I know
people will like yeah that's how the
business Works am I here and there like
try this like adding I've added sh
Banger to two of my strains now and
that's outside what a lot of my people
like the fabulosa does pretty well yeah
um and I'm hoping the original sin's
going to do [ __ ] great I'm pretty
confident because it like I said it hits
the fabuloso is a little light where
this is a little more heavy um but
trying to curve the market to your will
is kind of tough like it's only going to
go so far and then it's going to bounce
back and it might happen one yeah for
it's not going to happen every time I'm
not going to stop trying you know I I
have nine strains that do really well
yeah regardless of how long I've had
them because they're grown perfectly and
their quality strains I have you know
four or five more strains in my
repertoire that do okay and get grown
and offered sporadically just to mix
things up um but every time I'm adding
if I add three new strains one of them
is going to be something I want you to
like yeah you know not something I know
you're going to like like I did a lot of
candy on candy right you know I'm I'm
adding zetopia to grits and jam yeah so
grits and jam is a a candy it also has
an herbal nose like an herbal um I
wanted to bring some today but I just
didn't have any left yeah I only had
Smalls and I didn't want to show up with
Smalls but the grits and jam to me is a
is a candy but it
has not oregano or Rosemary but some
sort of cooking herb Essence in the
background well I've added zopi to that
some pump because grits and jam is one
of my best sellers yeah you just never
know though with breeding you never you
never know you might get something
totally different you you know you have
an idea of what might happen but I'll
tell you one thing about Smalls they all
look the same in a joint they sure Fu do
so I I like Smalls too sometimes you
know it's like Skittles Smalls are still
Skittles yep you know they're good um
you know so I'm not picky always with
Smalls I don't mind smoking Smalls
myself I smoke them all the time yeah me
too when I go to sack I'm like just give
me Smalls I don't need the [ __ ] big
buds you know that that needs to go to
the patience right you know my my my old
hatchlings thanks [ __ ] BCC now with
pedals even though pedals does really
well yeah uh I had to change if you
don't know I had to change my hatling to
pedals same product different name less
kid-friendly
way more female friendly though had a
couple but butt tenders like oh a lot of
women buy this which is it's kind of
anecdotally hard being a 50-year-old
dude trying to design and Market to
women specifically like I just grow
[ __ ] no I would love to know how to do
it dive into the soccer moms I kind of I
kind of with the pedals like I've had a
couple butt tenders like oh this I have
a ton of women who buy this all of a
sudden I'm like great like tell me what
else I got to do like I there's plenty
of girls we I would love them to be
turtle turtle pie fans like please um
but yeah I because I want I know the the
ace sell out my small sell out too but
when I go to sack I get my little
Kickbacks I'm like just give me small I
don't need too much big buzz yeah it's
like like you said it all smokes the
same in the joint well yeah Good Smalls
Are Good Smalls I mean that's what
people you know and it's like I do I
just like good flower at the end of the
day I want it good it's you know if it's
small if it's big if it's ugly I don't
care if the weed's ugly if it tastes
amazing and it makes me feel great have
you do you see pretty Skittles pretty
ugly Skittles pretty exactly Skittles is
not the most beautiful in fact we were
looking at some today and I was like
yeah it's not it's not a looker but at
the end of the day it tastes absolutely
amazing and it makes me feel really good
y the original py yeah wasn't an amazing
looker I remember being maybe because it
was it was always flat cuz it was you
know squished but it was it was like
gold and red and and had like maybe I
remember like wheat looking like like
buds as opposed to like nugs and [ __ ] I
don't remember the original I champagne
we had champagne and it was like nice
fat Buds and the bags we so we used to
get in this specific turkey bag that our
mutual friend had and it was always just
caked on the outside of the turkey B on
the inside where the buds were it was
like you could take a razor and you
could scrape up the crystals cuz it was
so Frosty I don't remember having
champagne and turkey bags we champagne
the crinkly turkey bags you know there's
the soft ones and then there was the
crinkly harder ones I remember the
crinkly using back then crinkly turkey
bagss God I wish I get out one wish can
you help me out with my memory paper
bags you guys are Safeway bags Cur paper
bag I used to cure in Safeway plastic
and paper bags that was my little
technique y I used to cure in the Sun be
like what the f that's crazy yeah but it
wasn't directly so this was my method I
would I would wa weight CU always J
hooked my weed I had a wooden the the
room I grew in initially was all wood
mhm it was wood panels you know and so
the closet was wooden in the winter time
the wood would be wet more than it'd be
[ __ ] dry because that's just how the
moisture was in the in the you know the
environment right um but it was always
two to three weeks of hang drying just
being patient always nope don't rush it
don't rush it when the when the tip of
the when the the tip of the cola the
fattest nugs snapped m I knew it was
time to take it off the stem then I
would take my Safeway plastic bags and
I'd fill it up I'd roll it down and then
I put it inside a Safeway paper bag and
I'd roll that down yeah and I'd have
eight or 10 of those sitting out and I'd
go get a thick like wool or fleece black
green blue blanket and I'd lay it over
the top of it and so the sun would come
through the window yeah and it would
heat the blanket up which would in turn
heat the bags up very slowly very gently
that's through the window yeah Frisco
it's what is it [ __ ] 82 degrees
window Sao no hell no hell no and people
be like what are you doing I'm like just
smoke my weed and it would be it'd be
the kind of weed that felt super wet and
was perfectly dry like greasy yeah
exactly it's got that greasy but it's
totally cured cuz you get to snap on the
stem but it still feels like it's wet a
little SP oil yeah where it's completely
Droid from the moisture but it's yeah I
love oil I used to do that by the F it
was like a two or three day burping
without glass jars I mean it wasn't
really bur it was never burping cuz it
was never I would whenever I burped yeah
that's when I would [ __ ] [ __ ] up because
I would leave it closed for too long
yeah you know six hours today was too
long it should have been three hours you
know and whatever it was like iied it
never worked for me so you know I
figured out this own my own routine and
I had great success with it like that's
how growing the OG I did is part of the
reason I got here just it definitely
wasn't selling bees be e and the [ __ ]
you know what I mean it wasn't that it
was it was getting the cultivation bug
and you know having a few grows and
learning all the [ __ ] trials and
tribulations that the gamut of [ __ ] from
Bugs to police to robbers to you know
bad Harvest to all that [ __ ] and
sticking with it yeah like [ __ ] I'm made
do this this is this is who I want to be
this who I am exactly exactly Dark
Energy you ever used dark energy back in
the day oh yeah yeah yeah yeah uh was
that no I'm thinking no I'm thinking
that wasn't the one that made the B
seelp it was the seelp that was like
steroids for your buds and I believe
it's it's banned now because it's like a
pgr but it's not a pgr it was no no it
was it was actually seelp celp is now
banned they consider a pgr and it was
but it was like the big game changer
back in the day that made our buds swell
up and it was crazy like the TPS
everything liquid caramel was another
good product you know this is the '90s
when it was like there wasn't a thousand
different things there was so see in the
'90s wasn't growing yet yeah I started
growing 99 2000 mhm that was when we got
the octagons was around that time it was
it was 98 or 99 that I started growing
weed yeah uh in an Atrium in the middle
of my house nice and it had a had a
glass covered Atrium and I ended up just
completely blocking off like a fat third
of it and had two
600s and my buddy Tau me to grow AFU and
J1 you can't [ __ ] these up yeah J1
actually great it was great [ __ ] he
yeah I made a J1 bubble gum that was one
of my old crosses that was that sounds
it was super bubble gummy it was also
super sativ like sativa effect
definitely that more awake but with the
bubblegum turps and then uh yeah J1 was
good and what was the other one you grew
the AFU AFU was another one of my
favorites that was also the most
frostiest thing back in the day it was
so Frosty and it grew like like three a
light four light it was it was a chunker
yeah it was a big he grew massive buds
massive can't [ __ ] these up so do
whatever you're going to do here's my
recipe try some [ __ ] out and then figure
it out and it was and I'm like I all I
want to do is grow Kush and he's like
walk he's like crawl dude yeah now
you're walking so why don't we give
these a try we've been talking about it
long enough [ __ ] hey we're GNA do the
refire test refire me up bro it's a
little bit of AB testing we're doing
we're going to go soil versus cocoa I
think it's a fun okay harmless test that
we can both enjoy okay
yeah when I smoke joints I I it's like
at night time before dinner or like in
between rounds of Call of Duty so I
don't have like 15 minutes to smoke a
whole joints so I'll do the refire no
problem three times though we we smoke
really good flour right so like you can
refire it a bunch and it's still if it's
really good all the way down to the road
should tastes amazing I don't care how
many re times or times you refire it
it's funny when I was pheno hunting the
Tahiti midnight yep because I was given
a couple strains like you know which one
of these works for you uh that one
worked because in the course of a
conversation with somebody over like an
hour we smoked this Dink and we kept
relighting it and we were both like damn
this the third time we relit this and
it's still [ __ ] tasting like we can
still get turfs off it what are your
thoughts on number
one super smooth it's got
that that's I don't I call it a twang I
don't know if that's what other people
describe it but it's that it's that
distinct pallet flavor it's not lemon
it's like if it's lemon it's like eating
the peel not smelling the lemon you know
if it's if it's something like that it's
more like not from the smell of it it's
more like the Citrus taste of it I guess
that the oils behind it right but it it
has that
distinct tur profile that everybody's
looking for when they're smoking their
Skittles yeah totally that's the one
thing when you smoke Skittles you expect
oh there we go we'll swap it out yeah
these were kind of rolled in a rush
yesterday to do the show shameful was
like yeah I just you know that how dare
you yeah these 1.75 or actually I think
I I put two grams in each one of these
okay do you actually weigh it out or you
I do I do because I feel like then I can
get more consistent and more even so
personally I prefer weighing out every
single one uh cuz I try to get that the
specific grind right feel like the
weight in each one the way I twist it at
the end the way it burns down I think
all those things are important I do use
uh the glue I use can gar glue and so
it's a little brush that you twist in
and a little bit of liquid comes out and
so that the crutch sticks to it better I
feel like you get better rib is it like
is it like that Agave stuff like sweet
tast little sugar whatever there's a
little sugar in there it's perfect and
then I use the raw crutches I I love the
raw crutches with the element papers and
the organ tips so it's very specific and
I've been working on this since before I
started this podcast we've been working
on the
recipe and it's just one thing we keep
keep on perfecting and it's
like I'm looking for a couple things I'm
looking for how it burns I'm looking for
the drip but also the taste how does
that paper taste is it is it clear is it
yeah is you taste through the paper you
taste the paper does it burn the back of
your throat if you use the wrong papers
they you taste them and I'm not about
tasting paper especially if you're
testing or if you're doing any kind of
Trials of your weed you want to use the
same grinder the same paper the same
amount of weed cut all the varials
variables out that you can so that all
you're really testing is the weed itself
it's not you know cuz a Raw versus an
element versus OCB they all taste
different yeah they all have a different
flavors for sure you can taste them a
little bit different in the back of your
throat sometimes uh you know and then
some of the stronger tasting papers I'm
not into I want to taste the flour right
but also we're looking for drip we're
looking for ash how does the ash
look what do you think what what do you
like better one or two I like that one
better nice I I I want to say this that
one is definitely smoother like I've
coughed after every hit with this one
where that one I got one cough out of
three hits yep it's hard because of that
I'm taking hits four through eight off
this I don't know if it's like I want to
say this is getting me high
but it could be the compounding of being
the second four hits I've taken it could
be um but flavor-wise are you getting so
this was
smoother this one has a different tur
profile though they
taste that one to
me has the more what I'm used to Z tur
profile right this one has its I taste
the Z but it's a different profile it's
almost like this one's perfumey a little
bit like I get perfume okay is that what
you mean like because there is like a
like if you spray perfume and you get it
in your mouth like that yeah okay I get
that too okay and I always thought
people say perfumey like it's smelled
like perfume but it's not that it's the
Coating in your mouth Coating in the
mouth feel yeah it's not like it tastes
yeah I mean this is making my hands
tremble I would love for sativas to love
me back but my canabo system as much as
I appreciate the turs does not
appreciate the effect of saiva's uh
again I know I'm using outdated terms
yeah I get it until we the community
come up with new vernacular to to
describe what we used to use sativa and
Inda for I'm going to continue to use
these once we come up with new terms and
and it's an accepted to talk about it
again because for me it's always about
feeling or taste right so this has the
feeling I would associate with sativas
long flowering varieties we can go lfv
or whatever I don't know yeah sativa is
just what we know am I wrong that OG
Kush genetically would be classified as
a sativa OG Kush can be a long flower I
think OG cush is a hybrid for sure but
I've seen it when IND I've seen it when
Inda cups and I've seen it when sativa
CS is it genetically I think it's
everything's a hybrid obviously does it
lean more sativa or indica I think
that's depending on the OG cut we'll
switch you go back to this one and I'll
go back to this one you look at the Ash
and I feel like the ash on that was
burning a little cleaner
but uh as far as taste wise this is a
this is levels up in my opinion um just
twise I think this is up here and but
that is the Skittles that we know and
love that's the Skittles that I know and
love the but this one is different right
this one is also strong one I'm telling
that's the stronger one because [ __ ]
like dude Skittles does not give me
highight this it doesn't uh okay yeah
cool normally it does not doinks of what
this would be
akin to this yeah and I walk away
unsatisfied right right and and it's
like I'm ready to go jump in my car and
hit my Cal Fire or just [ __ ] hit the
Cal Fire or roll up something else you
know if if if I'm in sack now that uh
Jordan's there all the time they got
like P90 and [ __ ] laying around so I'll
grab some of that or I just tried this
purple Dino for the first time and I was
like Blown Away with how good that was
he Dr amazing flower he's he's friends
with my friend Kyle I I need to get him
on the interview for a podcast he would
be great because I've smok would geek
out so hard because he's technically you
know what I'm saying he he's an amazing
[ __ ] cultivator and I don't know I
don't know about his breeding skills all
that much but well regardless Kyle who
works with him is one of the best
breeders in the world he's one of my
good friends and we've done stuff
together and he know yeah Kyle is he
from Washington okay he's from
Washington Kyle's the man Kyle's like
yeah Kyle Kyle also likes to nerd out
and Kyle likes good weed he just he
loves weed Jordan and I have been
talking about Kyle a little bit lately
and he he was just basically letting me
know that who he was and [ __ ] and I'm
like okay so I definitely know that
reference I haven't met him yet I
haven't had the pleasure but I
definitely know the reference so yeah
he's awesome he's he's uh yeah he's he's
he basically is
one hard dude I'm telling you for
Skittles that doesn't smoke like
Skittles in the sense that I don't know
if I would have smoked so much on my
last podcast had I known it was that
strong I was super ripped I'm curious to
watch the podcast
and see if how different I am from
before before and after the joint
because inside I'm going a million miles
hour right now yeah so Skittles doesn't
usually dab some OG cush right now
Skittles usually doesn't give me tight
eyes yeah but Skittles as far as eyes
are [ __ ] yeah it's got to be that one
it's that's that's making the effect
because it's it's the soil one for sure
it's cuz it does sidles doesn't normally
and it doesn't taste perfumey like that
normally in my opinion but this is that
tradition Z taste that everybody I love
it I love that too but this one is like
what is up with that and the only
variable different literally the same
light the same harvest the same
nutrients it's all the same the one
variable is soil y right and so take it
for what it is so um you equate that to
the slightly darker Ash as well I do
because I feel like with soil you
probably need a longer flush and it's
harder to get a different well maybe not
so different but definit like it takes
longer to flush soil for sure like we
used to do two weeks on soil I don't
really do too much soil you know I'm the
seed guy anyway so I'm mostly cocoa and
I love cocoa flour but really soil
there's something special about the
effect too like of this stuff especially
I'm like Skittles doesn't make me feel
like that normally these are amazing on
the relight by the way yeah both of them
one day later literally 24 hours later
we do these podcasts sometimes you see
them one week to the next but like we
we're filming these ones back toback so
you got to experience the relay it was
perfect for this instance where we could
test these on two days and get similar
experiences I mean I
think uh really special stuff just yeah
SF Canon dude they do a good job with
the Z they do a good job with it they've
been good for a while they do some good
cand some nice stuff absolutely super
candies the quality yeah I mean they
they get the the boxes it's like those
guys know what's up yep I used to get
this stuff it was super sour tan or sour
Tangi yeah and it was like a [ __ ]
Skyrocket like you were holding on to a
[ __ ] Sky you'd be so [ __ ] high in
it and my I yeah I'm too [ __ ] it was
it was the best and the worst at the
same time it was it was I was so far up
there it was just in up there I didn't
like I was uncomfortable being ghost
train Hayes used to do that for me the
ghost train would be like yeah that
could that was like Rocket Field where
you would just blast off if you dude
yeah
those super Silvers those did two oh so
you ran back with the 97 super silver in
the Bay Area dude that super silver was
so strong it was one of the strongest
and it would just get you lit like it
was it was stronger than anything else
around at that time and people liked it
because it was strong also the tur
profile was nose burning like intense
totally yeah really good stuff when it
was right it was right when it was right
and it was like big big chunkers in the
back you had these big huge buds yeah um
I miss those days so yeah and it's funny
like some of the stuff that I saw back
then that I thought was average now I
see it like power plant I was like E
power plant whatever and you see it now
and it's like whoa [ __ ] The Strain
and it was it was from Europe it was
brought over we saw it at Oakland in
Oakland uh I believe Bluebird Cafe and
some of those and I just there was some
stuff there was so much stuff Romulan
back in the day was super fire oh [ __ ]
yeah it was so I was a buyer for a while
and a lot of times I had to take
people's word for it yeah because
I'd never seen Romulan the first time
until I saw it the first time yeah and
then when I saw it the third time and it
was the same looking smelling thing as
I'm like okay this is officially Romulan
you know uh all these crazy St n9b
hammer and all these different strains
that would come through and I'm like
okay cool until I knew it was or wasn't
I ran with it yeah but it was cool
having that time on that side of the
desk where I could learn from all the
world work that other people did right
evaluate 100% 100% instead of the small
circle of Growers and and and smokers
that I hung out with is to be put in a
position to view hundreds of pounds a
month without smoking them making good
decisions right I was even I that's the
best those those guys the the buyers at
the dispensaries back in the day that
would smoke a joint of it I have the
most respect for those guys right but
not everybody has time you look at
Harbor Side you look at PG and it's like
the line's a mile long for people trying
to vend but like really you can gauge
the stuff I mean by the looks yeah you
know these guys have to make good
decisions by the looks but also you go
to smoke it and it's like so the
dispensary I worked for was was coming
out of an older dispensary and they
needed someone to put good weed on the
shelf and I didn't know [ __ ] about being
a buyer I knew good [ __ ] weed and I
knew vaguely what it was worth in in
within within a certain within a certain
realm like things I never seen before
you know I didn't know I didn't know
what crazy depths were worth until I
until I figured it out but being able to
see all the weed and try it because I
got my eyes fooled me quite a few times
yeah so I stopped looking at the weed
first and I would just open I'd talk to
you and open your bag and I close my
eyes and I'd smell it and i' taste it
and I look at you in your eyes and close
my eyes again and I wanted my nose to
make my first buying decision yeah
because my nose didn't lie to me my eyes
would [ __ ] lie to me all oh this
[ __ ] looks so good no no does it
[ __ ] smell good because ultimately if
it's rinsed and and and flushed and
cured correctly it's going to taste good
right regardless of what it looks like
except for purple punch but never yeah I
I had like that doesn't get
you but uh I didn't buy a lot of that uh
like I had to buy so much blue dream and
I didn't want to buy blue dream yeah I
was like what but but it was like the
blue collar strain like okay always have
blue dream on the menu but fire blue
dream is good don't get me wrong good
fire blue dream is so good like grown
correctly the real cut it's it's amazing
uh you know and it's not everyone's cup
of tea I was using that place to elevate
myself and my and eventually my brand
when I started the brand there uh I
elevated my knowledge of the game of the
industry of what everybody else was
doing I I my my knowledge of strain
diversity grew intensely I learned all
about hashes and Edibles and like why
are the Edibles and the hash companies
the only ones with names like why don't
the flower companies have names I
started telling the Growers like dude
you need to name your company totally
who the [ __ ] are you you have four
strains on my shelf and no one knows
that they're yours but every corova
black bar versus uh Coffee Bean whatever
those things are called bar they get all
the hype but they don't exist without us
anyways cuz I'm a cultivator not edible
maker speaking Edibles I got gummies
coming out soon stay tuned uh can't wait
passion fruit [ __ ] passion comos huh
gummies the only way to go I love rosin
gummies to taste like rosin because I
love rosin I'm hoping that I can even
list the rosin on I'm getting all the
packaging constraints but I'd like to be
able to list you know what exactly
flavor of rosin is going in there I like
my white Thorn Rose gummies those rosin
gummies are I've been hearing about this
white Thorn Rose somebody was like oh
you can smell the jar I have but they
weren't giving me a [ __ ] dab and I
was like that smells it's it's you're
like the you're the fourth person who's
like this white Thorn Rose and I love
the name I love the visual thing that
comes and it's purple hash and the weed
it's it's colorful and the effect it's
Feelgood weed uh I I maybe have some
dabs okay we'll see but either way it's
feel good weed it makes you feel good
like it's one of those ones where you
smoke it you smile it makes you feel
good and I feel like everybody needs to
try that stuff yeah I'm smiling I'm this
is pretty good feel I'm pleasantly again
I'm a little more up like underneath the
table my hands are trembling a little
bit hopefully my voice isn't quivering
too much but I'm surprisingly lit off of
how the seven or eight hits that I took
um like the the level of stoned I am
right now is pretty high it's it's a
little uncomfortable being completely
you know forcoming um but regardless
where I'm at I'm like I'm pretty [ __ ]
up right now yeah uh and I don't usually
get that way off Skittles me neither me
neither I can skitt one the dirt's
something special cuz I've smoked the
other one before a lot a lot yep um and
like I say I walk away I feel like a
like I don't want to get hated on for
not loving Skittles like I love the tur
profile again I smoke weed for feeling
first yeah like turtle pie doesn't taste
amazing it tastes cool tastes like a
gassy cook like a mild gassy cookie yeah
smells like cardboard but it [ __ ]
gets me so lit Oreos is more cardboard I
feel like yeah the turtle pie definitely
has something to it well I like wet
basement or they're like when when will
it be done curing I'm like that shit's 3
weeks old bro it's been cured for 3
weeks like oh again I mixed Turtle pie
and zovia I'm [ __ ] so pumped off that
like that I think I got like 12 beans
out of that it doesn't seem like turtle
likes to breed either she was very
stingy with the amount of seeds that she
gave me from the uh and I've never we
read we did the Magnum Turtle but I
wasn't there for that uh we got three
iterations two were terrible and then
when the Magnum Turtle came out the
Magnum turtle is gone right or I I mean
I haven't seen my knowledge so my friend
it fell out of favor with us but our
friends at SF Cana yeah seemed to have a
lot of favor with it it worked so
wanting to bring bring it on to uh the
recck line I I I was like okay so we did
it in sack yeah a few times and then
like three times in a row it Herm and so
so they were like we can't we don't have
time to fix this and we can't afford to
grow this so they got rid of it which it
is stressing right like so yeah whatever
maybe got some systemic bacteria who
knows right who knows they anytime a
like they've had to [ __ ] can some fire
ass strains because no matter what on
the third time they you know they it Hur
it grew once or twice good and then
Hermes a little bit and then the then
the next time it's cool and then Hermes
bad they're like yeah it's got to go
because it can't interex tra can [ __ ] up
a lot of things it's it's just not worth
it uhuh and that place is so many hunt
or have a catastrophic pollination orgy
one it's not designed for that at all so
for sure I love all these new flavors
coming out that are outside of the
spectrum of what the market is looking
at right now I'm I'm excited for more of
the long flowering varieties to get
mixed in even if we mix them in with the
gelados to see where it goes to get
people excited about those things again
how long before we got lcg sour d yeah
I'm down to [ __ ] try it yeah I mean I
I made some cool C I did the Skittles
yeah we did some double Cherry gelato
with the weasel's diesel and we did the
Skittles backcross the zbx I have a zbx
that I made that has uh weasel's diesel
in it and so that it looks crazy looks
crazy there's some interesting
fenos one of my friends in my network
said they just smoked some some lcg OG
that was really good nice and I if I
could remember which one of you said it
I would be happily say who you were but
I was I was like okay let's [ __ ]
check like lcg is not going away it's a
it's a wave it's it's not it's not going
anywhere I hypothesize that there's a
lot of people who like to smoke weed
that don't like to get Hella stoned
which would be perfect for the lcgs you
know perfect for Skittles there's lcgs
is a little the lcg is a little stronger
skitt absolutely but it's not in it's
not in the gas range it's not the GMO
the OG the uh the G [ __ ] yeah Sour's
probably lcg range it depends on who's
doing it s that would like it would test
it 14% but it would give you couch lock
too it was so strong like to me like
sour is a gassy version of Skittles I'm
hope I'm not bastardizing either one but
like the the they have that distinct tur
profile and a distinct potency level
that I don't know that one I I'm going
to need to smoke some Sour again to see
cuz it's been a while since I've had
some fire sour but like I never liked it
because I was a cush dude and sour was
like H okay we warmed up with the sour
where's the OG oh I love sour I love
just the turps over you know that one of
those things but I also like the effect
of sour it's something I relate to you
know I could smoke all day and enjoy I
feel like sour was one of those ones you
enjoyed in the morning you enjoy in the
afternoon or the evening it's one of
those across the board Skittles can be
kind of like that for me too but I feel
like the sour was like special and it
was the effect was good I don't know if
either one of those would be evening
strange for me yeah especially if I've
been smoking them all day I'm definitely
turning it up a level or or turning it
down a level let's put it that way yeah
I mean I I like mixing up and and you
never know what you feel like what am I
doing that night yeah if I want
something super strong yeah before bed
for sure but that guava Cherry is a good
nighttime smoke that's another SF can of
guava Cherry good stuff they got some
cherry gushers that one's I like that
one too yeah we got the TC did the TC
for their cherry gushes super fire I've
been smoking uh like random gelan lately
that's been pretty [ __ ] I like Gelade
I'm super I like Gelade a lot I never
had a phase with it so it's it's not
it's not new but I never like I never
had a zip of it I maybe you know hit a
joint here or there how about lemon tree
what's your thoughts on been a while
since I had lemon tree uh and melonade
the melonade I was a huge fan of melon
like good melonade grown organic living
soil melon from can Organics I got them
to cut and dude that cantaloupe and
sometimes I get cantaloupe chps with
good Skittles where you smoke it and it
tastes like fresh melon okay like
especially uh when they harvest it
around like day 53 and it's like super
fruity but it's usually not super strong
like that one is just all turs and all
flavor okay and I can I can a big joint
like that I can sit there and smoke that
30 40 minutes I'm not super high but it
like it leaves me fulfilled because it
tasted so good right right it's funny
how that works right
where where you tast in your teeth where
it's like yeah a good dab of Skittles
can do that for me
too I got some Skittles rosin right now
I haven't had any good Skittles I
haven't had any Skittles rosin lately I
did get some uh Mountain Man melt some
their kmy yeah that was fire nice there
I like that because it gave me what I
liked it gave me the gassy but I also
had that Z background to it I thought
that was pretty fire you got the little
punch but also the FL exactly yeah I
like the papaya crosses too there's a
lot of papaya stuff going around that
smokes amazing in rosin yep it's great
when I get like I like it when they come
in hash holes yeah um also it's like
when you're going to give me I want that
diverseness so if you're giving me if
you're giving me the papaya like roll it
in some biscotti yeah like [ __ ] give
me that gas with that super sweet little
punch switch it up don't put your
Skittles with your Skittles you can do
that but I feel like it's in that that
is complimentary in a different way but
I feel like using the diversity that's
the beauty is like blending wine or
blending whatever hairing it is [ __ ]
awesome if you got that skill too the
guys that are blending rosin now too
where they're taking two different
things putting them together you're
getting some amazing stuff out of that
actually shout out steuart doinks he
just won the proper uh the
um uh preferred Gardens uh dink rolloff
after like couple week long competition
we were in
Hawaii congrats Drew and who's the man
[ __ ] a amazing wedding you guys are
the best we were in Hawaii while he was
winning so it didn't really get the
attention from us it it it should have
but right uh he had some of those and if
I wasn't so high I could maybe remember
what the combo was but whatever the
winning combo was and you can look it up
on his page that was it was such a
killer combination of two different FL
like diverse enough to where you're like
okay you're the first three or four hits
you're like and then that hash starts
kicking in you're like wow that's
[ __ ] just like gives you this extra
little flavor blast in there it was
pretty nice yeah good stuff yeah so if
you had one piece of advice for your
younger self that was coming up in the
industry what would that one piece of
advice
be don't blow all your [ __ ]
money I had so many snowboards and
snowboarding jackets and [ __ ] Jordans
that I would have rather Sushi dinners
those were worth it because they were
community building right I had a homie
who gave me the best advice that I never
followed and I kick myself all the time
he was like T blow all your money on
[ __ ] he's like I know you like
spending money I like spending money
he's like I go buy gold coins they're an
ounce
each he's like and this at this time
they were 350 an ounce I remember those
the same as an ounce of weed he's like
so one of you know one ounce out of
every pound you go spend that money and
on a [ __ ] on a gold coin he took me
to his house one day and you might have
him you might have him your parents
probably have them they had these
picture books from like the 70s with
like super colors on the front and like
had a little spiral plastic thing and
each page and this dude had a [ __ ]
gold coin in each one of these things
and we were like 19 or 20 or whatever
and I don't know when or if he I don't
talk to him too much I wish I did but I
don't it was the best piece of advice
because I don't know if he sold them or
kept them or did some of both but the
ones he was buying at 350 and under are
now what 2,000 2,000 bucks
Z400 right that was the advice I wish I
would have followed and I wish I
wouldn't have spent all my money flexing
yeah cuz that's all it was you know once
I got my car it had beat and rims and
tinted windows because I thought I was
[ __ ] cool right and really had I
bought property would have been much
[ __ ] better Real Estate gold yeah
gold crypto yeah all these things now
crypto was like it took me a long time
to believe in crypto in the first two or
three times I invested I lost everything
so Doge come back no um but crypto's
wild yeah it took somebody really smart
to half explain how crypto worked now
was still was like it's still unicorn
money he's like it's basically unicorn
money he's like this if we both agree
it's a million bucks is a million bucks
and that's kind of basically how crypto
works and I'm like I'm on a super super
basic that's how Mone Works to 100%
right but we're not taught that as a as
children you know paper money and coin
jingle jangle it's that's how you need
it you need that like you both have to
agree that it's worth that for it to be
worth that you know so we're told it's
worth that yeah and it's been but we're
indoctrinated into believing that
because it's been our whole life way now
somebody's like I got this new money
yeah it's 97 digits long and you never
hold it or it doesn't jingle it doesn't
fold you'll never see it until you pull
it out of the bank yeah you know but
this not I don't know how many [ __ ]
numbers there are you know there's 150
numbers in your [ __ ] in your Bitcoin
address whatever it is but yeah this
this this is your uh this is your money
value right here like you sure but today
it's worth 500 bucks less than it was
worth yesterday but next week it'll be
worth 300 bucks
more okay I got a little bit I lost a
bunch but I got I you know I got a
little bit we'll see how that plays out
I like the I like the precious metals me
too yeah me too and the gold standard
may go we may go back to the gold
standard before too long this is not
good investing advice but maybe gold
ounces are worth gold is interesting and
silver is interesting and I think you
shouldn't just look at working at 9o5
you should look at Investments I think a
young thing thing that young people can
do is look at Investments look at the
future not just so linear you know it's
like smart man told me the way to be
rich is to make money while you sleep
yeah figure how to make money while you
sleep how figure how to make your money
make money for you yeah whatever you do
you got to do but you that you're using
that to be you and probably don't yeah
that's stay out of the canis industry if
you want to make money I mean it
technically makes money while you sleep
it's just man one mistake like we talked
about ear curing or [ __ ] drying or
flushing and it has no value or such a
little value well the value is the
lesson you learned hopefully yep
hopefully someone will blast it and I
can get some BH right yeah so it can
pass test
remediation yeah that's the beauty of
this world we live in now you can
remediate stuff out of stuff it's wild
but uh if people are trying to find out
more about Turtle pie company and about
yourself where should they go that's
actually a beautiful question because
that's something I want to talk about so
ironically couple of weeks ago we did a
post about how I was switching my
posting Philosophy for Instagram because
of all of the [ __ ] that goes on when I
just post weed like I'm not allowed to
post weed there I've seen they change
their toou but then you and and they are
allowed to but then you do and you still
get dink so I did this post saying my
new philosophy is just to post content
or goofy [ __ ] or whatever and not so
much weed porn yeah my my account was
attacked so bad that it probably almost
got shut down like for whatever reason
people took that as a challenge to get
my [ __ ] shut down if it was people or
some person like I every every picture
that was archiv like everything got
reported and I'm like what the [ __ ] is
going on here and as I've already known
for years like it's it's an important
tool to have in in the industry that
we're in but we're making a conscious
move to Twitter X because as disturbing
as I find a lot of the [ __ ] on that
platform at least I can post [ __ ]
weed and talk about it and not get my
account taken down it's it's like I feel
like I'm
moving backwards to go forward um and
like I got my I haven't used Twitter in
so long like I got my assistant like I
need you to give me the crash course on
how to use [ __ ] Twitter and we got to
start posting on it every day and just
blast weed porn on it and on our
Instagram I want to [ __ ] want to see
our new strain follow us on Twitter you
know what I mean because I don't feel
comfortable right posting what I feel
like we should be able to post at this
time yeah I I I don't use certain words
we have for a long time we don't use
drop or [ __ ] coming soon like we
don't imply that it's for sale we don't
expressly imply that it's for sale
clearly it's for sale it's a commodity
it's a legal commodity especially in the
state of California and [ __ ] damn
more than half the country um so yeah
follow us on Instagram turtle pyo turtle
pyo CA is our backup we do post a little
more weed on that one it's a a lot less
to take a little more risks yeah yeah
take a little more risks on that one and
then so yeah turtle power phone5 on
Twitter we're going to be as active as
we can be on there posting content that
we can we're still doing content like I
did I did some bacon yesterday I made a
soup yesterday that'll be on the
Instagram you know keep it fluffy keep
it nice keep it goofy whatever engaging
made a fire ass pumpkin pie with real
pumpkin like bake the pumpkin it was
[ __ ] great see it on my Instagram
Turtle pie co um Turtle pie co yeah and
you have to try type out the whole thing
Turtle pie company the whole thing uh or
cuz we're so band it won't come up
either sorry the [ __ ] Skittles got my
heart so harde I'm so turned up from
that Wei right now so Turtle pie have
you ever had Turtle pie if we're talking
the dessert [ __ ] yeah if we're talking
pies with Turtle meat absolutely not we
did a we sponsor it's funny you say we
sponsored a a reggae show on the big
island it was great cuz they they were
like on the radio station for like three
weeks it was like sponsored by turtle
and like this one dude came out to me
he's like in his super Hawaiian accent
that I'm not going to Butcher and he was
like guys put [ __ ] turtles in a pie
we're like absolutely not it's caramel
chocolate peans graham cracker he's like
the tongin put turtles in pie and I was
like I don't okay I don't we definitely
no turtles were harmed in the making of
any of our P this is not a shepher pie
with turtles this is a I love Turtles
they're [ __ ] great totally all the
turtle [ __ ] you guys send me I [ __ ]
love it cracking up well thank you so
much for coming on the podcast D let's
do this again F I'm gonna pop some of
these [ __ ] seeds and have you check
them out I can't wait to smoke some of
these new fenal with you we're ready
yeah [ __ ] a thank you absolutely y
looking forward to thank you everybody
good
night thank you guys for watching please
like And subscribe down below he