[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James loud
podcast and today our special guest is
Sergio picazo from cultivated and the
connect Community how you doing today
Sergio hey I'm I'm blessed thanks for
having me on James absolutely man you
have some great events going on the
connected community and the connected
events are fantastic I really like the
concept I think it's thanks man a modern
and fresh version of what other people
have tried to do in the past and I think
it works really well with the community
especially in the state we're in it gets
everybody together once a month and I
love it thank you I mean that's that's
the goal we just want to have a safe
place for networking and leveling each
other up education is something that we
all want to try to find good information
from and sources is hard to come by so
I'm I mean that's that's the cool thing
that the people that participate in
these panel discussions on whatever
topic uh whatever topic it might be
they're giving us a lot of Great Value
so just continue to grow that that
educational bank is really giving us a a
proper platform to really start leveling
each other up and the food is good and
the food is great food guy you know it's
a you know I love I love good food and
you've always had good food so yeah
we've had uh a bunch of different
flavors and know we've had we just had
schwarma the other day we had we've had
artisanal Pizza we've had Smash Burgers
so yeah I mean it we definitely have a
good variety yeah there's something to
look forward to every month yes so let's
dive into a little bit about your
history tell me about the first time you
started smoking sure yeah so I was know
I was in Middle School um it was
actually kind of funny the first time
that I thought I smoked um one of the
homies actually brought oregano to the
party and uh yeah that let's just say
that was not a fun first time experience
but um yeah he he definitely didn't make
it back into the circle for those uh in
the future but um I actually started
smoking um one of the homies dads had a
club card and so he was always coming to
the Oakland shops and you know he he
always had a good stash of like Northern
Lights and Tangi so like real Citrus
forward tur profiles so from the early
on days like I was I was getting some
great flavors and so that's really kind
of what got me into it was you know
Finding uh that we had a consistent
source and you know being an athlete in
middle school you know that kind of led
into high school being you know the
athlete plug so you know wanted to smoke
for free so it was a great way to get a
zip and you know continue to hold back
that eth and just enjoy it totally yeah
and
so back back then what were your
favorite genetics what were the favorite
yeah I got to stick you know nl5 was
probably the one that really resonates
with me you know that's it's just so
nostalgic and you know back then you
know the the other homies plugged like
we just had a bunch of you know really
nice sticky weed coming through and you
know we don't really know what the
genetics were we just knew that it was s
you know super sticky and it was The
Chronic it was either it was either
chronic or it wasn't yeah we had green
and brown yeah and there was you know
yeah The Chronic was definitely yeah
amazing so what area was this in um this
I grew up in the East Bay so uh born in
San Francisco I grew up in the East Bay
in a town called Danville oh yeah and uh
so yeah man I was I was blessed to uh to
live in that area you know there's a lot
of uh it's an affluent area you know so
I had a lot yeah I used to live in Alamo
yeah yeah Alam was beautiful you know
Blue Blue Ribbon School Districts and uh
you know shout out to my parents because
you know they both came from Mexico
first generation immigrant so we really
didn't have much growing up you know so
we were living in San Jose and you know
my dad was a garbage man you know so
came to this country with nothing and
started from the bottom attic garbage
company and eventually got promoted to
be a supervisor so he was able to get us
out of San Jose and moved into Danville
in 1989 yeah Danville is awesome yeah I
can't speak highly enough about Danville
uh you know in the you know I grew up 15
miles away yeah so 10 10 miles away uh
North and the flower was good the flower
was really good and I started smoking
like ' 91 sure but all the flour back
then there was good flour obviously
there was bad fler too but right you
know really really some amazing stuff
and we had you know being in the Bay
Area we had the widest variety of
genetics we did you know you saw the
white widows come through you know you
saw the train wrecks like all of the you
know DJ Schwarz blueberry all the
schools all the Cal I mean a lot of the
stuff was created in California but we
had a lot of the European stuff too you
know we had the skunks we had real skunk
we never called it roadkill skunk that I
remember but we had cat piss and that's
a big topic of debate you know but our
the Bay Area cat piss was the the real
deal I never I I I don't recall ever
getting a chance to try the capis back
that back in that area but you're right
you know there's there's a lot of uh
debate around well is it just some sort
of a profile that happened when it was
sitting in the trunk and you know
something happened along the way well I
think it's a an aroma yeah so it's hard
to call a genetic cat piss and say I was
the one that created cat piss because I
feel like sometimes flower you know in
breeding you come across stuff that
smells ammonia and people relate the
smell of ammonia to urine right and so
then we get cat piss and so I've heard
about people talking about catpiss back
in the 70s we're doing a little
documentary this year uh on cat piss so
I'm super excited about that I feel like
there's a lot of origin stories people
have some great stories to tell um and
verified stories that are verified from
other people as well and yeah I just
reconnected with some of my friends that
uh knew a lot more about the origins of
the ciss that we had and so I believe
there's different cat pisses I don't
think there's
just one one ring to rule them all right
you know so but there's a lot of schmeel
out there so yeah it's really
interesting so Bay Area High School what
did you play in high school sports yeah
I was wrestling in football so you know
one season ended the other one started
so yeah um but it was cool you know I
was Captain of both my teams and you
know that that really instilled a lot of
leadership qualities in me at an early
age so I think that was one of the
things that I really enjoyed was people
and just really being able to inspire
and motivate has has transitioned into
my professional career path along all
the different industries that I've
worked in from culinary to mortgages to
uh commercial Trucking to hospitality
and now you know all the way in in
Canabis and and genetics and you know
all of these different things have kind
of led up to some some skill sets that I
never would have required if I hadn't
tasted a lot of different things so so a
lot of people watching the show know I'm
a chef or the ones that don't know they
do and uh you have some culinary history
so let's dive into that real quick yeah
so I mean right out of high school I I
knew that I wanted to go into the
culinary program here at DVC and in
conquered um that was a thing like
growing up in a Mexican household we
were always cooking so I was always
helping my parents prep I was always
helping like understand what's going on
in the kitchen because I love to eat
yeah so that was really inspiring and
you know back then there was no Food
Network it was emerald agosi and Yan can
cook right so I wanted to be that next
Emerald Agassi you know just really
having fun whipping up cool flavors and
that was a thing like we didn't you know
we didn't have much growing up so my mom
was always encouraging us to get
creative right open up we don't have
anything to eat we'll open up the fridge
and she'll whip up this badass meal so
that was always like okay how can we
start to mesh different flavor profiles
so right out of the gate like I didn't
it's not like I was a bad student I just
wasn't inspired by school and I think
that was you know part of the reason why
I wanted to jump right into culinary was
because I I had this aspiration to have
my own cooking show and just you know
really get em embedded into the industry
yeah so let's fast forward um I did the
program for about a year and a half I
helped somebody open a restaurant that
was actually a graduate from the program
and I saw firsthand how opening a
restaurant was and that is not what I
wanted to get into or that wasn't the
life that I wanted I'm I have a lot of
respect for restaurant tours and you
know when you're 19 20 years old and
living that kind of a that kind of a
lifestyle it was it was a lot so it
really it opened my eyes to what I
didn't want to do but I learned all
these awesome skill sets along the way
with knife skills and how that you know
this the size of a brunoa cut will be
able to actually elaborate on your
pallet as opposed to a Julien or these
different type of cuts of of vegetables
so or how important it is to cut your
vegetables all the same size 100%
uniformity uniformity is huge uh but I
feel like the people in the restaurant
industry can very easily translate into
agriculture or cannabis big time uh and
vice versa they're both industries of
passion right they should be driven by
Passion otherwise you'll just you're not
going to be able to make it and I feel
like the culinary arts it's a young
man's career uh you know especially
working long hours you work on the line
you can you can do that for a while I
don't think you can do that forever yeah
some people can I have some friends that
are chefs that have been chefs forever
and they you know they love it and uh
it's a lifestyle too just like is it's a
lifestyle exactly you have to be
passionate for what you're doing every
single day and just being happy so I
realized that I was unhappy at certain
parts of that career path and then you
know it opened my eyes to what again
just tasting things that I know that I
don't want to go back to um however I
did walk away from that with you know um
a food safety certification like San you
know that's where clean behaviors and
clean practices have really applied into
the nursery space you know and I think
that was really it was a cultural set
you know and understanding like there is
uh there's definitely practices within a
nursery environment where you don't want
to cross contaminate you know that the
vroid is crazy you know pathogenic
pressure is a reality in what we have to
deal with today in commercial
cultivation so just you know going
through a room and defoliating going
plant to plant whatever was on your
hands just you just contaminated that
next Plant right so it's you know we've
already talked about Vector transmission
and you know making sure that you clean
your tools properly like ISO does not
clean and sterilize your tools it
stabilizes stabilizes the viroid right
so RNA versus DNA you got to properly
sanitize that 2% Veron 15 20% bleach 30
to 60 seconds scrub and agitate like
there's a whole system so when you're
operating at scale like what are these
practices is that you're that you're
implementing with your team right so do
you have a set of shears per table do
you have uh you know handwashing
stations do you require a team to change
gloves before they defoliate from table
to table just things that you know you
should really be cognizant of because
it's all about the mother stock right
yeah well and it's all about culture we
culture and people you know Sops are a
piece of paper you got to get people to
actually follow those people the pieces
of paper to actually you know Implement
everything that you're talking about
trying to get them to do that's the only
way to really do it and you know it's
funny because the kitchen is a great
place they don't have Sops in the
kitchen they do but they don't call them
Sops necessarily we've been using these
things for years exactly so at DVC I
used to judge some of the cooking
competitions I was the president of the
San Francisco Chef's association in 2008
that's cool and so with yeah so I I did
a lot of that stuff and we judge over a
DVC and then they had like the
gingerbread houses and I'm I'm a big
gingerbread house guy
um I've made some huge you know six foot
tall gingerbread houses and stuff like
that so yeah I mean the culinary
industry was great because again I I I
learned a different appreciation for
flavor profiling with food and wine and
again that kind of like led into my
passion for genetics and how combining
combination of flavors and you know
Finding unique uh combinations like yeah
that that was a very instrumental part
of my Foundation nice but um but you
know that moved into mortgages right so
we had a we had a mortgage broker that
was always coming into the restaurant
every day and you know we chopped it up
while I was making his his sandwich or
his Panini or whatever it was going on
and he's like yo you should probably you
know I'd like for you to come by my
office talk to me you're you're
personable I'm like cool thanks man do
you want extra you want pesto sauce on
this today you know it's just kind of
you know right it was one of those
things where I didn't realize like what
was mortgages I didn't understand what
he was talking about so um I went by
he's like yo I want you to hop on the
phones from you know 5:00 p.m. to 7:00
p.m. just cold call like what am I
saying and so it was just asking people
if they're looking to refinance and that
was like the Mind map of okay yes well
what are you refinancing for I want I
want to lower rate okay well that's the
next set of questions and then maybe the
other question was well I want to uh
debt consolidate okay well next set of
questions I didn't realize that you know
solution selling was a thing until I
went through and understood how you can
offer Solutions without selling
something right so this whole value
proposition based selling or you know
consultative approach was something that
I really appreciated because what I
learned in cold calling was some will
some won't so what next but you're still
saving money with a solution yeah and so
that's how you evolved into a Solutions
based company I'm a firm believer of
being Solutions based I think you don't
need to sell a product if you come up
with a solution you're not you know you
showcase what you're doing and what you
do best and let your product speak for
itself right exactly and that's you know
that was a a great learning experience
so you know from mortgages I went into
the commercial truck industry you know
after the crash there you know obviously
there was a lot of change happening and
you know I was um I fortunately was able
to sell my house at the time and walk
away without going upside down so you
know I was in a very um I was in a
blessed situation again you know my
parents are foundational I've had so
much support from them along the way uh
you know when they retired in like you
know mid 2000s right around there uh you
know they they pulled some cash out of
the house we lived in in Danville they
moved up to plumis Lake so I assumed
their mortgage right cuz I I was
generating income as a loan officer so I
qualified to take on that responsibility
so I was like you know 22 years old with
a mortgage in Danville and so I was I I
learned a lot at that stage and so and
that $850,000 house is probably worth
about 2.5 million right easily yeah so
you know and that was the scary part
it's like oh man you know the market
like I was about to go upside down
unfortunately somebody gave us you know
that break even point so we accepted it
walked away started from nothing at that
point so you know I moved up to Northern
California or I'm sorry to Sacramento
and uh you know my brother was an
executive with a company called
International uh truck and engine
Corporation and so he was like yo
There's an opportunity up there you
should check it out um you'd be
basically be like an assistant to the
you know the regional director so I'm
like sure what does that even mean right
so again I I didn't I didn't go to
college I didn't do I didn't get my
degree in anything it was more about
finding opportunities that came my way
based on who I was and just you know
putting off Good Vibes and ultimately
that led me to this particular role
which was really like an engineering
role and so I learned how um specking
out commercial trucks with the chassis
and the bodies and the engine and the
transmission and all these different
things that go into specific requirement
to um you know applications right the
state of California and V Safeway like
that was like our two major accounts so
being able to understand how these RFP
processes come through and we have to
spec out a specific model of a truck
that was some pretty intense engineering
stuff but I'm like I get this so it was
all computer base right so I I was a
gamer I was a kid growing up in the 90s
you know Sega Genesis was something that
you know I invested a lot of time into
Nintendo and you know what was your
favorite game on Sega Genesis oh Sonic I
was oh yeah but then you know as I got a
little bit older I went into like Mortal
Kombat right so you know that was the
that was the cool thing like I picked up
some skill sets along the way and you
know that opportunity actually brought
me here to work at a a dealership
offering Solutions at scale was another
skill set that I just you know I really
started Rec iing that I really enjoyed
nice how did you Branch off into the
Cannabis industry so after the after the
commercial Trucking industry um I had an
opportunity to join a team in the
hospitality space so being like a
territory manager you know working in
the Bay area again like it was a
recommendation from one of my brother's
friends that he went to you know went to
school with like yo I think you should
check out this role I think you'd be
really good at it it was just you know
account management walking into hotels
seeing what kind of products that they
sold and basically you know just
Consolidated all that so while I was in
that role I learned a lot about you know
organization and and and time management
because being able to manage 150
accounts in the Bay Area you got to be
very strategic with your time yeah so
utilizing technology and you know I was
just I was the youngest territory
manager in the company out of a team of
like a hundred different TMS you know I
was like 24 at that time and so coming
into you know the role all the other
sales reps in that company were probably
average you know 30 to 40 years old and
you know that that allowed to kind of
shine and show what I did with my
organizational skill sets using
technology I think that was one thing
that really wasn't being emphasized to
be efficient in the field so that led to
me getting promoted very quickly to a
district manager and as I was on a ride
along in Northern California um you know
we're kind of cruising down the street
on the 80 and you know I see a billboard
for dispensary oh that's so cool you
know they're they're advertising butt up
on the billboard and my rep's like you
know I probably shouldn't tell you this
but you know my husband's in the
industry
and I was like that's awesome tell me
more and so that conversation led to an
introduction that introduction led to me
investing into that organization um so
we had to prop 215 Nursery up in uh you
know West Sacramento and you know let's
just say that the um you know there was
a plan to get into the 64 space um you
know that was 2016 so that's when I
first got like introduced to the
industry at that point oh because I
wasn't I wasn't fliping packs or
anything in the past I was more of you
know I was I was selling to to smoke for
free right so that was never really my
world not trying to claim I was that's
just that wasn't me but when I saw the
genetics aspect of what they were doing
I'm like cool you got a nursery that's
awesome and of course at the time like
the only uh visibility I saw to Nursery
were like those YouTube videos that
Kevin jodry put up from Wonderland you
know and that was that was pretty badass
you know for Kevin to like walk us
through and showcase what they were
doing there so shout out Kevin like you
truly inspired me man um yeah he got the
Skittles cut spread out all over from
Wonderland Nursery that's it yeah big
shout out to Kevin big shout out to Kev
and um so yeah that was my first
introduction into the space um let's
just say that that project didn't go
where it was supposed to and you know I
saw I I learned a lot from that
experience it was a very costly
experience so I utilized that and said
you know what I want to do this I want
to do this the right way and here's
here's the vision I want to have an
indoor clean Nursery with verified
trusted Cuts right and working with the
Breeders and really making sure that
they that the attribution piece was
there
yeah and so you know um shot had
basically just started looking around to
see if there's any opportunities out
there for a you know for a c a building
with a cup there was nothing like there
is today like you can you can just
Google uh you know a building with a c a
conditional use permit so you can
actually cultivate and sayate nothing
like that existed so this was pre 20108
yeah this was this was like end of
middle of 2017 right around there yeah
so this is like medical about to go
wreck we know it's going wreck but it
was still I mean it's changed a lot
right in six years a lot exactly so you
know we had an opportunity from you know
somebody we knew knew another person
that had a building that was offering a
lease on a suite within a building with
the cup so you know we checked it out
and you know we ended up going through
with that but um I kind of skipped over
like the whole aspect of you know we
didn't have any investors I believed in
what we wanted to do so I sold my house
I was living in W the creek and so I
sold my house and you know basically
funded the buildout you know and I and I
started cultivated with four other
partners and we each brought our own
unique Skillets you know to build out
the facility to operate the facility and
that was really cool you know like we we
learned everything from the ground up so
from you know from the buildout phase
like that was that was a unique
experience uh you know there did it take
you twice as long and was it twice as
expensive as you originally thought
let's just say we paid the Cannabis tax
yes my performa invoice right I didn't
even know the hell of performa was so
like I taught myself all these things
along the way and so building out a a
you know a performa to understand what
budgeting was and I'm like okay well
I've got this much Capital to deploy in
that project and you know of course it
was like 50% less than what I had and so
by the time that the project was
actually done I had invested everything
that I had so I liquidated my 401k I
sold my house so I even sold my car
because we were to that point of like
you know the buildout was so dragged on
and you know this was the part of like
you know going through the Sacramento um
Building Division like bless their heart
because they want to know they want to
understand what it is that we're trying
to do and you know it was it was there
was a massive delay in like the
communication so um they've gotten a lot
better you know understanding what we
what we do as operators and stuff but
still it was the buildout process was
going way too long and we were paying
rent the entire time so I was just
hemorrhaging funds it's a tough County
to do work in you know I mean I think
they've changed a lot in the last six
years but it's definitely to break into
that area is tough right uh the power
company there is no joke it's much
different than other parts in California
yeah lot of fun lot of fun man so you
know we we fortunately were able to get
you know get all the sign offs and
everything so I remember Christmas Eve
on January I'm sorry December of 2019
you know we had we had gotten our
inspection finalized we already had
plants in so you know I I want to give a
shout out to uh to Dan at no last
because you know I saw this this post
from Kevin jod that he was at the
emerald cup with node and tissue culture
I'm like what the hell is tissue culture
um you know that's really where the the
idea of having this trusted healthy
clean Nursery with verified Cuts was was
formed so I just hit Dan up on on a DM
and he responded I'm like oh [__] like
this is this is happening so we just we
really developed a relationship from
there and just explained to him like
look man we want to we we don't want to
get into the TC side we just want to be
a propagation Nursery a trusted start
for people you know and just doing it
the right way and just you know
emphasizing relationships and we're not
just a transactional company like we're
part of your business we're an extension
of your farm so it worked great you know
we you know we brought in all of our
genetics from t uh from TC so gen zero
and we were selling first gen Cuts you
know that was that's how cultivated was
born so you know the the real special
part was like we did this all ourselves
like me and my partners and my mom and
dad like my mom and dad were so
supportive like they didn't want to get
paid they were there helping out they
were you know my dad was there on
Christmas Eve cutting clones their very
first batch of clones on Christmas Eve
and I I I will never forget that moment
and I was like this is happening you
know I've gone all in you know they
didn't they didn't like harass me or
anything like what are you doing like
going and doing something you've never
done you just literally liquidated your
entire life savings into something that
you're you know you've never done before
so um it was cool they're just hella
supportive and ultimately like they were
the ones that were sitting on that prop
table cutting you know propping
thousands of clones so from the very
GetGo like my parents were were in there
they were grinding with us and you know
there came to a point to where we're
like we were really getting scale and so
we had to hire employees and that's I'm
like guys you have to get paid like
legally you need to get paid here so you
know it was it was cool so my parents
were our first employees of cultivated
genetics that's where the Familia came
in the play really cool yeah man and you
know they've been super foundational in
everything that I've done so I couldn't
be more grateful are they still working
with you um no no my my my parents are
retired you know they've they put in
their time and you know fortunately
cultivated is on a on a good pathway
right now and really stabilized nice
yeah so tell me about some of the Gen
you guys have that you're excited about
James I would love to say that we had a
more diverse profile of a library but
got to give the market what they want
that's candies you know from a
commercial perspective like purple candy
gas you got it yeah so you know we've
we've had a very diverse Library like
really cool flavors from compound from
Midwest best from Full Moon genetics
like we've got some great genetics that
we've ran through but you know as I've
been connected with you know the the
commercial cultivators in the bulk space
and a lot of the wholesale buyers I've
got to I've got to see a lot of the
demand and what the requests are yeah
we're not fighting it it's it's just
it's commercial right now bulk candy
that's it so when I was in colonary
school I was told uh the best marget
marketing strategy is give the baby what
the baby wants correct right and so the
baby being all of our customers yeah and
whatever they want you know they want
purple candy gas right now that's it it
won't be like that forever I don't
believe that I think gas is coming back
I think Sour's coming back I think
interesting genetics beyond the purple
candy gas are making a comeback the piff
you know we're going to get some hazes
coming back and I think sure this stuff
takes time and you know there's es and
flows
and uh you know we're just in the purple
candy gas phase and we've been through
other phases before and this too shall
pass of course and you know we're we're
leaning into it you know we've been
working with the good greens candy
collection uh shout out Joan Phil from
good greens like you know we're we're
we're taking candy and just giving it a
Twist you know so we're finding a lot of
great great Keepers coming out of there
with very low intersect traits by the
way because when you start going through
the population of you know a lot of
gelados and just you know just crossed
within like intersect are a challenge so
fortunately we've had these things
tested with a bunch of different
cultivators in our community and we're
seeing some really good results we've
got some great selections we're actually
harvesting on Monday um on uh up up at
Kush Alley we're down in Kush alley so
really uh really happy to see what we
can where we're going to get coming out
here and get those new flavors out there
yeah so stress testing is a big
important thing that I don't think a lot
of people are doing enough of although
that's changing I think there's
awareness now at least for sure um and
just cuz one of the parent has it
doesn't mean it'll get passed on and
expressed heavily right but you need to
stress test it and find out I think
those are the type of things especially
for commercial viability if you're a
home grower it's not as big of a deal
you go buy some 10 pack of seeds and a
couple of them have intersec traes and
you find something that you really like
that's amazing uh you know I think
there's some really good cultivars as
far as taste and appeal but on a
commercial scale it's a little bit
different right so like when somebody
has aund lights of one thing or even 10
lights right MH you don't want a seed
you don't want a bunch of seeds of
course one seed is not a big deal a
bunch of seeds is an issue stress
testing is massive right commercial
viability and really understanding you
know we have a bunch of different
cultivators in the network that want to
help test with us that want to be a part
of the part of the journey you know and
I think people saw that with the glitter
bomb project that we did you know
releasing glitter bomb in a fast was
pretty cool we had Caesar on the show
yeah man shout out to Caesar like we we
we saw how this project can work where
you know you get something really cool
and special out to the group people we
all grow it we showcase you know the the
genetic potential of this thing but
again kind of coming back to the whole
stress testing there's specific
facilities that have their challenges so
I want to make sure that they get their
rounds with it too because that's going
to give us uh certain environmental
condition challenges certain uh
inconsistencies with um with a lot of
different factors so stress testing is
massive man and that's that's just
that's what comes back to us and really
what goes into the TC lab what's going
to go through Mir stem because that's
costly right you got to invest into that
stuff yeah the miror stem I it's it's
super important to uh get it down to the
callus and then replicate and clean it
and then be able to replicate from that
and I think the cleaning part is
challenging and there's not a lot of
people that can do it shout out to
apical biotech Justin over there and
Matt those guys are doing the Lord's
work in so many ways yes you know
they're our business partners and your
business partner as well and yeah really
good stuff and I I think the people
don't fully have a you know grasp on
what tissue culture is necessarily they
you know but but what they're doing is
something special you know and it's a
little bit different than doing Nole
it's a little bit different than the
stuff you can do at home um and you know
but that's the future and also pathogen
indexing is so important right so like
we get into pathogen indexing and being
able to verify that your stuff is clean
and being able to show your customers
that it's clean right um all that stuff
is huge it's it's massive and and I'm
glad you touched on the difference of
what Nole versus marem is I mean not a
lot of people can do meristem and I
think that's the reality people think
that they're getting their genetics
clean fully cleaned and restored when
they're just getting Nally propagated
which there's a there's a use for noal
there's benefit to it absolutely but
it's not getting down to the to the
cleanest form of that marem right so
that that I mean that's the that's the
kicker right there so being able to find
the winners that we want to be able to
commercialize and really put out to
skill because again the commercial
validation process takes time this is
not just an F1 release this takes years
to actually do variety testing and
phenotypic studies it takes a year
minimum to properly do it and to get
your selections and to prove them and
you know I think a lot of people they
find something good and then they
release it
and you know and that's okay too but I
think the the real process takes a lot
longer and it's a marathon and not a
Sprint so no doubt but you know I I I I
hope that the professional maturity of
the industry does gravitate towards more
gas and you know all these great flavors
that we want to bring back in unique
complexity because right now it's just
candy you know and understanding that
that's it's it's we're not fighting it
we're just we're we're making sure that
the cultivators that we work with are
positioned for the best possible outcome
with the highest tickets so really
emphasizing quality you know and I think
that's what we were kind of talking off
the mic was we have tools like shout out
to aoya that has this tool that we can
measure
and you know substrate water content and
EC and making sure that we're in a
parameter of an irrigation strategy for
a small Bud trait like a candy yeah
right so we want to make sure we can hit
these hit these optimal yields with
quality emphasis so being able to deploy
genetics that have uh irrigation
strategies is important that's why I I
handle all the sales at cultivated
because I want to make sure people are
getting what they uh you know what they
should be geared for so if you're if
you're calling me up and saying hey what
do you got on the menu I'm going to ask
you one question are you are you just in
the bulk Market CU if you are you're I'm
going to I'm only going to offer you
white run or Lemon Cherry gelato or soon
to come g33 and you know just being able
to just have that on the menu and be
able to say this is how you can irrigate
it to you know get your 80 grams of
square foot with quality behind it we
got buyers asking where's the stuff at
who's got the fire you know now it's a
battle of quality and there's price
points for everything so well I think
more breeders need to start sneaking in
stuff and Crossing them with the candy
um you know not tricking people but at
the same time reintroducing those
flavors in something that's approachable
no doubt um that's what I'm looking
forward to and I think people are
starting to do it I think we're getting
a lot of interesting Expressions coming
out and that gets candy along with some
other
Funk um that's not just GMO not that
there's anything wrong with that donning
burger GMO I think those are great I
think they have their place for sure
they do yeah but but you're right about
the uniqueness of of flavor profiling
and I think we also touched on that
earlier was like yo there's so many
different flavors sub subjective
profiles but we can really hone in on
certain things when we're hunting
through the progy I need that unique
Twist on the candy and I think that's
that's again that's where the good
greens candy collection has that new age
Twist of candies so you know we're
excited to be hunting through this stuff
and I know that seed release is coming
in the near future but um you know I'm
just I'm excited for the future of of
the genetic breeding projects that are
all going on I mean you've got a lot of
great work too I would love to get a
pheno or two from the you know from your
bank that we can put in and and let the
market enjoy CU you got a lot of great Z
crosses that are productive that are
mold resistant that have Vigor that fit
the 9we window you know like there's
there's a lot of stuff that I would love
to bring in from you yeah we're working
on some stuff that's way less than nine
weeks which I think has a lot of
Commercial
Appeal um but yeah I think right now you
just got to fit that specific profile
it's got to be candy color is in demand
like it doesn't have color it's so funny
because I feel like that being a
qualifier is just you know we want all
these things and it's it's almost
counterintuitive sure so especially if
you like Flavor I don't know it's just
one of those things yeah man it's again
this kind of goes back to the commercial
validation aspect if it doesn't fit
within at at most that ninee window I
mean you're trying to get that those
five and a half turns a year right I
mean if it doesn't fit within that
window then you know an INF arrogation
strategy is just such a hard thing to
accomplish within your facility and you
can't manage without measurement so if
you're not on any substrate monitoring
or sensors sensor Tech implementation
good luck so I got an interesting
question the other day about when do you
start counting days of flow and uh I've
always counted from the day you flip the
lights that's that's the first day of
flower when you go photo period 122 some
people they start counting from the
first day you see actual flowers on the
butts and I thought that was really
interesting because there's this big
confusion and either way could be right
if as long as you're doing it
consistently that way I mean exact
consistency is key however you're
tracking or managing whatever time frame
it is I'm just looking at from you go 12
from when you go 122 to full maturation
at Harvest so whether you're going you
know s to 10 days on on your on your
stretch period and you're going
generatively and you're flipping back to
you know to bulking at like week three
or maybe even if you're dealing with
candies you're you're shortening up that
window and flipping to bulking at day 14
trying to finish a day 53 yeah right yes
cuz I feel like Skittles that's like 50
day 53 to day 56 if you go to day
63 it's it's okay and it's it's got some
interesting flavor but it's not as candy
as if you pull it somewhere between day
53 and day 56 and if you let it go long
a little bit longer you're going to have
more of an over ripened you know tur
profile right and that's ABS that's
that's good criteria to let the
cultivator know it's like yo if you're
growing this these are the things that
you need to look out for if you're going
to be washing this maybe you need to
pull it a little bit earlier right so
some of those some of those genetic
profiling tips is what we're emphasizing
you know that's just having a manageable
Erp and data database to manage these
recipes and to be able to deploy them at
scale that's you know that's why it's
great having these systems in place
right it's really all about data points
with everything in life whether you're
cooking you know the The Culinary World
totally translates to cannabis in the
sense of developing a pallet right right
and I have my book coming out and
there's a Hu there's a whole chapter on
developing a pallet but it's just
collecting a bunch of data points and
the more data points you start to
understand it better the more times
you've experienced it you understand
what you like what you don't like uh you
know it's like rose I love the rose
turps right like rose is amazing but
there's it's not just one thing we have
rose petals we have rose water we have
you know there's so many different roses
like literally there's fresh Rose off
the stem there there's more floral side
to it um you know and there's there's
five different or six different roses
that I can think of right off the top of
my head that's it and starting with your
core base of fruit floral Fuel and Earth
right like where do you Branch off from
there and finding unique within those
criteria points so no that's that's
really I want to come back to your book
man like I know we've been talking about
Barcelona coming up and you know I'm I'm
blessed for the opportunity that the
connect Community is growing at such a
pace that we have support to get it out
to Barcelona yeah so um we've been
talking about you know doing a
collaboration and and doing uh your book
signing at the connect event on March
15th at uh you know doing that stuff too
so it's a perfect place perfect time I
love Barcelona you get the real cannabis
enthusiasts people who love flower right
love the industry love they're very
passionate people at spannabis and
that's what I love about spannabis the
most and to be able to bring my book
there and to share it with people from
all around the world that's great to
work together you know on a connect
event I think that'd be a fun thing for
sure and saman ofis is just you know
it's my favorite event of the Year sure
this will be my first time so I'm really
excited to get out there and yeah man
just just just really exploring and
getting more getting more perspective
you know spannabis that that whole time
the the trip just checks all the boxes
you got good food you got good people
you got cannabis you got people with
ideas and Concepts from all around the
world that you're hearing about new
things right uh you know Trends work
differently in different places you know
I feel like a lot of people follow suit
from what's going on in the Bay Area but
that's not the case always anymore I
feel like people are starting to do
stuff all over the world that can impact
what we do here in the states no doubt
and you just touched on something that
made me like really excited about the
topics that I've seen a lot of people
come out to yeah you know this past
Tuesday um up in Sacramento you know at
indors and Hydra we had over 250 PE 250
people show up for the aroya office
hours live CRA discussion on crop
steering you know and that was you know
it was a Tuesday night like this is the
biggest turnout we've ever had in
Sacramento and you know we've been doing
these events for a few years now so I'm
just super grateful for the the people
that have put their hands in to help
make this production occur it's just
it's small team like we're really
starting to build this thing out and you
know to find topics like this that we
can take across you know take across the
globe whether it's Barcelona or Thailand
or Colombia or wherever it is that we
want to do more events that's the goal
is to help unify everybody with
education and be able to provide this
network and you know just
cross-pollinating that's the biggest
thing is I want to get more perspective
and bring awareness so that we can just
grow better grow better tree that's it
the king of
cross-pollination there you go there you
go no I think that's great man I think
it's an interesting time to be alive
it's an interesting time to be in this
industry you know I think times are
tough for some people times are not
tough for other people but it's really
an interesting place we in an in between
time um you know I guess we're always in
an in between time because we're ever
evolving and with technology now we're
growing exponentially things are
changing uh Ai and probability and these
AI models for the future breeding or
it's just really wild the potential that
AI has to be able to contribute right
trait libraries and markers you know
everything and and you know not not to
go too far off track but like we we
understand that Gene editing is here
like there there's certain levels of
understanding and professional maturity
again with that space specifically
because we already know what happened in
the past so we have to understand that
there's definitely layers to what's
happening you can do this stuff
responsibly and being able to find
Pathways to improve the plant make it as
healthy as possible so that you don't
have to worry about you know PM or all
these other things that driven breeding
is just amazing the especially powdery
mildew resistance for sure I mean how
many of us have had issues with powdery
mildew if you're a person anywhere in
the world that's grown that that's
that's humid that is humidity you're
going to have PM issues at least one
point with one cultivar in your life you
know genetics that are you know Brad in
Thailand are going to probably you're
going to find a much more resistant
cultivar of PM that it's hunted in
right so this 100% humidity Factor like
yeah that's that's a big deal you know
carpent Tria just right here in Southern
California coastline you've got 100%
humidity for like four or five months
out of the year it's crazy it's a great
place to identify varieties that don't
have issues with ottery mild or Bettis
and this goes back to commercial testing
right validation and verification of
these genetics before this get released
we have to understand if something is
susceptible I'm not going to recommend
that to a you know a company out in
Thailand right I think that's just one
of those things that it comes back to
being responsible in the curation phase
right the actual the the phenotyping
just making sure that you're capturing
all these data points and this comes
back to data right managing lots of data
points you cannot manage without
measurement and being able to track and
manage all this stuff which is you know
a big reason why cultivate IQ is in
development right now yeah you know
we've we've got this this this Solution
that's being built from by cultivators
for cultivators they start tapping in
all these different variables from feno
hunting to uh you know POS retail supply
chain all these different solutions
right and so you know shout out to Mo
corid like he's developed a lot of a lot
of data within a A system that we're
actually using for for projects that
we're Consulting with on other
operations that are using this
information to keep track of stuff to
make sure that we're managing it with
measurements to make adjustments
accordingly yeah but really what's cool
about that James is like I've seen so
many operators have a a disconnect in
communication from the cultivation team
to the owners or the financial people
holding the bills like it's very
difficult for a lot of these operators
to have that discussion of why why we're
not hitting better yields why we're not
having a higher ticket on our packs well
sometimes it's not as easy to
communicate that environmental
challenges lead to you know
transpiration challenges which is why
we're getting lower yields or our
quality is not as good because we're
having these massive VPD swings and we
have PM or all this all these things
happen when the person writing the check
for the bills and doesn't want to make
the investment on these these you know
improvements the facility or maybe
different tools or maybe you're not
using sensors to to monitor your your
dryb backs you know all these factors
that's where you're able to bridge the
gap communication so truly emphasizing
on this tool that's really going to
centralize the communication gap and the
barrier is is what we're excited about
because it's working we're already using
this at at multiple facilities so you
know as as we continue to work and
develop on this thing it's going to be
more userfriendly and you know
ultimately just bring that solution to
table yeah really cool thank you yeah I
just the the future is looking bright in
a lot of ways you know I think some
people see the Grim side I try to be a
Optimist all
around but yeah technology is gonna have
its benefit for sure it will well if we
collect enough data it's just that's
just a given right no doubt and you know
that's the thing he just you have to
have the right team in place right
having people that are committed to data
collecting and you know making it making
it easy to collect data like that's the
functionality like there's plenty of
there's of great software Solutions out
there and you know really really
understanding why you're doing something
in and why you're having that that soft
cost dedicated towards data capturing
there's got to be a reason behind it so
you know well and and it it grows
exponentially the value grows
exponentially so the first year of
collecting data you might not get that
much value but if you look over a period
of five years and you can go back where
you've grown something out multiple
times uh in multiple places you can
really start start identifying the the
value of it production value at scale
absolutely and just understanding what
you maybe should or shouldn't be growing
also developing breeding lines right so
developing breeding lines that it takes
data to really do it it certainly does
and you know I built my own Erp for
cultivated I I've explored a number of
different outof the-box services and
nothing really got down to the
intricacies of what I was trying to
track and manage right I know every
single clone comes off of every single
plant I know every data point that you
can imagine I've tracked and managed
because I built it you know I understood
that there was a certain level of
criteria that it wasn't an outof the-box
solution so I really had to find a way
to make sure that I can build that while
we're building up this you know this
massive database of of genetic uh you
know genetic Library information so that
we know that if this is coming back into
rotation we can know how many clones
it's going to produce you know all this
different stuff what is the pathogenic
pressure when's the viral load actually
start to express what does it actually
cost to produce a clone totally yeah
totally
and so you know just making sure all the
plant stock like we test our moms once a
month you know there's there's there's
multiple types of testing leaf with root
Leaf only root only combination of two
like there's maintenance testing and
there's like uh intake testing right so
making sure that you do have a full data
point on like that that plant so are you
guys doing in-house testing or do you
send out for third party we send out for
third party and we I've worked with a
number of labs a lot of amazing Labs
that you know um I think deserve some
credit like you know Jeremy Warren over
at the darkart nursery lab out in Davis
he's done some fantastic work Al andl
crop Solutions out in baville an Alisa's
you know fantastic wonderful resource in
my FL DNA you know they've really found
their Pathway to uh to bring rapid
analytics at a cost-effective
solution and so yeah I'm I'm I love
working with multiple Labs But
ultimately just holding ourselves
accountable I want to know when there's
a potential pathogenic pressure hit so
and again going back to data we know how
to track and batch track to make sure
that we do have the proper protocols in
place to eradicate and make sure that we
can go back and track what's going on
right yeah that's really cool yeah yeah
I mean that's the future that's the
future that the the nursery models
changed so much over the last 10 years
you know it's really wild and and the
availability of testing now is like you
know you anybody can get their stuff
tested technically don't doubt I mean
you can you just get a vile take your
whole your Leaf punches and you get you
get your results back in a couple of
days if not sooner if you're like you
know really on the horn and be like hey
guys this is an emergency you know can
you please see if there's an opportunity
to maybe expedite this you know you can
mail that back and forth and you're good
to go yeah really cool so where do you
see the industry in five
years currently right now I think we're
in a very interesting point of
compression so I think there's a lot of
alignment that is going to occur and I
think that the future obviously with
legalization happening on the Forefront
you know there's just there's so much
potential to have organized groups that
are in the Craft Market or that are at
the full scale Market because we know
what's going to happen there you know
you are going to I would love to see the
Craft brewery model you know I I would
aspire to see something very cool like
that um but you know there's just so
much opportunity here that's happening
but ultimately it comes back to
professionalism how many people are
going to make it through that are not
professionally mature in this industry
and this comes back to good people and
good practice IES so being driven by the
by the p&amp;l is very difficult to do when
you're you know when you have moral
ethics and I think a big part of this is
around like who do you work with who do
you surround yourself with why do you
want to continue on this pathway like
why are you really here do you truly
have passion for this plan and I think
that's a big part of where we're heading
in this future is we're going to start
to see some people drop off that are in
this for the wrong reasons yeah you know
like I I may not have grown up on the
hill and and you know dedicated my life
to it back then but I'm here now and
I've I've I've gone all in all my chips
are in the center yeah and so I'm here
to help and I think that's really what I
enjoy about the industry of where we're
heading is again like growing the
connect Community has has given me so
much fulfillment and being able to
educate people bringing on Experts to
talk about what their experience has
been so that's that's the future I want
to see is more collaboration competition
over collaboration over competition and
you know growing together is really the
emphasis well and you got to look the
ones that are left you know I've already
seen a lot lot of people fall off the
people that are left are are really
passionate people for the most part
right and it is it's we're we're
collaborating with each other we need to
collaborate with each other and we need
to work together I think that is the
best way if you want to build a small
business that is the best way is through
collaboration we're not in competition
with each other a lot of people see this
competition side of it but that's not
what it is we need to work together so
we can improve the quality of what we're
doing and we can build the people up
around us that are doing similar things
James you know what the one thing that I
learned about this whole thing or about
myself throughout this entire journey is
what I'm not good at and what I don't
want to spend time on because it makes
me unhappy or whatever it might be so I
surround myself with people that
complement my skill sets yeah and I
think that's really important when you
start to look at the future and where
you're starting your business or maybe
aligning and merging with another
business partner picking your partners
is very difficult and I don't think you
really understand what it's going to
mean when you until you you know really
start getting into a partnership and
understanding that everybody has their
own skill sets where your skill sets may
be limited is perspective of your
partners and so whether it's going
through and really aligning myself with
people that supplement these other you
know aspects of what I'm not good at you
I'm not a good software developer even
though I you know taught myself how to
use Ai and do all my marketing and you
know all this stuff that doesn't mean
that I can code right so being able to
put you know this this this Erp together
like shout out Mo you know mo really did
create a very special platform that
we're really working and emphasizing on
that is the best part of in my opinion
that is the best part of the legal
Market is that we can become specialists
in whatever we're really good at and
before you kind of had to do everything
you had to be an you know if you're a
grower uh you had to do everything you
had to be the electrician I mean we did
extract we did cultivation and now you
can be a specialist you can move forward
as a specialist if you're really good
you will never have a problem getting
work for sure you know you will always
have a job if you're really good at what
you do
and so if you can become a specialist
the best whether it's an extract artist
or an electrician or you're going to be
a cultivator or you're going to be a
breeder if you are the best at that if
you were in the very top percentile you
are going to be successful and that's
the beauty of where we're at now and I
mean some people you know you get mixed
opinions on everything but I feel like
in my opinion that is one of the best
things from recreational is we can
really become Specialists we can really
work on improving the plant couldn't
agree with more man and you don't have
to have a cultivation facility to be in
the industry look at these curators
these taste makers these people that
have such refined pallets yeah you know
like that there's there's a lot of room
for opportunity in the space and really
focusing on what makes you happy yeah if
you're good at sales you can do sales
you know right the Brokers can evolve
into being brokers in in the regulated
market too and I mean I think there's
potential for growth as long as you're
passionate and you love what you're
doing and you become a specialist you
become really good at that you are going
to be successful consistency
consistency well and and it doesn't it
doesn't mean that you had to have
god-given talent you can just get up
every day and work hard and be
successful so that's the thing is like
sometimes it's about falling down seven
and getting up that eighth time to be
successful having gratitude for the gift
of work you know that was something that
was instilled in me at a very young age
you know my mom and dad were
entrepreneurs and my dad you know coming
you know into this world into the United
States with you know with nothing no
education you know it's it was
incredible to see like how work ethic
was instilled at us at a very early age
and just just being grateful for what we
have like not a lot of people have
opportunity to work so no and if you're
willing to grind you're going to be okay
you know and it's
like you gota you got to look past all
the [__] and figure out what to
focus on I mean I think being spread out
and have having too many focuses can be
uh negative too like it's GNA day and
age disallow you to follow through on
your on your commitments totally and
that's James that's what I'm seeing a
lot of right yeah it's unfortunate to
see how many people are casting their
their net as wide as possible and not
following through in their commitments
yeah you know just keep it narrow
understand what makes you happy right
getting up in what drives you if you
have so many projects going on that
you're just you don't know what to focus
on yeah you should probably step back
and audit what the hell you're doing you
really want to find what makes you happy
and What Makes You tick and make sure
that you're on that right path yeah
there's like the Japanese principle of
keay which is like what you're good at
and what you're passionate about and how
that crosses over and it's about finding
that perfect balance and life is about
balance you know and life is about hard
work
and you know when they said life was
easy they lied to you life is not easy
there's you know I think there's times
where life can be easy and some people
they want to strive for like but I get
more gratification from the struggle
sure so you know and it's it's really
interesting you start as we get older we
start learning about different
philosophies and different principles
and we start developing our own ideas of
what happiness is and what success is I
think when I was younger when I was 18 I
thought success was a lot different than
how I see it
now success is being happy with the
people you love and care about I truly
think like you know momentto Mor death
is inevitable right so just having this
like weird psychological understanding
that death is coming but appreciate what
you have and just be grateful for where
you're at because seiz the moment yeah I
me I mean dude how how many hours a day
are we on this thing just glued to our
attention right present it's the best
and worst present that we ever have but
just spending this time together and I
haven't looked at my phone this entire
time it's like I I really engage and I
really like that that connection that we
have because people that come around
your life you either get Good Vibes or
you get this you know we didn't really
connect and so you know that's that's
what good Business Partnership like to
me really means you've got a good
connection you're able to valid certain
things you're able to tell me if
something's completely off I'm going to
be candid about that you know there's a
term called kind cander that I truly
believe in I'm gonna tell you you [__]
up because I care about you and I don't
want you to make that same mistake
absolutely and tell me the same thing
you know yeah that's what you expect out
of your real friends you know honesty
you know it comes down to integrity and
honesty and those are like the the most
important things in business of course
and there's no blueprint to what we're
doing here you know that's that's that's
the biggest part around like
collaboration and you know just being
able to truly lead into our strengths
and it's like Yo dude I've I've gone
down this pathway like you should
probably take a look at this perspective
because here's the mistakes that I made
and there's certain people that just
don't want to see that or hear it and
unfortunately like that's why you got to
start auditing your inner circle of
really who you're spending time with and
how how much time you're dedicating to
that there's a ton of time vampires out
there oh yeah Time Bandits we call them
Time Bandits yeah so it's it's funny but
they they they say that you
are um a reflection of your five closest
friends so if you really want to look at
yourself sure look at your five closest
friends and that's pretty much who you
are you're an average of the five
closest friends that you have or five
business people that you associate with
the most and I I totally think that's
true yeah man you're you're impacted by
perspective and that's uh you know that
there's only so much time in the day so
yeah and I'm so blessed I have I have a
lot of good people in my life I have a
lot of good influence a lot of good
friends people that really give a [__]
right and at the end of the day that's
what accounts you know it's like that's
what keeps me going even through the
tough days cuz there's tough days of
course there's always going to be tough
days and there's always going to be good
days and they're just going to keep
going through you know till we're gone
yeah no that's that's a really good
point James and I I I really enjoy
seeing like all these brands that you
have up on your wall here man like
you've got a great Network you've
clearly done a lot with a lot of good
people and that's that's something like
as we start to build and you know grow
together like that's what we can do to
continue evolving and what's Innovation
like what you showed me earlier on on on
your you know on your pheno hunting
project that you've got going on with
the software like that's dope you know
like I instantly started thinking like
how do we work together on that side to
Incorporated with what we're got going
on over here IQ you that's what I'm
saying man like there's good business to
be had there's a ton of opportunity so
fast forward into the future right now
is the time to look at you know good
actors and Bad actors and abolutely
auditing that process and they stand out
and somehow the Bad actors every once in
a while get back into the mix and then
they you know they last for a little
while but you know times are tough sure
um but the beauty of this podcast is
that we're recording oral history of the
Cannabis industry right of what's going
on and you know I've had some guys
Richard delisi who did 32 years in
prison who's one of my good friends and
we we uh just did a interview with Luke
scarmazzo who did 14 years you know to
get us to the kind of point we're at but
like this
podcast I imagine that 50 years from now
or 75 100 years from now maybe even 200
years from now people are going to want
to know how the heck did it get to this
point and what were they doing that was
so crazy back then you know and we're
able to touch on that and kind of share
our stories and it's it's amazing having
people like yourself on this podcast
that can kind of share their stories and
you know who knows maybe we'll do
another podcast in a year or two years
and the industry will be completely
different couldn't agree more man it's
uh you know this is the origin story of
where we're at in the industry you know
we're we we've all clearly there's a
bunch of people that have paved the way
and given their lives for people like
myself to come into this as an
opportunity and like really understand
like this is what I want to do and bring
value in a certain way that you know
that I felt that I could y you know
there's a lot of gratitude for that and
and shout out to everybody that is still
fighting the good fight and you know I
really hope that we can get everybody
out of out of out of prison for
marijuana related crimes like this is
just absolutely there's it doesn't make
sense does make sense that we're able to
be here and contribute and pay taxes on
all this stuff and there's people in
prison for doing what we're doing now
legally non nonviolent cannabis crimes
like come on like get these people out
please they are getting them out but
it's taking a lot longer than it should
unfortunately so again I'm grateful that
we're here you know and I think there's
just a lot of opportunity collaborating
with good people moving forward and you
know if uh you know if I can just say
anything to um to the community and
people that want to get into the
industry it's just be humble get in
experience things for yourself because
understanding where what you don't want
to do is something that you're never
going to experience until you try it
because especially in cultivation
cultivation is hard work yeah it's a lot
of lot of
cleaning think a lot and that's how it
goes in life there's a lot of things
it's trial and error you might think you
really want to do it until you do it and
then you're like hell no I don't want to
do that and this is this is where you
know leaders uh building good teams it's
like you got to stay present with the
people that you work with you know and
having these quarterly collaborations I
hate the term review like I don't do
reviews I I want to make sure that we
can block out time every quarter so
James I can hear you I want to
understand what challenges you're having
I want to understand what makes you
unhappy because ultimately when you
start working in an environment that
makes you happy and you're dedicated to
come in every day like there's Farms
that we've worked with that you can see
the transition of like I want Pride I
want to have pride in the flower that
we're growing because I want to take
that flower out and I want to be
representing that that's that's the
flower that we I want to show it to all
my friends and show them that I was part
of this absolutely and that's the beauty
of it cuz it's you know it's an
experience too so we're sharing an
experience with the people around us and
that's the beauty of what're I mean
that's part of the reason you and I are
both here is because we're able to share
this experience with people around us no
doubt and you know a big part of that
comes back to you know leaders and
understanding if you're a good leader or
you have opportunity to grow as a leader
and being able to put somebody in a role
and understanding what their succession
plan looks like well once you got it all
figured out you got a problem if you
think you've got it all figured out and
you got to be able to re-evaluate
everything and be able to look at it
from an outside perspective a lot of
times be true to thy own self you know
and I think that's a big part of like
continuing to grow and you know just
what are the iterations of yourself and
how do you want to continue progressing
and that's like again why building a
strong team starts with communication I
want to understand what makes you
unhappy maybe you're in the wrong role
maybe this just is not the right career
path for you which is totally fine too
or maybe you need to go into retail
maybe you go need to go into extraction
whatever it might be totally have no
problem firing people by the way because
I feel and I learned this in being a
chef yes was that you know at first it
was tough for me to fire people but I
think it's important
to fire people and let people go if they
don't fit because they belong somewhere
else and you're holding them back by not
letting them go you're holding them back
from whatever their Destiny is couldn't
agree more and taking accountability you
know me as your leader that brought you
into this I think I I I may not have
given you enough time to really develop
your skill set that I initially saw
during the application process during
that onboarding time so you know just
understanding what people's strengths
are and you don't know unless you make
time so these quarterly collaborations
what do you want to do how far out do
you want to get into this you know at at
the nursery you know you're limited to
what you can get into right there's only
so many departments that we have in
propagation but as you start to develop
well now that I've seen the nursery side
maybe I want to get into flower so guess
what I got a network of bunch of
cultivators so hey I got I got this
person that really wants to get into
flow I'm the first person to make that
that recommendation
if somebody's uny I'm the first write
that letter ofation to get into
somewhere else because I know I know
what I hired them for you know that's
the part of around leadership that
people are just overlooking like listen
just talk to your team we they're you
know you're here with us this is when
that's kind of why You Know My Name the
custodian kind of came out I'm not
afraid to clean [__] up I I work
underneath everybody to make sure people
are successful and happy doing what
they're doing nice that's what it's all
about yeah um so if you had one piece of
advice for yourself that was just
starting out in the industry that you
could go back and talk to yourself what
would that be you know I I don't I don't
have any regrets about anything that
I've done I think everything happens for
a reason I think advice to myself I'm
just just be more be more open-minded I
guess you know because truly I I've done
a lot that I'm proud of and I've done a
lot of iteration and self-growth because
this is not easy there's no blueprint
like I've you know I've taught my myself
a lot throughout this industry and
really understanding how certain things
that I needed to do to build a business
and you know I've I've got a great
network of people that have helped me
along the way you know I think that's
the biggest thing is just my uh this is
kind of funny because like my dad you
know coming from Mexico he he's always
like don't trust anybody every time I'm
leaving he's like don't trust anybody
like like pops what are you talking
about man like and obviously he had his
own experiences but I always took that
with the grain of salt because it's like
yo be cautious but I also did the
opposite I'm like you have my trust
until you show me I can't trust you to a
degree right so I think that was that
was the one thing that you know working
in genetics and being able to work with
a ton of cultivators that were you know
calling us to to buy Cuts it's like I
got to work with the ton of great people
and I also got the exposure of a lot of
people that took advantage of my
kindness and so you know not to the
degree of like you know we're closing
the business down but just just just
knowing that there is people that are
trying to take advantage because their
backs up against the wall and I think
you mentioned this earlier like people
do some shitty stuff yeah when their
back is up against the wall and I think
that's just something we have to be
cautious with
right yeah well if somebody is trying to
get a hold of you where can they find
you I'm pretty active on Instagram you
know so Sergio thee custodian is my
direct handle um I also manage the
cultivated genetics handle uh and the
connect Community handle all of those
are at those specific words um so you
know it's I'm pretty accessible guys
like I'm here to help I mean if you
really want to like come and I encourage
you to come out to these connect
community events if you go to our
website or go to our Instagram page
there's a link in the bio that's got
everything you need to know about our
events the RSVPs the YouTube channel to
watch all the different panels that
we've put together you know I encourage
like right now people think it's just
for cultivators like no butt tenders
need to get to these things everybody if
you love cannabis and you want to learn
more about it it's a great event it's a
great place to meet other people in the
industry as well I mean there's the
whole aspect of that alone is amazing
thank you James and I'm I'm proud of
what the community is really supported
and that's really what's happening is we
want to network we want to level each
other up so yeah I just encourage
everybody to come out um you know yes
every month in Sacramento and we're
starting to Branch off we're doing LA on
the 22nd of February for salt Wars that
should be fun I may come down there with
books you never know perfect man um
always welcome so yeah and then we're
doing Barcelona in March you know Friday
March 15th is the goal Friday March 15th
if you guys are in Spain come check us
out uh hit up Sergio if you want to find
out how to go it's going to be amazing
uh we'll have books there we'll have
seeds we'll have all kinds of cool stuff
and who knows there might be a battle
royale there so the Battle Royale is
amazing yeah man it's uh so I do want to
start plugging the May 4th Battle Royale
which is going to be OG's nice so OG
Battle Royale we're going to do it um
the weekend of the emerald Cup in here
in the Bay Area um location TBD but that
is that is happening so if you're uh if
you want to compete in the Battle Royale
with OG's it's happening everyone's
going to be the Bay Area because March
4th and 5th is when the emerald cup is
so may the fourth be with you that's it
yeah thank you so much for coming on the
show today man really appreciate it and
I look forward to doing this again
appreciate you man in hell yeah
[Music]
thanks
back
Cru
yeah