[Music]
how's it going welcome to another
episode of the James loud podcast today
we have black sheep genetics on the show
how you doing today James is a pleasure
I am stoked on life stoked to be back in
the bay and it's glorious so I'm super
excited to have you on the show today
we've been talking online for a long
time yes uh you've been in the industry
a long time you always uh preach quality
and TPS
we have a mutual friend Leo from offici
a so yeah so welcome thank you man and
on the TP tip uh we'll we'll jump in
right away because we have another
mutual friend organic Brian oh yeah and
I've been making uh a blend of organic
freeze dried fruits and sucret of all
the forms of bricks sucret seems to be
the number one it's less processed it's
like these beautiful granulars they
sweep off the ground and it tastes
better than molasses wow and Oldtimer
told me so I took a note when he said
Sucrets the one Mark theves represent
doos and uh I built this new blend to
boost tpin to boost
THC and uh a side thing that came out of
it that might be bigger than both of
those is it preserves the quality of the
Cannabis really so I brought some bud to
show yeah uh that's four years old wow
and it's bright green and it's amazing
looking to where like more of that needs
to happen because as we know in the jars
it's like yeah if they don't smooth it
quick enough then we're all in trouble
well has a short shelf life I like the
tur loocks for improving shelf life I
think the tur blocks do a great job
uhhuh uh you know we mentioned turls in
my breeding book sweet I'm a huge fan uh
but yeah and then I think improving the
quality of the flour you know that
sounds amazing I think you know because
you're combining all these fruits and I
have some vegetables in there too and
what have you uh the health of the plant
and the the Vigor with the bricks yeah
is like so key so you know just making
it be able to repel bugs not get mold be
happy right optimal plant Health at the
end of the day we're all looking for
optimal plant Health yeah you said Leo
uh from offici andado and he told me you
know when we're taking care of our
ladies uh when they get sick he gets
sick really when they get cold he gets
cold no surprise there yeah so I love
being a plant myself on that note you
know connection so let's uh let's talk
about how you got started in the
industry the journey the journey let's
go back to the beginning when did you
start smoking I first grew my first
plant uh in India in the Kulu mountains
when I was 12 really and my mom and my
pops uh kind of bailed me out because I
didn't fit in with the jocks and I
didn't fit in with the preppies and I
was in a New England old school hick out
town so my subculture of skateboarders
and uh and delinquents kind of ran a
little wild and she would say to the
governor people if they asked how I was
doing that I wasn't in jail or the
hospital so was doing good and uh they
kind of made an intervention and they
took me to India for a year took me out
of eighth grade to show me the
world and well I was free in India I had
a account uh at one of the local stores
that had fireworks so I got to like
build multi-stage fireworks and there
was wild
cannabis and I you know had a connection
with the plant where I didn't even
choose it I started a garden uh behind
my house that I was living at and in the
center of one of the beds what comes up
a glorious plant and it's legal in India
so my mom was like sure you know rock
and roll with that thing nice and I grew
that we had a really fun time one time
we went down to the river and we cut all
this feral cannabis and we piled it up
in like a giant pile and lit it on fire
and we were dancing around it and we
didn't even know like we were pretty
innocent you know uh and I said children
weed of the Corn you know right it was
mashing and fed cows put cows to sleep
there's cows everywhere so we're like
let's feed the cows but uh yeah I got
connected to it early on and then uh I
kind of got my act together I went to
art school in Boston and that's when I
started working with the Canadian
yeah and as you know you know before uh
I've heard you mention the green Bud
wave that came in and we were getting
like the Canadian ice and other
strains and boy was it glorious the
orange crush there's the ice there yeah
there was so many good ones I think they
called the freeze too right yeah yeah
yeah yeah and that stuff was moving good
and Boston had the most colleges per
capita in the United States and it was
like you know duffel bags at the door in
Good Times back in the day you know
where uh that city was good to me and it
kind of I had made some great friends
there and and Dove deeper into the you
know cannabis life I smoked I'm leaving
out the most important part so after I
came back from India I was still
connected to the plant and I'd cleaned
my brain up a little bit and I was more
on point and doing okay in school so you
know no problems parents are happy and
every day before Home Room we'd go down
to an abandoned old church and we'd all
fade on a blunt and East Coast used to
be uh Phillies and you know we'd smoke
the Philly before home room and life was
glorious and I sat around with those
guys and I said James that I don't know
what it was about her but I knew I was
going to smoke in my entire life and
that like it was so I'm like I was in
love with it yeah and you know to
parallel that then forward from Boston
you know kind of got into the other side
of things and uh and I moved to
California I was going to school for uh
computer animation in Boston at school
of Museum of Fine Arts and toughs and I
also did kind of graph and some other
art and and
uh then I saw what was happening out
here in California and I was going to
have to get a job out here so came to
take a peek and it was like Boston was
in the dirt you know so competing
against the best animation schools
around where the industry is right and
so I toured around California with my
dad was an epic road trip we we drove
from La uh up to the bay and at one
point on the trip we go by vandenbberg
Air Force Base and my dad was like oh I
did not want to stop here and we were
prepared for like the whole way up the
five it's developed and then before you
hit vandenbberg there's like a 70 mile
Gap and like a 70 mile Gap after it
right and the whole secret or the
conspiracy my dad was a big conspiracy
Guy taught me a lot and he was like they
fly everything in from the ocean there
and it's like one Road in one road out
and we rolled into this town kind of
uneasy and it was really strange with
there was all the houses the cars were
parked in the driveways no lights no
people and we pull in there's like one
gas station so we get gas and my old
man's like leave the car run and he goes
into the uh get some things and uh and
get the gas and while I'm sitting there
Sheriff pulls up and he pulls up and he
rolls the window down a little bit and
he just stares and I'm like okay this is
a little strange and then behind him
comes the homeland security vehicle they
roll down the window they stare I'm like
okay this is getting really strange so
I'm like I'm gonna take five and just
maybe go take a bathroom break and I go
into the bathroom I've been writing
graph and you know having good time
coming up the road and this bathroom had
like uh a word scratched in the wall
like out of a horror movie like a
thousand times the same word and I was
like oh really sketchy now so I come out
there's the sheriff in the home of
security they're like look at me Sheriff
leaves he leaves my dad had an epic
timing where he didn't see any of that
he's getting coffee and snacks or
whatever and he rolls out and I was like
Dad you got to get out of here you know
and for the next like set of roads down
the mile we're looking for a brain wiper
you know or we're like if they take us
in we're not going to come out the same
way they'll know we
know yeah so uh I made my way up to San
Francisco went to the Academy of Arts
and I was doing the Arts like before but
really doing the herb yeah and art
school's kind of a farce to to you know
is it necessary Sometimes some sometimes
not but it was fun and you know college
for me was about Connections and people
and I still am friends with some of the
people that I met there totally and uh
then I was out there doing that and I
started picking back up things with the
Cannabis and uh I had my father he was
we were dealing with some family Strife
thus the name Black Sheep and so I said
dad you know instead of you getting you
know mistreated and having hard times
want come out to California with me and
uh originally he was all pumped up he
was friends with Paul stamitz oh wow and
he moved into my apartment and he
started growing mushrooms in one of the
old uh roommates rooms and then I was
like Dad you know I love the mushrooms
and all but we should really be growing
some cannabis so pops was like let's go
and I'm kind of good with people um
business on the front and he was you
know the master grower in the back and
the humility and the wisdom and
father-son relationship nice and we
started growing in Oakland in
2003 nice yeah those were good years
those were good years amazing years not
that there's been bad years but there's
been those were really good years you
know I think instrumental years for
cannabis and cannabis legalization we
were medical and yeah it was a special
time right especially in Oakland yeah
especially I mean I was around in
Oakland 2003 and I thought you know the
genetics that we had the passion the
people that were going and shopping at
you know the dispensaries I mean people
were really passionate about Wei back
then the guys growing the we can I get
that lighter absolutely you're the man
yeah I mean 2003 there was a handful of
uh places open third floor BPG I went to
all those I'm familiar with everybody
the BPG go upstairs
uh back then you used to have that
little room upstairs yeah yeah yeah the
buyers would go upstairs and we deny
people for 36 we'd be like no we're
passing on that we're moving on down and
you used to do the run to where it was
like you had to work Miracle your rent
was due and you go out and you go
through around town and hit your spots
and the you know my dad put it most
eloquently that I've ever heard in my
life is we spend a short time with the
plant I like to think of myself as a
Shepherd of the plant sure and you know
we don't know where it's going yeah but
my dad told me the plant knows where
it's going yeah it knows every joint it
knows every bowl pack it knows you know
all the people it's going to touch so to
be a part of it and help it's along its
way you know yeah a booster rocket of
sorts right sure we're all just stewards
at the end of the day
bless so you you know that
Journey uh you know that's kind of what
kicked it off and then in 2012 was the
Fallout when indor you know vanished uh
for the most part I remember going to
the grow stores and uh they told me
don't buy anything go next door to our
used warehouse and it was there was more
equipment in the used Warehouse yeah
than there was in the main store so I
went to some people for wisdom I worked
with my father father um I was fortunate
enough to be around people that I
wouldn't have if I wasn't rolling with
him that really cared about me and took
care of me and uh I asked for wisdom
from one of my mentors Steve Smith uh
owned H net uh with his family he was
running that with his wife at the time
Kathy and uh his boys helped him out too
and Steve uh mentored me and said well
and during this transition
uh I think it's best for you to maybe
look up to mesino yeah and you know
expand so he told me Willets was a great
place and we started looking for real
estate and little did I know that
shutting down the 50 lighter because I
was so tired we had three houses going
and it was like forever harvests forever
trims and back like you we were saying
back in the day when we had one house
with 14 lights and everybody was happy
and we were making paper it was less
complicated yeah and then you know more
houses more work to where I was you know
at the tail end after you know almost 10
years in the bay burning out so it was a
revitalization of my cannabis Spirit
yeah and the warrior marches on but yeah
so let's talk about the genetics in 2003
what what kind of genetics were you guys
running when you first started growing
what rhymes with
2003 GDP nice yeah uh I was fortunate
enough to run the uh Hell's Angels cut
and I don't know if you rever ran into
the Flatt top purple uhuh they only had
it at Grassroots and Grassroots was a
really great Club to me back in the day
Dan and Kevin are legendary they used to
take their employees to Hawaii like take
care of people was family you know and
Legendary Legendary and I also liked the
KKL I actually met the guy who made urle
really I'm like I don't think anybody
have you do you know anybody that knows
him uhuh he's totally unknown yeah uh I
was at one of the first farmers markets
in
mesino and there was an Oldtimer smoking
a
bong so I was like okay this gu is
serious yeah and I got the hanging with
him for a little bit and chatting and
he's like yeah you know URL I made
purple URL and I was like what and uh he
says to
me uh GDP just took my Ur and put big
butt on it and big bud sucks yeah and I
was like we all know if you came in with
a pack of the Urkle Done Right versus a
pack of the GDP the KKL was taken KKL
was fire the urk was amazing it wasn't
as big of buds though it was definitely
smaller buds but the TPS were there it
had that real floral floral TP you know
right you didn't have to cut the top off
on week eight right because they rot we
all dealt with GDP where it was the most
beautiful
plant oh it was the slowest vegging too
they were the shortest slowest vegging
plants yeah it was good stuff I used to
use the Dual Spectrum the HPS with the
metal H wow and that veg things for me
the best is still my you know I haven't
gotten into the new LED world so I'm old
school in that sense I like HPS I still
like HPS I still think HPS creates a
great product uh you know LED creates a
good product too what's your opinion
on seeds that are bred under
HPS and Performing
outperforming uh the new LEDs with the
old school HPS because of maybe
epigenetic
and I'm like is that a far some people
say not true some people say true so I'm
just you know looking for more show me
the money show me the results I mean I
think we're we're r&amp; ding stuff right
now so I'm doing a lot of R&amp;D side by
side LED versus HPS also with seed
production I know with reversals I can
tell you reversals under HPS are
significantly better uh you know we're
talking about far red and stuff like
that in the Spectrum right I think that
adds to it so I do my reversals right
now but also experimenting on what is
the best way to do a reversal not only
reversal spray but also Spectrum um you
know and then collecting pollen versus
using life plants I prefer using live
plants when I'm pollinating but
collecting pollen is a you know a way to
hedge your bets for sure yeah I like
taking the tops off of a live pant and
putting them into a bag and then you
know getting the right before when the
bells are just about to open they're all
swollen yeah and I just Zam in the
garden I've even put on my spirit
animals a wolf sometimes when I'm doing
the breeding it's my most passionate
it's my heart so I put my wolf suit on
and I head out and I pull out the branch
out of the bag when there's no wind and
I just open the flowerettes because I'm
like you I want that natural drift I
don't get a paintbrush anymore I've
tried that the hair's been all red
magnetism too we're talking about
magnetism there's all kinds of other
things that play I do a pollen I do a
pollen wand I don't know if you ever
seen that where you take when you're
when you're pollen's dumping on those
branches and you really want to hit the
room up rather than shaking it I'll take
and cut off the mail flowers tape up
several of them like a bouquet and walk
around dusting them you know you get
some good swings and it definitely
floats and you know pollen's a lot of
fun I think that that side of the the
plant is amazing to work with I did a
garden I I don't have neighbors close by
and I had retired out of you know
commercially growing and I just did a
seed patch and I let everything go and I
had multiple males and you know I called
the ones that I might not have liked but
I left a lot and I really got to watch
them just in their natural habitat come
to fruition and you know I made the note
as a breeder you know we spend this time
doing the selection but the plants seem
to also know to where I had my early
males get on my early girls yeah and you
know the L ones you know Finding their
mates and whatnot and it was really
special to me to just let them Zen and I
was walking through James where I bumped
into a plant and it was like a pollen
Cloud yeah and there's videos of me just
surrounded by pollen and it's sparkling
and I'm like that's our fairy dust yeah
well and it's amazing time it's it's
amazing to see pollen fly if you've
really seen pollen fly where it's like a
wall it's almost like a cloud coming in
it's just and then sometimes it'll just
sail over the top of the canopy that's
that's great you know first time I ever
readed now I got to tell you the story
so I asked the gouts it's one of the
most legendary families in Round Valley
U Mikey G is a real legend in the
industry 23 pound plant 23b plant
23b plant 20 feet tall by 12T wide yeah
oh wow plus he was growing the pink
Cadillac and I got to see it like this
guy's been amending his hoes so long
there's like a pallet of chicken [ __ ]
per hole wow and they're mounded up all
high been reworked and reworked he's got
big mounds and I saw that plant and I
was like man of course his name is Mikey
and I'm like ca he's Michael Jordan and
then uh he walks up to and he's like
it's got three layers of netting and
he's he's like takes a huge Cola and
it's probably a half pound and he bends
it down all the way to the ground like
rubs the ground and he's like look at
how strong it is and you and I know some
strains can bend and some will snap yeah
but just to see that strength and that
connection totally and I had set out for
a couple years after that being like I'm
going to grow a 20 PB plane and I was
like well maybe in the future but I
recognized you know I'm good at ball but
you're seeing Michael Jordan yeah and
you know just to be around them and to
see that Zen uh Magic totally yeah yeah
when your limit six plants that that can
go a long ways hey 25 they used to when
I first moved to meno they were like
unless you pull 250 you're just losing
yeah and it was like that's was a
daunting task coming from indoor rooms
were like 20 lb yeah 40 lb
but uh I got there yeah yeah yeah yeah
nice and I was part of uh the the
911 program in mesino with the 99 plants
which was the I wish we could go back
yeah old doc hop used to give out the
shirts where you'd go there and there'd
be line for like three hours wow with
like 50 people because he said that you
could grow 99 plants with his shirt yeah
and if the sh sh busted you I don't
think he was going to tell you that you
could but a lot of people including me
were under that Mirage sure and you know
in cannabis there's a constant you know
people have to realize that that's been
a it's it's a difficult industry to
navigate like you and me finding good
advice or the right people it's the most
valuable thing yeah people talk about
Terah and yeah there's the ground and
the air and the dirt but don't forget
about the friendships and the farmers
and like that is the knowledge the
knowledge right like we go to somebody's
Garden there's always something that
shines yeah where you're like everybody
grows different and you know a thousand
ways to skin a cat but uh you see that
gold and everybody I pick up you know
the little nuances and something from
this Garden something from that garden
and it takes years to get good that's
what a lot of people don't understand
they want an instant gratification
you know you'll have good weed you might
have good weed your first time you might
not right but if you keep doing it no
matter what you are going to get good
and that's just how it works I
everything's kind of like that in life
but definitely growing and if you're
passionate you love it you are going to
get to grow good weed it's just a matter
of time we had hard apprentices
apprenticeships back in the day you know
you and I worked in a a criminal time
where you wore a lot of hats in this
business you know you're an electrician
Security man
uh family man contractor
contractor you the funny stories you
tell people I tried not to drift too far
or at least you could connect somewhat
to reality to be like oh yeah I'm heac
guy we're working on a double stage
system with you know we're silencing the
motors right yeah that was key they
bubble wrapped the motors back in the
day cuz that thing was humming at
midnight yeah and it quieted up yeah I
mean there was a lot of problems to be
solved back
then uh and then without the internet it
was all about the circle of people you
knew now the internet's open it up with
information but it's still hard to
decipher what's right and what's wrong
you know because you'll hear on the
internet 20 different opinions on the
same thing salt versus organic versus
cocoa versus aquaponics uh you know dwc
whatever and they're all they're all
fine you just have to learn how to tweak
them and get them for you and figure out
if that's the path you want to go down
right I think it's really you know
interesting now that the Market's
expanding and we're getting into
agricultural equipment and yeah what
they're talking about and uh you know
moving things forward in large Fields uh
specifically I've been talking with
someone that grows this amazing varietal
uh of knf uh and fiber and it's a
hibiscus Hy hybrid wow and the seeds
look like triangles they're black
they're like the size of a dime really
and it grows the stock is like
30% more uh than any other stock on like
in the game yeah and it doesn't have THC
it doesn't have CBD so all these
pitfalls that now we're seeing you know
like um my buddies in Iowa and he's one
of the only four licenses and he grows
CBG
yeah and CBG helps people we don't even
understand how much yet cancer yep it's
a winner and thca CBG they are just
amazing golden he was the first time he
grew it he was all paranoid because he's
like what's up with this stuff on the
plants and he said it was almost like a
powder yeah and that was the
CVG I guess an expression of non
psychoactive uh both both thca and CB BG
non psychoactive CBD is also non
psychoactive but I mean all these
cannabinoids are extremely beneficial
we're just scratching the surface on how
they can be used and how they can be
worked in with drugs and other things
you know on the drug Discovery side I
think we're going there and it's not
going to stop and we're going to learn a
lot right so we were talking this guy's
in contract and working with some large
people in oil and gas yeah and this
plant is three times uh uh reduces the
carbon FR uh footprint three times of
rainforest yeah so there's a lot of
incentive and like like I was saying
with the World Market opening up it's
like we're working with an
engineer um Jason Randi he worked for
cocacola then loganitus Boonville uh ale
and then I met him in a a dive bar where
they have the best burgers in Yukaya
we're eating lunch with my dad me and my
dad were like we've been waiting our
whole lives to meet you is this recently
or this is going back
ways uh to where I also had a business
called Wasa nice you may be familiar
with or not did you ever sip one no it's
cannabis infused hemp milk awesome 400
shops James wow 2115 yeah yeah yeah
office in La an office in San Francisco
on Marcus Street nice filled with
freezers we made it fresh frozen my dad
invented fresh frozen manufacturing
really yes amazing we need to get him on
the show oh man he is he's in my heart
and he's in the sky so if the lights
flicker that's his 12-dimensional
communication so we'll keep our eyes
peeled amazing yeah so Wasa um the
oldest edible of time is bong oh yeah
and they drink it in India it's still
ceremony drank by the uh military once a
year and Steve Smith had made some at
hopenet and I tried brownies and uh
everything under the sun and when I
drank this drink I was like what is
happening yeah well people don't believe
wheed is psychedelic but it can be
psychedelic I've had the same kind of
experience with bang so right and so you
know uh he was kind of my grand father
uh and my mentor and I went to him and I
said you know I really like your milk
and I want to make something like it and
he said as long as you make something
different then go for it and so I was
like let's put hemp milk in it yeah and
instead of cow milk all these problems
with milk and people being lactose
intolerant not to mention that my genius
idea there that I felt felt was putting
it in with the plant yeah and so I'm
like the hemp is it the herb is it it's
multi-dimensional
Multiverse and uh we started making this
hemp uh
infused chocolate milk and so like you
said psychedelic it surely was the
stories that I hear you know I served
over 400,000 bottles wow and I like the
good stories versus the bad ones sure
you know you hear a lot more bad stories
than you do good stories so
paranoia oh list goes on but you know
what shines for me is when you know we
would drink it with a couple of friends
and you'd feel like you're in high
school and people start bouncing around
the trampoline laughing nonstop having a
great time and the wavelength of it uh
we always put in multiple strains we
were like into the Entourage effect I
wanted to fill the wheel out before it
was even the wheel yeah and you know
when I said my dad invented fresh frozen
it was specific for like edible
manufacturer I'm sure there's some other
people that also were experimenting with
that at the time uh and we were running
trim at the table and uh the old man
didn't want to deal with it so he said
just stick it in the freezer with the
garbage bag and then you know we're
running through material making the milk
and he said grabb that bag out of the
freezer let's try that out yeah and uh
we started working with that and it was
like yeah just like live Rosen you know
there's a world of difference so we were
like we're running with this and uh we
built that up James to where even out in
mesino I had a 10K garden and we put on
Leatherman gloves and we strip the
entire garden and we pack them into 5B
bricks I seen people doing fresh frozen
manufacturing and it's painful I'm like
having 20 trimmers come out to your farm
and sit on a table and manicure it all
fresh that's nice and all but I don't
have the money to pay for that and I
don't want to see it come out of my
pocket M and I had one of the most
robust extraction techniques ever to see
cannabis with putting it into a boiling
kettle of milk and just letting it ride
when we made the milk and uh got things
going uh you expanded uh we were
inspired like you said by uh the
hallucinogenic experience it offered so
we came up with the name
chakaa nice inspired by Co Capelli and
iasa oh yeah and like you said people
would have an experience and it put that
into perspective like we had a guy who
was cocky at the trim table and he was
like bro Edibles don't don't hit me I
I'm not even sweating I'll I'll Ace a
huge amount of Wasa and my dad and I
were like this is gonna be fun yeah and
you know we waited and got the last
bottom of the barrel just like in a
whiskey barrel you know really good
stuff back then and uh we filled up a
glass for him and it was like you needed
2 ounces of this stuff and you were
floor yeah and he drank the glass and
uh he bringing him back to his place
after it was after the trim we made sure
not to give it to him while we're
working sure so right before he leaves
and we I'm giving him a ride back from
Oakland to San Francisco and he's he's
starting to get a little
shaky and uh I said to him what are you
gonna do like what are you doing right
now he was like oh I have this date with
this girl I'm about to go home just
chill for a couple minutes get ready get
some food and then I'm going out and I
was like that's awesome and and uh and
then it starts hitting him harder I mean
it's coming in heavy and he's like bro
can you get me a drink and I was like
yeah sure and we're right next to a
Packy so we're like I swing and I'm in
the like parked and ready to go in like
10 seconds and he opens the door slowly
and he stands up and he holds the door
and he just
stands and then he gets back in the car
and he's like I can't go in there right
now and I'm like all right we Jet right
back to your crib and we're driving to
his crib we're on this this py is his
Corner Packy store and we're on his
street and he says to me where the hell
are we right
now so I leave him at his house and I'm
looking at him in the rear view as I'm
pulling off and he's just standing in
the middle of the row oh man and he said
he calls his roommate up uh from his
couch and he couldn't even talk it was
like his roommate like heard murmuring
and he's like wait are you in your room
right now cuz you could hear murmuring
from the other room he's like in the
living room and he's there on the couch
and he was like it was a threed day long
trip James W he was like it was more
powerful than any psychedelic he had
ever taken he was like all I did was
sleep and eat and like fry yeah so you
know not that I want people to go that
far but again like you were saying that
you can have the cere monial experience
you can repair it is a ceremonial
experience at a certain level and people
don't most people unless you've gone
there you wouldn't fully understand you
know it's not just heightened perception
you know your perception's heightened or
whatever it's like you can get full
colors you can have crazy
experiences it's not hallucinate yeah I
wouldn't say you're going to hallucinate
like LSD right or like mushrooms or like
some of these other but it is
psychedelic definitely especially colors
man I've seen some Wild colors and had
you know I mean hallucinations out of
the peripheral and like the whole world
is alive you know stuff like that and
good and bad I've had bad too I've had
bad experiences from eating too much so
we said the the strains in the early
2000s I thought of something on the way
over that I thought would be a lot of
fun I said why don't we just tag team
and go through some of the ones I like
and you like and we'll go back and forth
we'll give it a quick run nice Green
Crack Blue Dream same OG
Kush hem dog Sour
Diesel chemis
ogre ooh aota this is great actually
this is great yes uh let's go to Flat
Top purple okay we'll go to uh from Flat
Top purple we're going to go to Romulan
Purple Kush
Purple Kush uh meno pers
afy
uh AFU the candy the AFU I love it Hindu
Kush yes tallest plant ever insane in
the grow room we had no was epic and it
was so Frosty we had no idea we flipped
it like three weeks and Sh 5 feet tall
we had like Max I'm still super cropping
up the top you know being like I got it
you know totally knock it down pushing
it between the lights yeah as he grows
up past them yeah yeah no well I managed
I used to bend him over if we had to
knock the room down I'll knock it down a
foot two feet and just put that knuckle
in yeah everybody's got finesse with
that okay so we went AFU Romulan what's
your next J uh let's go J oh jagu jagu
that was that was an interesting one
that's what's in this jar nice yeah uh
purple Cadillac purple
Cadillac princess purple train
wreck we grew train wreck better than
the S there was two cuts the arc cut and
a San Francisco cut and my dad and I
grew train R shout out to Ty big up Ty
yeah dank plant my dad grew train wreck
and we brought it into the shop and they
said said you grew it better than the
people that made it nice and I was like
I can't sell it to you yeah and I was
like I'm taking it to
LA and an epic mission to La where it
was back when you know people used to
put names on things you mentioned some
old clubs
ccg the first one California caregivers
Y and they were down in uh originally
they had the B Oakland by and then they
had the San Francisco on the Easter on a
bus and I remember going in there and if
they had it on the menu Blue Dot blue
dot yeah that's a good one blue dot uh
Red Dot Red Dot Blue
Dot oh man there are so many good ones
Black Domina oh black domino the ladies
love black domino black domino was good
Juicy Fruit you remember the Juicy Fruit
uh cotton candy cotton candy the real
triple X go to Doug V's the [ __ ] triple
XX OG trip X rest in peace good stuff
yeah OG and then there's you know you
can go down the list of OG's right there
was the Diablo the
Tahoe uh the Josh D sfv there was the
sfv there was the kosher there was the
true OG there was the pure OG there was
I mean the names go on and on new Orga
OG yeah let them know Orga OG somoma OG
Sonoma OG it was a sfv pheno or C it was
amazing like that yeah the snow OG we
work with that a lot that was a good one
there was so
many everywhere there was OG's some of
them were the same some of them were
different some were renamed uh man it's
like was moving in La for uh $100 e i
remember Fairfax dispensary had six
Windows which was like legendary at the
time or six counters to sell at and it
was $100 HS just flying out the door
yeah
going down and working in that time was
a lifestyle you know why we did this
thing so much fun so much fun and I feel
like you're either meant to do it or you
you're not meant to do it it's like
either you love it or you don't love it
you know there's people that are wearing
it for the wrong reasons too but the
people that are passionate are still
doing it we're still here right right
you know I still we still love talking
about weed as you can tell passionate
look I've been charging this for a year
and what's today James a full moon nice
and I like to crack the beans I got
rainwater and at on deck at home nice
and I throw them in above uh the stove
where it gets nice little ambient
heat you do plates with a paper towel or
you just do I'm just an old school uh
shot glass or a glass guy you do
Straight water you do rain water rain oh
you do rain water rain water hydrogen
peroxide anything like that you just you
straight my seeds are so clean and I'm
growing my own genetics so I don't have
to clean off broad
mites oh talk about a dirty seed oh man
where people would mentioned that
there's eggs on the seeds and I'm like
scary bad but yeah running clean seeds
running the rainwater I'm not you you
know I I bought a lot of inputs and me
and you have been farming so long again
we get more and more into learning about
how to what we need and where to get it
so it's all coming from my land that's
amazing I went out and farg 200 pounds
of wild mushrooms with my kids I saw the
video I saw the video you guys are
crushing the mushrooms yeah that's
amazing threw them in the compost golden
amonita you had a golden amonita in
there that golden amonita in there I had
the devil's cap which is this mushroom
that's like this big and yeah I went to
the compost pile is here James and I was
like I want to show it the most love I
can yeah and I was like how do I make
the best compost and I was like putting
in things you know little Wheezy said it
pretty well where I'm so grateful
because I have ideas that no one else
thinks of and I don't know why but man
am I grateful and you know so building
into the compost and I was throwing my
turps in I'm throwing the mushrooms in
I'm throwing uh my mentor's weed in so
it's basically biodynamic One Step Above
organic you're doing it all with locally
processed inputs correct I can cut the
hay I have equisetum
arborium uh silica at my disposal where
I get the husks and layer that I'm like
hay is great but I love to layer the
silica husks and they just let them
break down that's awesome stalks again
we like to see thigh pieces yeah yeah
yeah your piles get hot uh they do yep I
I I turn it over and and work it and
then depending on sometimes I'm like
experimenting with taking it stuff
that's partially broken down yeah
because I've done experiments with tpin
where I put in fresh crushed grapes uh
my friend had concord grapes and I
crushed them up like The Wine Guys my
feet and threw it on top of the plants
and there was mad fruit flies but it was
outdoor so I didn't care and you know
that year was kind of a little bit of a
hint but then the next year the plant
tastes like pure grape that's awesome so
I'm like there's something to be said to
letting it just organically break down
yeah so I'm leaving chunks of fruit in
this time you know I saw apples in the
pile and uh uh rose buds and uh
different fruits I have an amazing
ancient Orchard uh around my property
and on my property wow so was like I was
just getting hairs I'm getting uh
everything that drops and you know huge
side by side loads of fruit dumping it
yeah awesome yeah so building the dirt I
mean it's fun again uh people say farmer
this is a big thing that I got so like
wrecked on do you know what farmer means
historically someone who works the farm
I thought so too MH and until I found
out historically a farmer is a tax
man and he collected taxes and back in
the days when we're talking about these
Farms they were huge yeah and there were
workers and peasants and the workers and
the peasant worked the fields and the
farmer collected the taxes huh so I'm
like I'm not a farmer anymore I'm done
with that with cannabis I don't
represent myself like that
uh and on that note I said what's an
Eden a garden and I'm like I'm a
gardener nice yeah and I like saying
that you know totally Gardener you know
Steward Gardener yeah that's what's up
yeah the Garden of Eden Y and so I
planted fruit trees this year in my
patch it was one of my favorite
experiences of my life to go to the uh
grow store where you know spent a
hundred bracks and nutrients over the
years and dirt and pick up trees and I
was just smiling and everybody there was
so happy and I planted them for my
family for my children for my wife I
said me and you have difficult things
staying in the Cannabis with our
families is extremely challenging yeah
it's uh different than a lot of other
Industries where there's ups and
downs and uh unexpected territory so you
know to have uh the family with you and
behind you is sacred and uh they help me
uh to this day and I put roses in the
garden James because sometimes me and my
wife might have a tough day and I said I
want to remind myself to how beautiful
love is and that if I plant more roses
in the garden that'll remind me how
beautiful my life is and my wife is and
my children are and all the great people
on this planet that's awesome and you
know more of that flee yeah and I said
the trees will grow up around and the
ganja plants will grow in the center you
can eat the fruit I always love walking
around outdoor patches with fruit trees
yeah and it's like on the garden tour
like when you go through your room it's
room to room you know outdoor it's uh
bed to bed and you're eating the fresh
fruit because everything is ready it's
harvest time it all comes down it all
comes down yeah so let's talk about
genetics for a little bit I mean you're
a breeder you do seed production you do
a lot of stuff I brought my box you
brought the box from my this is part of
my seed Vault and it's a little dirty
because it's dirty on the hill yeah you
know people talk about how you keep your
seeds this is a good thing I like to
keep mine in this generic box in the
garage in a cool place nice
and uh you control humidity uh it stays
ambient and cool yeah it's a three star
uh garage with an office and a two room
so the back room is Just Kosher nice and
uh yeah if I need to close the door run
a heater I mean a cooler I'm dyslexic
yeah part of my genius people don't know
about dyslexia they always look at it as
a uh you know I was brought up as a
learning disability MH and it's like my
mom was an amazing Advocate taking me to
India helping me with my dyslexia and
what people don't realize is people with
dyslexia uh get confused like the bus
going from the left to the right usually
people know their route and they go to
the right side and they come up with
similar answers but when you're dyslexic
you go to the other side and I love the
saying straight out of left field yeah
and you come up with something different
and also have ADD where like I can
single task better than anyone in the
room and you know people talk about add
with being losing your attention and not
being a to focus but it's actually quite
the opposite absolutely so you know I'm
loving that Superhero aspect and you
know my mom went to a seminar about
dyslexia and after they told them all
these brilliant things that dyslexics
can do the first question from the crowd
was what do I have to do to become
dyslexic
so to everyone out there that has that
you
know I I applaud you and it can be
challenging but it can also be rewarding
so yeah and genetics so I brought the
Box Black Sheep
genetics and I had I said you know I
wanted to really just show you some of
the work and here it is like me and you
make it I have fancy
packaging show you some of that
cool with the colors absolutely but then
I also got our tried and true Sif good
stuff yeah so I brought out some of my
library we can start checking out I came
up with a really cool thing I think for
the industry you know I like to be
creative I'm an inventor I'm an
alchemist uh and so there's all this
waste yeah and the seed packages you
know
nobody cares about this right right so I
said I've counted so many seeds with the
cards with the spinnies with a lot of
things and then I had the Epiphany what
about a pill pack and uh that pill packs
are made specific sizes so they have
like z z in a Range sure and then I said
I could just go over the swipe card like
the P they way they fill pill packs is
they have a board and you set them in
and then you just swipe a card over it
it fills to the volume right so I match
the volume to the quantity of seeds and
the size of the seed and then I'm
putting them in these gelatin pill packs
nice and I'm like that's biodegradable
yes it's a great way to compact it and
then you know the future of this is to
have you know a 10 um cell pack sure and
have 10 I shared pollen last year with
farms and it was an experiment James let
me tell you to where some of them made
some seeds some of them didn't that's
how it goes yeah that's how it goes I
feel you my my goal is that one day we
can share pollen and put in 10 of our
selects from each different breeder nice
and gift you know that as you know
ultimate fenal hunt yeah well and it's
really great if you have something that
you really like and to be able to take
the pollen from that put it on 10
different things from 10 different
people and then grow those out and and
look at what was passed on by the
parents uh you get some interesting
results and you really start to
understand your lines better I think
that's a great way to understand your
breeding
lines uh and it's also a fun way to
collaborate with your friends and people
that are out there you know it's it's
great higher Heights is you know has
high standards yeah and uh he was like
unless you make the four plants I'm not
even willing to accept it as yours wow
and you know he says you make the first
cross Y and then you make the second
cross and then you cross cross those and
then it's yours right and he works with
Shiloh a lot I really enjoyed the show
with you and Shiloh yeah that was a good
one that was a fun one he's a character
it was awesome yeah and organic Brian
like I said that's my other comrade
that's who I'm working with the
nutrients on yeah yeah uh so back to
genetics my ADD I'm all over the place
uh let's run through some I'll just give
you some names and then we can talk
about them so I got the pineapple zasio
yeah I've got a couple zasio cross I
really like the
z41 you know bachio 41 it's a good one
it's a really good one we got still
slapping out there I got seeds of that
in the Next Room AIO cherry pie
throwback classic doesn't get powdery
mildew nice was the problem with cherry
pie when we grew Girl Scout cookies and
Cherry Pie I honestly like cherry pie
better yeah but then got PM in the room
sure and we were like we can't run
it all right and then uh this is a poly
Ploy that I bred a pineapple caviar I
crossed Leo's pineapple tie he searched
the world like two times over for it and
found the original such a cool Plant uh
with his white caviar which was really
nice plan I know he's doing some
breeding with it now again he's brought
it out so I'm looking for his CRM Ros
who's got the CRM rose that shit's fire
we got we got to hit him up yeah I got
to hit him up I don't think he has it
right now but somebody has it out there
Frenchie kept everything Frenchie was
the Vault for him yeah he explained that
as every seed they got I just got some
of his vanilla berry pie I don't know if
you remember that one I ran it so yeah
so I did too and in 2018 I ran it it was
out in probably 2016 same year and so
out of a patch of a lot of plants in my
buddy's backyard there was this little
area of these white plants and and they
stood out from 50 feet away and
everybody that would go back there would
be like what's that what's that we lost
the cut it was the best and the turps
were amazing it was super turpy it was
berries and it was ass and it was amaz
amazing nose I mean it was very very
loud all of the Expressions were loud
out of 10 seeds or 12 seeds I don't
remember what it was but super white and
super Frosty and sticky like the old
school sticky you don't see sticky as
much as you used to I hear you uh it's
like a photographic memory for me James
and I could see vanilla berry pie on row
five in my upper patch 18 and it was
similar because we had people walking
through the gardens and I kid you not
people said the exact same thing coming
through my patch being like what's that
and the structure of it it branched out
it grew so uniformed and strong strong
and just boom boom boom just kept going
yeah yep so Leo gave me 20 of those
seeds we're running them here that's
what we're in the middle run I'm glad to
bring back some of these things you're
talking about bringing that back guess
what I have popped what do you got I
Caleb the
librarian uh CSI yeah and just released
GDP yeah I saw yeah and and Bubba he's
got
Bubba bro I gave the Bubba to one of the
best indoor Growers that I knew and I
was like I'm not sure if you're going to
want to run this and he was like
definitely yeah and I was like yes I and
as much as you and I can grow you know
you got to give some other things to
other people because we can't grow it
all no so I'm doing the GDP and I'm
doing the Urkel from him yeah and then
Urkel tends to be trickier where he ran
a couple different fenos he's on his
chit yeah and uh so he had like plant
number 106 and 103 and then he made a
cross of Grape Ape Urkle and I was like
yes please I really want to revitalize
the pers so what do you think Grape Ape
is genetics wi cuz I I don't know that
I'm not asking as a trick question or
anything but like Grape Ape there was
the big argument between Grape Ape and
GDP being sisters I don't know they're
they're very different plants I mean
they're completely they grow very
different from what I understand Mr pers
man made the great paper yeah rest in
peace Mr pers yeah there's there's
somebody else out there trying to take
credit we're not even going to say his
name on the show but uh you know either
way it doesn't even matter same thing
with GDP they're both amazing yes Grape
Ape was a it would stack it would get
huge whereas [ __ ] GDP would be small
and dude pungent super pungent and I
think grap apape was more subtle we used
to run nine plants in a 4x4 we had
played with all the numbers it's like if
you were growing GDP the magic number
was nine for us nice yeah my dad used to
run a flashlight over my canopy when I
started apprenticing under him and he
said if you could see the light and I
was screwing up wow and you know our
cies were so solid and we used to run
you know uh back in the day there was
two types of Growers I'd like to say you
know in the on the ends there was the PG
e Growers and there was the other
Growers right and so we were putting up
three lights per table yeah with the
ultimate goal of getting you know 4 lbs
out of a 4x8 table three lights per 3
600s 3, 3000s on a
3, my old man was a Savage where we
bought horux and were suckers for a
while and then he was like check this
out son and he pops open a case and it's
Gees yeah and he got him for 20 bucks
and he was like we're relamping every
run and he loveed cleaning the ball out
right next to each other you'd have
3000s on a 4x4 that's it split the table
with 3000 totally yeah yeah we did I did
600s I never did thousands like that but
we did 300 we used to do uh e and flow
flood and drain yeah and GDP was like I
grew it for years I mothered it for
years I had like I said the Hell's
Angels cut which was
amazing and uh I found that it was like
a swamp plant James yeah I used to flood
my tray for 12 hours and and then let
them out and it was the purplest
happiest plant it ever could be so what
type of hoods did you use when you were
going 3000s did you guys use the air
cooled so you were we were we were using
6 inch air cooled yeah uh my old man
would go to the grow we used to go up
the street here to grower Choice yeah uh
and Metallica's uh band would come in
and buy stuff from them and we'd see
other people and they had their pites
that are like scary ious PES known a man
yeah and uh my dad would break out the
light meter at the grow store and he was
friends with Steve and he'd have Steve
Turn All the Lights On and my dad would
geek uh he was a scientist my father
actually did missile propulsion for
rathon and uh so he was just straight
specking the lights and we found the top
ballast from you know all the ones they
had and at that time believe we were
working with hux or no it wasn't Sun Sun
something Sun Sun System Sun Sun systems
or something like that the old thousand
watt metal
B and we used to have to replace caps
bring it to the grow store get a new cap
totally ballasts were separate whole
whole different world back then right
you could put the ball above the room if
you wanted to if you're real smart you
put them above the room because there's
all that buzzing right right we used to
also hang our cleaners our scrubbers
yeah above the room and on that you know
I love because so many people use the
scrubbers the right way and when you use
a scrubber the right way what are you
doing using it the wrong way because the
way I came to figure it out was you run
it backwards really and we used to
reverse the flow and instead of blow out
we'd suck
in and my dad would joke about it
because we had a 12inch fan on top of a
big you know can yeah and you'd be like
don't get your hair CAU in that hippie
like hold on your hat and stuff you know
and people were walking by it but it was
way more productive and you didn't have
to duct it or you know just to reverse
it and slam it back out yeah my old man
was diligent about building the rooms
where when you shut the door it would
suck yeah Bo you had that reverse
pressure you know
yeah yeah yeah all about that reverse
pressure hey I said your new room's flat
white I love it my favorite color in a
grow room yeah so let's talk about how
you got started with breeding you you
know did you what did you start breeding
for I was started breeding because you
know I had done all other facets where
you know you get tired of repeat and I
always like to my old man said push the
science um and experiment some sometimes
I get pissed because he'd run around
perfect and they change something up and
it wouldn't be as good but he made his
case for you know uh pushing things
forward and uh on that
note I think when I had finished up you
know indoors and went to outs then I did
some
depths uh and I did greenhouse and you
know the the final frontier for me was
breeding yeah and so you know to have
the chance to make my own plant was the
most special
opportunity and I went into that and you
said the PLL chucking before and I was
halfway into that
story uh with I got inspired by the
gouder family Mikey G and his father and
I was like I'm going to ask the illst
breeder I know how to do it yeah
and um I went to
him he says to me so you gotta separate
out the mail that you like and repot it
up about a mile away from everything and
he's like you put it into a big pot or
in the ground just like you do the other
plants and you let it get huge and I was
like man this is a huge undertaking like
this is a serious problem
yeah but with his wisdom I I went on
that kind of route and I had this uh
male that was Giant in my garden that I
let rip and uh I didn't know what the
hell to do with it and uh so I banged it
a little bit and the pollen drifted on
like three plants and I was like oh well
and I was growing was at the time so I
was like I want to make seeds in every
because we use hemp seed I was like
it'll be even better chocolate milk yeah
and so I was like oh I messed that up
I'm by myself as we know in cannabis you
can have a lot of friends when it comes
to working in the field you're on your
own and I took the plant and I
went and the PLL went up like 50 fet in
the air with a huge plume and I was
like and I watched it just crushed the
entire patch nice and I was like well I
guess I check that
box and you know uh then getting more
into it and you know really being
inspired with learning about you know
punet
squares about uh you know
ibls
s1s you know uh breeding forwards
breeding
backwards and uh and all the diversity
and I was in hot spot in Round Valley
that has some of the most ancient
genetics you know from natives from uh
veterans from a lot of people who have
grown there over the years and I was
really fortunate with to be able to go
to these breeders and start you know uh
getting the genetics that I liked and a
breeder told me a long time ago and he
was spot on when he said to me you know
when you start breeding you'll figure
out what flavors you like and we all
like different flavors
and that's going to kind of drive your
train so you know with that in mind then
I started to you know find specific
cultivars and uh and Growers and reach
out to them build that terar Network and
develop you know my
own
and so fast forward to
today I got a couple more we'll run
through oh these are special
somebody gifted me these at eag Clash
and they're hemp seeds James that grow
25 foot tall hemp plants oh I need some
of those yes you're getting right now
and I want you to see how large the
seeds are take a look and I got some
other seeds but we can put those next to
holy [ __ ] oh my God big huge seeds it is
unreal how uh I was so ped I said that's
what I went to Ego Clash for and I was
like it's just another like we said the
plan is so diverse like no one you can
constantly experiment these are 0 z i I
would guess I can weigh this and I'm
pretty good at guessing weight because
I've done it so much but these are 04s
you don't see 0 Z4s almost never right
these are I have some 01 so these are
four times bigger if not bigger than
that so I got the here's some other
flavors the Lemon Cherry
skunk that's awesome I got
G10 uh G10 I said is the highest note
you can hit when people sing yeah this
[ __ ] gets you high kicks you in the nuts
oh yes and not only that are you ready
for drum roll yeah drum roll drum roll
we got it finishes in August and it's
not an Autoflower really no Autoflower
genetics in it it's got early Afghan
genetics that I believe have like this
really early photo period
yeah uh and it's hard to sex those
plants I've noticed some of these ones
that I found and I bred I have a couple
strains that finish in August I did a
collab with Leo uh and I called one the
Rainbird and there's this bird that
shows up uh it's also called like the
pikaa and uh it shows up before
monsoons and people always talk about
science and
spirit and that's a big vice for me in
our industry as we know there's been
lots of turmoil there so this bird
represents the
spirit and uh science caught up with the
bird and they were able to track the
bird and so to prove the lore comes to
find out James the spirit story and the
legend is true and that the bird
migrates in front of the rain and so if
you see that bird that means that the
monsoon is coming or that the rain is on
its
way and thus they're giving it that name
because the Cannabis comes in before the
rain and I said the people in Maine the
people in Canada the people in all these
climates need those genetics yeah you
know they are out there in their fields
there's the happiest person and then
they're crying because Frost came yeah
and it just devastated them speaking of
that we've talked about a frost solution
for everyone too and what we said is to
wait till the sun is
cresting and as it's tracking in on the
patch to spray the plants with
water and maybe there's a chance I
haven't tried it yet but you know if you
caught it in that window maybe it
wouldn't burn
and uh yeah so doing genetics that
finish early for people giving people
what they need you know working with the
plant to make the magic yeah so the true
breeding work is in the pheno hunting in
the selection process 100 seeds minimum
100 seeds minimum for you to do your
selections minimum yep and you do your
selections outside uh mostly you do
inside I'm doing them all outside now
yeah
well you're breeding for outside too I
feel like correct you breed indoors for
indoor plants you breed outdoors I mean
you can do both you could do you can
make your seeds indoor for outdoor but I
think a lot of guys when you're doing
the selection process if you're growing
for outdoor you better be selecting for
outdoor for that specific region it's
complicated though when I like pass on a
plant outdoors because it doesn't check
the three boxes yeah one box isn't
checked it's gone and then my friend
calls me up and he's like do you still
have any of number
four and I'm like what are you talking
about and he's like bro come over to my
greenhouse and take a look and he's like
it's the one yeah and so you never know
the expressions in the multi-
environments and I'm like there needs to
be more of that and more science you
know because again when people come to
us for genetics we might have it oh yeah
it doesn't work in this environment but
it slays in this one variety testing in
multiple environments it's always good
because it Expressions come so
differently outdoor from one region to
the next can be completely different
Greenhouse can be different side by side
with your outdoor so I'm bringing back
the skunk did you see the latest issue
of uh skunk magazine I did not okay well
Julie is an angel absolutely and uh I
got in there uh with a strain review uh
on the winter issue
nice and unlike I've ever seen in any
strain reviews
James I put a mail in that is a first
that is a first danst stud bro this
male BW me away and it's like it has a
story of course the I'm not worthy plant
does yeah and I found this skunk in my
patch H where I had had one plant come
up and I thought the patch got
sprayed wow literally I was looking for
a skunk and I live in the Hills I know
what a [ __ ] skunk smells like excuse
my French and so then I'm stumbling
around the patch looking and I come up
on the plant and I'm like all dang there
it is pure skunk purit yeah like I said
insane like overrode every plant in the
garden and I was like excited and that
was the year that I did the open
pollination yeah so uh I didn't know
where or when that would show back up
but I collected that seed from uh the
plant and then um I dealt with some
Strife in my life and uh I got
cancer and this plant uh is special to
me and has been you know my passion my
journey but little did I know it was
also GNA Be My
Savior and you know uh growing out
genetics uh whether it
be CBD like we said CBG THC it's all
medicine so you know I uh whether you
believe it or not it's medicine right
Dennis prone said that but yeah that's
one of the best lines ever there it is
and uh so you know I kind of had to step
back from
everything and my family and my friends
helped me get through it and I got
amazing treatment from not only uh
Western medicine but also Eastern
medicine my sister is a naturopathic
doctor and graduate from baser big
upis and so I tacted with everything I
was eating RSO blessed heart I was
giving it out in the waiting room people
say thank you it's like you can't give
out cake there and when people are
getting uh
chemotherapy but you can give out
RSL and you know it hasn't gone full
stream where they even have the fake
cannabis that they prescribe to people
and it's just the Marin the Marinol
straight trash yeah and so you know
there's all these great people that are
willing to donate I was donated medicine
helped me get through it um with putting
one foot in front of the other I was
happy that I could walk through hell and
my family and I uh persevered on and now
I'm a new version and I'm happy James
Sam back full remission full remission
amazing yeah absolutely amazing
congratulations we're glad you're here
yeah glad you're here on the show this
is great and you know to be able to
continue to work with the plant and gone
through cancer and come back you know it
changed me I'm so much more humbled I'm
so much more
grateful uh I appreciate you know the
elders for their humility I I try to
listen more and talk less coming back to
the table now uh I did I was I was a
little bit uh you know in recovery still
but I never gave up I grew the whole way
through yeah and I went up and there's a
video on me online where I went out to
the field and I said I couldn't hand
water that year and so I put a Rainbird
out and my whole family went up with me
and I said let's just go Chuck seed and
I got bags of seed right so I'm like I
can just toss it like Johnny Apple weed
yeah and uh went out there and told
people about how great it was and direct
sewing direct sewing
and and uh Moroccan style the Moroccan
style or Las Vegas
style one of the we should intersect
here because it's radical uh no manners
you ever heard of the manners family no
maybe manners family he's a quad OG or
was rest in peace no uh the capistrana
you ever heard that name he invented the
heart stint
and he owns a ranch in Koval and he's
about as tough as they come yeah and he
still runs cattle like Cowboys down the
road with leather coats and they got
their McNab dogs and they block traffic
and they ride through and he's a real
raner and at n's wake uh cistron came up
to me with the cowboy hat and he said
you know what null was he said no was a
quad OG and I'd never heard that before
and he said that size it
gets so you know I named a strain after
him with that I had to you know get on
that a little bit quad OG nice and uh
yeah null is the person that brought the
AFU and their family farms is gooey
Farms nice and uh he was kind of Eddie
Le page with crows everywhere you look
working with huge amounts of people he
told me stories about about doing the
loops from California to Texas with
duffel bags in the
airports and uh back to Las Vegas so I'm
riding his
car uh you know you're pretty special to
ride with the Godfather and I'm
wondering what we're going to talk about
one of my favorite places to be in the
car he says to me I went to uh Las Vegas
and I was working with this guy and he
was growing in pools and he ripped out
12 pools and they were in all these
different places and they would just go
like me and open broadcast seed and then
grow it up in the pool crazy and so he
said he went to check in on things with
his partner and that uh the person uh
coming to the gate was late and he was
in a fancy like the guy had a fancy
Corvette and was sipping around because
he's the magic man right and no is a
partner with
and so he's trying to repress him and
the guy that came up to the gate he goes
off on him and it was his son he started
yelling at him why weren't you here you
should have been here you knew we were
coming and so the Godfather said red
flag there's something
wrong and so he said I called up my
family I told them that I didn't think I
was going to be able to come home and
that that I was going to have to see
this thing through and he said he stayed
a couple days and sure enough there were
like three more other buyer or partners
that he didn't know about oh wow so he
had to stay there and see the course
from from you know middle to
finish and he said to me you know the
hard part was when I told that to my
family she said that's okay his wife but
I might not be here when you come
home and he
stayed yeah and she wasn't there when he
came home and that was a story you know
that when you hear it changes you he
shared it with me for a reason and you
know I'm grateful again to have my
family and again they learned to get
along later and he had a another
relationship and I love seeing families
that can separate and then hang out in
the room and be have a good time yeah
and thus me the black sheep that's not
how it went with my family a lot of the
time so where' the name came from so he
brought in all the you're talking about
gooey yeah where did the name came no
Black Sheep where did the name Black
Sheep come from uh that came from you
know my family background of being a
uh kind of a rogue character getting
into cannabis doing different things and
then you know I had a lot of Fallout uh
my dad battled with his family they had
restraining orders my uh mother had to
pull him off his brother you know and
take his guns away so it got pretty ugly
and you know I said we were a band of
two and me and Pops you know uh tread
the uh ground uh with class for a long
time and my mom and him got separated
and I'm good with my mother she's an
amazing uh person in my life as well
blessed moms all moms good stuff well
yeah so what what's your take on social
media social media I'm I I think that
there's great things I like you know
it's like a Multiverse I guess you know
it's it's a blessing and a curse yeah
there's I don't want to be scrolling and
have my kids call me out dad you're
scrolling on your phone right I don't
like eating food and seeing people on
scrolling you know sure uh but I do like
the connectivity I do like how many fun
people we've reached out to like that
this show is gonna touch yeah you know
the shine and I'm like I any of the beef
or the haters that's fine and all the
more you come up the more they are it's
just to it's just the you know props to
you because you're actually doing
something and it's like me and you are
working on very important work and it's
not of the moment it's of what people
will remember in my mind and you know to
build the legend to build the Legacy so
if somebody wants to find out more about
you or get your genetics where can they
go they can go to uh dark heart uh I
heard he said I was talking with him or
not dark heart I'm sorry Dark Star Dark
Star Dark Star uh and uh he said Tito
was on your show and that he gave him
some props too yeah yeah Tino's the man
yeah so uh that was cool he was like
props two different shows on James L
let's go nice good stuff Detroit Rock
City yeah I love to get my genetics
there I've got about eight or nine
different places throughout the us that
you can find uh seed banks that I'm
available on you're black sheep genetics
on Instagram Black Sheep genetics you
have some great reals you're a family
man you do some really cool stuff so
yeah it's been great having you on the
show we got my my new breeding book uh
you guys want to check out the breeding
book this is out now you can go to
jamesl genetics.com we got this fun book
that has 380 pages about genetics and
plants and all my uh favorite things we
grow together so on a final note I
wanted to tell you because this is
really special so this bud is I'm
calling it The leather because it's
tough when you smoke it you're going to
get
faded and uh it's from uh the legendary
family that we spoke of the gouts and
James guy that's helping him out
building his rooms uh one of his
right-hand men said that he worked with
the guy that grew this in kovala yeah
where I'm like it's a small world yeah
so my guy Matt he's the head
with James loud genetics he small world
used to work with the guy that grew the
flower that's in your hand which I his
name because he I gave him a nickname
because he's he's just a rogue character
he lives in a cave so I'm coined him the
caveman nice that's his new nickname and
he likes it so it's going to stick and
this weed was cured in a cave and I'm
like some estate aging where you know I
had to do some love when I got at home a
little little bit but the long cure
getting getting wet getting dry but not
too much no fuzz on this yeah yeah and
just bringing out those great flavors so
part of the gift is James that this is
my favorite strain of the year that's
awesome and there's seeds in it for you
that's even better so I'm like you got
the genetics you get to smoke it through
one of my favorite ways to pull seeds
out is smoke them through and drop them
in a little special jar we'll run some
here that sounds amazing boom so big up
to this the leather all the people
growing out there it's not you it's not
me it's us thanks for having me on thank
you so much for coming I look forward to
having you back someday all right Cheers
Cheers
[Music]