[Music]
how's it going everybody welcome to
another episode of the James loud
podcast and today our special guest is
uh catchmaster Alex how you doing today
good good yeah dude thank you so much
for coming on the show yeah thank you
yeah I've actually been wanting to come
on your show I've been a fan been
checking it out and we had some mutual
friends and yeah Josh Freeman uh
Silverback Freeman he's the one who
connected us uh I go 20 years back more
than 20 years back with him and you as
well yeah so we were running around the
same Circle and just different sides of
it yeah exactly yeah we probably even
were in the same room at one point I'm
sure probably yeah seriously and uh we
both like uh Sour Diesel yeah yeah sour
d y that's actually uh I think that's
how I met Josh really is I want to say
initially was picking up sour yeah and
then and then when he he was out he
needed more sour so and I was growing
more sour so then I ended up supplying
them sour it was it was really actually
for me it's it's you know we wouldn't
say it right then but it was chem dog
you know I mean it was getting the chem
the chem 91s chem 4S you're calling it
chem dog even though it sour calling it
sour they were yeah they were sour
passing is kind of how would say you
know we were I was I'd be honest you
know with Josh and let him know what's
up and all that but you know as long as
they had the good noes that was all what
was all about he used to grow the best
sour yeah that I remember yeah um you
know his his outs and his depths of sour
were sticky I know like Sticky Sticky
Buds you just don't see stuff like that
well that dead pass is indoor I mean
yeah well he sold it for more than
indoor like
even knowing it was depth you're like it
you didn't care because it was so loud
and you open the bag up it would hit you
in the face you know I love that that's
what's up for sure yeah I miss those
days especially somoma cazadero Menino
back then they were just it was at its
peak I think yeah and not that they're
not peeking now in their own ways but
like back then like the Cannabis scene
really peaked up there yep Sebastapol
yeah for sebasol to ocidental Sebastapol
Santa Rosa all those place there was
great flower going around uh late 90s
early 2000s even before that but like
man the the flower was great back then
yeah it was yeah how did you get your
start in the industry feel like I grew
up in the in the subculture this it's
kind of just part of my life you know
you kind of have no choice but to be in
it almost it felt like at at the moment
um just because it's like a big part of
like your circle my my my dad grew um I
was just around cannabis all the time so
um but I I've kind of had um kind of
kind of went more towards like my
natural my natural abilities was like
sales you know and just combining like
my love for cannabis and like my
community and having access I think is
probably a big reason yeah it's kind I
think probably the number one reason why
I got into it is just like you were
saying some of the best cannabis I think
um especially especially back then that
anyone had ever seen you know in the
world or in the United States they
obviously there's some stuff that's
comparable in the world but um coming
out of Menino humbal obviously there's a
lot of humble root
um the Bay Area I mean it just goes on
triangle Bay Area right place right time
I guess is I guess is what I'm trying to
say yeah we were blessed to be in that
place at that time that's really what it
is for sure yeah cuz I mean uh you know
it's funny it's to say I'm 40 years old
and to say I've been in it for 20 years
is kind of ridiculous you know more than
20 years I'm 47 you're 47 47 I feel you
yeah you know there's not a lot of
professions you can be this age and say
you've been in it that long you know you
know just to you know it's it's pretty
amazing we talk about are 18-year-old
selves a lot of this show like you know
I think there's only two people that you
really want to impress that's your 18yar
old self and your 80-year old self and I
think most of the people in this
industry you know their 18year old
selves would be pretty stoked yeah yeah
yeah so I know I know my 18y old self
would be like right on that's pretty
[ __ ] cool yeah it's pretty magical
honestly I owe a lot to cannabis yeah
yeah it's it's brought a lot for me I've
had some hard times you know and the
Transitions and and trials and
tribulations that I think pretty much
everyone has gone through especially if
they've been in it for last couple
decades yeah um but I wouldn't trade it
for the world yeah totally and you've
done all kinds of stuff in the industry
I mean besides the products you have now
you used to work with Botanicare It's
Kind of a Funny Story how I got into all
that I was I was growing and um I got
turned on to poan botanic like PR grow
Pro Bloom liquid Karma recipe yeah with
the cow mag of course cow mag was in
everything you know and I was just
rocking that recipe that was passed down
to me from someone older than me you
know we were picking it up from um Hydro
was I think was I think was one of one
of the connects you know and there's of
course Marin Hydro those two connects y
people started liking what I my results
right and they're asking me what I'm
doing so naturally I mean this is I
wasn't working for botanic a but I was
working for Botanicare on accident
because what I was doing is I was
getting everyone turned on to the
recipes yeah and we were pushing the the
EC high and like the ppm's high on on
that stuff because I mean it just worked
you know we especially with sour we were
able to push it right and you know get
that yield up and and get that that nose
up and all that M but um was I started
actually see here I moved to another
spot I had six grow Ops actually back
then yeah and they were all Partnerships
kind of kind of deals with medical Aira
stuff yeah and one of the spots was next
to Santa Rosa hydra's new little they
had they had a little shop I mean they
didn't have the big one they had a
little one that's now owned by grow
generation yeah um but so I was a
regular there and then um they really
started stocking a whole bunch of
Botanicare product because of me like
I'm going there and I'm I need five
gallons of this I need five gallons of
that you know over and over again you
know I need uh you know do you guys got
the 30 gallon drums you know totally and
they're like who is this guy you know
and so then um so then I actually
started helping them hire and train
there that's that's kind of got started
in the industry a little bit there at
Sant Hydro helped them uh find some
people um train some of their staff
helped with them purchasing like letting
them know hey you need these supplements
you need these you know these additives
um uh you know this is how you know this
is ready grow Coco you know this is how
Coco works because not a lot of people
were rocking it as as strong back then I
hated Coco back in the day where you
have to get the blocks oh the yeah yeah
yeah all that you put him in a kitty
pool and you got that's why ready grow
was like kind of a big thing back then
you know from Botanica obviously um
there's a lot of other companies that
make U just as good or better products
than than that but at that time it was
revolutionary to have something premixed
and ready to go and stuff but it still
required a lot of CM mag right you know
totally which was really really
beneficial for Botanicare but anyways
long story short I'll try on that side
was is that I they finally got opened up
a bigger facility you know and I was
rolling through with cards and TG the
founder of was there at the shop and he
had never seen such a large array of
their products you know usually when
they go in the shops it's just the Heavy
Hitters yeah but I was getting really
into the nitty-gritty all their cool
little supplements they had you know
clex and organic hairline and yeah all
these things uh humic and fulvic and and
uh kind of messing with those different
things and so they saw it it looked
really nice and it was really stocked
and then they saw me rolling through
with the big carts yeah he's all get
that guy's number you know I want to
talk to him yeah initially I didn't I
didn't want to stop growing really so I
wasn't you know I was didn't have time
and I was making good you know making
making good let's just say right with
growing so um they asked me to work for
them but instead what I did is I did
some development beta testing with them
um and actually help create a three-part
nutrient system we had we had like eight
bottles come in all white label and um
and we broke them all the way down to
just three parts it's called kind it's a
three-part nutrient system oh yeah the
goal was the goal was is to not have to
not require calmag yeah and if you think
about it this like Botanicare most
famous product that's literally used
with GH it's used with Advanced
Nutrients at that time especially was
their Cal Mag it was botan's Cal Mag
sure so then he's like well you know
what I'm going to do is I'm going to
make a three-part that doesn't require C
mag so it's kind of it's a very very
creative idea yeah and so Grilla was
sold to Botanicare was that before after
no I brokered that you're the one who
brokered it yeah yeah oh that's awesome
yeah I was yeah so I had so I had my
indoor Ops and then I had the um depths
and the outdoors you know and all those
and those uh Josh Josh really turned me
on to the top tress totally and all that
that stuff is great it's a lifesaver
really I mean just if you need to leave
and you got you're relying on somebody
that doesn't know what they're doing you
tell them okay look you lay it all down
and just water you know what I mean we'
scratch in a little bit you know
everyone's now doing no till and stuff
but yeah low till no till whatever you
know yeah exactly but um you know there
was some we had meetings I did a lot of
R&amp;D for Botanicare um we de we were
developing um a baker's rack tray at the
time I think right around that time and
uh we were making a a blend called
slacker didn't quite take off but it was
like soil blend and we they were talking
about a lot of organic inputs and I just
kind of brought it up in one of those
brainstorming meetings at botan in
Arizona by the way because I would have
to go to Arizona once a month for those
guys oh wow and um then um they're like
well tell me more about this grow Willa
and we kind went back and forth and I
connected connected them together and
brokered that that deal and now
technically uh Scotts Miracle Grow one
of the largest companies in the gr
Growers Market Growers industry yeah
owns our buddy Josh
agriculture product he created amazing
right like totally it's amazing how how
it goes yeah yeah Josh did all kinds of
stuff roots and Harmony and yeah I mean
his his we were just talking about our
last guest Kyle was talking about his uh
his mixtapes being the best oh really
yeah he's a DJ and Josh had calendars I
remember his calendar I actually hung
his calendars up do you have any of
those still I still do I actually have a
briefcase full of calendars High Times
magaz we got to bring back the roots of
Harmony calendars yeah yeah yeah those
are sick I mean I I literally have the
one like with kushage in it cuz he used
to goow kushage and Sour Diesel and then
he's also the guy who brought the Durban
down from Canada he went bought the Cy
seed pack of of uh Durban and then made
the Ripple Plum yeah and the raspberry
cheesecake damn and a bunch of stuff
Sour Diesel times Durban yeah he's that
dude yeah yeah he's a good that's dope
actually I had I had my hands on some
Durban for a minute yeah I was growing
it and and picking it up and moving it
and stuff so funny cuz his der is
different really than the Durban I see
from everybody else pretty much like if
his Durban is the real Durban I've seen
it for a handful of times but most of
the Durban that's going around is very
like super silver I mean I haven't even
honestly seen what I know is Durban uh
for years yeah I mean I've seen Durban
from people and I'm like hey that's more
like super silver haze than did like
Durban Poison because Durban is really
musky really musky it hits hard it hit
it yeah I mean it'll it'll kick you in
the dirt it will yeah so strong and it
takes it takes long to grow too yeah
yeah yeah yeah yeah I mean if you if you
push it you know but I mean you get
Monster Monster Co yeah to trade-off is
yield yeah for sure it looks awesome
indoors it's also kind of hairy yeah I I
remember it being a little dark too yeah
yeah yeah yeah and there's it's
interesting all the different bag appeal
things that happened over time that's
changed you know I remember going from
uh you want it to be bright and limey
you know to purple and then then not
purple you couldn't sell purple to save
your life purple was super unpopular
yeah there was like the yeah purple orle
GDP and all of a sudden yeah yeah super
purple purple yeah and there was like
good meno perss and all that stuff and
it was really popular and then one day
nobody wanted purple you couldn't sell
it to save your life yeah it was like
you you got to go to Richmond to sell
purple or wherever like there was a
couple places you could probably still
move it it definitely didn't want in La
the Bay Area was very picky and I think
OG and sour pretty much took over right
right then right is thatt is that the
right I think for sure yeah so and it
was all everyone wanted OG I have I have
a theory about that about the OG and
sour popularity thing is it's very
different than what we're doing with now
is that it was actually really hard to
grow it was actually hard to get it to
come out really good yeah you know and
that if you got really good OG or really
good sour like good Strong Nose right
you know it's it's full potential you
were the [ __ ] and you had the [ __ ] yeah
you know it's not everybody could do
that you know and so I think that that
had some play in it well and I don't
honestly think that they perform as well
under LEDs as they do perform under HPS
or c or combination of the two that's
just my two sents I've heard from you
know Brian and vital some of the stuff
those guys D the C is the the ticket
I've heard from some people other I like
HPS still yeah I like HPS flow I like
smoking HPS I like the turps yeah not
there's anything wrong with LED I think
it works for a lot especially the purple
stuff candy stuff I think that it works
well for that but you know it's just
it's a personal preference to but I
don't see a lot of good OG now you know
we don't really see it uh and it is it
is hard to grow s OG I've seen to this
day has always been light dep or been
light you know growing yeah not full
outdoor but like you know full sun depth
not light assist I mean I see some good
Doc O coming from Humble still like
there's some good Doc O packs that I've
seen that are that you know from their
friends grow that are like on that on
that on that point though really it's
chem 91 that I like the most like like I
mean in that realm you it's the most
nostalgic for me it's the most nostalgic
I like it it's it's subtle but it is
like burnt tires like chem 91 has that
burnt Tire appeal and if you love it you
love it see yeah it's anti- candy really
almost yeah it's totally anti- candy and
it's not like GMO or chmd because K GMO
comes from chmd and that's kind of like
it has that burnt Tire still but it's
different yeah yeah or just subtle
subtly yeah yeah and the chem 91 was
different than OG OG's very like earthy
and piny and citrusy and chem 91 it has
earthiness it you know I wouldn't say
it's necessarily really citrusy even
though there's Citrus in it yeah yeah it
is it's pungent yeah it's its own thing
um I like to see learn more see see more
come out about the the chps on the chem
91 yeah be cool yeah I like chem 91 I
like sour those are those are good and
they're coming back yeah they are yeah
they're yeah they're they're making
their comeback it's really like about
you know the right ones you know yeah
but we'll see but there's there's some
arguments sometimes about that over the
years yeah as people say they're you
know their OG right is the OG you know
or their sour is the sour that's that's
always been that's always been since the
beginning of those things early early on
and there's been a lot of like it's
whatever New York wanted really is what
exactly ended up being the but yeah that
gas there's something special about it
and you know gas is taken on its own
life we had like the GMOs and then the
Donnie burgers and you know then they've
evolved into the double burger or
whatever like and those those wash
really well but uh you know and but
that's still not m91 it's very different
so a lot of people when they you know
especially the younger generation they
relate to gas more of like that GMO I
mean gorilla Gorilla Glue that's another
one that took over I brought Gorilla
Glue up from from the cup in LA in
200000 that's another one that's changed
that changed pretty quickly 2013 though
it w it won the cup there and they gave
out clones to everybody it was the
smartest move it was the exact opposite
of whatever we thought we were supposed
to be doing with genetics we're like
close it promoted it it blew up you need
you needed to share it it needed to get
around people needed to talk about it
yeah and they they so freely gave it to
everybody it it was yeah rest in peace
Jessie whales yeah you know actually the
first time I was introduced to it was in
um actually at going into botan meetings
from uh Doug Mar do you know Doug marman
at all in Colorado I know who he is yeah
he actually gave me he actually brought
we kind of we would all we would do that
because we came from all different spots
States we do our our Botanicare meeting
we all brought our buds you know nice
and he he had his a nice Gorilla Glue
yeah I remember when Josh switched over
from sour to uh to glue it was so when
it gorilla so yeah it was in high demand
the silver silver back Grilla
yeah but yeah and and then his hair
turned gray yeah that's perfect time but
yeah so when I remember I gave cuts to
him and my friend Joe and a couple other
people that IID got from the cup and it
was that year other people too because
they gave him out so freely it really
spread like wildfire it went from
everybody growing sour to everybody
growing Gorilla Glue within one season
because it finished faster it New York
you rem that reminds me of something
blackberry kush blackberry kush is a
similar phenomenon it was it was you
know it was like that that no matter
what it looked good no matter what it
looked so good and outdoor it performed
well and it came dark yeah but it was
low THC yeah but you could dep it too it
would it would look like indoor for sure
it looked yeah it looked like straight
indoor yeah you couldn't tell there's
probably today you probably still tell
most people couldn't tell yeah for sure
yeah it was a good one I actually ran
that and did pretty well with Blackberry
Cush yeah yeah I liked it you know I
like the TPS but it was just never like
a strong well that's what everyone
complained they called it like like F's
gold or something you know people were
complaining about yeah but there's now
there's different you know philosophies
on you know what kind of different kinds
of feelings you know cannabis should
give you and sure and all that so maybe
it's something that could get come back
around again you know and people I think
for flavor and I think it's been breed
into a lot of things it has yeah yeah
for sure because I'm I crossed it a
little bit I mean I'm not you know I'm
not going to come on here and say I'm a
breeder you know officially but I I've
played around like a hobby nice you know
and I've crossed it with sour and things
like that dude that's what it's all
about my book is basically all about
that for hobbyists to I ordered I
ordered I ordered a book I saw that yeah
I think I reposted your uh your reel oh
yeah nice dude but yeah thank you very
much look for to it's it was an
adventure writing the book but yeah it's
it's for everybody and it's like it's
great being able to put all the
information you know Greg green did it
25 years ago but there hasn't been
anything since really yeah so I'm happy
to put a book on the market that I think
is a great you know resource for
information about breathing for because
I I think everybody should breed
honestly it's it's so fun if you're a
good girl or you should breed if you're
not a good girl you should learn how to
grow better yeah um but at the end of
the day because the pheno hunting is
where you actually see the difference in
the plants and if you don't grow them
well enough to have them Express it's
really hard saying this one's better
than this one this one's better than
this one and vice versa if you line them
up 10 at a time and you're not growing
them while it's kind of tough yeah and I
and I still find people um that out
there travel to the United States I do I
do uh speaking gigs and stuff for
conventions and stuff yeah and um you
know you meet a lot of people that are
just getting into it all and they don't
realize the some of the complexities
there are in youo hunting and and
keeping track of those and making sure
that you you know you keep the ones that
you want and yeah you know taking it all
the way to flower just to find out which
one is good and which one's bad and
there's a lot involved for sure I have a
lot of respect for people who are are in
it like like yourself you know it's lots
of fun and the thing is is like the
amount of genetic diversity varies from
one plant to the next and so you have
something like Blue Dream you make it S1
of Blue Dream and you basically get four
Expressions if you have the real Santa
Cruz Blue Dream cut but then you take
something like gelato 33 and you pop
seeds in every single expression is
different yeah you know where where you
you see the flower of it the way they
grow there's so much uh diversity but
then on the same note you have something
like gelato 41 and it has a lot more
stability than than the 33 and that came
from you know like I said it gives it a
lot of commercial viability for sure
yeah I mean it has and blue dream's cool
it's it's easy to grow I I think there's
a lot of people that hate on it for
whatever reason well I think that go
ties into that thing I was telling you
about like OG and sour being kind of
hard and where blue dream was easy so
blue dream kind of got ripped on you
know it's not that it was bad bad weed
totally yeah I well I think the high the
effect some people want that
like strong narcotic effect and other
people want the uplifting and then some
people want like through the roof Durban
that you know most people can't handle
because their heartbeats too fast yeah
yeah there are different types of people
like people have different react
differently too for sure we've been
seeing that well our body chemistries
are all so different that it affects us
different and then taste and flavor is
so subjective so is effect yeah so
that's true with wine too I see I see
that with wine you know you got the they
got the smell they're like you know
putting all the the hints in your in
your ear about what what you're tasting
and totally sure enough it starts
appearing it's like magic all of a
sudden butter I taste the butter and the
chocolate yeah well same thing with
cigars so cigars is a tough one cuz like
and after getting a bunch of data points
you realize what's what and cigar but
cigars are so strong it's you're looking
for the subtleties and the subtleties
are there but you have to experience it
enough just like with cannabis I think
the average person looks at weed and
they're like oh that's weed but after
you've tried 50 different things or 100
different things or a thousand different
things you have a real different opinion
of it yeah you know and that goes along
with growing too it's it's as basic or
as complex as you want to make it yeah
they're all they're very there's a lot
of uh parallels with uh tobacco yeah uh
cannabis and wine you know alcohol in
general yeah you know I I think tobacco
is one of those things that gets kind of
overlooked a lot I mean obviously
there's the cigar industry yeah but like
you know the tobacco plant and all that
I actually grow tobacco nice and I have
I have I have seeds and some some
crosses and stuff when I grow out a home
and you know there's little tobacco buds
I don't know if you've seen it is for
you yeah oh yeah yeah take that out of
the
podcast I just mean I'm my own little
hom grow I'm not promoting a tobacco
brand right now or growing home tobacco
yeah yeah no but it's it is awesome like
the leaves get all fuzzy they get cool
little like almost like triome looking
things all over the buds and the leaves
and Stuff tobacco is really cool it's I
know I have you know I think it's saer
that you could have a lot more respect
for it it's been kind of bastardized
like you're saying yeah you know when
we're talking about lung cancer and
other things I mean they've proven that
tobacco can cause lung cancer with
cigarettes but like I think from a
sacred and medicinal standal thank you
yeah yeah I mean I guess in some cases
as a as a pest control thing too in some
cases absolutely control yeah man yeah
you it's interesting because I can't
stand the smell of like regular
cigarettes I used to smoke cigarettes a
long timeo yeah I don't smoke cigarettes
either like I said I just hom grow a
little leaf you know roll blunt or
something like that yeah so our mutual
friend Josh he he smokes uh spliffs a
lot of my friend smokes spliffs but
these guys used to bong rip we talking
about that a little earlier about mixing
it with weed and then taking bong rips
grind it up I mean I I fell into that
for a little while cuz it's kind of like
a whip it almost or like you're kind of
you're like zorbing kind of like people
say you Zorb on it right we would take
those quick little mini plastic bongs
you know and hit it real quick you you'd
take like a she would grind up almost a
whole cigarette in with a whole Bud
right you know and grinded down real
fine so so you could smack the whole
thing snap it snap it that's what it was
yeah we call him they call him smokes uh
Mo snaps mix rips mix rips is another
one yeah yeah yeah it was one time I
actually took one of those while sitting
on a balcony thing like a edge you know
on a at an apartment oh no and I almost
fell over fell off I bet those will get
you yeah I got pretty sick on them a
couple times to it was enough for me to
stop doing them I was like a I mean that
was years ago many many years ago well
there's a guy named Paul Che and Paul
Che uses the volcano and he vaporizes
Tob I think he vaporiz other stuff too
but he vaporizes tobacco yeah for
concentration and so he does a lot of
writing and stuff that he's he's one of
the people I look up to like I said I
still respect these things they get they
get kind of blown out of proportion in
her bastard sometimes you know like
you're saying like natural form it's not
a bad thing yeah exactly yeah so and it
can be used responsibly and I think you
know you're talking about something
where there's no combustion he's he's uh
vaporizing it I think that's a probably
a safer and smar way and if it helps
with concentration he's a great writer
he's also you know uh he does sports
medicine and stuff like that so it's
it's pretty amazing stuff do that's
that's dope I did hear you mention Brian
briefly in there you know from vital
Garden Supply oh yeah we got this hat
right here yeah I got a couple of his
hats at my house too I worked actually
worked with vital Garden Supply for a
little bit in between royal gold and um
you work for Royal yeah between Roy gold
and what I'm doing now yeah awesome yeah
I went from Botanica to Roy gold to
vital to what I'm doing now which is
catchmaster nice yeah well let's dive
into catchmaster because uh your name is
catchmaster Alex on Instagram I've taken
a lot of ownership over this project um
you know it's a bigger company than me I
think a lot of initially a lot of people
I think they go you know that is my
company you know yeah but that's the
that's the way I I take pride in it and
I carry in it um when these guys
approached me they came to me and um
presented the idea of bringing them into
the Growers industry they were actually
called Atlantic past and glue company
and they have they do have a brand
called catchmaster that's um for the
professional pest pest world and they
they primarily made like uh like rat
glue trap
and and they made they made the yellow
sticky traps and all those kind of
things but they never really put any
hyperfocus on The Growers industry and
The Growers Market they did a lot of uh
they work you know work with some pretty
big companies like Terminex and orcin
and stuff yeah um and they're American
American company family-owned company
yeah um initially they're kind of
pitching it to me I was just like no no
like because I'm I'm a nutrient
fertilizer uh guy you know like all that
kind of stuff just uh the the Grower's
world you know almost never really
thought twice about the sticky trap you
know snecker TR just like but it's in
every grow room and it's always been
there right you know what I mean and
they really started breaking down to me
like like how what their perspective on
it is like the the professional way of
utilizing them as pest monitors we
always called them pest traps you know
and people are kind of half-hazard
hanging them in the Grow rooms and then
they're just spraying you know and all
these kind of things I mean there's a
lot of Growers for a long time that just
kind of saw [ __ ] and they sprayed right
yeah um and then they put the traps up
to control Nets that's kind of been the
emo for sure so that was to all honesty
that was my P my interpretation of what
a sticky trap was for it was just soil
Nets soil Nets right and then when they
started breaking down the the science of
it and all that I you know I started
studying uh you know I'm working on my
degree right now in sustainable
agriculture oh wow I'm I'm I'm taking a
lot of it really really got me going it
got me kind of more excited because it's
something outside of what I've been
doing all these years which is like like
I said soil and fertilizers um focusing
on integrated Pest Management
understanding the complexities of it has
been awesome um I actually I created
catchmaster grow like I've been the the
front of that um the head of that entire
thing it's a market segment manager
essentially created the helped create
the brand you know we the team we have a
team we a website of course um new
products developing new products and um
really getting the message out there
doing um a hit in the road and all that
um before that um there really wasn't a
you know there wasn't a clear concise
message about like how to use it so at
first I was like like there's no way I'm
going to go down this path you know I'm
going working three years now working
with these guys and on this project um
and uh the sky's a limit for me I really
I see so much more Improvement for
integrated Pest Management and protocols
for cannabis industry yeah there's
people who have their Sops and have
their protocols I'm not going to go
around telling people to change their
Sops necessarily but there's just a few
little tweaks and few things that the
professionals like the people who never
stepped stepped a foot in the in a
cannabis facility ever you know they
don't a lot of them won't even service
cannabis facilities you know these are
federally federally based companies
right you know but I got have a lot of
their information a lot of their
knowledge you know that you I think I
think the the biggest thing right now
for that side of things is having a
dedicated IPM manager is kind of a you
have you have a person who um that also
U you know does the cleaning of the of
the plants and cleaning of the room
things like that you have them also do a
good checking of the pest monitors
having the pest traps up actually having
monitoring for insects and seeing what
insects they have when they have them
where they have them that way can take
appropriate actions you know mhm and
this stuff I know you know yeah you know
but traveling around the United States
and all these Emerging Markets
everywhere um and there's a lot of
misinformation and so much
misinformation I would say when I first
started this I would say more than half
were doing it wrong yeah you know what
they're doing is they're they're
spraying like crazy you know and so and
that's okay I get it that's part of the
SOP and I'm not trying to tell people
stop spraying but the goal of IPM and
this might be controversial is to
eventually reduce or eliminate chemical
sprays or to reluce even maybe organic
sprays you know you want to get down to
the point where you pretty much aren't
doing any yeah and and that's not just
because of sticky traps sticky traps are
going to magically do that on their own
you got to do things like have good
genetics like yours yeah or you're doing
tissue culture uh they're tested they're
they're they're proven that's the first
thing right that's the first step that's
just the foundational step yeah I don't
think people fully wrap their heads
around how important that is yet yeah um
that's the only way they're going to get
to that next stage and and get to that
end goal which is to stop spraying
basically there's so many variables too
like you use soil what's coming in on
your soil yeah yeah exactly yeah that's
exact exactly right and then there's
cultural controls cultural controls I
mean humidity uh temperature um all
those things and then of course um like
we said sanitization and cleaniness all
those things so huge but in in the the
the middle of all of that the reason why
I'm so passionate about with catchmaster
is that it's to monitor the whole time
yeah there's not enough monitoring going
on in the industry you want to be
monitoring from the from when you get
the Clones you have you have your pest
monitor there and just pest monitor is a
sticky trap right but it's the
professional term you have it there and
you have it at the teen stage you have
it the the growing stage the flowering
stage you have different zones people
don't think about zones for a long time
people are just hanging them one one you
got to have one below the canopy you got
to have one near the medium yeah you
want to have one at or near the canopy
and one above the canopy as well and and
if you're in a greenhouse you want to
have up above in the way up there in the
peak you have like an agil rolled out
for mature insects you know and all
these things and have someone check
those things you know twice week yeah
you know and you know I'm probably
preaching to the choir but it's like you
know especially with you know what you
got going on with your brand is you know
your whole thing is having you know
clean good genetics you know but well
and if you're selling clones you're only
as good as your last clone so if you
give someone hop L and verid or whatever
new viruses out or you have tests those
are really big issues and that that uh
basically will uh you know that that'll
affect your brand especially over a long
period of time and people might buy your
stuff because you're popular or you're
you're you know the new hype guy yeah
but if you give them a virus right that
affects their bottom line fix their
wallet yeah see you you said it right
and that's actually the other aspect of
IPM too that I that I've been educating
people on is IPM even though it says
integrated Pest Management a good IPM
protocol or program or practices yeah is
about profitability and so and that's
why when you say reduceed pesticide
sprays well why can't I just keep
spraying well that cost you money for
one thing it cost money yeah and then
have mold and fungus viruses all these
things are going to affect yield um
spraying constantly could affect yield
there's a lot of reasons why you want to
have good good IPM good you know a good
protocol and actually follow it step by
step in that order at the very the very
last resort should be chemical spray to
be honest right that's your last resort
but um there's a certain point where it
always you has to happen in any industry
uh restaurants houses hotels throughout
agriculture there's there's a certain
point where you have infestations are
infestations and right sometimes there's
no choice well if you have a nursery I
mean there's protocols that you go
through and then same thing with your
flow it's but the less you spray the
better right you not only for your money
but for your plants yeah and you know I
think the controversial thing is that a
common sop is you spray this chemical
twice a week yeah you know that's the
that's like that that's to from from my
perspective from everything I've been
learning really what it is is you spray
when you see this particular insect
that's actually what it's supposed to be
supposed to be you have a monitor out
okay then you see a thrip and then how
manys per square does it trigger a
particular spray yeah and then that's
that's that's supposed to I mean in a
perfect world in a perfect world but I
think one of the problems with that is a
lot of people are lazy and they don't
have people going through the rooms
looking for problems yeah because if
you're very aware and it comes down to
awareness at a certain level it's like
how aware are you of exactly what's
going on in your room on a you know not
on a microscopic level but on a on a
pest level where you can identify I like
the word monitoring monitoring is super
important and and actually I I don't
want to forget to mention predatory
insects of course being a a great IPM uh
solution you know program part of a
program but that's another one where
people will just buy them those insects
out of the idea that they're going to
have mites or they're going to have
aphids you know there people are
actually releasing predatory insects
like as a PR pre uh preventative you
know measure and there's probably some
people in that industry that will
recommend that and that's you know you
know I don't want to start fights over
that or anything like that but I think
it's it's more ideal to know what you
have and when you have it and where you
have it and what insects to release cuz
again that's wasting money yeah and
resources and time you might not have
ever known that you actually had good
genetics and they were clean and your
you know your medium you know your
medium was clean like you're were saying
so on a 50 light room yeah how many
traps do you need how do you break it
down and and exactly where do you hang
so that's the thing is I actually think
of it as like plant plant count more so
plant numbers um and I you know if you
have planter beds it's a little
different than if you have pots you know
yeah um so with pots you know we're now
this may sound funny because I I'm now
selling siky traps so I'm be like put
one with every plant right sure more
mean but the you have plant tags so you
technically could put one with right you
can so I we now make um a a plant IDE we
call it a dual action plant label yeah
and that what that does is on one side
you can you write the name of the plant
or or or or or a date even yeah and then
you turn it to whatever your protocol is
for that and then the other side is
actually a transfer paper that you peel
and that will actually be your pest
monitor of the coolest things I've seen
this year yeah yeah for sure actually I
have one out I can show you yeah let's
go through some of your products yeah
these are this is the plant label this
is the newest thing um this is like pre
pre-released essentially I've been
showing just barely showing it around
yeah um so here's your standard thing
it's got to be a little thicker like a
like a because it's going to stick in
the medium right it's going to stick
right in the rock wall or whatever and
then you you write right on there this
is completely dry no glue and then you
have this nice transfer paper on here
and the transfer paper is what protects
the glue now you're going to think okay
this is going to be sticky it's going to
drip it's none of that happens um this
the like I said this company's Atlantic
past and glue company that that that's
really behind catchmaster and they've
been doing this since the 1950s and they
have like these viscosities down it's
non-toxic and um you can see it doesn't
leave any residue on the finger at all
yeah put it right on the skin doesn't
pull your hair yeah goad touch it yeah I
know people are scared sometimes but go
ahead oh that's cool that's amazing yeah
but this the right it's just the right
amount to catch flying insects and to
monitor for insects it's like that's
what you want a nice dry glue yeah um
and then you put these out um and this
is a very cost- effective way of doing
that um I actually see this as more of a
nursery application to be honest yeah um
personally I think 4-in pots uh clone
racks at the end of your clone tray
every clone tray um and the 4-inch pots
and then you move into like U you know a
bigger one which this is and this is
actually still considered small for a
sticky trap yeah but this is what I
would put so every box comes with 72
cards and it comes with stands yeah okay
and they're double-sided sticky the same
exact adhesive like they're really good
stuff and this one got the grid pattern
on there yeah so you can do your your
press monitoring totally like a
professional and then it comes with a
stand right here you just go right down
in the middle and you just put this
right in the medium okay and then they
also have the the twist ties of course
that's the what most people are used to
right you have the hole so you want to
hang one up there y so to answer your
question I would put you know one every
every planner every other the only
reason why I'm saying that is because I
have I have people that are doing that
yeah um I wouldn't I normally this is
probably the first time I ever actually
said it so boldly but I have people that
are doing it it's working you got Miami
mango yeah you had them on the podcast
he's a big user of catchmaster he a
great guy he puts uh he does double
double rock wall you know the tiered so
he's got one he's got a blue one and and
a yellow one and the blue blue one is
actually for monitoring for thrips U so
that's it's a nice little uh safety net
to have in there cool um and then of
course just hanging one every like maybe
500 square feet or something like that
above the canopy oh wow yeah for
monitoring yeah yeah that's that stuff
and then we have the roll you know I
don't want to make this too gimmicky
show all the products but no I mean
that's kind of what the show is for when
you got a good product I love sharing
products that are good on my show that's
really it's it's it becomes authentic
rather than like a s it's not a sales
pitch that's kind of how I like that's
how I got into you know going from
companies like Botanica and Ro obviously
very good companies vital Garden Supply
you know I do care about who I'm working
for and what I'm representing you know
just as well as I do those are those
were great products over the years and
the the AG roll is really cool this is
more of a greenhouse application yeah
and what you're looking at here if you
don't know already is this is 6 in by
328 ft of double-sided sticky nice
caution tape yeah it looks like it
pretty much is you put this one really
uh traditionally they they put it above
the canopy up above there are people who
are taking this cutting it in different
orientations um it's actually more cost
effective for some people to actually
take it and cut it it's obviously
Messier a little bit more labor
intensive to do that in my opinion but I
have seen it where people are actually
putting on as end caps in indoor grow
rooms and stuff like that oh wow I've
seen um I've even seen Alex experiment
with taking you know a 4 in or maybe 6
inch and then cutting it and then
sticking it on the rock wall you know so
he's do he's messing around with that
too getting some good results from it
nice um yeah but that's yeah that's an
AG roll so yeah um that's pretty much I
did bring some I brought one other thing
too that's way way outside of of the
what the industry is used to it's called
a vector flylight yeah and um yeah I'll
just I'll just pull that's the one I'm
excited the most about because this is
this is kind of a game changer and I
think it's going to be I mean this and I
think the plant labels are the biggest
game changer everyone's seen sticky
cards but um the plant label that's
sticky I think is super new yeah and
it'll be very useful and then this this
is actually something that comes from
the restaurant industry which we wanted
I wanted to talk to you about that too
because I know you're you're a
restaurant guy yeah this is made by
catcher catch masterer actually bought
the company Vector uh but they but
catcher as you know makes glue boards
yeah I'll show you how this see pull
this out so the first thought that
people have is this is a a fly zapper
like a bug zapper that would be cool but
see I know that is cool but here's the
thing it's not sanitary right bug
zappers are not sanitary you can't
monitor the insect um there's guts going
everywhere they actually implode oh yeah
bugs so this actually is a special UV
Phillips bulbs that attract flying
insects and it brings them to a glue
board here oh wow inside and this glue
board actually I caught some bugs uh
over down in La I brought this down with
me in La there's some knats on there
there but this is a Blackboard to hide
the insects so we do make white ones and
yellow ones you know and all that for
better for monitoring um but yeah that's
how that works it's pretty cool thanks
for bringing bugs in the facility I know
right no I know right no these are these
are these are stuck to the glue board so
yeah yeah no it's all good that's a good
point those one snuck by
me yeah um Homeland where's Homeland
Security right oh yeah that I think the
other thing to to to mention because I
get this a lot is um well Kitt you put
it in the grow room like that's not it's
that's not its application you want to
put it outside The Grow rooms everyone's
got the hallways leading to The Grow
rooms you got the entrance the exits you
want to have them all all there another
thing too is people put them up too high
yeah you actually want to have them
about my height which is about 4
feet and so and you put them up there um
and uh and you want to have uh near you
know near uh garbage areas too things
like that right um and that's just going
to be a really great addition to an IPM
protocol and and this if you have
garbages you should probably have lids
on your garbage in your grow I think
that's one of the most important things
that I see people doing it all the time
see there you go that's another one they
miss it that's another one um I mean
that should be added to IPM protocol is
making sure the trash is covered yeah
absolutely yeah we don't even allow
fruit no fruit in the facility nothing
hey that's good yeah you let me in
though yeah you're the
exception I'm just kidding okay dude so
I wanted to tell everyone about this
little collaboration that we're doing
you brought this special gift for me and
these are pretty awesome why don't you
tell everybody
about the collaboration yeah so these
are so prep packs y um so what they are
is they're chillums they're American
Glass by high quality chillums and they
come with these corks basically right um
the idea is that you they're they're
always they're always branded you know
they're essentially like um you want to
put your product in there so you could
showcase your product so if you're for
example like you're prom if you're
selling genetics right and you got six
different genetics this is a good this
would be a good example right here yeah
um you could actually have a label on
each one that would have the genetic and
then within it would either be the seeds
or or even better maybe have the flow so
that way they could be like hey if I buy
this guy's seeds or buy this guy's
clones this is the flower that's going
to be in there right I think that's a
really clever way of marketing uh your
brand randomly though but randomly
though yeah so I had these made they
actually fit perfectly in the Box yeah
they do yeah so so yeah these These are
the seed boxes that we have and normally
you get a glass vial and this is some
synchronicity right here dude some
serious synchronicity these are boxes he
already had bade and then I separately
so in the live chat we are going to be
giving away some of these for trivia
questions yeah uh yeah really cool dude
dude so I think Jos just showed up we
should have Josh come on camera and talk
a little bit with us yeah that'd be
awesome for sure I know he's actually
got some bud for me too he's got some
blue dream that he grew up
boys how you guys doing what's up dude
good to see you so everybody that
doesn't know this is uh Josh Silverback
Freeman yeah we go back 20 years more
than 20 years actually he's the sour guy
the man the myth one of my best friends
a long time good guy so yeah he he
actually is the real silver back now he
did not have he had he had full dread
when I when we were friends when we
first met but there was some silver in
there for sure it slowly turned all
silver it was more like a uh it look
like a dead squirrel on the back of my
neck but yeah so welcome to the show man
we've been talking about getting you on
here for quite a while long time yeah
nice to be here yeah and thanks for uh
introducing me to Alex this has been a
good show so far you guys having a good
time absolutely it's been great yeah we
were talking about Grilla and Botanicare
old school stuff yeah yeah good stuff
Royal gold Gold Kings mix
all Royal gold man yeah you a lot of
that
yeah yeah Kings mix that's the one
though that good I used a lot of Kings
mix in my life yeah man truck loads age
old that's another semi semi truck yeah
so we started this new thing and I want
to play a game with you guys and we're
gonna go around and we're gonna name
strains oh fun right okay and so it's
not a long game but it's a fun game and
it always brings out the best in
everybody because you guys are old
school so you guys remember some stuff
so I'm going to start out with the aota
oh [ __ ] all the above oh yeah well I
know the cats have read that yeah yeah
you do they're Farm cats they're from
the Tennessee farm but they're actually
been in were in Sona County when that
work was being done yeah but they've
been in Humble for like I don't know two
decades plus maybe three yeah now yeah
they went to college up there so three
decades so sour diesel yeah man Sour
Diesel let's let's talk about Sour
Diesel s you guys know each other from
sour diesel yeah I I met Alex before uh
this but some of the very best herb that
I've ever sour I've ever seen besides
the stuff I growing and Joe's growing
has been from Alex yeah I appreciate
that that means a lot come from really
good yeah y you know there's like with
sour I feel like there's like different
levels of Growers like you got you know
a guy that can pull it off and make it
look pretty good then there's some guy
that gets up like maybe eight out of 10
runs perfect but then there's that
perfect one and you're like oh H dude
this is just a different sour yeah and
he brought that and I actually I think
the key to that was actually I grew it
in six different climate six different
like situations and dialed like figured
out what was best that's really I had I
had I had the advantage oh yeah you had
the multiple sites I had multiple
multiple operations spread all over and
so I was able to actually dial it in you
know and like literally different things
like light movers to like I mean
everything you can imagine I did rock
wall to Cocoa to what was the best for
me my uh my best actually was uh Dutch
pots actually I did I personally I did I
did really good with so just so you guys
we've talked about Dutch pots on the
show but for those of you guys that
don't know Dutch spot the Dutch pots
were uh Square pots with a hole in the
back and they were imported they were $5
a piece and the only place you could buy
them that I know of in California was
the garden spout oh yeah yeah gab Gabby
man we all know we all know Gabby we
used to there to pick those up you get
100 of them it was expensive back in the
day you crazy what did you guys like
about that I've never used one for me
for me it was a frequent watering I was
frequent watering and and I think I
think the other part of that was being
able to correct problems like quickly
was that through a hydro or it was
actually it's actually more popular now
to be in smaller po these were pretty
small medium m mine was smaller mine I
was doing like two gallon that little
two gallon they had a few different
sizes yeah I filled with and then hydron
the hydron in there what were you
putting in there um I was actually I was
running B I was running no no they're um
little clay po Pebbles okay now those
were good for a while then they got kind
of messed up for a minute they're salty
and also one of the big problems is they
started getting smaller and they started
started and they started slipping
through the elbow and clogging and yeah
so that that and you couldn't get that
consistency anymore you know so I I
ended up switching switching off of that
after a while but yeah and also I ended
up switching off a sour too off what did
you switch to um what did I go from sour
to to um played around with you know
cookies and OG um and actually I was
able to fall back on Blackberry Kush a
little bit yeah you know because it has
it has its fandom you know it had its
fandom at that time so do you remember
the Hassan oh I
don't I'm trying to remember tell me
tell me more about that one tell us
about it well you know it is Lamb's
bread oh I was going to say lamb bre
remember the cat when you were saying do
the name game I was going to say lre but
let's be specifically clear here there
was some cats in Sona County that came
from out of town we'll say I'm not going
to name them out right but they were
tired of the Hassan name and their
buyers were they changed the H the Lambs
bread and I
caught I caught him red-handed cuz I
asked them how long are you flowering
your Lambs bread for and they said 52
days I said that's the Hassan I saw the
photo of it right and I knew that that
was a Hassan on Instagram and I was like
Yo dude that's not it man that's not the
lamb spread okay so I got another one
yeah pink cream Jasmine
soda yeah how about that so we go way
back so we can talk about these old
school genetics it's great because I
haven't thought about that so that was
the shortest flowering outdoor plant
that I ever G it was the one that never
had problem with [ __ ] caterpillars
and not never had a problem with those
tomato horn worms and it yields it just
doesn't get you that high my would never
yielded that much it didn't get that
high but man it finished early and The
Taste was amazing I would get 3x3 bushes
to be over a pound outside you know and
and that was nice cuz that money like
you're saying would be there early you
know and you'd have that set up for the
trimmers coming in for the all year
totally you know what was the lineage on
that one Dina I don't know I've looked
at the Jason King book and he has
something in there that talks about it I
can't remember but that came from the
same cat I got that East Coast sour from
he brought me both those at different
times there was some pink other pink
strains I remember I just I I don't
remember that full name like pink
Cadillac or something there's a pink
Cadillac too yeah pink panties was
that was that should have been called
black pants it was throwing pink it was
throwing pink hairs right that was the
the motivation for naming them pink was
that um I think the pink just depending
on the one because like the Wildberry
used to throw you know a 78 sour you pop
those you'd find a whole bunch of those
that would have pink pink pistols
raspberry cheesecake cush also known as
the raspberry cush that's the pink the
pink ones too that was a really popular
heavy yielder especially up in southern
Oregon that got really big up there so
yeah so Josh is one of my Inspirations
for breeding like I wouldn't be here
doing what I do without people like Josh
that's cool yeah Josh Josh came through
for me too like my book both of you guys
have been there for me more times than
not like both of you cats I I've let you
both know how you saved my ass a million
times and and you're both here in the
same room at the same time it's pretty
[ __ ] cool actually and we don't know
each other is crazy yeah we have some we
have some mut contact we have so many
Mutual contacts you were at dinner a
couple weeks ago and I know pretty much
everybody at the dinner party that you
at yeah that was that was a big one we
had like 20 people at that like a fun
dinner yeah yeah that's one for the
history books thanks for the invite yeah
I just I invited people that were going
to be in
La yeah that's wasn't even in La you w
in La that's no but you know Josh He
contributed the book he grows piff and
he grows Cuban black like I'd never seen
before those were great those were good
good personal man that's that I like
smoke smoking those on the side yeah
Sour's good your sour back in the day
was insane speaking of which yep uh bres
and I have been talking we're g to see
if we can't get that original diesel out
here yeah um do you want to roll up a
[ __ ] some blue
dream I got this blue dream here yeah
yeah we can we can do that no one's
really seen it for a minute yeah it's
actually and uh you know here it is if
it comes out bad I would really it's all
organic oh it's BL Dre look at the
colors look at the colors stra blue
dream it has that it has that beautiful
color has toac yeah that really light
that that orange color hair yep for sure
and the bright green this is this is
great man [ __ ] it's and the power went
out for four days yeah so let's talk
about that on the show I thought be a
great conversation I would love to it
really ties in with Alex actually and
you I had called everybody I knew to get
a thousand bucks because I was at Lowe's
and they were down to four generators
yeah when sebasol went out of power for
four days yeah let's just start there
and like on day two I was I started
really worry you know this happens in
the winter sure and I was like okay day
two was an issue I'm gonna definitely
need a generator so I called a couple
friends no one had anything to borrow
you didn't have an extra one to borrow
everybody was out of power up here
everybody in California especially
Sebastapol um so then I ended up calling
Alex and I said hey man I need help and
he's like okay and and within an hour
and a half I'm signing the release for
the generator and walking out wow I was
saved because like we hit 89% in that
room humidity yeah yeah and uh you know
I'd already had some a loss with mold
because um I didn't have any Deus in
there on this run well and blue dream
grows big fat monster
buds those colas I mean my outdoor I
remember one time I had the most
beautiful Cola and I was like looking at
it and I kind of Twisted it a little bit
and it split in half completely rotted
in the middle I mean the bud had to be
like that big yeah and that's what
happens sometimes you get a little bit
of moisture in there it turns into
petritis it's all bad it's done yeah no
that's the worst when you put all that
effort in you see the most beautiful bud
and you don't know it's there until you
just touch it and it does that like you
said folds over or you're looking for a
caterpillar and then you go in and all
of a sudden it falls apart you're like
now my eye that was the beginning years
of vtis but now my eye I can see it from
so far away you're walking in there's
that one leaf on the bud that's like
crinkled and you're like oh an off color
and you're like oh my God you can see it
from 10 feet away totally and then
you're like oh the whole room is now you
can't sleep you know yeah so that was
going on I would go in there like for
three nights cutting out about a quarter
ounce to half an ounce of of uh mold and
then the power went out and so I called
Alex and then he said I got you I'm I'm
I'm up in the mountains like I moved out
sonomi County I didn't tell you that but
I've been living out east of Sacramento
towards Taho oh nice up there so I'm
he's calling me and it's late and but I
but the thing is he's got he's got the
the product you know like I've actually
been saying for like at least couple
years now I wanted some good dream and I
I didn't have the dream I haven't grown
it you know since last time I grew it
was up above Corbell in gville up in the
hills up there and it was the only one
that didn't get eaten up by this that
the new mites that were around at the
time oh yeah when that when that was
going on the ogs were obliterated right
by the mites I don't was that the first
round when russet mes came it was no one
knew what it was everyone thought it was
systemic disease right you know they
thought it was a deficiency or disease
whatever it was exactly that that was
the last time I grew Blue Dream actually
and actually once you learn how to treat
russed M it's not a big deal not a big
deal anymore but I called my mom cuz
she's in town still because we used to
live out here and she's she's still out
here with her with her husband yeah and
uh I just told her was up and and then I
cashed her out for it and then now I now
I own you know one of you know one of
them so nice yeah yeah yeah so we traded
a pound of blue for generator totally
legit no I was stoked I'm like I already
have one taken care of it's handled and
it was like week seven oh yeah that's
the coffee out I was at week seven so
the nugs were thick right yeah and the
power goes out for four days I'd already
been cutting out the mold and then you
came through with that it saved that
thing I still hit three pounds of light
because this
is this is the work to do it this is the
working man's weed boys right it's
anybody can grow it it's grows itself
you just feed it a little bit extra I
notice this having right cut too though
I used more than anything oh yeah this
is a good C that's the other thing too
cuz like yeah sorry yeah you're going to
be I think you're going to have these
pre-rolled right I used to have a saying
yeah you could [ __ ] in the reservoir and
you'd still get 2.2 pounds of
light dream with Dre you absolutely
could it was it's the it's the one thing
that like like it's really easy to grow
it's the most vigorous plant the
structure is great it it makes you feel
good every time you grow it you feel
good about it it's fun you were saying
that when you walk into the room it it
makes you feel good about being there it
does you feel like you know what you're
doing it does man it's not always like
that with stuff there's finicky genetics
that they don't come out right every
time you do they don't they're not a 10
out of 10 every time where I feel like
blue dream is fairly easy to knock it
out of the park it's pretty easy man I
needed one like that so I was happy
actually you link me with the guy who
gave me the Clones right yeah so shout
out to Nick you know um he came through
with the most Stellar Cuts I've gotten
in a long time and I told him you know
normally I won't tell a guy because I
don't want him to inflate the price he's
got he's got this this is a limited
Source you know this guy I said hey bro
these are some of the best I've seen in
a long time I mean the stems I'm not
exaggerating are as thick as pencils
every time yeah on his cuts and uh so
that round turned out really good I used
the micro life I use biologic and um and
and just killed it it's so simple you
know like the grow I mean it's almost
identical to the grow and actually the
the last time I got you Cuts was um I
got you the Sher Banger I think yeah and
Sher good one his sh Banger bro sh
Banger before a lot of people got theb
that's right yeah and and the thing was
is his the way that that indoor sh
Banger came out yeah I like I prized
that that I mean that weed so far I mean
I travel all the United States you know
what I mean and I know I know you travel
too and stuff it's like blue dream for
example I go around look it's not blue
dream okay like if you say they together
Blue Dream It's not blue dream no you
know but there's a lot of s1's out there
that's what happens is people get a bag
seed and they're this round one like
there's this one that's going around
that's like round it's like rounded is I
mean this is the shape you want to see
you know you want it to knuckle out like
that yeah it's all still it knuckled out
extra because of the humidity spikes
that I was it looks like it's never
going to finish too totally look like it
could just go on and on it does it keep
popping white hairs a pistol like it
just just it kept on I put it on the
scale I'm like this thing keeps clocking
in I'm like this is a heavy hitter it's
a heavy hitter and you can just push you
smoking speaking of yeah it will smoke
yeah I mean it basically it it'll it'll
eat it'll drink it's it's super it's a
happy
plant and yeah needs extra water
compared to the rest of the genetics I
was running yeah and a lot more food
this one feeds so I think sativas are
making a comeback yeah I agree and I'm
happy finally people are starting to
figure that out some guys will say that
no but I would say that sativas
are
think the older you get the stronger the
weed
got yeah I want that leathery sativa
yeah yeah I'm on the Quest for more
hazes I got a friend uh shout out to
Funky specimen out east he's going to
get me the redline Haze he says that's
his favorite ni not a lot of people even
heard of it so I'm pretty stoked on it
here I do have to give some respect to
uh like I got some um white truffle
crossed with uh killer banana what do
you think of white truffle by itself I'm
not a huge fan no I'm not but with the
with the killer banana it actually came
get it grew like um actually grew a lot
like uh AFU nice oh that's cool I grew
it outside and it had a lot it had a lot
of AFU qualities yeah that's cool yeah
so yeah AFU is another great one that
was super silver super silver goo love
that super that was good yeah the Ripple
Plum the Ripple Plum that was one of
Josh's Creations we're going to have a
whole another podcast that had the super
silver in it yeah that was super fire
that was really cool the Ripple Plum
that was the sour I thought that was the
sour times no the Ripple Plum was the
Durban to the super silver goo oh the
Durban to the super silver goo yeah that
was heat yeah yeah yeah I actually did a
I did a cross that went around a little
bit for a minute it was um I did OG and
jagu and called it jger nice I've seen
that around I got I think I even grew
that actually that was you yeah cool
yeah I crossed that and then cloned it
and got it around for a little while and
yeah I'm I'm sure there's other
iterations of that that's crazy that
right yeah I either I can't remember if
we grew that J Joe and I are a homie
might grabb it from you might have
grabbed it from my house yeah maybe I I
don't I know I've seen it around lry
Bubba like I said I'm I don't I didn't
want to come on here and say I'm like
you know I'm a breeder or genetics guy
but like I I played around enough to
where I did one full year of J seeds
yeah you know and I was I I shockingly
for some reason it I had the intuition
to like do a bunch of early like low low
rider crosses before it was popular
totally like way before all of a sudden
it became like that was realing the
value in having something that for me
because I was going up on the hills and
we were trying to get those extra runs
out and not have to pull tarps and do
that's crazy you knew that because I was
reading that stuff in the 90s going I
would never buy that yeah that was the
thing was that was the thing is you
could get them like right you could
order Amsterdam they had all the the low
rider crosses that's why I call them low
riders cuz that's an Amsterdam that's
what they were call yeah blue Low Rider
red low rider it was Canadian term right
cuz it was a
BCC did that yeah it was the BC dep that
were running them because the BC guys I
mean
the were doing the a first can't
remember the breeder up there but he was
popular and he that was what he
specialized on I was like I would never
[ __ ] with that but now look at I think
it was Atomic something huh right do you
remember that uh Atomic anyways that was
some of the first Auto flowers um I was
I was messing with the the Mexican rudal
stuff like I was CU a lot of those Ludy
that's where you could get the cheap
like bulk you all that and so I but I
kind of got real friendly with them and
I was kind of kind of bringing in some
crosses of that stuff it was never good
though I always SM like hey no but there
was some good ones there was some orange
ones I never saw the really good ones I
only saw the coming down cuz well from
California we were getting them from the
guys in the valley or I will say it too
though a lot of it was brick that was
reconstituted from from and called they
called that Arizona weed that's
hilarious and they would just
reconstitute it and then call it early
girl right do you guys remember
the we were talking about blueberry cush
being called Blackberry cush yeah yeah
Blackberry cry cush but back in the day
like you get weed from Mexico and if it
was green it was the prend or the Mexi
the Mexican indicas yeah yeah well
that's where the whole there was
probably it was probably there was some
press green stuff that was okay it would
get you high and it didn't give you as
much of a headache yeah totally and you
were stoked when that came through at
least I was break it up and you put it
in the room with the shower on and get
that [ __ ] to poof up that's not how we
we just smoked it on a can you see I'm a
little your parents trained you up yeah
cuz my dad was my dad had that stuff
they had the dry version
yeah yeah you knew me what to do if you
haven't had a seed pop off a can you
don't know what going smoke it
is right popcorn popcorn yeah oh yeah
that's that's old
school I love it awesome good stuff yeah
man what other old strains dude there's
so many there's so many let's say uh so
you stole both of mine I wanted to say
Hanan and uh and I wanted to say pink
cream well we talked about the kushage
so tell us about the cush because you
used to crush the cush um that's Adam
done OG times the sage to to the sage
and interesting enough that thing really
was uh PM resistant it was leafy yeah no
mine the one I have had a great K Leaf
ratio in my opinion was not good hash
maker probably but incredible producer
one of the heaviest yielder strains I've
ever grown was that kushage and it threw
off a tart note and a creamy note and
then I put it to the Durban and that's
where we got the raspberry cheesecake
cush cuz it had where Rasberry chees and
and flavor come through it got shortened
down to just the raspberry cush later
and a lot of people mistake the
Blackberry and raspberry they look
totally different but um that kushage
and then I've grown his Sage
which is phenomenal if you get a good
how many weeks how many weeks did that
shout out to Adam and Mojave yeah big up
boys for sure that's the the real strong
[ __ ] the real strong yeah how many weeks
would that run the the the raspberry uh
it was like 62 63 days yeah was nine
weeks yeah and then but the sage is uh I
have access to some seeds that are from
Adam's creation of the sage a a mutual
friend of ours um Spiker he's uh one of
the owners of Dutch lighting Innovations
he's giving me those genetics that Adam
gave back to him long story and I'll let
him tell you the story sometime you
should definitely have them up here but
uh the seeds that were used to make that
they lost the genetics and so Bo still
had them and Adam reached out to Bo and
Bo gave him and so Adam gave him the
seeds that created the sage yeah and B's
going to give I remember picking up some
packs of that Sage actually with some uh
God's breath I think it was oh really
was that God's breath was good or God's
Gift God's Gift someone made God's
breath though I remember seeing packs of
God's that's why it came to mind but I
think it was God's at that time it was
God's gift but I think it wasn't to the
Lamb's bre I breath I think it was to
like a shark's Breath Right that one the
God you had shark's breath yeah God's
shark breath was it shark's tooth no
there wasar breath shark's breath they
had that so I feel like I feel like when
I was picking up th all those packs kind
of came together almost yeah the sage I
saw the sage what was that guy um that
was just crossing everything in am Dam
not um not Mr Nice all of those guys
were just crossing and then they were
making seeds of stuff that didn't taste
like as Americans we were like wait a
second that OG Kush Is Not OG Kush oh I
got I got one Strawberry Cough
Strawberry Cough good one yeah I like
strawberry cough that was that was
Banner Bruce Banner from the strawberry
cough but yeah the Strawberry Cough is
fire yeah you know the I didn't like
growing the cough because the you have
to thin and release that one so crazy it
branches out so much I like the fort
cough better than the Strawberry Cough
that for cough is good it's super
special I think I got some seeds of that
I made some banana banana Skittles yeah
the banana the banana cough is fire ban
cough I think I got that there should be
some really good got of those in there
that was made in my backyard so yeah
that's train hand water that's going to
be and it's going to be grown in my back
King mix age old hand water still hand
water so even at scale I enjoy I don't
know I I yeah 80 plants in my backyard
yeah and I woke up every morning I
watered them I Joe helped me water
sometimes when I was gone or whatever
out of town but yeah like I mean we hand
water I I still enjoy I won't do it
indoors I don't think it's practical I
think handw watering is you know for me
I'm not a huge handw watering fan indoor
but waking up in the morning where
you're tending to plants in your
backyard that's fun yeah it is I still I
still do it that's that's a thing now
I'm on the road all the time I you like
I said I used to grow a lot yeah I had
to like you know I gave that a lot of
that up to you know for the ancillary
Market you know hitting hitting the
United States and traveling and all that
but I still make sure I always I always
got my plants I do full season right now
I was doing you know I tapered tapered
from doing indoor to doing Deb and then
yeah back to full grown and started in
full grown you know full sun right but I
love it man and I love I love just
having like all different strains and
stuff dude I still hand water even two
acres I'll hand I won't do it by myself
but me and my guys will hand water two
acres indoor outdoor not at all and I've
got over 30 years doing it but the
reason why I do it is cuz I know it so
well you do it I understand it and it
understands me for me to try and learn a
different curve right now just there's
not enough incentive in it I actually
enjoy it it's you teach the system to to
water like you that's the thing you have
to teach it yeah of course but I really
enjoy it's kind of like my time like my
drive out to the farm and my space away
I don't have cell reception it's so
funny because you lived in the same
county but it was like such a long drive
to get up to
C yeah used to Caz was a little bit of a
tri in 20 minutes more 20 minutes that's
two joints
country windy roads C joint yeah exactly
some of our best times going up there
too hang out you know it's not like
driving up the 101 for an hour and a
half where you got CHP up your ass you
know like I'd see a sheriff a few times
a year driving out to cow that was it
yeah so smoking splits was great premium
weather too up there like you know had
some really good outdoor there you did
yeah your your depths were incredible
the [ __ ] elevation and
banana belt that cazadero has you know
that special climate it's really nice
really good for growing yeah you grew
some good flare out of there for sure
yeah and you know who was there before
me uh Mel Frank for years oh wow looking
his books and you'll see uh it was on
the same property no no no the same uh
Ranch same Ranch so the same Hill so
he's like um you know it will say
cazadero underneath some of his photos
in his books oh ni yeah I'm like that's
[ __ ] awesome yeah that's the spot
where you can see it 30 minutes away you
can see it on the hill and then you
drive up to it pretty cool yeah so
basetball kind of ended up being like a
little like broker Mecca you know for a
minute that's right Seb toown it was
like it was like because you had humble
folks you had La folks I'm talking
before that was right before we were all
sending it out you know or people were
sending it out to New York and all that
but it's like but La was actually coming
up M bringing it down to La that one cat
bought rented a house in town and just
have all the grows just drop off and all
the buyers come it went off in it was
going on for years right downtown I was
like this is nuts yeah yeah yeah yeah
yeah had the hardcore Coffee Spot oh
yeah there was some hardcore coffee I've
been there a few times this guy the
meeting spot you know you
got there's the Hot Monk Hot Monk
actually I I grew up in spas on IES Park
there's also I park right there but that
was like the that was that was that was
young that clol
yeah yeah I worked at Powerhouse Brewing
Company when I was he lives in oal yeah
on Harrison grade
up I would serve him at Powerhouse
Brewing Company they made you remember
that spot oh yeah well that's I used to
work for Lanes oh you did it's a small
world everybody's so interconnected yeah
those dudes contributed to my book too
yeah or not yeah Tony and uh well
because they got into all the um yeah
with the yeah they know good herb those
CBD drinks and all that too yeah yeah
you know it's actually funny too the
thing about hops too that I find a lot
of people just learning this for the
first time like they think of alcohol
right drinks yeah as just alcohol what's
the content like you know but you got to
remember these are you know what's why
they call them Spirits these are Elixir
you know and and they're all different
things and one of the best examples and
proof of that is a hoppy beer hops is
hops the hyoids is actually a uh a
nervous system sedative oh wow on its
own for so like forget the liquor and
the alcohol part a total the alcohol
form so then you start about that when
you think that like tequila vodka um rum
all these different things people go I
can't drink rum but I can drink tequila
yeah well why is that that's because
it's something to do with like the
alkaloids or the extracts that they have
from that plant yeah you know what I
mean and so I think that's kind of cool
like the Hops and hops actually uh you
know grafts to cannabis you know I know
they I've done it I really I know they
gra that's one of the coolest things
ever you got to send us pictures for
yeah so I so I had humb Hops and when I
my house in Windsor I had humble hops I
got it from Humble Hydroponics there
they had it under uh in their little
tents you know they're growing hops in
there and I got I took a cutting yeah
from that I brought it down and I
[ __ ] uh I I uh grafted it to chem dog
91 that's awesome wild they're R right
so they grow and they they go dormant
and then they pop up and grow like
wildfire they're they're really awesome
they're really awesome yeah you can
actually um yeah they're well Vine they
grow very different than cannabis
different but they they're genetically
similar enough to graph to each well
they're from the same family for those
who don't know but yeah for sure yeah
you can grow one on the
other you can grow a cannabis you can
grow cannabis on on a hop and you can
grow h on a Canabis I didn't know they
I've done it no I've only done it one
way I've only done hops on
cannabis yeah let's do it let's let's
let's spark it up again and do it you
know I'm all about R&amp;D so that is a
great R&amp;D thing yeah that's right fun
that could lead to a lot the whole
grafting thing is always interested me
mik and I back in the day we almost did
a nursery project where we got OG Kush
and we were going to graft it for you
know the outdoor season sell graphs of
Blue Dream o cool Bush yeah because OG
Kush has like a small root Zone it
struggles a little bit but what happens
when you put it on a blue dream you know
like put on a blue dream and I actually
think that root that's that's that's an
that's a an R&amp;D valid thing to do is to
see what kind of effect I probably the
best root talk to put anything on would
be a blue dream yeah yeah OG on a blue
dream gra root stock right there yeah
hey that's maybe that's the next stage
because you know it's there are some
crazy ass fruit trees out there of
course it's much easier for an an
something that grows year after year
after year the same root stock right to
when you graft to something like that
that's you know you're you're
encouraging that more and more multiple
strains so you just have multiple
flavors yeah well in the egg World
they've had to do that with fruits with
fruits with walnuts avocados y yeah
walnuts yeah yeah it's for so they would
self-pollinate and all that that's
another reason it's male and female they
do male and female like Walnut The Roots
the black walnut I think it was the
American Walnut the root stock was much
stronger than the European Walnut Y and
so everything was dying from Europe so
they figured out how to graft it onto
theer yeah so all of them that's
actually that's that's actually a great
segue for wanting to invite both you
guys to Kendall Jackson wiy I want to do
a lunch out
there my brother's a chef out over there
incredible chef of the best in the world
and the reason why I mentioned that is
because that's an old an old Walnut Farm
It's actually an old old Walnut Grove Y
and they you don't know this actually
sorry to interrupting but James is a
incredible Chef incred yeah he know talk
a little
bit I just got it well we actually
mostly talked about it in person I think
or private about you being in the food
World a whole different level like your
brother yeah yeah yeah well that's
actually what really inspired me to like
to invite you guys out to there like
there's two reasons is like there's the
food aspect but it's also like a farm to
table environment and stuff and I look I
don't work for Kendall Jackson but but
but but my brother does and it's and
it's it's an awesome environment out
there like their Master Gardener out
there um I'll have to get you the name
later what his name is but ni um it's
just the most Immaculate thing they also
do like a thing where they do a uh where
you smell different foliages like they
grow different plants that you smell
while you drink wine really I think
that's really cool so instead of being a
pairing because they do food pairing and
all that which you expect but they also
do where they grow plants just for their
smell nice you know for their you know
and you you break them and you take a
sip of the wine and part of that
experience yeah it's pretty cool yeah
yeah we'll have to do that maybe maybe
bring the show down all right Stoners
let's reel it in here what other
strains so cat
piss that's like a hot topic on my show
that hot topic for debate is cat it's a
real catpiss back in the day was so good
so there's people saying it came out of
San Diego there's people saying it came
out of everywhere anything that somebody
that had amonia smelled like cat piss
they called it cat so it's not like blue
dream or it's a specific name that's my
opinion we're doing a do people get to
watch the documentary but dude like the
photos that you did in the book not to
say change subjects but the photos that
you did you Ben actually did the photos
you grew the flower there's the chem 91
that was grown by Josh there was the
piff I love that there was the uh I
believe the stardog is in there oh nice
oh yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah we got
that we got the piff we got all those so
yeah it's great did you guys ever did
you guys ever come across the Starfire I
haven't not Starfire OG I remember the
star starf fighter star fighter sorry I
said fire I said fire you did say star
was Fire OG yeah there was Fire OG I'm
sure if you cross those together you
getar yeah it exists I swear I've heard
of it but I have not no no that one's
real like a real bright kind of um real
bright OG actually I mean still nothing
to this day like I was saying this
earlier it beats K 91 for me I I I think
that one goes down in the Guinness book
for me as like just all around High the
turps I know it's not the best
commercially to grow you know yeah it's
not as tight of a structure yeah it
doesn't yield it can have a really good
structure it just you indoor it was
really good the structure was really
good I wouldn't say it has the best
structure it's so subjective
right it might not fit the purple candy
gas model but it fits the model that I
like and that you like model yeah that
tur model for me is right there the Kim
91 but I were out I like the smell of
burnt tires there's something that just
brings me back I would actually use the
word when I was like when I was like
checking pounds out cuz you know you got
to you got to when you're brokering you
got to look at pounds and check them out
yeah that's that was I use burnt burnt
rubber is what I use burnt rubber but I
was always looking for I was like but
before
anybody well we're talking before
Instagram Instagram he was saying that
[ __ ] I was saying it before but I want
to say like Kim 91's great for sure and
big up Kim dog and the whole though it's
a high two but that's Sour Diesel is my
favorite smoke all around cuz the flavor
of that is just what I prefer and side
by side I I'd rather smoke that I think
it burns better in a joint and it was
named sour because it soured
relationships but it did the opposite
for us cuz I mean we're here today
because of sour there's a lot of great
stories we have that are positive about
Sour Diesel yes oh I've raised three
daughters yeah yeah more positive than
negative especially friendship wise like
it brought us together Sour Diesel was
the one that brought us together not
that Kim dog didn't Kim dog to you the
sour I had you gave me the Kim you had
and I think I gave you my silver back
gorilla at that time too you did and uh
but I'd been looking for that we'll talk
about the whole story later but the uh
the Kim dog I got from you was really
good the 91 I got from sent out from
Boston and it was good from
Massachusetts from the cape actually
yeah um and but side by side for me
personally I just like the smoke the way
it smokes in a joint is the sour you
know and the flavor you know for oh I
got I got I got one thing that we got to
talk about before you guys go what is it
the HK oh yeah the Henry Kissinger let's
talk about it man you might not know
about it because you're a little younger
no I was like was it Hindu Kush yeah
good yeah so you know about it Kissinger
the Kissinger yeah the Kissinger was
yeah that was the one that was
the amazing TPS it was before OG cush
and before all this at least my
experience like that was the original
Master Kush too bub it was very
different than OG kush yeah there was
Master cush and Bubba Kush with that too
master cush and Bubba was like yeah that
was like late 90s there was the master
and the Bubba and I loved both of those
they were both top shelf those were the
Exotics those some of my first I think
my first Exotics structure on the master
sucked it grew like the it would
basically grow sideways the buds would
have like side branches it was side
branching on actual I'm a little younger
than you guys just a little bit just
enough to wear like those were my first
Exotics for wasn't it a lower yielder
too I think so it was G and it was
really
like always got petritis you SM It Bubba
was fire though soapy that that's a
soapy too soapy for me and the btis so I
I I peeled
off with it because I was like that's a
potential the yield was a nice and the
look had did you make the Larry Bubba
who made the Larry Bubba that was you I
got it from Joe I think actually that
was a good one oh I didn't make that but
uh what were we talking about Hindu Kush
uh Hindu Kush yeah oh yeah we were
getting 6,400 a pound for that in the
early '90s
yeah was buy 1 o or you could buy like
how yeah how old I was like nine or 10
years old and like 92 91 so that was 98
is where kind of where I got in like 90
97 98 just but I was young then too like
91 was the first year I started SP yeah
and that's I'm I'm over here saying Kim
91 is my favorite album I had 91 was a
great year we had the we had the seeds
we were running We Grew From seed only
and was from the Cincy seed stock and I
think that was their
nl2 right do you remember James back
then I don't remember because I was just
I got jumped into this group uh as a new
grower and they were already established
like older guys and I was the new kid
you know and so but later on I've tried
to figure out what was that Hindu Kush
that we had um from Neville because yeah
uh and what I've deduced it down to and
don't quote me on it but I think it's
there nl2
is where the Hindu Kush came from
interesting and they changed it later
years to Hindu Kush it's own it's the
Hindu Kush is like a the mountain range
in the it's a region yeah reg so there's
obviously a story behind it for Kush
Valley the Hindu Kush yeah yeah but it I
think the Hindu Kush yeah I think it
also means something like Warrior or
Destroyer like a hind the Hindu word
Kush I think that has to do with oh
there's more meaning behind it yeah a
lot of violence and destruction yeah
well well we've got to wrap the show up
today we're so glad to have you guys on
but if somebody's looking to find out
more about you where can they get a hold
of you you know you can get on my
Instagram Silverback growa g r o w i l l
a and then I'm you know that's probably
the best way to do it y or through you
you know I'm going to be offering some
of this blue dream with your pre-rolls
and we've got all these seeds combos
we've done so that's happening you know
I just hit up your website yeah yeah
yeah seed com and then catchmaster Alex
yeah yeah I mean that's pretty much what
it is it's catchmaster uncore Alex yeah
catchmaster uncore Alex yeah yeah but
you can find it if you type it in
because there's I don't think there's
another catch Master Alex at the moment
you're not Shadow banned yet so you can
you can actually type in part of it I do
get my some post banned but yeah so far
so good but yeah man thank you guys so
much for coming on the show fun James
thank you well we'll do it again soon we
got to get our friend Joe on here and
then uh really talk about how the Durban
Poison came to the Bay as far as the
Urban Poison that I know came to the
came back to the Bay came back to the
bay through this guy right here so good
stuff all right thank you guys for
coming on yeah thank
[Music]
you