foreign
[Music]
[Applause]
welcome to the next episode of the
podcast a cannabis podcast for budding
enthusiasts
[Music]
you're joined as always by your boy
heavy days here from the upside down
library and as always this episode could
not happen without the amazing support
of our sponsors speed here now number
one seed bank in the game guarantee on
satisfaction not just germination why
grow anything else you might be unhappy
at the end go to seeds here now they
promise you'll be stoked at the end they
only stock quality breeders and if
you're not hit them up they'll sort you
out with some new seeds what more could
you ask for well you've got to make sure
you get the crop right first and to do
that you should go check out coppet
biological systems be sure to check out
their ultimate a predator might
breathing sachet for all your thrip
spider mite and russet my issues all
while specifically formulated the
maximum release rates in a cannabis
production climate
likewise make sure to go check out our
new spawn sucks Pro mix they've got a
fantastic new product called Pro mix
connect which is a mycorrhizal inoculant
that'll help ensure you have a robust
Harvest and you have to increase yield
increase resin density and all the
things that make your crop stand out
from the rest make sure to check out Pro
mix mycorrhizae via make sure to check
out pro-mix connects your number one
mycorrhizal product in the game
[Music]
and last but not least we would not be
able to do this without all the
Fantastic sponsors over at the patreon
Gang
we would like to help ensure that future
episodes continue to happen please go
check out
www.patreon.com the podcast you'll get
exclusive access to unheard interviews
bonus content giveaways and so so so
much more please go check it out
[Music]
welcome back for part two of our epic
episode with stewby of ACS I hope you
enjoyed the first episode it was full of
knowledge and if you haven't heard it go
check it out
however we've got a whole another half
for you to get through
I hope you enjoyed part two as much as
we enjoyed part one
without further delay
let's get into it
that's a great answer because my next
question was gonna be exactly about that
the killer A5 Haze I've been reading
about this because
it looks like it could be you know the
holy grail for sativa heads like myself
would you recommend this cross for
people who like the really sort of racy
uplifting High
yeah yeah definitely if you are looking
for extremely powerful and intensive
face hybrid that combines the enabled
world with us
with extreme potency is killarified for
sure
5 and how would you describe that one
for people in terms of the smells and
the type of high and the flower time
uh well the originally fight Colombians
along flowering planting it can go over
100 days and here we Harvest in in my
city in my in the coast last week of
August yeah sorry last last week of
November early December they are
although they are half Northern Lights
they are very Haze dominant and very
long flowering
um the if a case is the only plan I have
found I can compete with extreme potency
of the Malawi that was when I
experience also the efficacy
the first time I say my goal I say one
this has the type of thing the intense
and the low in terms I'm looking from
the Neville's close because the others
don't have the C5 is not so intensive
do you remember it
that is not so intensive is the Taste is
quite lemony Thai yeah but it's not
sorry yeah but and I say wow the A5 is
the one for infants and it's also the
one for the most extreme potency from
the naval world so if I want to keep
this extreme potency for A5
and I won't even make it a stronger
the only way is Malawi I we we roll the
A5 to
to the lab and it tested 25 percent but
it hits like 30.
I brought the new Malawi killer to the
same lab
and it was 30. so by Crossing A5 with
with my killer Malawi parental plans I
can increase even more the THC both the
type of ball effects are similar super
trippy but with narcosis
I'm very profound I'm super long nasty
very heavy in the head and in the body
both have this
so it was very natural for me to to to
blend them and the Malawi contributes
increasing even more the
the THC making it more richness then my
killer Malawi's are on the 8080 plus
fluorine drains so the flowering time of
day five is shortened down also
on the A5 contributes with the the
signature loading fence face heater pins
and that's killer E5 is so extremely
important in Sensei very high yielding
and and a bit easier to cultivate than
A5 and probably a bit stronger if you do
proper selection
yeah great information there I think
that's gonna be the one that I'm
probably gonna jump on the photos of it
look great as well in the last answer
you mentioned the hash plant Haze and
this is an interesting one because I
don't know if many people have heard
about it maybe unlike the C5 or the A5
which they might have heard about I
remember I got to smell it and I tried a
little bit of it but I think it was
seeded so it's a little different but it
smelt a bit like the C5 to me in the
similar Terrapins
um what was interesting about it was it
it felt like a real hybrid like it was
kind of you know the hash plant brought
some Indica the C5 was sort of sativary
what do you think it's gonna breed well
with would you want to pair it with a
sativa with an indica and how do you
describe the hash plant Haze to people
who haven't tried it
that's a very good question
I'm glad you
you you know both
and as you said uh both the the plan KC
from nebulance c5h which is Northern
live five I see are very similar they
have the same that
and we
um definition product is also very
similar the northern light five the C5
sorry has the lemon in terms a bit more
alive okay the husband case is a bit not
you can detect the same tie like Terps
from the hazy that but it's more
no more dark more dry but it tastes more
like uh the house plant I think is more
like Moroccan pollen taste the the jello
Moroccan hash taste okay is more
dry
earthy Hashim Moroccan kind of terpenes
that has plant yeah and they are quite
similar and as you say this the [ __ ]
adds this highlighter pins we brought to
the lab for terpen analysis both and and
we saw that they were very similar there
and for uh um for Canada they are also
very similar
um both are very similar in chemotype
and in terpene profile the effect of the
hash plant is slightly more funny both
very similar while the C5 smoke is more
tasty yeah I definitely definitely feel
like I picked up on some of those things
you mentioned one of our listeners was
wondering if you had any tips to help
them grow long flowering sativas indoors
and one of the things they wanted to
know is if they had maybe an a strain
that said it was going to go you know
say 16 or more weeks
would you recommend putting it in 1212
from seed or does that have negative
effects on the plant
yes because
it depends a lot long flowering
yeah I think anything
long flowering right
yeah
it's not the same like trying to grow
indoors at Ida or alternate case that
flowers four to six months indoors that
are assertive dominant hybrid that has
already refined
that it takes three months of flowering
universe and performs well indoors like
golden tiger
it requires different approach okay but
considering that you are growing along
flowering sativa okay and the problem is
is charged along flooring and the size
and all this yeah
indoors
the typical failure that the Growers do
with sativa is to provide a lot of pot
size
a lot of
growing time okay the tropical the
sativas and the tropical sativas take
longer to reach sexual maturity usually
seven eight nine weeks this means that
the plan will grow will grow will grow
from seed and until until reaching the
sexual maturity before the plant is not
able to flower no no no no no matter the
photo period you're using is not going
to flower so if you want to keep the if
the grower wants to keep the the plants
a small and under control during these
two months that the plant is rich in
sexual maturity it's better to use a
small pot for example three liter pot
just just to to let it grow until the
plants sow sex for example you say in
that way you can keep many plants in
small pots
and then when you if you only want to
grow females you say okay I discard the
females
I discard the man sorry but this didn't
didn't take much space only three little
potage then you have the families in
small pots and and then just switch to
flower but you keep them in the small
pot okay because the sativas and
especially tropical sativas they're the
flowering stretching is very strong very
very strong they can double triple or
even more
and multiply their size just in early
flowing what is the best way to
to control the side with without topping
is with Rod bound we're using a small
pot
typically if you let the the female in
the three liter pot after sexing and you
pass switch to flower the the dominance
hybrid or the tropical sativa will start
to flower uh we'll do the early flowing
and stretching but in a more moderate
way okay you the grower will be able to
to tame as much as possible the size of
the tropical sativa from seed
uh and then
some songs
hybrids will work work well under 12 12
like could be Panama Banks
Panama golden tiger this work well under
classic 1212 or their strange like
pirutai ultimate hairs you need to go
down in 11 13 10 14 even
yeah and obviously another trick is to
start from clones from sexually mature
clones
directly switch to floor in that way you
can have sativaso one meter less than
one meter a bit more but very very under
control yes
yeah great advice there I was wondering
have you ever experimented with
different day and night times like for
example DJ Short famously said that he
gives 11 hours of light 13 hours of dark
and he thinks that it makes the plants
Express more sativa-like have you found
anything like that on your own
okay every strand is different
yeah yeah I think I read some that his
approach was like to study the
germination of the tropical sativas and
the 1410 no I think so yes yeah because
this is for example in the subtropica
then we have been talking about in
Canary Islands in Hawaii in in
California in Reunion Island is that
photo period the longer days will be 14
hours okay and then you grow the plants
and
when when when you decide you switch to
11 30 yes very tropical strengths from 0
to 7 in from the equator
for example
ties extreme Colombians a extreme
Jamaican extreme
French Royal Africans these plants don't
flower Under 12 12. they are in in a
Everlasting early flowering stretching
so indoors they just grow longer nose
and longer nose and they put a few
pistols but they continue because they
are feeling that that they are in that
moment that they need to stretch and
make a space for the bad uh but they
will only this extreme tropical will
only go deep to the flowering process
when they are 11 13 and even to to make
them fully ripe and avoid more
reflowering some refluence you even need
to bring down the photoperation at the
end maybe to 10 14 photo period
yeah very interesting very interesting
I've seen online that I think you had
mention somewhere that you felt like a
lot of indoor Growers only really want
to do eight or nine week strains because
they think that they're going to yield
more but then you said oh you know but
if you grow a strain that takes you know
three or four weeks longer it will yield
more so it is worth the time
do you feel like not enough Growers are
sort of aware of this because it feels
like there's not a lot of sort of
commercial people trying to do sativas
you know how can we help get the message
out there that sativas are viable
that's a very good question and I I
don't think
many people realize especially the the
young ones and there's also the false
meat
without indica
there's no jail in hybrids you know uh
I have many many people that ask me the
same question over the years I want uh
seven eight week flowering plant that
deals well
and I say oh
Ellie flowering plants
are not the best healers they are good
indications but you want an Indica okay
there are good Indica strains that are
good yelling with nine weeks
but if you want even better years
you better to grow a 50 50 hybrid a real
F1 hybrid 50 50 that has a lot of
eternosis hybrid bigger
uh and wait until for example the Malawi
cross pck If Flowers 9 10 11 weeks but
the year is the double uh data plan of
eight weeks
so
is it worth to wait two three weeks more
uh until the double and harvest the
double uh and have something that has
more sativa probably can provide
different effects if you want me for
sure
and if we talk about the whole picture
what are the biggest kind of is yelled
in
in the world is
sativa dominant Hebrews with just a
thoughts of of indica
70 80 percent
uh hybrids that can grow five to six
metal
big and GL two three five kilos and they
have just you know Indica genetics to
add the bad density to make waste but
the long coldest floor restructure the
big size the super Vigor all only
strings that at the end will come on the
final jail come from the sativa
the good flower relief radius that is a
good trade for later for bagapin and for
trimming is the indicas had very bad
flower with
bad radio the sativa have better
so at the end of your own uh very high
GL team with very great flower you
believe right here you must go to sativa
genetics no indica and wait a bit more
but it will be worth
oh yeah I like the sounds of that
I don't know if it's the case worldwide
but I feel like in Australia and in
America at least people prefer indicas
over sativas generally speaking and I
was trying to think about why that was
like why do people seem to like indica's
more and I kind of was thinking oh well
maybe it's got something to do with how
sometimes people who sort of have
anxiety or are naturally a bit nervous
will use cannabis to help with that so
you know those people aren't going to
like sativas
but then I kind of thought oh I don't
really know maybe it's just individual
individual biochemistry like who knows
so I'm wondering do you feel like more
people like indicas than sativas and how
can we try to convert some of the people
who like indicas over to the dark side
to try the sativas
well
I I I I I realize you like indigos
I don't think it's the dark side or it's
a bad thing uh
um
but what I think is a bad thing is the
reductionism to simplify the whole
qualities of the Cannabis gem pool
towards only the the Indica dominant
strains that look good on Instagram
you know I think the economy is much
more than this
more than to offer than that
I understand that a lot of people don't
tolerate well the the sativa effects and
prefer the Indigo or or CBD I mean
perfect for a smoking Sativa no one is
better person is not
is not better okay but
yeah I think it has to do with both
things in one side there
the industry both in America in the 80s
and in Holland develop commercially
within the growing and the best
strengths that were developed within the
growing had a lot of money
this is a fact because
Northern California and all this
they they need in Northern California
the October is already called in Holland
they don't have a good weather
so
yes uh commercially
it went to
to fast-flowering indoor plants
of Afghani Indica genetic background
uh The Afghani also they were the more
suitable strains to adapt genetics to
indoor growing to certain flowering
times to make the the balls denser to
increase rest in production
so at the end the standard for
commercial quality width
after the scan yes and now with the
course and the cookies is obviously and
its effect is the Indica dominant
strengths yeah some of them have a bit
of sativa they are very complex
qualified you see the the produce
sometimes thinner leaves but the flower
is all all about the refinement of the
you know
is there and they are succeeding in the
the
they are the best on it in our in North
America and in North America the the
pioneers of the modern Western marijuana
we need to go to thank to to the hippies
that we are smoking and have this kind
of this culture today
they are the the biggest country
with the biggest
cannabis culture in in the Western
Country they are pioneers in Britain
so
I cannot complain much about them but
honestly their style doesn't match with
my my style of what I like but it's just
my
taste and I don't think is better or
than the other if you ask me I would
like to see more diversity more genetic
diversity and more sort of strange being
grown and being appreciated yes of
course
foreign
when the hip is started with all these
they they wanted to the to make the
Revolution and use the revolution use
the drugs for the revolution now well if
I in the days of
globalized capitalism no
um we deal with
with a lot of stress we are very
disconnected with the nature with the
Natural Life
and we suffer a lot of
the depression and anxiety increase in
this modern world
so
it's normal and
that people need approach
approach to canaries from the medical
way and then they prefer something that
we
that is more like a stone no that will
kill the day because they have had
another of the day
nature for something that that will kill
the day and we'll handle to go to to
sleep and that's all or they have a
medical problem that don't get high and
and get some medical reliefs from the
CBD
yeah great answer great answer
I was wondering if you could tell us a
little bit about the Spanish scene and
what I was interested in knowing
specifically was
is Hash still a big thing over there and
then as a follow-up are there any sort
of differences in the culture just even
regionally from say different areas in
different parts of Spain
he has been close to Morocco
the Spanish cannabis culture was all
about us
and then when when this first century
they grows they grow socks and the
genetics start to come from the people
start to grow indoors and
and then a very
a very thriving cannabis in industrious
started to to consolidate here
from from the seed banks from grocers
that are the small retailer to Big
wholesaler to fertilizer companies to
magazines to make an events
uh lawyers
and this everything everything there it
started 20 years ago or a bit more
but
it met when the Dutch season were going
down and we were just creating our
industry
so
yeah of course a few strong seed bank in
Holland it still remaining strong like
Greenhouse like that's passion and two
new ones very strong appear like Royal
Queen and bad news for example
but here in Spain
we were competing we were the Spanish
people managed to create companies that
were competing in products and in volume
of business with a Dutch company
and at all levels at all levels in a few
years
now after 20 years the the sector moves
a lot of millions creates a lot of
employment their legal legal companies
like Manda we pay a lot of taxes
um
so
the hearing Spain the weather is
extremely good and we are one of the
strongest countries in the world for
tourism we we are a population of less
than 50 and we have 70 80 millions of
tourists per year before covering
obviously a lot of people from from
England Germany Sweden when they retire
they buy a house here in Spain to live
because the weather the quality of life
is cheaper than lawful culture we have a
lot of different culture from the soul
the Mediterranean them the north the
central the the food is completely
different we are very tolerant we are
have a lot of uh yeah culture history we
we like a lot the party so this is the
perfect place so the tourists could come
and create a recreational marijuana
industry you know the they all come here
to to get drunk to enjoy the beach to to
all this is happening now with the Sofia
clubs in especially in Barcelona there
is more always the most tolerant city
than that is go ahead of us of the rest
of Spain but the model is not still
fully legal not for for the seed banks
not for the producer of the clubs not
for the clubs
is a very incomplete model that allows
to distribute seats
or companies is buy and sell seeds
legally
you you can make products oriented for
the Cannabis growing like the fertilizer
the
the lamps the soil Brands and all this
but still Spain is very very good very
very behind of the worldwide
legalization that is happening in North
America and Latin America now Uruguay
Colombia Mexico just now Ecuador also
legalizing uh
the in in Thailand just legalized in
many African countries we are realizing
Morocco to say two weeks ago that is
considering the legalization
occurring in in in Europe
uh Germany has included marijuana and
the national health health system
so they are buying the legal marijuana
from the blps from Canada from Israel
so yes it's happening it's happening but
some countries Europe is is beginning
slow compared with with United States
with Latin America
or I think I think Australia and you
know we are very stupid
we
in our cases
is is terrible
I was gonna say yeah I mean Australia's
Got a cannabis program but it's probably
not not very good to be honest
anyway I was wondering why because we
you know we're kind of talking about
hash you got me interested
which of your strains do you think makes
the best hash and then as a kind of
slightly different question which strain
has the largest trichome heads
for a section
the the best one there we have indicas
would be
which is
[Music]
this is not a very land race highway but
I like it so much and the customer like
it so much
that we offer
then the
the species also very nice for for us
and instruction
uh
the hash plan
and then the kalichina doesn't give so
much return but it gives a heart that is
very very special like very exotic
intense
the the China
quite different to to The Afghani houses
that are more common with the cookies
the orgies and the Bubba okay yeah and
then for for for Pakistani
[Music]
kind of Russian an extraction the the
Pakistan Violetta because it's very nice
that the trichomes really carry the the
the pigment the period the pigments so
when you you do the extraction and the
house the the house most of the time it
becomes purple or violet oh lovely
she has this this way is with Pakistan
Central Coast the purple dinosaur or
with Violetta
and this is quite interesting for
for Pakistani house and colorful houses
then here for moravity they already
recommend you
um for for CBD extraction CBD one
for sure is extremely resonance a very
good Philippines for extractions and if
you want to make CBD extraction on CBD
one is excellent
and we have sativas of
of that are very very resonance but
usually the the sativas
produce their
the the the Indica produce the
Russian more divided also in in the
bracks but also on the lips nearby the
the floor
the sativa concentrate much of the of of
the regime
on the on the black side not so much on
the leaf so for extraction they are not
so
so good in return
but we have sativa Domina and hybrids
that are very rationals but for example
Panama Fern works very well Panama Cross
Banking Haze also Malawi cross Panama
summer Deli Cafe
foreign
golden tiger film they are very good for
extraction
with sativas
there you go some great answers there
I was interested I was browsing through
your catalog of strains on one of the
seed banks and I noticed there was one
that I'd never seen before called
Hokkaido and it says that it's like a
Japanese hemp that sounds very rare and
unique could you tell us a little bit
about that
yeah of course
this was a another genetic shot boy with
a grower
a person from from Japan contact me
um
um yeah I I didn't sound research
when trying to get a picture of of how
the the true land races were divided
around the world
and yes I read something about Japanese
strengths
but but it was not clear the information
if whether they were really secretive
Japanese cannabis strain like breathe
for with the secretive you for sure it
was used for for fiber
um ceremonial uses for for thousands of
years at least is documented in
yeah in their own read to us
and
and also for your for in the fabric for
the clothes they have a long tradition
of of
cultivating hemp
um
for I have a gather there was many many
hamper strains
all around the the Japan because Japan
you know
the the climates are quite different the
South
there are some islands that are almost
tropical and Hokkaido which is the north
part is an island on the North
is is very cold the Summers is is a very
natural research very beautiful place
and
it has short summer but but the the cold
weather comes very fast the Autumn is is
very short and the winter is very long
so
yeah it was difficult because it was not
properly documented
and and uh when after the second World
War uh Japan have to comply
follow the the loss from United States
no and at that time the already the
United States had the the loss regarding
the
marijuana
so
so I think they tried
many of the
of the
old Japanese campus strengths probably
have been eradicated around during these
years the previous decade is of
prohibition
and somewhat in in Hokkaido which is
some uh a Wilder place
uh
the the hemp has escaped from the
eradication program so although they try
because they already carry millions of
plants
generally
but yes a popular population of cannabis
managed to
to
drive without human
help there in Hokkaido
and I I contacted with with one Japanese
and he Italian
and what about Hokage I have some excuse
I can send you them we did uh exchange
and internet
and
I was quite excited about to see what
could come out
and when we grow the first week it was
quite in the quite exciting because it
grew like a houseplant Indica like
like
wild leaves
and looks like quite like a funny camera
like the indoor plants you know it
reminds me a lot like the Chinese indica
China Yunnan in in some ways remind me a
lot to
but still those in the gajas plan trades
um
and yes I have hopes that it could there
could be a executive Indica stream
but but it's not the the the first
population the the P1 plants we grill
uh to be honest we didn't grow it to the
to the best potential because the first
cycle uh we got a
a spider might infection so we had to
take clothes then we flower them again
outside but it was extremely hot it was
in summertime here I think I did they
didn't like much the the weather and the
samples didn't Express we brought them
to the lab and they were very similar
with
like a hamper strain I can like
0.5
of THC and 0.5 of CBD
was active okay it was not
a
but very recently
um
then we we all open pollinated because I
didn't we didn't receive many seats we
didn't have
um for what we we saw in the P1
generation I I didn't see any secret
active plan the plans were not rationals
but I smoke they don't get you high they
can navigate analysis where under one
so it looks songs and tastes
like a hemp stream so we open pollinated
we I think we only discard one plant
that was hermaphrodite but all the
plants the rest of the plant that was
actually stable way up and pollinated
and
of our first studies is okay this is
strain
I said okay we we released
that's not a problem is obviously we
it's not going to sell a lot because our
customers are more marijuana type but
the ganja tiger wants to to get high
with the flower
but it's interesting to
from the pressure
from the preservation side to to
contribute a new home cultivar that no
one knows that the the Japanese and the
Japanese have had a very prohibitionist
since since the second world war so they
don't comment anything about their
Japanese strengths or they can be
secretive there are some studies quite
those
um
and a one year by some laundry is
Growers they say yeah Japanese well
that's interesting I'm going to buy you
some bags and it's an idea more because
from the preservation side and because
it's really exotic you know right then
it's secretive potential and one grower
that
grill or the the p2's generation we will
release
with no relevant secretive or terpenic
value
and and one grower the agree of a few
packs
phone a few resinous plant and a few
plants that were smelling really good
from from a field of thousands
um
um he brought into the lab
and one of them had 10 percent of CBD
and five percent of THC
very good
number and the others were
and the other is interesting were very
low in Tac
but a bit but a bit of Civility
and then the third type that was like
the one we found like him like
very low TLC I'm very low CV so you
really saw the
the uh
if we look for in first that the the
string has the potential to to be
more relevant for for their parents and
cannabinoids and with a bit of work
working to to this plan to to this kind
of camel type with more content we can
make it even secretive
but it will need like by Crossing to
this type of plants
then in breathe
remember line one two three generation
and and then fix fix it to do something
more selective or something
only with CBD but most CBD it can be
done yeah you give a
a more interesting value to this line
and it was we chose Discovery like two
three months ago thanks to a customer
actually had a chance to to agree with a
few thousands
and realize that there are a few higher
potential to be selective so who knows
I'm I'm in touch with him maybe we
collaborate to to hopefully increase the
economy new Enterprise
of this yeah but definitely the
potential to do it yeah yeah wow how
interesting maybe a future offering from
the Japanese hemp strain that's very
cool so you mentioned preservation in
there and it kind of got me thinking
about a question I've been thinking
about for years now which is for someone
like yourself who's looking to get pure
land race stock what does the future of
preservation look like to you in regards
to land race considering most people
kind of say oh you know you can't find
that pure anymore even if you go to the
real it's all polluted now what do you
think land race preservation is going to
be like going forward
the thing obviously many things has been
lost
that's that's true but many things are
left
many things are left more than the
indoor Kush
waiting for us to to
yeah I I think
that that is a pessimistic
way to see it yeah I agree that very
interesting lands have been lost
then you're not going to do anything to
to to Really find out
how many good ones are left and to try
to preserve
what is left
you are going to stop there only
I I don't understand this attitude
um
is is difficult because preservation
[Music]
how it has grown up the the recreational
and the industry
doesn't give money in the future we'll
mean long term when this gets when this
industry gets more complicated when the
genetic engineering starts when only big
companies that have this knowledge these
machines disqualified people
these patterns
will available
for that for that profile of companies
then the the different genotypes that
that the land races and and the temples
that we are not looking at
these are the the temple that that will
be very important and with a lot of
value for for these big companies
okay but it means long term
at the moment
and for the small companies
it has very little value
because what is the big Trend the Kush
the cookies this is 80 of the business
this is 80 of the business so if you
concentrate in if you want to make money
you need to concentrate on this that's
why that span the seed banks are coping
USA and the Spanish is that I'll also
coping USA because it's the next big
thing in USA is already there
you know that
and the only way to
the the commercial gentle is all hash
cookies
you could you can call it with other
name across it with other name and give
it another twist so it looks slightly
better but it's a very narrow part of
the Temple
and the potential and the qualities of
the cannabis
so
for me preservation I I saw it since the
beginning first as a passion for me to
learn to to where is the roots in the
hybrid we should we we find it all mixed
but where this the taste of the uh of
the scan cane where the intents of the
haste came where the color of this came
to understand all this from from their
Roots what what land races give give
these traits
and for me it was passionate for me it
was obvious that it has an immense
genetic value something that can give
you
something new
if you're always repeating the same it's
very it's very difficult that you came
out with something entirely new one that
that can make a new Revolution on the
cannabis you know in science
um
if you are always repeating the same you
always finish on on the same
if you want to reach to new territories
you must start from from new things and
for that the the land races and
obviously it's there
the the
source of the all the genetic diversity
we enjoyed right now
is the repository of this of the genetic
diversity all these genetic
widespread especially in countries like
Indian Nepal Afghanistan Pakistan
that they have such
cannabis code so for hundreds centuries
in so many parts
is
incredible the genetic diversity so
Stalone India Nepal Afghanistan and
Pakistan
um the other social Revolution that are
that have been happening
with their autoflowing Revolution the
CBD Revolution all these were trades
that weren't very obvious and easy to to
get from from Land races from the out of
Floridian from the Eastern hemp for
example on the Russian
and the CBD from from the the house plan
laundry School diverse while the
hospital
the
Lebanese the Pakistani
so the potential to find new things new
Canary noise neuter pins
will come
most probably from the the this the
Temple of the land race was probably
rather than the bottleneck
Jam pulled the the American industry
Industries driving the gentle nowadays
yeah great answer to a complex question
while we're talking about genetics a
different viewer wanted to know and I
was interested as well what sort of
Lebanese stock do you work with and how
would you describe it to people our
listener was wondering how often does
the red phenotype versus the blonde
phenotype show up in the regular seeds
yeah um they are some some people
I I think most of our audience knows but
I think it's going good to point it out
um
you usually people as you said or
connect
has with him because right
with afani Pakistan you know
but
many of the traditional hashes I
produced from sativas
the the most
excellent cases are the the Chara
sativas the The Nepalese and the north
Indians
okay
but also the the Morocco the Morocco has
and the Lebanese has that is used
following the dry safe methods using in
Pakistan in Afghanistan and Pakistan
are sativas
people confuse and they um
uh
yeah for for some people it's difficult
to understand that
the
Moroccan and the Lebanese
the the Lebanese population we we offer
from United States
came from from a friend from Israel that
in the 90s he
there in Israel is very racy to get live
on his house
but not so common to to get with but
sometimes he got away from the Bedouins
that
that were smugly and so on some products
and with us you know
and and then he saved the the seeds and
he came to to live to spam for a few
years
and we get we keep in touch and he's
here with us with um
this is of this leverness
and it was working mainly by by a friend
of mine called raspablo who who is the
first generation
um
and yes yes
is assativa completely adapted to the
dry and hot climate of of Lebanon is is
extremely
resistant against heat and lack of water
we did a test here outside putting some
Lebanese plants in a pot
that usually plants in a pod literature
is easier
uh hearing some time for in in Spain 40
degrees and add exit of the aircon
so the plans were receiving in the sun
40 degrees and the and the Heat of the
aircon we understand
and and with other plants
after one year the indoor Afghani were
or
fading down
you know
yes I he saw you how how resistant this
the these genetics these genetics are
and in the in the very one generation we
um there were not much is like 30 or
something and my friend reproduced the
line in in in in a few Cycles
using a small population but but always
removing the the
rmaphrodites and and using a a very nice
female in every cycle with different
females so we came up with uh three lots
from the same males that were pollinated
with many different males in each lot
for the P2 for the second generation
then we uh
we grew like 100 we put only three loads
this is the silver Bulgarian all and we
put all 100 plants and again a lot of
hermaphrodites uh
we came up
throwing jelly
40 from the 40 50 plants
yes and 11 is also has a a a a high male
radio
11s usually produce quite a lot of Mace
yeah well after removing males and
hermaphrodite we left with
30 40 females but we managed to found
sexually stable if females and males the
two men the two phenotypes one more
sativa with long nose that takes longer
to flower in 70 days 74 indoors a bigger
gelding more branchy type
uh thinner lips but they're still big
they have with more
Tangy
trick mango free liter pins and then
there's all the other uh fennel there is
a smaller more columnar faster flowering
55 days fluorine or so and more colorful
indoors it turns purple radish
is not so fruity
yeah I prefer the effects of the long
and the The Taste and the effects of the
long flowering and the interesting thing
of the Lebanese is is that most of the
plants produce uh both THC and CBD they
are rich in both
okay uh
like for example we found like a balance
one to one chemotypes seven percent TSC
seven percent CBD
then uh
once with very little THC like 0.5 and
16 of CBD
and
um radius of one to three like
four percent
[Music]
uh THC to 12 percent CDD
one radius of one two TSC CBD
it's very interesting
the the main interest of the Lebanese is
there is a new source for CBD it has
many interesting Rich CBD chemotypes and
also somewhere
with CV
is a
very resistant for for other places
where
with water restriction with with a lot
of heat
uh
and use that and and people really like
the the effects here
many girls really like the effects it's
not and it's not very strong it's the
potency is soft moderate because it also
has
CBD but it's really Pleasant very really
happy clear
yeah that sounds lovely
always wanting to ask you what land race
genetics do you think are
underrepresented within the Cannabis
culture so to speak for me I always
think about Haze and how there's
supposedly some Indian genetics in there
and I think to myself you never hear
about Indian what to you do you think is
really underrepresented
as you know they are
the main recreational gentle
comes from genetics that hybrids that
were developing in United States
okay so the
the the the
language the languages that were used to
to develop these hybrids
depended a lot on the land races that
the people in the United States receive
obviously
so yeah yeah at the end but
they they enjoyed the state they work
mainly with Mexican
with Colombia
and
Thai a bit lesser
I'm with Havanese
that's the main Temple that
the
does the land races the
that are more prevalent in today's
modern Western recreational
to change it so the ones that are
underrated and we should put more
attention to
is is for example the The Amazing World
The erasening of Indian Lander and
Brandy exchange is doing
yeah
to look
and what we will have uh discussed
previously that India and nepalis
probably and Afghanistan and Pakistan
the most interesting places for to look
for biggest diversity oldest land races
with other culture and more variety
and I I think yes the Indian Land races
The Nepalese land races are not very
prevalent in in the gym pool that people
are smoking nowadays
and
regarding indicas uh is is mainly a
funny
maybe some some Pakistani also made into
the North American Temple but uh I think
is mostly Afghani and Pakistan also has
very interesting indicas
to to offer and there are other very
interesting indicates in countries like
Uzbekistan
yeah interesting stuff for sure
so the next thing I wanted to ask you
about was something which a lot of fans
asked me to follow up with you
do you ever plan to have any sort of
Partnerships with any U.S seed banks I
think there's a lot of us Growers that
really want your gear but maybe find it
hard to get it
the
they are it's legalized on a federal
level we will try to establish there are
a legal business and to look for
partners there
I don't think right now is the moment
I have friends and
working there
the the half Hemi with with selections
and I appreciate a lot
but we never talked about making
business there
and now we're with we have so many
retailers that see worldwide I
understand that the people in the United
States very used to to have the the
problem very easy to access it within
United States on our list
but well even in this
globalized world the things are not
always so easy
especially regarding customs
and So to avoid problems that we don't
want problems
uh at this time
we're not shipping to
to United States but I don't think it
will take much time I want to legalize
federally
um and once we do a few steps here to to
get fighter certificates for
for an exportation of the seats I think
they won't have any
any complaint to to Donald allo the
importation of the she's there I should
be without any problem and fluently
uh until now I would recommend to anyone
interested to look in the in the many
retailers that see worldwide
we don't do it because we want to
to to
be quite a strict with a look here
um
but many retailers are shipping
everywhere
and
it's very easy
yeah having been able to get some of
your seeds of myself I'll let people
know it is possible to get them via
other means
uh speaking of Australia I wanted to ask
you are you familiar with the Australian
bastard cannabis plant
no no not much uh not much have you seen
photos
as you know the uh
we're actually at the other part of the
world yeah in Spain we say if you make a
holiday you will appear in
[Laughter]
so yeah for us Australia it's like woof
this is super far super far so it's it's
not something that that we have in in
our cannabis culture I remember when we
in overgrown when when some of the
Australian Growers start to join also
the the mulu Batman the showing some
Madness of five kilos plants that
were amazing yeah I remember some very
very
clear Australian Growers and then I knew
about the um
no a lot of the stick arrived in the 70s
and 80s there so you have a very good
Saturday
the purple name being I have hair and
scene but never smoke to be honest so
it's a Pity but I think it's just
because the distance and because uh at
the end the Australian hybrids didn't
make it into the Dutch genetics or the
North America genetics and it's a Pity
because many people say very good things
about about me Madness so I
don't understand how
after so many years Noah came up with a
good representation of of
that that could be spreaded around the
world so people can get a tote of the
fine flowers and breads from the
Australian Growers
it's really a Pity that but it was
obviously a result of the prohibition is
it's just like that
no you got a very valid point there it's
surprising no one's really locked down
the mullumbimby madness
I did want to ask you I know that you
grow organically and we're very
passionate about helping people to grow
organically on the show what sort of
grow style do you use do you just use
basic amendments and you just mix it in
do you do no-till give us a bit of a
rundown on how you grow plants
this is
yeah
for 20 more than 20 years following the
the same soil mix recipe I'm a soil
grower I'm an organic grower
I love the outdoor buds over indoor
and I am I always use this I uh we get a
very high quality high quality bit from
Cooperative here in in Spain and we have
been buying the speed for 25 years and
it's always the same um basically we put
like 80 90 percent of the speed then 10
of very high quality warm costume then
a bit of formal of one of these
depending of the strain on the stage
and the transplant
more for flowering the the wano and and
a bit of cocoa if this if it's a strain
that is slow with the roots
or if we want to speed up the first whip
the first weeks a bit more of cocoa and
this
organic fertilizer we use to Branch the
hearings in Europe are very very well
known is Canada the the organic line the
biocana
which is basically and Cana Flores and
their risottonic which is marvelous for
for transplants
uh and then also it's very nice I like a
lot of the the
obese there'll be a grow be a blonde
your face uh the phase one
use this one for 25 years and
and that's all I love the taste or on
the feeling and the vibration of how
they came out
yeah I don't need anything more yeah
there's room for improvement regarding
you
but I don't like to use chemical it
makes very natural The Taste and harsh
and gives a bad negative uh vibration
that I don't like in the if I like a
toxic feeling in the height I don't like
um and also I don't use much of these
new era flowering stimulators that the
yeah yeah yeah
more more more I just use and uh basic
organic fertilizer for fluorine and the
soil
no not bad Busters and all these no
there you go keeping it simple I like
that
so the next question I wanted to ask you
was
do you have any seeds in your stash that
you're really excited to look through
next like what's the next thing you're
excited to look on to look into
how it is
one of my colleagues got from hippie a
Spanish Kitty that lives there for four
decades and we have done a couple of
generations of this cash plan from from
Kashmir and it's very interesting
there's job to do because
there are different chemo types there
are solar air means but there are some
very interesting expression like very
rationals why leave the colors very
interesting their pins
and yeah it's quite interesting this
this question here
then some some sativa seeds that are a
friend of mine that is a sailor brought
me from the Caribe in from San Martin
island it's a very very small island in
the Caribbean
after going across the whole Atlantic
that he finished all the joints
and they they reached to San Martin
first
in America
we we in and then she was in touch with
with Rasta there that was growing super
crazy sativas like things live like
needles my friend told me that's what
went off to me like
I I go Tropical from the career the
Caribbean
the dog doesn't contain indicator simply
contaminated
then I have some interesting Colombia
song
the the one Chilean
he used to work for the encode do you
know the code I don't know how it's
called in English is the Department of
the United Nation for drug studies
oh okay
okay
they make uh some studies in Latin
America of
of the drug production area and their
relationship with the the cultures and
this
minorities the the group there
and and this person was part of it so he
was in contact with many
a Colombian Growers so the school
Colombian Growers and he brought me
and
[Music]
a mango which
and the one I want to have more will to
explore is maybe the Santa Marta don't
know
then I have differences from Sri Lanka
and another one that
the hippie here from from my Village
that is half Sri Lankan
from Sri Lanka very small seeds Ultra
long flowering
yes
or five five months of flowering
and I have another Sri Lanka but at the
summer first so
I I got away from Sri Lanka in 2017.
when I traveled there
and I always there I'm quite curious and
that I would like to wait in the fridge
is also won the Asurion one friend from
my sim mad send me is
this I'm very very curious to to explore
this I haven't Explorer
[Music]
from from Broadway
I was there in
in yeah in 2019 for holidays but
but I couldn't get with
there you go what a what a nice list
yeah that's and we have some projects
ongoing
this year which is to bring back the
pure China unan and hopefully to bring
the the pure touch on my oh gosh I think
there will be a lot of demand for that
well
don't don't think so usually the the
Chinese okay
um
plants give you
to say you know more reputation than
sales
[Music]
uh the tourists are very very few
Growers willing to grow a sativa that
take four or five months to flower
these are very very easy
small Market yeah only the hardcore okay
well while we're talking about long
flowering sativas I really wanted to ask
you about how you got the old-timer Haze
how did that go about and how would you
describe the Old Timer had it
yeah the ultimate cases are a very
unique line
is one of the most extreme tropical
sativa I ever had a pleasure to to
experience is
um
I don't know how to describe the Finnish
priorities is like it comes from two
centuries ago
if you saw a battle for the timer has to
to all this cookies guys and all this
they they don't know how to to take it
but that is is like completely different
thing is
two hundred percent sativa you cross all
timers with an indica and they all
called still 100 sativa and you know
is really extreme he's very tropical
from safe it could take six months to
flower
and the Clones we have are really old we
are 15 years old so
a bit faster
but yeah they are very very wild very
very well
what do you know about to know more
specifically about Old Timers I guess
something I'm interested in is how did
you get that stock from Old Timer and
how do the different phenotypes differ
is it mostly just the color or is are
they actually quite different the the
old timer has a
there are two main finals the green and
the Purple Haze okay
um they are grow and flower almost the
same
the the difference is
only in the second half of flowering and
in the finished product
but during the whole growth early
flowering
they look
essentially green
okay
if if you live in a call in a if they
are grown in outdoors in a cold weather
usually in October with the cold nights
the the colorful
phenotypes start to show okay not
usually showing a bit of the purple
veins the red red reddish tones
okay uh and depending how cold is your
weather
yeah it's just me that the through the
flowering the the nights are lower than
15 degree so this happened in yesterday
in tropics and subtropica it happened in
in in most temperate latitudes even with
good climate like the Mediterranean
so so yes
um regarding finished product the the
green cases
super clean Super euphoric
and it's it's a bit like the the like
the New Caledonia just the smoke that
you feel everything more
Amplified you are more alive
okay is
and you want to do things like you have
a lot of energy
okay the purple hay and and the green
Haze
smell like
an ancient world spices
their incense I I I like to to describe
it like
like uh the backpack of a Backpacker
after
traveling one month in India and coming
back with with infants and spices and
all the dirty clothes
something something like that is is the
smell of the of the or the other
alternative is a Green Inferno there's
some
and here's the green case even with cold
temperatures even fresh in terms is
completely ripe green then the Purple
Haze with the colder nights in October
November December
and start to show more more color more
color
um
yeah usually they saw a mix of red and
purple
and and yes that's also the the purple
fennel have more like red wine Brandy
kind of alcoholic serpentes uh more
Berry
uh Blackberry strawberry
the smoke is also very very terrible
is all in the head
but it's more introspective than the
Green Hills
okay
and how did you get the seed stock
initially
okay the the Seas came from from
Alzheimer which is
one of the Pioneers breeders in in UK
[Music]
um
he's an old person and he was in touch
with
with the the first marijuana movement
and the the first hip is traveling and
I'm exchanging series
that came from
from Asia
so he also traveled to United States
lines
uh
that he collected himself that are not
the rebelt from some school man
at least directly I don't know
oh yeah you know that all the original
Haze is the the haze the sun is
like this to Holland
um this is supposedly uh
a pure case line
collected by All Time and another person
and that has been preserved parallel to
original yes
[Music]
told me that he had three lines but
because he gave away to people to
reproduce but never no one did at the
end he he lost it and he he used to
breathe in UK so he can only breathe
indoors
so the whole timer were too too extreme
for
the breeding goals
and needs
so he made a few hybrids with with it
but he ended up losing his his pure his
population
are the only one person that
that was called Pacific
was one one of the persons that received
the
pure seeds from from
him from Alzheimer and he did a small
reproduction
he gave Oasis to
in Canary's world I think it was yes to
to different people to people like Santa
Barbara to us
and I think there were not many seats
left and well I I think
Old Timer
appreciate us chariots and like he gave
us I knew that
we were really passionate with sativa so
he gave our life 40 or 50 seats of the
from the Pacific
reproduction and and those were I don't
have any
any record or no or news that anyone
Grill
moral timer haze from the original
Channel but for the religion robots or
that anyone
preserve any other headline from from
Alzheimer different than this one
or only the
the work we did is what remains alive
yeah fantastic it's a it's a very highly
sought after strain in terms of the cult
following just as a random side question
did old-timer ever talk to you about
giving genetics to Sam the skunk man or
being involved in the skunk project no
no uh I I think I
uh I I cannot pull I cannot say now that
that he said that that he work in this
country yeah okay he never said that he
worked to develop the haze he only said
that he got his seats yeah coming from
yes
what others are saying I
I prefer not to go
it's all polemic about things that I
don't know they are a fact so I prefer
not to go in yeah so just as a sort of
general question what's your favorite
offering from Ace seeds if you could
only pick one
so difficult
for others or for me
um how about do one for each
if you if you watch for me I will
date you
date you for me it is
the noise
press all my buttons you're making me
feel I
don't know like
is is what I call a spiritual wind I
started us is really magic with this
very special and the incense
from his magic with yeah and for others
if you want I wanted to impress someone
and don't know anything about or sativas
and something that is grow up on a
micros fan
and and you will get a good into
introduction
into our work
well to really solid offerings there
I was hoping I could ask you a little
bit about the Panama Red Line you have I
noticed obviously it's an F10 so it
sounds like a lot of Works gone into
this project what sort of traits were
you looking for in it and do you have
any plans to breed with it more in the
future
oh
the Panama strain is probably the the
stream we we have work
longer more generation
and probably
or for long-term lines is probably the
best one
yes and most of the Merit or on this
line came from the job of of kaiki or of
Charlie Garcia
it is the most difficult
generation and and to pull it at a level
that is incredible the the Panama or
Panama or
is is a fifth Panama hybrid it started
in the United States the uh there was a
a
grower a matter of breeder
and in the upper Grove forums that he
was a friend of mine and suddenly
Charlie Garcia he his name was green
grocer
and um
he used to grow
a Panama Panama lines he had a a hybrid
of apanema old Panama green on an old
Panama Red Line
okay and he worked I don't know maybe
one two generations this hybrid being
grosser
then she passed the
the
genetics to Charlie Garcia to kaiki from
Canada when we were working the first
years of his seats
and I'm with
um we took a third Panama
Colombian registry from Alex Mano Negra
okay
and we put several Rhythm male red males
from this Fair versus Sativa male into
the the two-way hybrid
making a three-way hybrid okay and then
kaiki will award the hybrid in
at least until left 6 F7
until 2006
and the
same here here
the most difficult job is that Panama is
like to to capture the best trace of the
of the best Panama race
in a strain that can be grown with
modern standards and compared with
racing interpins potency bag appeal
quality with the modern strings
um is is an extremely good job we don't
say lightly that is the the best purusa
diva Central Americans of the last 20
years because it is
amazing quality it has different Thanos
and the red ones the green ones some
that have so much resin that is white
purple one
and
um cakey work the telegraphy award the
panaman deal the F6 F7
and then I start to work with the line
on 2006 2007.
ideally two or three generation
and then the the time that I work better
myself the Panama was in 2013.
when I bought like seven different
Panama lines from X F6 1210
and then we selected among 100 different
females
and then I came up with the Panama gold
sf10 Elite
which is my work after kaiki after
Charlie Garcia
of a mix of his Elite Panama Red The
Elite Panama Red we had a the assist at
that time
mix it with greens that I like
and then work three four five generation
work
some of the lime the the the main
parental plan we use for Panama breeding
is the Panama goddess it's an F
10 F10 sorry and his Elite it has
everything I want is probably not the
more radius but regarding GL
type of FL
the quality of the effect terpenes
is the the best female I have seen
until now after 20 years working with
Panama
that's awesome to hear
so I was hoping to clarify I noticed
that the Pakistani chitrali Kush breeder
pack it kind of had a lot of different
phenotypes listed in it is that similar
to how you were talking about doing like
the different xamls where they're sort
of like unreleased mothers and you're
including them in this pack that aren't
normally in the others and how would you
describe the other Pakistani mothers
compared to the usual one you use
okay the the concept of the breeder
packs is more more addressed to
to to Big breed or two breeders and I'm
a big Growers that want to make a big
selection to find that really really
outstanding plan to to keep us a cloning
and keep for years
these people that
that wants to go into one of our
strained
as much as Steep and wide as possible
and
in in the bigger pack it's each pack
it's a strain is different so it's
pretty pack is different
but when I try to to offer is
a seat from the different
baselines
that represent the strain
okay
for example in the case of the Panama
breeder Pass movie to put a good
that the grower can initially find good
seats from the Panama Green from the
Panama of the red pink pistil
from the latest job we have done with
The Strain coming from the Panama
goddess
Etc with China with different lines they
are
cautions one half
slightly different or pain
the other different slightly different
effects
so if you for example want to or in the
Pakistani truck which is the
the Pakistan there has been used more in
the industry to produce colorful hybrids
whatever they name they want to put on
it but I know it's basically
[Music]
it's so easy to to
because this is the abiental plans you
working 15 years this like recognize one
one of my daughters
and for example if you want to read with
Pakistani dragons in a more proper way
you take the breeder pack and you mean
from the green line I focus to find the
best from the green
this is the the best purple for their
pants this is the black one very red
phenotype and the colorful ones
Etc and depending of the reproduction we
have done and what have been the most
remarkable
plants then I
make up either pack
that provides the best from the last
breathing step usually
what a great answer so there we go guys
if you want to do the big Fino hunt you
know where to look so we're now on to
our final quick fire questions which we
ask all breeders at the end of the
interview so the first question I wanted
to ask you was if you could go back 10
years and give yourself some advice
relating to cannabis what would you tell
yourself
foreign
10 years ago
I believe everything how it is
yeah that was the Beautiful Life
oh that's poetic I love it
the next question we ask yes is what is
the single most memorable bit of
cannabis you ever smoked be it flower
hash whatever it is what's the most
memorable for you
oh
the man was memorable there
the most memorable the cherries in my
memory a lot is The Nepalese Commando
was one of the Freeland races I grew
it was a flower with purple pinkish hues
it was such a delicate plan that
follower with its delicate call us
and you smell like wild strawberry and
when you smoke it it was in fence I like
being in Nepal
why we were we were tiles
uh and they say my God this way foreign
incredible trippy then other strains I
miss a lot are the
the the the the funny Mexican effects
that make you laugh with your friends
like a bit like the new California
that is maybe your
smile and live here more I missed this
this kind of effects you're very settled
on finding it today in today's week
[Music]
or other strain I smoke
burying the resting purpose sativas in
Northern Laos
in bandian
or that was very strong and unique
I never try anything like this
and then I smoke work and when I was in
North Sumatra
a
in a
orangutan Reserve
you know we had to there they would like
to try the the
the
actual is how we call it the Americans I
guess the football into everything but
it was in in it was black
and it was just
it was true and I haven't smoked in a
few weeks it was on holidays and if I
was there in
in the dark in the jungle and one of the
that was traveling with her with a group
uh
got some of the of the local wheat from
from northern Sumatra from from
and they were
a black fermented thing that almost had
no brags and it was only leaf and sticks
where we make one or two years high and
I wish I live in between three and four
and he was
extremely extremely strong
if you grow this properly with good
flour
and you let it ripe because the the
flower will smuggles and ripe
the I think the
is one of the strongest races
I come I have experienced them in
Northern Sumatra
I know that I I cherish
from from the commercial strains
the first Maple Leaf not the smell like
babysit
incredible
their pins
and of course the best hybrid is from
maybe from the 90s
uh
jachter is a masterpiece
and the Hawaiian has he was incredible
only try once but
it was
they're probably one of the most trippy
and entropy
and best hybrid from from Neville
um the Cali means the old Kali means
from serious and Simon it was a
spectacular
it was a spec member
um
yes one Philippine Kaling had a
from Cordillera Centralia that tastes
like I just mean it was purple and there
is like like Jasmine
these are probably
the the land races and Commercial
strains that
the Richer is more and had more impact
in me
fantastic what a awesome list you've got
there so the next question I wanted to
know was if you were gonna get dropped
off on a desert island and you could
only take three strains with you for the
rest of time what three strains are you
gonna take with you
foreign
dominant selection love it love it okay
so have you ever had a strain where all
your friends are telling you about it
you're getting very excited to try it
and then it finally comes time to try it
you do and you feel like this isn't very
good at all it's quite disappointing
yeah it happens
me very frequently without anniversaries
to be honest with the gg4
all these cookies
yeah look good and
um look very good but
doesn't tell me anything
for yeah I like this is the kind of
smoke that I like to smoke I smoke in
the afternoon
and yeah people is crazy about this
about all these with some but honestly
like you can only smoke
to give you an example I will take the
new value on your back
fantastic so the final question for our
chat today if you could go back in time
any place any point in history to
collect some seeds where would you go
and what seeds would you collect
I I
I would go to to Thailand in the 70s
together through Thai stick
Colombia in this life I already have but
yes definitely I will go to Colombia I
will go to
to get the Finish
Colombia's from the 60s and 70s
um
before all the mess
and the wars in afghanist from the 60s
and the 70s
and yes I think the monster is still
alive
yeah there's especially a nice in Asia
in Africa where where he was really um
all to have it
there you go good news yeah yeah Mr
positive is it's amazing it was the time
to to see people like erasmine if from
India language exchange because
I'm so active and they they should be
the ones that to do to do this and
another Western man the Western man even
if he goes to Thailand or or Africa or
India is not going to get the best
you know only only the locals I'm from
from Valencia you're only going to read
the best paella in the world if you are
from from Valencia and your grandma
cookies for you is is the same you
cannot pretend to go to any place and
and come and come back with the best so
it's it's super interesting it's finally
there was the moment that the the people
of the the the people from the
traditional
the traditional farmers and people from
those countries start to understand the
value and the importance of the
preservation of the of their their game
pools because
there are very uniquely there with many
other traditional life who are lifestyle
and who can do is better than the local
people
and who should do it ethically a morally
others first than them
so it's amazing what that what he's
doing and that's why if the races we are
trying to to support the world uh the
Indian Landry Saints are doing to to
document
the land races of of the countries that
have more and and showing us that there
are still so many left
um and there are still so many things in
cannabis to discover
that that shows the same thing
so yes that's why I like to support the
people I like him I'm
extremely excited but with we everybody
with every project they do
um
[Music]
and yes I think the future already is
there now that the legalization is
coming to to all these countries that
people try to empower their local
strains uh and try to preserve what we
have left
and then try to to to develop near
strains
something really new
what a fantastic answer so I think that
just about brings us to the end of the
episode today were there any comments or
shout outs you wanted to make
nah
that I love you everyone
I love you people
I really appreciate it
this reporter
two Aces I has been
some years it has not been very easy
well they have many ups and downs
it has been very hard we have had to
sacrifice many things
but we did it because we love it we
because we won't tell because it was so
passion
and we wanted to contribute with
something
[Music]
um
I really appreciate how
how the our genetic symbolic some
Growers are
how happy
makes people how happy this this make it
this makes me feel
is a really beautiful thing and it's
very creative
and there's a lot of love involved
so yes this industry is not easy
I probably I never did all the things
always correctly I'm not it's just a
human I'm just
but I just try to be as much school
person as I can be and give the best of
of me
in my work
and this is this without you it will
never happen
so thank you very much
love
fantastic so again thank you so much for
coming on the show giving us all the
history all the knowledge from the land
race preserver himself to be a base
genetics thank you so much again
thank you so much has been a pleasure to
start the spring this beautiful day with
you
and there you have it friends a
fantastic episode with doobie of AC
thank you so much dude for taking the
time to come on the show and share all
your knowledge with us we're incredibly
appreciative
[Music]
likewise we're incredibly appreciative
of our sponsors as always
go check out see you here now they have
a wide variety of both modern and more
land race type lines
anything a seed addict could desire
they're going to be able to help you out
they've got all the top quality breeders
and a guarantee on satisfaction at the
end of the Harvest not just on
germination why would you go anywhere
else there might pick go check them out
likewise you need to stop on by our
friends at coppet biological systems
with the largest range of predator mites
and other natural enemies in the game be
sure to check out their ultimate a
predator might breeding sachet for all
your Thrift spider mite and russet my
issues all while specifically formulated
the maximum release rates in a cannabis
production climate
and next up who could forget our friends
at promix they're here to help you get
the best crop possible check out the
pro-mix connect mycorrhizal inoculant to
ensure that your crop is productive
resinous dense flavorful all the things
you want we know microrize is important
the god Jeff lowefield told us what more
do I need to say guys pro-mix connect
fantastic product go check it out
finally the patreon gang you guys know
it I love you you are the lifeblood of
the show and you get access to episodes
early as well as bonus unheard content
so if you want to be a part of the club
go check out
www.patreon.com forward slash the
podcast The Early Access bonus content
giveaways and so much more
so there we have it guys thanks for
hanging around to the end
appreciate you all as always
[Music]
this is heavy day signing out from the
upside down libraries
[Music]