foreign
[Music]
welcome back my friends for another
episode of the podcast the Cannabis
podcast for budding enthusiasts as
always you're joined by your boy heavy
days here from the upside down library
and we are hugely appreciative of our
fantastic sponsors you know them and
love them she's here now number one seed
bank in America not just a guarantee on
germination guarantee on satisfaction if
you don't like it at the end of The Grow
hit them up they will make it right they
will sort you out why would you go with
someone who doesn't have such a
guarantee if you're in the UK though hit
up our buddies at simply souvenirs with
a hand selected range of Boutique
breeders and smoking apparatuses and
apparel simply souvenirs offers some of
the best customer service in the game
you will absolutely be looked after well
by our friends there please check them
out in the UK international and local UK
breeders huge thank you to Simply
souvenirs
likewise huge shout out to our friends
at cope at biological systems for all
the best predators and predation
technology in the game you have to check
out copit and their products if you've
got aphids get the athlete RM if you've
got spider bites get the spydex vital
how many times we gotta say it guys a
clean garden is Next to Godliness what
more could you want than Peace of Mind
knowing that your plans are Pest and
pathogen free check them out Copic
biological thank you so much guys
[Music]
huge shout out to our friends at Paul
sensors if you've got one room three
rooms multi-state facilities you need
pulse sensors the reality is there's
many variables that can hold your crop
back and you may not even be aware
they're not optimized get yourself a
pulse sensor dial in your parameters
increase yield resin flavor all the
information at your fingertips check it
out guys pulse sensors get serious get a
pulse
oh
shout out to the crew at purple who
create the purple Pro a modular handheld
unit capable of giving you accurate
flour and concentrate cannabinoid tests
from THC to CBD water content water
activity and more grab yourself a purple
Pro guys they were kind enough to send
me one I've been playing with it it's
fun I think you guys will like it
[Music]
and last but not least the patreon gang
thank you so much for your support you
are the lifeblood of the show we could
not make episodes without the support of
the patreon gang we are hugely grateful
if you want to help support the show get
access to early content unheard
interviews exclusive patreon early
episodes as well as monthly genetic
giveaways check out the patreon
www.patreon.com the podcast
huge shout out to the patreon guys
[Music]
all right all right all right welcome on
back friends for part two
the man himself Tom Hill
here to talk all things Hayes
deep chunk
x18
pintar could so much more
thanks for coming back to check out the
second part
thank you
so without further delay
[Music]
let's get into it
so let's go back a bit you uh you moved
to the neighborhood and you started
getting exposed to a lot of the strains
we've talked about what was the progress
like before you started to do your own
open pollinations or did it happen
immediately
uh yeah no it didn't happen immediately
you know we were reading like uh
Rob Clark you know marijuana pot is was
the one you know that we were reading
back then and it's a great great great
book you know Timeless uh a real gem
uh but and and he would give you hints
you know about not backing yourself into
any Corners with your with your
selection you and and you give examples
of heterosis and stuff about you know
how how you know F1 was great for this
grower but in the next year there's a
few less and then eventually drove this
you know line into the ground and he
would give you examples of that in that
book and uh you know because and and and
and and speak of how this guy
inadvertently you know bred himself
backed himself into a corner and I can
you know so you could you could if you
could if you could hear that message
you know that he was trying to tell you
back then you know for for me first came
male pollen mixes was the big one okay
I'm not gonna I'm not even gonna try to
select a male here because I don't want
to I don't want to lose something that's
special
and at the time something you can't even
really test for because you know you're
talking about smoke right how do I know
which one of these [ __ ] which one of
these males uh it smokes best you know
and uh I mean I'm not actually gonna
smoke and that's what Rob suggested he
said you know dry out a bag and see
which one disappears first
you know which is what I do with my
females but I'm not going to do that
with my males I'm just going to make a
[ __ ] male pollen mix and not back
myself into any corners and then
eventually you know a couple you know
after thinking about it more you'll
you'll end up at open pollination before
too long for that reason it's a it's a
way to make sure that you when you have
something you like it you know that you
don't [ __ ] it up just let let all the
pollen all the girls fly and then after
that you can [ __ ] around all you want
with more intensive breeding
yeah nice and I mean you've spoken
fondly about Rob Clark he's a phenomenal
source of information and a Pioneer I
was interested were there any other sort
of gurus breeders or other sources of
knowledge you hold in higher Steam
yeah
yeah I know
um gosh
any of them that they're
okay
any of them they can go out on a limb
and and voice something new when they
might be wrong you know
uh guys like Hive and and uh DJ Shore
you know he's got some bizarre theories
DJ Short does and uh you know and I
admire them for putting them out there
when uh you know
possible that people are going to laugh
at you
you know there's there's nothing I don't
respect anything higher than that people
that are willing to uh
you know say something that might sound
bizarre to a lot of others but you know
just just pure observation and and being
able to Bounce It Off people you know if
you don't say [ __ ] about what you're
thinking you know we're not going to get
very far are we
um and so I admire people that come
forward with you know bizarre new uh
theories and such
yeah a lot of those people you just
mentioned uh equally people I hold in
high esteem I'm interested now though
you mentioned it have you got any what
you would describe as bizarre
observations of your own
[Laughter]
um
sure I mean who doesn't I still suspect
these damn rents are where it's at you
know as big hire somebody back then said
it might have been spoken breeders to
you or somebody
but uh hey those might be the ones you
want
um just because you know so many times
this this best plan is is you know just
lacking in in in growth you know what
you want to see in in the growth of a
plant it turns out to be the best plant
but can you low yielding thing
so you know I kind of sometimes you'll
see these ones you know and they just
for a minute for for brief seconds you
know they can't bed dry you know but
then they they'll grow out of it and you
know and do fine but it's almost like a
regular environment is it freaks them
out you know uh these ones these ones
I've always I always like to keep an eye
on
they often they often are exceptional
one of the ones that won that uh you
mentioned that I see mag uh Cannabis Cup
or whatever 420 cup it was a plant like
that too
it's just happened so many times that I
always keep an eye on these ones that
are kind of
this one's you know kind of freaky doing
its own thing over here what's going on
but they'll often end up they'll often
surprise you and be kick ass you know
and it's never the plant that I always
say your favorite plant like changes
three or four times during the course of
a season you know
uh you know during gross you'll say oh
this one so I can kicking ass that's my
favorite plant as you enter buddy and
your favorite pal this one look at what
this one's doing oh this you know
it keeps changing changing changing
looks smell resin resin you know and
then it changes one more time and by the
end that's when it hits the pipe and
that's the that's the final that's the
final say
you know
yeah I certainly have noticed that
myself a few times as well
it's a bit of a random sidestep question
but I'm curious to know what are you
growing this year
oh a bunch of popular crap or not even
popular just you know same stuff that
other people are you know growing in the
neighborhood a big variety of stuff I
have that that gelato 33 and that I
really liked
um I like the high off of it I won't lie
you know that's a good cerebral smoke
any other notable ones that you've been
impressed by
well there's a few that are coming in
now one Mendo fuel or something
uh that I haven't smoked yet it's still
uh it's just coming off the line uh
the [ __ ] that one I haven't even
harvested yet
there's a few of them that still need to
come in none of them are super
impressive from what I can see so far I
would say
and that's a drag
yeah
but they were free
[Music]
while we're talking about runs is that
sort of one of the reasons why you like
to grow from seed because you see those
runs pop up whereas with clone you know
you don't
all right but I've been going where I've
been going from clone for a long time
for for production you know but I I love
I love uh growing from seed because you
never know what you're going to find
it's like fishing isn't it
um you know you don't know what you're
gonna bring it up
yeah definitely well I mean let's let's
go back uh to when you know you're
learning the ropes and you're first
starting to do the open pollinations
with these lines which of these lines
really you know uh how should I say took
your heart first you know was it the
Deep chunk was it the x18 which one
really first captivated you
yeah it was deep chunk by far was my
favorite for years and years and years
um you know
I couldn't very well grow even Hayes
commercially you know it just wasn't
even an option
um all through those years but deep deep
chunk did exactly what I wanted it to do
you know produce well in in low light
conditions and um and it was really good
smoke I liked it cerebral smoke had very
uniform pounds you know that that plant
breeds true is the driven snow
um and so it turned out real very
consistent product for for decades for
me
yeah and when did the idea of Crossing
it to Hayes come into your mind
well probably after I read Rob Clark's
marijuana botany
um you know right away and that you know
as soon as I had that Haze and and knew
how good it was that that was the plan
kind of thing
so and what was it like when you first
grew those out the F1 were you surprised
by what you saw or it was all pretty
much what you expected
I pretended I've never really I've never
grown the F1 commercially you know I was
uh back then uh the Deep chunk was it
was so good and giving what I wanted for
what I was doing you know but I was
trying to move weight
and uh it was predictable and easy and I
knew that Crossing out to that [ __ ]
14 to six week plan you know was gonna
have me into the end of November or
something here into the rains and stuff
so I didn't I wasn't looking to cross it
out uh it wasn't looking to cross them
together so much for production as I was
for my own head
yeah okay sure that's completely
understandable and I mean you've got
some other notable F1 hybrids like
particularly the [ __ ] Creek where you
cross the pine tar to the Deep chunk I
know that um you know that was one that
seems to get a few mentions online did
you did you like what you were able to
see from those F1 hybrids and would you
consider doing other F1 hybrids with
your lines
um you know I was just going for that
you know for that recombination
generation thing that we were talking
about before I was I was trying to uh
you know create something something not
not seen in either line by get by
getting in into that that was just
rightfully to those Generations uh and
and that was just Remnant seed that I
had sent in
um
but I never really continued on with it
much much after that I haven't done a
bunch of F2 searches through the through
them I still have f2c that I made which
was the point and and most of those f1s
were just uh Remnant seed that I passed
out along the way to what I wanted to
put away
yeah okay yeah so you're stocking up so
do you have any plans to get into those
or you just the other stuff is more
interesting right now
well right now I think you know uh the
haze is on the list
um and the and Andy chunk because it's
been I think his last reproduction
was 09 or something on both of those
and you know it's time to do a germ test
I'm probably flirting with with you know
something below 60 on what I have here
so that's kind of my next my next plan
is to do those things outside open
pollination time again
but I bet I'll probably make a point of
saving uh clones from the from the haze
a portion of that and try to find a good
one
yeah brilliant and do you feel like open
pollination captures everything in the
sense that have you noticed any
variation over time in any of the lines
you've done with open pollination or do
you feel like it does really just
capture the whole thing
well everything everything goes downhill
uh you know
at a fast pace or a slow pace and open
pollination is a way to make that slow
and and you know something's not going
to stay killer forever if you keep
reading with it you know breeding is is
both you know what how we have such
great cannabis and it's and it's also
why we have such bad cannabis or you
know or lines that have just been driven
into the ground you know
uh that's a lot of I think probably
what's happened everywhere in Thailand
in India you know all these places
you're like where is this great where is
this great [ __ ] from the old days man
well uh you know the the great spots
only stay good for this moment in time
you know if it's a moving Target man
yeah some wise words there and while
we're on the topic of it Thailand
recently legalized cannabis any thoughts
on that ever wanted to go there set up
shop over there
no I would say no I like um I like
southeast Asia but
um you know the language barrier there
is something that'll never be gotten
over uh with me anyway you know
so it's it's the other for me you know
for sure it represents something that's
true that's true that's too mysterious
for me I'm not that adventurous
yeah I feel you I feel you it's not too
far for me and yeah it also still seems
like a a big jump but just to loop back
you know obviously you know him for
doing open pollinations but you've done
some F1 hybrids and a focal discussion
point of the show is around selecting
males and I was curious to know do you
have any thoughts on selecting males do
you think it's just a fraught Adventure
given your preference for open
pollination and if not do you think
there are any traits that are associated
with a better male because I guess
that's one of the common things we
discuss like you know how do you select
a male what's your thoughts on the
subject
well resin you know
um if you have resinous mail uh that's
that's worth something more than a
non-residence male I think I used to I
used to go and and feel the stems of
page plants if I was going to try to do
a you know a half sib uh Cross or
something I would you know if I was
gonna try to get a a group of males out
of a big population and do some more
intensive breeding I used to whittle
them down by whether or not their their
stocks were sticky and veg because a
good portion of them are
um and uh and you can smell them and and
know that that's oh and here's this
here's this you know kind of a tie
profile that I'm after
yeah okay interesting and I mean I'm
curious what sort of terpene profiles do
you gravitate towards in general
rotten meat
[Laughter]
you know I was worried that you were
going to ask me how you know how does
one taste like that my neighbor brought
over and that's like what I that was my
first impression this thing [ __ ] take
like rotten meat man not rotten fruit
but rotten meat like this this is a
pretty foul you know unpleasant odor if
it wasn't cannabis
um so I I you know I like that one and
there was there's been a lot of like uh
Jamaicans and stuff like that that kind
of had this weird uh smell that uh
flavor and stuff that were really
bizarre but that's one that I like I'm
not kidding you know they're kind of a
rotten fruit rotten meat you know that
that that area in there
um
citrusy stuff I like to tie the Thai
um you know tends to tends to wane as it
stores you know you know the like when I
when I grew that that chocolate tie that
we had grown out on my friend's rooftop
there and it was like oh this this
doesn't smell at all like the brown tie
Bud that we had smoked you know of the
parent
it's entirely different it's kind of
citrusy and and uh you know a totally
different thing if you and then if you
store it and all that stuff kind of
oxidizes and stuff feels you'll get some
really more complex uh flavors and such
out of it but you know and I suspect
with Haze too I would say but you know
when I find a good Haze I
unfortunately don't have it or any
around when it but you know I'm still
smoking that [ __ ] gone while it's still
green because you just you don't reach
for anything else
I mean in more recent times there's been
a lot of discussion around the uh usage
and the benefits associated with an
actual curing phase and I guess most
notably one of the big companies in
California and now in other states like
Florida and a few others the jungle boys
they their owner Ivan he famously came
out and said they don't cure their weed
at all they think it's best as soon as
it's harvest like as soon as it's dry
and smokable that's when it's best would
you say that you think that's incorrect
or do you think it's strain dependent
what's your take on a cure
yeah um the everything's going to be
different you know
um several you know modern plants will
probably be best when they're relatively
fresh and
well you know there's a bunch of them
that might get better with age you know
I think it's going to be different from
Individual to individual for sure
yeah interesting and with Hayes are
there any notable changes that take
place with the Cure like obviously the
color changes how does the effects
change over time
I wouldn't know I smoked that [ __ ] when
it's fresh until it's gone gone
[Laughter]
all right but recently I have seen
people that you know have grown some of
it out and
um and we're just kind of meh about this
one and you know kind of put it in their
closet you know when it was fresh
and then they'll break it out months
later and and remember this plant being
kind of meh and just to have it and be
incredible months and months later after
it sits around and oxidizes them and
reveals something that was you know
there all the time lurking underneath
once the main you know profile kind of
dissipates what's lying underneath and
settle it at first up and it's like
really really unique and beautiful and
that's what Ty was for me and and the
brown Hawaiian and stuff and Jamaican
you know none of these uh
stuff that that we were getting in
Imports back then was fresh you know it
all it all had months
um and and [ __ ] gets really interesting
when when it when it has that but you
know if you only have a pound of it or
something you're and it's the best thing
you know by far you're just gonna go
through it you know yeah you're gonna
get to that stage to realize it
yeah definitely definitely
let me give you a hypothetical right
you've just been hired to uh consult for
a Thai company and they say look we've
got like this facility we can do outdoor
we can do indoor we can do whatever you
tell us what to do what do you think we
should do what would you say would would
you say that they should grow land race
stuff are you going to tell a modern how
would you help them
haha in Thailand yeah I really liked it
too I liked it what they're doing there
you know good for them it's pretty
ballsy in that area of the world you
know
I would go on a gene pool search they're
locally you know go on germ plasm hunt
there locally and try to turn up
something that was that was you know
worth it worth the name
of how good that stuff can really be
um I I have my doubts that uh
the stuff that they're working with you
know it's probably some evaluation some
loud stuff or something that's kind of
mediocre as Ty became it in the end
there but I I want to believe that the
old seed is still there and I would go
on a hunt for it you know
but hire a bunch of hookers and and
tuk-tuk drivers it's up there somebody
and Uncle Bill's the attic you know the
old seeds has to be around somewhere I
wouldn't even pass go until I found
something worth talking about and I kind
of suspect they didn't wait for that
I love it yeah it would be really cool
to see like some uh tewa land race Thai
stuff coming out I think I think there's
probably gonna realistically end up
being a mix of both right because you
know USA hybrids are a popular worldwide
no doubt about that but um that's really
interesting to to hear that that you
would be Keen to do that that's really
cool just to take us back to the the
breeding sort of questions from um and I
wanted to ask you a lot of people talk
about selecting a male around this sort
of Paradigm of hemp trait versus drug
trade and like you know just to give you
a common example they'll say the really
fast flowering male that wants to put
out ball sacks first that's like a hemp
trait Associated mail like it's probably
not your best male whereas we've heard
earlier that like you're not going to
Cull that male you keep it around
because it's got something to offer
which is interesting so I'm curious to
know do you buy into the hemp trade drug
trade Paradigm or do you think like
they're all drug trade really
that those traits are inherited
separately and um and that's why I don't
call them
but yeah you know yeah uh that's a
correlation that I that I that I don't
believe you know I've had early plants
uh uh that were and they were very high
in potency
um so
I wouldn't I wouldn't make that
Association I wouldn't bet on it pal I
guess would be my answer to that man I'm
not buying it I'm trait
um yeah no the the I I believe those
those characters to be inherited
separately
yeah cool that's an interesting answer
okay so what sort of males do you like
besides resinous one is there any sort
of profile you like or it's just
independent and each strain is its own
thing
yeah I don't I don't try to even judge
them too much I I just go for numbers
when it comes to males I have for you
know decades too um I've always been a
big fan of the male pollen mix
and and you know resin you know you know
resins were something to me
you know
but other than that I I really I can't
think of anything else that I would even
dare to try to place importance on okay
well I mean while we're talking about
importance do you have a sort of like a
hierarchy of traits you like to breed
for and I guess notably someone like DJ
Short has sort of always commonly said
everything is secondary to the effect so
he's sort of saying like I don't care
what it looks like if the effect is good
then that's it do you feel like oh you
know you've got to sort of like balance
different aspects it's got a yield Okay
blah blah blah where do you fall on that
one with your trait hierarchy
well you know um it's uh it's like I
said before your favorite's gonna change
several times you know throughout that
cycle and then once more at the end when
you smoke it when it's in the pipe your
favorite changes again every time
um and that's the most important thing
but you should be you should be growing
and breeding your favorites
um
I'd like to see a plant that grows well
and stuff like that but but I'll trade
all that for something that's better
smoke and and that's why you know that's
I think the only thing you can really
say is your favorite right so yeah I
agree with DJ on that
uh you know I'll judge other plans uh
certainly like when I'm when I'm [ __ ]
counting or calling clone material from
growing in gaps or something you know
like I despise a plant that can't hold
itself up you know I you know I have a
bunch of other criteria that I'm very
picky about and such but when it comes
to breeding cheat you know
um you know if you're if you're just
talking about the average guy you know I
hope that they're breeding for the best
smoke
um I don't give a [ __ ] about anything
else I don't think anybody else should
either
I agree and I wanted to touch on the x18
specifically because I think out of your
strains it's known for having a very
unique flavor profile as well as being
like a fairly quality Pakistani all
round I was always interested you know
the Apple phenotype is sort of
referenced here and there and it it's
like an interesting flavor because it's
not really apparent in many modern
strains the Apple flavor what's x18 like
to you how do you describe it and what
are your what are you fond of about it
it's one of the ones that still you know
that still survive of what it was like
you know in the old days that's that
plant's been grown here in this
neighborhood where I'm sitting right now
for you know since the early or mid 80s
or something I guess it's
um
it's a very old and and Divergent and
not related to anything that's you know
that's going around in the in the modern
gene pool for the most part you know
so it's Unique in that way it's
different you know it's not it's not
gonna rip your [ __ ] head off like uh
you know like some of the OG so it would
or something
um but it's certainly unique and um and
that's where something you know you know
uh to a lot of people for something to
me because you know that's what that's
how you get that you know transgressive
segregation is you know you need plants
that are Divergent from each other it's
not going to happen when you're breeding
brother to sister or something
yeah definitely and I mean to me one of
the things I like about your offerings
is that there's sort of a few pakistanis
in the mix with the pine tar cool Shaw
so I always got the impression Pakistani
sort of didn't get enough credit because
they've got that real cerebral aspect to
the Indica High which really underrated
in my opinion have you been like a big
fan of the pakistanis do you do you
favor them or where do you sit on it
yes and I you know for the exact same
reason I think that you know a lot of
the pakistanis have probably likely been
outcrossed to some really cerebral
Indian
at some point in the distant past you
know
um and uh I also do you find them more
cerebral than a lot of certainly than
most of the Afghans uh that I've come
across are more of a sleepy you know
dreary lethargic High
whereas the pakis or the pakistanis are
are you know much more cerebral and up
which which I've always liked I always
like I'm not that's what I'm looking for
and pretty much everything that I smoke
yeah it's interesting that like for the
longest time I thought you must have
been like a real Indica head because
like on paper it seems like there's
these Indica offerings but like it's
more the cerebral stuff you like it's uh
sort of ironic
though those are the ones that I capped
anyway yeah yeah
um like there's a lot of you know people
you know like like this you know purple
Oracle and some of some of these old
broad leaves from up here and stop by
for me they just make me sleepy and um
and yeah it's not it's not where I'm at
what is what's your thoughts on the
Oracle it's got a really big rise in
popularity over the past years have you
grown it and what do you think the
genetics are
oh we used to grow it we used to grow it
uh quite a bit you know some I don't
know 20 years ago or something
um that's a pretty old one that's been
around forever and uh it's I I thought I
thought I remember it coming off of
Salmon Creek or somewhere up in there up
in Humboldt but I'm not sure I think it
was introduced to me as like a salmon
Creeks version of the monkey balls or
something you know the old you know the
DC okay it was there broadly but they're
real flavorful got a nice grape flavor
um it breeds really well but it's you
know until it's relatively homozygous
and Crosses out well
um to a lot of stuff
and uh but but yeah it makes me sleepy I
smoked that stuff and it's just kind of
it's not not very potent and it kind of
makes me sleepy it didn't float my boat
um you know so I stopped growing it
yeah okay interesting interesting and uh
we had a lot of listeners uh chime in
that were hoping to hear about and I
noticed this myself that DNA for a while
was offering the x18 what was the
backstory behind that
hmm
um I think it was on one of the uh
forums or something yeah they just
caught up with me I don't remember what
happened I think I sent him a bunch of
pollen and some seeds or something
though and they did some crosses and may
have done some reproduction I don't I
don't really know but I do remember it
was like the only people that I ever
seen any pollen out to you know because
they were into it and I was like yeah
well okay I just happened to have a you
know big bindle of pollen right here but
you know because I was you know doing
some breeding with it myself at the time
I think they did some crosses originally
um and and you know and I probably sent
him seed as well
um so I didn't really follow it but I I
know that did happen okay cool I guess
like you're sort of confirming it's like
it's authentic it's not just like random
seed they found yeah I would I I would
hope not I don't see why it would be I
did have you know I did send them a
package at one point way back when
yeah cool interesting okay okay so
what would your advice be for a new
breeder who's looking to get into it a
lot of people talk these days about how
it's also a poly hybrid that you know
like we're not getting anywhere with it
how can someone like get their toes wet
while also actually progressing towards
something from your point of view
well I mean Slammer you know you develop
a library of your favorite things and
keep them separate and you know and and
try to cross together things that are
the most far apart from each other the
most Divergent you know and try to get
into these recombination generations and
find something unique and extreme
you know is is basically where all
breeding starts
um
that's Crown zero that's what I would do
and and make it be something that you
like
forget about what you think people are
gonna like just focus on what you
actually honestly like and and you know
that way you're more likely to not not
lose it
and um and that's that's what's really
worth something I think
trust your own taste and and uh just you
know do your own thing and if it's you
know if other people agree with that
then
you know you'll you'll you'll be a
winner
yeah beautiful stuff I wonder what do
you think would be a good place to start
genetics wise out of Southeast Asia do
you think just go for Thai
no I think that
um
you know there's there's a lot of places
around there I would just scour that
whole that whole area including you know
places like Reunion Island and stuff and
and you know but uh Hawaii's probably
totally different today they're probably
growing white runts and stuff out there
now but um but there's probably some
Pockets you know over over there in in
that in that region that still have some
really good stuff you know uh Vietnam
even places like this that it probably
all came you know from [ __ ] and Ty but
uh
uh you know it held on a little better
while the tide got bred into the ground
that would that would be a rich hunting
ground for me I might you know I don't
know what things are like in Jamaica
anymore
um
Colombia maybe you know some of some of
the more Southern parts of Mexico and
the Caribbean side there might be some
good stuff down in there
but I don't know you know
I do know I smoke some kick-ass
Colombian in Costa Rica you know not you
know not too many decades ago uh late
90s around around you know around 2000
or something I smoked some really nice
Colombian uh that this guy had in Costa
Rica
uh that was extremely cerebral and very
auditory and
excellent so you know I still have hope
that there's good [ __ ] in all these
places and you know hopefully they turn
up from time to time
you gotta trust that the cream's gonna
rise to the top and if they're good
they'll probably stick around
but people do appreciate them these days
more it seems like
yeah I think Colombians are certainly on
the rise at the moment they've been a
focal discussion point I I would love to
see more in circulation do you have any
Colombian seed stock
no I don't
just uh adjust the haze is the only
narrow the tropical that I that I have
ever that I'm growing there's some stuff
in neighborhood like I said that
Hawaiian and you know you probably try
that stuff out but I've smoked some of
it from the guy and
I'll stick with A's
do you ever like try to search out
certain seed stock or are you more sort
of wait for it to come to you
yeah I know I have what I have and
that's probably all I'm ever gonna you
know bother to reproduce I enjoy you
know I enjoy clowns whatever the
neighbors are going it's always exciting
to smoke
but I don't think I would I don't think
I'm reading new stuff is not really in
the cards occasionally a plaque comes
along that you know that I really like
and and the market stops agreeing with
me and I know that I'll probably not be
growing it you know for very much longer
and I'll do like a quick back Crossing
you know stay on it and put some seed
away of it you know like I did that with
the Mendo docs OG cut that I really like
because it grows so well and adapt but
the market got burned out on it and then
everybody [ __ ] canned it and I was like
well but wait wait this is a good plan
forget about your taste you know about
wanting something new forget you're
burned out on it that's a good plan guys
and then so I'll do a quick you know you
know either shelf it or do a quick back
cross program and make sure to you know
try to save stuff that I like that I
think to that the markets gets sick up
and and and uh we'll probably come
around back around too at a later date
Ah that's interesting what plans have
you solved out of curiosity I guess it's
a reflection of what you think's good
yeah well I felt that one we just
mentioned the docks and that was a
couple of years ago
um I'm still growing it by clone but the
market has certainly turned tower on and
we shut it down everybody's throat for
probably a decade here it probably you
know one of the most popular ones that
that people were growing in hoops for
for a long long time the market was so
saturated that the buyer said nah no
more of that you know so people stopped
growing it but but I still am [ __ ] them
I still grew it just because I like that
I like the way the plant grows and
produces and it's kind of it's got a
good high you know it takes off a lot of
boxes you know no it's not the original
this or that but here's a plant that
does what it does really well
um you know comes in early all that [ __ ]
you know it's a Grower's dream uh
interesting and when you when you back
cross something do you have any
particular thoughts on what sort of
pollen donor you use like for example
some people say use a pollen donut
that's very different to the planetary
Crossing too just because it's easy to
phenotypically like curl those plants
out in the F1 do you have any thoughts
like that
I would use something that yeah that you
also like and I wouldn't have any I
wouldn't have any criteria after that
um it depends what you're doing if
you're like trying to isolate some trait
and and you know that would what you
just said would be you would do in a
back Crossing scheme you you know
something that would be easily easily to
know that you know it's not coming from
this parent it's coming from this parent
you know if they're two plants of the
donor parent is is very Divergent from
the recurrent parent then you're gonna
easily you know separate And Trades from
each parent but that but that's never
like my I use that Crossing just as a
dirty quick way to keep this this pool
of genetics
I love the dirty quick way okay if I
guess that's good yeah
that yeah that's what it is you know I
mean but some people like you know get a
bit sort of how can I say it they take
issue with s1s and they would say oh bx1
is way better do you have any issues
with this ones or you think like no
they're good they do what I needed to do
yeah yeah I have no problem with with
selfie implants
um but depends what you want you know
but it's there's no inherent uh you know
bad thing about it or problem with it or
argument against it if you're trying to
you know capture something as quickly
and it's dirty dirtily as possible you
you would sell but
um you know and you know you boom over
one generation now I can store the seeds
and and readdress it at some later date
you know
uh well you know why why take what'd you
say first generation back cross versus
BC ones you say that takes about one two
three you know it takes a few
Generations
um there's no extra points for taking
longer to get to the same place
yeah definitely definitely I've thought
that I mean you're sort of hovering
around the idea of like some people
would use that same analogy to say we
should be using like labs to help us
analyze things do you feel like there's
any need to use like high-tech lab stuff
what's your thoughts on labs
this is going to be a tough one in a
perfect world like you know I mean if I
have my own I I might use it a little
bit but uh I wouldn't rely on I would
I'd proceed with caution let's say you
know I I
most Labs you know a guy had some weeds
sends it to three labs and uh whatever
one tells him he has the highest THC
this is his favorite lab that he goes to
from now on Labs know this and they
inflate numbers these are some of the
shiftiest [ __ ] in the whole in
the whole industry right now and uh I I
wouldn't I wouldn't rely on the
information
um too much
and I
the other you know
you know because it because it's you
know it's kind of a scam you know and
the labs know this they want to make
money they're going to kick out these
high numbers for you you know so they
have a giant customer base it's a
business don't kid yourself these these
guys are can be Shifty too
um so I don't trust it for that reason
and uh and and more you know [ __ ] you
know we could be wrong about you know
about this being such an important deal
you know high THC or something we could
be entirely wrong about that there could
be giant pieces of the puzzle that are
still missing and um I you know I still
think that the first bag that disappears
out of the group of your samples that's
the best weed and I don't care what a
lab says especially if there's room for
human error and you know uh that's like
asking somebody else you know what you
should smoke you know I mean I think
that's a judgment that you should make
in the old-fashioned way and be very
leery about how I mean these numbers
drive your drive your selections
so we're this is like a really
interesting discussion point because a
lot of guests end up discussing this and
how the market is being led too much by
numbers and I guess when I think about
it
the issue that I see is that a lot of
the really hardcore smokers and Growers
are very aware of this but it's it's
largely speaking the 80 of the Casual
consumer base so to speak that are
driving a lot of the decisions and
purchases through what is seemingly just
looking at the numbers so I guess the
question becomes how do we educate like
the Casual smokers out there that you do
need to use your head because for a lot
of them it's sort of like they just want
an easy metric to fall back on and the
THC percentage seems to be that is it is
it education or do you think like maybe
the Growers just need to force it on
them by just saying no we're only
growing this like Haze
you do have to put up a shut up you know
kind of thing I mean if the cream will
rise to the Top If if you have something
that only tests at 17 or something and
and it just and it [ __ ] rips your
head off and there's no denying it
that'll eventually cut through all right
and you know and become popular and
people people will smoke it and want it
and covered it and uh and it'll it'll
rise to the top I don't think uh and all
this high THC stuff it's kind of oh man
you know most of the time I try these
new things that are supposed to be all
this and all that and of this sticker
with this big high number on it and
stuff
it's like yeah you know not not too much
of it is what I would call
you know incredibly potent or cerebral
yeah okay interesting interesting there
is very much like a sentiment that
there's like a same sameness about a lot
of the modern stuff some of the notable
older heads are like notably not a fan
of like cookies and the the derivatives
of it are you are you a bit like that do
you feel like cookies is like the poster
child for us backing ourselves into the
corner so to speak or do you like it in
some of the uh offspring of it
[Laughter]
I think it's too popular you know and
it's driving too many people's uh
decisions in their selections
um because they want to get a piece of
this popularity and stuff but that but
that's grabbing this huge giant market
share of of breeders time and stuff and
they should be doing something else man
but at the same time you know I've I've
enjoyed some very cerebral plants out of
that gene pool
um as well and you know I think it goes
back to really the OG
that's like TK and stuff these things
are are pretty good man
Yeah a hundred percent and the story
that goes around about the TK is that
it's essentially like two Hindus crossed
together could you believe that
oh I don't know I wouldn't even touch
I'd rather try to touch the moon than
try to figure out the lore of [ __ ]
cannabis that everybody is so con you
know obsessed with in the history of
this and that you know um because it
doesn't matter you know what matters is
it's a really great plant it breeds you
know it breeds really well
and um well I speculate on what we don't
know it would be I guarantee it'd be a
guess that we don't know what it is so
why the [ __ ] guess about it you know
that's silly I like it I like it so I
wanted to ask you you know you've grown
up during what would be arguably the
golden years of Northern California
being in the Mendocino area what's it
been like to live there over the years
and what are some of the interesting
changes you've seen unfold
um
you know not much has changed you know
when you don't go anywhere kind of thing
it's a beautiful place to be
um and it just has a really good vibe
and and you can live your and you can
live your life you know in peace
um you know there's when when you know
medical came out and stuff or you know a
bunch of new guards came up here and
guys with dollar signs in their eyes and
stuff but that's you know that's
fading away now too
um
I I just really enjoy it it's it's
peaceful you know you can you can live
how you want and that's really important
to me
yeah I mean I know you're fairly
self-sufficient do you like that sort of
more isolated lifestyle being up there
oh for sure
um you know people they're the worst
crabs and animals sure you know I I love
both of those things but um yeah I'm
kind of a Hermit in that regard I have a
bit of autism and and um I'm perfectly
fine to to be for long periods of time
by myself
I've done some single-handed sailing you
know too and enjoy that a lot
uh tell us about the sailing that sounds
cool
well back in I think it was 99 or 997.99
I um about a sailboat and um
failed from California down through you
know Mexico and Central America down to
Costa Rica I mean in Quebec a couple
years later you know it took like took
some time to uh to do some sailing some
you know to the tropics and such it was
good fun
uh is that when you got to try that
Infamous Colombian
um no actually I tried the Colombian on
a just a previous uh plane ride trip
down there looking at property the real
estate guy was the guy who actually had
it but what a sales technique get you
all high on Colombian take you for a
walk through the tropical you know
properties that he had for sale you'd be
like wow man but yeah it was a real
estate guy and in the western uh side of
Costa Rica but that yeah that was that
was previous to when I sailed down there
was about I sailed down there about 10
years after or something
yeah okay interesting interesting and I
mean if we jump back to sort of the
growing up in the Emerald Triangle so to
speak a lot of focal discussion takes
place around like the legal changes that
have occurred over the past 10 years how
some people have been forced out of the
industry and even out of the area in
general do you feel like there are any
changes needed to the current sort of
regulations and legal landscape or do
you think it's like you know that it's
just about the cream rising to the top
well I think you know that's going to
happen regardless
and I don't know I don't I think it
would be wasted effort to to try to
change anything there there are people
that are crying you know about big money
coming in and stuff
uh but now there's big money it's crying
you know packing its bags and heading
back down to the city
so um I would I wouldn't pretend to know
what to change you know nobody's getting
busted and going to jail now for long
periods of time that's good
um you know whatever else comes with
that is just tough [ __ ]
yeah certainly certainly I think it's
definitely the number one metric we need
to take into account despite how uh
incomes might be affected but um I
wanted to ask you because I'm invariably
gonna get hassled if I don't if people
wanted to get your seeds is there a way
they can get them are they available at
all
um I don't you know I don't know if any
of these Banks still have seed stock
well there's a lot of people that have
done reproductions and stuff I think
yeah I don't know I'm certainly not
doing it anymore or you know you know I
still pass out seeds to friends and
stuff and sometimes friends will do a
reproduction too I think I think it's up
there at CSI did maybe a ptk one or
something you know and that's good but
it's got you know and and he does a good
job you know I mean I if I was me and I
would have no problem going to him you
know I've seen some really good Haze uh
stuff out there too that have been done
by other people
the business is just it's not for me
really I'd rather breed I'd rather breed
dogs
tell me what dogs do you braid
um uh British working carriers I like
Patterdale and and Jack Russell and and
lakies
um you know digging dogs work working
dogs of the you know Terriers from from
Britain from UK
uh that's brilliant have you got any on
your property now
in Asia right is where is is where I do
it you know I have a farm or you know
place there and they have a big rat
problem I mean it's something like I
don't know up to 20 or something per
year of their rice crop is just
demolished by rats
you'll see them out there with a stick
of bamboo SWAT net rats in the in the in
the fields you know trying to kill rats
like that and I just thinking oh there's
got to be a better way man
so I so I imported a bunch of Kick-Ass
little terriers from from the UK you
know to Asia to try to help out the
farmers there with their with their rat
problem in a more uh you know efficient
manner that's cool do you have like a
little base you've set up over there
like where you go and spend time every
so often
oh I have children there and family
there
oh wow that's cool I don't think anyone
knew that
yeah yeah in in the Philippines I have
two uh two children fantastic and you
just alternate between California and
there
yeah as much as possible I mean the
whole clothing uh kind of screwed us up
a whole bunch didn't it you know travel
is is more difficult financially too you
know now everybody's busy working you
know and and not taking off around the
world as as much as they'd like
including me yeah yeah certainly
certainly it must be tough how long has
it been since you've been able to get
back there oh it's been just I think two
two years now
or 2021
I'm hoping to get over there this fall
but yeah it's been a good two years now
that whole country was on lockdown for
God for several months and when I came
back here the last time from there I
barely got out of the country and um
I was like you know I mean it was the
only plane that left that day everything
else was canceled canceled canceled down
the list I was really lucky to get out
and then for a while I was it was still
teetering on the edge and I was scared
to go can I go back and get stuck there
and and you know and not be able to be
here at work where I need to be
things like that so but I hope to get
back this year things they seem today
everything has settled down quite a bit
now
as far as you know worldwide travel goes
yeah certainly certainly I'm curious to
know how do you find the difference in
climate do you do you feel like you've
adapted to the Heat
um
yeah uh yeah I mean it's hotter here but
it is it is humid there
but you know it's only like low 90s
whereas you know here the other a few
days ago I mean it was a record-breaking
heat day but it was 110 here the other
day
um and it was hot I mean your water your
water water bottle jug that you had
beside you all day by the time six or
seven o'clock in the evening rolled
around you'd take a swig off of it and
you'd be damned it's water if it feels
hot in my mouth that's how hot it was
and it's never like that there and you
know where I'm at it's kind of coastal
and it gets a breeze and you know
there's a little elevation so it's not
too bad where I'm at
okay nice that's cool to hear that's
cool to hear
on a sort of unrelated note I wanted to
ask you I've always loved the names of
your lines I think like deep chunk and
pine tar Kush they're like they're cool
names where did these names come from
um
party Chris was just my my
um you know like I I would call it D15
you know or whatever the chemist calls
it they call them all by numbers and um
I know you know I kind of felt like that
wouldn't do you know for people when I
when I passed around so I tried to you
know describe them and you know the the
first the early time I was passing out
the deep chocolate you know it would be
called monkey balls because that's what
you know it used to be called you know a
friend of mine named it that actually
it's a you know there's a tree that
grows all over uh
Suburbia United States that that when it
seeds it drops these like round golf
balls onto the sidewalks everywhere and
we used to Skid on them when we were on
our skateboards and you know it you know
people would have fights with them
throwing them at each other you know all
over the small towns of America and and
that nickname for this these round balls
that cover sidewalks and streets and
entire neighborhoods are it's just a
shade tree it's not good for much else I
don't think but but the nickname for
them these these round balls are monkey
balls
so my friend said he got any more of
those monkey balls one day and it was
pretty funny we kept the name uh for a
long long time right before I put it out
there in public to people from like
overgo and such
um I had seen like I think it was like a
South Park cartoon or something where
where they actually said Jesus Christ
monkey balls or something something I
looked up monkey balls I'm like working
where'd they get this from and um
and monkey balls it was what it was a
video game right
and I was like [ __ ] I'm gonna get sued
right by this [ __ ] video game kidding
people I can't [ __ ] release this [ __ ]
under the handle monkey balls right some
stupid Nintendo or somebody right it's
gonna come after me so I change it to
deep Chunk on the Fly real quick before
I put it out there to the public
um the x18 was one that my mother Kim is
called number 18 and I was just too lazy
to come up with a name for it
um the pine car crash you know it does
have some some uh Piney and tarry kind
of things going on and it's a broad leaf
you know so it's just just threw it out
there
beautiful I love the name d chunk that's
a a flash of creativity if nothing else
I love it our our buddy Caleb inspector
he actually said at one point that after
doing that plantar Kush Recreation like
having gotten a bit of experience with
the line through seeing the numbers he
says he wouldn't be surprised if it's
somehow in her cool do you have any
thoughts on this given you've seen both
um
I don't know I think
they're probably both derived from you
know similar [ __ ] from the from the
similar neighborhood up here inspect is
always trying to find you know figure
figure [ __ ] out that he's never gonna
know for sure you know but why spend
time on that I I don't know it's
certainly different from you know
they're different but they're the same
type of plant you know these are just uh
sir you know broad Leafs from from from
this region that you know that were
around way back in the day
I'm talking late 70s early 80s you know
right from the beginning of the
introductions to broadleaf and up in
these up in these you know communities
up here they're both certainly survivors
of that but as to their relation I don't
know Urkel's very different
um from it
and so I don't know
yeah so I understand I understand
out of curiosity have you ever heard of
Christmas tree bird or Christmas Bud oh
sure yeah that was uh that was
um stuff that we used to get around
Christmas time back down in Southern
California I would come in it would come
in late
um
at least the one that I remember we used
to call it Christmas but
um and uh
it was uh also called something else I
think it was a three River sativa or
something come out of the like Yosemite
region or not Yosemite but uh what's
that other national park down there
Sequoia
in the foothills of this National Park
uh you know East Northeast of La you
know they that was a growing Community
they're called Three Rivers and there
was some late sativa that came out of
there that have always be in by
Christmas and that's what me and my you
know people that I knew down there we
used to call it Christmas bud uh okay
the reason I ask is because I'd heard
some people I can't remember who I wish
I could credit them
compare the Christmas Bud to ptk and I
guess like someone was sort of saying
like are they the same thing maybe
they're just similar sort of pakistanis
I guess really
yeah who knows so I I if we might be
talking about a different holy different
totally different term you know this uh
there's three River sativa that that we
used to get down in L.A
um that certainly didn't smell like a
Christmas tree if if that's what these
other the stats with this other
Christmas you said Christmas tree bud
it's probably something all right
probably something entirely different
um but uh the ptk does have some of that
type of some some of those type of
profiles in it for sure
you know kind of kind of piney thing
going on and but it's pretty variable
still too you know I mean it's pretty
raw that one the x18 I think was more uh
stable uh from of the chemists you know
of those two I think that's a ptk still
still pretty raw there's probably lots
of good stuff in it you know
yeah interesting and did you ever try
any of like the fabled Northern Lights
clones that circulated the Mendo area in
like the 90s like and did you were you a
fan of it if so
oh well we up on this road where I'm at
um everybody had it in seed form
um it was you know everybody was growing
from Northern Lights from seed
feminized seed mind you
um from you know stressed out rooms and
stuff that and that stuff came out
really uniform
um and sold real well but yeah most
people grew Northern Lights from seed
none of the Clones
um you know five two all these ones
um that everybody else knows of we're up
here that I know of but everybody had
Northern lifetime sheep and Seed Farm up
here and they and they used that because
it was all female seed but they kept on
you know producing in their rooms you
know it would throw a couple of seeds
and as you're smoking or whatever you'd
save your seeds from it and you'd end up
with the pile of these Northern Light
seeds and you'd [ __ ] grow them again
and it'd be it would it would be a way
to without cloning rent all female uh
rooms up here that happened for years
and years and years and years
um I know several people that grew Craig
and Lester's Northern lifestyle that's
what we call it up here
um they've both passed away now so it's
okay to say their name
but these two brothers had epic Northern
Lights uh line up here on on the hill
where I'm at and that that was that was
like the earliest thing that anybody was
growing up here and they and they did
that for years and years and years later
you know a few people would try out some
White Widow or something but uh then the
Northern Light seed from the hill here
was was a staple for like you know the
first decade of indoor growing up here
big generator grows you know it's with
60 lightrooms and such
and what was the the bud like
it was pretty much um
looked very similar
um to this that went up in Canada BCC
here or something
um I've seen photos of some pretty legit
looking Northern Lights but it's very
resinous but it's another one with these
small resin heads man and it was pretty
lightweight I have to say it didn't get
you super high I mean it was serviceable
smoke for sure but it was one of these
ones that were that faked you out man
looked like a sea resin but um they were
empty nests man nobody was home upstairs
their small one-bedroom apartment
that small resin head man
um I I didn't particularly like it I
still have some of the seed here and you
know but they don't they don't they
won't germinate for me anymore they're
that old but um but I save them anyway
we might be able to get them back that
way you know via other tissue culture or
something one day
so I'd say seeds even if they don't even
if they don't want germinate for me
anymore but
yeah there's there's a famous old one up
here up in the hills
but I don't remember the the clothes I
remember it a thing that the Northern
Lights didn't grow anywhere near as good
outdoor as it performed indoor you know
you you weren't gonna like try to try to
grow giant plants of it or something it
it lacked bigger compared to a lot of
other stuff that we were growing outdoor
back then
um it didn't produce as much it was just
a smaller plant you know less bigger
um there's decent serviceable weed but
it was kind of a morning smoke you know
it wasn't going to floor you
it's a great breeding plant I you know
have no doubt about that we've seen you
know kazilian hybrids with it in it that
are good you know so it's a great you
know nothing to say that nothing bad
about it it's it's a it's a famous and
and an excellent plant that's that's
certainly been valuable to the gene pool
I think
um
but you know I mean it itself as a line
yeah it was okay
you know
my more value it for breeding words
probably
yeah well you read my mind when you said
you know you're still sitting on it even
though they won't germ I was curious to
know do you have any other notable seeds
in your collection that are like special
to you even though they may not germ but
you know yeah memorable for one reason
or another
yeah well I still have all those uh the
pro the I think the original uh uh ptk
stuff
the stuff that went back to all that
[ __ ] Creek that's getting pretty old
now that was like I don't know 2000 or
something might have been even been from
the late 90s or something that's
probably about sprout anymore but but
I'm gonna throw them away
um let's see there's some old I have
some old Reunion Island stuff that
probably won't Sprout but I won't throw
it away and yeah
um that old Northern Lights fine
um some old Salmon Creek hybrids
probably yeah yeah I have I have a few I
know that I know are Like Beckham won't
Sprout and then
um but but I refuse to throw them away
I'm just a
you know a seed junkie I guess and they
might be worth something later I can't
throw it away
I love it I love it and uh were there
ever any notable clones that went
through the area that were really
special to you that have just been lost
to time
yeah well you know I mean
some of the Great Outdoor performers you
know I wish people had kept had held on
to
um any other Salmon Creek
you know uh I I even I missed the blue
dream sometimes to be honest people are
gonna laugh though that was an okay plan
Old Faithful Got You High you know
um I'm there with you I thought it was
great
yeah yeah I mean it wasn't it wasn't you
know I mean there's there's a certain
there was a certain what I call
muddiness to the high it wasn't like
crystal clear and stuff it was it was
kind of a little bit
um you know fuzzy and and cloudy I would
say ever high but uh it was certainly
potent and man that plant's bomb proof
you grow right through a snowstorm
hell yeah and I mean given you're in the
area did you ever like you know you hear
stories about the famous brothers of
eternal love and stock coming from the
early stuff they brought in did you ever
see any of that or do you think that's
sort of a bit more fabled
I have no idea
um I don't have a
any opinions about that that's mostly
that's I'm not probably quite that old
that's like Sam Skunk Man old
I'm not quite I'm not quite I'm getting
up there but I'm not there yet
um what I do know that there is lots of
really really good [ __ ] and you know I
mean California and
you know
um Surfers you know they smoke weed and
uh the California has always been a
great big fan of weed
um and there's some really good [ __ ]
that that got shipped into California
ports you know due to that
and uh you know there's great Mexicans
and there was and there was crappy
Mexicans too
um but that was probably the the you
know the most popular
um or the most you know
of what was there I think you would get
the Jamaicans the Thai the Hawaiian you
know all this stuff came in occasionally
and there were some really really great
stuff
um here in California always you know
and it's allowed us to like you know
kind of be be a kind of a place where
you know things thrived for a long time
yeah interesting and I mean I don't
think you've mentioned it so I'll just
ask and get it out of the way do you
ever have you ever had any experience
with like African strains do you have a
spot in your heart for them what's your
thoughts I grew a Malawi up here one
time
um during the late 80s and it and it
[ __ ] it was a
intersex you know nightmare that was all
seated and just gave me a headache and
uh and I threw it I threw it in the
toilet
but I probably wish I didn't I would say
you know if I probably should have you
know if I if I had known I would have
probably grabbed some of those seeds and
set them aside
you know but you know the one time I had
a look at some African here it didn't
work out and I quickly called it
yeah okay there you go not as much
successes with some of the hazes
yeah um there and there's some you know
before before the broad leaves came up
here everybody was growing Mexican you
know the earlier Mexicans you know there
was a there's definitely two different
kinds of Mexican
um you had your you know your really
trippy cerebral you know ones that were
down from further south on the on the on
the Mediterranean or on the on the
Caribbean side and then they had those
Northern Mexican stuff that came in real
early and it was like the bulk of what
got shipped North through California it
was lower quality but some of that stuff
came in early and you could finish it in
Northern California you know way better
than the ties and everything else
um so you know early on that's what most
people were growing up here with some
Mexican
um there's there were some good ones of
those around
um and I saved one I forgot what the
hell happened to that thing I guess I
don't have it now but I had it and you
know 20 years ago or something and sent
it to somebody I forget who I don't
remember anyway
wow very interesting very interesting
so we had some of our listeners as well
as myself were curious you sort of have
had a bit of a notable absence in the
community for a few years are you
willing to share any insight about what
you've been doing in that time or why
you decided to take some time away
and you know I mean there's there's a
there's there's good people
um
that I've met from those places uh from
the you're talking about the forums yeah
there's some great I've met some great
friends
um you know getting involved with all
that but there's but there's also some
you know there's some real bills that
somehow for some reason seems to get
attracted to this to the whole to the
whole scene man
um and that kind of freaks me out a
little bit you know
um
uh that that not everybody has your best
interest in mind so I so I just don't
you know I I felt like I had to have a
presence there when I passed out a bunch
of genetics you know and made available
a bunch of genetics I felt I owed it to
people you know to try to to try to you
know say something about him help them
with them or whatever
but um
but I felt like those dudes you know
that that you know that I've done that
and um
and other than that it's like and it
kind of gives me the willies to even to
even go there I feel the same way about
going to Europe you know I mean I
um I'm just uncomfortable in that in
that in that scenario kind of you know I
don't like being the center of attention
although you know I'll get drunk on some
beer and just kick my foot and pour
gypsy's front door and just raise hell
until you know and play off the handle
it doesn't bother me you know when I'm
hammered
when I'm sober and and probably have
something to actually add it's just yeah
it doesn't even that I'm not even
attracted anymore you know
um I wanted to ask you there's actually
a notable clone that goes around like
the NorCal area it's chemd across to Tom
Hills Hayes have you ever heard or seen
of that one by any chance never have
that's awesome though
um that somebody's taking the time to
you know to actually set aside a club
and I think that's [ __ ] bitching I'd
love to I'd love to check it out but
yeah I have not heard that there you go
yeah we'll have to put the feelers out
for it try to get it into your hands
it'd be cool
[Laughter]
uh so I I wanted to ask you a bit
unrelated but um what do you what's your
thoughts of Sam you know Sam often gets
scapegoated as like a bit of a villain
by some people but it sounds like you're
more of the school of thought that I am
which is that he's you know maybe done
more than anyone where do you fall on
that one what's your thoughts on Mr
David Watson oh he's he's you know he's
a there's there's not many that have
done what he's done uh for the for the
community and and the worldwide gene
pool and stuff you know he made
available stuff that people you know
would have never even you know had to I
mean what were they doing in Holland
when he showed up I think they were
smoking some dirty hash from Morocco or
somewhere mixed with tobacco so yeah I
think he's I think he's a good man and
and uh and honest and all that you know
um I don't I don't think he you know
I'll give him hell when I'm hammered but
um but about I think for the most part
this guy's this guy's great and and his
friend rob you know I think those guys
are are absolutely you know excellent
uh ambassadors of
of cannabis
yeah here here here
I should have asked you this one a bit
earlier when we were talking about you
know sort of being in the NorCal area
but I wanted to hear your thoughts on
the idea of like clones degrading over
time and people speculate like maybe
it's like genetic drift or like
deterioration what's your thoughts do
you think that clones degrade over time
and like do you think it's possible to
stop that through like maybe keeping
them like really happy their whole lives
where do you fall on this
well I think that time itself is it
won't degrade them I think that we're
actually talking about pathogens
um
that that you know eventually get them
and uh and and they'll succumb to them
and and you know put out less
performance and that's just a a fact of
cannabis unfortunately it doesn't last
as long as a grape clone or
something else you probably clean it up
in the lab and all that stuff's possible
and such but yeah it doesn't just
deteriorate and fall apart genetically
uh anyway you know I mean I mean you
might have drift or something or talk I
don't even know yeah no I don't see it
happening
um I I think they said we're talking
about pathogens that just you know
eventually the plant succumbs to
have you ever heard people talk about
dudding
yeah same thing same thing
um you know these are likely pathogens
that have you know taken hold of the
plant and and [ __ ] up its performance
yeah I know that um in the community The
Hop late and viroid is like largely
considered the source of that but I
guess you know being secluded and
growing from seed you probably don't
really encounter much about that do you
no
um I don't uh when I'm growing from seed
and and and luckily I haven't you know I
haven't had any bad problems uh
from clone either
and I I don't know I don't know how I
hear that it's widespread but I'm
probably pretty removed from you know
what everybody else is kind of working
with
um I'm not going down and you know
buying clothes from the dispensary or
whatever
yeah true Advantage the uh the ultimate
quarantine I love it I love it so I
think that brings us to a quick fire
question so I wanted to ask you first of
all what is your absolute favorite
strain of all time
hmm
Ty Reid
Thailand race I love it I love it okay
so next one what is the most single
memorable experience you've had with
cannabis be it like you know because it
was potent or just because of like the
Saturn setting and it was super
memorable what's the number one most
memorable
um this flavor that I came across in a
deep chunk plant once
um I call it top rock because that's
where it was grown but it had such a
rich uh kind of coffee flavor that
actually would coat your throat and make
your throat actually numb and give your
throat a numb feeling
um it was nothing like ever anything
I've ever experienced with cannabis um
before or after
wow you've only seen it that one time
yeah
oh gosh that's beautiful love it okay so
on the other end of the spectrum what's
a strain where everyone was hyping it up
and you were really excited to try it
and then you finally did and you were
just disappointed
[ __ ]
could I say most everything that's been
that's around right now you know I mean
um
everything's hyped up these days and it
never [ __ ] comes through
um you know as much as you're hoping you
know you you just you know that the
majority of what's out there
um fits that description I think
um no so not one sticks out you know
thousands upon thousands upon thousands
of wave of them stand out to me it's
like you know everything is hyped up and
it never delivers
holding no punches so let's say I'm
gonna drop you off on a mythical magical
desert island you've got everything you
need to grow and you're only allowed to
take three strains with you you can take
seeds or clones what three things are
you gonna take that are gonna do you
right for the rest of time
huh
uh
Hayes High and deep Chunk in seed form
all
that's brilliant and then if I come back
in like 20 years you'll just have
recreated everything
no I'd probably still be growing Haze
[Laughter]
okay so final question
what is your ultimate hopes in terms of
the future for the Cannabis sin in what
direction do you want to see it go what
would be the best outcome in your mind
well for to you know finish to finished
making it not a a criminal activity you
know around the world that would be nice
um and for you know as far as the Scene
goes I wish people would just you know
be be more doing what they want to do
what they'd like doing doing what they
like growing what they like reading what
they like what they like not what their
Market's looking for anything else but I
wish people would be more honest with
you know what their favorite is and and
kind of kind of take it upon themselves
to be a steward of you know of those
varieties
what a brilliant sentiment I love it I
can totally endorse that one so I think
that just about brings us to the end of
it for this one do you have any comments
or shout outs you'd like to make
no I'm good um you know I just I know
it's hard time for a lot of a lot of
people that are still in the you know
cannabis Zone
Growers out there and stuff and hang
tough you know
um it's there's a you know everything
seems dark but but there's there's Sunny
sides to it too our roads are a lot
quieter and you know it's kind of
peaceful outside right now and um and
you know you're you're just one kind of
awesome clone away from changing the
world so stick with it brilliant stuff
so once again a huge thank you to the
old school legend master of both the
hashplan and the haze Tom Hill thank you
so much for joining us
thanks Harry great to talk to you
[Music]
there you have it friends a huge thank
you to Tom for stopping by sharing all
of his knowledge
and a huge thank you to you for making
it to the end
as always huge shout out to the sponsors
guys we couldn't make episodes happen
without them shout out to seeds here now
in simply souvenirs if you need seeds
whether you're in America or the EU they
got you covered with all the biggest
names hottest drops simply souvenirs
seats here now shout out guys we
appreciate you so much
likewise shout out to our friends at
Comfort biological systems all the best
pest and predited Technology get their
stuff guys you won't regret it just like
pulse sensors you need to get your
garden dialed in to get the optimal
yield if you want to get serious get
yourself a pulse
[Music]
a shout out to the purple pro team
sending me a purple Pro I've been using
it it's a very fun accurate handheld
results flowering concentrate
so I'm using it to feed her hunt check
it out
last but not least the patreon gang we
love you so much please consider
supporting the patreon if you like the
show and want to ensure it continues to
happen all while getting some cool
benefits
it's about it for this one my friends
I'll check you for the next one
[Music]
foreign