[Applause]
[Music]
alright alright alright hello and
welcome to the podcast your cannabis
podcast for budding enthusiasts as
always you're joined by your boy heavy
days here from the upside down library
and we are thankful for our amazing
sponsors seeds here now best seeds in
the game guarantee on satisfaction not
just germination you want to get that
new exotic mic red pop drop or that new
archive drop it's coming soon hit them
up they got you sorted likewise a huge
shout out to carpet biologicals they've
got the best beneficial bugs in the game
in my opinion everything to keep those
mites at bay those fungus gnats dead
and everything to keep your garden happy
healthy and poppin hit em up they got
everything you need and last but not
least big shout out to the patreon gang
you guys are the lifeblood of the show
as always we appreciate you helping to
keep the show happening if anyone wants
to check out additional content
unreleased episodes and early access to
future episodes google the podcast
patreon it'll bring it up trust me
on this episode we're extremely
extremely grateful to have steve from
potentponics and the growing with the
fishes podcast
here to share here to share all his
knowledge about aquaponics grown in
africa ipm organics and so so so much
more i feel like i'm doing a dis justice
at this point
without further ado
let's get into it
alrighty so a big thank you and welcome
to our friend with the fishers steve of
potent ponics and the growing with the
fishes podcast thank you so much for
joining us today
thanks a lot for having me man it's
quite quite awesome to have you uh we
had you on a long time ago and you're
one of the
more favorite episodes that we have on
our
on our audio version so it's really
awesome to come and hang out with you
and talk with you on your show and
learn more about uh things down under
oh you're too kind man i i love being
able to come on your show and i
certainly learned a lot the first thing
i'd love to ask you though what have you
been smoking on recently
oh man lately i've been smoking on a lot
of concentrates i've been doing mostly
live resin and live rosin um some
gorilla glue 4 lately just because it's
quite available here in
southern oklahoma and then also a little
tenth planet uh and then what else we
had a a
strawberry banana sunset or something
like that i think was the other one that
we've been smoking on lately but i'm
more of a concentrate person uh
i have some digestive tract stuff that
uh that concentrates really help a lot
with and um you know
as someone is using it daily for medical
reasons as well as enjoyment uh i tend
to get you know a lot better bang for my
buck spending money for concentrates
than i do for uh for flower
wow what a range of awesome awesome
different directions we can go in with
that one and i want to hear about all of
them i guess the first thing that comes
to mind is
oklahoma you don't hear a lot about the
scene out there what's your take
uh oklahoma's very interesting you have
a lot of
very opposite ends of the skills skill
spectrum i guess
you have people that have you know just
found out about cannabis that you know
maybe have a lot of acreage and and you
know a lot of money that they've been
saved away that are just you know
learning how to grow cannabis for the
first time maybe you don't even know
what a photo period is
and then you have all the way to you
know people coming in from cali that you
know have everything kind of uh on a
nice system that you know they just plug
and play and away they go so it's it's
kind of interesting you you have um the
price is stabilized at around twenty two
hundred dollars a pound for quite a long
time plus minus i mean you do have some
super cheap stuff coming in now and then
but um you know it really is kind of the
better quality stuff really is kind of
holding its price point uh more than
some of the other newer markets uh
having gone through this in colorado
california and a couple of other states
and a couple of other countries now as
well um
it really is kind of holding its price
point a little higher than some of the
other places i guess uh maybe just
because of of the demand going up
because of current global events but
um
uh it really is kind of interesting it's
also uh one of the lowest regulated
scenes so if you're interested in
developing products if you're interested
in um developing methods if you're
interested in developing stuff that
you're going to
um you know further refine it's a great
place to do that because you know 2 500
bucks
up until recently was all you needed to
get going and you could have a full
vertical a cultivation an extraction and
a retail space for less than 10 grand
so
you know to have all those licenses in a
straight row as a you know for for for
that cheap compared to the and anyone
that's tried for a license in california
or some of the other states they're
they're probably sitting here screaming
at
whatever they're listening to this on
them uh you know i know i spent a year
and a half trying to get licensed in
california and and working with the city
council and working with you know
everyone that we needed to to to
properly go about that and we're still
denied one and then to be able to come
out place like out here and just waltz
in and immediately work with someone
that's you know established out here and
get going is quite nice and and kind of
takes away a lot of the regulatory
hurdles it's kind of interesting to see
kind of a conservative mindset to the
cannabis industry and there hasn't
really been a lot of other states that
have taken that now one thing i said i
mean one downside would be that it did
take them a little bit longer than some
other states to get universal testing in
which i would have liked to have seen
done earlier but
aside from that uh you know they are
kind of slowly catching up incrementally
uh with some of the other states in a
more sane way i think than than a lot of
other places
yeah wow it sounds like there's a lot of
opportunities going on there and a
really nice detailed analysis of the
situation
would you think that the environment
itself is conducive to growing cannabis
and in the long term do you think it'll
um kind of rise as a premier sort of
state to be producing it in or do you
think that it's just the the friendly
legalities at the moment are what i was
allowing it to kind of flourish
i think it's a little bit of both i
think that um there's definitely
oh
a small i would say maybe 15 to 20
percent of the cultivars that are
traditionally going on say the west
coast that'll actually really excel here
and most of them having done two two uh
summers now growing stuff out here the
durban poison the malawi uh malawi and
swazi crosses and southern african
crosses and then some of the other
equatorial strains seem to be the ones
that really you know they're used to the
heat they're used to the higher humidity
they don't really care so much about the
heat uh and um they seem to really you
know pack on a few extra pounds or not a
future pounds but a few extra grams and
you know when you're talking fields or
rooms a few extra pounds uh when you're
doing greenhouses or outdoors
specifically um you know you have really
high temperatures you know it can get to
be 107 110 so
what is that in a celsius is that like
37 38 yeah yeah
i think you're back um yeah so
yeah so sorry i just came back from
zimbabwe so i'm still pretty fresh with
my my conversions um
but uh uh but you know so so you have to
have strains that'll tolerate that your
your pure indicas really do not like
that heat uh or traditional indicas we
all know that the classifications have
changed now but um your traditional
stuff that you know your purple heavy
stuff really doesn't do super well out
here on the outdoor stuff again that's
more adapted to cold climate
you know again i'm being very generally
broad obviously there's lots of
exceptions to that but um you don't see
a lot of that stuff and you see a lot
more fungal issues that people aren't
used to um
i've seen last year there was a huge
outbreak of septoria not only in
oklahoma but in tennessee and a lot of
other states that were doing hemp and i
really think a lot of it came from
the lack of biodiversity in the soil you
had a huge outbreak of septoria fusarium
and there was all in these fields that
were corn or soybean or wheat last year
that were just completely dead fields
there was no microbiological diversity
in the in the soil so how is this plant
going to have any type of microbe for
lack of better uh or for simplification
a microbial and not a vaccination or
exposure to fungals to know how to make
any type of resistance against them you
know if you have a totally dead field
it's not going to know what what
something is if it comes against it it's
like taking someone that was living in a
bubble and dropping them into times
square you know their immune system is
not going to know what to do
it's the same kind of way so i think
that um we were able to quickly at least
in the three farms that i worked with
last year on this with the septoria we
were able to quickly use a heavy
microbial inoculation of both um a
bacterius complex bactilis pamila
spectulos subtilis and a lactobacillus
making labs uh uh i prefer kefir based
labs in the traditional k nf labs but we
can get into that later um but
and then doing an imo treatment after a
week of that of rotating those other
treatments
and uh just as a water and a foliar and
we were able to treat almost all those
fields and we only threw out maybe 15
plants across those three forms so um
and again we caught it early if those
one you know once septoria gets beyond a
certain point those plants are boned
right so it's systemic so um but if you
can catch it early you can treat it and
we had very good luck by doing that but
again it was with microbial inoculants
not with a spray not with the fungal not
with sulfur with it with proper
probiotics it's the only way to treat
some of this stuff
wow i'm already looking forward to this
chat already but before we get into it i
definitely want to chat about zimbabwe
because that's just itching to be
discussed i did want to quickly clarify
or not clarify i just wanted to quickly
ask you mentioned that in oklahoma the
prices have stabilized at about 2200 a
pound overall what do you predict will
be the kind of long game
pricing for a pound do you think that is
the ballpark of what you want it to be
do you think that it's maybe still a
little high and with more production we
could get it down where do you think a
good price point is long term
i think well i guess the the first
answer i would have is i don't think
anybody knows the honest answer to that
question
but i will tell you what i think is that
i think that you're going to have craft
growers that are going to have and that
are going to stamp out a brand for
themselves that for high quality and
they're going to hold their higher price
you see people like dragonfly earth
medicine and the wonderful group of
people in the den purity network that
they've built up and all those wonderful
farmers that work so hard to grow you
know clean medicine and they're able to
hold their brand and hold their prices
up i think you know following similar
type things you have um you know other
similar type groups out there that have
these uh different um standards for
their product and i think that's going
to be a way for people to really
separate themselves from the pack and
and allow craft growers to really excel
when you have you know a lot of these
bigger producers and especially later on
when you have other countries when you
have you know nations like colombia and
zimbabwe and places that can grow for
you know much cheaper prices than than
the united states has you know could
ever grow for i think you're still going
to have a a absolutely be able to
compete you know right right there at a
really great price point and you know
probably around that fifteen hundred two
thousand dollar maybe even higher price
point uh per pound for that really craft
cannabis because it's worth it and and
the inputs are there and if you don't
you know you're not gonna get that
a cheap pound that that's hand trimmed
right like it's there's just certain
things that just has a cost to it for
the quality and and the same way with
with um
uh you know fine wine or or any fine
food you know you pay for that higher
quality and i really think that that's
going to be you're going to have your
craft growers that really separate
themselves pretty quickly and then
you're going to have the kind of just
you know general production for
everything else you know
yeah certainly and i would love to get a
little more into the nit gritty of that
because i've had a lot of people message
me over the past year or so and they
kind of reference this idea you talk
about and they're like i would love to
do that i'm wondering what are some ways
to do it and the thing i would always
reply with is
i always think that if you're trying to
set yourself apart one easy way to do it
is to
get like a strain and find your own
unique keeper of it ideally something
that's not already in circulation maybe
you even breed it yourself which that's
you know a bit of a different discussion
but what are some of the ways you think
people can build a brand because i
thought like unique strain maybe you
know even unique cultivation style
aquaponics what do you think how can
people help to establish themselves as a
unique producer
well i would say definitely look at
unique products if you have the ability
or if you have a recipe for something
that grandma made that was super awesome
make an infused version if it's
something that's allowed in your state
you know and these types of things where
you already have something unique you
just didn't think of using it in the
cannabis realm or some other stuff so
but in particular one one way that i
work with a lot of companies is with
aquaponics and in fact there's a group
right now i'm working with on a licensed
application in chicago where we're going
to be donating 100 of our fish to the
local community so our cannabis facility
is providing free food for the local
community on top of all the medicine
we're providing for our for the patients
within the community so we're able to
feed people we also will set up
with a lot of these aquaponics systems
we'll set up wicking beds on the outside
because we do have to um you know we can
discharge a little bit from our
filtration system if we're brewing and
we make extra and we need some place to
put it without having to pay for
disposal in places like california we
can set up wicking beds and just have a
public garden out front and have and
grow vegetables for our community again
being more than just a cannabis
a company but being a pillar of the
community that's giving back to the
community and you know using the whole
uh converting greed into good and
and and really bringing the whole
message and the energy of cannabis i
mean think about everyone listening to
this show how many times has funds that
started with cannabis
ended up creating and helping someone
that you knew
in in a hard spot or with car parts or
with rent or with whatever all of us did
at some point all anyone that's in the
cannabis industry started slinging
eights or slinging grams and that's why
we're in this point there's very few
people that didn't get into it that way
or if they did they got into it late
but if you got into it pre-legalization
that's what you did all of us got
started that way right that's and then
we got into growing and then we got into
you know more and more and more so
so
this is really a way where we can give
back to our community and do it as a
byproduct you know those fish are
providing fertilizer for us and we're
able to just give them back to the
community as a way to to feed people and
again that that helps us with our story
helps us with our brand helps us with
our whole you know eco or eco not only
equal responsible but community
responsible with our company
yeah what a powerful message because i i
even had a question about that so we
might even jump to it but whenever i
discussed aquaponics with i've got a
friend
let me let me clarify you you know the
guy i'm trying to think of the real big
aquaponics guy in queensland in
australia
mr murray holland murray so i got a good
friend who has trained under him so he's
quite knowledgeable and um you know
firsthand knowledge from murray and he
said he's interested in cannabis um and
he said that he always kind of struggled
to see
a big cultivation facility doing
aquaponics purely for the sense that he
was like it just seems weird to have a
store that sells fish and cannabis
because he's like that would be the end
goal like you've got fish and cannabis
you need to sell them both
i guess you've just provided a really
nice alternative pathway to use those
fish do you think that idea though that
they raised is a legitimate sort of
concern about like you've just got
you're ending up with these two
different products or do you think we
just need to look deeper like what you
mentioned as to how we can utilize the
resources
so so there's kind of two pieces to that
so first off one of the other things
that we've i've talked about with
california producers is doing a cannabis
infused smoke fish so taking taking the
fish doing fillets and then doing a
cannabis glaze a flavored glaze and then
smoking it and then doing it selling
that as a product so you could actually
have a very good um you know a
value-added item with the cannabis and
have the cannabis be the value added
rather than you know so depending on how
you want to go with your business model
you could also raise tropical fish and
flip those as well for profit and that
and often can be much more profitable
than raising food fit and actually in
almost all cases is more profitable than
raising food fish so if you're strictly
focused on profits as a cannabis company
you know avoiding food fish altogether
now the other component and this is only
an issue in the united states
is you cannot get a meat processing
license which you need to have to kill
the fish and clean the fish
and
a cannabis license because
cannabis is still federally regulated as
a schedule 1 drug and the meat
processing
facilities are all uh inspected by
federal inspectors from the usda they
can't step foot into a facility that has
schedule one drugs on the property and
then
they're just conflicting right so so you
have this issue where i have to license
a third-party processor that's already
licensed
where they come pick up the fish or i
deliver the fish either live or or
frozen uh whole frozen on ice and then
have them clean them you know
third-party and to legally resell them
so that that is a regulatory issue that
is currently an issue in the united
states because because of the current
federal law that people it's kind of a
weird
thing that i'm sure no politician
thought about as a weird but you know
it's an off weird thing but it is a
legal hurdle uh for aquaponic cannabis
facilities currently in the united
states now in kentucky
i actually helped
the guys over at um
one of the universities uh i don't know
if they got the thing but i helped write
a grant for um i believe it was langston
university if memory recalls last year
but anyways help them write a a grant
for a truck a processing truck so that
they'd be able to go around to the
different aquaponic cannabis companies
in oklahoma because oklahoma currently
has the most number of aquaponic
cannabis licenses of any state in the
united states right now so
in terms of number of businesses so
um uh there there's quite a few
different companies that have adapted a
coup both uh existing facilities and
then you know new built from scratch
facilities uh in the tulsa and oklahoma
area as well as oklahoma city area as
well as further south where i am um
that are all uh all doing cannabis now
and um yeah
kind of lost my train of thought there
no that's just a trail of knowledge we
need to leave some cookie crumbs
um so i guess the question it raises for
me is you just paint such a beautiful
picture with this do you anticipate that
as the years go by we're going to see an
increase in aquaponic cultivation or do
you think that it's just one of those
things where you know you're always
going to have the people who want to do
the rock wool and you're just never
going to change their mind
oh no i think you're always going to
have people that have their set system
that works for them and hey if someone
has a system it works for them and
they're crushing it why change it like i
don't
i'm not going to you know if you have if
you just kill it with soil or you kill
it with hydra or you kill it with cocoa
like rock it man
but i do think that and having done lots
of side-by-sides now and then consulted
for lots of companies that paid me to do
side by sides um we can crush the i'm
sorry about the pupper i have a younger
pupper that uh all poppers are welcome a
little bit younger we can edit that out
so um so with aquaponics we've managed
to get significantly higher terpenes
than all of our our hydro or soil uh
controls across the board we've had not
a single test out of over 120 ever come
back lower on the terpenes compared to
uh dual root zone aquaponic control um
even non-dual roots and aquaponic
controls
will about 75 percent of the time will
be almost all but the best living soils
and that's just through terpene and
cannabinoid testing that we've done now
what we attribute it to is one of two
things uh either there's an endophyte
you know certain endophytes that are
colonizing the plant from the aquatic
microbiome
or the stimulation of having both the
terrestrial and aquatic microbiomes or a
combination thereof of what i just said
and this um of having those two
microbiomes the terrestrial microbiome
in the soil area and the upper half of
the root zone and the aquatic layer in
the lower half of the root zone with
dual root zone pots allows you to have
you know such an increase in
biodiversity that um uh you know you get
that increase in stimulation of the
plant's immune system and what does a
plant do when it needs to defend itself
and gets the planet's immune system
stimulated increases terpenes and
depending on what the stimuli it is so
by increasing the number of
non-pathogenic microbes to the root
system you can basically give it more
vaccinations for you know a simplified
way of thinking about it and increase
the total terpene production by giving
an exposure to more microbes in a way
that's not going to screw with it and a
negative input so that's that really
allows us to give us a huge advantage
the other big advantages that we have is
we use around 18 percent uh with my
methodology
of water compared to many other uh soil
grown methods you know a drain to waste
or most of your soil outdoor
and that's just gallons per day per
plant uh under a four month grow three
to three and a half to four month growth
cycle so assuming you have a minor veg
and then a quick flip so um uh you know
uh we've had really really great luck
with that and then also increased
acceleration and growth so in veg
we have no problem hitting the two to
four inch a day mark all day long with
aquaponics it's not even we don't even
have to try
it's just incredible how fast and anyone
can go onto my youtube and and see for
themselves time-stamped videos of
different farms if multiple farms on
there that you can see you know
incredible acceleration of growth
um but uh the
the farm i was just working with here in
in southern oklahoma we were averaging
two to four inches of growth per day on
all of our mother plants in the
greenhouse it was you know
it's kind of goofy it's it's fun to or
it's not even it's annoying to go back
to soil because you're like this is like
watching paint dry you know it's just so
slow and then we were able to shave on
flour anywhere from 5 to 14 days off the
flowering cycle
by increasing the speed of that as well
um
just in terms of speed of growth again
we attribute that to increased gas
exchange in the root system it really
does make a big difference
wow yeah there's so many things we've
got to talk about there i just want to
quickly jump back because i'm a really
big fan of when you were talking about
the plant's immune system and the
increased terpenes to assist with that
what's your thoughts around the use of
chitin-based products as i mean to do
that and are you still able to utilize
those in aquaponics
oh yeah in fact you asked a really
awesome question so um i actually just
did a trial of three different
chitinase-based treatments for insect
control when i was over in zimbabwe so
we did um a liquid so
are you familiar with imo or indigenous
microorganisms from korean natural
farming okay so so if you're familiar
with that what we do is um we did one
method where we took that and did a 30
insect frass and then 60
or 70
rice
and then mix that together cooked it and
then did that as an imo treatment for
collecting the um
microbes and then we were able to
collect uh a chitinase feeding you know
uh microbes that would feed on the
exoskeletons or the plants or i'm sorry
the insects not the plants um to defend
the plants from mainly the biggest issue
we're dealing with is these large
african grasshoppers um
they're i don't maybe they were locusts
but they were huge and they were they
were the biggest problem we had because
they chew the bark off the plants and
they that was the biggest issue is
they'd chew the cambrian layer off the
plants so um
uh that was the biggest problem we had
so the the uh
the large grasshoppers would chew the
cambrian layer off the plants and then
the plants would you know basically the
top anything above that would start to
die off so we started spraying with that
and that was by far the best treatment
that we had for any of the things that
we had and we were able to kill the
grasshoppers it took a couple days to
work but once we were spraying the
plants and sprayed the ground and we
were doing that once a week um it worked
incredibly well and we just made a
liquid imo from from that the same way
that you would make liquid imo from an
imo uh one and you get imo2 and then we
also tried
where we did the normal imo collection
and then introduced insect frass at the
point of im03
rather than at the point of im01
and we found that while it did work it
did not work anywhere near as well it
did
the the efficacy wasn't anywhere near as
well and then the other one we did is we
did it with im04 and again that was very
similar to im03 while it was it did work
it didn't work as well as doing it at
the im01 stage
so um with that and then again now you
have a bunch of free chitinas that's
available for the plants to absorb in
you know via the roots or any other way
that it wants to because you're just
melting insects in your fields and that
was one of the best general insect
sprays we were able to use that as our
one of our mainstays for our insect
control over in zimbabwe
yeah wow i mean you know what i think
it's probably about time we jump into it
so for anyone who hasn't quite picked up
on it you did a stint in africa just
fairly recently would you be able to
give us a rundown on i guess how the
opportunity just at least initially
presented itself
sure so i've been working with a couple
of different groups out of canada and
for off and on for a couple of years and
one of the groups i'd worked with
previously had someone that was working
with a different group over in europe
and africa and
started talking to them and
they kind of needed someone that knew
the ropes on the cannabis side of things
to go over there and kind of train
people up so
uh ended up getting together with them
took a little bit longer to get the
funding together mostly because of the
fda rules that came in place uh back in
october was october 27th when the sky
fell so um
or whatever it was so that happened and
then anyways ended up over in africa and
in december so um so i was over in
zimbabwe or ended up over in zimbabwe
and then
we're getting everything going we had
750 acres
that we were prepping we had about 15
acres that we had planted and ready to
go
and then the virus hit
and everything stopped
and then i had about 72 hours to get out
of the country if i was gonna get out
wow
so uh yeah so that was uh
that was my stint so hopefully when this
all settles down next year
probably
the i'll think you know we'll we'll
figure it out but right now they
harvested off what was there and
everything's on pause because
i it's it's it's psychotic to try and
move any products around the world right
now and trying to move cannabis is even
harder
so it's just kind of a process it all
and sit on it for now because
financially it's the only thing that
makes sense on the scale that we're
doing it
yeah i totally get that and i mean we're
gonna probably dig around this topic for
a little while but just to go back for a
minute
you mentioned that things are on pause
at the moment i actually know a guy
who's involved in um general hydroponic
stuff and many years ago he was
contracted to go to zimbabwe i think
just to grow some lettuces and things
like that
and he set the operation up it sounds
like kind of a similar situation to you
he felt confident he'd trained them up
well enough and then he left and it was
all going well for probably six twelve
months and then after a while it just
started going really bad and
he was getting emails about it and he's
just like i don't know what's going on
but apparently it's starting to go
really bad and what it ended up
happening was that the locals were just
so kind of unfamiliar with um he was
using salt based nutrients in a pure
hydroponic setup but basically what had
happened was they were using like a part
a and b nutrient and
one of the a or the b had run out and
they just didn't understand how it
worked and so they were like oh we just
used the a in replacement if we don't
have any b
and it just kind of highlighted that
like it was such a foreign style of
growing that they just they didn't fully
understand it
do you feel like that might be the case
now that if you
like that might be why things are on
pause because there is still a bit of a
learning gap for them to fully get
autonomous with it
no no the reason why everything is on
pause is because they're uh the value of
their dollar is uh
collapsed because of the virus but uh
so that that's honestly but um the the
the other reason but as far as
agricultural stuff um they are
incredibly learned with agricultural
practices especially organic
agricultural practices they they are
very good about uh uh doing a lot of of
stuff that we would consider similar to
maybe natural farming uh but
they also have a huge presence of
syngenta uh if you go into um or
monsanto as you guys may also know them
as um
uh for those you know they that's their
other name but and if you go into harare
or any of the bigger areas uh kodoma or
vic falls or anywhere you're gonna see
syngenta syngenta syngenta and they sell
all they probably sell 85 to 90 of the
seed in the whole country
which sucks
but that's probably the biggest issue is
that it's hard to find it's hard for
farmers to find a seed now the moment
you get away from any of the big cities
it's all organic as can be they they
they don't they've never seen a
pesticide they don't know what a
pesticide is like it's fine right so
it's just about or they do but it's
organ you know they're making ferments
and stuff right it's not like
or artis or they're there's burning
something you know a
smelly herb that to have the smoke waft
through to get them upper you know they
have some other method it's not
one thing i would say and it's funny
because i had this conversation with
somebody else
zimbab actually this week um just
because of the current events in the
united states is that i said you know if
something were to happen with the
government in zimbabwe everyone can just
kind of farm like everyone knows how to
farm everyone knows how to self-sustain
themselves from a survival standpoint
whereas in the united states people
don't you know large percent united
states doesn't even know how to plan to
seed
and grow a bean or tomato you know it's
just not something that people are
familiar with or been exposed to so
whereas you know a lot of these other
parts of the world yeah maybe they don't
have all the things that we have but you
know what everyone there can feed
themselves if they have to or you know
they they they all have a garden every
single person has a garden in their on
their property they're they're grown
food you know and it's culturally you
know
a lot different where they're they are
more so sustaining in terms of food
production and you know if i was going
to get stranded and something like that
you're going to have more food in a
place like that even though it sounds
kind of crazy
so i i think that probably a question a
lot of a lot of our listeners are
wondering is whereabouts in zimbabwe
were you based geographically and what
type of strains did you found work
really well there
sure so we were growing a couple of
different cbd cultivars in kodoma um i
actually don't have the strain list in
front of me i have it i posted it up on
my instagram i have the exact strains
that we were growing there we were
actually the first company to legally
import them into zimbabwe um actually
funny story on that which i'm sure the
uh
the guys at the airport don't want me to
tell you but i'll tell you anyway
because it's funny um
so we we get these seeds in right and
it's like a big giant pack of seeds and
like you can smell it right because
they're fresh seeds right so they they
smell like terpenes like you it smells
like a fat old bag of wheat and they
open it up and the cops are like whoa
and then they're like can you do this
and then they want to see paperwork and
then they held it for a couple of extra
days and and checked with the ministry
of health and all this other other crap
so so we finally get it clear and then
they come out and then so the the they
have like the like the narc cops or like
the drug cops there and they're laughing
about and they're like cool well let's
test the dogs right so they go and they
grab the dogs and they bring they put
three packages out and ours is one of
them and the dogs completely ignore it
and they get real mad and we're just
sitting there laughing and then we
realize like they're getting really
they're they're getting more mad so we
just kind of like can we get the paper
can we get paperwork and get out of here
now like
it's time to go
like let's not push the limits
yeah
lovely so i mean in terms of zimbabwe
were you more up north more down south
or do you feel like the whole area is
just pristine it doesn't matter where
you are
sure so i was like i spent so i did go
out and visit in yonga which is in the
far east over by mozambique um but then
i also um where my the farms where i was
working in was one is in morindera
and the other one was in um north of
kodoma i'm not going to give the exact
location just for security reasons but
north of kodoma
so
um was probably the biggest large city
nearby
do you feel like zimbabwe in particular
has a really nice sort of environment
that's conducive to growing or do you
think that the end game is that like
most african countries will just be set
to go hard
no i think zimbabwe particularly has a
wonderful climate temperature wise and
humidity wise and everything else and
the soil is very conducive for it so
fantastic and i mean when you're there
did you try to grow anything in the soil
or was it all aquaponic so
one one of the two farms i worked with
was aquaponics and the other one was
soil so
okay cool and what would be your
recommendations for someone looking to
work with some soil they've got that's
never been like tended to so to speak
and they're going to have to maybe put
some inputs in what are your go-to
inputs that you might put into the soil
to help give it some nutrients
so um
oh man it's really going to depend on
what that soil is so if there's a lot of
not a lot of organics in it i would say
you know making sure you can add a
compost or some you know leaf mulch or
something like that
um or you know it's really just going to
depend on it you know my first thing
would be get a soil test and find out
what's going on in there and you know
get some under a microscope slide so
that you can see what the heck is going
on
sure i guess maybe one of the more
commonly heard claims i hear is that uh
basically
uh what is it biochar and cover crop i
always hear those two things because
it's like it makes sense in theory right
do you feel like that actually works in
practicality
so
i've done a lot of testing with biochar
um i'm gonna be an outlier and tell you
i think it's in
75 to 90 percent of people's farms
complete snake oil
i don't think it'll do anything if
you're doing good composting good
microbial inoculation your knf inputs
you are going to notice absolutely zero
difference in yields terpene content or
cannabinoid content and i say this
because there's a farm in gilchrest
colorado that i've worked with that we
put together in 2013 or 2000 2013 and um
i couldn't remember it was 13 or 14. um
and so they have six acres of hemp there
okay now there's half acre of uh zero
control half acre of one percent biochar
half acre of control half acre of three
percent biochar half figure control half
acre of five percent biochar and a full
acre control that we were doing some
other testing on
um
in
all those years we've had no difference
in yield the only difference we've
noticed is the size of the cover crop
uh is larger on where the higher amount
of biochar is so you could say that
there's more microbial biodiversity in
the surface of the soil strictly
speaking for cbd hemp
it has made no visible financial yield
growing at a half acre scale
over all those years
so and i can say that based on you know
numerics and you know financials so
based on that then yes i i think it's
not no if you have a super compact clay
or you have just really terrible soil or
no organics at all yeah it's going to do
wonders for your soil but if you're
dosing with all your normal you know
probiotics and your knf inputs and
everything else it's not you're gonna
you're already adding all the microbials
and a lot of the other stuff that you
have you don't need an extra space for
it to survive
so you're not really adding us something
that's not already being colonized
happily you're you're inoculating on top
of
you're just adding a space for the
inoculant but if you're already adding
the inoculant it's kind of a redundant
sure
and just as a sort of a random curiosity
for myself
do you feel like the microbial diversity
there is plentiful enough that you don't
need to supplement with any sort of
microbial product that would might be
like more external or even something
like say a mycorrhizae
uh it really depends on what you're
doing now i prefer to still do some some
external inoculants um i've found in
aquaponics just in terms of products
mammoth p is probably been one of the
biggest in terms of
uh amount of testable
in ppms available of a nutrient from any
microbial i've ever tested with
aquaponics it is the one that has
increased
any nutrient by the largest amount by by
not adding any additional salt right so
by not adding any physical phosphorus
just by adding the micro microbe it is
increased phosphorus on average around
30 to 35 percent in on aquaponic systems
so if you can get that established and
get those microbes in your system it's a
great inoculant i often recommend that
and recharge from from real growers over
at uh the guys that do do grows we often
recommend both of those for people
inoculating their new aquaponics systems
to get those bacteria species as
nitrifying bacteria those those initial
mycorrhizal protectants you know
something that's going to get in there
and outcompete pythium and root rot and
a lot of the other issues you have with
with aquatic-based systems be it
aquaponics or hydroponics
yeah wow what a powerful testament to
the product
so
if we get into the nit gritty of the
aquaponics itself what sort of things
are you feeding the fish and
supplementing the system with and do you
still have to use any because i i think
i remember i spoke with you maybe a
while ago and you mentioned that
like iron can sometimes be hard to find
you might need to supplement with it
have you found workarounds for those
things or it's still like you know
there's certain principles that still
apply
so um regardless of what's doing with
aquaponics you know fish waste is not
microbially or i'm not not microbial
chemically designed
to grow plants right like that was never
part of the plan with that so um fish
waste does not provide everything it
will provide the vast majority so we can
get anywhere depending on cultivar 80 to
90 percent of the nutrients that we need
for feeding uh
you know for almost any cannabis
cultivar uh is going to fall into that
range from the base nutrient now we will
need to supplement potassium
calcium
uh iron and some micronutrients
depending on the cultivar now certain
cultivars will really plow through
molybdenum and zinc and a couple of your
micronutrients other ones don't it seems
to be more predominantly on the ones
that are more colorful your purples and
your oranges and they seem to especially
molybdenum they plow through it because
they need it for the anthocyanin
production
so
and and anyone that doesn't know if
you're having problems with your purples
not being purple add some molybdenum
sodium molybdenate at uh like a 0.1 part
per million dosage it'll it'll
immediately turn your plants purple if
they have the genetics for it
again it has to do it and you got to
trigger the gene but plants will also
create extra anthocyanin to bind up a
mild molybdenum toxicity so you can
actually force the plants if it has it
to
produce extra anthocyanin by a forced
mild quote you know again
mild
molybdenum toxicity
you go too hard you're going to cause
all the problems with your nitrogen but
you know that's a whole separate
discussion but uh um but for purples you
know definitely so
uh and silica so i've done a ton of
side-by-side testing with silica and we
did silica testing um and what actually
uh i'll we'll start off with the
beginning of why we started looking at
silicon with aquaponics was
specifically was there was a gentleman i
can't remember his name at a boulder
when i used to work at the aquaponics
source i used to work and help we had a
whole plant team and a product team and
everything and we had different things
that we worked on and developed
well the plant team was trying to figure
out why our aquaponic tomatoes always
tasted slightly different than the than
the hydroponic or soil tomatoes so
we went and had them tissue sampled and
sure enough it was silica and chloride
were the two things that were missing
which was very strange um and this was
before we learned about flavonoid
testing and all that we were looking at
this more from a nutrient kind of
perspective before uh you know
anyways i was a little bit greener on
the trying to fine-tune this on the on
the plant side of things i wasn't
thinking cannabis mindset with the
vegetables you know what i mean um so
anyways so
uh so um the issue so what we did was we
tested that and noticed the silicon the
chloride so what we did was we upped the
silica we upped the chloride and we had
a huge increase in uh not only yield
above about 15 to 20 but we also had a
reduce in reduction in powdery mildew
and molds and we also had a reduction in
um
we also had a reduction in uh issues
with um uh uh crispness so if we
harvested lettuce and put it in the
fridge we were able to get anywhere from
five to eight additional days in the
fridge where it's you know before it
started to wilt and look like crap
so we were also you know and other
things like powdery mildew and cucumbers
and and
the total um um failure rate of flowers
on cucumbers were also increased by
increasing silica as well and it seems
to be a threshold around
60 parts per million in aquaponics
really seems to be that minimum
threshold at least for most crops and
then cannabis seems to be a little bit
higher than that but um
but in general that's some of the
different rabbit holes that i've had the
pleasure of jumping down with some of
the different groups that i've worked
with
yeah wow very very detailed analysis of
what's necessary there
a question i've always been wondering is
do you think that
even with the use of aquaponics if
you're in somewhere like zimbabwe you
could still get some sort of terroir or
do you think it just it probably has to
be in the ground to sort of do that
also i do think and i and i
so i'm two minds in this so one you're
not i wouldn't qualify it i wouldn't go
in with an aquaponics system into humble
and say it's a humble terrar right like
that's it's not gonna have the the
microbes and the flavors from the ground
what i would say is that you could make
a good argument that aquaponics is its
own terrar because it is its own root
biome that is completely unique now you
will have unique two different climates
and you could say maybe you know certain
things and you could absolutely develop
something similar because again your
microbial biodiversity and it's funny
you mentioned that nasa did a study
a couple years ago and i was working
with a vegetable farm that participated
in this and they did dna studies on
trying to see okay well what are all the
mineralizing microbes if we went to mars
or someplace like that what's the pack
of microbes we need to bring to
aquatically mineralize either human
waste or animal waste or whatever we're
going to do for fertilizer so so
whatever you know biological waste that
we're going to process and to plant food
what packet of microbes do we need so
they tested all manner of soil microbes
and aquatic microbes and they had some
cool results so one of the things they
found was that the the most are the
least biodiverse aquaponic system
was um 168 percent more biodiverse than
the most biodiverse soil system they
test in terms of microbial species count
so they they the aquatic biome just
slaughtered it but if you think about it
the aquatic microbiome has had an extra
billion years to evolve
so of course that makes sense right that
that's a no-brainer
so
that was really interesting and then
also uh they found that you know none of
the aquatic tests had the same microbes
you had radically different chains of
microbes that were mineralizing the same
minerals and completely different chains
some of them were two some of them were
up to eight and everything in between
and each each one was different there
was no universal and that was i think
one of the even trippier things is that
you have all these different ways that
this has co-evolved around the planet to
mineralize xyz minerals a thousand
different times so who knows you know
there is such a big rabbit hole and no
one's looking at it for aquatic
mineralization it's there's billions of
dollars in ag tech sitting there on the
table and and no one's even looking at
it you know it's really a huge if
someone out there is listening to this
and wants a gold mine there you go you
know pick what pick pick literally any
microbial chain and 78 of them will live
in a terrestrial microbiome so you 78 of
those microbes that you can hunt for
will live in both soil and aquatic so
it's it's an area that needs a ton of
research it needs lots of university
students doing lots of papers it needs
all of those things
wow yeah that's almost like a gold mine
of papers you could put out on that
subject
i guess
i then start to think
what would be in your mind the most
optimal end goal for these producers in
africa do you think that it's going to
get probably turned to oil or do you
think that the flower could become of
good enough quality that it gets
imported into more kind of uh expensive
western sort of countries as a
generalization or what what do you think
is the ideal end goal for these african
countries such as zimbabwe
i think really their bulk goal is to do
bulk isolate production doing oils that
are separated out
they're not again they're not going to
compete for quality the they can compete
for scale you know the cost of labor
there is very cheap um your average
person there makes eight to twelve
thousand dollars a year most of them are
closer to eight or less i'm just giving
the idea of people in zimbabwe in terms
of u.s money per year
and that's you know middle class so
um
do the math on how cheap some of these
people are living per year or per day
you know it's
you know
something that neither you and i could
are capable of doing that's for sure um
and um
but um
uh definitely something where i think
that you're gonna have you know these
low labor costs are gonna end up being a
player in the market long term where
what are you gonna do when someone can
bring over shipping containers and stuff
that's being produced for eighteen
dollars a pound
or twelve dollars a pound you know
uh if you're competing you know whether
they what they will do is drive out the
aurora drive out the canopy drive out
the the the budweiser drive out the
marlboro and the philip morris that
they'll drive all those guys out you
know what i mean and and i'm okay with
that
you know we all the craft growers that
listen most of the craft girls on the
show they're not competing with them
anyway they're not even on the same
league
so yeah so i've actually heard of some
other people who've done some stuff down
in africa like most notably uh gene
finder has done some stuff and i'd even
heard some rumors i think it might have
even been put out by of all people
chimera that
um like the philip morrisons are
interested in looking into africa did
you see any other people or other
operations down there looking to do
anything like that
oh yeah and actually the the i guess
what i would say is the most concerning
is you have uh there's a chinese uh
group that's kind of moving into africa
that wants to kind of push into the
cannabis market and they're trying
really hard to find genetics they don't
have genetics they were desperately
trying to talk to anyone westerner for
genetics they wanted to desperately buy
anything that i had um that that seemed
to be the thing that they didn't have um
but they are setting up some big
operations over there and you know who
knows what they're going to do the to
the the price points in the industry i
mean they already have completely
collapsed the fiber market and the oil
market you know price point wise to make
it really hard to compete so um let's
hope that they don't try to move in on
the other stuff but again
they're still never going to compete
with the craft growers you're not going
to the people that are going to go you
know that are buying high quality stuff
right now are not going to ever look at
that anyway you know what i mean
yeah of course and so i guess my next
question although for you it would be
specific to zimbabwe but i think you
could broadly apply it to anyone who's
going to a kind of an area where
like there is cheaper labor and they're
looking to set up a bigger operation do
you think in that sort of general
situation you would look to bring in
some genetics like what you just
mentioned or do you think that it might
be more wise to work with any
pre-existing cultivars that might be
there
no so i actually i well
i i have access and have some some
wonderful zimbabwean cultivars i picked
up and then younger but
they are not heavy yielders they're
they're not commercially viable stuff
you if you're growing on a commercial
scale and if i'm growing and setting up
for someone as a consulting client i'm
setting it up as a resin factory and it
needs to pump resin out i don't care
about anything other than that you know
we're trying to pump flour and pump
resin you know that that's what we're
doing it needs to turn over quickly it
needs to be resistant to most things it
needs to not be a pain in my ass to grow
it's not to have some wack-ass feeding
schedule that's going to make me pull my
hair out or some other baby thing that
that particular strain is is going to
annoy the crap out of me about that
everyone you know everyone has a strain
they love but it does this xyz weird
thing if you don't do it right right so
um
try to avoid all that stuff and just get
to something that's easy consistent that
people that aren't on the same skill
level as me can can pump out and run and
and it doesn't matter what i can do it
matters what the guys i train that leave
behind can do and that's the thing i
think that a lot of people set
themselves up for is that anybody that's
high skill level could come into
anywhere and crush it and get the place
back and go online it's can you train
the guys and then leave them with a
coloring book simple methodology that
they can follow after that that that
they can succeed with and that's really
i think
an area where um you know
it's hard to because there isn't a lot
of agricultural education in africa in
local languages
in fact there's almost nothing in
agriculture stuff in shona which is the
native language in zimbabwe it's really
hard to find even plant names and stuff
like that when i was trying to research
plant names and pathogens and and pests
it was hard for me to look up that in
shona or english right like there's just
nothing they just it's all verbal like a
lot of african stuff is just verbal
right they just don't
there's not a lot of documentation or
there isn't
like the language isn't there for that
type of long-term documentation for lack
of a better word with
with the languages right for for our
specific craft it just hasn't been
developed yet there's no word for
terpene or cannabinoid or it just did
you see i'm saying like it's almost like
with the
with like the people that um
uh i know uh uh uh was it uh oregon
pdx uh um
oh i like blanking out on her name right
now uh uh jared and angela uh pranks
they're working on the the sign language
for the cannabis um it's almost like
that they don't have the language for
our industry in the african languages so
some conversations are hard to have
yeah just trying to explain things on a
basic level when they don't even
understand even if they understand
english i just went over their head you
know what i mean
yeah yeah and then you know
and and then also just trying to make
sure that like
when you're trying to find seeds or if
you are trying to acquire anything that
like it can be quite the
quite the hectic thing to do and and
quite the long journey to get to the
farm or you know you might have to
i don't know jump on one leg and rub
your belly to get them to believe that
you're not a cop and all kinds of other
goofy stuff but generally when you have
waist length dreads it gets you by most
of that
i like that and you you bring up a very
valid point you know like we both need
to have the same lexicon otherwise we
can't really talk can we but just to
jump back to one of the previous points
if you're willing to what sort of
genetics did you take with you that you
thought would do well there and long
term do you think that down the track
people will breed stuff specifically for
that area
sure so so the stuff that i specifically
brought was durbin uh and then i brought
some uh reunion island seeds
which uh the old zamasu
yeah i love it um so uh because they're
damn near there it's very close latitude
wise to where we were it was not far off
a lot so i figured hey if it's gonna
work
and get me the that that weird gene
expression with the continuous flower
i need to grow it you know at that same
lot you know as close to that latitude
as i can and hey if i'm going to be in
zimbabwe hey let's go for it right i'm
going to be there so um
and then um what's the other one g13
hash plant from dragonfly earth medicine
was the other one that found its way
over there allegedly um so
uh that's the other one that uh was the
the thc cultivars that we brought over
um we had some other stuff that again i
haven't written down on the post i i
don't remember what the other stuff was
but those are the ones that i brought
over
personally for my own smoke
sure and i mean to me the the first two
you mentioned the durbin and the zamal
sounds like pretty clear winners you can
understand why it's going to work well i
am curious to know did the g13 hash
plant just freak out or it handled it
pretty reasonably well considering
it loved it yeah i know
yeah
all of them did great i mean and i
specific i knew it was a pretty it's a
pretty sativa leaning plant and it i
just it's my favorite thing to smoke all
day long if i'm gonna smoke one plant
all the rest of my days
uh ever since last april when i was
first introduced to that cultivar and
it's got its claws into me so
yeah it's thanks josh and kelly yeah
it's a beautiful plan i think i've been
lucky enough to try some of that same
cut and yeah very special stuff
so the next question i guess i was
interested in is that we're hearing a
lot of talk these days about how
there's kind of this detrimental i don't
know if detrimental is the right word
but people comment about how we see a
lot of hemp sprayed with distillate and
it's getting passed off do you think
that's that is a bit of a risk with the
massive influx of cheap distillate
coming into the market long term or do
you think that's more of just like a
short-term thing and people will catch
out how like you know they'll learn to
pick up on it and just stop buying it
no i mean i think it's definitely a
problem i think it'll definitely become
a problem especially international stuff
where it's a lot easier to hide it on
bigger batches
but i mean [__] i
i can remember a lot years and years ago
seeing people spraying garbage weed with
terpenes in california you know as soon
as they were as soon as uh river was a
blue river or what was it blue river
chirping yeah yeah it came out with blue
dream yeah
yeah and as soon as they came out with
those terpene vials man it was all over
like like that's
when as soon as people started doing the
isolated terps and spraying it i can
remember seeing i know
i was where i went and had a guy i was
consulting for in san diego and he comes
up to me with this bag of white moldy
like very clearly pm covered weed he
thought it was awesome because he
thought it was frosty and he had never
seen pm before and it was sprayed with
terps to hide the the boy high school
locker room smell yeah and he it dude we
i about fell out of my chair laughing
because this dude had paid like three
grand or some [__] for some moldy ass
weed oh yeah i guess it is a it's a real
risk factor isn't it but i mean it
brings us on to the more valid question
which is
what do you think will be kind of the
next step with distillates where do you
what sort of products do you think will
be utilizing this more cheaper
distillate do you think pens is going to
be just you know it's just full steam
ahead or where do you see things going
well the pen market is rapidly changing
because um you have all the one we don't
know well the pen market's interesting
because you have terpenes that are
highly regulated in europe in an
isolated form that are not regulated in
a blended cannabis form which at some
point is going to have to have some type
of legal reckoning at least in the eu
market and probably on the wider
international market
and then you have um
you know pens are popular but again you
have the coils that depending on quality
can be a health hazard you have you know
depending on the blend with the terpenes
can again be a health hazard so but
people love them
the pens are one of the most popular
things out here edibles are also super
popular and cooking oil is super popular
here in oklahoma those three are are
about 65 of the market because it's a
lot of older people they want to be able
to dose themselves and they want
something that's not a little more
discreet and not you know chiefing out
the neighborhood you know what i mean
yeah certainly and i mean
it raises a really personal point to me
because i've actually uh i've cut down
my usage quite a bit over the past year
and i'm i'm perfectly happy with that
and it's made me realize when i go have
a hit of some of the australians i used
to be puffing on all day it it sends me
flying and so i can totally empathize
with older guys who are like i just want
something that tastes good and doesn't
destroy me do you think that this will
become a growing
kind of demand in the market and
eventually we'll almost see like a
divergence of strains where there's like
the everyday stoner strains and then the
more casual guy ones because
being in that more casual sort of
like let me just put it this way if
someone gives me some weed and i and
it's strong and i hit it man i'm just my
day's gone
yeah i know and it's funny um you
mentioned that i i was in the colorado
market when that first legalized and
wrecked and you know what one of the
highest sellers was the first two years
was the rookie cookie which was a five
milligram cookie
five milligrams right so think about
that you know so there's a huge market i
would probably say it's 30 you know an
enormous percentage of the market of
people that are they're weekend warriors
the people that haven't smoked in 20
years or whatever and they they don't
want to get obliterated and they don't
know how to dose themselves like
with a joint or a bong or certainly not
with dabs right so so
uh they need a way that they can dose
themselves so you know i've worked with
a bunch of different technologies that
we'll be bringing to market later this
year that help with that um that uh
we're not ready to release publicly yet
but um i have a new facility that we're
pretty close to getting ready here in
oklahoma uh in the next couple of weeks
that will uh in august we'll have some
announcements about but um we have a
couple of different versions of stuff
that allow us to adjust the potency and
maintain the terpenes and a couple of
other cool things that'll allow us to um
give some more rookie versions but of
those types of products but i do think
you are going to see a huge demand for
those you know more lower potency
products because again that really is
the vast majority the people that dab
all day and the people that smoke lots
of blunts and joints and you know a lot
of the people that grow
use it pretty heavily right but we're
not the majority of users we're we're
probably you know we're five ten percent
of the market you know we're a very
small minority uh of the overall
cannabis market so we need to all
remember that and i think a lot of us
forget that because we get so used to
the dab culture and everything that uh
you know we forget that most people just
smoke joints on on weekends right so
or after work you know
yeah totally totally and i mean it's
interesting you raised the point about
the rookie cookie because my next
question to you was going to be do you
think there are any major leaps to be
made in the edibles field or do you
think it's simply just about making it
taste better and less like weed or do
you think there's like some next
generation like leap that might happen
that makes it even better
oh yeah there's a ton of advancements in
bioavailability that are not being
exploited right now in the market
without getting into specifics and
getting myself into trouble there's a
bunch of different ways that you can
rapidly increase the the potency of of
cannabis and sometimes you know 5x
uh and efficacy or even more on you know
by changing some variables and and
changing the way that your body looks
and uptakes the the molecules be it cb1
or cb2 receptor or some of the others um
you can get down some pretty cool rabbit
holes um again without getting myself
into trouble uh with ndas that i've
signed
yeah we won't we won't uh go too far in
that direction but that's there's
definitely some cookies for people to go
follow up on them
if they're so interested
so
on the topic of edibles i was interested
in picking your brain do you feel like
there's any difference in the quality of
edibles produced in terms of the strains
used and i don't just mean like in terms
of the yield you might get back but do
you think a certain strain makes a
better edible or it's it it's a
processed it's so processed to the point
that you kind of lose that sort of
originality of the strain it came from
originally
uh so i think there's it's kind of a
two-part question so uh first part i
would say is that one terpenes
absolutely are going to have an enormous
impact on the efficacy of your
um um you know medicinal value of your
edibles the same way that they do for
smokables um uh you know let's just take
example seizure medications okay so if
you have cbd okay and i have um and i
treat someone with cbd and they don't
respond okay you there's certain um uh
cannabinoids i'm sorry certain terpenes
that you can combine with cbd i don't
remember the exact ones but i know that
um
uh uh
what's his name house of harlequin uh
wade laughter um he he talked about it
extensively when he was on my show uh i
believe it was episode 140 of of the
growing with fishes podcast if you want
to know exactly
he talks about the specific terpene
groups in that episode but um
there's certain terpenes that actually
will help dramatically suppress cannabis
seizures when taken with cbd but there's
other ones that will antagonize them so
if you take pining and terpinoline and
beta-carothylene those are
hyperstimulative terpenes you do not
want those as a seizure patient you want
to avoid those explicitly because they
can induce seizures so you might have
someone that has a cbd cultivar that's
high in those that's not getting relief
from their seizures or even having them
induced by them
whereas you take that same patient give
them a cbd cultivar with those different
sets of terpenes and absolutely you know
have
efficacy with that product so so that's
a absolute thing now um
one thing that i found that and this is
goes back to when i was first doing this
back old school uh in the free people's
market was um uh doing decarboxylation
in sealed vessels so we would do it in
mason jars or in a pressure cooker or
some kind of other seal thing and
initially we did it was to see basically
to not let the whole neighborhood or
apartment complex know that we're
cooking right
it's kind of a problem if i'm making a
big batch you know everyone knows in the
neighborhood you know my house smells
great well when you're in a less than
legal area that can be a very big
problem depending on who your neighbors
are so we originally did that but what
we realized was we were trapping the
terpenes in so we so the method that i
prefer to decarboxylate if you're
decarboxylating flour for those at home
that are are making their own edibles is
take take your flour
dry it out and then fill your mason jars
up about fifty percent of the way and
then put them in the oven uh
and and cook them at about 240 degrees
for you know one hour and that'll
decarboxylate your stuff really really
really well and then also trap those
terpenes in it also won't stink your
house up or it very you know you'll be
it'll smell maybe like you're smoking a
joint like you'll know that there's weed
there but it's not you're gonna bomb the
house out right
so then you take those and put them in
the fridge
and what that's going to do is
cool and condense the any of the the
compounds that were turned into a gas
mainly your terpenes allow them to
recondense back onto that plant material
and and come back out of the gaseous
form
well that means that when i take that
and now uh use that for making my
edibles that that's now rebound back up
on the plant material or what i prefer
to do is i'll take that that half of
decarboxylated jar and i'll fill it two
thirds of the way with with my oil or
butter or whatever i want to infuse and
i'll throw that in a pressure cooker and
we'll we'll pressure infuse that and
decarboxylate that uh you know and we'll
decarboxylate it first and then we'll
we'll pressure infuse it for you know 30
to 40 minutes
in a pressure cooker
at you know 5 to 10 psi real low psi
real real low uh and you know just
enough to to get that pressure on the
jar and then and then take those out and
then take that strain it now i have my
infused oil and that's that's one of the
easiest ways for people at home to make
high quality high potency decarboxylated
oil and you don't have to use a pressure
cooker but it does help
what what one thing i did want to add to
that don't do the butter or oil and then
put them in the jar if you don't have a
pressure cooker they will explode in the
oven
if you're going to do that method with a
jar infusion you do have to put it in a
pressure cooker you have to have even
pressure on the outside and inside
otherwise they will explode just as a
safety thing
yeah very valid point
so if we just jump back to the africa
stuff for a minute i just wanted to
touch on a topic you mentioned way back
but i put a little dot because i wanted
to come back to it is you were talking
about how
with your aquaponics system you could
get away with i think you said about 18
of the water usage usages some other
sort of methods and it immediately made
me think for for somewhere like africa
or anywhere where there's like a water
scarcity that's got to be one of the
determining factors in terms of the
system you use is that correct
absolutely places like island nations in
the caribbean uh australia uh africa and
particularly island nations because they
don't have a big water supply i know
there's a there's a gentleman who does
um
uh i can't remember the name of his farm
but he's in barbados that that is now
also doing cannabis but he was doing
vegetables for a long time and it he was
doing it because they their their entire
total gallonage of fresh water on the
whole island is very limited they only
get so much rain and that's all the
fresh water they have unless they bring
it in or desalinate so um you know
having an area that especially when
they're hyper limited on that and and
cutting that down can be a great way to
you know reduce the the water per crop
yield and you know you can even further
reduce it if you're in extreme measures
now i don't recommend this for
commercial cannabis production because
the liability of if your indexing valve
fails you can lose five rows of cannabis
in a couple of hours um but
uh if you're doing it for vegetable
production and you're willing to ha
to gamble that or have someone that's
just actively inspecting them every few
hours
which you can do when labor costs are
cheap obviously um
and then um
uh you you can do that with with
indexing valves where i can run just
enough water to do one trough and the
sump to to take that back in and i can
run four or six troughs of of plants uh
you know whoever length
off of one body of water and you can get
extremely low in terms of total water
volume for a large amount of plants
you know per run in extreme cases and
we've done vegetable production that way
in jamaica and then uh some cannabis
with that methodology again i try to
avoid it with cannabis because it's too
much of a liability if i have an
equipment failure i just lost a
greenhouse and
you know if you you do not ever want to
explain that to someone you're working
for because
it's not going to go well
yeah i can i can certainly imagine that
conversation
in terms of when they're finished
growing the product and they're going to
harvest it they're going to dry and
they're going to process it what sort of
things happen there do we see the sort
of drying techniques you might see on
say
mr nice's instagram feed where there's
like these crazy warehouses just with
tons of biomass just all drying out is
it like that or is it a bit more like
out in the sun how do they dry and
process and manage all of the biomass
once it's grown
are you talking in africa yeah apologies
yeah in africa
sure so in africa remember zimbabwe was
the tobacco capital of the planet so
tobacco it has this enormous tobacco
infrastructure so they have these huge
brick tobacco barns that are
you know an acre two three sometimes
four acres in size that are that are you
know basically just um uh corrugated
steel and brick
and you know some local wood to timber
them up
and there's huge bays and they have
these furnaces on the end where they
heat them up and they run warm air
through them to heat the tobacco so
they're they're basically taking those
and you know cleaning them up uh running
ozone through them so they can uh kill
all the bad microbes or anything that
might be living in there to to sterilize
them
and then converting those into cannabis
drying barns and at least on the large
scale i've seen three separate farms in
zimbabwe i had a chance to visit some of
our competitors not competitors but
other producers i guess is probably the
better way to put it in zimbabwe and
they were all all of us included all of
us were using you know old tobacco
properties because they have the uh the
well infrastructure they have the
irrigation infrastructure they have the
water reservoirs and they have the
tobacco drying bar you know the drying
barns they have the the tractor
buildings that we can use for you know
extraction and everything else so it has
kind of the
pre-built infrastructure or at least the
the framework for a pre-built
infrastructure that you know maybe it
needs to be brought up to code maybe i
need to
you know update things in terms of
modernization but
you know 80 of what i need is already
there
yeah wow and in terms of the processing
does it take place in africa or does it
go somewhere else how do they do that
part
so so uh almost it's interesting
there's a couple of ways that it happens
from african countries
so one way that happens is they'll take
it dry it and ship it out as dry biomass
another way they'll do it is take it and
separate the oil and then sell that and
basically 55 gallon drums of
of oil or 30 gallon drums of oil or
whatever
the other way that they'll do it is um
they'll take it they'll dry it
safe
down to 35 40 or 35 percent then they'll
ship it to australia and dry at five
more percent and now it's processed in
australia and now it can qualify for
australian gmp and and thusly eugmp and
backdoor into the eu so you have a lot
of companies that are producing in
you know other parts of the world be it
south america or africa that are
backdooring it into the eu market via
australia and
i don't know how long that door is going
to last but at least currently that
that's a way that some of the larger
companies are doing it and
you know again i haven't moved anything
since
february january or february so that
could have changed you know i don't
quote me on that and say that i was
wrong if that's changed since then but
um that was how it operated up until you
know
things started getting crazy over there
in africa and i came back in april so
yeah i mean of course all comments taken
in good faith
you mentioned earlier and i wanted to
specifically ask about this
the price of the oil it's astronomically
low i think i heard before we even
chatted a few months back someone quoted
something like 200 a gallon or just
something which just blew your mind open
what do you think that's going to do to
the global kind of pricing and is it
like what is the price like what's the
going price over there
uh so i don't
i don't know what the current price in
africa is um we were all looking at
that refining it into internet mostly
european markets um
without getting into specifics that may
or may not get me into trouble but um
that was all all going into european
markets so i i could tell you what that
price was but i don't know what you know
what the the low ball stuff that you're
seeing out of there's a big company at
lesotho and a couple other places um i
also know that we originally wanted to
get launched in south africa and then
south africa started randomly arresting
producers that were legally licensed
that were not violating anything
so we got real
sketched out about throwing a bunch of
money down there and i certainly don't
want to spend any time in the south
african jail
so
i hear it's not a very good place to be
so uh we we decided to move up to
zimbabwe where it was a little more
stable and then now
that's happened things have gotten a
little bit a little bit more interesting
in zimbabwe than they were when i was
there and so what kind of seo it all
works out uh we kind of have some
different assets in different african
countries so and that was kind of the
plan too we kind of know that
if you're going to get involved in
africa
africa doesn't always have the best
stability when it comes to government
and regulations so you kind of have to
diversify across a couple countries and
have you know kind of one export company
that can kind of conglomerate the uh
output of those different countries into
you know set contracts for for
different different people
internationally so that's kind of the
easier way to operate over there it
doesn't matter what type of agricultural
crop if we're doing you know maize or
corn or or whatever you know
or cannabis it you know all of them
pretty much operate that way by
diversifying across nations because
again
it just changes too often over there
yeah
sure sure
and so just to go back to yet another
point you mentioned much earlier you
said that you did come across some of
the more indigenous cultivars the land
races but they just weren't suitable for
what you needed the ones you did come
across did you feel like they were
likely affected genetically by some
modern form or they were likely
untouched
well i look i look forward to bulking
them out and giving out a bunch of seeds
for people to to tell me uh uh that's
actually one of the plans i'm working
with a mr green jeans garden
in in uh in california to bulk out a
bunch of those um
so that we have those available for
people to give out but i found that they
are incredibly high in pining it's like
smoking a pine tree i think that was the
thing i instantly noticed and then the
the cerebral high that i don't remember
having since i was maybe a teenager you
know just a mind-blowing cerebral sativa
high that
it was intoxicating and just
i haven't had in just such a long time
and it just was
ugh i just i missed it and i forgot that
i missed it
oh yeah i mean as a lover of sativas
myself that sounds beautiful
in terms of the local population the
local culture what's cannabis
consumption like over there do people
generally grow and smoke it or it's just
not really used
so cannabis is a very uh hush-hush thing
it can get you well the locals can get
seven to nine years in jail so they
generally uh don't share it very often
um but you will find that like in
private
well okay let me make sure i don't get
myself anybody else in trouble in
private areas and private clubs and
things like that it is fairly well
tolerated i've smoked in public quite a
few times but again it was gated public
right like it was not
not like you had to pay to get in but
like
it was on like a balcony or it was like
in a courtyard an area where you kind of
had to get you know go into the bar and
back out the back you know it was kind
of a
off on the side kind of thing kind of
off maybe kind of the way it used to be
in canada before 2004 maybe anyone that
remembers those days where it was
accepted but kind of like keep it on the
dl you know what i mean maybe not so
much bc but certainly more towards the
quebec side of things
um
uh
kind of kind of in that vein so um but
out in the country like you know [__] we
smoked all the time like it was no big
deal but um and then out with the rasta
so there's a lot of rastafari and they
smoke and chief up and that's you know
obviously anywhere near them you're
gonna have a cloud right so but but uh
but in general culturally speaking it's
not very uh popular except for like at
the bar so you go to a bar and and it
has a courtyard outside you'll smell it
right but it'll often be like
stuff that like mexican brickweed people
wouldn't buy
right it's going to be something that
like looks like pine needles and it's
like
probably 80 leaves and maybe there might
be like a little bit of maybe 0.1 to 0.2
grams out of a gram as an actual bud
and then maybe like 0.3 grams of that
seeds
and then like the rest is like leaves or
like some other part of the plant that's
in there
so and then that's on the low end and
then all the way up to stuff that would
compare with like cali stuff like like
really good high quality like some of
the people over there are taking notes
and watching youtube and listening to
podcasts and there i mean it show you
know instantly you can tell who's who's
paying attention to to education and who
who knows what a sense amelia is and all
that and who doesn't because you know
one one is bushweed and one is a
something that looks like it came from a
store here you know
yeah totally i mean and that's that's so
promising to hear that there are there
are people pushing the craft and the art
down there something i've wondered is
you know days gone by and probably less
so zimbabwe but you know historically
there's been certain african countries
which have been notable for the kind of
unique hash they put out and it often
historically would go to amsterdam and
that's how it kind of got the reputation
do you feel like as more modern
production comes in there will be
probably we'll see an end to that and
like maybe not zimbabwe but other
countries that are known for their hash
it'll fall off a bit or do you think
it'll always be there
no so there is no shona word for hash
zimbabwe no one in zimbabwe knew what
hash was and what a dab was like that
a large part of africa doesn't know what
a concentrate is
like or the concept of thereof
like
smoking also is more of a taboo like
just smoking anything is more taboo
there like just culturally than here
like
in terms of general acceptance like yeah
people smoke cigarettes and you can buy
them or whatever but like
not it's it's it's more
like living in some of the more lit
really progressive areas where there
really isn't that many people smoking
um you know it's just not
they export all that like that was like
the dirty white people thing right like
that was not not trying to be racist but
like
that was that was kind of thing that
they kind of were like yeah that's for
them right like it's not for us yeah
sure sure and yeah not trying to be
derogatory by saying that but it
culturally that that's really how it is
there
no heck in in terms of if we're talking
about tobacco i can i can get behind
that that's that's not something i need
but um
you've made me realize this is probably
the longest we've ever gotten to an
interview where we're finally gonna say
all right time for the usual first
question take me back what was your
first experience with cannabis
oh man first experience with cannabis
so my first experience i remember having
i don't remember my first experience i
can remember the first time getting
really high i remember that that i could
tell you had clear as day i was going
and i was working at a
cyber cafe at the time and no one who
knows me knows exactly the cyber cafe
and the town near where i grew up and
there used to be a train station near
there with a guy named dan
and uh
we went there with a friend of mine and
dan and pat and we went over there with
a ceramic bowl that he had made in art
class that looked like a dragon
and uh we had packed a bowl of some good
[__] that one of them we got from a
relative
and uh man and it was a good spot
because of the train station you could
watch the police station and we were
kind of up in elevation so if they
pulled out we could peace out before
they had a chance to come up to where we
were and be out or you know at least
have a chance to hide your weed so it
was a good place to sit and smoke if
you're a teenager
[Laughter]
because it's hard to get snuck up on so
we used to go up there and man i just i
remember that first time going holy crap
like this is
and then the day after that was the
first time i ever got so high i couldn't
get off the floor
i remember that too
brilliant and so
how did that progress did you quite
quickly start smoking more regularly or
it took a bit of a while
no i kind of was off and on and then i
didn't really start smoking heavily
until maybe
four years later
uh and that i was starting to get sick
um and that's when i was so i have a
digestive tract issue and i have issues
digesting things and i was glu i'm hyper
sensitive to gluten and it causes me all
kinds of without getting into gross
details unpleasant trees so um with my
did this digestive system so
i started smoking more and more and more
flour because it was a thing that was
allowing me to eat i was gaining weight
again i wasn't in pain and it was like
solving a long list of my health
problems
and then finally i was dating this girl
and she goes have you tried a raw food
diet and just you know make just
eliminating the possibility that it's
your diet and i said no i haven't but
you know what screw it like i've tried
everything else let's just try it
and uh so we did that and um
found out that that was the issue so
then after that i smoked a little less
cannabis and then i got
when i moved out to colorado in um
2010 or 2011 or whatever it was um uh
got into concentrates and then really
got a lot like suddenly that was like oh
my god i can be a normal person again
like medically like i can feel like a
normal the way i used to before i
started feeling sick
and that was really a huge change for me
but what really made me commit my life
to cannabis was working at the
aquaponics source
and we had this this guy come in
uh and his son the first time he came in
he was a cannabis refugee and his son
was strapped to a stroller he couldn't
move he could he was completely unaware
of the world around him uh and you know
he was disconnected from reality
and
uh
they had just moved there he wanted to
buy a system for himself to he wanted to
grow his son's medicine he wanted to
like you know get his son better
this next time i saw them was three
months later
that kid opened the door on his own
ran in and started smashing eight ounce
measuring glasses and shot glasses i
cried for like an hour straight
because that kid was
functionally a vegetable three months
earlier and he's in here smashing stuff
now acting like a little boy that is the
best gift you can give any human being
and if i can do even half of that for
somebody else
that's what i'm gonna do every day till
i'm dead
and after that that's what got me to
commit to this and that's why i've got
on this long crazy train of riding the
cannabis industries up and downs
throughout all these different
industries and countries and
all the different craziness that it's
brought
me and the different projects i've
worked on and
you know makes it easier to get through
when something like the virus suddenly
pauses your project you're like eh i'm
still doing this for a reason and i'm a
thousand percent behind and i'm not even
going to trip on that
yeah 100 what a what a powerful and
personal story there
so
what was it that made you really
kick the gear and to shift in terms of
kind of seeing that the the cannabis
community wasn't really utilizing
aquaponics in the way that it could be
what was it that got the fire under your
ass about getting the message out there
about aquaponics and cannabis
sure so i've always been a big uh
adequate proponent of um the pet trade
and i was been uh being involved with
aquaponic i'm sorry aquarium societies i
was heavily involved with the bucks
county aquarium society when i was
younger
and um working in the pet trade the pet
trade and the drug trade have a heavy
amount of overlap in case anyone's ever
not worked in the industry uh so
there's a lot of things that get shipped
in boxes from point a to point b and get
labeled as plants or
fish or
other things and they're not always what
you think is in the box and we'll leave
it at that
um so
um i got exposed to a whole lot of
things that
maybe uh not everyone else my age was
exposed
to and i learned how to grow and one of
the things that we did at one of the
places allegedly that i worked at that
um
we would do is take the filtration from
the fresh water systems that would
separate out all the fish waste and we'd
use that on the cannabis plants as
organic fertilizer because we were
trying to cut down on the amount of
fertilizer that we were buying because
you're trying to reduce the amount of
red flags that might get you busted so
allegedly so um
so so i i had kind of worked with that a
little bit and then
um i had gotten into soil growing uh uh
later on uh not long after that and uh i
kind of went down that rabbit hole but i
still always use kind of like tea from
well i would do my water changes and i'd
suck all the fish waste out of the
gravel and it always and the plants
always just kicked butt when we did that
right so i was always kind of fiddling
with it kind of half halfway then i got
into river tanks which is basically
aquaponics uh if you're familiar with it
was a product
inserts for aquariums that allowed the
aquarium water to kind of flow through
little channels where it had plant pots
you put soil and it would kind of
automatically water the plants and
filter the water at the same time and
really allow for a healthy ecosystem
for reptiles mainly um so it was really
cool so i had been doing aquaponics but
i didn't call it aquaponics we called it
river tanks but that we just didn't have
the terminology i had never been exposed
to that word um so when i when i came
out uh west i worked
helping grow some cannabis with some
friends of mine and
when the floods happened in 2012
in colorado when we had the the heavy
floods and it took out the um
uh the uh we had a big mod wall at one
of the places working at the obliterated
half the building so
uh i i was suddenly out of a job so
i applied for i typed in the word aqua
on craigslist and got hired at the
aquaponics source because they were just
moving into a new place and they needed
someone that could help with both the
lab and and product development at the
time when sylvia bernstein was there and
she was kind enough to to give me a
chance over there and
um
uh hired me because i had a you know an
immense amount of experience both with
cannabis and and in vegetables and
everything else i worked briefly for a
company called blood good landscape
which is the oldest landscaping company
in the entire united states based in in
horsham pennsylvania and they've been
around since the 1700s and they have an
incredible
place there but i got a chance to learn
large scale ipm and fertigation and
stuff like that working with with um you
know trees and bushes and shrubs and
annuals for people's landscapes and
stuff and i worked you know selling
plumbing kits and designing stuff for
ponds there on the side helping him out
so i got a chance to kind of get into
that kind of scale before jumping into
cannabis but having that kind of
cannabis experience kind of on the side
at the same time so coming into colorado
and having those kind of dual skill sets
really
really worked out well uh coming into
the cannabis industry and and working on
the bigger scale of things and um
uh and and made an easy transition
working with the aquaponics first and
then we did a whole bunch of research
you know they wanted two weeks after i
was there she goes so we're thinking
about doing canvas i thought it was a
trick question like they're they're
trying to see if i smoke weed or not and
they're gonna see if i admit it they're
gonna fire me so i just totally played
dumb and she about she like adjourned
the meeting and i was like oh you're a
serious
let me tell you some stuff so
so we sat down and then we ended up
doing the whole project and i started
working with the gentleman and robbie
who was actually just on my podcast last
episode
and him and i did a ton of r d with with
cannabis and a whole bunch of different
setups in aquaponics uh a lot everything
from wicking beds to dual root zones to
media beds to dwc to dual root zones to
55 gallon drums to like any kind of
combination or setup you could do so
we're trying to figure out what's the
best commercial viable way because we're
trying to figure out how can we sell
more aquaponics systems and how can we
turn this into a heavily commercial
production how can we further produce
fruit fruiting crops you know not just
cannabis but anything we learn from
cannabis is going to help increase
production for peppers and tomatoes and
cucumbers and and all of those things
are easily transitionable over in terms
of production so
we worked hard on not only medicinal
herbs and essential oil crops but also
cannabis production in an r d greenhouse
that we had 50 by 30 by 18 and we did a
bunch of additional experimentation with
climate control models and stuff like
that with geothermal and solar water
heaters and and
some other stuff that we can get into if
you want to but um we did a whole bunch
of cool r d on that and and really got a
chance to wrap our heads around stuff
and figure out what works what doesn't
um you know what
could work if we did some changes and
really kind of uh splay that out and
figure out how to make it work and and
after that we kind of just took that and
ran with it and then we we started
working with a medical dual root zones
where we have a soil
zone and that really allowed us an extra
layer of control where we can supplement
not only supplement nutrients but
um have additional microbial zones you
know mycorrhizae fungi are incredibly
important for anything that's heavy and
lignin and having done a wide range of
crops in aquaponics the more wood
and lignin a crop contains the more of a
soil area you need so if you're doing
fruit trees you might do a dual root
zone pot that's maybe two-thirds soil to
one-third flood and drain whereas on a
cannabis you're going to be more 50-50
and then on a lettuce you might be able
to do straight dwc you might not even
need soil at all because it doesn't need
any there's no lignin at all in that
plant hardly right so so
that that lignin content is heavily
dependent on some of the metabolites
from the fungal
inputs that come from the fungal part of
the root zone if you don't have them you
either will not get very good growth or
you'll get strange or [__] growth or
you'll get a lack of fruiting production
one of one of the three depending on
what fruit tree species we're talking
about or genus at least that i've worked
with
yeah wow i mean so many questions the
first one which which comes to mind for
me is
for you in your mind right now what's
the ideal composition of your root zone
do you want all living organic soil do
you want like what you just mentioned
maybe a 50 50 where would you be
shooting for
sure so my ideal setup for a cannabis
plant would be 50 50 living soil
with a layer of burlap or cloth or other
root permeable membrane that would be
separate the soil from the flood drain
and then lava rock below that to get you
know some trace minerals and anything
else inside of a contained pot and i
prefer plastic and i know people don't
like that but plastic or ceramic over um
cloth pots because the cloth pots don't
give you a seal if i have a nice seal on
the side of it with plastic or ceramic
when the water floods and drains in the
bottom half of the pot like it does with
the dual root zone pot it creates a
diaphragm action that causes a forced
gas exchange through the soil zone so
not only is the lower half breathing and
getting better gas exchange the soil is
getting better gas exchange meaning all
the soil microbes are even happier so it
gives you this added benefit of almost a
lung effect going on in the root zone
yeah what a brilliant way to kind of
help people um conceptualize the sort of
gas exchange that's going on with the
diaphragm i really like that so a
question i like to ask most of our
guests is a bit you know specific to you
in this case is do you remember your
first aquaponic harvest and will it
always be like you know this golden
thing in your mind because we always
talk to organic growers and they're like
man that first organic crop i'll always
remember it
oh yeah the the first crop i did i
harvested it entirely too early
and i i gave it way too much sugar so it
was like starting to droop leaves
because i had
suffocated the roots
but
and i had it but but it tasted great you
know but i i definitely remember just
the sweetness and how it almost tasted
like caramel it's like smoking caramel
and it was an island sweet skunk and in
fact that's the plant if you go back and
look at my my very first article i did
with high times on aquaponics it's the
plant that's in that picture
oh that was the first one we did that
was full term
with with cannabis we did pictures with
that one
and that we did in aquaponics that was
of any kind of size i had done some
small stuff before that was
pure
i'm sorry i did some other stuff that
wasn't pure aquaponics but that was the
first one that was pure aquaponics start
to finish
including flowering and everything in
between you know from seed
and uh that island sweet skunk is that
cut to this day was still exists in
denver area i gave some to uh to the
dude from dude grows and a couple of
other people and i know he he's raved
about it for for a while on his show as
well
lovely and i mean
i know you're also a friend so you know
shout out to our mutual buddy breeder
steve for creating such a nice strain
hell yeah actually uh one thing about
breeder steve he's the original person
to write about aquaponics in in any kind
of written form back on overgrow he's
the very first person and you can go
back and search i've searched the
internet top and bottom he's the very
first person to ever write about
anything that you could call aquaponics
uh in in with cannabis in documented
form and it was back in 1996 or 97 on on
overgrow.net
wow there you go that's a cool little
tidbit from the archives i like that
so the aquaponics is going well it's all
starting to come together at what point
did you have the idea for starting the
potent ponics podcast
sure so uh potent products podcast
started actually as a debate between
marty and i marty and i were debating on
whether or not you absolutely had like
what the differences was in yield
between dual route zones and non-dual
route zones and marty and i kind of got
into a he a heated discussion then we
realized we were the only people that
were really on a on a had enough
experience to have that level of of an
argument and then we quickly became
friends and then we got both got sick
and tired of hearing you can't grow weed
in aquaponics like we we heard that a
thousand times and we're just sick and
tired of it because we got plant and we
i've pulled six and a half pounds off of
a single plant and aquaponics that we
planted in a greenhouse the last week of
july and pulled down the you know in
october right so
don't tell me you can't grow a lot of
weed on an aquaponic plant you can grow
psychotic amounts of weed on an
aquaponic plant if you if you do it
right so
um and i can prove it i got evidence
video and everything else so
so we basically started the podcast as a
fu to everyone that told us that we we
couldn't grow aquaponically so we're
like screw it we're going to put the
education out and teach everybody how to
do it you know and maybe not every
single trick that we know but you know
98 of them so if we put out education on
how to do it then everyone can know how
to do it understand how it works and
actually
you know they can wrap their heads
around it and maybe they'll even convert
it or adapt it as part of their facility
and and and one of the things is that we
see a lot of soil growers adapting it
for their nursery facilities because
again the accelerated growth rate you
get with the mothers if you're just
producing clones for other people or
you're you know or you're producing a
large amount of plant volume for high
turnover facilities
you need to kind of have you know
accelerated growth rate on your your veg
production and and either you know
growing them out in size or for straight
clone production so a growing you know
even using it in a large soil production
facility it makes a lot of sense to have
it for your nursery operations being
aquaponics even even you know on on just
a minor scale
yeah what a powerful testament to the to
the technology i guess
and i guess for me the question i want
to most know is what's it been like now
to have been running for you know over
200 successful episodes it's such a
tremendous milestone in the podcast
industry you know seeing as we're still
yet to crack 50 over here
what have you learned in that time and
what's your key to success how do i do
it
um i would say uh
one just experience of working with a
wide range of different people um and
then two you know making sure you you
spend a little bit of time to research
your people before you interview them
and and you know try to learn a little
bit about something that maybe they
haven't talked about in other podcasts
or maybe you know get them to go down a
rabbit hole you know we i'm both of us
have had a lot of really incredible um
uh conversations and really wonderful
explanations of some pretty complex uh
ideas and and
methodologies and um you know
biological mechanisms and all types of
things that that you know kind of came
of maybe even an offhanded comment from
someone in chat or or a weird question
or an afterthought that maybe wasn't
even on your original list i know some
of the coolest answers i've gotten or
someone that just randomly had an
offhanded question about something or
maybe something that one of the
panelists had you know it wasn't
something i had written down for
original question list so
it can be really cool and and and
not only that just the diversity of the
industry i mean you have so many
different ways to crack the nut that
um
of growing cannabis and and doing pest
management and doing nutrients i mean
you got hydroponics aeroponics soil
growing living soil
uh aquaponics and everything in between
so it's you know
it's really interesting to see how they
different compare and how different one
accelerates one thing that it's always
interesting to me is seeing you know
different cannabinoid interpreting peaks
with the different production methods
and and how uh certain stressors because
of those different grow methodologies
can really peak certain things as one of
the things i always find really
interesting especially when you're doing
side by sides and you know that maybe a
certain weird thing happened maybe your
ac failed or a pump failed or you know
something else went wrong but it causes
a weird side reaction or
a weird peek we had a
uh
oh how can i say this without getting
myself into trouble we had an anomaly
happen
that caused an immense increase in thcv
uh uh
production in one of our grows that
allowed us to kind of chase the rabbit
hole on what actually is the secondary
uh increaser for that so um we've we've
managed to hit some pretty high levels
on on thcv with some of our one of the
clients that we're working with in
colorado
so
um uh you know there really is a lot of
different and i think that's really an
area where there there isn't a lot of
research especially with cannabis there
might be a way to really you know pluck
the strings the right way to piss off
the plant to really produce a large
amount of xyz compound uh that might be
a a value commercially that is easily
replicatable i mean look at something
like cornsmut um let's use that as an
example with with corn you have corn
that the they spray on the corn which
increases makes this wonderful flavorful
mushroom well um what they found uh and
and mike west has talked about this on
my show uh if you if you're familiar
with him from embark health in canada
he was one of the people that was
involved with uh you got a chance to see
some of the data i believe it was from
emerald cup and they noticed there was a
dramatic increase in cbt levels which is
a miter cannabinoid from powdery mildew
uh infected plants so plants that failed
for pm also seem to have elevated levels
of cbt
so what if cbt ends up being and this is
just for the sake of argument
that cbt ends up being like the next big
breakthrough in cancer drug you might
have people intentionally infecting
flowering rooms two weeks before harvest
with powdery mildew to spike the cbt
like this is something that mechanically
might make sense or or some it might be
a non-pathogenic microbe that we spray
on the plants to boost something in a
way
or it might be a gmo microbe i mean you
know
people might get mad at me for saying
that but you might have something that
that's human made or or human isolated
maybe not even human-made but maybe that
grown
uh and that's isolated from a natural
source that that increases an xyz
metabolite to spike a cannabinoid or
terpene that that we use that we that
five years from now we can't even think
of not using you know i mean that you
could have something that's that much of
a breakthrough that suddenly increases
thc by 10
or or some other thing that that we just
didn't know you know and these are all
things that because of the the
some of the results that i've seen with
different issues that we've run into or
or variables that we've experimented
with but because of the the amount of
control that we have with the dual root
zone aquaponics we've managed to really
have more knobs and buttons that we can
turn and and push and levers to pull
uh to change things and have more more
variables that can be changed in
different parts of the system and and
allow us to unlock some of the stuff and
i think that again is an area that
really could use a lot more flushing out
and a lot more research
a hundred percent that makes me so
excited to hear talk about that because
i mean you know to call on him again
thinking back to when i spoke to breeder
steve myself we kind of spoke about this
not in the level you just did but
talking about how you know when botrytis
infects grapes it led to the like a
creation of a new type of wine and it on
face value you'd be like no i don't want
botrytis
so what you just said it just speaks to
that philosophy so greatly which is
amazing and i guess what i'd want to ask
is
kind of relating back to dragonfly they
mentioned to me that
they feel like when your soil is really
alive and popping you can get different
expressions and you kind of alluded to
that yourself have you noticed a
consistent sort of thing that comes out
when you grow things aquaponically like
a consistent way the profile is affected
or maybe the tur have you noticed
anything like that or you think it's
variable you can't quite make broad
rules of thumb like that
sure i would say across the board
beta-carotelline is is is above
is elevated across the board um
other than beta-carotelline it's the off
the top of my head it's the only one
that i can say is is pretty universal
there's definitely spikes in other ones
and certain in certain cultivars but
that's the one i would say that
you know
any of them express in any kind of a way
are going to have a night and day
difference with the aquaponics um
not not really ringing a bell on any
other ones yeah no but that's great info
in itself because i mean i was always
surprised when i looked at like um
terpene analysis of cookies and you'd
see it had a good amount of
beta-carotene in it and so it's like if
that's what you're growing maybe you can
get an even better profile profile out
of aquaponics
so we one of the biggest increases we've
had strains go from four percent to nine
percent cbd
with aquaponics versus soil control
that's been a huge increase and i know
that uh green the there's a university
that was working with green relief
incorporated which is one of the bigger
companies in canada doing aquaponics
they noticed a 14 increase in thc
production against dwc controls with
dual root zones so um you
know and then also against soil as well
i forget it was like 18 or it was even
more against the soil so um and they
have actual there's a published white
paper on on their breakdown i don't
remember the name of the paper anything
but you can look it up um
if you look up the the
uh aquaponics association meeting for
last year um i believe it's referenced
in the the um the conference meet there
if you're trying to hunt that down
yeah some great leads there for the
listeners to follow up on just to jump
back to our last question about you know
having accumulated all of this
experience and knowledge from having
done your podcast for over 200 fantastic
episodes now
what's one thing that's changed in your
mind since the start and what's a cool
discovery you've learnt along the way
i think uh
the biggest thing i've taken away from
is is thinking about
microbes as a machine i can use to make
things for me
in a plant way like a plant useful way
so for a great example would be like
thinking of knf as a machine that i can
put plant inputs through to isolate
minerals or plant hormones or other
plant bishop beneficial
compounds to accelerate growth rates so
a great example of this would be
something like
a
lactobacilli lactobacilli are great
because that not only do they
out-compete most pathogens e coli
salmonella listeria
they love to feed on all of those things
which has been documented in both the
meat processing industry but also the
agricultural processing industry and in
aquaponic production
specifically through the university of
kentucky state who did a research on
both plant and fish production were they
able to get increase in fish production
of 10 to 15 percent in terms of growth
rate and plant production on average 18
to 20 percent and most crops
uh and that's all aquaponics to the
university of kentucky state um you can
check that out uh uh um joe pate uh um
is the guy that uh
uh george pate i believe is his actual
name is the guy who did the paper on
that uh a white paper on that um but um
i was involved with the lactobacilli
part of that so
what i prefer to do with labs and i'm
sure you've had other people on talked
about labs on the show but i prefer to
do it a little different so i prefer to
do kefir based labs so i'll get kefir
kefir depending on your culture
on how you say it and it's a
lactobacilli culture that seems to have
significantly higher levels of different
vitamin b complexes
also works faster if i'm doing this on a
commercial scale i don't have time to
wait days and days and days for this to
work it needs to work tomorrow so if i
do
large gallons and large volumes with
kefir it will go
you know 24 to 48 hours and it's ready i
don't have time this is commercial
production this is again a resin factory
we're not going after you know trying to
baby everything i don't have time for
that um so
we do a kefir based so we do kefir and
milk instead of the traditional air
collected um stuff
and we find we get dramatic increases in
growth rate compared to
side by inside by sides doing everything
everything else is identically the same
just faster growth rate you get better
vitamin b complexes
what you can do with that is is that add
spirulina so if i'm doing four gallons i
lose some five gallon batches so if i'm
doing four gallons of milk
i will add
um
four cups of spirulina two cups of kelp
extract and top off um uh whatever's
left over with water and put a lid on it
and ferment that
for
anywhere from three to five days the
first time and then once you get the
good culture
of microbes it'll go anywhere from 24 to
72 hours depending on the temperature
you're doing it and what it'll do is
it will separate
your
phycocyanin from your
the spirulina and it'll also separate a
lot of the auxins from the kelp which
and along combining with the vitamin b
gives you kind of three major groups of
plant stimulant
compounds that will dramatically
increase both growth rate but help with
recovery so if i have a plant that's
been mauled by insects that's been run
over by a lawn lawnmower that's been
i don't know
whatever you did didn't water it you you
over watered it you whatever you did
it's just it's hurting bad it's a great
fix-it spray if you i've put it on
plants that had pepper plants that had
been watered in two and a half weeks the
leaves were so dry they were crispy like
paper
and crumble to dust and we put it on it
and we had new growth on every single
leaf node within three days
on dead stems wow so it does unreal
stuff to plants we just recently last
week had it on a
cherry tree that was completely
defoliated defoliated by japanese
beetles and we had new growth on all the
branches within five days
of foliar application so it really just
it wakes the plants up and says hey time
to reboot you know let's get going again
and let's let's just go fast and let's
just crank it out so i wouldn't use it
late in the flower never use labs full
yearly in flower it can mess with the
trichomes
and and you know
great for veg you can use it on the
roots in flour do not ever use it on the
trichome heads in flour
what an absolute goldmine of knowledge
right there i just got to quickly
clarify because this is the question i
probably get asked more than anything
related to kind of what you just said
we often hear the saying you know you
don't want to generally speaking apply
really any foliars during flower because
it can mess with the trichomes as you
said but then you'll often hear some
people and i'll acknowledge sometimes i
say it too it's like well you know if
you don't have a lot of pistol
production before week two i mean you
could use it in the first week maybe the
second do you feel like that's
detrimental or would you say look you
know at a certain point there's buds and
that's when you're damaging it
no the issue is not the pistols the
issues the trichomes the lactobacillic
acid has a negative impact on the
trichomes themselves and it will
directly impact resin production that's
it's a much bigger problem than just
turning the pistols a different color
like with the with the ph changes
sure so just to clarify that point if
someone was early enough in flower that
there was no trichrone formation but
they felt the plant really needed the
fixes but you still you still have that
pre that pre-trichome production you
remember a lot of those trichome heads
they're not developed yet but that
head's still there the the initial cells
are already present on the leaf tissue
right so it just has to grow
so so you're still damaging that site
yeah right so fantastic fantastic
so the next question i wanted to ask i
mean it's on the same topic when we're
talking about knf it's a whole world we
can explore in its own right a story a
story which has always stuck with me
which i believe i think i'm pulling this
out of the libraries of my own memory
here so forgive me if i'm wrong universe
but i think i saw it on the australian
weed growing subreddit and this person
was saying they were doing an aquaponic
cannabis system and they were using i
can't remember the number maybe five
maybe six different types of kelp and
they were like if you use these
different types of kelp you kind of
cover most of the bases have you ever
heard of anything like that and what
sort of k f stuff do you like to
implement into your aquaponics
sure so
so i think that part of that is coming
from a lot of the aquaponic people will
tell you that sea salt or
just kelp in general is kind of the the
mineral fix it for aquaponics like i
don't know what mineral deficiency i
have but if i put this random mix of
trace minerals it'll probably fix it and
it never does but that's the general you
know with lettuce when you're dealing
with the low levels of nutrient they
need yeah it'll fix it most of the time
the problem you have with cannabis is
and this is the problem i see quite
often with people that follow the
direction with cannabis specifically
is that what does kelp have a lot of has
a lot of boron
now what happens if i do a lot of boron
in a closed system i'm going to get a
build up of boron now what does boron
start to displace it's also going to
screw up my calcium uptake because the
boron the calcium ratio is very
finicky if i go too high on the boron i
need to really up my calcium where my
uptake is going to be all screwed up so
um
you end up with these really big
imbalances between the boron and the
calcium that that chemically starts
screwing stuff up in their own right
with the people that just kind of go
balls to the wall with the kelp extract
and or the the the the sea salt the
dilutions which they and usually end up
with sodium problems but that's a whole
other issue
but there's again there's a lot of and
i'm working on it currently on a book
called um aquaponics which will be
aquaponic cannabis book that'll kind of
have all all the stuff broken down all
the different normal reference stuff
that as far as minerals that people are
going to want to use
and and all you know what you can and
can't use why you specifically shouldn't
use certain things just because of all
the different stuff that i've kind of
figured out over the years
because there isn't really a good source
in all and that's one of the biggest
problems is there is no really reservoir
other than the podcast that we've put
out that i put out there isn't really
anything specific to aquaponic cannabis
that really has any kind of you know
weight behind it certainly nothing
that's been been done on a commercial
scale so it's it's hard you know i i i
fully understand why someone coming into
it just doesn't have a lot of reference
to it because unless you've listened to
the podcast or taken you know one of my
classes you're really not going to know
what ppm's your stuff should be at what
you know what is going to kill your fish
another great example would be yucca
extract yucca extract or sapenin is
often used as a wedding agent for both
pest management products and for for
root wrenches and stuff like that
the problem is it's incredibly fish
lethal it is so fish lethal that the
indians the yurok indians among others
and and the northern um uh california uh
would collect a yucca roots and they'd
squeeze the juice out of the roots and
collect that juice as a concentrate and
put it in vessels and they'd evaporate
it off and make a even further
concentrate out of it then they get a
couple of guys with a couple of those
vessels that go upstream about a mile
wait for the salmon run pour it into the
river and it would kill all the fish
within about a quarter mile of the river
but they'd have about half a mile a mile
down they have the whole village waiting
in the river
so they collect all the fish as they
float by and then they cook them off and
it gets rid of the sapen and then they
can eat them so but that was literally
used as a method for for you know entire
tribes to feed themselves for years so
this is something that's well not only
documented in western culture but this
is documented going back
10 000 years that you shouldn't use
saping in around fish so
yeah i mean it's funny you mentioned
that because i remember when i was on
your show i brought that up and you were
very quick on the ball to be like up but
if your necroponics guys don't use it
but um yeah very valid point and just
you know further i just wanted to say
you know we're all really grateful for
the the archive of knowledge you've put
out around aquaponics because you
certainly hit it on the head there's no
other resource quite like your show
what you just said raises a really
interesting point in terms of what do
you feel it's important to supplement
your aquaponics system with versus
what's it important to not supplement it
with which you might for example bring
over as a bad habit because you know you
could you use me as an example i'm happy
to do that you know i come from soil i
might you know without your knowledge i
might be like man saponins are amazing
so yeah what's some good things to bring
with you and what's some things you
should probably leave behind
i would say um
number things to avoid would be one safe
and in two brassicas as a companion
plant i for some reason still see people
suggest that and i do not understand why
anything in the mustard family kills
mycorrhizal fungi it releases something
called lillipathy
which is a
loose term for chemicals that kill
nearby anything else that's living it's
used both for coral or for the roots of
plants or for it it's used for a wide
range of different things but basically
the plants uh brassicas do not have
associative mycorrhizal fungi about 85
percent of the world's plants do they do
not they actively kill associated
mycorrhizal fungi because it inhibits
their own growth so they will not help
you um
and there's something again that i still
suggest i still see people suggesting i
don't understand it
another one that i've learned this this
year in particular in oklahoma southern
oklahoma is do not grow cilantro
anywhere remotely near anything outdoor
cilantro attracts aphids of every type
it's just a magnet root aphids
regular tree aphid
uh
you know cotton aphids
i've seen
entirely two we just all of it got
trashed and just no nowhere near the
grow and then i went to another
vegetable grow and found an incredibly
bad root aphid infection which i posted
a couple pictures uh not too long ago on
instagram of probably the worst root
aphid infestation but that again
thankfully wasn't not in a cannabis farm
was it a vegetable farm but again if
that wasn't a cannabis farm we'd
probably have to burn the whole place
like if it looked like that like i don't
honestly know what i would tell the
owner
it was that bad that like vegetables
people are a little more okay with
trashing everything you know
yeah look i was gonna say anyone who's
ever had to fight aphids in the cannabis
context when they see that photo you put
up there's a visceral reaction to it
it's just like you got punched in the
stomach you're like oh no
well i got i got a picture if you scroll
down a little farther on my instagram i
got pictures of bong aphids from a grow
i was called to and they should have
called me probably two two months before
they actually called me over there
and
every single plant probably had a
minimum of 15 000 aphids on it an entire
100 by 30 greenhouse every single plant
like there was as much weight of aphids
as there was biomass a plant in that
greenhouse
man they growing biomass or insect frass
you know
you could ferment all of that and sell
it as an ipm like we were talking about
and and you know you could maybe recoup
your carbs
yeah gosh please guys just grow good
weed
yeah
so for me i think the logical next
question is
would you be able to give us a basic
rundown on how someone might be able to
go up setting about a relatively simple
setup at their home if they're
interested in getting into aquaponics or
would you advise that unless you're
really ready to jump in there might not
be a sort of get your toes wet option
per se
sure i would just say you know set up
your system like you're gonna do for a
flood and drain cocoa
setup and then instead of doing cocoa do
do root zone pots flood and drain and
you know cut your stand pipe to to four
or five inches and just flood and drain
the bottom half instead
and then top feed with your upper half
with either automated like we do on a
large scale or you know hand if you're
just doing a couple of plants at home
and and you'll have a hell of a lot more
control you'll have a lot better flavor
on your plants and and again you're not
going to have to do a lot of adapting
you're going to you know you could
absolutely do this if you don't even
want to deal with the with the fish you
can do hydro dual root zone and you'll
still get an incredible increase in
impact and i think you you anyone that
even does this with a hydro dual root
zone will notice immediate difference in
flavor against any side by side
yeah amazing and for someone who might
exist like myself in a little bit of a
more warmer country most of the year do
you think that that is quite problematic
because i think i've heard someone say
that you know like in australia during
peak summer you're going to really
struggle to keep the fish alive because
it gets really hot is that just
something i've missed heard or do you
feel like it's not particularly any more
challenging
no i mean i don't think that you're
going to have any more challenges than
we do here in oklahoma i mean frankly
we're getting you know you guys have
very similar summer peak summertime
temperatures if anything we might even
top out a few degrees higher than you
guys fahrenheit wise so
um you know if we can do it here i don't
understand why you guys can do that i
would say that in australia in
particular i'd be much more concerned
about doing geothermal cooling both for
your water and for your air uh i you
know the the impact of pulling that cold
air out of the ground is going to make
it you know much much cheaper in terms
of cost effectiveness for climate
control
and again with the thermal mass you have
with the water you can run coils in the
ground like we do here in oklahoma where
we run coils in the water and then run
them underground just to wick the heat
off and the water sucks the heat in and
we can actually pull air temperature
degrees off of it by sucking it into the
water using the thermal mass of the
water as a battery basically to suck
temperatures off and then bleed that off
underground
and we can again turning that off
increases the temperature in the
greenhouse i was just at about you know
two and a half degrees
so yeah that's very nice yeah that's
that's not trivial that's a good amount
of heat reduction for sure
especially we're talking about btus on
an ac unit
yeah when you're chomping through power
i feel you
so the next question that came up for me
is
in australia tilapia is actually illegal
so
what sort of fish would you recommend
that might go well in one of these
systems across the board and then maybe
a specific one for australia seeing as
unfortunately tilapia is out
sure so across the board i would say
anyone getting started
you know depending on your tank size but
assuming you aren't going anything
incredibly small go with coir or
goldfish because they're really
bulletproof they'll tolerate all kinds
of stupid things that you might
accidentally do
and uh you know they have a good resale
value you can almost always unload
decent sized ones for people for their
pawns you know i mean regardless of what
country you're in
especially butterfly koi butterfly koi
are easily you know you're going to
increase them exponentially per per you
know every inch that you add them you're
adding you know anywhere from five to
forty dollars u.s
uh per inch so uh depending on how big
they already are so you're talking quite
a bit of money so if we're talking about
cannabis production
we don't generally care about feeding
people i mean we do in terms of
community outreach but
most cannabis companies just want to
turn as much profit as humanly possible
right in terms of business model so if
that's your goal with your business
model going with butterfly koi or
something that really is going to be
your long-term best bet or with tropical
fish that you can again turn around and
resell arowanas arapaima
other large fish that people have a hard
time raising in large tanks that you
happen to have a whole bunch of that's
easy for you to do at the scale that
you're operating at
can be a really really great option
financially
for australia specifically
murray cod or jade perch both will work
very well um
uh you know
jay
murray cod i believe will also go into
brackish water or the jade perk i know
correct me unfortunately i'm not the
authority
yeah so so those guys i would say be
careful of anything generally that goes
from salt water to fresh water they tend
to absorb potassium at a higher rate
salmonids in particular uh unless you're
doing decoupled systems which i don't
recommend um
because it adds a whole other layer of
complexity to your chemistry and just it
adds money it adds cost to your run as
well which is pointless you know we're
trying to cut the cost down not adam um
but unless you're doing that
salmon ends are just not an option um
again for the same reason because that
mechanism that ingests salinity also
affects potassium uptake and
chemically with the fish
yeah and the potassium levels that we're
running with cannabis will kill the fish
basically they'll have heart heart
issues
yeah yeah wow that's pretty serious
so i guess to for me to wrap up this
little segment quickly i just want to
know do you always grow aquaponically or
is every now and again you're like ah
you know i don't have a pump on here
just do some soil
so i i always prefer to do aquaponics
but i i still do living soil i'm a
i love uh we spoke about them earlier
but i love dragonfly earth medicine and
the whole living soil and and
sustainability and ferments and moving
into you know trying to to develop as
many possible nutrient sources as
possible without outside sources and
that's some of the stuff i'm working on
in the book as well is is what nutrients
and ferments from k nf can i take and
what inputs can i take in ferment and
add to my aquaponics system to replace
those minerals kind of like you're
talking about with iron and other things
irons a particularly difficult one
because of oxidation but a lot of the
other ones can absolutely be heavily
supplemented one that's often uh just to
circle back to silica again uh silicas
often people say ferment
horsetail which is a a very common plant
worldwide i believe i believe you guys
even have that in australia if memory
serves me correctly
the downside with that is it has a
compound and it actually affects vitamin
b uptake
which is going to slow my growth rate
yeah now you know what has even more
silica actually four times as much
silica
stinging nettle and everyone loves the
ferments thinking that all ready for the
garden so if you're actually looking for
silica
forget the tail horsetail can also
heavily accumulate trace metals
including heavy metals which can cause
you to fail for your testing so if
you're in california you could actually
ferment horsetail and cause yourself to
fail your heavy metal testing by
accident whereas if you go with the
stinging nettle you're going to avoid
those issues because it doesn't tend to
accumulate the heavy metals at the same
high rate and it'll also add you know
even more silica than the horsetail
wheel so again it's just one of those
things where once you start looking at
some of the numbers on some of these
ferments and and the breakdowns when you
actually test them you realize some of
this stuff is actually
not what we thought it was and there's
actually much better options that we're
already using as part of our regimens
that are actually supplying these other
minerals at a much better rate that we
just didn't realize
yeah wow still so much to be learned i
guess
um the a question i wanted to ask is
just a really quick one
can you use the the ward from aquaponics
does it like can you use it as like a
rooting stimulating agent or do you
still use something else to kind of
clone
oh absolutely in fact i i've had an
immense research built mainly with
aeroponic growing but also with with
just plug growing with aquaponics and
media beds as well with accelerated
growth rate with the roots as well uh
particularly with moringa trees we were
able to root moringa trees within you
know 14 to 20 days and we're talking
trees
but with cannabis there's quite a few
not only my own research but there's a
uh
what's the name of the company fish [__]
and then the other one's called poof or
poom
uh there's a new company i just found
out about the last last week or so that
has another
fish waste based cloning product and and
both of them are based on fish waste
or fermented fish waste or dried fish
waste or shelf stabilized fish waste uh
for cloning and all of their research as
well for their both of their independent
companies also backs up my own data on
the accelerated growth rate from the
fish waste as well so that again that
increase in microbiological activity
from those mineral sources really seems
to make a marked increase in um
and rooting rate and reduction in
rooting time
yeah i kind of suspect it as much so
that's that's lovely to hear that that
is the case but but we found that you
know results with everything from
cannabis all the way to moringa trees
moringa's in jamaica we were doing a ton
of moringa cloning because moringa is a
[__] to germinate
if you plant 10 seeds two of them will
germinate right but you can clone the
living crap out of it it clones pretty
well if you just cut it and stick it in
a media bed and let it flood and drain
for three two three weeks and you know
pull it out and you've got a tree you
can plant in the ground and away you go
you can plant the whole forest you know
pretty quickly that way so uh these are
all methods that that you can do and uh
you know very rapidly uh scale up and
that was one of the things that we
worked with the rastafarian group in in
kingston and nayabingy was was helping
them get some of that stuff going uh
um i don't know what they're doing with
it now but that was one of the things
that they're doing as the main export
was grinding up moringa leaves and
trying to figure out how to increase
their production
yeah great info great info so
one of the last topics i wanted to spend
some time chatting about with you
because i know that i mean it's it's
obvious by just listening to the podcast
thus far is you've got such an extensive
knowledge on ipm i was hoping to pick
your mind a little bit about that and i
guess my first kind of question would be
are there any common ipm treatments that
you think people have kind of got it
wrong and they should maybe stay away
from and like i mean something we've
already spoken about um saponins you
know i've seen people use them as an ipm
folia spray before would you be willing
to do that if it was say living soil or
what would you use as your first port of
call as a general sort of spray to fight
off some bugs
well as far as general sprays for bugs
my first go-to just as a regular general
spray if we're not talking about
off-the-shelf stuff would be the ipm imo
that we talked about that we're doing in
africa for off the shelf stuff if i had
to pick a single product that worked on
the widest range of stuff it'd probably
be a product called kapow which is
lemongrass oil and castor oil
i've had it work on everything from
white flies to spider mites to powdery
mildew and everything in between um so
as far as a shotgun blast that's gonna
just hit everything and it's gonna not
really negatively impact your plant or
its flavor that you can also use well
into flour when diluted uh it is the
best as far as
doing all of those things simultaneously
if we're talking about single sprays for
mold it would be probably a product
called sonata which is a bactillus
pamilis which i found is the hands down
best product for mold of any type and
any type of indoor grow
i've had the chance to work on it seems
to knock back damn near anything i throw
it at
um and it's you know it's bactilus
pamilis it's nothing crazy it's nothing
toxic i don't have to worry about i mean
yes you have to wear your ppe just for
compliance reasons but realistically
it's not going to hurt you in any way
um you know it's not like a chemical
spray or something like that where i
have to worry about my nervous system or
some other issue that's going to be
affected right it's just a bacteria
right it's no big deal
and then as far as insects beneficial
insects i would have to go with
uh lace swings and aureus
hands down the those guys are and
nematodes uh you know they're kind of
the
the pillars of any ipm that i'm going to
do off the bat and then we'll kind of go
into
depending on climate really it's going
to change
around that more than anything else you
know what what are the temperature
ranges that we're going to do with an
average day and that in that growth
cycle and like right now in oklahoma
our current regimen that we're doing for
pretty much everything outdoor and
anything in greenhouse
is radically different than anything i
would ever do indoor because it's all
stuff that can tolerate 95 degrees or
higher
you know what i mean that's not a whole
lot of insects that's your assassin bugs
your californicus your aureus
and your rove beetles and that's about
it there's not a whole lot else that's
going to live past that you know once
you get above 100 fahrenheit fahrenheit
there's not a lot of insects are going
to
thrive in that environment
yeah what what great information and i
guess it does highlight you know it's
hard to give these generalized answers
sometimes you've got to be a bit
specific i know that you do a lot of
consulting work for a variety of people
especially for specifically ipm what
types of things do you find you're
normally getting called in for and what
are often the challenges you face
um i would say number one people that
don't realize the the mineral
deficiencies they currently have going
on at the farm um i've gone to grows
where their head grower didn't know
that they needed to balance the ph the
nutrient solution
and they had been there for quite a few
months
and had balked their way into the job
somehow
i've been into a grow where i watched a
head grower transfer stuff into a room
that had an ungodly amount of money
worth of plants into it
and then not prune off the damaged
leaves
and then immediately didn't even know
that he had an affection because he
sprayed all this stuff and thought it
was just done and thought it didn't even
realize it because he didn't know he was
supposed to prune off like just all
kinds of just a lot of just like
rudimentary stuff like people that
pulled someone that had done like a tent
grow and then put them in charge of an
acreage or you know multi thousand
square foot facilities it's like look
don't do that grab someone that did cut
flowers grab someone that did pansies
grab someone that did geraniums you know
who cares like just any amount of scaled
agricultural experience like at all
um uh really what makes a big deal you
know if someone just you know even
growing beans for you know that's fine
like i'll take that or you know the
other thing that i noticed is people
that from the military are really easy
to work with veterans
great man because they're used to
procedures slps all that stuff they're
used to regiment that you know the the
it has to be done this way and it can't
be done a different way
and they don't think for themselves they
do what the directions say oh you know
they do to the point where it's helpful
and not to the point where it's a
hindrance um uh uh you know i i've been
some of the easiest people we you know
we often love to hire veterans for that
reason also a lot of the veterans are
legally able to have firearms in states
that you know you're also allowed to
have them you know under premises with a
license so they're also a great way to
hire veterans for easy jobs as far as uh
you know a high-paying job they don't
have to do a whole lot uh and support
people that maybe need a little extra
help in society uh you know a lot of
countries have have a hard time finding
jobs for some of their veterans and it's
a great way for our community to support
again we've talked about multiple ways
that we can support our community it's
just one more way that we can do that
yeah definitely it's a really lovely
sentiment there to try to help out
people who maybe need a little extra
help and have certainly helped out
others throughout their life in one way
or another
so
something i would not only that you know
if you think about what's the number one
enemy of our industry
education or lack thereof and so so by
by just providing good things in the
community it opens people up to the idea
of educating themselves about our
industry i don't have to go out of my
way to convert them they will convert
themselves
yeah
that's that's awesome isn't it
so
you know kind of related to this topic
we've seen that there's been a rise in
educational sort of events platforms we
saw last year there was a whole range of
regenerative cannabis symposiums and you
even mentioned yourself you're now doing
aquaponic classes which is fantastic and
people should certainly jump on top of
that if they want to get the inside
scoop on how to do it all do you predict
these will be more common going forward
and what's your hopes for the sort of
educational classes that you're involved
in
sure so i've been teaching educational
classes since 2013 um both on vegetable
side of things and on the cannabis side
of things depending on who i was
teaching for as well as medicinal herbs
i'm a passionate herbalist as well as a
mushroom picker i love to pick
all different types of wild mushrooms i
used to teach foraging classes in
colorado anyone the the pleasure of
going up with me uh
almost everywhere to come with at least
a grocery bag full of food
so uh and it's sustainably you know we
weren't out there taking everything out
there either you know we're taking no
more than 30 or 40 of what was out there
so still leaving some behind it to be
there for the next generation so
something i'm very passionate about but
um
um uh we marty and i as the gentleman i
do my podcast with we have a long format
commercial aquaponic cannabis class that
we'll be releasing later this year um
we've been teaching a version i've been
teaching a version of that class since
2013. um
we've since turned it from a two-day
class into a four-day commercial class
and then now into a week-long
intensive course that we have filmed at
a whole bunch of different locations
with a whole bunch of different chopped
up cool stuff and uh just all different
types of interesting things that we've
had or you know maybe we can show you an
example of somebody that screwed up real
bad and maybe i just don't tell you
where it is right so uh you know we
could show you a bunch of stuff that
maybe i just couldn't show you in a live
class right or an example of something
that i just i had to be taken right then
and there and we just shot us some some
footage of it so it's it's all together
in this next nice cool educational
format we're also putting on um
and you can find more information on
that at potentponics.com uh we'll have
that out hopefully in the next uh
uh 45 to 90 days
we're almost finished completing filming
and then we just have to edit it all
edit it all up and and add that extra
stuff to it but um we're also working on
the virtual aquaponic cannabis
conference on october 3rd and 4th which
has a wide range of different speakers
we have murray hollam which we spoke
about earlier this year he's pretty much
the leader in aquaponics uh he's based
out of australia we'll also have breeder
steve who we also talked about on the
episode
we'll have chris trump talking about
aquaponic k nf we'll have matthew gates
or zenthanol who's one of the the
leading experts on cannabis and
pathogens especially in terms of uh
evolutionary history and
you know uh treatments and just um uh
ah he's just such a wealth of knowledge
i love talking to him uh dr wil wilson
lennon uh wilson leonard um
another aquaponic great he has the the
wonderful commercial aquaponic cannabis
book which i highly recommend to people
if they're listening to the show and
they want to learn more about just
general aquaponics and they want
something that's really an incredible
reference guide um it's one of the most
in-depth and detailed books out there on
the topic and and one of the only ones
that really does a lot of things right
um
i don't always agree with anybody 100 of
the time but he uh he has uh probably
the single best book out there in terms
of system design
um that's that's currently on the market
we have roger terry from true aquaponics
he's a wonderful gentleman that i will
also work with on nutrient subscriptions
if you have an aquaponics system or
you're interested in getting a system up
and running he's a great place to get
nutrients from or we can get you set up
with a subscription service we do
provide a subscription service that we
test your nutrients for you and provide
you custom custom nutrient solutions for
your aquaponic or hydroponic system
based on your current nutrient values
not based on some you know part 8 par b
solution so we can dial that nutrient
within you know a very small range to
specifically boost you know heavy
feeding cultivars or anything else that
you're doing and make sure that you're
getting the production that you expect
we also have angela tenenbrock
ten brock she is one of the leading
experts in biosafety and food safety and
one of the leading researchers in food
safety and aquaponics for vegetable
production she's going to be talking
about
biosafety and cannabis facilities and
how to protect yourselves from
biological pathogens how to stop the
introduction of insects and pathogens
into your girl in the first place um
she's a wealth of knowledge if you're
ever trying to get compliant uh with a
government you know um certification or
any type of audit um she's a wonderful
person to check out marty weidel the
co-host of my show uh myself
uh brennan strathman from spectrum king
as well as grow more
microbial which is the first beneficial
archaea on the market uh leanne keys of
chief cultivator on instagram or from
habitat life he's one of the
if not the the best um head grower up
there for aquaponic cannabis production
up in canada up at habitat life he's
killing it up there many of some of the
best cannabis in bc um they sold out in
seven minutes the other day um from
their harvest so to give an idea of how
good their weed is
and they have josh rutherford and dutch
blooms the gentleman who puts on the
regenerative cannabis conference he's an
awesome guy he's going to be talking
about large-scale integration between
aquaponics and soil production and how
to utilize aquaponics or mineralization
from aquaponics to further benefit
large-scale soil production and we have
uh even more speakers that we haven't
announced yet that we're going to
trickle out um to you know release a
little bit more hype as we get a little
bit closer to the event
i don't know how you could get any more
hype because that's got to be one of the
most well-rounded list of speakers i've
ever heard and i'd like to give a little
shout out to our buddy josh he's uh he's
a great guy he's he's like yourself he's
doing a lot to try to help promote
education in the scene and i think we
all value that greatly
it goes without saying guys you got to
get a ticket to this event i just got
sold listening to that i don't know what
you need at this point
the best part is it's free we're just
going to host it on youtube and we'll
have free product giveaways
you know
with the virtual stuff it doesn't you
know normally with a conference it costs
money to put the conference on you have
to rent the event i have to rent chairs
you have to rent you know all the
different things you have to get hotel
rooms you have to you know it gets quite
a few
people don't realize how expensive it
can be to put on a conference it can be
incredibly expensive and if you don't
have the funds to do that it can be
really hard to do so by having a virtual
conference we don't really have a whole
lot of overhead to do that so what we're
going to do is we have a bunch of
company sponsors people like recharge
true aquaponics grow more a couple of
other guys that are out there um
what's the name there's another company
that does a fermented comfrey and some
other stuff
that all going to be donating products
that we'll have out there during the the
event
and that are all aquaponic safe or are
or fish-based um we're talking a couple
other people right now uh that we'll
have out there and and donate those as
well and just kind of promote the whole
education around aquaponic cannabis and
just sustainable can not even just
aquaponics but we'll be talking about
how you can utilize some of this
methodology in your soil growing we
understand that
70 80 90 of people that are watching
this probably aren't doing aquaponics
and we're going to make sure that you're
you know you're still gaining a
knowledge and things that you can take
away and apply to your soil grow that
that maybe you hadn't learned before
and there you have it guys you are now
obliged to watch it's free what more do
you need and i think that comfrey
company you mentioned might be casual
fields shout out to him he's a really
really nice guy
great product by the way it's also
aquaponics safe and a wonderful product
yeah yeah he's another lovely guy um one
of the final things i wanted to quickly
ask you about before we get into the
quickfire questions you put up a post
which just blew my mind and struck my
curiosity like nothing else when you did
an episode recently on your show with
kevin mckernan about how covert 19 was
found in cannabis tissue i mean this is
just wild you know i guess the question
is what implications do you think this
has like i the thing that jumped to mind
for me is it's like do you need to be
worried about getting covered 19 from
your plant
so so he
so okay so to clarify something on that
and this is something that i
misunderstood when when i read that
paper and i read it twice before i even
interviewed him on that um he developed
an allele to test for the presence of of
of covid19 so if you had an employee
that sneezed on the plant or coughed on
the plant or if i'm at a cannabis
dispensary and we allow patients to
smell the cannabis before they purchase
it
is there a way to test for that using a
qpcr
and then what type of tests do you have
to have what type of standard do you
have to have so he developed all that
but what he did on that was also develop
it for the
inputs and what he found that was scary
and what was really interesting if you
listen to that episode was how insane
the bat guano was
and how many different coronaviruses
there were in the bat guano and how like
it just scared the living crap out of
them and and how like we really need to
all immediately stop using bat guano
completely
in the cannabis industry in terms of bio
safety for all not only as a liability
for ourselves as a company for whoever
you're working for but as an industry
because we could be
at least accidentally in theory the
source of you know the next covid and we
nobody wants that
yeah thank you for that clarification
it's still such an extremely valid point
i've been thinking something not too
different myself i remember i had a
friend who got an atypical pneumonia
from handling guano last year and i was
like this isn't just something you read
about it actually happens
yeah it's pretty scary i i had a pretty
gnarly experience when i was younger
with a pretty rare type of pneumonia as
well and we they never figured out where
it came from and it makes me wonder
because i was often heavily into
gardening and now after listening to
that it made me wonder is that where it
came from
yeah i think that it there could be a
whole range of things like that but
that's that's interesting and yeah
thanks for clarifying that so on to our
quickfire questions i'm really
interested to hear your answers for this
one so the first one i'd like to start
out with what's the most memorable
cannabis you've ever smoked in your life
hmm
memorable cannabis
probably two things one the last joint i
smoked with dennis perrone
at new year's eve
about two months before he passed away
would be one of the ones that i can
think of where i'll never forget that
one ever i'd it's the last time i saw
him um
the other one was
and that was at the castle on new year's
eve um a castro castle anyone that knows
the industry
or knows dennis um and then uh
the other one would probably be
dr uh there was one that i smoked with
on the dragonfly earth medicine tent
two years ago at emerald cup
and i'm trying to remember who gave it
to me i don't remember i believe it was
a weight laughter strain but i don't
remember i
he handed me the ball and i think he's
the one who grew up but i don't quote me
on that but it was like a 16 something
or other and it just
kicked me in the teeth
like it was the most
most i've had my bell rung in 10 years
um and that was that just stuck with me
i still i don't even know remember what
the name of it was but i just that one
just hitting that that pipe you know
just a regular glass bowl two or three
times
just kick my kick me in like i just did
like three gram dab or something like
that like it just the terpene profile
was just exactly what my body needed
wow yeah that's awesome when you get
that special hitter like that so on the
other end of the spectrum has there ever
been a strain where everyone else was
really into it hyping it up and you're
like oh cool getting excited and then
you try and you're like it's not for me
i don't get it cookies
[Music]
man i love this answer because i'm such
a die hard cookies fan like i [__]
love it but i get how much people hate
it
as a grower
if i never saw cookies again
it would be too soon
because cookies grows these little tiny
larvae buds that are just absolutely
annoying is all hell for any of your
trimmers that actually it doesn't
produce nice fat stuff it's easy to trim
it's all these tiny little
you know super ball size bouncy ball
size nugs that are you know quarter
sized that are just a pain in the ass
trim
yeah 100 i can certainly agree on that
point i won't argue there but for resin
production for concentrates i get why
people grow it it makes sense
but i agree for me smoking i love it for
me growing it a little less
so the next question if you were stuck
on a desert island and you could only
take three strains with you which three
would you want to take
so it would be hash plan
g13 my blue hash that i've been working
on for quite a few years
and
hmm
island sweet skunk bite uh or sweet
skunk not island sweet sound sweet skunk
by breeder steve uh great picks and just
for the viewers what what went into your
blue hash it sounds interesting
sure it's blue dream and afghan one um
and hash plant so it was hash oh the
plant it was afghan won a hash plant and
we crossed that
and we got a really fire male out of
that let me cross that with a blue dream
cut that we had that was really thick
stocked like freakishly thick stocked
and just kicked ass in the wind
out in the plains in colorado that was
just it would grow like into like tree
trunks right and it would just hold
itself up with fat nugs even in high
winds it would just take whatever you
threw at it didn't didn't really get
broken at all and we crossed those and
and the progeny from that we've
developed kind of two lineages that have
since been just we've gotten so many
different good crosses out of it that
that we've kind of
you can get if anyone's listening and
want some you can get some through mr
green jeans garden if you hit him up on
instagram uh he he does have them
available and he's one the only source
of the the actual original genetics that
i have out there currently
damn i'm gonna have to hit him up
so
on the other end of the spectrum and
this is one of my favorite questions
if you had to drop off someone you're
not particularly a fan of maybe you
might even use the hate word though it's
a little strong someone you're not a fan
of you've got to drop them off on an
island and leave them with three strains
what are you gonna leave them with okay
i'd have to think on this for a second
um
[Music]
blackberry cookies
mac cookies
and what else has completely no
resistance to anything
uh
citrus sap the citrus there's like a
citrus glue
citrus sap [__] citrus gorilla glue
cut that's going around oklahoma that
just seems to get every pathogen known
to man as well
the magnets yeah
okay so final question and i'm
interested to hear your answer if you
could go back to any point in history
and go anywhere around the globe
presumably to collect some cannabis
seeds or a plant where would you go and
when
um
probably to southern africa
like
south africa swaziland or currently
eastwatini and they just changed the
name about a year ago
and uh in zimbabwe that area has some
really really bizarre genetics or re no
take it back take it back reunion island
hands down
brilliant answer one i've often thought
about myself with the the ever elusive
psychedelic nature of the zamal i think
that just about brings us to the end of
it
i mean you know thank you so much for
all the incredible education knowledge
on aquaponics k f ipm organics just
beyond it's just it's incredible if
people wanted to check out your podcast
what would be the best place for them to
go find it
sure they can check me out at pomponix
and youtube soundcloud itunes
i heart radio spotify run over 200
different platforms so they can find us
on whatever whatever fits your post
if you know some of our episodes
definitely are more video heavy you know
we have a tour of a glassblowing
facility and stuff like that you
probably want to check out on youtube
but i would say 95 of them or 98 of them
are perfectly fine to listen to them the
audio version but we get over 20 times
the listeners on the audio version i'm
sure you're similar as well where you
get you know
significantly more listenership on your
audio version than the videos
yeah that's it guys just google
potentponics you'll find it very easily
with that being said did you have any
comments or shout outs you wanted to
make before we wrap up
um just uh if you guys are looking for
more information check me out at a you
know growing the fishes podcast or
potent products and if you need uh
aquaponics safe nutrients check them out
at true aquaponics
uh is really it
awesome so again steve thanks so much
for your time today i know the viewers
will absolutely mop all of this up and
thank you for your broader contributions
as well
i appreciate you having me and uh you
know if we can ever uh have you back on
the show again we'd love to have you
[Applause]
damn guys anyone else on their way to go
buy an aquaponics setup right now
i think i am
huge thank you again to steve such an
amazing amazing episode please go check
out all of his content at growing with
fishes podcast potentponics you'll find
it google youtube everything it's all
there
likewise a huge huge thank you to our
sponsors seeds here now number one seed
bank in the game all the hottest drops
best customer service everything you
need why would you go anywhere else i
love them they're the best seriously
likewise huge shout out to copper
biologicals they've got everything you
need to keep your garden happy and
healthy beer soil soilless bugs no bugs
they got something for you trust me go
suss it out they're gonna make your next
harvest even better they're gonna keep
your garden happy and healthy the number
one in the beers i love them you'll love
them give them a shot
and finally the patreon gang we love you
guys thank you so so so much for your
support you really keep the show
happening we appreciate you guys
incredibly if anyone wants to check out
the show if anyone wants to check out
the patreon and get early access to
additional episodes unreleased content
and so much more please check it out
[Music]
so that's it for this episode gang i'll
see you back here for the next one from
the upside down library this is your boy
heavy days signing out
i'll see you
[Music]
so