hello and welcome to the next episode of
the podcast a cannabis podcast for
budding enthusiasts
this episode as always was brought to
you by our sponsors 420 australia your
number one store for lifestyle and
apparel
organic gardening solutions your
one-stop shop to grow the best no-till
around and finally seeds here now you
know best in the business guarantee on
satisfaction not just germination check
it out
on this episode we're joined by the
amazing josh and kelly of dragonfly
earth medicine
stay tuned for all the knowledge bombs
let's get into it
[Music]
alrighty so big thank you and welcome to
the dynamic duo josh and kelly from
dragonfly earth medicine thanks so much
for joining us
thanks so much for having us we're
excited to be here thanks for having us
today
so
first question i want to ask is what are
you guys currently smoking on
a homesteader we actually have a big jar
of homesteader here which is um one of
our really long time
strains well it's actually a cross of
one of our really long time strains so
it's our zeli's gift times our 840.
um
and it has a temple spice as a female so
we've been working with the zelly's gift
for a while
it has a jack herrera mom and uh a gooey
mother
clone that came from oregon which is
really really awesome that we love
forever and uh yeah we've been breeding
up here for a long time so we we do have
a lot of other people's strengths
there's a lot of wonderful amazing
people that give us strains but we
really like ours um because they're
really um you know intelligent for our
area so the homesteader is kind of a
uplifting kind of lemony
um high in beta-caryophyllene and has
some really a beautiful full-spectrum
cannabinoid profile it's like it's spicy
oh nice and so is that got any like um
cbd or anything like that or is it more
thc dominant one it's mostly thc
dominant but it's probably like a four
to one so
we're guessing you know we wrote we go
from seeds so it would probably be like
a maybe a 17 to 19 thc and we're hoping
for like an eight percent cbd we're
starting to bring more cbd into our thc
varieties and they still have a lot of
flavor
and then they have this dynamic
um cannabinoid profile which we really
like a lot and we're also breeding for
the cbdv and the cbdn
and yes we're breeding for the
cannabinoids we don't know about yet
yeah that's such an interesting point to
make because something i've always
thought about kind of in my subconscious
is what if breeders began to embed just
a small amount of cbd in the background
of profiles such that maybe people
aren't aware that it's even their per se
but just everyone's kind of enjoying
that added medicinal effect
do you think that that's maybe something
that will like come out more so in the
future
absolutely i mean um you know trying to
have as much cbds in there and still
getting that nice high that people are
looking for you know is is totally
beneficial so we've been breeding in cbd
from an ac dc clone that we got a long
time ago
and we have like a one to one and sort
of a two to one and a three to one and a
four to one and we're just continually
trying to make sure that that cbd makes
an appearance in all of our new strains
we know that the uh there's kind of like
the hemp cbd
and then there's the
thc variety throwback cbds
and that's where some of the original
cbds came from cbd plants and stuff like
the harlequin and everything came from a
thc variety um that was you know
thinking it white might have had
the high um cbd and then you know the
tsunamis and the sour tsunamis and
everything um got created after that but
um if you're not breeding it
you have to be careful with breeding
into the hemp
to try and get your cbd varieties when
you find like a really flavorful high
cbd
that is easily breedable with the thc
varieties and our opinion i think it's
what along the lines what you're saying
that's a real winner
yeah and then we just sort of keep our
hemp uh breeding with each other we
don't really see the difference between
medical and recreational and in fact we
would love to just sneak in whatever
people consider medical into
recreational because
why not be medical while you recreate
yeah exactly so you touched on a few
interesting points there the first one
which jumps to mind though is one thing
i've heard commonly is that some strains
particularly the cbd dominant ones have
this kind of general slash bland terpene
profile i think some people even refer
to it as like a cherry kind of profile
do you
agree with that view like do you
subscribe to that or do you think maybe
that's just a bit too nitpicky
um we definitely see that more in the
hemp varieties but now we have lots of
friends that are in the industry that
are starting to like pop like 1 million
seeds and then they're testing 10 000 of
those seeds and one of their number one
things that they're searching for is a
wide variety of a terpene profile
so there's some new seeds out there in
the hemp world called a spectrum there's
also one that's the cherry wine
one that's called a number five that
really has beautiful terpenes sort of
you know all over the map so
yes i do agree with you that sort of the
cherry was the first flavor to come up
in the high cbd hemp varieties but now
that there's just more searching out
there and more testing more terpene
profiles are becoming apparent
and so another question i wanted to ask
you is i've found a strain by i believe
it's cbd crew and if not cbd seeds it's
one of the two it's shanty barber's
company but basically he says he's got a
cbd strain where instead of having any
hemp being brought into it at any point
he found a regular kind of you know thc
dominant strain which happened to have
some cbd in it and then over multiple
generations selectively bred it out like
selectively bred the thc out of it
he says the the advantage of this is
that you don't get that hemp terp or and
you get a little bit better bud
structure but the thought that i had was
is that really an issue with you know
like for example when we look at the
work you're doing is the bud structure
from the hemp genetics which maybe
brought the cbd many generations ago is
that still evident or is it just not
even there anymore really
still looks a lot like the hemp when you
get the hempy ones yeah definitely it
still has sort of that you know smaller
flower nodes um maybe even less of them
on a plant
um taller thinner leaves you know i mean
really you know i feel beautiful
terpenes and there's i know people that
are making oils out of it and even
making rosin and stuff so there's still
you know there's still profiles there to
go with but
yeah i mean there's really there really
is kind of the hemp varieties and then
the the
the more broad leaf varieties there's
broadleaf cbd's is basically what you're
looking for
and so in regards to kind of what i just
mentioned with that uh selectively bred
out thc phenotype would you be
interested in looking at something like
that or does the advantages on paper not
really kind of seem like it's a
worthwhile in exploration so to speak
definitely we feel like um breeding out
the thc you know more in what is called
the drug cultivar
cannabis
um
so yeah being able to breed out the thc
and up that cbd is going to give you
those beautiful you know dripping
resinous flower
flowers i mean essentially if you if
you're a farmer or if you're if you're
going to start a business an apartment
you're looking at it kind of like
are you targeting no thc or cbd um or
high cbd with no thc which allows you to
sell more you know globally and more
internationally and that's a real you
know that's a
an attractive incentive so in that way
you know breeding out the thc and just
having the cbd is you know when when if
someone's putting in that much effort to
create those seeds though those are
really valuable
and we also know that the hemp variety
you know sort of across the globe it's
that 0.3
that they're looking for so that it's
you know
non-structured and it's not going to be
necessarily put into the cannabis
industry with restrictions so if you're
looking for that 0.3 thc that's going to
really be found in the hemp varieties
we're finding those super super low thc
and then you just want to you know up
all of the rest of the cannabinoid
profile in your terpene profile so it's
a big hunt in the hemp world as well as
in the cb drug cultivar world right now
so i'm not sure if you guys would be
familiar with this next part but
basically what i had noticed was
whenever i had tried a cbd extract like
most notably the really highly refined
ones you know like they're looking
really white crystalline type of stuff
i just found like yeah it just really
wasn't medicinal in the way that like uh
say a cbd flower was is this like a you
know a kind of a pertinent point in your
mind like are you kind of on that same
wavelength of like it loses that
medicinal value as it gets more
processed
absolutely that means that you're just
extracting just the cbd and then you've
got that 99
cbd crystallite and that means that it
doesn't really have any other you know
terpenes in it for sure there's no
terpenes and as well as there's no
cannabinoids so you've lost sort of this
dynamic profile where they all work
together you know
one what you're saying there is really
interesting because you could have
something that you know is maybe a five
milligram
cbd and if it has cbdv in it and cbdn in
it and it's sort of like a full profile
you're gonna feel that so much more than
say a hundred milligram straight cbd
isolate at least that's been what i've
really experienced and other people have
experienced across the board and that
has a lot to do with the terpenes um you
know and
and and the dynamic effect of of the
entourage where everything's working
together i mean
and it's it's just it's almost
pharmaceuticalizing it in the sense to
to try and you know isolate or
distillate you know you know certain
parts of it and there's reasons for that
and there's a lot of medicines you can
do that so i'm not i'm not saying at all
that's not a that's not a good thing but
i feel like
i do think you it's more dynamic in the
um in the
corrective medicine aspect of it when
you get the other terpenes in there
because they work together and they
really create the your immune they
really boost your immune system and in
the end
you know you're trying to boost your
immune system and those are that
endocannabinoid system will be charged
up with the with as many different
cannabinoids as possible and most of the
doctors have
have proven that through
research is that you know one by one
is a good one is it good
yeah i definitely have found personally
at least that the one to one seems to
work really nicely for me if we take a
little step back though from what we
were just talking about with the the uh
the ultra most extracted slash process
end of things and we just go kind of
more to the midway how do you guys feel
about say extracts which have added
terpenes put back in them do you feel
like it's like a two-step forward
three-step back type situation or what's
your view
well i think that that you know there's
there's people using terpenes that are
made from foods and they're just getting
like mercy from wherever mercy comes
from and for sure that's not really a a
thing that we that we you know promote
or condone at all i mean if you're going
to use terpenes in there they should be
from cannabis and really i mean the
whole goal is to
is to preserve your terpenes with your
growing practices and with your um and
with your uh
your curing practices and when you go to
extract it i mean hopefully you don't
need to add any terpenes but you know
when you're making different oils you
can get terpenes from it and it is
really fun to work with terpenes and do
different things with it the
aromatherapy and
different things you can do but i think
you have to be
kind of um
gentle with with using them
for sure
yeah
so last little thing i wanted to touch
on on this kind of cbd topic was i
watched a little segment of you guys
talking on youtube and you were talking
about how you think uh some cbd slash
just funky you know cannabinoid profiles
may be related to the soil itself
and that was a really interesting point
and the first thing i thought of is
do you think it's more related to the
microbes or to the amendments you're
using
um definitely to the microbiology
because if you've got a living soil um
then you're really not feeding your
plant the focus then becomes that you're
feeding the soil and then that soil
becomes a vast organism that then you're
trying to feed
and and when you feed them say
terpene-rich nutrients then it's really
the breakdown of the fungi and the
bacteria and all of the different
microbiology in there that then feeds it
up to the plant
so i think to feed really you know
biodynamic accumulators that are terpene
rich is probably a really good idea but
it's going to go through the
microbiology before it hits the plant so
there's always a through way um you know
with a beautiful living soil and yeah
we've definitely found um with testing
with our medicine before that you know
we a lot of the facilities we've worked
with have seen you know a really um
broad array of cannabinoids and even
some really unique ones that they
haven't seen before and for sure you
know science backs this is as as
the the microbiology is what really
allows the plant to produce the
secondary metabolites that it has i mean
we definitely know if you grow one
the same clone and you know 10 different
environments indoor outdoor and whatever
it is with different even with different
nutrients you will get different
cannabinoid and terpene profiles so so
for sure there's like that that's what's
fun about growing this plan is that you
know when you give it something really
um unique it allows it to
um express itself to its full full
extent so so yes adding um a really
really
live and rich microbiology to your soil
is going to really really help
you know the
the diversity of your cannabinoids and
terpenes and we're going to be we we
have been working with a lab here in bc
for about a year and actually they're
going to be coming out to our farm and
we're going to be doing soil tests along
with
plant tissue tests and really trying to
get to the bottom of it because this lab
is seen like josh had said some really
rare cannabinoids and they don't even
have the ability to test them all
so we really feel like we can give a
seed that's you know our own
uh
you know that we've been breeding up
here for maybe 12 years and we feel like
it's it's a pretty stable strain after
12 years and then we'll give it to
somebody else and those rare
cannabinoids are maybe not being found
and we feel like maybe more and more
rare cannabinoids are going to be found
with you know building of soil so we've
been on our land for now 11 years um and
you know what is it going to be like 15
years from now when our soils are built
up to even more maximum are we going to
be able to get cannabinoid profiles
that are really rare we believe that we
will and we and we have um you know a
long time strain that we've been using
and last year all of a sudden we had 10
cbd in it out of nowhere so
we did have cbd show up and
for sure there's a relationship within
the soil and within the roots growing
together
so we really envision that when we're
growing and in the teas and everything
that we're making we're thinking oh how
is this going to affect our rhizosphere
and that community and that that neuro
communication that happens within the
soil and it's super
i mean we really love
thinking about the roots and and when we
see the hyphae and how it all goes
together
and you it really dirty and and and
people have even proven that there's
electromagnetic you know pulses going
through there so
plants communicating with themselves in
the soil allow them to be healthier and
ex once again express themselves
to more diversity and we believe that
you know cannabis is a social plant and
the reason why we believe that is
because it drops its seeds on the ground
right around the plant and then all of
that mother plant then drops all of the
mulching leaves and actually feeds it to
her next generation so all of those
seeds will sort of grow close together
in a natural setting and that makes it a
very social plant
and that's something that we recognize
if
plants are in pots and then we put them
out into the ground we immediately see
that there's some kind of a completion
of the circuits the completion of the
electricity a completion of the
communication between the plants so that
they can help each other out
um
so you know that's definitely a part of
the cannabinoid profile as well is how
happy is your plant
if your plant is incredibly happy then
it's going to be able to show its full
capabilities for the medicine and the
terpenes that it puts out and it's also
why we we really you know
um
we really condone having your plants in
the earth and not in pots above the
ground and that's part of our pure
certification part of the farms that we
work with and stuff everyone
is building you know
beds connected to the earth and it's
better for water water retention you in
australia you know you guys have a you
know big huge water problem you know a
lot of times in the year and
you know you know learning about those
techniques is going to be extremely
important for you all too
yeah so i've got a whole bunch of
questions related to that but i just
want to jump back to something you
referenced a moment ago where you said
you wonder what the soil slash your farm
will be like in 15 years from now
something i wanted to ask you
specifically was do you know if the
concept of probiotic runoff exists so to
speak like let's just say you know your
beds are just pumping it out for the
next 15 years do you think at some point
you reach saturation and the microbes
then start to leach off to elsewhere and
you're kind of by remediating elsewhere
or do you think it's going to be quite
localized
well i i'm going to i'll we'll reference
paul's statements on this and i mean in
in his um studies is his
is that there was cow farms above
the um
oyster fields out in in olympia and the
oyster fields and oyster farmers in the
water were you know losing or their
their their crop and not being able the
oysters weren't growing and they were
losing their crop there oh my god what's
happening we're getting poisoned by
cows and so what they did is they
inoculated bales of hay with um
oyster mushrooms and they built channels
for the runoff so the water when the
rain came in when and when and extra
ground waters came
the
groundwater could filter through
the bales of hay which in and in the end
did save the oyster fields and that just
goes to prove and we talk about this a
lot
with um
land um formation when people are doing
earthworks on their property is to build
um burlap balls and and inoculate it
with um
with um biology because we we know that
you do affect the area around you
through biology so
having really dedicated beds or swales
around your property that have really
live mycology or biology in your soils
it it does affect your your neighbors
and and it does
affect your water and and you have to be
really careful
about um
you know uh you know building your
property properly so it does affect your
neighbors in a positive way
did i answer that and if there is going
to be runoff you know with your
beneficials or your microbiology in your
beds then if it's on your land that's
nothing but you know awesome as far as
like reaching like ultimate peak of
microbiology microbiology is just
constantly eating and colonizing and
dying and eating and colonizing and
dying it's just part of what it does it
changes seasonally it'll change on a hot
day you know if we're having blazing hot
days then all of that beautiful
microbiology that might be in the first
inch of the soil is going to go down
quite deep so not only does it ebb and
flow in numbers but it also ebbs and
flows in in depth
and also how wide it is so we really
encourage people that you may start with
one garden bed but the view is to see
a beautiful intelligent microbiology
biome
that you know expands out from your
garden and then it goes out to your
property and then if it attaches onto
your neighbor's property then all you're
doing is creating a beautiful
safe haven for
a lot of microbiology that's dying in
the world today with all of the
different toxins so if microbiology can
have beautiful islands of health and
well-being you know in people's farms or
even in a garden bed or or in a large
farm then it is a positive impact for
the whole world
and and the beds are never done so we're
always adding to them like kelly said i
mean in 15 years we'll have to add to
our beds 15 times at least
yeah
so i know that you guys are big
advocates of the use of imo and as we
just heard microbes in general however i
was wondering
you know obviously you've never said it
but are you against kind of bringing in
external microbes you know or are you
okay with that but you just prefer to
use indigenous ones and i guess the most
notable example of this would be mammoth
p for example where do you sit on that
um well i mean we do we have our own
products
that have a different array of bacteria
as well as endomycorrhizae fungi
as well as different glomus species
we feel like if you can introduce
something that's really beneficial and
it's going to take then that's
absolutely fantastic it's really no
different than adding probiotics to your
to your body you know if you add um
different types of probiotics you know
the lactobacillus or the bacillus is
then that's just gonna inoculate your
body it may only inoculate your body for
72 hours and then you have to
re-inoculate it because it's going to
stay in the upper respiratory tract but
some of these soil microbiology that we
introduced to our body which we know as
human beings were completely deficient
in which is hence so many
health issues on the planet today ibs
and colitis and i could go on and on
leaky gut syndrome and all of these
things even even clear thinking brain
capabilities you know all really are
based in microbiology so in the same way
that maybe we're going to be deficient
in some type of a really important
microbe you know you can introduce it to
your body in the same way that maybe
your farm is deficient in microbiology
you can also you know introduce it to
your farm but the most important thing
is when you introduce it
you can't be introducing it in a way
that it's not going to be colonizing
so to really look at what kind of
microbiology that you're bringing in to
create a beautiful environment so that
it will colonize right away is the real
goal so that you're not continually
buying this microbiology to inoculate
inoculate inoculate your soil it's great
to re-inoculate your your t's and maybe
josh will talk a little bit about that
well
another thing that we think about when
when it comes to biology is that our
number one question is
what biology and where did it come from
and there's a lot of biology companies
out there that are rooted in gmo
companies and
um ones that do are are involved in a
lot of practices worldwide that we don't
agree with
so uh when it comes to even predators
you know if you're getting predators for
your garden you have to be really
careful of you know where you get your
predators from because some of those
companies are involved in really you
know large-scale you know gmo products
and and and farms that we don't agree
with so that's a number one question
and some of it's produced on substrate
that's gmo and you have to know what the
biology substrate is that it's being
colonized on so those are some of the
questions i mean mammoth p you know for
example if you you know we don't like to
you know to talk about any in particular
companies a lot of people use that you
know in in products but you know if
you're shipping liquid around the world
and stuff you know you think about the
container that it's involved in and
stuff and if you can try and even with
our products you know we try and you
know tell people how to
make it locally because it's better for
the gardening and better for your
environment so
biology is
best being tried to be made in soils
you know um and then i'm bringing it
into teas um you know that's um where
where we have our products and stuff
like that our products um represent
herbs and an herbal medicine which is is
certified organic herbs with a certified
organic
bacteria count and when we make a
bacteria colony and when we make teas
out of it
the herbs just go through the tea and
when they you water the beds the herbs
go on to the top of the soil so you can
colonize them in the tea and then you
can
they continue to colonize when they're
in the soil and and we're talking a lot
about our products but more importantly
we teach people to not use products at
all
so you know all of our products have
every single recipe on it we really we
really encourage people to grow this
herbal biomass themselves then it
becomes closed loop you also can
inoculate and grow out all of your own
species of different types of inoculants
whether that's a fungi or a bacteria
you know we utilize a tremendous amount
of lactic acid bacteria cultures here as
well as different types of soil bacteria
to help break down the raw
plant mass so we grow a tremendous
amount of
herbal biomass on our property here that
then gets chopped up and broken down
into a tea container and then you add
all of that microbiology so that it eats
it up at a very rapid rate
and then you aerate it so that's a
really an
anaerobic um beginning stages of that
because those anaerobes are incredibly
you know verocious and they eat through
things that are very rapid
and they're digesters so when you have
that in an anaerobic and then you switch
your anaerobic fermented teas into an
aerobic compound by adding you know air
to it then that gets all of your
anaerobes away and then it's ready to
drench and then it will be
fully
full of all of the the great
microbiology that you're looking for
that's going to continue to break down
that material in your soils
so a question kind of relating to the
teas that i wanted to ask you is do you
see any downside to artificially
extending the life of your tea so for
example maybe you know you've had a
brewing for a few days and you haven't
used it all so you just throw a bit of
extra carbohydrate sauce in there or
something along those lines do you think
that that's like you know detrimental
would you
sorry avoid doing that or how do you
feel about that
i mean it's not going to be the best way
to build the colony of your tea i mean
you know if the the purpose of of having
a tea to begin with is to is to
build mycology
essentially and not mycology but
microbiology you know i mean you start
with one thing and you add a little bit
of molasses or something to it organic
or not and we can get into that whether
to use organic uh to use organic
molasses or not but
you use the aeration to charge up the
tea and when you charge up the tea um
you know you're building the
colony and that's the point of it so if
you if you just extend that you're just
losing
the colony that you built because
they're not they don't wait around
they're they're just live and die you
know fast organisms so they've if
they've eaten up a lot of the nutrients
that you've already put in there and
then you add more inoculants in there
then it's not going to be the same
colonies that have eaten up the the
initial
foods or nutrients that you've put in
there it's going to be sort of a
different colony that takes over
and it's really interesting because
colonies can change in a tea brew from
hour to hour you know they can change
depending on how warm the weather is how
much humidity is in there or you know
depending on what you put in there so
it's a really
we we really don't look at our t's any
different than you would like a stomach
or a digestive tract we want to make
sure to put everything in there and then
give it the ability to be able to digest
it fully with all beneficial
microbiology
and we really don't separate it between
the human digestive tract and and a tea
brew as far as yeah the teas we just do
it a little differently i mean we do it
kind of like the art of fermentation on
one side and then we activate it on the
other and and that's different than a
lot of people
so i think a lot of our listeners will
probably kill me if i don't ask how long
do you brew your teas for generally and
do you use uh like a kind of a rule of
thumb to see when they're ready like you
know a lot of people will say when
there's a nice healthy froth on top but
then you know you'll have other people
who'll say that's not always indicative
that it's done things like that like
where do you sit on that
well most importantly you know the very
end i could go through the beginning of
it but the very end is taste it
you know really
if you're utilizing things in your tea
that you know are good for the soil and
good for the microbiology
you know of course you can get a ph
meter of course you can look at the
bubbles you can smell it but when you
taste your tea it's totally inert it has
zero flavor at all it's crazy you could
put a tremendous amount of
biomass in there chop up all of your
plants and in the anaerobic part of it
which usually is between five and seven
days it can go up to ten days during
really cold cycles if it's more warm
then it's going to be faster to five
days
that's your anaerobic brew and then when
you take that anaerobic brew and then
you put it into another container you
know by straining out all of the biomass
and the herbs and everything you put it
into another container and you aerate it
it should have
zero smell
and the taste of it should be totally
inert and for us that's saying it's done
and then that gives a really beautiful
color to the tea and everything and our
aeration usually is between
24 and 72 hours depending well 12
actually 12 and 72 hours depending on
you know what cycle our plants are in i
mean the general rule of thumb you know
is
12 to 24 hours
tops i mean that's but you know you then
you're going on just
you know compost tea knowledge just you
know basic compost tea knowledge you
know which is a certain you know a third
of a tablespoon or a of a pound you know
per gallon or and then you and you
bubble it overnight you know or 12 to 24
hours if you do it longer than that you
lose your colony but there's a lot of
reasons why you know even just steeping
it overnight makes a lot of sense so you
can take like
herbs like dried herbs and some compost
tea and you can just steep it overnight
and then just
drench it onto your soil
and then that's really good for your
soil microbes so there's really a lot of
different ways to make teas um and i
think that you have to really think
about you know what your goal is and are
you indoor are you soilless do you have
um you know outdoors so i mean there
really is a lot of questions on how
you're growing on how you're going to
attack you there's not just one way to
do a t from our perspective and we
really like to you know us personally
just like josh said there's a lot of
different ways to make teas
but we really like to have control over
you know what's in our tea brewers which
is the reason why we work with herbal
biomass and our inoculants we're not
really working with
compost because you know
the variety of
differentiation of microbiology in there
is so huge it's so vast so we really
like to have control over what's in our
tea brews so that we know
what's going to be the end product that
we're not going to have anything
anaerobic in there we're not going to
have anything i mean unless it's a
facultative anaerobe and then that's
really awesome but you know nothing that
would be detrimental to the root system
so
we really like to have control over what
is in our tea brews and we pick and
choose particular inoculants that we
make here on our own property
to to make that happen
yeah wow you just read my mind because i
was gonna ask you about facultative
anaerobes i was gonna say i was talking
to mr bob hemphill and he's saying he's
a big fan of adding bokash or you know
em4 imo 4 whatever you're making it with
do you do you feel the same way like do
you like adding bokashi like where you
kind of incorporate that you know the
anaerobic with the aerobic or do you
prefer as you referenced a moment ago to
have you know like your ferment stage
and then your activation stage
well i think with um with bokashi and
and different things like that you have
to be careful because it's it's acidic
in nature so um really using less of it
is using more and we do like bokashi
because we like lactic acid bacteria
because it's you know the main
you know fermenting microbe and
sauerkraut and most of the foods
that we eat so we do like propagating
lactic acid bacteria on our property and
we usually do that through making teas
as far as you know our soils go in our
beds
we we treat them like a compost pile so
we're kind of always adding stuff and
and it creates like a healthy gut for
the plants
and we you know we're slowly adding to
it all the time so
our imo's are basically
attracted to our beds and we don't feel
we need to go collect imo's
even though we'll bring handfuls of dirt
from different environments that we
think are really healthy and maybe we'll
propagate those through teas and drench
them onto our beds
to to spread the microbes but
we we generally use mulch and biomass
and and covering our beds to attract the
indigenous microbes to our beds and we
have less and less compost piles and
more and more just our beds or our
compost and yeah to answer your question
the facultative microbes are just
totally imperative for the beginning
stages of the fermentation those
facultative microbes are the ones that
are just so hardcore and quick digesters
and they can make you know the
difference between a pretty pathogenic
tea and a totally beneficial t and the
and facultative means that they can can
propagate in an anaerobic condition or
an aerobic condition so
you know we're attracted
in our life we're attracted to microbes
that we that to us that's adaptogenic
there they adapt they're able to
to live and propagate in in an anaerobic
situation and then when you go to what
we say activate the the t
then they change with that and we we
like having those kind of microbes that
can that can adapt and we want to
propagate that and put those that into
our soils because you know the
environment is ever changing our bodies
are ever changing and we just want a
really healthy um you know biome around
us
of course so i noticed on a few
different instagram posts sometimes
people will ask you maybe like what
you're using in a specific picture in
relation to say a top dress or like
something along those lines and the
general answer you kind of give is like
oh you know like we're just using stuff
that's around the place
would you try to maintain that
philosophy everywhere you go or is that
more so applicable just because you're
like obviously on your farm you've got
access to a lot of this stuff so you are
able to just kind of use what's around
but maybe somewhere else like i guess
what the question is is do you think
that there's stuff people can use no
matter where they are or do you think
you guys are a little bit lucky and that
you do have stuff laying around so to
speak
absolutely it's totally important that
people utilize what they have around
their own environment because that own
and whatever they have in their own
environment is is intelligent to that
area
you know to utilize plants that are
growing really well and that are super
healthy um we also you know with our
pure certification we have to have you
know people are looking for this at
least six closed loops and creating your
own nutrients and growing your own
is a really big part of that loop and
that's ever-changing depending on where
you are you know if you're in arizona
you're going to be utilizing a
tremendous amount of prickly pear and
cactus and different types of sage brush
and it's incredible the nutrients that
are available in those in those plants
and and also the cyanobacteria
that's on the outside of those leaves
are are there for a reason they're there
to keep the plant healthy during its
life but they're also there to help
digest it in in the time of its death or
when the leaves drop to the ground so
when you're collecting biomass in your
area you're also collecting microbiology
on the leaf structure as well
so you know your teeth should be
absolutely as intelligent as they
possibly can be and that's going to come
from your own property so we've we
definitely have chosen the area that we
live in for a reason because it is rich
in biomass and we do really resonate
with this area so that part is true we
are really lucky where we live
but um like kelly said and we we have
traveled the world to a lot of different
places we've worked in a lot of um you
know international projects and in a
disaster projects and we went to jamaica
for a month this year and and worked
with the the rasta village there and we
worked with with um you know making
biomass gardens um everywhere that we've
gone in each country that we've gone to
so we we don't think that it's it's
something that just we do on our
property we we say it's absolutely
imperative for people to do it
everywhere they are and every time we go
somewhere we really um you know really
look to the area as soon as we get there
and say oh what can we use and what can
we use there so yeah i i think that you
can um get really creative and that's
the thing about our pure certification
as well
and all of the farmers that that we that
are are part of that movement and that
regenerative movement of cannabis is
that you know it's part it's part of
connecting with your environment and
that's the way that you can really
really
um ensure that you're you're getting
clean inputs into your farm and we
haven't talked about that yet but having
clean inputs onto your farm is
absolutely imperative and moving forward
in the new legalization paradigm of
cannabis um we have to be real extremely
careful about the products that we bring
into our property and i think that's
been a big part of this
regenerative cannabis uh movement is
people that's why
people have have started to grow more
diversity on their property i mean part
of being pure certified is you can't
just have a cannabis farm you have to
grow other
other biomass like like kelly was saying
and and and that's part of connecting
with your land so trees and bushes and
food grass and and even you know local
livestock and stuff are a crucial part
of building life on your farm even if
you have an indoor operation you can
still use you know the edges of you know
the land around it to to make
um you know mass for your gardens and
and part of being regenerative is
understanding the botany that grows
around your region and your area and and
a lot of people that call something
maybe a noxious weed that's come in from
an outside source
those noxious weeds are there for a
reason it's because they have found a
home that is going to be able to
help them express you know their true
health
and well-being and those can be utilized
so much and then that helps
down the noxious weeds in your area but
then you're also utilizing them in your
teas and we suggest to make sure to
utilize those noxious weeds you know
before they seed so that you're not
continuing you know the propagation of
them but if it's something that you have
on your property of course use it you
know in oregon and in northern
california they have a tremendous amount
of of a himalayan blackberry and an
alpine blackberry it grows there like
crazy
but when you start looking at all of the
nutritive capabilities that this plant
has when you chop it up or you put it in
a tea the amount of growth hormones that
are in it then you have an understanding
of why it's so noxious because it has
such incredible capability to grow so
fast
in a really small space
so we really encourage people to look
around and understand the plant life
that's around your area and then start
picking and choosing what you want to
propagate and also what you want to put
into your teas or into your compost or
chip up or put on the top as a mulch you
know you could go on and on so i got a
question where it's kind of like the
devil's in the details but i guess what
i'm wondering is
would you want to say
not use something which is kind of
external but it would have been a waste
anyway so what i'm getting at is i love
to go down to my local coffee store and
grab the coffee grinds you know it's
just my plants love it when i talk dress
it with them but i understand it brings
with a myriad of questions you know like
where's the beans is it gmo like you
know all that type of stuff that comes
along with it for those reasons is it
just something you would look to avoid
or are you okay with something like that
where broadly speaking you are kind of
using what would have otherwise been
wasted
well i mean we're living in a in a world
of of international
products and in an international world
of food and if there's something that
you feel like wow you know this would be
really good for my farm definitely find
out what the source is go all the way
down with it but if you have an
intuition that those coffee grounds are
going to be great for your farm and you
feel like it would be really helpful
then it's good to take in a small amount
of whatever said thing that you're
bringing into your property and utilize
it in a small area give like a trial of
two to three weeks or something like
that have a look at it and then say yeah
my intuition is right because i believe
with science and and and all of these
tests and trials that we do involving
science it's starting to take away
you know our basic innate
understanding of intuition
and gardening is such an intuitive thing
you know humans are of the earth plants
are of the earth of course we
communicate with each other of course
we're having conversations on another
level and we really encourage people to
have those conversations with your land
and your soil and the plants around you
and and also the inputs that you're
going to be able to bring in it's it's a
really
an individual
matter but also whatever inputs that
you're bringing in make sure that you
feel really good about it and that your
intuition is right and it is sound to
create an a good ultimate immune
response and wherever you're putting it
and for me it brings up you know another
question is
number one where are you in the world
and of course we always
you know
we always talk about being crafty and
and you know you we have to be
resourceful and use you know what's in
our area
and
depending on where you live in the world
and with cannabis especially it is a
dynamic accumulator accumulates stuff
out of the soil so depending on what
level of scrutiny you have i mean
there's
some farms that can't
use
you know municipality um compost like
from different cities because of
different sprays that might be used you
know on the roadside if they used that
compost thinking oh geez you know
our city produces compost and i just
want to use compost from my city it just
only makes all the sense in the world
like on a human level yeah it does make
sense but if on on an actual reality of
testing
you could potentially fail tests with
cannabis by using bad
inputs so yeah i mean you have to be
really
pretty mindful in certain places in
other places you know it only makes
sense to use what's around you and also
to add to what you know josh was just
saying is that there's a tremendous
amount you know in north america right
now and also in other parts of the world
of the use of glyphosate
and glyphosate is not something that's
even being tested because department of
ags all over the world and these really
large multinational multi-international
corporations feel like glyphosate is
totally healthy and that you know we
should be able to drink it so why is it
a problem but we're finding it more and
more along the roadsides we're finding
it everywhere and then prolonged use in
your soil beds is going to kill your
microbiology it is an herbicide and an
herbicide you know kills all different
types of microbiology and it has a huge
long life you know the half-life they're
saying now you know they've already
negated at least 10 times over so the
truth is that we don't really know how
long those half-lifes are of these
horrible chemicals and over prolonged
use in your gardens you're going to be
killing all of your microbiology which
is going against everything that you
began by being able to bring in those
inputs so
it's a really it's a difficult question
yeah if you have an indoor garden you
may not have as a
soil that's as
vigorous as an outdoor garden an outdoor
garden you have the ability to create a
ton of biomass and a ton of microbiology
and if you're if you're
positive microbiology outweighs
the little bit of toxins that you might
be getting from an inorganic coffee
thing that it would probably might it
might remediate it
but if you get anything out of balance
you could throw that off and kill the
microbiology like what kelly's saying
and we're not really believing that you
know
nature and microbiology
um you know are not very good at
remediating horrible toxins on the
planet any better than we're able to
remediate those toxins when we ingest it
and we always go back to human health
soil health plant health it's just all
the same
so whenever there's information out
there in the science world and you're
looking up a particular
product or something or or
some kind of an input look at all of the
human health that it has attached to it
as well you know take the time to google
all of that information and go deeper
affects pollinators and it affects
pollinators or how it affects our own
immune response
yeah okay that's very interesting so
i want to know then
if i so for example here in australia
glyphosate is incredibly widely used
there's almost no concern about it at
least in the sense their ways in the
states which is a little alarming but
essentially if i was to buy a new
property and move on there i would you
know bet my left leg that it's been
sprayed down with glyphosate a lot so
you know obviously you know the details
would give the specifics of this
situation but if you had to give a rule
of thumb how long would you think it
would take for me to kind of buy or
that uh kind of land i bought and more
importantly would you be okay with say
consuming the first crop produced on
that land or would you want to do some
work first before you were feeling
comfortable about that
i would i would start um to sort of
begin
the the question that where you started
at the end there was i would definitely
start bio remediation with plant matter
that wasn't vegetables that i would be
eating
as far as a time period of how long that
would take to remediate it i mean
possibly your whole lives and and your
grandchildren's lives that's something
that we just don't know because the
information that we're getting is so
one-sided because it's all being put out
by the makers of this particular product
so they've got
you know
a real
uh
investment to make sure that the
scientific research goes along the way
that they would like it to go along but
we know for sure that heavily laden
glyphosate areas you just simply put a
pea in there or a bean
it won't grow
they don't you know those are kind of
plants that don't do very well with
herbicide before you buy the property
go
try and plant peas on it
because peas are one of those they're
they're they're one of the most
susceptible things to herbicides so you
just be like you know what i just can i
plant a row of peas here right now and
come back a week later and if they've
sprouted then you've got something you
can work with but if they do don't
sprout and there's no reason for it
you might seriously consider it and we
and we totally tell people to test the
soil for sure if you're going to buy a
piece of land you can test it in and
with glyphosate like i know i i'm not
sure exactly about soil tests in
australia but
um
there'll be soil tests that have you
know 30 different you know pesticides
and herbicides that they test for but
glyphosate will not be one of them for
the same reason that you just said
because you know they think oh you know
you can dump you know glyphosate in your
cheetos in the morning and it's totally
fine um but
um
so
you you really have to be you know very
mindful of what you're using
and and get a soil test
so the
kind of in related to all of this stuff
the first thing i'll add is that i think
unfortunately in australia soil tests
are quite cost prohibitive like i think
um to get a fairly basic one you're
probably looking at around 150 to 200
which i think that's some tests in the
states are like that expensive but it
certainly seems very expensive here
especially considering you know we're in
like an illegal market
but um
something i did wanted to ask you guys
about was just the interesting range of
soil additives you have in that
excuse me the cocoa that's the one which
the cocoa sorry um that's the one which
grabs my interest the most you know
because it's like you see alfalfa you
see you see a lot of stuff being used by
a lot of people and i think that you
guys use all of that stuff in a really
interesting way but the coco the kokoa
was the one which really grabbed my
interest because you just you don't see
it outside of your products so how did
you come up with that and what was kind
of the rationale behind it
well the rationale is when you look at a
plant and you see a plant through its
whole cycle it starts out as a sprout
first of all it starts as a seed and the
seed has all the vast nutrients that are
available it almost becomes like a micro
superfood a seed does because it
contains
everything that that plant should
contain in
and then once it grows out then it
starts to have other different kinds of
nutrients like say nitrogen and calcium
and then as the plant starts growing out
even more
it's up taking different minerals and
different nutrients from the soil
throughout its entire life cycle and we
know that for cannabis you know we add a
lot of nitrogen at the beginning and
then we move to their phosphorus and
potassium and phosphorus and that sort
of thing well plants are no different in
in the wild so
they're uptaking you know basic
nutrients at the beginning and then when
they turn into a seed form like the
cacao then it starts to become a very
nutrient dense
uh
product or or you know in this case it
was a product but you know nutrient
dense part of the plant
a cacao
uh
mines a tremendous amount of magnesium
and manganese and copper out of the soil
and had a million other you know and a
million other things so we utilize the
raw cacao because when you test raw
cacao it has a tremendous amount of
nutrients that helps a plant finish
because it's the finishing part of the
cacao tree
it's no different than say you know
you're utilizing maybe sesame seeds are
going to contain a lot more finishing
compounds and minerals and nutrients in
it than the first sprout of that
particular sesame and that's why we use
spirulina in our radiant green in the in
the vegetative one
because you know nothing's
more nutritive than one celled organisms
and algaes so
you know the raw cacao has a wide
variety of trace minerals and and
nutrients and vitamins at the very end
and this and also the wild yam is one
that you did
did you want us to talk about more of
the
ingredients yeah yeah i'd love to hear
more about it especially what i wanted
to hear was um what organic ingredients
you look to for phosphorus because
phosphorus is one of those ones where
it's a little less common to come by
phosphorus can definitely be mined up in
a plant there's lots of different plants
that are going to contain phosphorus and
like i was saying before it's going to
be the ending part of the plant that's
going to have the most phosphorus so
tubers
wild yam has you know phosphorus as well
as like yams that you eat out of the
ground potatoes have a lot of phosphorus
in our products we utilize burdock root
and the reason why we utilize burdock
root is just 5 000 years of ancient
chinese history you know of of of
healing of the body
and like i had said before we always
look at the healing of the body the same
as healing of the plant and burdock has
so many healing modalities because of
the tremendous amount of nutrients in it
and one of the nutrients in there that's
so rich is phosphorus
so rather than getting mined phosphorus
or phosphorus that really leeches out
into the soil you know you can add rock
phosphate and you're going to lose about
80 percent of that rock phosphate
whereas if you
feed phosphorus rich plants tubers seeds
finishing parts of the plant and you
feed it to the microbiology then it
becomes immediately available to the
plant
and phosphorus is one of those ones that
you know can be found like i said in the
finishing party and also a big a big
part of our um you know practices that
we that we promote is is having a you
know a type of
soil that has a lot of compost in it
that's composting and living
and the the breakdown of of
of leaf mold leaf matter and and
different stuff like that produces
phosphorus in the soil so we really
believe that you know having an active
soil that's being that's breaking down
is producing enough phosphorus we don't
actually we never use more phosphorus
ever on our property than what's
produced just by our soils and these
plants and and the seeds and the the
roots that we use so and turkey rhubarb
is another one in there for the last 20
years we've been growing you know in a
way that we don't utilize any of those
bat guano phosphoruses and it's like
this
thing which is rock phosphate anyway
yeah actually it's not in the baguano so
just having a really active soil and
then using roots and seeds which is the
ending product of the plant um provides
the phosphorus potassium
um
you know manganese and and all that
stuff that we need and josh just create
the flower josh has touched on something
that we feel is like incredibly
important is the use of trees
the use of tree leaves
trees the ultimate miners
they send down their roots as tall as
they are you know they're mining all
kinds of things in the soil and then
they bring them up into their leaves and
then they drop their leaves and i'm
talking about deciduous trees in this
particular instance not eucalyptus of
course they don't use any eucalyptus
anything
and so they they take all of the
nutrients up into the tree and then they
drop all of those and then the cycle
continues again
so utilizing tree leaves um you know
contain an incredible amount of fuel
term minerals and phosphorus is
definitely one
and is that something when you say the
tree leaves you're referring to like a
leaf mold type of thing or just a direct
top dressing type of a situation
yeah you can direct top dress um because
it's gonna turn into leaf mold
immediately anyway
we we now look at our beds like these
living beings like i we had opened up
the conversation to begin with you know
so we're always layering things on top
of our beds
making sure that we're not layering
anything that would turn it hot
you know we don't want necessarily hot
composting to be happening in the beds
but we certainly want cold composting to
be happening in the beds
and the beautiful thing about nature
is that especially when you're in an
area that has seasons
everything is available all at the right
time
and then when the seasons come it it it
provides the nutrients that your gardens
need at that time you know all of the
flowers start coming out and the seeds
and the tubers start coming out right at
the same time that your plants are
needing phosphorus that your tomatoes
are needing phosphorus to produce juicy
tomatoes
there's some kind of a beauty in the
cycles of nature and if we just pay
attention then it's all there for us i
mean you know permaculture did come out
of tasmania in so many ways and
in australia and there's there's plenty
of examples you know across the
you know
across the country there in the in the
continent that that show is really
similar to what we're talking about
yeah definitely definitely there's a a
lot of really good gardeners shout out
to steve solomon in tasmania
um so
yeah he's a big guru so
something i wanted to ask you is i'd
noticed that over say the past three or
four years there had been this kind of
unspoken trend within the no-till scene
so to speak that there'd been there'd
been a move away from animal products
and
especially you know in terms of like
amendments and so the question which i
was wondering is
do you think that it's the case that
we've just found better replacements or
it's more a case that there's also an
underlying objection to you know like
the raising and the slaughtering
um
well
all of it so to answer that question i i
always say to people okay so what does
it look like on a hot summer day when
you throw a steak out on the lawn that's
raw and then you leave it there for a
week or if you throw an apple out on the
lawn and then you leave it there for a
week
what kind of different bacteria and
fungi are going to overtake that to be
able to digest it down and basically
turn it into soil
the meat is going to have incredibly
aggressive
anaerobic fungi and bacteria bugs and
worms and maggots
yeah i mean it could be fun watch it
it's going to draw a tremendous amount
of pathogens in order for it to become
beneficial
whereas the apple that's like you know
being digested on the lawn there in the
hot summer day is going to just start
drawing
all of these beautiful
things that turn white and you could you
know things meaning microbiology it's
great fungi and and different bacteria
and you could almost take that rotting
apple and you know put it right into
your soil
you know i don't necessarily suggest
this but then that would be come you
know a beneficial colony you really
couldn't take the steak and put it into
there
at all so
we haven't used animal products
ever
it's just not we've been growing for
almost three decades
and and we haven't utilized any animal
products other than manure that's you
know from our own farm here you know
that's all grass-fed no grain
um
because we feel like the pathogens that
break down that animal matter is just
not something that we want to bring into
our gardens and nor do we like
to support something
that is unkind or harmful to the planet
yeah and through soil testing i mean you
when you're doing no-till you're doing
something that's that's continuous
you know where you're using the same
stuff for a long time you know you do
have to be mindful of what you put in
there and just like kelly said you know
certain animal products
just don't have the same kind of
longevity that you're going for
and that's why the forest is so
beautiful because you know it really
shows the power of of plant medicine and
and how well it can do
and also you know organic farmers here
in
north america
to be certified organic on a vegetable
farm
they use a tremendous amount of blood
and bone meal like a tremendous amount
and when you test that blood and bone
meal the glyphosate levels are really
high because the cows are eating the
grain that's glyphosate laden and also
they're eating the grass that's
glyphosate laden and that's bringing all
of that into so you're not only bringing
possible pathogenic nutrients into your
property but you're also bringing a
tremendous amount of glyphosate and who
knows what else
so
you know
really supporting the slaughterhouses is
not something that we feel like we want
to touch at all we don't want to support
those slaughterhouses and we really
don't want to support the microbiology
that it takes to break down those
slaughterhouses we're also really
careful with plants like neem and
karanja and different you know seed
meals that haven't also lasted very well
in soil
that's interesting so you guys are not
big fans of neem
well i mean
you know there's
neat the neem tree is phenomenal
and so of course you know we love the
neem tree and you know to take neem you
know there's neem tease and knee
medicine is is a good thing
it's just also you know it's it's
it's not something that promotes
you know by microbiology in the soil
and um
it's a volatile oil so you know anything
that has
any plants that have large aromatics you
have to be really careful about what
those aromatics are you know if you're
going to
break down a ton of geranium you know
you might really want to think of
putting a ton of geranium into your
soils because it contains high geranol
and geranol is great to get rid of pests
and you know pathogens possibly on the
leaf source or maybe in the soil but if
you're utilizing it over a long period
of time then your beneficials aren't
going to be like yay this is an awesome
soil to be in because there's just such
a vast amount of volatile oils
so we really stay away from you know
eucalyptus or black walnut or even neem
in large amounts or karanja or any of
these like super volatile oil plants
it's not a way that we want to deal with
the pathogens that those are trying to
kill so that we're we'll use predators
for that instead so we we don't need to
top dress with neem and those kind of
things because
we know that the neem is going to kill
other microbiology because we work with
you know a lot of people that you know
do soil testing all the time and and and
we've that we they've shown that you
know and so
that's not a thing that we use and we've
always felt like that kind of weary
about it
okay and so in general do you veer more
towards wanting to have say a bacterial
dominant soil a fungal dominant soil or
just a kind of a one-to-one type of
ratio
always a blend
always a blend you definitely want to
have your bacteria is just going to last
in there for a short time so it's
awesome that your bacteria that your
teas are super bacteria rich
and that your soils are really fun fungi
rich so that the bacteria is going to
stay in there long enough just to break
down that green material the leaf
material light material and then be able
to give it to the plant but you know the
prolonged breakdown of the soil is
definitely you know our fungi friends
it's almost easy to get the bacteria so
it's not you know it's it's you we
with hugo culture and with you know
carbon sequestration and
carbon farming is is really to attract
fungi so we're we're really kind of
doing all we can to get more fungi into
our soils because through a lot of soil
testing
um you know you'd find that there's
lower fungal mass and there is
bacterial you know mass so we you know
that's why we're adding biomass so much
to our soils is
the the fungi really interact with the
roots and to directly feed the plant and
you're feeding a lot of soil fungi by
feeding it bacteria so there's a whole
lot of really awesome fungi that eats
bacteria directly that have you know
this beautiful relationship with the top
layer is totally bacteria rich and then
as you go down lower you've got more
fungi so that's why adding more you know
bacteria-rich compounds throughout the
time to make sort of a calm cold
composting in your
in your soil beds is a great idea
because then in time that bacteria top
layer is going to turn into a fungi rich
lower layer yeah i mean you can add
anything hard and you're going to get
more carbon more sticks
you know a little stick maybe stocks
from your previous harvest you could
work into the top part of your soil
um or even adding for a you know
pre-made soil of people that have indoor
adding sawdust
to your to your soil is great as well
you know when you're having a pre-mixed
soil or some wood chips yeah deciduous
because then you're not dealing with the
acidity but it but if it's really old
then the acidity you know goes away as
well that's a whole other conversation
there's so much
yeah yeah i mean something which kind of
i think is an overall topic of this
whole kind of thread is and i've seen
you reference it on a few different
youtube videos there's kind of this
conundrum of organic certification
organic labels you know just that the
whole the holiday thing it's like it's
like a minefield these days so with that
being said are you happy to use
something which is not strictly organic
so long as you're confident it's kind of
beneficial in some way or another
yeah absolutely there's a lot of people
and a lot of farmers out there in the
world that don't want to have anything
to do with a certification
even if they're an alfalfa farmer
because they don't feel like their
regenerative practices are
representative that certification and
unfortunately it's like there's not many
certifications
and that's the reason why we came up
with the peer certification is because
we just felt really sort of angry
really upset with what the commonality
of what people saw as organic and if it
had that label on it then oh that's good
enough for me but when you start reading
into it you know 30 of your inputs can
be non-organic and then there's a whole
list of pesticides you can add and a
whole list of herbicides and
all different kinds of things that are
underneath that and like you said yeah
it started out like in in the u.s with
the oregon tilth and they did a really
good job but now they can't utilize that
term organic unless it's along with the
usda organic or the canadian organic
standards and certifications so yeah i i
say it depends because it's kind of a
know your farmer situation i mean if you
find yourself in the countryside
and you've got in your area someone
who's been farming you know a certain
way their whole time and they just
didn't want to go bother
going through and buying the
certification and getting that kind of
um you know validation then i mean we
would say use that because that farmer
is probably just more
radical to keep it natural than someone
who's part of the system it's almost
like when you're part of the system you
have to question it more so it's kind of
really knowing your source you know of
where it's coming from and now there's
been this incredible
movement of power in the peer
certification because pure farmers are
now joining together and going out onto
farmer's plots and saying hey
we'll buy all of your hay or your straw
every single bit of it if you don't
spray it and you add these things to it
and you let all of the weeds grow so now
the farmer is getting a higher price
from pure farmers and that's just like
sacred commerce that creates
knowing your source you're actually
creating knowing yourself powers your
alfalfa farmer and empowers your field
farmer who may not have had a reason to
care
that person might have just been like oh
you know what the farmers these bigger
companies are just they just pay me and
then i just do it and they give me seed
i don't have to think about it but you
might have farmers that you know
if they were if they had a community of
people that were like listen we value
you not using any chemicals on your
products or on your field you know we'll
pay this specific price and then farmers
now have an incentive to to
to grow you know their their their their
alfalfa in a good way and that's why the
pure farmers are making an impact not
just on their farm but but even way
farther and we encourage the listeners
to look up dem
purefarms.com
which is a website that we've created
which highlights um close the closed
loop practices that we talk about and
the farms that that do those practices
and shows those farms and in the
different states so when you say is it
just us on our farm no you can see you
know close to 80 different examples of
other people doing it in in different
places in the world
there's mostly in the us and canada at
this moment and and this certification
you know that we're talking about is a
movement it's an activist movement it's
not something you can even buy it
doesn't cost anything it's free
and it's in its community run in that we
don't decide the final
you know if somebody is looking to be
pure certified we set the standards and
we and we sort of set it out but it
becomes a community brain and a mind so
that say somebody in humboldt is wanting
to be certified well all of the pure
farmers in humboldt are the ones that go
to that farm and make a decision on
whether it is
matching their farm and whether they
feel like it's the same standard as
their farm and in that it creates
community and more of a conversation so
that we can all get better
and that goes into your conversation
about sourcing just right back at it if
there's more people trying to source the
same thing then we know exactly where
we're getting it from and we know
exactly what it contains and you know
i'll just i'll just make the point that
you know we
we love ganja and when we smoke it we we
feel like
in harmony with nature and we have that
connection of naturalness and and and to
be a naturalist and so we we really
it is an activist movement just to just
make the impact as widespread as
possible and that that that's really
what this is and it is really exciting
and it's nice to have something exciting
in a time when you know there's a lot of
doom and gloom
yeah of course and so i think the thing
which you touched on and which appeals
to me the most about the pure
certification is that yeah there's
there's the kind of uh community
responsibility aspect to it all do you
think that that same kind of philosophy
needs to be extended to more parts of
the movement and i guess the thing which
jumps to mind to me the most is kind of
the activism within say the legal sector
you know do you think there needs to be
that same kind of onus on ourselves to
kind of take responsibility for the
things we want to see happen in a way
absolutely cannabis is not just a plant
it's a culture and it doesn't matter
where you are on the planet it's so cool
i mean so many listeners out there and
i'm sure you would feel the same way you
know you could go anywhere in the world
and you're seeing somebody that's
totally different from a totally
different place from a totally different
you know whatever different age group or
different socioeconomic group or or
possibly a different race or whatever
but if you have cannabis in in common
all of a sudden that they're a dude
that's like great you know you're just
like all of a sudden friends with that
person and i believe that
that camaraderie and that family energy
and culture of cannabis
absolutely needs to be in the forefront
having a rightful voice for this plant
that has given us so much
you know when we ingest it it gives us
uh you know a higher understanding of
nature and and more of a community
mindset and i think that that community
mindset is everything that we need to be
able to move forward both in the
political sector and also all the way
down to the cultivation sector
yeah and then and and i will and i will
say that this this movement has gone you
know political and and we do have
friends and family that are working in
in politics and
i don't want to say the word politics
but influencing laws and and
and
you know give thanks give thanks to them
and regulations and stuff and so and and
it's also just in in cafes and even
beyond like and midwifery is something
that's really important to us you know
and there's just a lot of things that
see this kind of movement this pure kind
of movement as more of a lifestyle and
that's why regenerative is a word that
that's being used a lot by us in the
community is because it makes sense to
to use a regenerative lifestyle because
we really do need to regenerate you know
we can't sustain you know where we are
in this world or in this in this path we
have to go beyond sustaining and
regenerate and so the pure certification
is it's it is cannabis and food based
but it goes way beyond it really does
and we're in an international you know
community now i mean as a perfect
example we're talking to you in
australia as if you're here in our front
room and what a wonderful opportunity to
be able to reach out to the whole world
and i think that cannabis needs to be
seen as is international now you know we
all need to join together we all need to
be on the same page and that's the way
that we're going to be able to
have the rightful voice like i was
saying before for the plant and i
believe that you know so many investors
we call them outvesters but just for fun
um so many investors and so many
different you know corporations out
there trying to own it but nobody
brought a seat up for the plant
in that conversation or in that
conference call nobody is having a
conversation you know if they're in that
corporate mindset and i believe that as
we move forward into the rules and the
regulations and into our own use
and you know into the health and
well-being of of introducing our
cannabis culture to the whole world we
have an incredible responsibility to
have a rightful voice for the plant and
that she's always part of our
conversations and how we move forward
yeah okay i can definitely agree with
all of that
so i had one question which i was
actually struggling to think of how i
was going to slide it in but you guys
just gave me the perfect segue when you
mentioned that midwifery i know that you
guys have been toying slash you know 100
doing like a kind of pregnancy brew for
a while i was interested in that like
how did that start and like can you just
give us a bit more information about it
um
well i'm a midwife and i've been in the
natural health field
naturopathic medicine herbology
chinese medicine
uh since my early 20s
and um
you know mid to early 90s yeah so it's
really early
for a really long time yeah
and um
yeah and we're so so youthful we're
still saying don't worry
well the veterans are really around us
we like to give like a lot of respect to
the the veterans yeah the truth the
elders yeah
um
but i
i've always utilized you know a
beautiful tea blend and i've
thought that herbs and steeping and
brewing herbs were just a really good
way to get immediate
results in a human condition so any
maladies that anybody had you know
whether it was a body wash which is like
a fuller ear spray or whether it's like
in you know drinking it and you're
drinking it for your kidneys or whatever
different things that you know utilizing
herbs for that and pregnancy tea
uh is is really close to my heart
because i feel like
you know you can take pregnancy
supplements and
because it's like mined minerals and
it's very
difficult for your digestive tract to
understand
herbs in the same way you know like
pills
in the form of capsules or something
like that you know like a supplement
whole food capsule wouldn't be the same
as a whole food
you know coming out of your garden
so and then we know if you steep those
teas then it starts to extract the
minerals like overnight
and you can grow a beautiful healthy you
know mama and baby with with great
breast milk after the baby is born just
off of herbs
and that's where we took that whole
ideology and started putting it into
soil
and i had a an old tea brew blend you
know i could
grow all of my own herbs and then give
them out to all of the ladies that i
work with i
had one that was a year old and the new
crop was coming up and i just thought
hey you know what i'm i'm just gonna
steep this we've always just steeped
nettles and horsetail before i'm gonna
steep this entire pregnancy brew
and see what happens and it was like as
if the plants were just screaming out
the next day like this is it you got it
you know it's it's herbology for plants
you can help us and treat us and help us
grow and help stimulate our immune
response
through other plants because it's
something that they understand and we've
always had a really spiritual connection
with our gardens and with our gardening
and with our wild crafting and foraging
and we've always had a you know a
spiritual connection so you know we we
definitely recognized of course that
we're growing a female plant in the
female cannabis plant so it was a
natural connection to using herbology
for women to using herbology for female
plants and so that's why there's like
wild yam which is a feminine you know
hormone
herb which is in in our fat flowers
blend
and that's why people we feel get such a
great response in their flowers and in
their terpene um response by using you
know the products and our blends that we
put together or also utilizing even
flowers you know when you see things
that are flowering it's a great thing to
utilize in your flowers
so that's a you know a feminine quality
to a feminine quality so that's why we
utilize a lot of flowers on our property
and we suggest for people to do that
it's just been an intertwined you know
let's say um work of life that we've
intertwined you know the gardening with
the human health
and it's been extremely beneficial and
we feel like it's timeless it's
something that doesn't go away and it's
it's almost like it awakens something
primal inside people and when they learn
about it you know they just want to do
it it just makes so much sense
yeah of course i can relate to that
so when you say you use um say things
like even flowers from other plants in
the teas
is that
kind of like the more terpene rich the
better and the reason why i asked this
is because uh i've got this frangipani
tree in my backyard and it smells so
much and it drops so many flowers on me
and i've been looking at it for so long
gone i need to make a ferment out of
this what do you guys think
oh i think it's fantastic it's a great
idea you're just taking all of those
terpenes and then making them totally
usable for your microbiology and then
uptake into your plants
it's great and franjapani oh amazing i
just had a big whiff of it go through my
body when you said that that's beautiful
um another thing is um as far as you
know fermenting it and extracting that
there's really kind of two ways to
ferment biomass and i think it's good to
touch on it which is
you know using sugar to extract it and
make
a concentrate with the biomass or using
let's say water and doing more of an
herbal juice
and so we've
we've touched on this in this in this
disc in this discussion already but we
really we really prefer the juice the
water version as opposed to the soil one
it does depend i mean you may live in
like in your area with you know near
sugar cane or some kind of like sweet
crop or
something that you can use sugar really
easily and it might be fruit it might
make a lot of sense in your area so
once again you know farming is a
bio-regional thing and it really you
can't say one thing for all areas but
in a lot of our areas um in the northern
hemisphere um you know
sugar doesn't do well you know up here
it doesn't grow and and in our bodies
it's it's like a hot it's a hot thing
that goes through our body and it burns
out quick so we don't really want to use
that it's not good for our health so
when i'm extracting with sugar and when
it doesn't come from our area it doesn't
make sense we really want to try and
make a tea that's from our area which
empowers us to not have to bring
something from far away and using water
and just chopping up your herbs and and
putting herbs and water and letting them
ferment and juice
you know with the lactic acid bacteria
mother culture and fermenting it and
juice and then straining it out and
activating it is um our favorite way to
extract biomass yeah and what josh means
by juice is the natural plant sugars
that are already present in the plant
and you know also the the reference to
hot you know sugar
sugar is something that when you eat it
in your body it creates immediate energy
the energy is quick it's fast
and then as we all know that's why
people call it a sugar high because
there's a downside to the sugar high
and microbiology has that same thing so
if you add a whole bunch of sugar to
your tea brews it's going to spark an
immediate microbiological
like effect
that then burns out very quickly and
maybe sugars are okay to add a tiny
teeny tiny bit to maybe start spark that
microbiology but you want your
microbiology to be subsist
off of the plant material and the plant
sugars in the plant extracts that are
already within there
so you know we we don't utilize sugars
in our tea brews because we really don't
eat sugar in our home either
um you know people utilize some of these
as an extract i think that maybe it is
it is a good idea if you
have an opportunity to buy a product at
a store or you have an opportunity to
make your own extract and concentrate
from plants that are say seasonal and
then you bring it to your indoor um you
know operation then that makes a lot of
sense because the more homemade things
the better
but
fresh is always going to be best
and we feel like utilizing the plant
sugars over
any type of processed sugar
is going to be the best and and also to
interject here really quickly sugars are
very different you know evaporated cane
juice is very different than beet sugar
and you know you have to be very careful
um what you're eating and also what
you're putting in your tea brews the
beet sugar is a monosaccharide you know
your your microbiology doesn't recognize
it it just starts killing things it's
the same within your body so when you
look at a label that just says sugar
it's mostly going to be beet sugar
because that's a gmo crop that they're
producing on a mass level and it just
produces a lot of candida and yeast
things within our body and also within
our soil so looking up what a
polysaccharide is and the more
saccharides that are in within a sugar
is definitely what you're looking for
because that's going to be a prebiotic
to certain types of organisms that are
beneficial and yeah cone is one thing
that's came and that's coming to our
life which is from south america and
it's a watery tuber and it's really
really
um sweet and it's a really really good
companion plant planets aerates your
soils and it's a really good thing to
use for and a great prebiotic and also
polysaccharides it's high in inulin as
as opposed to insulin and it's just a
prebiotic um
it's a prebiotic for good microbiology
yes that's all really interesting stuff
especially with that inulin comment i've
been looking into that a little more
myself recently
something that i wanted to ask about the
evaporated cane sugar this may feel like
a little bit of a redundant question but
i notice it's in some of your products
and so i guess the question is do you
find like that's the one you would pick
if you had to use one or is there
something maybe a little better but you
know for whatever reason you don't put
that in the products like where do you
sit on the sugars like which is your
personal favorite well we put that in
our product because we know the source
of that and so the source is always
really important we know that that farm
that makes that sugar
is of ups you know standing value it's a
smaller you know farm it's a good
product it contains a lot of
polysaccharides it is from cane sugar
and we put a tiny bit in there
just to spark the microbiology to wake
them up to then have them start eating
the herbs and that's exactly what we do
within our tea brews as well but when
you've got fresh
plants then you're going to be having a
lot more sugars that there's no need to
add any other extra sugar because we
notice the microbiology is sparked up
right away but in our product there's
dried you know um
herbs in there so to spark the
microbiology immediately is a good idea
but you don't want them to sustain off
of the sugars because then that's just
creating you want yeah fungi that's
pathogenic the herbology that you put in
there
the herbs
yeah perfect makes sense so if we just
loop back to one or two questions ago
when i was talking about the kind of the
onus on the community to be you know
more solidified in a legal sense i guess
i just wanted to ask a few quick legal
questions like i guess the most kind of
relevant one to me is if you could kind
of just change one
law or maybe a few which ultimately just
kind of change one thing ultimately
what's the one thing that you feel is
most pertinent to get fixed or changed
or whatever you know set right so to
speak
i mean right off the bat i would love to
see cannabis decriminalized and not
legalized
because legalized means that you're
immediately going to have rules and
regulations and all different kinds of
conference calls and people and money
and investors and corporations and big
bucks and everything is coming in and it
really has a negative connotation but
when you decriminalize something that
allows people to go on about their
business and lots of herbs are you know
decriminalized
you can't really like go and make a
whole bunch of them or whatever you know
say like poppy or something you can grow
them in your garden and it's up to you
as to what you want to do with that and
just right off the bat
that's really uh you know radical did
you mean agriculture laws
yeah like anything really i mean maybe
maybe a a better example would be maybe
something a little smaller than like a
you know broad scale decriminalization
like because i hear a lot of people
complain about lots of the the smaller
like kind of sub legalities of the
legalization like whether it be
limits on how much small producers can
grow or just you know like financial
hurdles for certain people to get into
the game you know all those types of
things
yeah well i mean capping capping you
know the the your farm canopy your
canopy is i think is a great way a great
law
because um
when you don't cap
when you have a legalization structure
and you don't cap what farms can do then
you just get crazy farms
like in canada and different places in
california you get these farms that are
like 20 acres and they're a million
square feet and all of a sudden it's
like how many million square feet
companies do you need
in a country or in a legalized
area so i think
capping it and having more farms is
going to give
more you know ability for more farms to
grow and really what we need is and i
think this is a problem and and a lot of
agriculture is is the corporatization of
it and the mass scale of it all i think
we need a lot of
smaller farms producing more intentional
um
products
and so i think that capping it would be
one thing another thing with with as far
as agriculture laws and organics goes i
mean i would like to see organic mean
absolutely no chemicals used and another
one
plastic mulch
not allowed
plastic mulch not allowed with organic
farming
sorry
it's not organic sorry organic farm
not okay yeah i mean every single year
you're gonna throw away your plastic
mulch because you can get your
zucchini out two weeks earlier your
strawberries out a month earlier yeah
and so when you say that are you
referring to kind of like that shredded
polypipe stuff or more of like just a
general plastic cover type of thing
it's poly pots we don't agree with
either it's a sheet of plastic that goes
over the ground that people utilize for
weed control it burns out any kind of
weeds and seeds that is there and also
of course it's going to burn out a
tremendous amount of your microbiology
and also it makes the soil warmer in a
lot of regions so that you can push a
crop earlier earlier earlier harvest out
of it and it keeps the moisture in there
there's tractors that have
you know giant rolls of plastic i know i
know people have to acres they're
they're organic farmers have acres of of
of of earth covered in black plastic
that's covering their mounds and every
year they throw it away
and this is like charity
this is the majority of the us's you
know 88
of the organic market in the us comes
from california alone and then like over
90 percent of that comes from like the
salinas county and you know all of that
area and region and all of that is
covered in black plastic and they can
still put an organic standard on it and
they can use glyphosate as well
very well goes on and on
another another thing i remember you
specifically referencing kelly was in uh
one of the talks i saw on youtube you
mentioned that there's an increasing
amount in terms of say your percentage
or composition of your products which
can like be kind of ambiguously labeled
or just blatantly not organic but still
gets that label do you think that that
for example is kind of like the ultimate
nail in the coffin for organic
certifications and labeling
it is it definitely is yeah because
you'll get farms that use things while
omri is something in america that people
use
and north america yeah and and
they will use a product that's
registered and then they'll find out
that it wasn't even what was on the
label it was something that was a
carrier in the product in the liquid
that maybe makes their their their
product fail in a test
so that's that's kind of your big
problem
and also the you know the fine print you
know will say that this product is
registered
for use in organic agriculture
it is not saying that it is organic
the language that is utilized is
utilized and geared towards big ag no
matter what country that you're on
department of ag the epa whatever your
standardization you know names are
they're all under the same umbrella and
that's big agriculture big agriculture
makes up those rules and regulations and
they're the ones that have all the way
down to the labeling i mean you would
not believe we need to change our labels
for every single state like practically
every other month because because they
can do toxicity levels well and they
continue changing the language we can no
longer utilize the term healthy
on any of our labels because the term
healthy implies that you have used a
pesticide on the pesticide list so if
you have a pesticide then you can say
this pesticide will bring health to your
garden so they've taken away that
ability for us to be able to use
language in a way
that is actually educational labels are
not education we need to look further
than labels to be able to get our
education because they're out there
trying to trick us and part of looking
further is you know when you get organic
liquid fertilizers of any kind liquid
itself is a problem
you have to have some type of stabilizer
within that and a preservative and that
preserves it in order for it to not
explode on the shelves and if it's not
exploding on the shelves then how much
is it really doing for your microbiology
to begin with because microbiology
has to live or it dies so different
things that preserve liquid are a
problem phosphoric acids and different
things that can be in there
um so you have to be
you have to be a little bit um you have
to be aware of of the companies there's
there's even different things in sprays
and foliar sprays that that are um in
the in there that are not on the label
that can be a toxic
residue on your plants later and that's
why we use only
powders in our products because then we
put the power in the farmer's hand to
make liquid out of it
and then you're not and then we have
everything in glass and not in plastic
so there's no plastic garbage and we
encourage people you know to grow your
own biomass and not buy our products
so that's the ultimate goal is that
everybody is closed loop and that you're
creating your own nutrients and wow that
is just like the best middle finger in
the world to big ag there's no more
power than we have than to grow our own
seeds and propagate our own vegetables
and our own medicine on our farm with
the nutrients that we grow there
so if we just kind of reference the
comments you made about encouraging
people to close the loop
where do you ultimately see dragonfly
earth medicine if that were to happen
for example let's just say you know
there was a substantial number of pure
farms and you know we had reached that
goal would you would you kind of launch
dragonfly as you know like a slightly
different direction at that point or do
you think there would still be a need
for in the way it currently operates so
to speak
um
i mean you know dragonfly i guess a lot
like the species we're just all over the
place we feel like education is number
one
and you know we're farmers first and we
came up with our products after we were
farmers for 20 years you know and then
then the education started sparking out
because we came out of the closet and we
realized wow we're doing things really
different than everybody else because we
had to hike you know seven hours out
into the bush or a two-hour hike
straight up the mountain
you know from our property we weren't
able to bring anything and because we
didn't share with other community
cannabis members or anything we didn't
know that we were that different so when
we came out of the closet we started
thinking wow this is actually really
unique and we maybe have something to
share
with the rest of the community and it
turns out that people
all over the world are hungry for this
knowledge and it's not even really that
we're teaching people we're just
reminding our basic human instinct of
our relationship to the earth
and as far as dragonfly and dragonfly
earth medicine in the world and as
we're really proud of our products and
and they do we feel like they'll always
have a place because there's always
going to be someone on earth or in a
place that you know doesn't live near
biomass or or even farms that we work
with you will use you know the products
because it makes a really quick and nice
and easy tea so it's knocking out it's
safe and it's easy and you can and the
plants respond to it right away so
we we see our our products as timeless
we have human health products as well
you know our raw cacao and so our that
part of our we and we've never taken
you know we've never um done marketing
without with with any of our business
either so we've taken this unique stance
of
showing a lifestyle and having you know
products as well so we we we will always
be
connecting with farmers in the world and
that's that's i think our true love our
true love is is homesteading and working
with raw materials and and building and
doing timber framing or or he or his or
midwifery it's a home birth or our
gardening and on that level we always
want to expand with that kind of direct
contact with farmers and at the end of
the day you know if the business fails
and you know it all goes to hell in a
handbasket we're just gonna be humble
farmers because that's what we do so
i'll be helping catch babies and we'll
be humble farmers
because that's our true love and
everything else is sparked off of that
well it's a good thing i don't think
that'll happen but one thing i did want
to specifically inquire into is will
there ever be a point where you know
dragonflies seeds will be commercially
available for people to buy
an interesting question about seeds is
that um
the answer is we don't know because
we've been
giving away our seeds and we give them
away to people that we see and we never
felt like you could put a monetary
number on a seed
so it's really interesting that it
involves ethics it involves you know
getting it out there to the public it
involves
exchange between two people there's so
much you know with seeds it's it's it's
sort of the essence of of all of this
and
we've always just given them away
so
we don't really know what's going to
happen we've we've just been breeders
because that's part of our closed loop
and we're breeders because we didn't
have tests
you know and and facilities to be able
to tell us so we went off of smell we
went off of how it made you feel
and now we've been breeding for almost
25 years now off of what it made us feel
and now those genetics are being tested
and they're awesome
so here's a really beautiful
you know focus on
intuition than matching science and
maybe the intuition was always right i
know i'm going off the subject here with
the scene definitely you know
we like we've
seen our seeds grow in a lot of
different environments and we've gotten
a lot of feedback from people that have
gotten our seeds and there really is
a really strong vigor that goes through
the seeds they're like the first ones to
pop and they'll be you know big leaves
and everything so i mean
what we can say is we will always breed
we always will be making seeds if if if
it does become available to the world
it's because of all the sudden there's
this crazy world demand but but for now
it's just it's just a labor of love and
anyone who comes in contact with us
we are pretty damn generous about it so
just feels good to exchange
yeah of course
and so
if we kind of look at your specific
situation i know that you guys do all
your breeding outdoors and you don't use
clones or anything one of our viewers
had submitted the question of wanting to
know do you feel like that makes your
breeding a little harder in the you know
you know sorry i keep saying you know
it's such a pet peeve of mine i'll cut
that out
but basically they were wondering do you
feel like it limits you in the because
you've got a male outside there's say
you wanted to do a few different
projects you may not be able to do as
many as you wanted because you have to
be mindful of you know the pollen may
carry and we only want to do so many and
not risk having too many males around is
that something whichever goes through
your mind or is it just not actually
like that in reality
no we feel like the best breeding is
done in nature and that's just been
proven you know to do fast cycle
breeding is not something that we want
to do because we want to see the full
expression of the plant we want to see
it from seed all the way through and we
do take cuttings sometimes we do take a
cutting off of like if we have a bunch
of plants and we're growing them out
long season and we've got one that's
like oh my goodness this one is so
beautiful we're gonna have to keep it we
won't even think about keeping it until
the very end maybe when we're harvesting
it you know so that will be like an
extenuating circumstance but some of our
breeding has come off of that
but long season you know when we call it
an f1 it's a true f1 that's a full year
well i mean for sure
you know if you're going to start a
genetics company you know i wouldn't
i wouldn't necessarily do it the way we
did it i mean we're doing it because
yeah you could get
you know you could stabilize a strain
you know technically you know by you
know doing it five or seven you know
generations which no one does but but
you know so yeah well we've gotten to 12
if you're gonna start a genetics company
you know you can get a lot more out of
it but i i will say this i mean
our breeding is a labor of love and it's
an expression of ourselves
and
we think that there's an incredible
amount of strength that comes from
breeding underneath the sun
and and we we've we've grown seeds from
other people that grow underneath the
sun and we've seen that within other
people's genetics as well
and um so
you know we feel like there's an
incredible vigor that comes from growth
from creating seeds outdoors and we we
put a lot of intention into you know
choosing the right mail and we grow that
male outside you know
all the way out until the very end and
then we bring it inside like the room of
our house in order to keep the the
pollen um
from going all over the property but yes
we we we think that it's a good way to
breed because we've seen a lot of good
results from it and then when you get
our seeds and our genetics it's a full
expression of our microbiome here on our
farm it's a full expression of the
flowers and the plants that we grow here
yeah well i think that's probably why
the seeds are so healthy because there's
certainly an increasing demand i should
say for seeds produced by growers slash
breeders who are breeding in you know as
much of an organic environment as
possible because you can kind of see you
know the seeds come out really healthy
but
i wanted to ask one other quick question
about um
in regards to you said if it's if it's a
keeper you know you want to hang on to
it does that i mean i guess the
implication is you re-veg it do you find
that that re-veging process is
detrimental at all or not not after
you've got it back to where it needs to
be
no we haven't seen that you know really
really beautiful healthy plant can
definitely produce a healthy clone
zelly's gift is a plant that we cloned
in 2014
and it's still going really strong for a
lot of people so
the initial stages of cloning you know a
flowering i mean the zelly's gift we
cloned it the day we harvested it so
then these were big plants these were
like you know 10 10 12 foot plants that
we're that we're talking about and on
the inside part of the plants there's a
lot of
you know inner branches that will leave
some of those inner branches on the
inside part of the plant during the
flowering phase and not we won't clear
out everything in there just in case we
do find a plant that's just like amazing
and then we can clone it
so it's not like you're cloning like a
bud you know you're cloning like an
inner branch that has less of a bud head
on it and has a little bit more leaf
matter on it and that's going to be
you know way more likely to re-vegetate
so you have to have a little bit more
patience with it you know it's not going
to be like a typical clone that you're
getting off the end of the meristem you
know of the plant but and also you know
you can get a clone we've noticed we've
gotten clones before and then if we put
them in a full outdoor cycle then it
really rejuvenates the clone
you know
so many of our our genetics are getting
either watered out or we're losing the
vitality of the genetics both with inner
breeding and also just over breeding and
if you have an amazing clone that you
just love to bring it outside and let it
go full season and then reclone it
you're really going to reinvigorate that
strain and we've done it over and over
again we've even taken like a clone that
test out something and then put it into
the ground and had a full season and
then it tests out something totally
different
so
you know that's where we were talking at
the very beginning that microbiology
does have a tremendous amount to do with
the health and vitality cannabinoid
ratio cannabinoid profile terpene
profile and and another thing is you
know we would never grow
a feminized seed
we just don't believe in feminizing
seeds
and we don't smoke tobacco around our
plants i don't have a problem with
tobacco and and people smoking and it's
spiritual it's not healthy to have
tobacco smoke around you know cannabis
plants in there and and um you know you
have to be careful with you know just
breeding and breeders and knowing your
breeders
and knowing you know what kind of
environment you know
being grown in because the plant is up
taking like information as it's growing
and when it's growing in a totally
healthy environment the information that
it's up taking is just
full happiness full expression no
barriers
so a question that we kind of normally
start the interview off but i mean we
were having so much fun talking about
other stuff we didn't get to it so let's
go back what was your guys first
introduction to cannabis
um well
mine was in um in the formation of my my
seed and creation
so my my very creation on earth
um has been me being surrounded by
cannabis
so um my connection was being born into
it
and um
i really have always felt really um
a beautiful connection to it it's always
been you know good quality
around and
um it's it's
always something i felt really called to
and connected with in my life and josh
is from southern oregon so you know one
of the weed capitals of the world and uh
it's just yeah yeah you need to add that
yeah
yeah no it's it's it's it's been you
know a huge part of my life and i feel
really blessed to be able to have such a
you know just still have such a
connection with it and stuff and
everything so it's multi-generational
and even for uh you know our kid too and
uh and his partner the snog grass family
and my
my um
connection to it was i was definitely
not born into it quite the opposite
you know family that believed in the
just say no campaign you know was real
and um you know anything outside of you
know copious amounts of alcohol
you know shouldn't be done
um
and so i was raised in a very
conservative
family
catholic
uh you know just all of sort of the
pointing fingers that what to do and
what not to do
and
i
tried my very first joint that worked i
think i had to try it a couple of times
but the first joint that worked was
actually up on top of a mountain top
skiing back country
with eight of my really good friends and
i got high for the very first time
when i was 16
and it was a white out and i had to get
down the mountain with all of these
amazing hot shots
and i just thought
had i not been totally baked
i would have never gotten down the
mountain so
immediately i had a relationship with it
and then from there
um
i worked
in
up in alaska and i was blessed to work
with
a man called johnny appleseed who
literally during festivals in mid-summer
would drop cannabis seeds out of his
airplane
yeah the matanuska thunder [__] which
was the original
alaskan
bushed weed that was awesome and super
flavorful and yeah and he did a lot of
his um you know cultivation practices
were then what i took on later on in my
life
but that was my initial introduction and
i just started working there
almost full time
around the clock in a big cannabis field
when i had just turned 18. and luckily
and then it's never ended yeah luckily
kelly and i
we've been together for 25 years now we
got together when we were really young
27 now and uh you know we have a 21 year
old son now and we've you know it's just
been a part of our whole entire life
it's given us that's why we have so much
respect for it we feel like it's given
us
you know everything that we have
essentially and i feel like you know
just first being introduced to cannabis
then it opened up my eyes to the whole
cannabis culture and for the first time
i felt a belonging i felt like you know
i went to my first grateful dead show
when i was 17 years old
in 1986
alpine valley
and i was immediately around all of that
culture and for the first time i felt
family
so not only has cannabis given me a
tremendous amount of education
and health but it's also given me family
wow that's an amazing answer just as a
quick little side point that may
upset some of my close friends do you
agree that the dead fell off in like 90
90 onwards so to speak
um the dead fell off when jerry died
yeah that's just and that's when we
moved up to canada
but when you say the dead the dead off
at 90 that means that you love brent
and really
billy you should love brett because
there was like a fire that happened
within the band when brent was around
and that's just a real thing
and and it had a lot to do
it had a lot to do with crosstalks and
and really strong lsd as well so you
know as as the drugs changed things
changed as well but as far as the
culture of traveling and being like what
the dead represented which was more than
music i mean for sure that did nothing
happen to that it only got you know more
more strong and all the way we would
have never moved to british columbia if
it wasn't for jerry and
honestly i was able i made my way
through university by swinging kind buds
at dead shows that's that's how it all
happened for me so i have a double major
in university and almost a masters
because you know cannabis gave me that
at a very young age
fantastic and did you have any of the
kind of how should i say like deeply
meaningful experiences which so many
people say they have had at the dead
shows or was it as you said more of just
like a welcoming community and things
like that
i mean there's no other church having
jerry
just going off and the whole crowd
elevating a foot off of where they're
standing and every single person having
an unbelievable group experience of
total
oneness
you know i have yet to experience that
at any other place and you know that
goes into all of our psychedelic use
that we you know have taken on
throughout our adult life as well
you know all of them very important but
there was something about sharing
that experience and that high with the
same like-minded people yeah i mean
there's nothing more
we've had the most mind-blowing you know
transforming experiences at grateful
dead shows and then it just goes into
the parking lot afterwards and there was
camping afterwards so
and there was no internet at the time
and people weren't just like buried into
their their phones and stuff instead
they were buried into like their each
other and
hacky sacks and guitars and drums and
drum circles and disco busses
and you know you would get to like know
people and and you would hear about
people communes and people living a
certain way and you would you know it
was the most amazing thing in the world
and a lot of the grateful dead family
are still really really close with us
and we're really blessed to have a close
relationship with a lot of them they
live in eugene and and in oakland and
stuff and we have a lot of respect for
them huge amount of love huge love big
love to the merry pranksters and and
mountain girl and every everything that
the whole family has done and still do
they still
rock our community with love and those
are our builders those are our elders
that's when we were saying at the
beginning you know we really don't feel
like we're elders in this community
those are the real elders those are the
ones in their mid 70s
that you know helped bring this plant
forward you know mountain girl she wrote
one of the first cannabis
books out there that are totally
relevant you know the primo plant today
and those are our real you know teachers
and guides that have helped us catapult
forward to then catapult into the next
generation yeah
yeah i was about to say wow it's been a
minute since i've heard of the merry
pranksters
uh so i guess with that all being said
at what point did you kind of have the
initial thoughts to start dragonfly and
what was the ultimate catalyst
well we
we moved
to another country in 98
and
lived the way that we lived for a really
long time and
we
got we became citizens of this country
through doing um imports
from
indonesia and then
that we started transforming out of that
after
you know a while and started feeling
like we really wanted to do
um a service you know to the earth and a
service that really represented our
lifestyle
and um it became you know and by 2007 we
we formed dragonfly earth medicine
as a representation of our lifestyle
yeah and i think that also as a
representation of our direct you know of
our recipes
so it was the first time that we were
able to share our recipes and it didn't
start out that we just had dragonfly
earth medicine it started out that we
were just making a ton of stuff for all
of our friends and then they were
getting it from us and oh my god you
guys this stuff is so amazing and you
know teaching them how to grow it and
then them drying it out and then you
know taking all of the different herbal
concoctions and then it really became
about sharing our recipes and
we're working on a book now it's been
several years working on it it's just
getting bigger and bigger and bigger
because there's so much information but
it is it's really that same thing it's
it's sharing the recipes of our life and
of our cultivation practices
that's a really good answer and so
something which a lot of people have
asked us questions about is your recent
trip to jamaica and you you referenced
it earlier but i wanted to do a whole
bunch of questions on this i figured
we'd kind of dedicate a little block to
it first of all what was the uh the i
guess you know the inspiration to do the
jamaica trip
the inspiration was um we had been
reached out to by certain parts of the
community and um you know they had to to
come out and
to collaborate with them and and work
with
them on their the project and so and
they were needing you know some help and
some some ideas and and some changes
they wanted to make changes to become
you know more closed loop and they had
been asking us for you know maybe a
whole year to come out and we finally
said yeah okay we'll do it now
and um that's just sort of how it all
began and it was an opportunity for us
to bring together our community and
theirs and for us to learn
from their community and and from us to
and for us to teach them you know from
um our community you know things that we
had learned and stuff so it was we felt
like it was a really beautiful
information exchange
yeah and so when you got there what were
kind of the first or i shouldn't say
with the first like what were some of
the initial
styles of gardening slash principles
slash methodologies however you want to
classify it what were the main tools you
used when you were kind of revitalizing
the land it's from from a third from
like an outsider point of view it looked
like you were using kind of you know the
use of imo some kind of k and f style
principles is that how you would
describe it or how would you describe
what you did essentially
yeah well it's the same you know you
just go into an area and you just try to
figure out doing a lot of really good
practices on the property and and
building soils and stuff and when we got
there we were
able to
you know continue the work and and
connect more with the surroundings and
you know using a chipper was a big part
of it you know
yeah and just seeing what was available
in and around the property and what it
is that they had available so
you know we had talked to them at the
beginning and they had gotten a chipper
you know
and we just started
you know talking about you know what
type of ratios of chipping that you can
utilize and you know within two to three
days we had massive piles of soil that
we just planted directly into
and it's amazing how when you just
utilize what is there around you it's
great to go to the tropics too because
it's a whole different
like
reality of what we deal with up here but
really it's the same in that you just
look at the biomass that's available but
there's not like a lot of earthworms
there you know when you go to tropical
climates
you're you're dealing with massive
amounts of microbiology
you know tropical regions
you know rejuvenate themselves so
quickly you know jungles are just eating
themselves and regrowing themselves you
know so quickly
and in jamaica really has like that
jungle feeling so the microbiology is so
much you know
finding indigenous microorganisms is
like it they're everywhere
you put something down on the ground you
add a little bit of water to it and it's
going to disintegrate within a day
so what kind of things could you lay on
top of the ground that could become soil
really quickly and we just sort of got
into the brain of the microbiology there
and went through well yeah i mean for
example i think uh a regular bale of
peat moss like a four cubic yard um bail
pmos is like 70
or something it's like some crazy amount
of money you know what i mean so you
really can't take the mentality of oh
i'm gonna make soil for you know a ganja
garden or something or be you know buy
from the store type thing so
you know you could get a bail or have a
couple bales and then you would maybe
want to like you know extend that as
much as possible so
one thing is we started digging around
on the property and saw other you know
areas on the property that were dug out
from greenhouses and stuff
and we started realizing you know on the
on the property what parts of it had
really good deposits of earth
so there was i mean i mean like soil
usable soil
some of it was kind of like clayish and
and had like a tendency to want to bind
together but so what we did is we just
would take wheelbarrows to that and just
start mixing it you know with the
biomass that we were collecting from
different places and we were basically
aerating it
aerating it with biomass and stuff so it
was
it was a hands-on collection and we
walked around with the you know with the
the the people from the friends from the
village and
and we really connected with what
vegetation you know was good to use and
we
would reach our hands into the ground
and see what kind of you know dirt there
was in earth and we would see how we
could bring that up and propagate it and
stuff so that that was our you know that
was how it started when we first got
there this is an example of really a lot
of the island being full of a lot of
clay very hard stuff to be able to work
with and just getting out of the mindset
that you have to go in the ground you
know that you can come up and out of the
ground and that soil is available
everywhere you look because it things
grow so voraciously everywhere you know
the same as in australia there's so many
northern regions and areas that things
are just growing so much that is your
soil and if we start looking at what is
the above is below
then it it just makes it really easy to
adapt to garden very quickly even if you
don't understand the surroundings or you
don't even know the vegetation
yeah yeah some really pertinent points
there
one thing i personally noticed from the
the images that i saw on your instagram
for example was that
the soil itself didn't look all that
aesthetically pleasing especially if you
come from like an indoor setting where
you know it looks all nice and
homogenous however you couldn't deny
like what you said you know they're
planning straight into it there's no
issues all that type of thing
what i ultimately am interested in
though is how do you think that soil
would have ultimately compared like do
you think that
it was kind of like you were making the
situation work but at the same time
there's kind of you know a bit of a
honest truth that you know maybe it's
not going to perform as well as the pete
but you know given the situation the
cost all the rest is clearly the
superior option
well it's definitely clearly the
superior option no matter what even if i
had available soil to be buying from the
store what we were making if it comes in
on that land was absolutely superior and
i mean if you look at the whole island
of jamaica i mean you know there's a lot
of different kinds of soil on the island
there's red soil there's black soil
there's
hard soil and stuff so it is extremely
dependent on on where you are
and it is amazing you know when you go
to even hawaii and different places you
know there's the red dirt is an
incredible dirt that grows you know
plants amazingly so really
you can't really go on visual
what you really need to have in there
once we what we say all the time is just
biomass
so i mean that's how we're aerating the
soils and that's how we're attracting
more worms there wasn't there was worms
around but there wasn't a ton so we were
trying to like just gather them from
wherever we
we found it but you find that it it's
they're not the big digesters you know
of soil the big digesters is the
microbiology
in the soil so the soil that we were
digging up in the soil that we made
we
made a whole batch of soil you know
within the first week that we were there
and planted seeds that we brought
in that soil and
you know we had gone on some other farm
tours and went around and but we got to
see those seeds germinate out of the
soil that we made and got to see the the
health of the seeds and stuff so
i i do believe that you know the soil
was really really powerful and good
yeah that's awesome to hear so you i
mean you just tapped on the genetics
point the question i have is because
i've seen other other people go to
jamaica most notably uh sonic seeds uk
based breeder he's been there and done a
bit of a
land race hunt type of thing and
obviously you would have been exposed to
different genetics on the island what
did you see when you were there because
a lot of what people say is like it's a
lot of really acclimatized dutch stuff
from years gone by and that the general
consensus is there's not really any pure
land race anymore would you agree with
that
yes definitely as far as like
climatized i don't know i don't we
didn't really see too many climatized
patches
you know they're all really short and
there's even an eight week can be
flowering out in five weeks it forms a
tiniest little bud on it
you know it's not something
yeah it's all hybrids that you know have
a lot of maybe the high himalayan
cold climate northern cali or european
strain all dutch i mean there's a lot of
california influence in there and for
sure i mean there's you know i i'm not i
have no idea about percentage-wise and
stuff but
i would say that we found with the
jamaican farmers that you know they were
no very similar to any one of us who
really want the best flavor and the
newest
genetic and the newest you know best
crystals and and hash making things so
over the years they've met people and
people have come to the island and and
they've you know would would be get
gifted or something and so what you find
when you go to the farms is a
is a lot of small plants which are
mostly hybrid from a lot of years of
people you know yeah breeding from other
places in the world
and it's really you know there there
is that that farm or that place that has
land race and
if they're off the beaten track and you
know it's it's really not a sought after
thing on the island really because it of
you know what they they feel like they
can grow now let's say and we we felt
like it was really important you know
that that the genetics that we brought
there were very thought out
and we brought genetics um you know from
bodhi and from coastal seeds and bob
henpel
you know that were climatized that were
more like thai varieties
that we know that maybe they could start
interbreeding and trying to find you
know a biologically intelligent
tall long flowering because anywhere
around the tropics you know it's a 12
12.
and that's the genetics that we you know
search for in in our realms is that you
know
two month eight week plant
but when you're there
you know you put out a really small
plant and immediately just starts
flowering you're not going to be able to
number one it's not going to reach the
full potential
i mean waste if you're lucky we saw you
know whole fields of just like knee-high
and
it's because these these plants don't
have the intelligence of a 12-12 cycle
they don't have the intelligence of an
equatorial
you know region either so you can get a
really sweet producing sativa that does
take longer it makes their plants you
know bigger and
nice and
and really expressive i mean
you know that so that was a big thing
yeah we went and talked a lot about
breeding and went and talked to a lot of
breeders there's a lot of open breeding
happening by a lot of farmers where you
know they just let you know a few males
you know pollinate gardens in certain
areas and stuff so
you know
that is a really good way of breeding
from from their point of view and it
gets a lot of different flavors and
their flavors are all
you know they they get through them they
sell them and and do it you know it's so
it works in in that climate but
um
yeah so like when on the island itself
if you have to take a guess does kind of
marijuana make up a large part of the
the economy or it's a relatively a
smaller part nowadays like is it is a
big thing for them
well back in the 80s it was huge and you
know they were cutting out swaths of of
jungle and landing you know big
airplanes and then all of that you know
ganjo was brought out all over europe
especially uk and holland and and all of
that and then turned into hash and so
there was a really huge economy
for you know weed growers on that island
because not only did they have the
culture of weed but they also had the
know-how how to grow it and it was
really good and they were already
growing you know pretty large amounts of
it so for them to be able to expand
was really easy but now they're seeing
the same thing
as the whole cannabis industry you know
anywhere that it's been legalized you
know with legalization comes regulations
that then make it really difficult to be
able to have an economy
off of that so
now all of a sudden through legalization
you know they're keeping all of their
weed into your island and there's not
enough people you know and they're
looking to be able to get it out for
sure but that's a whole other
conversation with pharmaceutical
companies i mean you know every
for sure most people grow i mean uh
smoke cannabis on the island and you
know it's it's everyone's smoking ganja
and it's it's not a thing at all to
worry about and it's it's definitely a
huge part of the thing it's not valuable
on the island i mean it's it's valuable
i'm not saying you know there's there's
farmers and they and they sell and they
make monetary value you know it's it's
it's inexpensive you know on the island
type thing so it's you know to make a
lot of so i'd say it seems like cannabis
is is definitely in a really big
transformation in on jamaica because of
of legalization like kelly said but
with legalization is becoming
international
um you know farming is what you're
starting to see on jamaica and other
countries and
i think jamaica's big you know
goal or thing in life is i mean they've
helped bring cannabis culture to the
world through their practices and
through their love of rastafari and
reggae music
and so they they want to still save
their culture and save their farms and
their way of life and growing and they
they they do want to see legalization
but they to see legalization meaning a
bunch of international companies coming
in and using their island to grow a
bunch of weed like say for example
canadian companies could potentially are
are you know working in jamaica right
now and a lot of weed on jamaica really
to be valuable has been exported over
the years even in the 80s so now that
export market is now transforming to a
legalization market and you know i think
that there's a there's a cultural thing
at stake there and i think they really
want to save their culture and there's
also a health stake there you know so
these large
corporate cannabis are coming to the
island you know not to spread doom and
gloom but to give people an education
out there we think that it's totally
imperative once it becomes federally
legal then there's a play in the
international market with all other
federally legal countries
and then all of a sudden now it becomes
pharmaceutical so it's going to be
really easy for large pharmaceutical
companies to
to partner with large cannabis companies
and those large cannabis companies not
even grow the cannabis because they'll
get cheaper cannabis with the labor um
and also you know the dollar exchange in
jamaica or say in colombia you know the
cut flower market is a huge industry
and now the cannabis big corporate
cannabis is starting to have massive
takeovers in colombia and in brazil i
mean most of the farms we visited in
jamaica even you know ones that were
like roots farms that have been growing
for a long time had been visited by
these international companies that were
talking yeah this is happening now we go
there this winter and as of us going
there this winter all of the farmers
have been visited by international
companies i mean that's that's a that's
kind of a generalized statement but
that's that's what we found is that
they've been and they want to make deals
with it and they and they say that you
know they don't care how it's grown and
other countries don't have the same
restrictions with pesticides and with
fertilizers and with herbicides and
fungicides and on and on so that it
opens up
and it opens that they either irradiate
it or they say they're going to wash it
with petrochemical solvents and then
they think that they're washing out
all of you know
any pathogens or purities that are on
there
it's a really big conversation you know
this could be a whole other podcast that
we do
yeah well i mean the exact same thing is
happening in australia in regards to the
uh international you know kind of
companies moving in and doing their bit
but something i would love to ask first
though is do you think part of this
problem arises from the increasing
demand from the consumer market
for concentrates or products which
derive from concentrates and thus you
know there's
maybe not demand but for example the
stat i heard was that something like 50
of all cannabis sales in the states are
related to like vape pens or cartridges
or like something along that line and if
it's true it just goes to show yeah like
there's just an exponential growth in
the the demand for these cartridges and
so do you think that's a problem because
it facilitates you know like just these
kind of
you know shady concentrate deals going
on
well there's there's that's a whole
other conversation too as far as like
concentrates and the cleanliness of
concentrates and the importance of the
cleanliness of concentrates because it's
not just a concentrate it actually has
the name of what it is you're literally
concentrating everything that's in that
flower you know so utmost respect for
cultivation practices all the way
through
is imperative for concentrates and then
to look at your other question about it
taking over the large market
is that you know now that pharmaceutical
companies are going to be entering into
the cannabis market of course they're
going to be concentrating it they're
going to be getting a product that has
the same exact cannabinoid ratio no
matter how or where they put it out and
it is a way of dosaging and it's
something that they understand that's
not you know it's taking it out of sort
of the organic
um you know world that we know of
looking at flowers now it's going to be
you know going into different types of
supplements and in all different types
of you know pills and caps worldwide so
that's definitely going to take up the
majority of the market i think that
you're right to say that you know the
the demand of the people to buy oils is
is part of it and it's it's driven you
know farms to make concentrates
and um it's a convenience thing you know
it's not as smoky and everything so what
you find when you talk to dispensaries
and you talk to you know who's the you
know the the people that are buying in
the dispensaries they want something
super easy that they can drive around in
their car with and stuff so
there is an ease that comes to you know
having a pen
um pre-rolls is another thing that sells
you know really really well in
dispensaries which i think is another
thing of ease you know it's just easy to
get pre-rolls and stuff and you know
it's always
a better high i think in a lot of ways
to have like the full flower and
i think that um from a farmer's point of
view i think it's almost good with the
um concentrates in a way because you
don't have to grow all clones you can
grow you know a bunch of seeds seed
plants and have different varieties and
then do batches
of your flower and make a good oil batch
and it's going to be all that you know
number and everything so
um number of cannabinoids and everything
so i mean it's it's kind of an amazing
question you know that you know on which
one came first essentially
yeah
and well so what do you think then is
the necessary steps for us as either a
community or just as a scene so to speak
to get things back on track and do you
think that it's a knee-jerk reaction to
say just try to push people to go back
to flower
um i think the most important thing that
we can push people to is know your
farmer the most important thing and then
understand
where your flowers are coming from
understand where you know
what dispensary that you want to go to
what breeder that you're working with
you know really finding out and
understanding their products and
extraction company you're using yeah and
what what so i no we're not saying
everyone should only smoke flour
you know we only smoke flour and
we have some you know really amazing you
know extract companies that we work with
ice water hash too yeah well i mean
there's some really really good good
companies out there um that do
extracting and stuff but so what we want
to say is
you know yeah it's totally it's totally
fine to to use but we don't we as a as a
certification and as as a as a community
we don't use any petrochemicals
when we
extract our
our
materials so that's what's really really
important to us and i think that
customers and people that are out there
that are consumers should ask you know
what did it come from was it made from
propane or butane and then or hexane
even that white powder cbd that you're
talking about is a hexane product and
those are just coming from petrochemical
companies and they're just coming from
from sources that we just don't want to
be involved in which goes back to what
you were talking about with animal
products it's the same reason it's the
source of what happens within the animal
product industry the source of what
happens within the petrochemical
industry as well as the final product
so
you know all things need to be looked at
and unfortunately you know
education
is paramount how are we going to share
education with each other in the
importance of being really open
and that hopefully dispensaries are
getting more on their game and that you
know more growers are getting more on
their game because
it's really important because so many of
the people that are going to be
listening to this podcast and us having
this conversation
you know were a different group of
cannabis enthusiasts of cannabis
cultivators of cannabis you know
business people
than the other
side that i'm talking about with this
massive cannabis
corporate model that is the other side
of cannabis so it's so important to have
education on this side
so that we can share and really get the
message out
yeah 100
and so this is a bit of a doom and gloom
question but what's your prediction for
what would happen to the high-end market
so to speak if all of the small
producers were kind of pushed out phased
out whatever you want to call it
well what you're going to get is a bunch
of irradiated weed
what you're going to get is you're going
to get you're going to get basically
um
the same thing is going and buying um
packaged processed food
so by by pushing out the small farmer
you're pushing out
the intention
and that'll never happen
anyway there will be a reassurgence no
matter what right now is a hard time
but a lot of the true soul growers you
know already had their properties and
are trying to navigate their way through
and
i think that you're gonna just like
craft beer and craft wine and craft food
you know you're gonna find you know
regions where it still works to have
small farms and the small farms are just
going to have such unique flavors and
such unique strains that you know
those those mass-produced farms will
they'll never be able to produce that i
mean the large automated farms that are
happening up in canada are talking about
being
no peep there no people grow the weed
it's all automated the whole entire
thing
the all the watering all the spraying
all even the harvesting is it's done
like robotically
and i'd like to think i'd like to think
that you know
the cannabis plant
um you know has her own intelligence and
the reason why i say she is it's just a
feminine energy plant it doesn't mean
that there aren't males and females
um but you know she will probably i hope
have the last laugh
because we're learning that the happier
she is
and the more
grown with better intention and in
you know beautiful soils she's going to
produce the well-rounded cannabinoid
profile that really puts out the
medicine that science is going to soon
come to it's what we as old-school
growers already understand we know what
strains made you feel good we knew what
was going on already before
so if we can just keep that intention
moving forward then the voice of the
plant will continue to be moving forward
and and i just hope that the same thing
won't happen to this
sentient being that has happened to
tobacco you know tobacco is a plant and
it's been taken over by corporate
tobacco but and everybody wants to maybe
deem it and say that it's bad but it has
such a sacred
amazing
special plant medicine for the rest of
you know the world
and i just am hoping that through
science and through our intuitive
processes bringing it forward
that the plant will have the last laugh
and she will demand to be grown in a way
that is respectful yeah and and is in a
soulful living soil you're going to find
more diverse cannabinoids so they'll
never be able to produce that
yeah of course so with all that being
said though do you ever foresee maybe a
bigger facility or operation adopting
approach similar or maybe even the
complete pure certification
oh yeah we have this large dispen i mean
large facilities um
you know green life productions in
nevada's uh an indoor operation that
that does fully no-till um soils and has
been expanded in a hard market
in a market that's you know they're one
of the only organic cultivators in all
of nevada
um so that that's one example and you
know there's there's a lot of examples
in colorado and oregon yeah california
that we work with that have adopted it
so we we work with really large
facilities and turning over that you
know the idea of of just all bottled
nutrients and npk ratios and sort of
dead soil and growing plants that really
don't have the liveliness that the
market is going to be looking for and
also we're going to be coming becoming
smarter as consumers
you know we're going to start having an
idea you know as a larger group a
conserva of consumers of what makes us
feel good oh yeah that made me feel
really good i had a great day on that
and oh what was that and that's going to
start you know more and more
conversations for people we're working
behind the scenes with you know
facilities all over the place i mean
really over the last 10 years i mean
we've talked to you know
seems like you know
a whole hell of a lot of people and
there and there's more you know coming
and and different states are are still
opening up and different places in the
world are still opening up so we've
always offered ourselves you know for
him for um you know information and how
to so you know whether they're a pure
farm or not you know they they may have
taken on some of the practices that were
that we're working on
yeah of course and i think that's maybe
more of a realistic end goal anyway
right if everyone could adopt most of it
rather than expecting it yeah i mean
yeah i mean once again you know we we
we've never claimed you know there's a
lot of the people make it what it is you
know all the farms are so unique and
stuff and everyone brings something
unique to the table and you know there's
the regenerative farm award and
permaculture institute you know high
tide permaculture different people that
are doing amazing work on farms and and
helping people adapt their farm to uh
natural cycles and um you know it's it's
it's really an amazing expansion of
consciousness right now that's it's
really amazing to be a part of and and
to watch and we get people you know
emailing us all the time that talk about
you know us and this changing their life
and and just us talking about the things
that we talk about them you know
opening their eyes to like making
changes on so many different levels so
there's been amazing you know positive
feedback from it and just the each one
teach one you know when you go out and
educate a group of people then those
whole group of people are then going to
educate other groups of people that can
then educate other groups of people and
we just feel like free it up free up the
knowledge and we're never going to be
those people that are like this is the
way to do it and this is the only way to
do it there's so many different ways to
do it to where you're practicing
conscious cannabis
and i think that you know
any any way that works for you and your
environment whether it be indoor whether
it be outdoor how you know whether
you're up in antarctica or whether
you're in the tropics or wherever you
are cultivating your cannabis just do it
in a conscious way
that is going to get out better
education to the people that then
utilize your product because we're the
shamans of of this medicine we're
effecting somebody's day you affect
their life you could be affecting their
health
you're affecting their family
it's so important to have that feeling
of every single flower that you touch in
every single plant that you grow that
that is going to have an effect on
somebody else's life
and that's what real conscious
cultivation is about so
important yeah of course and so if we
just look back for just two seconds to
how we were talking about the automation
that's going on in canada
kind of you know on that same train of
thought how do you feel about certain
types of automation i mean the one i'm
most notice most interested in is like
the automated watering systems like you
know the blue mat or the floraflex i'm
not sure if those are the brands in
america those are the major ones in
australia but essentially is this the
type of technology you advocate for or
do you feel like it's kind of removing a
certain level of connection with the
plant when you say hand water
we advocate for more mulch and hand
watering you know i mean i'm not going
to say that
you know having one of those systems
doesn't doesn't work because it does it
works
and if you can't be there and you really
want to have a garden i mean use one you
know what i mean um
it's just involving more plastic into
your gardens as well and how your teas
and what they're running through and all
of that stuff breaks down
over time and then really you think that
you might be helping yourself but how
many times do you have to fix that
system and then order out parts for that
system he's like oh god there's a lot of
pathogens that build up in the hoses too
that you have to be careful of so and
it's taking away that human interaction
with the plant and
anyone who is out there and is a
cultivator totally understands what that
is you know you can have an ailing plant
or a garden and all you do is just give
it some attention by giving it good
energy and it turns everything around i
mean you know sometimes that's not
enough of course you have to go you know
into the deep dredges of education and
try to figure it out but
oftentimes just giving good good energy
is enough so if we're going to become
you know automated the more and more
automated that we we become the less and
less that we're having an interaction
with the soil and this is why we choose
to build you know soil the way we do you
know like whether it's an indoor bed and
you keep you know wood chips in the
bottom of it to keep soil down there or
you you know cover the sides to keep so
you know the humidity in there you
whether you're outside and you use rocks
like thin rocks across the top
where you'd use like a rock mulch you
know there's there's a lot of ways to to
keep the water in there and
just using
we've never used one of those systems
and one of the reasons is um it's kind
of a shallow watering yeah you know
water it's and it does keep biology nice
when it's always wet and there's you
know there's a lot of reasons why it can
make sense but
from our point of view you know deep
watering you know gets it you know to
the lower parts of the roots and that
really gives a true watering to the root
system and when you start getting down
into the sub layers of your soil that's
a lot where the clay is and the minerals
are and then your plant has the ability
to sort of break down those you know
when you have really long tap roots and
you're
you know planting them into the earth
you're going to want a deep water
because you don't want your plants just
to have shallow roots and then a big
wind comes along and then you're done
with
so you know deep watering has a lot of
values more than just you know a system
or whether it's easier and we don't use
a lot of trellis you know um systems on
our plants we don't we we let them blow
around in the wind and having you know a
more saturated root system that has you
know more ability to
to give its you know stock strength and
to give you know the lateral um
capillaries and and the branches you
know more strength and stuff without we
believe that's why we
to grow you know you have to think of
everything so what we
we look at our soils and we build our
soils in a way that that we it's going
to enhance our watering for the season
you know it's it's kind of
it's not just putting a
soil mixture together and hoping it's
going to like hold water for the season
we got way off track on your question
but no that's good because i got another
one related to exactly that so what i
wanted to know was is you know if if you
could kind of choose so to speak do you
prefer your soil to be like more of a
water retaining soil or would you prefer
to water more frequently because it kind
of you know it dries out a bit quicker
well less frequently is better because
your microbiology is giving a chance to
be able to colonize and when you have a
soil that doesn't hold any water
then when you water it it's you're
actually losing your microbiology
they're out of the bottom of your pot or
into your subsoils
so
you know it's really good to have good
water retention but we believe in layers
so there's different layers some of them
are water retention layers and some of
them aren't and another one may be rocky
and another one may be this so then the
roots can make a decision
you know on where they are and maybe if
they want some dryness that they're
going to be able to find it in a layer
that has more aeration and if they want
more water then they're going to be able
to find it in an area that has more
moisture yeah i mean your soil has to
drain there has to be a good you know
cation exchange and there has to be good
you know
aeration in there and aerobic you know
qualities and breath you know in the
soil and hydrogen and carbon so you know
we we do build our soils though to
retain water
and we think that's important because
water is a huge commodity on earth and
there's a ton of areas that are in
drought and that's just to react
so i think anything that we can do to
build you know soils to save water even
if it's indoors
i think it makes all the sense in the
world and i do think it saves your
microbiology to to stay wet
but dry out all the time your biology
has to like wake up and go to sleep all
the time and that doesn't
truly serve the rhizosphere
okay and so what's your thoughts on rock
dust and i'm wondering and do you
believe they're as vital to the soil as
some people make them out to be
well i i know that steve solomon has
talked about rock dust over the years a
lot and he said that he's you know not
seen a good balance out of a true
glacial rock dust that's a true balance
um
and stuff so
you know we've always
used different
rock dust that were available you know
maybe the paramagnetic rock dust basalt
or or you know glacial rock dust and you
can use a little bit of you know those
powders but really
you know our our main mission in life is
to try and get the minerals from our
plant life in our in our area and that's
so our our big thing is once again it
goes back to building soil so our big
thing is to trying is to to think about
the trees
and the different stuff the ways that we
can build the soil to get minerals in
and in each different you know different
plant species uptake different types of
minerals and you know that certain
plants are rich in certain types of
minerals and if you're looking for that
in your garden why not feed your biomass
all of those minerals and then cut your
biomass down and then feed that to your
garden because then your biomass has a
long time to be able to uptake it and
the bio microbiology in the soil has
more time to uptake it
so we really believe in if you're going
to bring in rock dust or if you're going
to bring in you know ocean salts or or
or different things that might make
sense and have a lot of mineral content
feed it to your biomass rather than
feeding it directly to your plants in
your soil because then it just makes an
easier exchange into your soils that
what you want to grow if you can get
dehydrated ocean water i mean it has you
know 84 trace minerals in it and stuff
but you know the oceans are really toxic
in the world right now so you'd have to
have
a toxicity report you know if you're
going to use any of that and mines are
are so sketchy you know we really again
you need to look at from where all of
the inputs are coming from we know that
we're reaching a phosphorous ceiling
right now because of rock phosphate on
the planet and all of those mines that
they've totally depleted and now all of
the big ag that's totally dependent on
it
you know and people are feeling like oh
without it what the heck are we gonna do
this is the only way that we know how to
get phosphorus well it's a really shitty
way to get phosphorus truthfully because
it's being mined and all of the people
that work down in the mines what kind of
health problems are they having
i you know if you just start looking at
all of it
it's like we've over thought ourselves
humans do that consistently we just have
like this big
you know ability to mess up stuff and
this is just a perfect example of that
we have to go and get mined material
from somewhere else to be able to get
our mineral content i mean if you're
building an indoor soil from you know
coco choir and stuff i mean you have to
have something for sure so you might as
well get you know
as many different kinds of dusts as you
possibly can you know what i mean and
and that are consciously you know what i
mean like glacial rock dust in our area
there's there's tons of it and then
there's there's tons of volcanic ash
and there's tons of you know basalt you
know
quarry and you know basalt that doesn't
take
you know very much to create powder out
of so
there there are areas where it can make
sense and we and we really encourage
people when they're making these soils
and we do work with people that have to
make soils from scratch
is to what kind of native soil in their
area can you mix into that that's going
to have all of those you know minerals
already there and it doesn't mean you
know you can make a soil that's
intelligent enough that it will be able
to unlock that um you know all of those
minerals pretty easily
so again just being conscious about
where all your dusts and things are
coming from
yeah so this is going to be a bit of a
weird question but it's just kind of us
when we were mentioning steve solomon it
jumped to mind but steve's got this idea
that he he thinks that you can use
nutrient density as kind of like
an overall parameter to quantifiably
test things on their quality so you know
i i think i'm right when i say this but
i think if you asked him he would say
something like if you got two different
bits of cannabis and you tested the
nutrient density between them he regards
nutrient density as that quantifiable
kind of parameter and so he says you
know if you just tested a whole bunch of
cannabis the one with the highest
nutrient density is going to be like the
most enjoyable so to speak put aside
maybe personal preferences do you have
any thoughts along those lines or would
you maybe disagree with that and i guess
maybe overall do you think there is like
a one
quantifiable parameter we can use for
testing
um
i don't think i think you could utilize
a lot of things you know as much little
things that you have in your basket to
help you out along the way little
tidbits of information or little testing
things that you have along the way is
great but absolutely believe in that
idea you know the healthier your plant
is the better it's going to taste as far
as food is concerned your medicine is
definitely going to be better more
terpene-rich the plant was able to fully
express itself in health you know the
brix reading is something that i know
that he utilizes we utilize bricks
testing here free fractal a
refractometer to test the sugars and
stuff in the plant and we analyze our
plants in as many ways as possible under
microscopes and leaves and we analyze it
through pests
you know knowing whether your your
plants getting eaten by a pest
is one way of seeing whether it's
healthy or not so in some pests we're
finding like aphids and stuff have been
attracted to healthy plants so there's
always an exception
but you know a lot of times
um you know a healthy plant repels pests
and that's the goal of it and stuff so
um
yeah
yeah definitely health health and
well-being of the plant is going to be
the looking at the plant and seeing it
vibrate and seeing it's
it's leaves extended out and not
constricted i mean you know there's
that's the the the like the emotional
touch that goes into looking at it
right there so kind of on the same topic
we referenced it earlier and i was going
to bring it up but i forgot to but i was
talking to jeremy and from builder soil
and he said that
one thing he was interested in is that
there's the development of new organic
ipm based products a lot of them have
microbes in them you could look at one
say
em5 perfect example you know microbial
based uh ipm product the interesting
thing about it was he was mentioning
that when people undergo testing these
same probiotics like the the cfu's the
colony forming units get counted all the
same and you can fail tests because of
it is that something which kind of is a
bit concerning to you like the fact that
i i guess maybe we're not able to use
microbial products in an ipm remedy you
know in that way or do you think that
there's a way around it
what's concerning about it is the
testing um the testing is what's failing
us
it's not it's not the problem of what
we're spraying on it and if we're
utilizing a nice ipfm we always add the
f in there because it's integrated pest
and fungal management program um
uh it just
it's like it adds
i forgot what i was doing with that
oh you're just talking about the testing
oh right
the testing sorry thank you it was like
off on another tangent thing um is is
that they're not testing the
differentiation between the dna so they
they can they can but it's a very
expensive test to be able to find out
you know if it's a bacterius or is it a
bacteria spore that's healthy for you or
is it a bacterial spore that's unhealthy
for you and they're just doing a full
round spectrum of just like putting it
all together in one basket and they're
just saying it's all fruit even if it
could have like you know 50 different
species of fruit and some of them could
even be poisonous to you they're just
saying it's all fruit and if there's any
fruit in the basket then you know it's
no good if there's any type of
microbiology even dust spores that are
perfectly fine and healthy we breed them
in all the time you know that it's going
to fail a test so the problem is really
the testing
the problem is not so we we're trying to
get smarter to the test but this is a
huge conversation in the industry right
now several states have let go of the
microbiology um the microbes counts this
is what it's called microbe count you
have to i would talk about testing a lot
because you know that's what like the
recreational scene brings and that's
what farmers have to deal with so
the answer is
if you have um a microbial test that you
have to pass
then you can fail that microbial test
from using
healthy beneficial probiotic organisms
so does that make sense
no it doesn't make sense
but the answer is
you can fail your test with those things
so you if you you live
in an area where you have to basically
pass the test i mean you have to do what
you have to do mm-hmm so a lot of people
is it healthy for you to use bacillus
you know strains and
and even
and other you know things on your on
your plant absolutely
of course it is em5 is it is it
beneficial for you yes
does it make a better flower absolutely
yeah and and i think that we've touched
on this already but i'll say it again i
mean our body needs to be able to
process
dust and and probiotics and and without
like to having a sterilized product for
our body it does our immune system no
good it does our health
no good so those laws are prohibitive
laws
put in place to make it damn near
impossible for an organic farmer to to
to do what they have to do and it puts
out different the differentiation of
what is the word clean to you
you know is clean hospital clean is it a
sterile clean because some of the worst
most horrific diseases come out of that
height you know parentheses you know
clean
so it's just a really interesting topic
clean the way that we see it is
beneficial microbiology everywhere that
you're dealing with you know beneficial
microbiology that if a pathogen is
digesting yeah it's even coming in the
door at all it can't come in because you
know there's totally so many beneficials
that are holding it back
to us that could even taunt the pathogen
because you're so strong with good
microbiology you could taunt it yeah and
it would never you know be a part or or
or come in as a pathogen
yeah i think that's a great way to kind
of uh
i don't know visualize the situation or
approach a situation i noticed on the
site it says you have had you know
really extensive range of trialling
various different mycorrhizae and
micromicrobial products is there any
kind of little tips or tricks you've
learned throughout that process you'd be
willing to share with us you know like
certain things which maybe indicate
you've got a good micro product beyond
the obvious you know like are there
certain things you can kind of um you
know share from your both trial and
error with all the different microbial
products
well it's really fun to get a microscope
we really encourage people to get a
microscope i mean you just learn so much
when you start to enter that world of
you know
little things
you don't have to get a professor or
anything like that in order to get a
microscope you can just
learn after you get the microscope and
just start seeing yeah and you don't
have to buy an expensive microscope you
can buy you know one that is used for
like high school or finishing school
science class or something like that
there's so much out there and you can
actually look at the teas that you make
you can look at the soil that you're
making and also looking at the plant and
what kind of reaction you know of course
that you said you know under except the
obvious that's that's the most obvious
is how does your plant react
because unfortunately you know these
department of agriculture regulations
and big ag are going to be giving so
much
different information you know if you go
on threads out there in the cannabis
world whoa the crazy stuff that's flying
around is just difficult for people to
determine so
you know
do your own science learn your own ways
well define your intuition in your own
gardens that's going to be the best way
to find out if products are working for
you and you can trust good companies
like ours and others that have been
tried and tested through the community i
mean
the community does not stick with
companies that don't have integrity so a
lot of the companies that have been
around for a long time are around
because they have
you know they've our our products have
been tested by you know a million
different people and there's so many
other companies out there with with
beautiful integrity you know we really
you know want to highlight you know
those farms that are making good
products and also those companies that
are making good products for the farms
you know we're out there and there's
lots of us and we're all over the world
yeah most certainly and i so strongly
agree with that that final point about
you know like the community doesn't
trust brands without integrity and
i think you can look at that especially
if you look at you know the people who
are using your products it's some of the
most
um you know like the leaders of the
industry but also that not just the
leaders you know but the ones who are
viewed with integrity themselves so you
know it's almost like a two-fold
mm-hmm
yeah and that's just
and that was a big part of this culture
to begin with it's just word of mouth
and everything and trusting in each
other
yeah
so something i wanted to run by you is
what's your thoughts on throwing
mycorrhiza into a tea specifically
before you brew it because
you know in
the i i refer to it as the bible of
organic gardening you know teeming with
microbes by jeff he says very very
clearly in the book you know if if
mycorrhizae doesn't come in contact with
a root within 24 hours it dies and so i
always see people throwing mycorrhizae
into their ts and then they're going to
bubble it for presumably at least 24
hours and i'm like does that not all
just die
makes no sense it will a lot of them
will become dormant and they'll just sit
in there until they reach a root if they
do so it really doesn't make any sense
at all
you definitely want direct contact onto
that route and one of the best ways to
get direct contact is because so many of
our gardens we're growing fast plants
and we're having fast turnover with
cannabis plants is that your cover crop
can grow the endomycorrhiza on it
propagating and it can propagate it so
when you're feeding your soils different
types of mycorrhiza make sure that you
put you know great cover crops like
clover is an awesome one for so many
cover crops i could go on and on and
they're going to help propagate it for
your your cannabis plants so that's one
of the beauties of really utilizing a
lot of different species in your garden
so you can put mycorrhizal spores in
water and drench it into your soil that
is an application that does work it's oh
it's not going to be as good as direct
contact it's direct contact that really
you know propagates the the spore to
come to life
but um we always suggest to people that
if they're going to do a tea brew do the
tea brew and then just put the
mycorrhizae in like right at the last
second right before you're about ready
to drench your gardens
and that's that's a good application
yeah that's that's definitely what i
always thought was like kind of the
optimal
yeah it does not grow in in an aeration
setting
so another little point i wanted to
swing by that jeff made in one of his uh
verde natural talks was that he said
that there'd been some kind of you know
newer discovery around how it was just
kind of one of the subspecies of micro
that was responsible for the bulk of the
work and i think he said it was the the
glomerus type
do you know anything about that and
i mean like if so would we not expect
all
mico to switch to that one subtype
essentially
well the glomus intradices is the one
that's been known to be the supposedly
the one that
um you know
communicates and and bonds with cannabis
roots
do
from our point of view i mean fungi is
made like to break the rules i mean
there are there are no rules there's the
most adaptogenic when it comes to
you know petri dishes and science and
and maybe like soilless mediums and
different things like that you know if
you're in a soilless indoor medium and
you're just getting like two months
cycle or
something you're not going to get a lot
out of a two-month cycle with
mycorrhizae it kind of has to live
longer than that to be truly beneficial
to the root zone
but
you know
diverse microorganisms communicate with
each other in garden settings so you
know we we have
four different ones that we work with
right now and we just
always enhance that type of mycorrhizal
growth in our gardens just because we
know that all the answers are not there
and biodiversity is so incredibly
important in your garden so you know
being able to have you know the classic
endomycorrhiza
um you know that that's out there in the
market that's grown organically and
consciously which is really important
can also speak to the other root zones
that's going on in your gardens which is
just like your cover crop and and and
and and i don't know you know the whole
thing have just did that it's singular
species
i'm not really sure of that yet i can't
say one way or the other it just doesn't
make sense of nature at all it goes
against all of nature's rules where
she's just like so full of diversity
um why is it that we're separating out
and concentrating and isolating and the
more that we do that we bring it away
from its nature which really doesn't
involve the entourage effect of of
everything that's going on in the rise
of sphere and i mean it's been proven
that you know
inner that species
of different different types communicate
with each other and share food like a
pine tree can share food with a birch
tree and there's no like
law in there that says that they can do
that but they do it
so enhancing
you know biodiversity in your gardens is
a big part of cannabis growing and you
would want to enhance as much different
species as possible so
they can communicate with each other so
did that make sense i mean yeah you can
just get in glomus intradices and put it
in there and yeah you could just be off
to the races with that one but i think
in life we should try and get you know
more dynamics happening than that
okay and so i mean i guess the thing i'm
interested in is overall you would kind
of say that you don't think that you
would get better results from just
exclusively using the one
yeah we think that diversity is key in
all aspects diversity and microbiology
and diversity in in nutrients
is key
can you guys hear my cat meowing
okay great sorry i had to make sure
otherwise i was like you've got to go
tell it to go away
um
so
yeah she's she's got a mouth on her i'll
tell you that
um so something i saw on your site which
i was super interested in because i am a
self-professed coffee addict you guys
say that you know it's a bit taxing on
the adrenal system you're not so into it
for that reason do you guys think you
know like that there are actually some
long-term negatives if you know kind of
bludgeon your body with coffee over a
long period of time
absolutely yeah i mean it stimulates the
parasympathetic nervous system
and if your parasympathetic nervous
system is stimulated all the time which
unfortunately you know everything that
we do
is stimulating that you know nervous
system
and then it starts to drain the adrenals
and when you give your body a full sense
of stimulant then it starts to kick into
action
you know that
the all of those different systems which
makes a depression in the immune system
and then you have things over a long
period of time that you know just start
breaking down the other thing about
coffee is that it's incredibly acidic
and um you know if you're drinking it
often then it's really changing the
acidity of your body
and you know more alkalinity uh you know
contains more beneficial microbiology
than acidity so if you're constantly
acidifying your body then you're not
only killing beneficial microbiology but
you're also breeding pathogens
yeah wow
and so the the solution to this or maybe
not the direct solution but you know in
instead you guys have the cacao and
mushroom kind of tea you make how did
you stumble across that one
uh we just you know we were really like
has been a really important thing in our
lives we've been mushroom collecting
for a long time and health and
well-being has been you know a big part
of what we do and also incredibly long
hours of work we put a lot into
you know our property here on our farm
we put a lot into the education that we
put out to other people we put a lot
into our business
and we need something that is going to
work for us long time josh and i have
always been joking that we're just in
training to be 90 year olds
um
so
we just want to make sure that you know
everything that we're putting into our
body is going to have incredible
longevity it's going to be adaptogenic
and it's going to decide what our body
needs rather than depressing it and we
we we recognize you know with the first
thing that you drink in the day you know
really kind of sets the tone for your
body for the rest of the day so we
you know have been really
wanting to drink something really
powerful and potent for our bodies so
every morning you know we're drinking
the raw cacao
with you know the medicinal mushrooms in
there we're just slowly building up our
immune system with the mushrooms every
day and it doesn't drop us you know in
in energy levels later in the day so
it's kind of like our secret serums like
our secret recipe and like our secret
life
force is just to smoke dubies and drink
cocoa all day and work
on the farm you know and then have a
good meal in the afternoon you know and
it's like it's like a good way to live
um recently we've been you know making
new recipes with um our essential six
which is six medicinal mushrooms and
making a golden milk which has the
turmeric
cinnamon
ginger black and black pepper
and then they're adaptogenic chinese
we've also
fallen in love with moringa over the
years so
my my kind of big secret thing not
secret my big like thing that i love
lately is just moringa our gold milk the
dragonfly earth medicine gold milk and
the cacao together
and this oh and maca well and we drink
nettle tea all day too during the season
that it's nettles and then we'll drink
comfrey tea during this time it's come
through we're drinking super foods all
day long yeah actually and we love the
antioxidant both my my dad died of
cancer kelly's mom battled cancer her
whole uh a long time and and she beat it
though yeah and uh but we so we've been
you know propelled on health
um
through that and you know also our way
of life so you know it's again that's a
representation of our lifestyle
yeah that's that's so awesome to hear
and do you guys kind of advocate for
people to look into say maybe taking
medicinal mushrooms or like a regular
kind of schedule thing or do you think
maybe not that broadly applicable to
everyone
yeah i think that it's important
um if they're adaptogens which means
that they go into your body and they
decide what it is that you need you know
they're sort of like a higher
intelligent being mycology breaks all
the rules fungi breaks all the rules
you know um fruiting bodies you know are
here to help us you know they they
exudate
uh co2 and intake oxygen just like we
are we do so
they're just sort of an interesting
anomaly and
we we know that prolonged use of
mushrooms is what's the best
so you're not going to really notice a
difference if you start doing mushrooms
for a week you'll definitely notice an
energy
increase absolutely you'll notice a more
mental
increase you know your words will come
to you quicker you you'll have sort of
like you know a better memory base
immediately but the long-term effects
are you know over a long period of time
and we feel like years of mushroom use
is what people need to be doing and
let's let's let's get more specific i
mean chaga
is you know one of the most powerful if
not the most powerful antioxidant of any
herb on earth as we know it
it has more sods in it which is
superoxide dismutase which is a
longevity enzyme it's got one of the
most you know highest amounts of
longevity enzymes in it um the siberian
shamans you know done a tremendous
amount of work and
in teaching the world about it and
russian and and korean
um chinese you know have done a ton of
work on
medicinal mushrooms um cordyceps builds
um
your blood and and builds uh oxygen in
your blood and you know there's they've
been used by olympic athletes for years
um to enhance their performance
you know and their daily routines of
working out and everything so
um there's a lot of you know the
agaricon works the lungs and and and
also nootropic medicine is is is part of
what mushrooms are in nootropic means
that
it regenerates um cell life
so it helps you it's a smart drug
particularly in the brain so it helps
generate brain cells um and also yeah
helps generate them
for the cell to be able to propagate
itself
in a memory of a healthy cell rather
than in a memory of a non-healthy cell
because that's that's the goal is that
you know in cancer any kind of malaise
or people that have ailments
it's that the cell is reproducing and it
will reproduce
an ailing cell or it will reproduce a
healthy cell so what is it that you're
going to be able to give your body the
memory of reproducing a healthy cell and
we feel like mushrooms really help give
that much higher intelligent
intelligence of the body to be able to
produce the healthier cell because we
know that nothing fights cancer other
than the immune system
of course cancer can be diminished along
with everything else through
chemotherapy and radiation but the
immune system is the only thing that
transforms cancer cells into healthy
cells again and that's something across
the board and we also went into
you know we were talking about the
intelligence of trees
and
a lot of these medicinal mushrooms come
from trees and they're taking all of the
minerals and all of the intelligence and
they're growing directly off the tree
and we can't eat the entire tree but we
can eat the mushroom that's coming off
of that tree and it has all of the
nutrients that that tree has
so like chaga comes off of a tree and
agaricon comes off of the tree in the
lion's mane and the turkey
so many are wood loving um
mushrooms and and we live in a toxic
environment in general you know we're
just it's just the way it is and it's
fine you know we do we have toxins
around us so we should be ingesting
things that rid ourself of those paths
you know of the free radicals and and
that's what mushrooms do we raised our
son like this he's a professional
athlete you know so you know it works
that's awesome to hear yeah i definitely
believe that something i wanted to touch
on though
bodhi made a comment about how he he
loves to do both gardening as well as
breeding while under the influence of
psychedelic mushrooms is this something
you guys have experimented with at all
and did you find it was productive or
maybe counterproductive
extremely productive some of the most
important information that we've gotten
from the plants some
one of the most life-changing
experiences that have ever happened to
me have been in my greenhouse with my
plants
on psychedelics
you know it cuts through stuff
it it it leads you it it breaks the
veils and it gets you to the point of
importance it puts aside the ego
and and what you think is happening and
it really allows you to see what is
happening i feel like
responsible use of psychedelics
is absolutely imperative and you know a
lot of people say that you know that
kind of use could be checking out we
call it checking in
and checking in
is so important especially when it comes
to nature
you know these mushrooms have a higher
intelligence that they're they're there
to teach us they've helped transform our
whole entire evolution as we know it to
begin with so
you know and and psychedelics for some
is like oh a big scary thing
and psychedelics really shouldn't be
they should be thought of as as
um
into spirituality i mean nothing
in this world is easy to to
explain so having insight you know makes
a lot of sense and micro dosing is
something that you know a lot of people
are doing nowadays and so it's a lot
it's not something that people are
really checking in on and
you know you can create medicine where
you're just micro dosing and having a
little bit of a check in and it can be
extremely
not only positive for gardening it can
be extremely positive on your well-being
and you're you know some people have
problems with
depression or anxiety or detention
deficit disorder and sometimes it's just
a neurological connection that they ptsd
yeah so many so we we
highly suggest that once again know your
source
um
mushrooms in particular um take up a lot
of toxins from the environment
um so know your source in that area but
yeah it's a good check-in
yeah nice i dig it and so you kind of
answered it but just to get a final
clarification i had someone talking to
me saying that like they were mixing in
like i i'm just gonna say cube essences
or whatever like just because you know
it just jumps to mind
like a micro dose of that with say like
their regular dose of lines main things
like that and what they said was that it
was they felt like it was acting as like
a potentiator do you think that's the
case or maybe it was like they were just
maybe feeling some of the effects of the
cubes or whatever it was they mixed in
there
i mean you know mushrooms are a catalyst
they're a catalyst for all different
types of well-being they're a catalyst
for mineral uptake in our body they're a
catalyst for so many things and cubensis
is is one that you know is sort of a
master of the mushrooms in
in the way that when we take it and how
we perceive the world so that wouldn't
surprise me at all that it's a catalyst
for the uptake of the nutrients as well
as
a cognitive understanding
of it biologically
you know and when you sit with chinese
herbs and you mix it with other
different adaptogenic herbs then you're
going to get full spectrum uptake and we
don't you know
we we do do lipid extraction
concentrates with our cbd
and we would never do that without a
huge array of mushrooms and different
adaptogenic roots and and herbs
non-psychedelic
non-psychedelic for that yeah but uh as
far as the psychedelic um ones going it
makes sense to use them with other herbs
for sure that support your
your system while you're in that state
and we do know that that's hard on your
liver so you have to have things that
are supportive
of you know um the uptake of the toxins
as well
yeah
so question that's a little off topic
but i
remember i think you've even said it a
few times in a few different little
talks that you kind of wanted to remain
like kind of like a mom-and-pop type of
company where you were still really
hands-on with things
is that still the case and do you
foresee that you know like a point where
you ever might expand your network
beyond say what you could physically
deal with or is it very core to you to
remain kind of that hands-on approach
it's awesome because we are expanding
and we're expanding
through other farms and they're
expanding through us and the knowledge
is being passed on
from one farm to the next and it's just
becoming
like
we're able to almost be everywhere and
the information is able to be everywhere
and that's the real power
and
i mean hands-on experience yes
absolutely it's just totally important
to us to have relationships with people
and community and we feel like this is a
way that we can have relationship with a
greater wider international community is
through
like-minded and like practicing
cultivators and extractors and business
people and
yeah and everywhere we've not taken on
major distributors or major investors in
any way with our company
and so no it's not a goal for us it's
not a goal for us to sell our company to
you know say a global distributor type
thing and you know get it into every
grow store worldwide you know do we you
know would do we want a successful
company yeah do you know if it happened
to where it all went into all the growth
stores and it was somehow imagined an
all-in-one
organic uh you know expansion yes we
want that which is what it is now um you
know like josh had mentioned really you
know briefly we don't do any we don't do
any marketing marketing like at all we
haven't spent any money ever on
marketing because we just feel like
pass the information on and then the
good information will rise to the top
and
and you know
it's more important for us to be walking
forward with integrity than walking
forward with anything else and and
having the voice of the plant
you know always in our mind and and
being able to share that voice so that
other people can also have it within
their integrity and their intention as
they
you know grow their flowers in their
gardens
so
this is kind of an interesting one
because we've been talking a lot about
the immune system about the plant's
immune system the human immune system
i'm really interested in
you know i call them the
immunomodulators that's kind of i guess
more of like a human term for these
types of molecules but things which
activate the sar response systemic
acquired resistance like yeah chitin
salicylic acid
jasminic acid these types of things
what are your thoughts on these ones do
you kind of play around with insect
frass or chitin or any of these kind of
immunoboosters for the plant and do you
advocate for them
well interestingly enough one of the
highest forms of natural chitin that
comes through the plant form is in a
mushroom
so we utilize lots of mushrooms we
utilize mushrooms as biomass you know we
chop up some of the tree mushrooms that
we have here that we would use in a
medicinal lipid compound you know that
we make here
and also put it into our tees
so chitin is definitely something that
we utilize we utilize white willow bark
um we make it here on the property we
put that in our teas for the acid
acidicity acid um you know we always
look for the plants
yet again for growing on the property
yeah and we're always looking towards
the plants to give that information to
us because if we're feeding plants we
feel like
plants understand plants the best they
communicate the best with each other so
we're looking for the plant version of
it you know we don't get the the other
part of it like the powderized version
and what's interesting is all the
pharmaceutical companies that have had
like hexane extraction on a lot of these
you know say aspirin i mean it
originally came from a plant or all of
these different compounds that we see in
pharmacies and and also you know vitamin
supplements they originally came from
plants and we've also we've we've made
them like synthetic to where our body
can't necessarily break it down
so that's why you know plants and teas
and these things are just so incredibly
powerful
for boosting the immune in the immune
response
yeah i can definitely agree with that
have you actually done any like toying
around yourself so to speak with uh like
chitin and its effects on the immune
system because i know it was used in
traditional chinese medicine for a long
time but i couldn't really find any
clear evidence of whether it was like
you know because it's not it's not
offered as like a supplement so i kind
of was thinking i don't know how
effective it is
well right now it is being offered as a
supplement there's a lot more things
coming out now with cricket powder
so you can you can buy cricut powder
and
they're taking crickets and that are
problems and areas and they're turning
it into a supplement
and i think that that's great
one thing that we know for certain is
that you know there's been test studies
done in india
and um
they couldn't really figure out why is
it that certain jain regions you know
that only eat certain vegetables and and
certain types of beans and this sort of
thing why is it that their b12
rates were still pretty high in their
blood counts you know where is it that
they were getting that b12 to be able to
uptake it
and after you know several years of
research and study it was all of the
small bugs that are in the grains and in
the lentils that they're eating every
day
so
that's a a perfect example of
you know
that sort of like bug and insect we call
those macrobes you know can be a part of
our diet as well as our as our plants
diet yeah makes sense right just the
holistic approach
so
you know you feel free to you know we
can cut this one out if you don't want
to answer it because it's i don't know
it's maybe not in your style but i've
noticed that there's kind of like this
cyclical wave of like fad products on
the market and like the one that jumps
to mind to me is like fulvic acid you
know fuvic acid has always been around
but recently we had like the shilajit
surge you know it kind of came back with
a force and then it's died off again and
what's your experience with the fad
products like are there any ones where
you see it just like so my example was
the fulvic acid where it's like you know
it's just a basic product but it just
keeps getting recycled and rebranded and
you know kind of i guess maybe tricking
some people who aren't familiar that
most of the time it's just fulvic acid
in that in that example do you have any
kind of products which jump to mind
which are like this for you where you
know like they get this surge of
popularity and it's like it's just the
same thing that's always been there
well we i think they will probably pass
on that question because we wouldn't
want to you know point out
you know a name of a product and then
maybe put that down or make a fad of it
you know what i mean i think that it's
important that
you know in it's all about them
yeah it's about the evolution and again
the the community gets to decide so
they're going to be lots of things
thrown at the community and how is it
that the community is going to sift
through it
is more important than focusing on the
company that put out some kind of a fad
product it will be up to the community
to decide on what's going to have the
longevity
yeah of course
and so are you familiar with uh
tricantenol or tricontinol however you
want to pronounce it um like the natural
growth hormone
you mean alfalfa you mean alfalfa yeah
yeah so definitely in that um so my
question is basically there's now like
more refined versions of it coming out
and it's kind of slowly getting some
traction in the market as far as i can
see have you looked into those more
purified versions because obviously a
lot of people maybe knowingly or not
engage in it through alfalfa top
dressers things like that but what about
a really kind of purified version would
you be in favor of that if it worked
similarly or is it kind of you know down
that same school of thought we don't
engage in
well the the
the idea of it really would be is how is
it purified how is it concentrated and
really you you get such high levels in
super healthy
really awesome alfalfa
and if you're only going to use it once
you know
you know one time a cycle are going to
use it two times for a whole cycle well
you can use alfalfa in every one of your
feedings and that's just going to be
prolonged over time it really goes back
to
you know sometimes we overthink
ourselves sometimes the basic raw whole
food is really what's best for us more
often rather than
less often and a bunch of you know
pre-packaged stuff in between and then
people are gonna want gibberellic acid
because it makes their plants grow you
know super tall and yeah you know you
might just find out that you can just
use your urine
with water and and you'd be like oh my
god this works a hundred times better
than anything i've gotten from the store
i mean seriously it feels like we could
go right back to the basics on almost
everything and it really works
better
it just does so no we're not really down
with all the the new
and improved
not saying that there's not a place for
evolution and not saying that there's
not a place for all
things and all good times you know what
i mean it's just
um
we constantly look towards nature to be
our mentor
so maybe what we'll find is a new
biomass bush to grow you know maybe
we'll find a new
you know tree that that blooms all
summer for the bees now now i'm talking
now we're talking about a product you
know what i mean yeah totally uh
a grass that propagates mycorrhizae you
know what i mean like now now let's talk
you know
yeah so
this is a bit of a weird one but a lot
of people commonly will say that you
can't do kind of like a no-till type of
philosophy unless you're in a certain
size pot i think the commonly uh
reference number is about 30 liters or
so
do you do you drive with that like do
you think people using small pots can
successfully under do kind of nutrient
cycling and the the concepts of what
no-till is advocating or do you think
there is that requirement for a certain
size pot
i don't like to limit people yeah but uh
you know it's going to work better in a
bigger pot and and but the plant's going
to grow better
plants gonna grow better in a bigger pot
and plants gonna grow better in a bigger
bed you know and it's easier to keep
your biology happy there's options you
know but but some people only have small
pots and if that's and if this is the
introduction that they're getting for
them to be able to grow really awesome
medicine to share with your friends or
you know if they're needing it then
that's awesome and like josh said we
just really don't want to
limit you just do your very best there's
so much conversation out there right now
on what the word regenerative is you
know for us it's like if you're creating
more balances than checks you're doing
good and we all can't just automatically
have some closed-loop regenerative farm
where everything is just running
perfectly you know some of us have to
start in a closet with a couple of you
know one gallon pots do your best yeah
do your best there really small plants
for that you know if you're gonna do you
know a small pot you'd have to have
really small plants otherwise the roots
would colonize the root zone too much
and it would just it would choke out the
life that you're trying to do in a
prolonged environment so you know the
smaller pot you have the more you know
thought out and tension you're gonna
have to put into it
yeah you have a little bit of room you
know of in a bed you know
yeah it's like a safety net in a way
isn't it
it is oh it's a huge safety net we
always say that you know a soilless
medium is like the plant uptaking
through an iv
and then a a plant a
soil that just has a little teeny tiny
bit in it
is somebody who you know a person that
may have you know not a very good
digestive tract but when you have big
heaping
soil piles and you've been working on it
for a really long time it's the same as
that person that you would call that has
an iron gut
that they can take anything and you can
throw anything at that person and
they're not allergic to it they've got
nothing because they have such a
tremendous amount of microbiology
and that's it you know the more you
build your microbiology the more you're
going to be able to throw at it the
least amount of microbiology to be very
careful what you throw at it because
your plant can't understand it balance
yeah yeah i can definitely see that so
on a lot of your products they're used
for fatigue and for top dressings
however i have seen the odd person just
using it as a straight soil amendment
just mixing it in or like kind of like a
revitalization thing after a cycle do
you find you get pretty much the same
results doing that or do you kind of you
know if possible advocate for them to be
used as teas or like the way maybe you
marketed it
it's just valuable you know anyway yeah
it's fine
it's an absolutely amazing soil additive
it's just phenomenal what what the roots
do with it and even and it's really just
a transplant and it's really not just
you know our products it's the idea of
just bringing in green material into
your soils you know making sure that
you've got some herbal compounds and
some plant material in there more than
just kelp like take all your sun leaves
from your previous harvest and put them
in your soil
and that just really helps increase the
bacteria you know breakdown and then the
bacteria then starts to feed the fungi
it's just you know when you up it all
its best
and in nature you know when you go to
the most beautiful pristine forest it
has
varying amounts of decomposition from
the leaves
all around it and that's something
that's really easy to mimic in your
garden and it's easy to mimic even in
your first soil mixes
you could mimic you can mimic that by
adding more leaf material
yeah okay i think that's actually
something people are a little scared of
at least mixing it into the soil i mean
i'm a bit i don't mind top dressing but
yeah
i think there is a little bit of
yeah i don't know what the word is
better than
yeah like really mixing it in you know
what i mean yeah
we utilize all of that our hash
leftovers you know all of the green
material from our hash we make sure to
make it at a time that we're mixing our
soil
for our nurseries
so
you know we make sure that that's all
like cyclical and all that green fresh
material just goes right in and it's
amazing even carrot pulp will be making
carrot juice and we'll put carrot pulp
in there too and it can be really good
just the idea that you can utilize so
much different vegetation to help spark
your soil
yeah definitely
so we kind of indirectly touched on this
question but i just wanted to get the
final ruling on it what type of ipm or
sorry ipfm methods do you guys use
throughout kind of the more flowering
phases if you had an infestation let's
just say a mite you know a lot of people
kind of deal with that what are the
types of things you'd be looking to use
or to like you know kind of philosophies
to utilize
if you're if you're in flowering cycle
which is always the most difficult
definitely bringing your rooms up to 120
degrees fahrenheit 50 degrees celsius
um kills all
thin
exoskeleton
mites as well as aphids they'll
literally explode
so utilizing heat treatment is fantastic
but making sure that your root zone is
damp and well fed because your roots
need to stay very moist and they need to
stay cool
and it's not it's not heating up your
indoor rooms through lights you can't
have your lights on high and heat it up
that much because the pores of the
leaves are going to open and when the
pores of the leaves are open they're
very susceptible to like uv light in
greenhouses you can get it up to 120 no
problem it's really easy
you can watch the buds actually swell
you'll get more yield where we're really
noticing that
with the resin is really coming out and
you're being able to kill off really the
thin exoskeleton you'll be killing off
your predators
as well
but you put your predators on afterwards
it certainly doesn't kill things like
wasps you know and and plants love 50
degrees you know people say oh is that
so hot well you look at where they the
plants actually come from and the season
that they grow in they just love heat
so it's not something that is going to
be
definitely stay in your room
have a glass of water for you and you're
sort of like taking a sauna either in
your greenhouse or in your room or
wherever you are to try to reach that 50
degrees and we use celsius swirsky and
cucumarus um and together for broad
mites and russet mites
um and um you know a person millis or
californicus or anders andersoni for uh
the spider mites and
to have a good predator um
colony on your plants allows you to not
have to use the sprays
so and and and usually use like two to
three times the amount that they
that they suggest
to you
and um and not two to three times as
often just two to three times the amount
so you do the heat treatment if you're
infested in later flower you do the heat
treatment and then you just bombard your
room with predators and hopefully you
know you've got enough enough time
that um the predators will eat all the
rest that's there and then they just
leave they're not interested in staying
on your plants they don't colonize on
the plants they don't breed on cannabis
plants they're just going in and they're
eating so a lot of people worry about oh
geez my smoking predator is no they're
eating and then they're leaving
yeah so that's just really helpful and
we love the use of predators and in
vegetative times if there's an outbreak
we love botanical washes
and not utilizing you know essential
oils or volatile oils and heavy amounts
you know i don't really like my skin
covered in heavy oil neither do the
leaves
but if you want to you know wash them
you can take fresh neem leaf
and a fresh rosemary or fresh you know
eucalyptus or fresh lavender and make a
nice tea brew and steep it with
horsetail or with another herb that you
want and make it a botanical wash that
isn't good for pathogens it's healthy
for beneficials and it's also healthy
for the flowers
and literally like washing the plants
down it's they just love it and that's a
really good preventative as well and
also to help get rid of an infestation
you want to follow that up then with
predators
yeah sounds like a pretty good little uh
ipm regime there so
last question before we hit the little
short fire ones at the end
you're gonna have to forgive me i'm
gonna mispronounce the name but i have a
feeling you guys will know exactly what
i'm talking about one of our viewers
wanted to know what are your thoughts on
the sealed wallopini greenhouses is that
how you say it walopini i don't know
wally peony
uh that's what we have on our property
when you say sealed
you know um
i you know we like to have a flow
through design because
the the humidity stays nice stable it's
stable you know the temperatures are
more stable the plants love it
everything just grows
yeah it's a huge biological sink and we
have them now all over so we've been
working with wally peonies for a long
time inspired people other people to do
it and we have lots of designs that
we've just freed up and given out to
people we've been working on it anytime
we do consultations we always talk to
people about you know wally peonies and
bringing that in and then you're
utilizing all beneficial things you're
utilizing the geothermal from the earth
and then you're utilizing the heat
you know from the sun
and that's stability it's awesome
it's a great way to grow yeah fantastic
so we're on to the last little quickfire
questions
um so the first one we'll probably
probably get two answers here what's
your favorite strain
uh
well i'm gonna have to say the
homesteader
because that's what we're doing right
now and it's been really amazing to me
and i've been only wanting to smoke it
so i'm gonna go with the homesteader and
that's got its roots in um
let's see a jacket i really love that
jacket
which is like a purple tie times
the god bud times a
really awesome afghani zelly's gift
we'll say i'll say zelly's gift she'll
say homesteader yep they're so uplifting
that's great that's a good answer just
out of curiosity
that jack herrera that was used in the
zelly's is that that famous one that
goes around or just a just a different
one
oh it absolutely is clone that came from
oregon yeah it came from eugene it's
really special one of the one of the
best ones so that was really special and
now it's in a lot of our genetics so
that was a really wonderful mother that
we got
and super lemonades are a big part of
our
um genetics and we like that lemon
mm-hmm yeah see that's great because
those are like two cut species or two
strains i should say specifically where
if you get that cut that's on the money
you know like it's just it's almost
unbeatable isn't it
yeah i like it a lot it's so true or
when you find that one seed too that
you're just like whoa this plant is
amazing you just want to be able to
propagate it yeah finished outdoors for
us really nicely
yeah so a slightly you know derivative
question instead of favorite strain
what's your favorite land race
acapulco gold
i'm going to go with acapulco gold too
which has roots in the in the um
the jack herrera although
the chocolate thai i'll go with
chocolate thai since she went with them
yeah and i could go with chocolate type
second
i should just both switch to chocolate
tart now
that's good did you guys
sorry i was gonna say did you guys see
any of the uh
the pearl tie that body had
no
i hadn't seen it that was but we were
oh we had brought down some of his uh
thai strains uh to jamaica uh okay yes
he would have seen him there anyway
and the pakistani chitral
yeah that's another good one which
probably would have done well in jamaica
as well wouldn't it because they they
flower a little later don't they
yeah we brought that down so that's
that's going down there
so we'll see how they go brought down to
so many different types of varieties
we'll see what what comes up we're
excited to see what happens out of it so
excluding your own work
who's the breeders work who you're most
excited to pop next
oh that's so hard i would have to list
the top ten
okay that's tough i mean we really like
the people that we've already mentioned
which is you know mr bob hemphill um you
know but the two of them graham and
darcy are both you know they're amazing
people they have a connection with the
plant you know cody for sure he's always
like on such a higher level of things
and absolutely tommy big ups the
connection that he has with the plant is
so kind and true
um green source garden source garden
makes amazing seeds um jesse from
biovortex makes
making really really beautiful
intentional seeds um
cush kirk our friend our family down in
uh
southern oregon or you know they're not
they're not selling see he's not selling
seeds actively but it's the people that
have the really intelligent garden beds
yeah a lot of the purifiers
family genetics not grass family
genetics that's gonna be a top one
that's gonna be something to look
forward to everyone's such a beautiful
intention there too yeah there's so many
breeders out there that are just now
stepping in you know we've been trading
seeds for three decades now we've all
been working together and if we weren't
working directly with the person then
indirectly we were working with them and
now it's like all of everybody's work
that they're able to put forward and
aficionado means amazing yes
those guys can we keep talking yeah keep
going keep going
we already said spliff he has some
really amazing strengths yeah
and i mean i know that yeah evolved
evolved oregon i mean he's been amazing
lion tree lion tree farms they're really
doing awesome stuff with th cv
lion paw he's also working with like cbg
people are starting to specialize in
different like cannabinoids and then you
want to make sure to get those
so then you can interbreed because
they've got like really super high cbg
or thcv house of harlequin yeah house of
harlequin
wade laughter big ups to wade laughter
thank you wade for bringing forth all
the harlequin what an amazing humble
beautiful person
i mean he is of the earth you know if
anybody gets to grow some of his strains
were only lucky
yeah well what a testament
so
moving on to the next little question
though
kind of similar to the first one but you
get a few choices desert island strains
so i'll let you take two i find two's a
good number because everyone wants three
so it makes it that little bit harder
you can only take two strains with you
oh
two strains with you
that's all you got forever
i would probably take um
the healer is the seed that uh a strain
that we've that we've created i think i
would go with the healer that is you
know the the half cbd half
um yeah they're beautiful one to one i
would do that because it's really good
if you don't feel good so that one to
one is super awesome if you're having a
hard day on the island you know if
you're feeling like wow
this day is hard i got sunburned i'm
gonna go for the one to one i'll take
like a gold i'll take like a golden
pineapple
like i think i would go with a gold i
think i would go with an acapulco gold
i think i'm going to go with a healer
and an acapulco gold so a one-to-one
which is an ac dc cross with like a
really awesome a40 afghu
type super high marker
because that's the reason why we created
it
so i'm gonna take the homesteader and
the healer because after i'm done
homesteading i need to do some healing
that's good telling a story
all right
sorry the next one is
as long as there's lots of it there has
to be a lot
right yeah yeah infinite infinite okay
there's plenty okay that's that matters
quantity probably was the first question
[Laughter]
so
the flavors flavor of the month so to
speak tends to be very much a cyclical
thing what's your prediction for the
next big flavor of the month
i think it might be the hemp i think the
flavor of the month is going to be a
super high the cherries are coming on
strong yep and i think that's not just
cherry wine like there's a lot of cherry
sherberts and puffs and cherried [__]
diesels it's amazing the the the sour
diesel and the and the chem dog and
and the og i mean
they're so gnarly and so good still and
it's like you can like have all the new
varieties and i mean the cookies
have taken over you know in a lot of
ways there's like a certain spice
that you get from that that people like
a lot um
but um
you know i think that people are gonna
go for the more lemony uplifting stuff
personally coming up here in the future
i think that we're sees an uprising the
grapefruits too i think that the
grapefruit strains are going to start
going through the roof but i also think
they're going to see a huge surge in
really low thc and super high cbd full
spectrum cannabinoids and that will be
in like the the hemp work that has been
done in colorado and beyond
yeah cool i like those predictions
uh one other thing is there's there's
definitely gonna be like new
cannabinoids that we learn about so it's
gonna be a lot about learning those
cannabinoids and i think the strains
there's going to be a lot of specific
strains for cannabinoids that's going to
be the future
that's a that's a that's one i kind of
thought about myself actually
so
lucky last one here we go if you could
go back to one place in time anywhere
where would you go and what seeds would
you collect
i think i would have gone back to 1982
in south africa and i would have gotten
the durbin poison
darn it i missed out
have you tried a good durban that like
you know and it's won you over type of
thing
well we've we've got somebody in south
africa that has sent us seeds that he's
saying is definitely the best but i've
yet to see
the durbin that i smoked in the 80s that
to me
what i had seen was a beautiful durban
poison i have not seen that since then
so yeah i think i would definitely like
to go back like
pre-industrial revolution probably mid
set you know anything before
you know eighteen hundreds maybe let's
say a thousand years ago and and i'd
like to go into the pygmies pygmy tribes
and smoke pygmy weed and build like
pygmy bridges and and villages that's
what i'd want to do and their rhythms
they're i don't want to play drums
and sing with pygmies and grow weed in
the jungle in the middle of africa
that's a good answer josh
that's the best answer i've ever heard
yeah yeah i think that one's really good
that's great all righty well i think
that one might bring us to the end of
all the knowledge and information we've
been able to get from you guys is there
any comments or shout outs you wanted to
make
uh you know shout out to all the the
people that are working really hard to
bring this medicine forward to the
masses um shout out to you
for putting this type of intention into
the community and education
shout out to all the pure farmers out
there and all those people that are
still working within in within integrity
and
and the biggest shout out thanks to the
plant the biggest shout out to the plant
thanks for bringing us together and
helping us you know i mean i know that
she's made my life so much better and
all of the people that we have you know
been a part of so i'd like to give a
shout out to the earth
for for giving us a place to do all this
magic on
and the stars and the sun for giving us
a cosmic connection
yeah
pretty much
so thanks so much again josh and kelly
for coming on the show
thank you so much for having us
yeah take care thanks so much what a
great fun this was
so there you have it guys a huge thank
you again to josh and kelly for taking
the time to talk to us
a huge thank you to you guys for
listening through to the end
and a huge thank you to our patreon gang
these guys are the mvps
as always thank you to organic gardening
solutions 420 australia and seeds here
now
best sponsors in the game you know you
love them
i'll see you guys next time
[Music]
you