[Music]
hello and welcome to the next episode of
the podcast a cannabis podcast for
budding enthusiasts this episode as
always was brought to you by 420
australia your number one store for 420
lifestyle and apparel as well as organic
gardening solutions your premier organic
gardening store and finally seeds here
now you know they're the best guarantee
on satisfaction not just germination
check it all out
on this episode we're joined by the man
the weed nerd himself sub cool
chatting all things breeding and
controversy
let's get into it
[Music]
alrighty so big thank you and welcome to
the infamous weed nerd himself sub cool
thanks for joining us on the show
thank you very much
so first question we're going to do a
little change of pace here i want to
know what are you smoking on right now
um i'm smoking uh cookies and cream
live resin rosin that um a friend of
mine sent to me because i'm getting the
cubans cookies and cream cut next week
so i'm beta testing this live rosin and
it tastes like
caramel and coffee with creamer in it
it's delicious
wow
i certainly have never had anything that
nice before do you think that's kind of
the future of concentrate is going in
this super primo fashion
yeah i think so i am i mean i was a big
rosin head before the house burned down
i had a sasquatch rosin press and i
learned so much about it and
the flavors and everything you can get
are just amazing you take some really
high quality water hash and you press it
and press all the contaminants out of it
and what you're left with is
truly some of the smoothest tastiest
stuff in the world now i prefer to smoke
thc crystals which are torture made you
know with solvents and stuff
but you can't beat the flavor of live
resin breast it's like like i said it's
like eating caramel but smoking it
nice and so are you a fan of the
sasquatch presses i've seen a few people
with them
yeah i am i'm more a fan of the the
people that were really nice to me and
now the rosin pressers are good there's
so many people out there but sasquatch
themselves made me a press put my logo
on it shipped it to me and then when my
house burnt down they built me another
one and they have it ready to ship to my
new house and that's pretty nice
customer service
yeah i can't argue with that so we'll
jump back on to the regular first
question now what was your first
experience with cannabis
this is going to draw out because it
sounds like such [ __ ] but it's the
truth so when i was around nine years
old
i had the opportunity to go to a concert
with a guy that had a roach okay
seriously
so i think it was edgar winter or
something so we walked around the entire
show even though everybody was smoking
cannabis everywhere and we were too
scared to smoke it because we were kids
and so we went home to his house and i
remember we stood on the toilet and
turned the fan on and we each got one
hit
and we blew it up into the thing
and
i will never forget what it tasted like
it was to me the most incredible
interesting thing i'd ever done in my
life
so about a year and a half later i had a
best friend who had an older sister who
i used to look at her you know she was
she was cute i used to have the thing
for and
her boyfriend left roaches in the
ashtray really long ones he was a
cannabis seller and i mean he was my
hero he was sleeping with her
and he had weed you know so i used to
steal his joints roaches not steal his
weed but take his you know lipstick on
them from her and we'd take them out
back and smoke them and this was
colombian gold
so it would make our ears ring and i
have to continue the one thing so the
first time i got high
i heard in my head i mean really high
about a little 10-ish or 11. i heard
this
and i heard it for years when i got high
and i was 15 when i heard the immigrant
song and i heard the sound again
why the hell did i hear the immigrant
song when i got high even though i
didn't know led zeppelin was
huh there you go you reckon maybe
you you heard it when you were really
young or not just never exposed to it i
don't know i think led zeppelin smoked
some weed and heard it and that's why
they wrote the song
that's a good explanation
so
kind of from that point forward how did
you really get into cannabis i guess you
obviously just progressively started to
smoke more from that age at what point
did you kind of become did cannabis
become really quite involved in your
life
well i went to back up a little bit so i
come from this i come from the south
where um cannabis was very prohibited
and it was very expensive so at a fairly
early age i don't want to
i don't want to lie 16 17 i think i had
a car you know i started buying weed
from a guy and selling it and so i was
the weed guy you know always i bought
pounds of seeded crappy commercial weed
and our profit margin back then was we
sold six ounces to make our money
and then we kept six ounces of stash or
or whatever and that that's the way it
always worked and so
that continued until the drug war kept
in and cannabis went to 400 an ounce
down in gainesville with gainesville
green and
at that time i started growing i got
some seeds and i
from a bag and i put them out in my yard
and i
i grew some tall male female plants and
when they got about my height i cut them
down and smoked them
and then um i started reading um ed's
book um they did there weren't such
things as the internet so i started
reading books
and it was a book called since amelia
tips and i had pictures of pot plants on
concrete blocks with fans and lights and
i talked about females and males and i i
got it i was like okay i got to kill the
males and it talked about sexual
maturity and i was like wait a minute i
just cut them down so the next year
we actually grew really good cannabis
outside i mean we harvested at the end
of the year it had resin on it it was
really good
and we instantly became famous people in
our circle because we had dank seedless
tank
and it it made me people like me and i'm
going to say some things during this
interview so people get to know me
better
i have a very serious uh inferiority
complex i i feel alone in the world uh
i'm very gregarious and loud but it's to
hide a shyness
that i have and
cannabis made me the [ __ ] man i mean
i was the man chicks like me dudes like
me people like me
so it it helped me get over this this
thing i have where i just don't feel
like i belong in the world and
and i just ran with it i mean i started
growing indoors um i was growing in
georgia by the time i was
in my 30s um i'll tell the story quick i
went to amsterdam to buy some seeds and
the guy that i was living with decided
to rip all the pot plants off while i
was gone
and kind of set up a pot plant in the
front yard to get me busted so i came
back to a police tape
and that was my first bust i went down
for five years for
um they found the trailer where he moved
everything so they got us for 362 plants
um
he got the majority of the problems
because i was out of town but but i got
my five
and then i moved to florida because they
banned me from georgia and my son was in
georgia so i wanted to see him on the
weekends so i illegally moved close
where i could skip over the state line
and see him
and i started doing the one thing i know
best i started growing weed in
gainesville and one of my favorite
stories before i take applause on the
story is never forget the probation
officer call me in my grow room he goes
well how's everything going i looked at
my plants and i think everything is
going [ __ ] great dude
so that's how i got started i just grew
weed and soul weed and
in florida i also got in trouble i got
busted there for selling really good
cannabis and
they kind of found us
which led to me leaving um to amsterdam
i lived in amsterdam for a couple years
with gypsy nirvana hiding from the comps
i came back in through canada lived in
canada for a while
finally got busted in canada um and they
extradited me to america where i came
back in and did my time
um i'm clean no probably no no felony
that's i'm clean i have felonies but i
don't have any probation and nothing on
me
and that is when i moved to the west
coast when i moved to the west coast
i moved to oregon where cannabis was not
illegal and i stopped getting in trouble
wow we definitely need to whine back
there there's hours worth of stories to
dig into so the first thing which caught
my attention was all the way back at the
start you mentioned um ed's book in
those early days who were some of the
other people who you looked up to
besides ed you know because i the thing
that i seem to notice was besides ed and
maybe neville there wasn't a lot of
people you really could look up to
there was no one mate i mean we heard
heard of jack but
you know uh me and ed are friends if you
guys don't know ed is really calling pop
he calls me son he published my book
he helped me get my book in the
jefferson memorial library the library
of congress i mean the guy's awesome guy
but it's not like i believe everything
ed says the whole photos interrupt this
thing we used to argue but when i was
growing up there was one book
it was the marijuana encyclopedias it it
sat on our toilet when we went to the
bathroom we read it and it was ed and
mel and we read it forwards and
backwards and backwards and forwards
and that's i mean that and sense of
media tips i mentioned it earlier i
don't know if you remember since emilia
tips that was the first
cannabis magazine i ever saw because
at the time high times had cocaine and
heroin and pills and it wasn't a
cannabis cultivation magazine it was a
drug magazine so
yeah there was no one else there was no
internet and there were no books and
believe me in georgia you didn't even
let anybody know you had that growth
book
yeah wow different times wasn't it so
with that being said what type of
strains were you growing were there any
breeders that you're aware of or was
everyone just kind of growing their own
little thing they had
yeah we would the very first named
stream i grew was grape ape but it's not
the grape you would know it was just a
bag of wheat we bought from tabi island
georgia that was purple and it was
killer
i had about 20 seeds in it so we grew it
out i mean now now i wonder was it
feminized was it a herm was it
one male how did they get them but we
grew it out and it was killer and i
mentioned it at the time and i'll take
some heat for this cannabis was 7 200 a
pound in georgia
just it is what it is if you wanted
really good
cannabis and they all called it dro
hydro even though we grew in soil
but that's really where it was at it was
only when i ordered and i loved telling
the story
i ordered them um from mark emery i
ordered puna butter
and i ordered uh something called
dominia
and that was god i wish i could do years
i'm not the guy that does in 1986 i
don't know what the [ __ ] it was but it
was
it was when you when you bought seeds
from mark and some girl sent them to you
you went like to some website and you
sent him a money order
and the poodle butter was sixty dollars
for ten seeds and i grew it out and
i i didn't like it i was like well my
grape eight was better
so that's when i actually flew to
amsterdam for the first time and bought
uh i got a bunch of american growers
that i know
and we got 3 000 american dollars which
was 8 000 gilder
and i smuggled back uh about a thousand
seeds for all the growers i know in the
united states i put them in my belt
buckle
and we snuck them all out and from that
and this is going to sound so cocky from
that overgrowth was formed
because some of my friends got northern
lights and some of my guys got black
dominants some of my guys got white
widow and some of my guys got russian
and we all started working together and
growing and working with the canadians
that also have genetics and that's how
these things form i mean northern lights
5 bam right there in the channel is
being mixed with white widow and g13
and some of those trains are still
around today my favorite is a mighty
mite
chemo widow it would blister you like it
would make you not be able to speak it
was so strong
wow and obviously that's not commonly
spoken about at all i guess a lot of
this stuff has fallen off
it's fallen off and it's gotten mixed in
with others and you know remember those
stories i told so in georgia
when they rated me i lost 83 mothers i
lost dank ass [ __ ]
a dab it's a strain that growers would
know i lost i lost nebu's uh uh rush and
i mean i lost lost tons and tons of moms
and then i lost another thousand seeds
that can never be replaced and i would
imagine that a lot of the core genetics
that we have built and collected over
the years before the things changed it
got destroyed by the police
wow
and so just to look back on that trip to
amsterdam quickly
do you remember what brands you were
buying based off what you said it
sounded like you were buying a lot of
the seed bank and
as well as maybe
um super sativa seed club you know were
those the people who were around at that
time or was it a little after that no no
they were the greenhouse was there we i
was a big fan of serious seeds a white
russian ak-47 a huge fan and also
tony with sargamantha who comes to my
chat channel and hangs out i'm blown
away
so he used to sell that yum bolt
and we went to a place they're called
the grey area and the gray area is an
americanized coffee shop it's not dutch
they have
soda pops and rock and roll and metal
tables
and the keith they had there the cali ms
keith was some of the best i've ever
smoked in my life so we went to buy the
genetics we smoked at the coffee shop we
were naive we were like that's where the
good [ __ ] is that's where the good seeds
are
so that first trip we bought a lot of ak
and by the way that ak that i bought
that cherry aka
still used to breed with today by about
four breeding companies
well yeah so are you of the opinion that
the stock back then was generally of
higher quality than it is today
yeah i'm i don't want to start a war but
for sure it's pretty common for them to
lose a mother and a father
and just grow it out again and start an
f2 i mean i can guarantee you that ak-47
we bought in 87 was not the ak-47 that i
grew out three years ago it was
homogenized crap
and i'm not talking talking bags it was
tons i got three pounds off the off the
back
giant plants but it was homogenized it
lacked character in what we call dank
yeah okay
so if we scoot a little forward then you
mentioned coming back a lot of these
genetics giving birth to kind of
overgrown
before that was there many people
bringing seeds back do you think
um there were but we weren't organized
this is what overgrow gave to us
overgrow gave us a platform to speak so
i was speaking to bogg and i was
speaking to soul
and i was speaking to be kai
and we started sharing notes well what
are you growing what do you breed well i
make killer queen what do you make well
i have a g13
and that's when we started trading
genetics and growing together so
me and seoul and sly used to
talk a lot with the a13
um the cindy and then vic had the space
queen
so if you wonder how i created vortex
i knew those guys so they gave me their
genetics
i crossed them together
and i get a lot of credit for the a13
across the vortex because it won the
cannabis cup a guy grew out of five pack
renamed it god's [ __ ] and beat me
and but it's it's not rocket science i
mean i got the very best phenotype from
um
from seoul which was one female a13 out
of 500 seeds the only one that existed
and then i crossed at times space queen
i mean
i'm sorry but if you have really good
[ __ ] you mix it together i don't think
you need to be super skilled and i take
heat on that people like well subs not a
breeder
well i don't know i made jack the ripper
you know i had to make it somehow and it
started back then so
the exchange of knowledge through
overgrowth changed the world it allowed
me to talk to another grower how do you
grow a growing water what's your ph this
what are you growing this
that knowledge just
superspeeded
cannabis growing in america we learned
about lights we learned about co2 we
learned about nutrients we learned about
super soil through vic
vic had a very basic recipe online
called vicks super soil and i still have
that copy
i took the recipe and added about 25
units of things to it
to make it better in my opinion
and people still use that super soil
today
without overgrowth i would have never
talked to vic vick would have never gave
me his recipe and we would have never
had super soul so it was the knowledge
that overgrow gave us it wasn't all the
[ __ ] and the trolls and
the karma liking system it was being
able to pm bog
and say bro let me have a cut of your
bog bubble sure sub how about how about
a cut of your jack's cleaner yeah boo
let's make jack's cleaner blueberry
which bog still uses today to make
lifesaver
yeah that's interesting you just you
touched on so many questions i think
we'll rewind back try to quickly touch
on
you reference the god's [ __ ] that was
funny i had a question i was going to
ask later basically do you have any
plans to maybe try to get that cut and
breed with it because my friends from
round table basically explained this cut
to me and they were saying like yeah
it's you're not going to believe it it's
phenomenal and so immediately i was like
like you know what's the go with that
if you grow 100 seeds vortex seeds
you'll get 49 of those phenotypes
see uh one there was one percent
difference between my phenotype and his
mine tasted a little peachy his was a
little more lemony and that year the
judges that were judging like citrus
they were stand even and that sounds
cocky but it's not it's
last i was looking for a male vortex
okay about six years ago and this is
documented on roll it up so i started 20
seeds and i got 19 damn females not what
i wanted
and
every single one of them was exactly the
same i mean if you go look at the thread
there's 19 plants we're just taking
pictures of them over and over again
they look exactly the same
slight differences between peach pear
lemon you know that
that slight essence of cannabis terps
but it's the most stable strain i've
ever created i didn't do anything to it
but cross a male and a female plant
yeah okay
so another thing i just remembered that
you spoke about was you referenced
talking to sly sly's someone who really
had to get a lot of information about
him what was your relationship with him
like and you know kind of how was your
what was your impression of him
well you know slice um both fly and vic
um and me had a very unique way of
learning we argued with each other i
mean you if you would have seen it it
was like you dumbass you don't know what
you're talking about but that exchange
of information
got us somewhere but sly was the kinder
he was the smarter he was the scientist
you know
um
a soul was definitely more the sales guy
i mean i'm not knocking rick if he was
sitting here right beside me i'd say the
same thing he was with his fingernail
polish and his and his cinderella
slippers i mean he's a
good good good
um salesman and a very good
representative for the company but sly
had the brains man he knew
he knew about dominant dominance and and
traits and he knew how to work these
trains together and he knew what would
work
and as importantly he's brave enough to
send us all clones so if you knew vig
high when i was
20-ish if you asked vic for a clone he
just sent you a cut out of killer queen
and we didn't have clone shippers back
then dude it was
a different game but he got it done
that's cool so something i did wanted to
quickly mention was
i think for a lot of people like myself
you were the person who kind of got them
into organics through making the super
soil easy so obviously you know a big
thank you for that because i'm very
passionate about organics now but
something which it led me to do was to
dive further into the supersore recipe
and i believe i found a screenshot of a
really old overgrowth thread where vic
actually says that he found the recipe
in
an old book by like forest agronomist or
something like that and he basically
said that um they would make this recipe
they would put the dry amendments under
big trees when they transplanted big
trees into forests so that you know
they'd grow into the nutrient-dense
stuff anyway i found it was interesting
because what it essentially goes to show
is you know it's just it's just
continually built over time and i think
that that's a bit of a people make the
mistake of thinking that he fully made
it and it's never been modified and the
point that you brought up is really
relevant that you added a lot to it and
if you do compare his recipe to yours
you'll see that yours is a lot more kind
of holistic in in all of the amendments
whereas his is a lot more bare bones and
it's just you know like manure and blood
and bone and one or two other things
really
and it goes further i mean you know kids
take my super soil that are smarter than
me and they adjust it they measure it
they take it to soil shops
build a soil has an entire [ __ ]
thread
based on my super soil where one
scientist says i'm an idiot and it
doesn't work and another scientist
explains why it does work and you can
buy
super soil and build a soil you can buy
the dirt and a charge pack and you just
mix the [ __ ] up and put the
worm castings in and you have it so
the only thing i did with with supersoul
was give people the idea to mix it up in
your backyard and play with it i mean
we've made hot batches we've made coal
batches
gnats are part of super soil i'll go
ahead and tell you now the newest thing
we do
is we put two inches of neen cake on top
of all the barrels after we make super
soil
it prevents the fungus gnats from
getting down into the compost and then
the manure
and then when you go to use it you just
scrape the neem cake off with your hands
and throw it away and a little bit extra
that stays is good for the soil this is
something brand new we figured out so
super soil is not static and it's not
for sale it's the way a guy grows pot so
i mean if somebody wants to give me [ __ ]
about it they can kiss my ass it's how i
grow pot
and vic vic taught me to take dirt and
mix it up in tubs
and then the other thing that we do now
is when we first made super soil we used
really shitty ingredients like i buy the
most expensive ingredients now organic
down to earth
expensive soils
nice crab meals stuff that's made
properly and not not cheap and that's
another reason super soil works well and
just so you know i mean we have people
here in arizona that grow commercially
in super soil buildings full of the
stuff
and i think
maybe i'm wrong
but i think the no-till revolution kind
of spurned from this what do you do with
all the super soul well we don't want to
throw it away so guys started figuring
out how to do no-till and treat with
teas and
hell geek mike up in oregon takes a
super soil and runs it through like a
a machine and shakes everything out of
it and rebuilds it like he's got a
factory to redo super soil so they don't
throw it away so
vic taught us so much he taught us that
you could grow dank
without hydroponics and then a lot of us
played with the soil until we got it
where it is today
yeah i think there's definitely some
truth in that statement you made in
regards to super soil and the no-till
which has come after it something i have
seen raised a bit though is people do
seem to feel as though super soil is
quite wasteful would you ever you know
in that you do inevitably have to
exchange the soil out after a run or two
would you ever consider doing more of a
no-till option
i'm doing it right now i don't close
super soil out at all i haven't done
super soil out in years
oh that thing yeah we have 100 gallon
pots in our pool we don't reuse it i
mean we don't throw it away we didn't
throw 100 pounds of soil away
you amend it you put teas in it
one problem indoors is a problem so
outdoors you can amend the pots in the
middle of the season
cover them with straw and you get a nice
you know you get a nice natural
re-amendment
indoors we don't have the same issue i
mean when we finish our giant plants
indoors
we take a five-gallon bucket that's got
the bottom cut off of it like a razor
and cut it down into the pot we cut the
root ball out
but it is the same process you reamend
um
you use teas and you build a giant cover
crop in between while your plants are
vegging
cover it with straw it's the same
process you just have to do it faster
do we have small problems yeah
indoors is not as easy as outdoors but
they're definitely growers now that grow
in super soil that have not changed
their soil out in many years
yeah
totally and so if we just kind of
jump back to what we were talking about
earlier you got back and you had the
seeds and overgrown's just started out
is this when you would consider yourself
to have truly kind of begun the breeders
journey or do you feel like you started
a little before that
no that's where so i made jack's cleaner
um
blueberry
and i made excuse me excuse me excuse me
jax cleaner bx and i'm a danny boy and
there was a site a sister site to
overgrow called cannabis world
and on cannabis swirl was the auctions
and so we went to uh sea bay and you
could put your seeds up and i remember
the first pack of seeds i put up with
danny boy was five dollars stayed up for
three days no bids
put it back up
stayed up for two days and someone
bought it for five dollars
within a year
people were bidding on the seeds upwards
of forty to fifty dollars bog joined
soul was in
and i gotta tell you this crazy story
about human nature so in the seed
place you could buy a pack of seeds for
a price it was called instant purchase
but then as a breeder you could lift a
pack of seeds up there for less and let
people bid on it
there's some bizarre human nature
people would bid past the instant
purchase price so there'd be a pack of
danny boy sitting there for 40
and three guys would be bidding up the
other pack to 90 dollars
and as a businessman i just [ __ ]
laughed
i was like if you want to pay me 40 more
dollars for it so you guys can argue
with each other great so an enormous
amount of money was made on the on the c
bay with people bidding against each
other and that's a form of trolls and
haters already already starting on the
internet people arguing with each other
over a pack of seeds and as a seed
seller not a breeder
i laughed my ass off i was like all over
paying for the seeds
it's just part of the history of seeds
interesting and it seems as though so
many kind of notable breeders did get
their their starting foot
in these in these forums do you feel
like there's any reason as to why we
don't see the same popularity for forums
nowadays it seems to be quite contained
to like instagram
um i think i think trolls are a big part
of it i mean there's there's this we're
going to talk about this as well because
i mean i will bring it up i mean when
you said i was going to go on the show
today at 150 comments that was the
biggest piece of [ __ ] on the planet
so that's in the internet you got to
roll it up right now and it's like hey i
grow good pot no you don't your mom
sucks you suck dicks it's just it's
exhausting
on instagram the same thing occurs but
you can block people
you can ban them you can get rid of the
comments
on roll it up if somebody's up your ass
there's nothing you can do i mean if
every time you post a picture the guy
calls you a dumbass
so that's part of it that's part of it
the other thing is you just said it i
carry instagram in my phone bro i ain't
got to sit at my house and upload
pictures i don't have to
you know remember the old uploading a
picture to overgrow would take like five
minutes remember that [ __ ]
dial-ups and stuff i mean nowadays
somebody sends me a picture i hit a
button and i'm making an advertisement
that's part of it
the other part of it is
i think there are too many
forums i think it got fragmented when
roll it i mean excuse me when overgrow
got started that was it bro
we were all at one place all of us
now there's roll it up which is run by a
bunch of kids there's no moderator
there's ebay there's icy mag which i've
been banned for life because gypsy
doesn't like me i mean i never even
could go there i was funny one of his
guys called me one day to advertise
there i was like dude
gypsy won't even let me walk in i'm not
gonna buy an ad
and then there's thousands more there's
cannabis and this and this and this
it's fragmented so instead of
a hundred thousand growers all in one
spot talking every day it's spread apart
i could compare it to dating sites i'm
not you know if there's one dating site
then you meet everybody but if there's a
thousand how the hell do you find
everybody
everybody's on instagram if you're in
the pot business
you're on instagram
yeah that's the truth isn't it
so something we haven't been able to get
any information from people but you'll
be the perfect person what was it like
to live with gypsy what what's he like
as a guy
god man uh it's all it's all gonna sound
bad i'll spend a few minutes on it but
it's all gonna sound bad
so i met him he's very nice i mean over
the over the internet great i went over
and i lived with him and his wife nikki
that was kind of cool in england
um stayed in a little pop um i i liked
it i thought english breakfast was
intriguing nicki was cool his his crew
was cool
and then gypsy got a business
opportunity to go to amsterdam so i went
with him and we opened up uh his shop um
that's zeta 42z like
uh my pictures are literally still in
the guy's shop because i had a
laptop with all my photographs on it and
gypsy didn't have photographs so but the
guy this gypsy's two people and we can
talk about this with me too because i've
had my about this gypsy was a fairly
decent gentleman when he didn't drink
but in the afternoon he would send me
for two bottles of red wine and i would
go get his i was just do boy make no
let's not glamorize this [ __ ] i was
gypsy's [ __ ]
so i'd get on the bike and i'd ride up
and get him a couple bottles of wine and
then by eight o'clock he was screaming
holler at me why are you on the [ __ ]
internet mate what the [ __ ] you sought
so he's rude and people have seen gypsy
attack people online if you haven't i
mean come on and that's what you get the
gypsy in the morning was a fairly decent
guy watch your breakfast take you around
his car show you some stuff when he
drank he was rude and
i will address that as well there are
people one of the things that somebody
said to me
is that in public i was rude to them
between the time i was diagnosed with a
[ __ ] progressive fatal illness
and today
i went through some [ __ ]
and there was about a year i will tell
you right off i was checked out of life
i was drinking i was taking drugs
i was trying to escape a diagnosis of
choking to death on my own it's not
i got my [ __ ] together and i don't do
drugs anymore i haven't had a drink or a
pharmaceutical drug in over 450 days and
i won't don't think i'll ever do them
again
so the reason i bring that up is alcohol
is a [ __ ] up thing and then
what i found in gypsy
was alcohol not gypsy and i didn't know
that until i
had my own bout with it so about three
years ago if you came in contact with me
and i was rude as [ __ ] to you i was
trying to kill myself because some
doctor told me i was gonna choke to
death in a hospital
i have dealt with it emotionally and i
plan to live my life every day the best
i can until that time comes instead of
sitting around and worrying about it
yeah i think that's a it's a really good
kind of message and i think a lot of
people will be happy to hear that
just to kind of how did you wrap up the
amsterdam i think you said that you
ended up going to canada after that what
was what oh no let's no mate back up so
my best gypsy had this great idea to
turn this uh giant house where it had a
table from the
anne frank house and uh
this excuse me a chandelier from the
anne frank isles
and a table that came from an old hash
baron so the house was a hash parents
house
[ __ ] history mate it was crazy
guy that owned it was worth 42 million
dollars african guys super nice people
drum so it was all a great thing
gypsy had the idea to set it up as a
hotel and have a bunch of american
stoners come over
and stay party smoke weed pay gypsy stay
in this awesome house that's in the red
light district i mean the whorehouses
across the street is [ __ ] awesome
so the first person i had bring over was
my best friend danny boy
and before i tell the story i will tell
you that danny was almost 40 he ate only
meat he did need vegetables he smoked
four packs of cigarettes a day and he
worked all night at a roach coast
business he's [ __ ] out of shape
they came over to amsterdam and he
partied with me we were cannabis cup
judges gypsy was awesome he was a
cannabis judge i mean a real one we had
the real [ __ ] hash weed everything
sitting there in the house smoking it so
danny um
we smoked 20 something samples of weed
hash
and danny was i don't just say danny
liked prostitutes he didn't he didn't
have a way with women back at home in
fact i don't think the guy ever fell in
love in his life is such a sad story so
he'd come to amsterdam and spend his
yearly income getting laid
and the second night he came back and
started hard for me to tell but the
second night he came back
he was sweaty and he was winded well of
course
and he came in and he sat down and he
was obviously you know
i said are you okay bud he goes ah man
that was rough i said okay goes i'm just
my heart's my my heart's pounding you
know i just need to go lay down i said
do you want to go to the hospital he
goes well do you know where hospital is
i said well [ __ ] no it's two o'clock in
the morning amsterdam my stone as you
are
so he's like i'm just gonna go down bro
so he went lay down and the next morning
at breakfast he wasn't there and i guess
it was like 7 30 i was like well where
the hell is he at so i went upstairs and
he was dead he was laying in gypsy's
fourth floor and he had died of a heart
attack in his sleep
so we had to carry his body down the
steps first time i'd ever seen a dead
person and especially my [ __ ] best
friend oh yeah by the way i performed
cpr on him for about 30 minutes and
because i thought death rattle was life
and
nah perform cpr on a dead guy that's
always good for your brain
so we get we get blown out i get blunt
to the american embassy get him home
like i'm supposed to i do all the things
a friend's supposed to do and i come
back and gypsy's drinking
so within a couple hours he said get
your [ __ ] [ __ ] mate and get out my
[ __ ] house he didn't pay me and he
threw me out so
i had about 200 gilder and i called rc
the owner of overgrow
and he said fly to uh canada just get
your ass to montreal and i'll get you
some money and some weed
so i landed god this story is so weird i
landed and i took a cab to this high
performance f1 club i mean
it's all these fancy models and jackie
stewart likes i did not belong there
dude i was an american on the run with
my ass kicked
but there was rc and he picked me up and
he took me to a little hotel called the
samurai a little teeny little place and
he gave me some weed which rc did not
carry weed because he owned overgrowth
and he gave me some money
300 to 400
and from there i went into the middle of
the country in amsterdam to i mean
excuse me
to winnipeg to a weed nerd's house not
at the time was not a weed nerd just a
friend
and i started him on a girl i was like
basically can i come to your house and
grow shitload of weed and he said yeah
so that's how i got from
amsterdam to canada was danny dying and
that's why i named that stream danny
boyd
and so how do you think that's affected
you in the long term having to kind of
been there for danny's death and the
subsequent you know there was a it's
obviously like a dramatic kind of exit
in its own right
and what pissed me off because i
couldn't come back to the united states
to watch him get buried because i was a
fugitive from from the law for growing
[ __ ] plant
so i had to deal with not going there i
had to deal with people hating on me
because i didn't love danny you didn't
even go up to the [ __ ] funeral
could imagine how torturous that was i
was stuck in amsterdam on my best friend
you know i mean excuse me stuck in a
knock i was in canada i could not come
back in the country
and um i mean i later actually went and
saw danny's gravestone and danny's
mother and father were both friends of
mine danny's father has since died
and i have to tell you one of the things
i'll get all [ __ ] sad but one of the
things i lost in the fire was a
i had a hand-drawn picture of danny and
it burned up no [ __ ] can't get that
back so i don't have a picture of danny
that's tough to hear
something i thought was always really
inspiring though is that you did create
that strain in his honor
um is that something you ever plan to
maybe try to work with further maybe
bring it back i think i've heard you
speak about it on the weed nerds episode
but i think you also said that this the
stock's kind of gone as well
yeah the taco mom um was lost and then
not only that you know danny boy was
very special to me danny and so is danny
boyce so the 500 and something seeds
that i created if you don't have a cut
you don't get to see it either
so if we just go back to the canadian
part of the story you were at your
friend's house growing the weed there
how did you sleep
sweetly okay so what strains were you
growing in canada at the time
um a lot of the same stuff a.b high had
given us ab and hob and the dab the
blueberry cheese
g13 um ak-47 all those and and i can
shorten the canadian story simple
because we don't need to tell a lot of
time i lived in a winnipeg it was 45
below freezing and [ __ ] we moved into
the house and we grew 10 pounds of dank
in two months and we dropped it onto the
street and the cops were like where the
[ __ ] did this come from
i met a kid named miles weed was 2 200 a
pound in canada i said well i don't sell
my wheat for 2 200. we're going to 3 200
he said you'll never do it
i harvested showed it to them they said
yeah we'll pay 3200 for that and then
within a month we got busted i mean the
cops knew they knew that there was weed
in the city and they just chased it back
to us and
never forget so in florida when i got
raided they kicked my door down held a
machine gun to my head put the knee in
my back generally treated me like [ __ ]
stole everything from the house stole my
cds
just treated me like [ __ ] in canada they
rang the doorbell
hey mike how you doing
sit down don't don't be silly and i sat
down
and while they were busting us they
found the warrant so you're gonna love
this one i love to tell the story
stayed in canada for a long time in a
place called the headingley hilton built
in 1929 i was a chef i cooked it wasn't
the worst gig you ever had for 12 months
in jail i got high in jail i had food in
jail
you could have a blanket so you could
beat off in jail a lot of things you
can't do in america
so it was like not the worst experience
of my life so then they deported me to
america and
at the border of dakota and winnipeg
they let me out cavalier north dakota
i stayed in this little box and the
guard cooked macaroni and cheese and
hamburger helper and peas that was
supper that's how small this place was
and they held me and they asked
florida to come get me in florida didn't
want me
so they killed me for 30 days and i had
a law there that says florida doesn't
come get you in 30 days they'll let you
go so let me go
so i moved in down in um
to the city and went to work with a
friend of mine named squid
i worked as a heating and air sales
person i made a lot of money i went to
your house and gave you an estimate i
was good at my job
and one night i went through a damn
speed zone and the guy picked me up
came to the car he goes you know you got
a warrant and i said yep and i said i
got a warrant florida they're not going
to come get me well this place was a
little different
they held you for nine months and they
call florida every day
so in the 11th hour the very 11th hour
um they came and got me i started
talking to jill at the time um she was
writing me every day and we had started
a relationship
they got me at the last hour 11 59 and
there's something that this is part of
the story there's something in america
called trans core
go look it up on the internet transcore
prisoner services
that's so beautiful we transport your
prisoners in luxury [ __ ] you they
strapped us together in a school bus and
drove us 10 000 miles in fetus
mcdonald's and when you pass by the jail
you're supposed to go to you ride right
by it because they can keep you on the
bus for 30 days and they make a thousand
dollars a day per prisoner and they keep
it full and they drive it out around and
there's hundreds of them in america
right now it is the most egregious [ __ ]
i've ever heard of my life it's called
transcore and i was shackled to another
man for 17 days and i [ __ ] in a steel
box and i was fed mcdonald's three times
a day and i swore to god that's a true
story
i'm not sure i've ever heard of that
that's that's really kind of scary
that's how they transport a prisoner
from one place to the other and the
reason they treat you so shitty is
because you're convicted you're not you
know you're not like going to court
you're on the run or you're moving and
it's
it's rough i was i was strapped to a guy
that blew his dad away with a shotgun
so
it's pretty
pretty crazy to take a guy who grows pot
and has a loud mouth i mean if i have a
flaw i have a loud mouth that's it and
and put him through the system and i
learned
so much [ __ ] i learned about guns and
murder and
i mean i learned every criminal element
you could ever learn in your life in
jail um and then anyway so that was
florida they dragged me down to florida
and i get to florida
they just let me go
they're like well we don't want you
anymore it's like why the hell did you
come get me because they kept calling us
so they gave me three years drug
probation which is you basically piss
once a week you have to go every
wednesday and piss in a cup for three
years and i did it i quit smoking weed
and i passed that test and i got off
probation that's incredible i couldn't
imagine even to having to do it like a
year at three years
so were you growing during that time as
well and just abstaining you bet no you
bet i was growing
[ __ ] i couldn't do that remember the
story remember the story when the guy
called me and he said how are you doing
how's it going and i said man
everything's going [ __ ] great i was
standing in the grow room but i didn't
smoke
you fail a piss test on on this kind of
thing you go back to jail so it's not
like you don't get a wrist slap if you
have two years and four months left and
you test dirty you go back to jail
it was pretty incentive you know
yeah jail or not get high
so i guess from a different angle those
were kind of financially profitable
years seeing as you were just just a
marketer
yeah florida's you know florida's was
around seven thousand dollars a pound
and i lived in gainesville and we were
just
pumping it out um to the college there
and ounces were 400 to 450 maybe 500 on
the weekend and
i mean it's the drug war created these
prices i bought my first bag of wheat
for forty dollars so thank you nancy
reagan appreciate that nice car i drove
in that badass house it was really nice
give me a raise
yeah there's a lot of parallels in
australia right now i think you know the
prices are arguably even a little higher
than what you're quoting what they used
to be but yeah very much the same thing
you know it's supply and demand to the
largest extent
absolutely
so what type of strains were you growing
in florida and were you aware of any
other kind of notable people in the
florida area doing their thing like i
mean did you think like oh there's
definitely someone in the town over and
they're putting out some good stuff you
know i've seen it
yeah it's great thank you for the
opening of this killer story so i met a
dude named tommy holland
he passed away last year by the way i
don't know good guy
but uh excuse me um i met him
and he came into my house and he had a
joint of this [ __ ] it was fluorescent
green and i was gainesville green if
you're from the south you know what i'm
talking about but
it had a name but he goes it's moonbeam
that's like what he goes we got the
mickey nope moonbeam and the mickey nope
madness now i find both of these trains
a little leafy now as a grower and
breeder
but at the time
they were [ __ ] afghanis that finished
at nine weeks and we were getting two
and a half pounds of bud off of them and
i mean we were just crushing it we were
using hydrofarm one on light movers and
in a bedroom i was getting four pounds
every 60 days so
i mean that's 28 000 every two months in
a [ __ ] two-bedroom apartment so
that's you know that's what we ground we
literally ground i had a little desk
downstairs that i'd internet and stuff
and i this part of the story always
cracks me up so i was on the internet
called merck
internet chat relay we talked
same thing trading clones trading
information i was in pot weed and
reefer and all the stuff and lots of
friends that are on the internet now
we're in those irc days it's a lot like
instagram i mean to be honest with you
we're chatting and talking it's just got
some more pictures but
i was online and there's this you'll
love this there's we made a sound wave
that said i think i can recreate it it
said hello
this is subcool or woo with a bong kit
and then i go
for forever and then
so it's we used to play it it was a real
bong hit that went on for a really long
time and they used to play it so as i'm
and all you got to do to play it is type
wave sub slash in the text and it plays
so i'm cuffed i'm sitting on the couch
my friends don't know i'm on the couch
cuffed and so they keep playing the
[ __ ] wave while the cops run out
so
so the cop reached over and snatched the
cord out of the wall and when you snatch
a computer out on merc it does something
called a k line in in the text box it
says k line and three of my friends word
of god said i wonder if sub got busted
in the channel they were like i wonder
if sub got busted and then i didn't come
back for a month
there you go that is kind of a funny one
so um
from florida how'd you then transition
to the west coast
well once i got once i got out of
florida uh i talked the guy into letting
me come to oregon to be with jill um i
convinced him that i had a job and i
didn't and i don't mean like at a
[ __ ] gas station i'm actually a
trained engineer heating and air
professional i do blower door technology
i understand refrigeration gas piping
electrical
um my dad taught me all that when i was
young so
i told the guys well i got a job with
the train corporation making like 80 000
balls a year and i can't get it here so
he let me go out there and then me i had
three days to get the job
so i opened up the book i went to every
train dealer and i sold the [ __ ] out of
myself
and one guy's wife said either this guy
is full of [ __ ] or he really knows a lot
about heating and air and i really do
so they gave me a job and um that was
you know that was
out there with jill and
i worked every day up in lines georgia i
started literally framing in houses
because he wasn't impressed when i had
to have him call my probation officer by
the way after i got the job
hey buddy i need you to make a call for
me
so he put me to work roughing up houses
putting in ducks and [ __ ] but it wasn't
long he could tell i worked my house off
when i was a good guy so i became head
of sales and
i started growing cannabis in oregon
under the medical program um in a home
that me and jill had
we moved to the country to a bigger
house and i fill the [ __ ] upstairs
with weed that's it i grew weed i sow
weed i made seeds
part of the success of uh sub cool um is
the wheat i grew i mean we sold some
seeds and [ __ ] but
while jill was raising kids and
homeschooling and gym and things that
mom do
i grew reefer and i [ __ ] sold reefer
as much as i possibly could
because i wanted to put the kids to
school i wanted a nice house i wanted to
buy nice things for my family i wanted
to have a retirement i pay taxes like
any good american i voted i i will
[ __ ] tell you one thing right now
about sub cool i pay my [ __ ] taxes my
accountant is lhrs and i pay my taxes
and i always have
i think that's important
so that's how basically we got started
we worked there we formed a company um
and we
sold stuff on the internet it wasn't
long i built the website i will tell you
that i hand typed every [ __ ] word
took every picture when people want to
talk about claiming things you know in
my organization there's only one guy
that wrote built that website there's
only one guy that did the pollination
same thing with all the breeders when i
went out and i found jinx and odie and
all those guys they're great people and
they're great growers and everything but
i had to teach them how to breed they
weren't breeders
here you take a male you stick it in
here you take this much time you want to
stagger this male 7 days you want to
stagger this male 9 days
and taking nothing away from these guys
nothing some of the most talented people
in the world i have worked with with
giant egos
but i took their seeds and i sent them
overseas
and i put them on catalogs and i put
them on posters and i put them on high
times magazines and we developed these
strains so when people talk about oh sub
didn't make it well [ __ ] i shipped
it to [ __ ] amsterdam and i set up a
store and i sold it and if you're one of
my breeders that are out there talking
[ __ ] about me that don't work for me
more there's a reason your shit's in
canada there's a reason your shit's in
israel that's because i sent it there
and i wanted to make very clear
so just to maybe clarify
why do you think od and jinx for example
because i think you mentioned those two
specifically why do you think they've
just moved on to you know doing their
own thing or is there a reason why
they've moved on
i'm hard to work with
i'm very type a it's money so i'll give
you the money so i used to pay these
guys two dollars for seeds and sell them
for four when they got famous enough
they just sold them for four
sounds simple
don't need sub cool no more everybody
knows who we are but it's the egos the
problem and i'll tell you right now
jason's a great guy a great breeder and
i hated every god like this
the fact remains if you work for pepsi
cola and you develop a product and pepsi
cola spends fifty thousand dollars
developing your product
it's pepsi's product it's simple patent
and trademark law
the only difference between now and then
is if you do business with me now you
sign a contract and we agree on
everything including the divorce
what happens if you don't pay the bills
what happens if you don't provide the
seeds
what happens if your seeds herm
aphrodite well we have a contract and
the only difference i'm so sick of this
the only difference was
two guys broke as [ __ ] shook hands on a
deal and then later down the road
there's a shitload of money involved and
the handshake didn't meet anymore and if
people don't understand that i really
don't care
that's the real truth of the matter i
busted my ass traveling around this
country i've wrote books and put
magazines in it thousands of posts did
not create these strains
not saying i did i marketed them
that's it it's it's law if you create
something
as a company it becomes your proprietary
property and i've never done anything
different i don't breed with those
strains anything i simply want somebody
to give me some simple credit
and i'm gonna get i'm gonna go hard on
this
when jinx walked on stage in one [ __ ]
cannabis cup with high nine pound hammer
and he won it all i wanted to say was
thanks sub
the [ __ ] what was wrong with that but
instead of that we created a war and i
lost a friend and now we all are this
division of people we don't even dislike
each other
awesome family great people
but that's what happened that's the
story it was money
two dollars wasn't enough so let's sell
it on the open market for four dollars
and i don't flaw anybody i think
everybody should get in business
but if you do business with me now you
sign a contract
contracts are how we do business the
reason we didn't sign contracts in the
old days is because it was against the
law
that's that's the best i can say it
um i don't harm anybody but when you
take and make a menu and you put nine
strings on it and you create artwork and
you ship
thousands of packs of seeds
and then you don't get credit for it
you're gonna get mad and that's why a
lot of people think i'm a dick
all i want is credit for the work i did
does that sound like an [ __ ]
with with that being said we see a lot
of the strains that were formally
released under tga now under their
respective breeders individual line is
that because you guys have kind of come
to an anatomical conclusion in regards
to that or is that because the contracts
ended like no
i just don't do it i'm not going to make
those strings i don't i don't want to
make any of them i don't there's nothing
wrong with i make my own strings and i'm
not making or recreating anything made
by anybody that's ever made with me
it's not like that
now
in my new business we process cannabis
under my like anything that i've ever
processed under my label i'll process
into hash or flowers i'm not talking
about breeding cannabis i mean you can
go out and buy 50 pounds of jelly bean
and make cash out of it and sell jelly
bean hash can't you you can that's all
i'm doing i prefer to work with strains
that i worked with
if my name was on a pack then i prefer
to sell that strainer dispensary it's
just kind of common sense
and i don't think anybody would deny
that i helped develop this stuff but as
far as recreating it breeding it i don't
i don't that's not what i want i'm not
trying to make money off of anybody
all i want is one thing
yeah man the guy worked his ass off for
us thanks
that's it
yeah and i can understand that there's a
chat room somewhere it's [ __ ] melting
down right now just so you know oh it's
just me and you
but i was about to say i think this is
gonna be great i think this is gonna it
is what it is i'm not gonna you know
this morning i was mad and i wasn't
gonna come on but i'm not a [ __ ] i'm
not gonna dodge all these questions i
don't i'm not
i you know i went to the school of dank
and raised 40 000 for jinx's
organization then i went back and did it
again i spent my money on the hotel
bills i spent my money on the weed the
seeds and everything so
if i'm an [ __ ] i'm an [ __ ] you
know but i'm pretty sure
i was involved and i'm gonna take it
even further farmer john is one of my
hashmakers here in arizona and he was
talking to somebody the other day some
somebody was online saying oh and he
said you know what i was there
i [ __ ] watch sub teach these people i
watched him take the [ __ ] plant and
put it in place a by plant b
and show teach he said he said it to me
he said so if i was there
it made me feel good you know he wasn't
trying to start arguing he's like sup
you did help these people
and i was like thank you john
yeah i can understand that
so i think maybe a nice way to end up
this general thread would be just to say
that many of the breeders who were
formally under the label have gone on to
obviously achieve success in their own
right and that's going to make you proud
seeing as you're involved in it but
another thing is that a lot of the work
does have remnants of tga lines you
created and so surely it must be
rewarding twofold because you know
you've helped them to achieve their own
success and there's some of your own
work embedded within theirs
i'll tell you something right now
quantum kush by homegrown natural
wonders is the singest most single most
potent plant i've ever grown in my life
and you should buy it from an od it is
[ __ ] knock your dick in the goddamn
dirt potent
over 30
um my time wreck mail was used to breed
it and there was some controversy on
that um
dioxide
grew out a 10 pack of plants and that is
where the time wreck plant came from
i showed joel how to pick the last male
plant that shows sex
i showed him the difference between a
cordage male plant and a sex plant a a
excuse me a drug recessive plant
and that plant went around and it's
still used today and that's it that's it
i don't want anything
go buy a quantum kush it'll knock your
[ __ ] dick in the dirt go by doctor
who it's awesome
they both were created with a time
wrecked mail that's it
so this is going to sound like a weird
question but i heard this and i i don't
think there's any particular good spot
to slow it in so i'm just going to slow
it in right now
i heard that um some bikeys came up to a
tga booth at one of the cups and said
stop using the hell's angel's name and
is that true is there any truth to that
not true
have you heard that story
i have heard that story it's not
do you have any idea where it maybe
comes from yeah troll rumors it's that's
not that hell's og cut doesn't belong to
hell's angels like they live right next
door to me they don't give a [ __ ] about
a cut you break
yeah it's just the name hell's it's
named at harborside i mean it's not it's
not nearly as deep as you think and i'll
tell you something blow your mind
we lost the hell's og cut last year at
one of our breeding facilities
so the 8 000 jesus og seeds that exist
today that's it
that's it okay and so would you ever
look to recreate it or are you of the
opinion if something kind of leaves like
that you just want to move on
well here's my smart ass answer
i think as it dies off we'll find a new
og male and we'll kill jesus and then
when we make a new one we'll resurrect
him
but
we'll see we'll see
okay my new business is growing cannabis
i don't need to make seeds um we are now
germinating 1 000 jesus og seeds and
finding the best two phenotypes
those phenotypes will be logged into
philos
uh candor um
[Music]
testing labs
be listed um trademarked as our clone
and protected and then that clone will
be grown and sold in in dispensaries and
my company name will go on them it'll be
grown under something called the dank
standard
which sets minimum for terpenes
um cannabinoids and and
sets the standards for not having
pesticides and we test everything three
times
and so before long we hope that you'll
be able to go to a dispensary and buy a
of cannabis product it's in a
nitrogen-filled box that's prepared by a
professional that is the exact same
cannabis that you will buy in colorado
oregon washington and california and the
way we can do this is we are setting up
these facilities in each state so i'm in
arizona now
i'm a d.a i can sell to all 131
dispensaries and i can buy from 131
dispensaries
i'm setting the same thing up in nevada
right now and also in northern
california
so we grow the cannabis in the facility
there the seeds are put out there the
clones are put out there and we're not
crossing state lines we don't even
change banks
the money from colorado stays in a
colorado bank and stays in a colorado
company
this was all formed by my partner tj
will and three lawyers who came up with
what they say is a landmark way of doing
business
instead of growing cannabis in one area
and shipping it to another
we're going to set a set of standards to
produce it
and i don't know if you're watching me
but we hit 96 thca today
with cbd a i don't know what the hell it
is
so we are knocking the charts off with
quality this stuff was tested three
times we spent three thousand dollars
testing the cannabis flowers
and then we're testing the extracts
twice
the reason i'm doing this is because
arizona specifically has no testing no
state testing and people are smoking poo
stew and avid and all kind of [ __ ] when
we go out and buy cannabis we test it we
make sure that it doesn't have mold
and trash and that's the cannabis we use
the time of of selling cannabis with
crap on it or grown and poorly it's
gotta go this medicine it's not medicine
for everybody
some people like to get really [ __ ]
stoned
but if you have an autoimmune system you
need to make sure there's not [ __ ] on
your weed and you make sure there's not
avid or sm-90 and it's a set of
standards that we are very proud to
uphold
and it is we think is the new future
i do not see the seed business staying
where it was in the past
the home of the five dollar grams here
so many people in the world used to grow
cannabis because that's the only way to
get it it ain't gonna be very long at
all you're gonna be able to go to
walmart and buy weed
you're gonna be able to go into a liquor
store and buy weed and americans
generally like to smoke shitty pre-rolls
not good cannabis
so the people who are going to grow
cannabis are the people like
us that have a very serious passion for
it
i think a huge market of people used to
grow recreational get weed well just buy
it i mean growing wheat is is the hard
work it's a lot of dedication and if
they can go buy weed i think the seed
business will fall off and there's
another thing
clone business is taking off when i
started doing this you had to buy a seed
you can go buy a
clone right now of all 40 of my strains
in sacramento you can drive to alpine
alternative and buy the damn clone you
can buy the clone that i selected you
can go get my time wreck that i grow
here
so why you need to buy a pack of seeds
so i see a shift that's why i'm growing
flowers now
still a breeder
still i made 12 new strains since my
house burned down
but in the old days we were basically
the only seed company other than some
europeans and there was cali connection
then there was dna there's 12 new seed
companies every day
the market's thin
without a doubt do you feel though that
part of the drive people have to buy
seeds is that there's almost a
similarity between like gambling you
know it's like it's a very small risk
but maybe it'll be a really big payoff
and
i think that plays into it because i
think the majority of people know that
their chances of getting something
phenomenal from a pack of seeds you know
like obviously it improves with breeder
selection but for the most part you know
like you can get clone onlys that'll
probably be better than what you get out
of most packets
i think that's part of it but there's an
unknown and you guys are gonna laugh do
you know where like i i'm just gonna
throw a number out there and y'all can
beat me up but it's probably 30 40
percent of the seeds aren't ever grown
out people collect seeds like baseball
cards bro wow
i got some 2003 black russian
well grow it [ __ ] they're probably bad
by now you know yeah that's my favorite
that's huge i have guys that showed me
their collection on instagram and i'm
like jesus dude you own ten thousand
dollars worth of seeds
yeah
just gonna hurt they pop so with all
with all the things you were just
mentioning it sounds very much like it's
kind of
the the general industry is moving that
way something i wanted to mention though
is that yourself and a few other
companies do outsource some of their
strain reproduction to other breeders
this seems to be a growing trend do you
think that do you agree with that do you
feel it's a growing trend and do you
feel there are any downsides of this
practice
there are downsides a man that's a great
question so that's one thing that's one
of the wonderful things that that might
attract he don't even make his own sage
well we have 48 strength and there's not
possible to make 48 strains in one
location
a
b
we operate in several different
locations california
arizona bada so there's that
and you take the simple fact that we
like to keep one male
in one location so that we'll mix it up
and the last factor is talent
so my breeder's name is badger he's
probably one of the best growers i ever
met you know i got that way a [ __ ]
hand trained him for three years
taught him every single thing i know
so now he lives in another place in a
nice building and he does exactly what i
taught him to do with the exact same
clones
so when he makes jack the ripper he
makes it just like he did when he was in
my basement
nothing changed
why would i change that you with me why
would i take that incredible talent away
he just created a string called queen
anne's revenge that has more resonant
than i've ever seen in my entire life he
created it with passion
it's not a job for this guy he's [ __ ]
sub cool's breeder and he happens to be
my best friend and he named his [ __ ]
son montgomery which is my name
so this isn't some
shack in the middle of a [ __ ] field
somewhere this is my [ __ ] brother
so that makes a little bit different
than
outsourcing your genetics who else makes
my genetics
a friend of mine named norstar i've
known him for 25 years
his house was the house i took a shower
in after my house burned down
his kids are my step or my god children
again
outsource yeah i talk to these people
every single day and he has 75 mother
plants that no one else has
that's why we work with him
yeah anyone who's seen uh northstar's
library or his instagram feed in general
is it's quite impressive
to be able to work with happy are you
kidding me to be able to call this guy
up and say hey man why don't you cross a
times b and you go sure
you gotta bro
if we just go back to the the storyline
for a moment let's go back to
i think you correct me if i'm wrong i
think it was shortly after you moved to
oregon is this when you popped the
packet of space queen
yeah so great that's great so and by the
way everybody thinks we should stop
calling it space bomb because nobody
knows what it is it's simple vic sent me
a pack of space queen when i left the
united states i left all my seeds at
danny's house because i didn't know
where the hell i was going the pack of
space queen was taped underneath the
keyboard this gets creepy at dinner at
danny's wake i had one of my friends go
into his office and get all the seeds
and send it back to me
danny would not have wanted to be thrown
away
i cracked those seeds and from that we
found tiny bomb which is a female space
queen plant we found sea which we call
cherry which we have since got rid of
and we found the dude
which is our space queen male we call
him the dude and he's made over sixty
percent of all our crosses i've taken
heat all he does is cross this yeah
this is one plant out of a billion for
real you could cross it with a turnip
and it would get you high
so that's that's why we're using he also
influes excuse me
and infuses a cherry flavor so if you
have a grape strain and you cross out
cross sometimes this train it becomes a
great cherry stream
that's how we made cuvee we took a
strain that tasted like chocolate
and we crossed it with space queen and
it tastes like cherries and chocolate
cuvee is means to combine two things
together that are good to make one
better and i would say that chocolate
and cherries are better than each one
alone
so just to try to set the record
straight it's been alleged that the
space queen was in fact a c99 back cross
is that the case
i all i can tell you is vic sent me a
pack of scent of steeds that said space
clean with an ink pen on them that's the
story
okay you'd have to ask vic
and so maybe a different way to approach
this question and to kind of satisfy
some people
if you were to find out that it was say
a cindy 99 back cross would you want to
say try to rectify the information
sources out there
no i don't i don't care and i that i'd
you know what's funny i've never even
heard that you know vic sent me a pack
of seeds in the mail and he said they
were space queens so
pretty sure that's what they were so
i'm not aware of this actually not aware
of the c99 rumor that's that's a new one
okay
so i guess while we're on that general
topic how do you feel about fire loss
and about the general kind of testing of
plants finding out their origins is is
it a concept you're in favor of or
because i know that some people aren't
in favor where do you sit on that one
we um we are mapping all of our mother
plants absolutely and you're you're
indicating a problem that my ex actually
talked about um
during all of the testing that we sent
in to phylus one time we actually made a
mistake we did and we sent the stem of
the same [ __ ] plant in each envelope
i don't know if you've ever done a five
loads test kit but you have to take a
stem and you cut a piece of it off and
you wash it with alcohol three times
and that's how you get it there
the guy that did it for me made a
mistake simply had six bags and he just
put one in there and they turned this
into this huge thing and by the way
tried to destroy the reputation of my
company which kind of cool being is the
other person owns half of the company
but it didn't work because we have two
strains that are pretty important and i
love telling a story so one is called
cuvee
so that's pinot noir
space queen which has a cherry flavor
and there's tinto de verano which is
taste of summer
and it's pinot thomas jack the ripper
and it has a lemon taste and those
strains are easy to detect
and if you grow them out they're there i
got a friend named eagle right now
that's grown out 45 of my strains i was
talking to him last night i said well
what do you think of this [ __ ] he
goes well i got cuvee and it tastes like
chocolate and cherries and i've worn the
cup here and i've got your tinto and
this lemon
but even funnier is
everything burnt up in the damn fire
anyway so now we're dead we're vlogging
our new mails other than dude so it is
what it is i checked it again and it was
right i've taken so much heat on this
i've never actually told them so we made
a mistake on the clipping that was sent
in but not the resulting clone because
the clone gets tested all the time and
when we test our strains that are made
with the clones they test right go and
file this and look go look at jack the
ripper go look at jelly bean go look at
all the strains they're right but people
in the business wanted to turn this into
this huge thing
because hey if you can make sub luck
like a dumbass
you can slow his business down and take
his business
it is what it is
my friends and my fans that grow my
genetics love them the shops here that
grow jesus and time wreck they they
laugh at this [ __ ] they think it's the
biggest
internet joke in the world but it is
something i had to address and that's
that's the very bottom truth of it the
space bomb we have
jill's got a copy of it i've got a copy
of it
mendo dope just killed a quirkle mail
because our corporal mail burn up it's
headed to philos right now to get tested
jack the ripper was pulled by 25
from badger so we got three males headed
to philos right now we're going to test
three and catalog three males and chase
them to the system
and we're rebuilding from the fire so
you know i think philos is a very
important mechanism
but i think the other problem with
philo's if you actually go right now to
the philos galaxy as a layman and try to
read it you can't understand it because
i can't understand it so i have to ask
nishan the owner
and me and nishan are friends and he's
been on the show
and me and um phylos and subcool seeds
are pretty tight so that's pretty much
it
we'll have all 30 of our moms and dads
catalog by the end of the year and
they'll get a hologram certification for
our program
and when we take a clone into a shop or
something like that we'll know exactly
what it is because it'll carry
certification
so the stuff from the old days it won't
be like that anymore because we have
open
source breeding like we've never had
because we can look at it you guys can
go look at it so i think everybody needs
to get involved
and and log their mails i got to go back
god's [ __ ] is logged into the
philosophy galaxy by the way and i can't
change it because i didn't enter it
there you go so go look it up i i may
have misheard you but i think you said
that you weren't going to get space dude
tested
no yeah and it's in there it's basically
oh okay yes i was just going to say if
so why was that i was thinking maybe
i was going to say is it possible to
maybe try to like propagate a clone from
just a cutting because if so i could
understand why you'd not want to send
your prize mail in
yeah no no they can do that and here's
another thing it's kind of cool we know
now that we can actually take a plant
and bring it down to a cell
cryo cloning you know and you can ship
the cell
i mean it's we could talk about this for
hours but if you can take a plant down
to a single cell
and put it in a cryo ship it you can
ship a cell it ain't a plant so we can
move genetics nowadays i mean you'd have
to get a lawyer involved to talk about
the rest of it but as far as the ability
and a [ __ ] heartbeat you can ship a
cell
and a cell can be propagation so that's
going to be the new
a new thing of cannabis is coming pretty
soon
and that's cellular cloning the clone is
going to be able to be moved around the
world and we see this coming in the next
five years
yeah okay
so i did have another one or two
questions on space queen i wanted to
bash out before we move on one of the
common sentiments i've heard is that
some people feel the repetitiveness of
space queen across multiple different
strains can kind of just ultimately lead
to if you were to say grow out a few
packets of tga you might find those more
space queen phenos popping up
repetitively which is obviously to be
expected do you feel like that is a
little bit of a detriment like in the if
i were to say grow three or four packs
of tgas i could end up with say half of
them being essentially really similar
no not even close you can go in any
dispenser in america and look at all 40
of my strings i'm not saying it's in a
vortex is apollo 13 space queen it
tastes like baby puke and peaches
it's got a very pronounced sick sickly
smell but in a good way
jack the ripper smells like lemons it's
pure
lemons
cuvee also these are all space queen
crosses it smells like chocolate with
cherries
every single one of them has a distinct
profile and that's because the mother
plants are so strong
i can differentiate i can take five jars
and differentiate from them now
do all of my strains have a fruity
pungent
pukey smell yeah i like that [ __ ] i
don't like fuel
i don't like goobers rag i mean we have
a kim d time jack gripper which is
brutal i don't like it i don't like
grease that's a personal thing when i
started breeding this is what i wanted
crepe
lemon banana
lime
orange cherry and melon i wanted a
rainbow and i [ __ ] did it
yeah undeniably some very tasty weed
which kind of brings us to another
question i think this this one
definitely depends on kind of the lens
in which you view the question but
another kind of sentiment you commonly
hear from people is that tga strains
extremely tasty but generally not the
most potent have you heard this sentence
and how would you respond to that
i would respond to the jesus i ran today
for extract tested at 26 and dumped a
[ __ ] pile of crystalline like you've
never seen in your life so i call
[ __ ]
so what i was gonna what i was thinking
was
in a way though i guess the other way to
view it is
even if even if you did kind of think oh
well even if that's the case there's a
certain niche because the follow-up
statement that people will say is a lot
of people i know really like the tga
strains because they're not just gonna
like make you totally [ __ ] and
they've got a lot of flavor and you know
it's a good often a good like this this
might lay me a bit of heat but it's like
it's good weed to like get people into
maybe the more obnoxious stuff like the
gassy stuff and all of that
do you feel like there is a market there
to fill like someone who's looking for
the most tasty weed and you know that's
their main criteria
i do that's great you were you were
really good at this just so you know
yeah i mean there is a reason we have 48
strings on our menu and you know not
everybody wants to smoke vortex and be
scared shitless and puke on the ground
like matt ryze did when he smoked a
joint with me
you can smoke a joint of jelly bean and
lay around and want to [ __ ]
you can smoke some coracle and kind of
lay around on the couch and just be
mellow they're all different there's i
mean they're not just all cannabis we
call it cannabis but there's reasons
cheese quake is one of my favorites
cheese quake is in the
18 to 21 range according to how you grow
it so it doesn't blister your forehead
or make you scared
but it's got a nice
danish taste it rolls around your tongue
and the mercium and the from the quirkle
brings an overall calming to you so so
when you smoke it you're relaxed
but you're not scared shitless and you
can focus like like my jack's cleaner
too
you couldn't type on jax cleaner too if
you had to your vision blurs
you can't see very well and you can't
focus
but you take another strain of mine like
third dimension which is done in like 49
days
it has a very coconut pineapple kind of
flavor i can smoke that [ __ ] all day i
wouldn't call it weak
it's just a different way of a profile
so
what you say definitely has a lot of
truth and you know i don't think
cannabis is all about just getting
blasted i mean i get up in the morning
love to smoke some of the the more
sativa mixed hybrids
chili bean in the morning makes me laugh
and giggle and [ __ ] but like if you
smoke vortex in the morning you wouldn't
want to get in your damn car you'd be
going why are they following me and [ __ ]
so
to me cannabis is not just a medicine
and a recreation it's a sacrament so
if i want to trip then i'm going to take
something that's like that but if i want
to
listen to
you know peter frampton and lay around
and make out then i'm going to pick
another kind of weed so
to me cannabis is just all over the
place and you know that's what we talk
about we talk about the cannabis that
actually you know makes you smarter
apollo i'll never forget when i was
making apollo 13 bx i'd be online typing
and i'd be staring at a cursor if you
write you know that blinking cursor
and i would say i'm going to smoke a
bowl and the next thing you would hear
is
typing it was literally i was like wow i
can just make one bowl of this apollo 13
and start typing so i don't think you
can categorize any cannabis is one thing
yeah i think that's a really good answer
so something i did want to ask you is
what do you think outside of say space
dude and space queen would be a strain
that you think really nicely embodies
tga seeds
coracle was a project i mean uh
coracle's you know somebody called fakes
that fake ass circle the other day well
i mean we know it's not we know it's
article because it's just tested it's
the same one that three of us use
um joel didn't even get his from me they
just happened to be the same plant but
what i wanted when i made coracle was a
breeding plant i wanted a way to
a paintbrush of purple and grape
urkel's a female plant and i don't
believe in feminizing
so i was like well what can i do i was
like well what about
outcrosser time space queen
cool
and then since space queen is cherry and
not colored
and urkel is
grape and colored as we look at the
progeny we can see the variance if it's
really [ __ ] purple and short it's
urkel dominant
if it's really limey green and cherry
and tall
it's space queen dominant and you can
see it
you can also see the males and i'm not
going to get a discussion on male
selection because that's another game
but you can see
the coracle dominant males and you can
see the space queen dominant males so if
you want to breed something and you want
to make it grape
like we make we just took and we made
great goo so we took an half gooey and
we crossed the toms of purple
porkal male the thing actually gets
purple leaves it has a very grape scent
it's very indica dominant and has a ton
of mercium in it so with that male we
can control
the flow of the strain do we want to
take grape
conversely we also have a coracle male
that is a cherry flavor and produces
more resin
it tends to make a strain less
short it tends to leg out a little bit
it has larger trichome heads
and the trichomes themselves have a
larger amount of liquid in them
so as a grower breeder these are traits
i can literally see
so in order to make something i had to
create quirkle so i had to make a seed
that would grow a plant that was a male
plant and that male plant would either
give the attributes of purple
grape
or cherry
and that's how you control a breeding
program i had to make quirkle in order
to make anything i couldn't make cheese
quake without making quirkle and cheese
quake's grown by everybody it's big and
chunky
it's a fun strain to grow mendo dope
loves growing it they got 12 pounds on
their outdoor
and all i did was create a male plant
and then cross the top cheese and so
using that formula i can do it times
everything
anything you have that you want me to
turn purple and give it a great flavor i
can do so
so i can take something that's lemon i
can make grape lemons i can take
something that's cherry i can make grape
cherry
or if i want to make it more cherry i'd
use the cherry mail
did i lose you no no no no i'm just
trying to take it all in
yeah so that's it's it's to me a male
plant is a paint brush
okay perfect so
one of the earliest kind of tips i don't
know if you call it a tip on breeding
but i just i i vividly remember it from
the weirdness episode and i think you
said it in a few you said something to
the effect of
you think that the male brings generally
potency and the female brings more of a
structure i might be
you know getting that vaguely wrong
opposite yeah sorry i might get
something wrong with that
do you think that holds generally true
yeah the male has
the male in my opinion provides cordage
and structure um it also provides pest
resistance but nobody ever talks about
the male plants there i mean cannabis is
duplicious and and the male plant and
the female plant are there for a reason
and in my opinion when we feminize a
plant and i got lots of friends that do
it we're we're presenting a slightly
less quality version i think that nature
would always make a better version and i
that hybrid vigor is what i've always
liked you don't get it when you feminize
seeds
so i've just always believed that you
have to work with the real male plant
that's the 10 chrome so the mixed with
the other 10 on the female
that picks up the spacious trains those
genes mix together and you get the
hardiness from the male plant with the
potency of the female plant with the
pest resistance of the male plant with
the resin production of the female plant
it's a [ __ ] puzzle and it's why it's
called breeding it ain't pollen chunking
you got to know what you're doing and
how you know what you're doing is you
make 97 strains and that's how many i've
made
and so i think something which might
jump to mind for people who are paying
attention is that
the the number you just quoted is
obviously a lot more than what's been at
market so obviously you've culled some
that didn't make it
what for you is the process of deciding
whether a pack makes it to market for
example
a really a sentiment that i really like
was bodhi said that he pops a 10 pack
just a single 10 pack to kind of get a
feel for what the customer would
experience and if he's not happy with
that then he feels it's probably not
good for market where do you sit on this
one
well about 12 years ago we saw a problem
with people buying 10 packs of the shows
for 120 so we created the five pack and
the way we created the five pack is we
grow out tons of our shrines five seats
we want to make sure we got a keeper out
of five seats and we do
if the five-pack theory didn't work my
ass wouldn't be living in this house i
paid for because i'm a profitable
businessman that's a five pack sucked we
wouldn't sell them
and so yes body's right you have to have
a customer get what he wants out of that
pack
if he doesn't get a representation out
of it then he's not going to be a happy
customer and five's tough
they don't get it i'll usually replace
them but it works all over the place i
mean it works so testing is huge so if
you don't know this
we grow a lot of our frames ourselves
and then we send 1 000 seeds into the
ethernet
and we watch
we watch instagram and we watch
facebook and we watch
roll it up and they tell us it's
instantaneously
you start hearing it it's like a rumble
it's really good it's like grapes stable
and if you hear the opposite yeah it
wasn't very good
didn't look very good which has rarely
happened dennis
you know to go the other way but you've
mentioned something else culling
culling happens a lot when you get
busted you've been busted four times
it happens we lost danny boy in a bus we
lose things
which leads to um most of breeders
nowadays hold our clones so
duke diamond with uh um
dominion seed company i'm sorry just
left soul he has my jax cleaner
um
the trichome jungle seeds in europe
he has my giants cleaner but [ __ ] you
talking about getting a clone somewhere
that took a while
so these clones are alive and they'll be
there for a while
next year i'd like to take these clones
and get them into fino seed bank
into their cryo cellular thing so that
when i pass on
these clones or these these genetics are
available for life
and me and will are setting up a trust
that lasts 500 years
just so that this stuff will live on
wow so i mean you just referenced
trichome jungle a good friend of mine
and more so a man near and dear to my
heart duke diamond
he actually told me that um
you were the one who put him in contact
with seoul and that kind of led to the
the resurrection of brothers grim a few
years ago well how did that all go about
let's just say the phone call from sub
cool carries a lot of [ __ ] weight
that's it
that's old this guy's a friend of mine
he needs a job he got a job i still do
it today i can i mean love or hate me if
i call you on the phone and ask you a
favor you're probably going to answer
the phone
and i'm probably going to have a good
reason for calling you you're probably
going to listen to me
and that was gay so this guy's awesome
duke diamond great let's go together
tommy thanks me all the time
yeah it certainly got them both launched
again in on their own respective
platforms which i think is a good
outcome nonetheless
so
something i just wanted to loop back on
quickly
just as a bit of a pot question when
space queen was first released
did it stand out to you was it something
which caught your eye was it only really
until you popped your pack that you
really kind of started to
gain traction for you
to this day the space bomb mail we
pulled out of there is still jill's
favorite strain on the planet
that says a lot
i mean thousands of seeds we crack that
one female plant is still our favorite
yeah it stood out it still stands out i
mean
a quarter pound of tiny bomb grown
properly it's
it's hard to believe it looks like pot i
mean it's got so much resin on it and
smells so
crazy i mean it's like wow this smells
like cherry candy and it's got sugar all
over it and it's not even hard to grow i
mean you still get super soil and you
harvest it at eight weeks
duh
it's like
you top it you harvest it you get two
pounds of light every time
yeah and so i guess maybe what i'm kind
of getting at is
do you think it had much of a following
before you popularized it
i don't think so because vic was kind of
a cult kind of thing i mean vic you had
to know vic and vic was an [ __ ] and
you know vic died last week did you know
that i i saw that on instagram that's
really sad to hear
his um there was this kid i'm sorry i
want a dirt first a little bit there's a
kid that's hanging a kid there's a guy
that hangs around in one of my chats
and he's pretty intelligent he's you
know i got to know him very well and he
you know he said vic's my uncle and i
said you [ __ ] he told me enough
stuff
that convinced me that vic was his uncle
and he was going to see him i love this
story so he told me that he told vic
this stuff cool said hi and he said he
just started kicking and that you know
just all agitated
but no i don't think a lot of people
know spaceman and i'll tell you this i
don't think
that that pack of seeds and that male is
some magical
ethos or something i think i worked hard
i think i took the strain and i made a
shitload of genetics and i ground my ass
out for seven days a week for years and
years to where you actually heard about
me and invited me on the show and i
think any business just like that it
takes a person
that works his ass off and that's why
you know about space queen i don't think
anybody else agrees with it but i mean
there's there's 50 threads right now on
the internet you can go sub cool growth
space queen tiny bomb
i used to sit and grow and write sit and
grow and write
so
just as a personal question because i
would very much say to people that if i
had to kind of attribute what my
influences are for this show i would say
adam done show in the weed nerd so i've
got to ask what kind of inspired you to
start the show obviously you had the
passion for it but what made you decide
to go i'm going to actually turn this
into a media format rather than just a
written format
well we've got to back up a little bit
remember that that thing that i talked
about still embarrassing that i don't
feel uh
feel like i belong well when talking to
the camera made me feel like i belong
and so i did the weed nerd camera i was
we lived in oregon i had a little office
i grew weed i didn't leave very often um
you know chill did her thing with the
kids and i stayed out there locked in
the garage
and i didn't have anything to do
so i listened to music and i started the
you know the recorded weed nerd and i
had a lot of fun with it but the current
weed nerd which is the live show was
inspired by the grow tube round table
crazy [ __ ]
after my house burned down i was at his
house he's letting me stay at his house
for a couple of weeks and friday night
he has a show
and i was like you do it live
he's like yes you don't record it yeah
now as a problem the old show i use
music
and a lot of the weed nerds can stick up
there's certain bands like don't ever
play foo fighters but you can play chili
peppers you can play k you just learn
this
you can play them off of youtube and
they won't copyright it but if you play
foo fighters off of youtube on a youtube
video
they will ban your account which is what
happened to me
i was live streaming playing the new foo
fighters video on youtube
off of youtube and they crushed the
stream and they killed my live stream
for 90 days
but having said that it they go daigo
taught me about the live stream and
bubble man
bubble man's format
is something that
i love watched and i
i think it's stiffer than mine i mean i
yell [ __ ] at my fans i toss people out
i'm the howard stern of my show he's
much more structured and classy but i
will tell you for all the people that
say i'm an [ __ ]
my fans love it they pick on me and try
to get me to throw them out they they
try to get me to rant on them they they
ask me stupid questions so i'll yell and
holler at them they go oh just [ __ ]
so it's a it's a show it's not reality
i'm not
i don't scream and you don't [ __ ] and
relax all the time you know it's that's
a show
i've taken bubble man and crazy [ __ ] and
vader and for goalie and mouse and other
people like that and formed my own
character
and i'm gonna say it one more time i do
it because i'm lonely i need human
interaction
it's a self-fulfilling thing
when i have 200 people watching me and
we're listening to music and we're
talking i would rather do that than
watch tv or read
or just about anything and because of my
position it's kind of a job too i teach
people how to grow cannabis
i give free seeds to any sick person
that needs them no questions asked
i raise money for people who are sick
and that platform which is the weed nerd
allows me to do it
so i think some some of the critics and
a point you know brought up in the
thread is
that it seems to be unclear how much of
the work was done by you and how much of
the work was done by miss jill a lot of
people seem to think she doesn't get
enough share of the credit do you think
that's truthful and you know is there
any do you want to kind of give her
credit for some things and like make it
clear that that's what she did or it was
it all by you where do you sit on that
i will not speak about jill
i'm in the middle of a brutal divorce uh
revolving around millions of dollars i
won't speak about it
alrighty
so
something i noticed myself was that
jilly bean
bean has kind of got a bit of a cult
following around it i think it's because
both the orange and the mango of both
the parents meld together well but at
the same time i think it's also because
there's a little bit of you know a
shroud of mystery around orange velvet
are you willing to comment on orange
velvet at all like do you do you think
it it is skunk and why do you think
julie being such successful strain
i will not comment on jill or jelly bean
in this interview sorry
no worries
one of the rumors that has been going
around was that at some point i believe
jack's cleaner male was supposedly lost
in a space queen took its
place
do you know that's the
yeah that's the philos sample i told you
about uh
so
the current tga setup appears to have
jill in oregon you in arizona is the
plan to go forward with both of you
contributing under the same tga banner
um i can't answer that question buddy
i can i can make a statement if you want
to make me lab yeah you can say whatever
you want so i own
sub cool
um seeds and subcool.com it is mine um
outright
um
me and jill share ownership of tga and i
can't
i don't know what will happen um what i
hope
is that jill will be incredibly
successful and make jelly bean and make
agent orange and make tons of strains
and help tons of people
and be happy
and find happiness in life
that's what i want
that's a good answer
so just before you express that you
weren't particularly into the idea of
feminized seeds i've got to imagine
there's a pretty decent demand for some
families from you would you ever
consider it or you're just not looking
to do it
no it's it would it's number one i don't
believe in it um so i don't know if you
know there are companies that make 50
million dollars a year selling seeds to
morocco feminized seeds to make ash
there's certainly on the table for me
i've been offered it
i don't believe in it
and i certainly don't believe in making
a billion seeds to send over to morocco
to make ash out of them because they
don't care that they are mephrodite or
not it's just not my game
two things happened in my breeding
career and they would not have happened
without joel of north star genetics i
have to make sure i give him credit and
we created dead lights so with dead
lights hits 26 27 28 cbd
i don't give a [ __ ] what anybody says
about me at 56 years old i offer a
strain that is
above 27 cbd
i'm good yeah that's i didn't think i've
ever heard of cbd that high really
it took a couple of years we had to make
pennywise we had to get the ac dc we had
to back cross we had a test we had to
lose a pennywise mail we had to refire
it my house burned down i had to i mean
it's work it's like i told you before
work is work
right now i have
dead lights and dead lights test over
and over above 20 and you can literally
go google the [ __ ] or instagram or
whatever you surf it and you'll find
right now lab reports above 27 i got one
on my phone
i would say that is success
i would say that prison terms and trolls
and hates and divorce and everything
that's gone on i created a strain that
helps people
heal that's what i do that's my passion
another thing we haven't talked about is
charity i give away
so much i mean yeah i have a nice car i
have nice things i have money i work
really hard seven days a week 18 hours a
day last night i was up till 2 30 and i
got up to six this morning don't accuse
me of not working but if you ask me for
something i will give it to you if you
need something i will give it to you
it's that simple if you ask me kindly i
would give any human being anything
kids
poor people
i mean we're turning the pool room into
rso if you didn't know
my giant pool full of weed we're gonna
turn it into rso and give it the [ __ ]
away here in arizona
that's what we're doing
that's that's really nice sentiment and
i'm sure a lot of people will benefit
from that i've got to ask though what's
with the pool like you know beyond the
obvious like is it just to prove a point
at this point
yeah i'm having a blast dude i got a
pool in my house with like 30 pounds of
weed in it do you
it's awesome sadly no it's got a stereo
we go hang out we we get our beach
chairs and we smoke bowls and we look at
the weed and we teach people how to grow
weed and i got a dab bar you can come
over and get hi at my dab bar and we can
talk about the ba
i mean seriously but the story is true
when i moved in here i have alpha 1
which is a progressive fatal lung
disease i have the lungs of 105 year old
man i don't breathe at all i can't walk
upstairs i can't carry bags of concrete
i don't do a lot but talk and yell at
people and
and point my finger at things nowadays
and so that's just something i have to
deal with you know of having alpha so
that has formed almost everything i do
in life
um the the the not being able to get
around and everything so that's kind of
how i ended up where i'm at now
so
it's just something you deal with on a
daily basis
i've you i mean anyone who follows your
stream would see you know you post
regularly of the uh the infusions you
have to have to keep on top of that do
you find that that's helping you because
i remember and maybe you can clarify
this for me it's probably two or three
years ago now maybe a little less even i
remember that you were saying that just
even generally smoking it was really
quite irritating for the lungs and stuff
whereas you know forgive me if i'm
mistaken i think i see you puffing every
now and again do you think things are a
little better than what they were a
while ago like any is that due to the
medication or
no i it's a great it's a great story and
leads me into i wanted to tell a story
here so when i was diagnosed they told
me i should never smoke again because i
had lung disease and i quit smoking
and uh within a couple weeks i'm very
nervous person so i got some wine and i
drank it and i like wine i tried i had
me a
glass and a corkscrew and i bought wine
i bought cheap wine i bought expensive i
[ __ ] hated it
so i bought some beer one day and i
liked beer and i drank beer and then i
drank alcohol so rock specifically a
couple fifths a day and i turned my life
into a toilet
and then one day i decided i said well
[ __ ] man i'm killing myself i should
smoke weed again and so i started
smoking weed
even though the doctors told me not to
now i smoke only hash generally teeny
teeny hits in a little bitty pipe i
don't dab
overheat i have a specific way of
smoking it's almost a vaporizing method
to do with my pipe
but within a couple weeks of doing that
i was able to quit drinking and quit
doing drugs and i became my old self
i felt normal again so i smoke hash in
spite of the fact that i'm not supposed
to nobody with a lung disease should
smoke anything
but i am a miserable
[ __ ]
when i don't smoke cannabis
i'm a hateful mean
[ __ ]
so i smoke cannabis and that's it that
was it's been a year in my life off of
cannabis
and my with sick and it sucked now
the reason i can do better now as i
moved out of northern california the
weather in northern california was
crushing me
on the humidity all that it's dry here
and and i got lost because i'm a little
high
the pool so
i drained the pool because alpha one
sucks and the moisture was making it
hard for me to breathe so during the
pool they're standing around the pool
one day and somebody on instagram said
remember chi chin chong well of course i
remember teaching challenge iguana gun i
can recite the movie
so somebody said you should go weed in
the pool so i said yeah we should so we
built a floor and we started and
somebody said
300 people
commented either i was a genius or i was
the dumbest redneck in history so i took
that as a challenge can't grow pool and
weed in the pool so
we're growing weed in a pool and we're
sponsored by smart pots and hortologs
and solatec and
method seven and hydrofarm and yeah it's
an amazing thing and guess what
everybody on the [ __ ] planet no sub
cools got a pool full of weed and that's
another part of what we do this whole
craziness like like i'm gonna tell you
something about your thread today okay
that little thing you put up your avatar
what was there 170 comments right i
think so yeah
guess what bro
they're talking about me
so it doesn't matter what they're saying
they're talking about you
it's business
yeah all publicity is good publicity
sorry so if you guys want to keep it up
when you log onto a thread and 160 times
type my name i probably sold a whole
shitload of stuff today thank you very
much i appreciate the advertising
so kind of on that topic what's it like
to have the tga brand extending into the
european market do you find the demands
are different or the same because the
thing that i've seem to notice from my
very limited interactions with the
european market is they tend to be more
focused on the terps and so with that
being said i would imagine tga does
fairly well
yeah and i will say that and god i got
out of habit it's sub cool seeds i
actually changed the name of the company
and i own some cool seeds so that's just
the thing so the sub cool strains are
yeah there's there's a reason your buddy
with trico and jungle seeds grows some
of my gear there's a reason because he
likes the terps there's a reason that
some of the hashmakers use my stuff
because they like the weird
comical cherrygasm do you know about
cherrygasm i've heard of it i've heard
of it are you kidding me
[ __ ] it makes white
rosin that crystallizes it comes out and
it'll turn in those little thca crystals
if you press it right
it tastes like cherry sap it
it's this side of having an orgasm to
take a hit of it that's why we call it
cherrygasm i i'm not kidding have
friends that come in my house and
they're just like as a matter of fact
when i moved here there was a guy that
was making sugar wax
i bought all he had at full retail
it wasn't tested i was like can i taste
that he's like i said jesus christ man
that tastes like smoking candy can i
have more
so it's just one strain cherry gasoline
by the way we lost cherry gas in the
fire
scotty 016 was nice enough to bring the
cherry pie og back to joel
he has the space dude mail we just
released cherrygasm again [ __ ] you fire
ain't no fire gonna take me out
so one of the claims i've seen raised by
critics is that i mean well let me put
it this way you've made it clear that
certain strains were discontinued
because the mothers were gone is that
the case that pretty much all the
discontinued strains fall under that
umbrella or were some of them pulled
from the market because there were
issues that weren't realized until after
release
nah i've never had an issue with the
strain i've i've had strings that were
better so like pandora's box we took
pandora's box off the menu because it's
a back cross of jtr
it's very similar to jtr i think
[ __ ] if you go to jtr and your
pandora's box you'd be like man these
things are very similar
that pandora's box right there is a lot
like that jack ripper female and all it
is is a more stabilized version so we
took it off the menu guess what we just
brought it back on the menu you want to
know why because 10 times a week
somebody goes bring back bring that
here's some ones jack's cleaner
blueberry i tried for five years
to make a blueberry flavored string
every time i glue grow blueberry in
super soil it pushes it in
hermephrodites i used to think that
blueberry was a hermetic strain i've
taken heat on it it's not
it's a low feeding strain if you put it
in super soil you push it all the time
i didn't know that back then well we
know that now
so i kept working with it i kept trying
to create something and i thought i was
creating herms because [ __ ] males
kept messing up and the females kept
messing up it was too strong so i spent
five years trying to do one thing and it
didn't work
i took the space queen mail across the
thomas jack's cleaner and we made jack
the ripper and you can say what you want
i mean jack the ripper test is six
percent for thcv and you can't go in the
shop here and not buy it i would say
it's a successful cross
without a doubt
so
something i'm always interested in is
deeply embedded within that cross is the
pluton genetics which i remember you
told the story and i think you said that
your friend sent you some of the working
parts so i don't think you actually work
specifically with the pluton but do you
think that that comes through it all in
the cross or do you think it's more of a
structural like you know like it's
embedded in there but you don't see it
particularly
i think jack's cleaner is heavy on
northern lights so that the story is my
friend scooch who passed away two years
ago by the way all my friends are dying
because we're all old
but excuse excuse me sku sent me a 100
skosh skosh skosh seeds and
that's what it is it's northern lights
times plutonius that it's that thing you
see me type
northern lifestyle pluton tom hayes time
that's that's what he sent me that's
what he told me it was
and so i grew them out and i got this
amazing female plant call cleaner i mean
it was the best female out of a hundred
seeds some of the females out of that
pack were shite i mean they just were
they weren't any good the one was
exceptional and at the time i had a
major fascination for jack hair and i
had grown out a pack of jack here from
scentsy seeds i picked the last female
to excuse me the last male to show sucks
and i pollinated i made jacks cleaner at
the time i was heavy into drugs steroids
fast cars women
cocaine and i lost the seeds i have no
idea where they were
but that jax cleaner female was giving
us a couple of friends of mine and when
i got my [ __ ] back together it stayed
around i passed it out to everybody i
could get it just like seoul passes out
his a13 so people don't lose it
so who do you think are some of the
breeders who
still around now but maybe just largely
go unnoticed by the masses
i don't think there is such a thing
we're all players now kyle cushman has a
giant contract duke has a giant contract
seoul has a giant contract with
cinderella he grows cannabis and sells
it across the nation
and i have a little statement so
there was only one snoop dogg
and there was only one willie nelson
there's a bunch of pot growers
and that's what you're gonna see you're
gonna see people aligning themselves
with someone i have four felonies and
everybody knows who i am so it was
really easy for these guys to come and
pick me up and trust me they know all
this this this this drama that revolves
around me and the divorce and jill and
all the things that happen to me and
they [ __ ] laugh
like i must have heard subcool's name 35
times today well that's why they picked
me
soul has the same power duke
i mean tell me you wouldn't want duke
diamond breeding for you and putting his
name on some strain
of course you do
but i think that's what you're going to
see moving forward anyone that has done
anything
of fame is going to align themselves
with a company
or shop um help kyle just got a massive
contract with hydrofarm so he's going to
be the hydra farm spokesman the [ __ ]
does that have to do with growing pot
nothing he likes hydro farm lights so
he's going to tell people they're good
lights i do the same thing every day i
got a big sign hanging in my house
so it's just a new the branding thing
the lining thing the outlaws the days
are gone they just are it is a time of
paying taxes and businesses and working
with other people
we work with a greenhouse here we buy
their cannabis and we sell our
products at their store
we've collaborated together we're
putting all their bud tenders and our
uniforms and some of their our people in
their uniforms and
it's the only way you can move forward
in this industry is to work with people
that that you can get along with
and you know pump it up so it's saturday
we're going to drop our sauce for the
first time 96
thc isolate with cbda whatever that is
we've got nine pound hammer jesus and
girl time
um we've pre-sold a couple of hundred
units and we're going to show up at 11
o'clock and i'm gonna sign books i'm
gonna pass out things and we'll be
friendly
you know this is working it's a form of
work that i enjoy we have like a willy
wonka thing everybody gets a box and
whoever gets the special box gets a book
a bank books are almost gone by the way
i have 12 left and that's the only ones
left
and then um you know give some pipes
away just give some cool stuff away give
a fan
the experience because for as much
hard-ass questions as you as asked me
today
when i go in public people still walk up
to me and treat me with massive respect
people shake my hand and they thank me
for teaching them how to grow and
teaching them how to maybe buy a house
or
pay their taxes or do something right so
i enjoy what i do very very much and
it's very rewarding to to have so many
people you know
look up to me i can't tell you how many
people say
hey man you told me how to make
supersoul and then you taught me how to
clone and i own a seat company now it's
so many people and i'm not trying to
take extra credit
if you catch me right now tonight after
the show in my stream and you ask me a
question about growing i'll answer it
that's what i do
and so i noticed in the past you had
done some kind of seminar things you
even referenced it in regards to the
jinx charity do you plan to do any more
of this going forward
no um my health really i really
shouldn't go around a ton of people um i
shouldn't travel if i get a cold like if
i get a cold or flu because i got on a
plane or travel i have to go to the
hospital so alpha is not a joke if
anybody wants to google alpha one it's a
progressive fatal lung disease and it's
brutal so yeah getting a cold is not
good for me most people that have what i
have die
because they get a
virus or a flu
so i don't fly all over the place and i
don't generally
i didn't go to cushdock this weekend i
wanted to so bad i hope there are people
listening that know about this they're
like sub said he was going to cush duck
and he [ __ ] let us down
man i wanted to go so bad i really did
it's a [ __ ] smoky ass building seven
hours away
[ __ ] hot as [ __ ] it would have been
detrimental to my health there's no way
i can stand in a hot ass dusty building
breathing smoke and so at the last
minute i bailed and people think i'm
being wrong i'm sorry i was i really i
was like oh god i want to go be sub cool
can i please go stand in public and pass
out seeds and have people shake my hand
and pat me on the back but i made the
choice not to high times in san
bernardino it's kind of the same thing
so i've been invited to be a judge there
and i've been invited to be a judge at
chalice and i'm invited to speak at both
places and we may do chalice but
on the 20th me and we'll have a grand
opening we're dropping sauce and 12
dispensaries here in arizona so
i don't really have time to go talk and
you can watch me talk 40 hours a week
you just have to watch turn the phone on
i'm talking
so
just if we loop back on that point you
made about how you guys market and stuff
you would be a good person ask this
question to
this is a hypothetical i'm not referring
to anyone specific but do you think it's
possible for a breeder in today's age to
produce quality work but not be
particularly present on social media do
you think it's going to work or it just
won't be viable in this current you know
scene
you know that's a really interesting
question because there are certainly
breeders around that don't
you know rip up social media but you
know like my favorite one of my favorite
breeders right now is bodhi have you
seen his camera work on instagram yeah
all the tobacco and stuff
the resin heads and stuff he does he's
just out of control and
so he's about i don't know how do you
how do you sell your strains if you
don't tell people about them how how do
you sell the donuts if you don't tell
people you got good donuts i mean
i think there are people working well
here's one badger
badger is probably one of the best
breeders in america today do you even
know who he is yeah i definitely know
who he is
that's so he's coming up
is he on social media yeah
you kind of have to almost if that makes
any sense so i i don't think you can i
really don't yeah well i mean just most
notably having had a chat with gooey
breeder i kind of think of him in that
regard i think he maybe limits himself a
bit by being so absent you know
yeah he doesn't make any money i mean
i'm not dogging he's he's got money he's
a very successful
wealthy person that's not that sounded
wrong the way i said it but does he have
45 strains on the market selling them in
every dispensary in every shop does he
have a strains and attitude and no
it's because nobody knows about him we
know about me and you know about him
because you know joel and we know his
stuff is the bomb
oh yeah
you know he's he's an eclectic kind of
guy i've only met him twice and hell i
live down the street from him
there you go closer than you would have
thought
so good good reference by the way gooey
is a hell of a breeder that doesn't
that people don't know that's a great
reference by the way
so
something i wanted to quickly bring up
this this one you may or may not have
heard of
when i remember you first talking about
super soil i'm pretty sure the cook time
has always been about three months you
know
i swear it's like a competition now and
i hear people saying you know like six
weeks eight weeks and i just feel like
it's going to be somewhat detrimental to
the plant
do you find that uh reducing that cook
time is detrimental to the plant
okay so eight weeks is really good six
to eight weeks um yes if it doesn't if
you don't break down especially if
they're using uh
if they're not if they're using glacial
rock dust which some of the recipes
people still use that that does not
break down um
if they're using leonardites a little
slower there's a couple of things in the
mix it takes a little longer
we
have something we do it's completely
different here we keep six cans made
so if we drop three cans we keep six i
can tell you that i happen to know that
that um
jill runs nine so we keep them full all
the time and i would say most of our
supersoul is approaching two months of
age
people think it goes bad
soil it's not gonna go bad
but remember the nat thing
if you leave it outside for too long and
it gets moist you can
make a breeding sanctuary for gnats
two inches of neen creek across the top
will prevent that
good advice good advice
so one of the things i saw in that
thread today someone wanted to know how
come you were banned from breed bay i
don't actually know any of the context
to this so it's just going to be totally
all new to me
yeah well i mean pistols was my friend
and we sold stuff and he had kind of a
beef with my ex i never really got along
and
in the end uh he
owed me 90 000
and he basically you know he's overseas
paid me drafts
and he let it get up and i was hitting
him on it and then he one more order and
it got too high and i basically he said
[ __ ] you
i'm not paying you and he banned me
i did
huh
is that is that a common thing dealing
with seed banks nowadays or is it oh my
god
yes yes yes yes yes yes uh here's
another one i love this one so logic um
what is logic which one is logic
god it's one of these forums i can't he
he at 420 something
i'm sorry
anyway he he he tried to get me but i
tricked him into paying me by telling
him i was gonna send him another order
and didn't he got two other people
everybody left his site his site still
runs and he still does business with new
people i guess he doesn't rip people off
anymore it look when you're dealing with
an email what are you going to do
sorry bud
[ __ ] off
what do you do you're going to scream
and you're going to holler you're going
to start a war on the internet that
turns into some big drama and nobody
knows the truth but what do you do if me
and you establish business and i just
tell you to [ __ ] off
you know your name's red baron and my
name's subcool
sorry
i mean logic yeah how the hell am i
supposed to collect from some guy named
logic
so it's part of the business which is
why
some of the people that we work with
like ed borg of delta 9 a 22-year
relationship
hemp depot
19-year relationship attitude
14-year relationship
work with people you trust
it's interesting you mentioned attitude
one of the other criticisms i've heard
from people is that
i think it's probably true that at one
point you were definitely one of the
main breeders on attitude it seems like
you've done very well on that
historically
what i heard was that you had a lot of
influence over attitude and who got to
vend on that site is there any truth to
that or do you want to comment on that
at all
no it's not true at all
i was there when there was only a few
breeders and so i made a ton of [ __ ]
money i was the guy going to the
cannabis cup there wasn't anybody else
really i liked a couple of people and
then they started picking people up you
got to realize i was there before big
buddha
my first high times cup i stood ass
cheek to ass cheat with big buddha at a
three by three table him behind me he's
selling his cheese i was selling jack
the ripper i mean we all kind of started
from the same roots you know
so
yeah what's it like to deal with these
international banks now do you still
have these issues like what you
mentioned with logic or is it a bit more
business-like nowadays no we we we
actually have i have a business in
amsterdam i own a business in amsterdam
i have a bank account there
i have a facility there and so i i own a
business in amsterdam so it's not it's
not the same thing as it used to be so
i mean i
will can go there and visit ed's office
uh it's it's not smoke and mirrors
anymore if that makes any sense i mean
it's a business you know it's um yeah
you open up a business you do business
you run the money through the banks i
know this man's name address tax id
number uh i have a oh by the way there's
another thing now you're lucky i didn't
make you sign an nda and i'm laughing
but me and will have a stack of
non-disclosure agreements sitting next
to us if you come in my house and we're
going to talk business you're going to
sign that [ __ ] because if you talk [ __ ]
down the road i'm going to bust your ass
it's another part of this business is
people can't keep their [ __ ] mouth
shut
yeah no i i can totally understand that
and nowadays the people that we're
talking to come with ndas and now we're
having nba dick
i want you to sign my nda and we'll will
by the way one of the smartest contract
people out there
he read this one guys thing he goes no i
said why ain't signing because his
contract says if we have a dispute we
have to go to [ __ ] new jersey
oh yeah we're not signing that [ __ ]
and the guy bought it he goes why won't
you sign money he goes cause we're not
gonna dispute the [ __ ] where you live
and they're like okay so he signed ours
so we have a better nda
so
i gotta give a little bit of credit to
uh my friend who i have actually
forgotten his name but he helped me with
this one
basically
in one of the old weed episode weed nerd
episodes apologies
you asked the fan for suggestions of a
strain name and eventually the
suggestion of electric watermelon hash
plant came up but then kind of the next
episode you said oh we can't use that
because that one's already in use
however a lot of people will point out
that there's a few strains from the tga
stables which have taken names of
already existing strains like deep
purple from jordan of the islands as
well as strawberry daiquiri from
surefire seeds
do you think that you know like you do
try to avoid this overlapping of the
names being taken was it something
you're aware of
yeah so in the old days it was easy in
the old days you made up a name and it
wasn't taken
simple
when i started doing this there was no
such thing as the name of cannabis it
just wasn't though you can name anything
we want to we could name it dump truck
[ __ ] that was cool but now the
other day this is a great example so
joel just released a strain to me called
great goo
so i typed the [ __ ] thing into google
and it comes up all over the place
so i changed the name of this tester to
af groovy
and joel calls me goes hey
this is [ __ ] it's great goo when i
said well no great goo is he goes no
great goo is just names and [ __ ] there's
no verified genetic heritage and we're
keeping the name
[ __ ] changes
so yes i would rather not the other part
of it's kind of i'm pretty sure my deep
purple was before jordan's i was aware
of the strawberry daiquiri okay so i
grew the strawberry dacrop
uh the plant out and it has to be
strawberry daiquiri it's it has to be
it's kyle cushman's strawberry cough
times the thc jack the ripper male and
it tastes like a [ __ ] strawberry
daiquiri onion wasn't aware of it until
i had already tested it under those
names when i looked it up i said well
you know what
there are only so many names to go
around
so that one's going to be somebody
else's strawberry daiquiri and this
one's going to be sub cool strawberry
daiquiri it was a decision because
they're just only so many names left
every stoner on the planet has sat
around smoking weed and put cheese times
butthole times northern lights there's
just nothing left i mean there's a
strain called thunder [ __ ] there's a
string called dog [ __ ]
uh there's 12 strains with the
watermelon name in them so yeah i really
at first really tried now i don't give a
[ __ ]
okay
so one thing i definitely wanted to ask
you before i forgot was i noticed in one
of your posts you said that the i can't
pronounce it but you did it perfectly is
it the peanut noir or something along
those lines i think you said it
yeah it's your favorite strain and i
think it's from aficionado or at least
this is what the post said can you give
us some information on it you know like
i couldn't find much at all i'm really
interested
it's a clone only strain that leo and
frenchie work with they have lost theirs
the only copy of it was at my house two
nights before the fire frenchie was at
my house the night making hash
i said frenchie take it he says oh
that's so cool
i said okay leo there was next day hey
bro what's up i said man take this clown
he goes man i'm going to the bay i said
we'll swing back by and get he goes okay
and he didn't and it burned up in the
[ __ ] fire so leo says he has a line
on it but right now we do not have a
line on it which means we can't make
cuvee and we can't make tinto and
they're my two favorite strains i'm
trying to call leo as much as i can
you also understand when i call leo he's
busy as [ __ ] he's got 300 acres and he's
growing
so while he loves me and cares about me
and wants to help me he's busy so i
hadn't heard from him in four weeks
three days ago he sent me a text that
said sub
i have a line on the clone and i'll be
contacting you i texted him back and he
never even responded
busy is busy you know
yeah it's interesting we speak about
aficionado because in the uh the
infamous thread we reference one of the
very obscure points brought up was that
someone felt that tga genetics were
overpriced
forget that for just one moment i want
you to consider that in contrast to
aficionado you know do you think that
that statement holds any weight when
you've got people admittedly you mean a
300 wooden box no i don't think my
proceeds are overpriced i'm sorry and i
love leo to death but i sell seeds for
forty dollars and that's a very
reasonable price we pay two dollars to
manufacture them and we
what happens is attitude turns around
and sells them for 160 dollars that's
not me
would you ever consider trying to impose
some type of ceiling on your
prices where you say look i just don't
ever want it going above this level i
just feel it's a bit excessive at that
point
no the industry did that crockett was
standing at cush talk this weekend
himself selling 13 c's for 50 you're
about to see the price of siege take a
[ __ ]
yeah okay
so
do you think that's just going to drive
out the small time producers
well yeah i mean you got to keep up it's
uh
well i mean that shocked me he actually
came over to my boot to our booth and
talked to our people and i love croc
it's not i mean all i'm saying
was it's tough out there this man was
standing there selling seeds that's it
it's
13 seeds for 50 that's
that's a really good deal yeah for
crockett seeds
that cheap
so in the old days we'd go to an event
we'd make two hundred thousand dollars
that cush stock would make twenty two
hundred dollars you think i'm going back
wow yeah
plus you can buy a pack of seeds on
instagram like
it the [ __ ] domino's pizza guy
bringing a pack of seeds nowadays i mean
it is become silly you can uber [ __ ]
weed to your house so
you don't really have to
do the other things we used to do i mean
you can have somebody bring a pizza and
a bag of pot to your house here so
yeah
so you could probably swing by and get
your pack of seeds
i had heard rumors that uh
agent orange was possibly used in the
creation of tangie have you heard
anything along those lines
no i mean i'll comment on that for sure
so eric 77 brought us california orange
california orange is used by me to
create things in the old days it's used
by dna to create things and orange
velvet is california orange it's all the
same cut
our cut came from some people and it was
called melvin and we thought melvin was
a [ __ ] stupid name
and it smelled like oranges so it's
orange velvet but they're all california
orange
and they came from eric 77 in
gainesville in 1979.
yeah i've i've heard that a lot of it is
very much just callio dominant
expressions isn't it do you think that
we'll see the orange trend come back or
do you think it's kind of peaked and
we'll you know we won't see it again for
a while
i'm so over orange i will never smoke it
again so you won't see me making it
that's a good answer so what type of
flavor profiles are you looking to move
on to
chocolate cherry banana and watermelon
those are some pretty unique ones you're
talking kind of individually or more
blending them all together
just those remember that rainbow story
yep
so i'm still on it
so we got cherry and now
we lost pinot but we had chocolate dude
i made chocolate weed get the [ __ ] out
of here
i made chocolate weed ask any of my fans
what cuvee tastes like tastes like
chocolate that's just it's a flavor
thing man so yeah i tasted some
brandon with third gen i bought a gram
of something from organic can last year
called melons
with a z melons
dude jesus i was licking the lick in the
jar it was so some of the best tasting
terp i have ever had in my life and it
was real
so yeah i'm chasing that um i know where
the terp is the cherry terp which is the
cherrygasm
we really love it uh a new one we have
is a nepali queen and nepali has this
really
hashy grapey old school
like old dope
you know when you went and bought a bag
of dank when you were kid that old funky
incense smell
so that's the nepali and that's one of
joel's man it's old clone that we
brought out
a new and lemon stilton are you kidding
me
he took jtr and he crossed it with the
cheese so you get the
thcv pain killing effect
with the pain killing effect of cheese i
don't know if you know this
but people who have rheumatoid arthritis
swear by cheese and i can't tell you why
scientifically i don't know
i know i know much old vets that are
beat [ __ ] and back and they love cheese
and so when you mix it with that jtr you
get an additional pain killing effect
thcv acts on the cb2 receptor the cb2
receptor is responsible for your
autoimmune system so if you can
stimulate the autoimmune system you can
help heal yourself and that's why thc is
so uh important and it's very rare and
since we discovered it and five percent
in the jack the ripper you see a lot of
people running jack the ripper looking
for a male in the hundreds of seeds
trying to find that that rare jtr male
yeah i can definitely agree on the
stimulating the immune system idea i'm a
big believer of that as well
so
i am interested to know do you have any
theories i think you may have said you
do on where those watermelon terps lie
because they seem to be the most kind of
the you know they're just being exposed
and i'm sure they're amazing i haven't
yet been able to try them where do you
think they come from genetically
i don't know but there's a strand called
goji and it tastes like watermelons and
i don't even know where it's at i just
this is uh internet research okay yep
and i gotta go try to find golgi i don't
i don't even know what it is or anything
about it but i understand it has a
watermelon tarp in it
but i will have to say something else
that's gonna stagger you i'm not
currently breeding
i moved here we have a very unique
program here
we have a numbers game so
right now i'm at 24 tuesday we get a
piece of card i get 36.
on thursday i go to 48 and eventually
we'll have 60 here but when we moved in
i can only have 12 plants which is why i
have [ __ ] eight giant plants in my
pool it's really simple
i couldn't grow
the number of plants that i would grow
in the pool so we grew big [ __ ]
plants i would imagine
unless the pool project is the most
successful experiment in life
those things will get torn down and
we'll go back to the standard four 10
gallon pots under a 1000 where we get
almost three pounds
but if you've seen the pool
we've employed these special cages
called grow efficient cages
steel frames five by five and this
gentleman says strain specific we can
get five pounds a piece
and that would be 40 units i'm skeptical
but if we get that we may just continue
growing the big trees indoors because
it's [ __ ] fun
so a lot of our viewers love to get the
kind of growers tips from our guests
a lot of our viewers also organic which
is going to work perfectly because you
know you're speaking to the the choir
what type of things do you like to
supplement your super soil plants with
you know you mentioned teas earlier what
are some general tips you might have for
us
so last year we started making our own
teas which we got great results from
that's kind of what we call a low till
so you have a super soil with a lasagna
tech lasagna texas crabmeal and alfalfa
and different things in between with a
cover crop
but we have teamed up with the dragonfly
earth nutrient company and um i have to
tell the whole story so in the old days
they sent me some and i didn't
i didn't take it serious i i joked
around oh hippy crap and i didn't take
it seriously i actually burned my plans
because i didn't pay attention
so when we we had them on the show and
they were such nice people i'm like well
these people are really nice people i
need to pay attention and stop being an
asshat so i paid attention and i got to
know their company and they sent us
uh a large amount of products and so
we're feeding the super soil now we've
been in veg
for god
14 weeks now
so yeah and this is not your standard
system so we've been using the luscious
green
and the flowers we also used the we did
fuller last night
which leads me to a crazy thing and i
won't get back to the tips but check
this out did you know that if you use
fuller spray
that your micros testing in a lab are
going to test above 10 000 and based on
new regulations in washington
oregon and colorado that would fail the
test for natural by the way cannabis
cannot be organic because organic is a
word of the fda it's a federal
term so there is no such thing as
organic cannabis
there's natural cannabis
and that's a real definition in there so
we really like the idea of using
beneficials but if you spray stuff on
your plants in certain areas you may not
pass the lab test because they can't
differentiate between bad microbes which
would be [ __ ]
and good microbes which would be like
basilius
that that's a really important point a
lot of people in those areas may not be
aware i guess maybe a question which
immediately jumps to mind is do you know
if there would be a rough cut off time
if you used it in veg it'd be okay just
don't use it in flour or buy a certain
week of flour stop using or do you think
it's just a bit unknown at this point
i wish i knew we we just learned this
i'm sounding awful smart because a lab
scientist stood there and talked to me
about 40 minutes just three days ago or
i wouldn't sound nearly as smart but
what we found out is some really good
cannabis that we looked at was testing a
90 000
jewels or jazz or whatever the hell it
was
and see if you thank you cfuz i thought
you smartered me
and um but it was good there's nothing
wrong with it but at 90 000 under these
new regulations it would immediately be
destroyed
so they don't understand the difference
between good beneficials and bad and i
think it's one of the things that the
weed nerd is you know i've been doing
shows on it i've been teaching the
growers and one of the things i can use
my platform is to send information out
so i've already been teaching the world
that they're trying to ban organic
growing because the simple solution to
not testing above 10 000 is to grow with
salts and cocoa and that's not the kind
of cannabis i smoke i prefer not to
smoke salts just all there is to it
so i'm i'm you know hugely passionate
about organics but a debate i'm
interested in is
if you got the absolute highest quality
produced salt grown and the highest
quality organic do you think do you
think they're on par or do you think
there's still a better because i
struggle with this personally i i've
from my personal experience i think the
absolute best salt grown it can be close
if not on par you know and that but but
it's i never see it you know i see it
like once once a year at the emerald cup
from one person soul growing is not easy
and not everybody does it right i can
tell you that long ago me and um
me and jill did a side by side she did
hydro and soil and she crushed me on
yield and we both agreed that the soil
grown pot tasted better both i mean it
was not it was like she got like eight
ounces and i got like three ounces
because they're playing oversized mine
it was just really fun cool experiment a
wonderful memory but in the end i mean
her body even looked better and had more
resin on it but in the end when you
smoked a bong hit
the [ __ ] in the dirt smoke better turn
white and disappeared
that's that's why a lot of people grow
soil and i haven't said that
scientifically there's no difference
but we both know there's something
symbiotic going on down there in the
soil and the roots and there's some kind
of harmony and some kind of hippie [ __ ]
going on there and that's why so many
people grow in soil
yeah i i totally agree and i um i don't
get into a lot of hippie [ __ ] but i get
into a lot of hippy [ __ ] around soil and
the benefits of like just even
interacting with it and stuff i think
it's real
one of the last things i wanted to ask
you about was the chernobyl line this
and especially the slimer clone has
gained a lot of popularity would you
consider ever working with it more
it's yeah i mean i actually have slimer
here and not only do i have slimer here
but we talked about earlier i have the
genetic rights to sell it it was
marketed under my own strength but the
story of slimers clarisse a guy named
coma found the clone and started yelling
slimer slimer slimer i never even had
the damn thing and it started showing up
in clubs and everything and then
somebody gave it to me and then there's
the golden ticket man these are just
phenotypes i i cannot buy into this
[ __ ] i mean there's one fino that
runs around called slimer i guarantee if
you caught a 10-pack you'd find another
one another 10-pack you'd find another
one it's just a genetic expression
yes it happens to make a lot of resin
but all chernobyl strains make a lot of
resin i mean
it's a strain called blood wreck and it
just it piles it out and i'm happy to
report that badger has the blood wreck
cut and the jack the ripper and he's
making chernobyl right now so
something that we really enjoy making um
is still around and what i would suggest
is if you are a grower to grow out a
10-pack and find your own slimer versus
something that somebody else selected
because we all have our own taste
and what someone likes you may not so
i've always been the growit and selected
guy to the point where even around here
the shops that the people around here
will not crack a pack of seeds they'll
come to sub's house and take some cuts
hey sub will you take a cut for us can
we have one of your cuts i was like
crack a pack of seeds and i can crack up
a 10 pack and find the best female in 50
days
it's just laziness that people don't do
it having said that i'll keep cracking
seeds and finding those winters and
putting them out on the street which is
what coma did and that's why you hear
about these things there's other ones
there's the watermelon fino of nine
pound hammer
there's the there's the marmalade fino
of jelly bean
there's the rubber tire pheno of agent
orange there's the god's [ __ ] pheno of
vortex there's the purple quirkle they
just the internet tends to put labels on
things and then people latch on to them
it's great stories
yeah okay
i certainly can uh echo that sentiment
of you know popping more seeds and
finding your own one because i i can
attest you know i found my own slime and
it's amazing
this basically brings us to the last
part of the interview where we do the
quick fire questions so first of all
what's your favorite strain right now
god that's hard
it's got it's got to be the jesus man i
mean
it's just it dumps so many crystals and
it does it so well it's got a great
inspiring high but that's an unfair
question
yeah
my favorite strength today is pineapple
express because john gave me three grams
of it
crystals it's just a list i my favorite
strain is cannabis man let me change
that answer that's a good answer
it really is i just love the [ __ ] i love
it all i really do so on the other end
of the spectrum what do you think is the
worst strain in your opinion that got
traction with the masses
wow that's a good one
that's really hard you know
i'm going to take a lot of heat for it i
have the hardest time finding a good
blueberry
i agree
i've grown five packs of the damn stuff
and i every time i say it you know dj
sun ty tax me and i ain't like that man
i read dj's book i love dj's book i
would love to grow a 10 pack and get me
a bomb ass blueberry do you believe me
i mean come on of course i do i just it
hasn't happened in my life so that's
that would be the one that you know i
see it everywhere and i see people with
it and for me four packs nothing
nothing so
yep
so if you could only smoke one land race
for the rest of your life what would it
be
apollo 13.
no sorry it's going to be a land race oh
a land race yeah well it makes a little
harder it's not my thing that's not
really my thing i mean i i i definitely
like um joel's uh i
i messed this up every time i say well
hawking you know o-a-x yeah i think
that's how you say it
it's wahawking but it's oxacan yeah
so i like it man we got a string called
pina rita that he made with that old
school colombian jesus man tastes like
peanut butter
i'm a hybrid guy i want the juice i want
the flavors and the terps
um i
was never a thai guy i was never a
jamaican guy i was never a lamb's red
guy
designer weed may be my thing i don't
know
so lucky last if you could go back to
any point in history you know whether it
be just within your life or within any
point in all of history and select any
seeds what would you get
i did
i did it i mean i had there's nothing i
haven't worked with i know it's a cheeky
answer there's nothing that i haven't
asked for gotten or worked with in my
life nothing the g13
calimus a13 c99 the killer queen
aka i know i'm happy i mean i'm i would
like to have the pinot noir back really
[ __ ] bad so if anybody has a line on
it i
would really really really like to have
it but
i pretty much have access to anything i
want and i
maybe the original northern lights you
know before it was adulterated so i
could actually maybe see what it was
like before it became five or whatever
but
even that one but i mean i smoked it and
worked with it you know so i guess i'm
saying i'm really happy with my life
it was a really good answer so i think
that probably just about brings us to
the end of it thanks so much for
stopping by and for dropping all the
knowledge and for all the history is
there any comments or shout outs you
wanted to make before we wrap it up
yeah i got a couple shout outs to make
i'd like to give a shout out to all the
people in my current crew i mean will
victoria i don't know what i would do
without these people will save my life
came to my house my house went down and
physically
put me in his car and brought me to his
house and put me on scotch i would have
nothing without that man
jen and joel on the north shore genetics
i lost every [ __ ] thing i owned every
seed every roach clip everything i own
and i went to jen and joel's after the
fire and i acquired the genetics i alone
and if it wasn't for that this company
would be gone i owe them a debt i can
never repay
and that's that's that
fantastic so again thanks so much for
coming and spending some time with us
awesome this was fantastic thank you
thank you for letting me address
directly just you know so much stuff
that swirls around my life and last
thing i say i'm a i make many mistakes
in my life my biggest one is i open my
mouth when i shouldn't but i'm a
passionate person i love this plant i
love my culture and i love all of you
[Music]
so there you have it folks
a big thank you for sub cool for taking
the time to come on the show again
and a big thank you to all you guys for
listening
big love to all our patreon fans these
guys are the lifeblood of the show if
you haven't checked out the patreon be
sure to go check it out there's going to
be a whole bunch of new content going up
there very soon as well as some prizes
[Music]
4 20 australia seeds here now ogs
love you guys
check them out
[Music]
we'll see you
la la la la
[Applause]
[Music]
lalalala
you