[Music]
[Applause]
well hello my friends and welcome back
for another episode of the PO
a cannabis podcast for budding
enthusiasts as always you're joined by
your boy heavy days here from the upside
down Library we want to give a massive
shout out to all of our incredible
sponsors who help ensure the show
continues to happen CED here now number
one seed bank in the industry all the
hottest breeders the latest drops
everything you can look for and more
whether you're after indoor outdoor
feminized regular autoflow they've got
everything under the sun to keep you
loaded on all the hottest gen ICS
producing the most fire Bud you've ever
had I hear they've got some incredible
lines from heavy days still in stock if
you want to go check that out make sure
to do it before it's too
late big shout out to CT now we
appreciate you so
much as usual a massive massive thank
you and shout out to our good friends at
copit biological if you want to harvest
the best crop to date you have to ensure
your garden is pest and pathogen free
pumping on all cylinders if you're
battling spidermites check out the
incredible spidex red likewise I know a
lot of you guys are battling AIDS at the
moment check out their apip parm this is
another product I absolutely stand
behind from copit if you want to get rid
of apids get rid of spidermites check
out the a parm check out the spidex red
big shout out to copit biological thank
you so much we appreciate your ongoing
support the final piece of the puzzle to
ensure that your room is killing it is
good friends at Pulse their sensors are
second to none industry-leading and just
recently they announced the pulse Hub
what more could you want an integrated
unit for all of your sensors to ensure
that your garden is automated and
tracking all of the variables you may
not be consciously aware of from VPD to
ppf dupoint temperature humidity so much
more you've got to get yourself a pulse
sensor guys it is revolutionized the way
I grow flour and increase the turpine
content the cannaboid content the year
build so so so much more shout out as
always to our friends at Pulse sensors
likewise if any of you guys have been
listening to the show you know that I am
passionate about helping people
transition to vaporized options if
they're considerate about their
respiratory health and for me dap are
the world leaders in this dap helped me
to transition from bongs to vaping and I
tell you what I've never looked back
their unit is the most potent the most
highly replicating of a bong hit I've
ever come across cross and through their
incredible munit I was able to
successfully get off bongs a few years
ago now truly one of the most Innovative
and interesting Vapes on the market
using a totally different design to
others you have found check these guys
out you will not be disappointed massive
shout out to dnat thank you so
much and last but not least we want to
give a massive shout out to the
incredible patreon gang without you guys
we could not continue to make episodes
if you want to get Early Access to
upcoming episodes exclusive content just
on the patreon including the likes of
mean Jean Bob hemp Hill bod triome
jungle so much more be sure to go check
out our patreon we give away genetics
every month to our supporters along with
artwork Vapes sensors so much more
please check out the patreon guys I
promise you you won't regret it you'll
get your money back in swag to helping
support us show you love thank you so
much to everyone from the patreon
[Music]
on today we're incredibly stoked to have
a man who wears many hat breeder of the
sage old school Amsterdam Legend one
half of the incredible bio agronomics
group with Rob
Clark so much
more we are stoked to be joined today by
the one and only Mojave
[Music]
Richmond Peter talk all things breeding
predictions for the
future old school
history of course some big sir
Legend and so much more so without
further
delay let's get into
it Al righty gang a massive welcome for
joining us for yet another episode and
on today we are extremely grateful to
have one of the biggest heads in the
community a californ native preserver of
the Big Sir holy weed co-founder of the
bio agronomics group with Rob Clark and
a connoisseur all around a big big
welcome to mve Richmond for joining us
today how you
doing hey doing great thanks for having
me oh look I am so grateful for you
joining us today and as usual I want to
start off by asking what have you been
smoking on
lately o um actually I've been triing
out some or I've been testing out some
trial selections from um a project last
year with um group Haze Valley up in
Watsonville we did some crosses they're
Sage times um it's actually Zeta times
Kim diesel so um it's Sage OG chem and
Diesel and these are the f2s um some of
the selections um that's what I've been
puffing on lately but the thing that
I've been really enjoying is this
Cambodian that came from Mel Frank um he
gifted me some seeds a few years back
and it's just super super nice like
really friendly all day approachable
just lovely
weed oh I'm I'm so so jealous I guess
like the first thing that jumps to mind
when I hear that is what sort of
qualities does a Cambodian bring because
I mean I I sadly haven't had a lot of
exposure and when I think about it the
only real call back to Cambodian I can
think of is you often heard about uh the
original C Mist seeds as like having
some amount of cambod in the maybe maybe
it was like sort of just Whispers but
maybe it was true but I'd love to hear
from you what's what's smoking a
Cambodian like and what sort of traits
and qualities does it bring to the table
in your
mind um well I can't say about the C
Mist I haven't heard that before but
definitely I think C Mist was one of the
most exotic and really just amazing Cult
of ours with Once also really
approachable just elegant High um
this Cambodian is really interesting um
Jim U Mel Frank Jim Goodwin Mel Frank
gave me these seeds a few years ago and
actually no first he gave me some flour
and it's you know narrow Leaf very
equatorial looking kind of similar um
minty SL spicy kind of Aroma um and this
one it had a really nice high really
nice effect but you know um Mel had
shared that you know you like yeah we
really like this and then he got it
analyzed and um it came back it was a
one:1 THC CBD which was really eye
openening for me because all the um I
typically don't like most CBD varieties
for one just you know my I guess um my
uh curiosity around CBD and whether how
effective it is and whether it's you
know modulating or you know mod you know
how it's impacting the overall High I
think is basically you know always been
my question in terms of you know how it
impacts THC but the the interesting part
here was that this was the first time I
had a onetoone variety that was
completely non Afghan derived it wasn't
ACDC Charlotte's Web um canonic from
that whole
pool so the overall profile was very um
narrow Leaf but it also had CBD so um
that kind of made me think about what
these one to ones were really like and
how much of the thing that I didn't like
about all the Wonder ones and the CBD
varieties as a whole was that they came
from this other pool with these other
traits in addition to being CBD because
I've never really been a big Afghan
consumer myself so that was interesting
but then and also it opened up the whole
discussion of whether you know is this
do I like do I like this Cambodian
because it's it's a one to one or do I
just like it because it's a low THC
variety because there's something about
you know these 10
12% THC varieties that are just
completely
approachable um compared to you know
higher THC varieties so but it's just
really nice it's really Pleasant smok's
really good and it's I'm just looking at
it right now and as it goes into later
into the fall it's putting on a lot of
really nice color so it's a nice
plan wow the I mean so many cool little
TP in there I mean first of all to to
get an equatorial that's putting on some
nice color I mean I always say to people
that it's a bit of a rarity to see that
which is really really interesting but I
want to probe a little bit deeper
quickly cuz I'm interested to go down
that line of thought about how it is a
like you know lower cannaboids so to
speak and there is the onetoone
component and yet it's still really
interesting and I think I share that
sort of thought you expressed about like
wondering over the years what is the CBD
actually doing is it is it just bringing
the high down like in a sort of in a in
a way that I'm not looking for peray um
but I'd love to hear your thoughts on
why do you think it's just that the fact
that like it's offering this unique
effects so the cannaboids don't need to
be so Sky High and as a bit of a
followup I've I've asked people for a
long time why is it that like land
Racers generally speaking don't have a
ceiling or less likely to you know a lot
of the modern strains you smoke them all
day and you sort of only get so far uh
but some of these older varieties
especially you know the one people talk
about is like Hayes and taii Mexican
some of the components of hay they're
like man you just you keep smoking it
you keep getting higher and higher and I
almost felt like you were sort of
getting to that point when you were
describing the Cambodian i' I'd love to
hear why do you feel that like some of
these uh land race varieties or more raw
sort of genetic building blocks have
that ability what what do you think
we've lost when we get to a point where
OG can't do
it well that well that's a really good
point and there's let me just back up
and just say that I when I say A
Cambodian variety you know nobody you
know there's there's level there's
degrees of um of you know how sure are
you that something is really what it's
supposed to be in terms of you know
germplasm right it's it came from
Cambodia that I can
I can say and the person who sourced it
got it from someone that they trust but
that doesn't mean that it has a whole
bunch of other things in there and maybe
that CBD component and the color
component came from Modern weed that has
been in Cambodia for decades so it's
always really hard to know um what you
know what really is you know and and
it's Cambodian derived and it has
Cambodian influence and it came from a
Cambodian grower and that's all we can
really say about most modern germplasm
right um we we want you know I mean and
and hopefully through genomic work you
know we could you know we could un
unravel a little bit more of that but
it's still hard to do because we lost a
lot of the original data to reference
all the original reference points um but
uh and this on the the potency and the
ceiling thing I mean I don't know I just
you you know there's there's something
about how certain varieties burn burn
you out kind of is what I've always
noticed like certain things you need
like this recovery period and some I
mean someone once hypothesized that that
was like a hydroxy 11 thing that
overtime you're going to build up
hydroxy 11 in your system and you're
going to feel tired and lazy from just a
large dose of THC running through your
blood I don't know if that's it or if
it's an aroma profile thing something to
do with the Entourage but early on in in
my life I noticed that certain varieties
if you smoke them before another
variety um specifically you know like
more Afghan leaning things versus more
quote unquote sativa leaning that it
kind of like if you smoke um and this
this was my experience specifically with
like sage and OG um is that if you
smoked OG first it was really hard to
feel the effect of the sage afterwards
and it wasn't because there wasn't
enough potency in this age it was just
because there was something to the
effect of this other plant that put up
like a barrier and you can't you you the
only thing you can do to crush through
that barrier is to kind of reset maybe
your your um receptors so that they can
accept something new but it generally
takes time right like you you know
that's why people smoke cannabis in the
morning they got that wake and bake is
because they got that fresh you know
receptor um you know effect so I've
always wondered if there was something
in these other varieties that have no
ceiling quote unquote No ceiling in that
the the onset of the effect and the way
you're accumulating it in your body just
never creates this big wall that you
can't get through so you can keep kind
of stacking and stacking on it because
it's an uplifting you know all those
varieties that were quote unquote
seiling lless you know they are tend to
be you know uplifting varieties um so
they got a little bit more of that so um
you're not having to break through the
fog you know so to speak of something
that really puts you out but um but
there's also there is some kind of
common effect you know and i' one
interesting thing that I've notic is
that people at times have assumed that
some of the cultiv ours that I've um
developed or presented are lower potency
than they
are that like oh this feels like a 177%
variety where they're actually like
25% because it's such a different
feeling that people are assumed to
because like and racy varieties you know
are like racy and uplifting until
they're not right and then they're
harder to perceive versus just something
that just puts you in your chair um so
it's like uh yeah I I don't know it's
it's I think it's puzzling and but
there's but there's so much more to
potency I think is the real question
here is like what is potency we really
don't have a handle on it because it's
not just like alcohol where you can
drink um two or three you can drink a a
5% beer you can drink four of those and
or you can drink two 10% beers and
you're going to have the same effect but
with can there seems to be some type of
a Time duration thing where the onset of
the effect is going through this kind of
this Arc and what you put on it after
that is also having an impact so it's
not just a simple as stacking the
potency you would the way you would with
like ethanol so like what all the other
compounds that are in play are shaping
the effect of that you know the whatever
it is that is potency so I mean to me
that that that's that's why you know you
you hear people smoking sativas in the
morning and indicas at night is because
it's not just because sativas are
appropriate for morning which they they
are because they're less lethargic and
you know sleepy and disassociative but
it's also that you can keep smoking
sativas through the day and then in the
night with indicas and you still have
kind of a functioning
effect whereas if you smoke heavy
indicas all day and then you turn to
that sativa that beautiful C Mist
elegant high at night it like it doesn't
cut through you know you you've got
you've got to like you got like cut
through with like a a a chisel you know
to get through the wall that you put up
and um and maybe that chisel was
increasing the potency and that's why
people you know smoke Dabs and all this
other stuff because it's like you're now
forcing the high but when you're when
your tolerance is fairly low um
obviously you need less but um it's just
anyway I I guess back to the to the the
ceiling thing I I don't think we even
know we can't even look at what a
ceiling is until we really address what
potency is and that's that's just so so
complicated right totally look you given
me so many good Avenues I could I could
dive off into and I guess the the the
first one I wanted to ask you is it's
sort of like a twof folder but the first
one is I'd be interested to hear how
your relationship with tolerance and
smoking might have changed over time I
certainly am going through a bit of a
transitionary phase as I was mentioning
to you a bit earlier like I've got some
kids now so I find like I'm pretty
consistently not smoking until later in
the day and then through doing that as
you were just talking about you know
your tolerance changes significantly and
then for me personally I found myself
enjoying these strains that I used to
think were kind of a bit tame maybe back
when I was smoking you know more heavy
chem stuff From Dawn till Dusk so I'd
love to hear you know how has your sort
of relationship with tolerance changed
over time and as a follow on and this is
probably the one where there's a bit
more meat on the bone but we often hear
people talk about being really fond of
strains in the old days and they'll say
look I had this cut of let's just for
for just easy discussion sake we say
look I have this uh this purple urle I
used to grow it all the time it was the
dopest stuff ever and then nowadays I
grow it same cut it's definitely not a
different cut and uh it's just not
hitting the same but like I swear to God
it was really good and put aside all the
other factors that could be at play I
guess what I'm wondering is is people
talk about this idea of like well why
why did it seem so much better back 20
years ago ago and one of the reasons we
hear people talk about is that maybe it
was the case that you know on average
the weed wasn't as good so like you'd go
through these periods where you'd have
not the best weed and then so when you
did get something good like it was
really memorable but then nowadays when
you grow that same thing it doesn't
really strike you as particularly
memorable to me that's one of the best
explanations I've heard you know like
I'm sure that if you were smoking brick
weed when you got anything that was half
good you know it' be quite memorable but
at the same time I'd love to hear your
thoughts on why do you think that has
changed you know are strains getting
weaker are we just used to Stronger
stuff how is our relationship with
tolerance evolved as a
community that is a fantastic question I
think it's really important because you
know we are coming out of prohibition
and we are reintroducing ourselves to
cannabis in a big way on a global scale
and you know how people consume
substances is relevant you know whether
it's coffee or alcohol or sugar or
cannabis right um I have a particularly
long relationship with consuming
cannabis I would say I mean I'm 54 years
old and I've probably been consuming for
55 years um just because I grew up in a
world where cannabis was already
normalized and it was always
around um and but that being said it
wasn't always potent it wasn't always
around um it was always there but not in
the quantities that most consumers
wanted it to be in or in the potency or
the quality so we are now having this
Renaissance of availability and I and I
do think that that has shaped our
tolerance in a big way that even us you
know people who always had access or
relative amount of access never could
just turn to the left and open a jar of
some of the finest grown amazing
genetics in the world anytime they want
you know so we've all we've all upped
our tolerance for sure you know and that
has changed the way a classic cultivar
works the way you remember it because
none of us and you know we've also
increased our our our skill as a um
cultivators so I mean I'm looking back
at Sage that I grew 30 years ago and
thinking about how I grew it and under
what kind of gear and what type of
environmental controls and thinking like
wow what would what would that have been
like if I could grow that same plant
today right now you know would have
expressed itself higher or what um but
that also expressed higher in what
that's also back to the the potency
thing but um but I do think cannabis has
been potent for a long time I do think
that I don't think that
we've I think there's this conception
that we've bred higher potency
cannabis that as an industry that we've
kind of Franken that this Franken weed
that we've our lab breeders went down in
the underground and we took 6% cannabis
that was you know what they were saying
based off of seizures that you know we
took it and wrote it up to 30% I think
that's a fallacy and a misconception
about how modern potency works that to
me in even in in land race based
populations if you went through enough
seeds you'd find outliers of all
different potency ranges right and some
of the the outliers that impacted modern
cannabis are pretty old and and arguably
not even that far from their land race
um source so bag seed that was imported
crossed a couple times and then seeds
reproduced right not decades and Decades
of of um
of breeding right and remember back in
the day we didn't grow or breed indoors
we did it seasonally so you only had one
selection a year so it it we didn't
basically to me what happened is that
the we we learned how to clone and when
people selected really potent
cultivars we saved them and then we
shared them with the world and in doing
that we shared High potency THC
genes you know that that that whatever
that THC synthes you know ramped up
however you know to the world but is
that breeding or is that selection or is
that distribution is that you know
disseminating founder cultivars that
brought those traits we didn't take 6%
THC and make it seven then eight then 10
then 12 then 14 then 20 then 22 then 24
it was people found boom whoa that stuff
is amazing it's potent and they shared
it with everybody so then everybody had
material to use breeding material to use
to ramp up their potency and that wasn't
through breeding that was through
cloning and sharing
clones in in my opinion that's the way I
I saw it and I mean I know that the sage
that was tested in
1998 tested at 21 point something per
THC um and that stuff was you know my
breeding effort wasn't a big giant you
know project it was me making a few
selections from things that you know
were either in the ecosystem and also
things that I brought back from from
Cali but it you know I'm just saying 30
years ago we had 20 plus per clones that
were going around and in my experience
growing cannabis over I mean consuming
cannabis throughout my whole life is
that every now and then you encountered
some flower that knocked you out but
just really strong and another thing
that is really sometimes overlooked
about you know um potency and people
waxing poetic about the flower they
smoked in the past is that in a a pound
of cannabis in the 70s and 80s and 90s
for one it was almost all grown from
seed but it wasn't one plant if you got
a pound of cannabis or multiple you know
large amounts of can it was homogenized
batches of a bunch of different seed
plants so you could have a 100 different
plants in one batch all mixed so you
weren't if you if someone a consumer
bought an ounce of cannabis at the dead
lot before clones were going
around that 1 ounce could have had
multiple um you know plants in it some
of them were incredibly potent and some
of them weren't so it was always this
kind of weird like every now and then
you'd have this potent experience with
cannabis and just go like oh my god do
you remember that time we smoked that
one thing and and I do believe that
those were potent varieties and they
were probably also very high in THC but
you didn't
get five pounds of cannabis from someone
in the 70s 80s and 90s that was all the
same 25% THC clone grown the same you
know beautifully cared for so to have
that consistent potent experience was
really rare even even when you had good
flour you were still fishing through you
know the the PO Perri or the mage of all
the different seed plants so just you're
just the ability to like in interact
with that much consistent High potency
quality cannabis is super super new I
mean I would argue it's only 5 to 10
years old for most of the world I mean
even in California you know 20 years ago
you there was really amazing flower but
it wasn't always everywhere and it
wasn't always grown really well so I
mean we're we're we're definitely in
this new new um realm of what is you
know what our tolerance levels are and
what what our consumption habits should
be in order to reflect our tolerance you
know to consume it both in it's safe and
productive but also to get the most
benefit
and I think that's really what the
tolerance discussion kind of speaks to
is where does the most benefit for the
consumer lie because that really when
you have a high tolerance and you do
small amounts you it's very potent um
but you are consuming less and you could
argue that you know consuming more of
that substance might be beneficial for
you for whatever reasons for pain relief
or stress or or you know um inflammation
or whatever if it's a medicinal reason
or if it's just you know um wanting to
have a higher tolerance so that you
don't have any of the um um the negative
side effects associated with cannabis
and that's definitely something that you
could say that people who consume more
can consume more where people who
consume less have to be very careful
about when they're consuming because it
can really knock you
out yeah totally totally I mean I can I
can so deeply relate to what you just
said as I was uh sort of explaining my
my own relationship with consumption and
tolerance is changing and you know gosh
I tell you what I I feel the munchies
these days in a way that I didn't not so
long ago and it's it's it's so
interesting because your own personal
relationship with cannabis can often cuz
we are you know we are so far in like
the top one percentile of consumers I
often say like you know anyone listening
to this show right now like you're in
the top 1% all like no one else is going
to listen to this and it it can become
very um like atypical I guess what I
realized when I took a tolerance break
recently was that I became extremely
lazy like basically I would I'd get home
from work and want to do something and
I'd just be like Oh I'm tired and then I
realized in those moments I would smoke
a sativa and have the energy to go do
that thing and I thought it was such an
interesting sort of observation because
you know so often the conversation is
like oh oh you know Stoners no
motivation no energy and and in that
moment I realized I was actually the
opposite I was finding myself more lazy
without it but I mean that sort of
brings us to the discussion about
sativas and I'm someone who used to not
be able to consume them I would just get
so
anxious and then I don't honestly know
when but at some point I sort of just
checked back in this is over the course
of years I checked back in and I sort of
felt like I could ride that horse a
little better and now we're at the point
and all of our listeners will know where
I I just love it it's my favorite
sativas what I'd love to ask you as
someone who's got you know a rich and
wide experience with a range of sativas
including many of the building block
land races that we're all so you know
Keen to
try how do you think we can help expose
a wider audience to the beauty of
sativas because part of me thinks that
uh a lot of people a aren't aware of the
creative and stimulative and you know
all these unique effects that sativas
bring you know so often people are like
well I just thought it was sedating how
do we how do we get the message out
there and as as we've sort of been
talking you know it doesn't need to be a
28% OG it could be a 15% sativa and
it'll it'll take you somewhere totally
different how do we try to get that
message out there or how do we just
raise awareness in
general um well Ju Just and and just I
have to say for my for my taxonomy
Brethren and stuff that you know um for
for really this is for you rob um
cannabis indicia subspecies indicia
right we're talking about narrow Leaf
varieties and that we colloquially call
sativa um but I think it's important I
think it's I think and I also you know I
love the word sativa so I'm happy to I
think it's a great you know it's it's
part of the the you know we the word
strain as opposed to Cult of art
sometimes you just have to accept that
it doesn't really have to have the the
science the meaning behind it for it to
have the impact right and so I love
using the word sativa again more and
more um but
um if you think about what people wanted
cannabis to be like what
and I know that I'm going to like go
deep down in the rabbit hole of you know
humanity and you know our relationship
with this plant um because it is a weird
one right you know the the
endocannabinoid system was in us it was
in our family tree before it was in the
plants family tree right it we it goes
back further in in animals than it does
in plants so it's kind of cool how we
how we met um but if you look at all
cannabis around the world you know up
until
before um before the 80s really it was
mostly these narrow Leaf varieties these
kind of Equatorial tropical varieties
you know if you think about Thai Thai
cannabis and you know um Indian and um
you know Vietnamese Cambodian um African
South African you know Mala um Tanzania
um you think of South America you know
Colombia and Panama and Mexico and
Jamaica and you think of all these
places and all these selections that
happened over a long amount of time sure
they all I'm sure came from somewhat of
a narrow gene pool because it was an
export commodity as well but people were
selecting cannabis to be something for a
long time right and they were working
within whatever population they had but
these populations are dynamic
and there's the ability to move the
needle left or right and kind of steer
the selection how you want it steer the
gene pool and for whatever reason they
steered it towards these you know
electric uplifting psychedelic soaring
energizing um varieties that were also
potent and had you know all lots of
other attributes too but that is kind of
what we think of these varieties as for
being these sativas you know these
narrowly
varieties and if you think about how the
the other class the the Afghan the
indicia um chemotype if that's
appropriate and I'm not a scientist or
anything so I forgive me if I you misuse
any terms um I'm just kind of an
observer and I hang out with a lot of
cool scientists so I have been gifted
some cool knowledge but um if you think
about how that entered the gene pool um
at least from my perspective you know
growing up in California and having
family that grew cannabis in Big Sur for
instance is that Afghan gave them the
ability to grow a shorter plant that um
that they could hide um in the brush it
gave them the ability to grow an earlier
flowering plant that they could Harvest
before um you know some climate issues
but also Harvest before initially
Harvest before Camp came and started
seizing plants and it gave a variety
that you could grow indoors which was
also about evading law enforcement um it
gave you a variety that was more potent
you know but it wasn't about people
weren't going in my experience like oh
wow the effects of this new um this new
Afghan stuff is so amazing we now want
to feel this way it wasn't like all the
Breeders and Growers were select in for
these new
traits they were they were happy with
the sativas they were growing before and
they just took on all these new traits
because they were agronomically friendly
they helped evade law enforcement blah
blah
blah um and it's important to kind of to
draw the comparison between all these
traditional Farmers around the world
that grew and smoked flour versus um a
hash producing region like
Afghanistan so if you're you know a
small farmer you know growing your your
small plot of cannabis or just Grows by
you wherever and You observe an amazing
plant um and you consume that plant as
CIA or as
flow um and the seeds fall out you go
wow that's amazing flower I'm going to
keep these seeds and I'm going to grow
it again next year right that's just
that's how Farmers work so you're cting
from an individual
plant so you get to interface with the
plant you get to you get to consume the
plant and then you get to decide whether
it fits in with what you want where you
your expectations were and then you grow
with it or you breed with it or you
continue down that line but in a hash
making culture like in Afghanistan they
don't consume individual plants you know
or I imagine it happens very rarely so
you're taking a whole field and you're
homogenizing that and then you're going
through you're you're drying it in the
sun and then you're aging it and then
you're sving it and agitating it and
then you're pressing it often with heat
and then you're drying it some more and
then you're consuming it so your only
real selections are for like resin
content and like you know higher yields
of API of you know that that active
ingredient that you're putting into your
hash so you're not selecting for
individual plants so you're never
selecting for those individual
traits and you're not selecting for
individual plant traits you're selecting
for
hash you know
so we kind of snuck in all these genes
and all these traits and all this
chemistry and compounds and things and
into our gene pool really quickly
worldwide and I'm just I question why we
did that you know
because it it wasn't necessarily just
for their for the
effect and then at the same time because
they these hybrids and stuff were so
much more agronomically valuable really
than these narly varieties just because
how the yield and all the sativas fell
out of favor because they couldn't
compete but it wasn't on
effect and then we slowly turned into
just a complete completely different
cannabis consuming culture you know um
and now I mean I I don't you know it's I
guess it's just it's um anecdotal to say
that at the same time that modern
cannabis exploded out of prohibition we
are in a weird disassociative State as a
as a people around the world people are
more Tapped Out than ever um people are
also more anxious than ever they don't
need to have any anxiety induc ing
substances in their lives um so and
there's I mean if you look at opioid
crisis and all this stuff you know
people maybe in some weird way I hate to
think it's this this is true but in some
weird way as we're now we were Shifting
the gene pool away from these narrowleaf
varieties into this hybrid model we were
also
shifting what the drug was being used
for which was no longer about
celebration and insightfulness and mind
expansion and Community it was about
accommodating a new culture of people
who were tapped out and disassociated
and need to just be numb as much as
possible you know and then when you do
introduce sativas to people and they do
sometimes have a negative um
reaction I mean maybe that's part of of
the symptom of you know why is it why is
it hitting that vein now in our lives in
ways that it didn't before
um and and I mean that is I mean if that
is one of the inherent risks with with
cannabis use is you know that you people
can it can they can have negative side
effects but it's also the risk of a lot
of other therapeutic
substances um it doesn't mean that they
don't have value it just means you have
to proceed cautiously so I kind of feel
like when we when people have a negative
effect from assuming a sativa that spins
them out and they have like a slight
panic attack or they have that Tac
cardia thing they create these
associations with that negative moment
that carry on into their regular
consumption where if you were just a
little bit more mindful or maybe you
know your set and setting wasn't right
or you just accept that hey [__] happens
in life then you can continue to consume
these sativas because they do deliver
this other thing you know and like you
said earlier you know um if you think
about how people's lives were in the
past when what what what they needed
cannabis to be for them you know and not
30 years ago but 300 years ago you know
you you people don't have the luxury to
just sit around and do nothing you know
life happens you've got to get out there
you got to go on the hunt you've got to
go and forage for food you've got to go
and collect firewood you've got to dance
all night long and celebrate and worship
and do all the far out things that being
human is so I think people were
selecting plants that facilitated that
in their life and if you took that out
of their
lives then there's no need for that
anymore right so so what are we having a
discussion about why we should have
sativas in our life is probably also a
reason for why we should have all the
other things sativas so you know
accommodate or or you know um go side by
side with but yeah I'm I'm a big fan I
am and and you know I really I I think
cannabis can be a lot of things for a
lot of people um and that's the beauty
of it that's what makes it so
complicated and complex and interesting
but like you like you you mentioned the
the 1% it's like but cannabis is for
everybody it's just the one % that is so
involved in shaping what
everybody sees cannabis as or or or you
know delivering cannabis to the
99% so it's like we have this
responsibility almost like an ethical
responsibility to help them get to the
right place right which is to me is
really important because
we if you think about if every everyone
was consuming more sativas versus more
hybrids and more you know Afghani
varieties people's lives would be
different what that means who knows but
it does mean it would be different
because like you said you'd get up and
go do the cleaning you'd get [__] done
you
know yeah no it's I mean I before I
forget first point apologies Rob for the
uh incorrect
nomenclature it's it's it's such a
conundrum isn't it because I always
think to myself well I use the word
sativa because I'm just wanting the
person I'm talking to to understand like
you know we're using the same term
essentially and then you think oh okay
so what really I'm saying is is when a
majority of people adopt the new
nomenclature then I'll do it because
then we'll be talking the same language
so to speak and then so then I feel
guilty and I'm like oh so I'm not being
part of the
solution um but anyway we'll uh we'll
get there one day my apologies but um I
I guess just to continue that train of
thought a bit more forward I I wanted to
ask you um like how do you see the mode
of delivery of cannabis as because you
were talking about how the way in which
we've consuming it and the the needs
have changed over say 300 years which
undeniably true and I guess just over
the next like 50 years like I can't help
but feel like I don't want to say like
it's following the path of alcohol but
in a certain sense we're seeing like the
The more mass appealing more economical
option in this space you often hear
people saying like look it seems
undeniable The Vape patterns are sort of
filling that space and heck even I meet
people all the time who like were not
really cannabis people who have now got
a vape pen so handy so discreet all
these beneficial things and I guess what
It ultimately leads me wondering is is
it going to be like what I fear cuz as
as like a breeder myself I I fear that
loss of genetic diversity and you know
we we all fear this but I I worry that
it's going to become like wine where
it's like we narrow ourselves down to
like these 40 or so accepted varieties
and even within those 40 there's just
like five that get used most of the time
and I can't help but feel we're
following down that same path where you
know OG's shard and Run's cab saav and
just with those two alone you've covered
a huge swath of consumers in terms of
they're like yep I'll happily take that
um and I know obviously it's a bit of a
stretch in terms of an analogy but I
think there are some elements that are
you know
comparisons uh I I'd love to hear what
what's your thoughts on the future
delivery and do you think we might
follow a similar model where we get to
this point where it is just a small
handful of accepted ver
Idols well I think I mean the one thing
that's always going to be different for
cannabis and and wine is wine all the
diversity in wine is just around flavor
and
Aroma it's all just
ethanol so there's no chemical diversity
in terms of the drug side of wine you
know maybe a little bit you could argue
that you know some some different types
of alcohol have a slightly different
effect whether it's whiskey or vodka or
wine or beer um there's obviously a lot
going on there's a lot of chemistry
there but the main driver is one single
thing so cannabis will always be more
complicated than that in that there's a
lot of
drivers um to to to create this effect
which we still don't fully understand
but I think the the issue is and why I
do think it will follow like wine and I
think it'll follow like a lot of other
products or commod agricultural
Commodities is that you can't create a
functioning supply chain with that much
diversity and so so it's like it's not
about the diversity in the gene pool
it's about the diversity in the supply
chain which ultimately means the
selection of the
consumer right so there's this whole
Paradox of choice thing where if you
give people too many choices they can't
make a selection analysis paralysis
where it's just like I don't know what
to choose because it's just I just see
too many stars it's like picking out a
star in the Milky
Way and I think that with cannabis more
than any other crop especially
considering it's the top crop you know
in a state like California or in the US
you know is that the farmer has to pick
from thousands of cultivars essentially
um and the distributor has to decide
what to purchase the retail has to
describe you know decide what to put on
the shelf and then the consumer has to
decide what to purchase um and it's like
there's you it just it it crashes the
whole system falls apart and then the
other thing is like and the farmer has
to do this every cycle every or every
year it's because it keep keeps changing
there's no Foundation to grow on there's
no like people don't grow the same Cult
of our four years in a row in four
different places in the US in order to
have like agronomic data on how it grows
well or to you know to you know even for
breeding to exist like breeding you know
improving crop Improvement is about you
you got to select the crop first and
then improve it you know if you spend
five years breeding a cultivar that
nobody wants anymore then that you know
so so that to me is the issue is like
you know you want to maintain the
diversity in the gene pool and you want
to make sure that you always have the
ability to Pivot and all the the
complexity and all the chemistry is
represented in the gene pool but at the
same time you want to drive products to
the consumer in a way that meets their
needs and demands right and while doing
that you want to create a functioning
supply chain so that the farmer can feed
their family and the retail Shop is open
and everyone's doing well so how do you
do that without um limiting
diversity to me it's about creating the
lanes of you know these kind of bulk
Lanes of what cannabis can be um in
terms of their
chemistry um which is really hard and
really complicated because that requires
you know the consumer to learn about all
these things just like we're to the
point that we mentioned before about
sativas you know um but that to me is
the only way to really create a
functioning supply chain I mean I hear
that these words cultivar dependent so
much as a disclaimer in our industry for
like oh the reason we couldn't you know
we can't tell you what the light recipe
for these you know this with these LED
lights because it's cultivar dependent
or we can't tell you you know what the
nutrient you know schedule should be or
whether this is susceptible to powdery
mildew in this region or not because
it's cul of our dependent or we can't
tell you you know so we can't really
build this bigger functioning supply
chain and the last thing we want to do
is end up with limited diversity and
like you know um Rob and I have written
we write we have a column in cannabis
business times called um um growing
pains and it kind of highlights a lot of
the challenges of like these
Transitions and you know you see you saw
in like in apples for instance apples
are also a clonally produced um very
heterozygous crop and the diversity in
apples was just narrowed and narrowed
and narrowed and narrowed to the point
where we just had like Granny Smith and
red delicious and you know a few other
apples were just like that's like you
have a green apple and you have a red
apple and because they need to be these
things they need to be they need to
transport well they need to be shelf
stable and you know resistant to pests
and blah blah blah so they narrowed the
genan pool to the point where you know
people demanded a better Apple and now
you know we see this big you know
emerging Apple breeding industry where
we've got all these amazing Fuji and
honey crisps and all these really groovy
apples of today but that was because a
stepped in and said no we need to dumb
things down and simplify it so that we
can create the supply chain that
functions so we need we do need to do
that with cannabis because we do need to
you know we do I mean especially for the
farmer I think you know and the consumer
really is the the two people that move
Miss out the most the consumer is not
getting the chemistry that they could
because they're not getting access to
the plants the diversity of what the
chemical profile could could be because
they're getting so much of you know
Limon Cherry gelato or you know or so
much a blue dream or whatever it is um
but the grower the farmers really you
know just can't build a robust model of
production when they constantly are
chasing their tail for like I don't know
what I don't know what to grow next
season that's going to sell you know and
um so yeah it it's that that to me is
and I I think that there's probably like
a fixed to
number in terms of like what that
analysis paralysis number is for all
crops where you can have a huge amount
of diversity in rice or you can have a
huge amount of diversity in some other
crop but in each individual Market you
can't um like I'll give an example and
this might I don't know this might be
even going down the hole too much but
years ago
a friend had this idea of doing a um a a
cannabis bird book um that we would kind
of copy the oton society's bird book for
consumers so that they could learn about
the different varieties of different
cultivars and they could go to
dispensaries and they would know what
you know just like a a someone who buys
a bird book could grabs orb oculars and
goes to the park and they can spot a
bird and after we started doing a little
research just like 10 years ago or so
started to do a little research and I
started to compile some stuff and I
started to go wait a second for one
people don't even agree on what the name
of the bird is and then every dispensary
you go to just like every Park you go to
there's a whole bunch of different birds
and you don't see those birds at the
other Park you know so you go to one
dispensary and you learn these 10
varieties that are amazing oh I love
these then you go to another like how
come you guys don't have any of those
you know or they just renamed them to
something else you know so the consumer
is just completely out of the loop and
is can't ever figure out what is a house
finch or what's a red tail hawk or what
anything is because
we've over complicated things we've
almost sold the dream of the feno hunt
and the whole unicorn searching thing to
the consumer as
well um so that prevents the supply
chain on their side ever from developing
so they can't become the informed
consumer where at least in wine which
you're totally right I mean here in
California I think the numbers are
exactly the same where like maybe even
two or three varieties produce the bulk
of the whole state but the consumer
learns the different appellations the
consumer learns the different varieties
the consumer learns a bit and they over
time learn where their preferences are
and that that's once again that's just
for aroma that's just for mouth feel and
sugar content and um it's not it's a lot
easier for someone to be a wine snob
than to be a a weed snob um but they do
learn and it takes time it took a lot a
long time for you know the the French
and Italian wine industry to to create
that culture and that knowledge base it
took California a long time to do that
so it's going to take a long time but
the main thing is to build that consumer
base that really has that ability to say
like this is what I want you know they
have to experience it so it means
everyone's got to kind of step up and
take some risks to actually present
unique chemistry unique um plant you
know Aroma profiles all that stuff and
not just you
know dumb down to the lowest common
denominator which is you know I I hate
to say it but you know we're in this
weird candy gas world where you know
dessert flavors sell really easy and
maybe even just because they your mind
thinks of dessert before you consume it
or whatever you know it's just you're on
a totally different path um so we need
to figure out how to get brands that can
kind of like cultivate and curate and
experience for the consumer so the
consumer becomes informed and the
consumer drives the Breeders and cultiv
cators to continue to provide the
products that they demand um that that
to me is like the only way to bring you
super long-winded way to bring back
sativas for one is because you know
unlike Amsterdam in the 90s you know the
Dutch the Dutch coffee shops they would
pay you more for a sativa and they'd pay
you more for organically grown because
they knew you as a grower it cost you
more to grow something that was longer
flowering and lower yielding you know so
but they knew they had to have it on the
on the on the menu so they did it and
that's why even today I bet you it's
probably an artifact of that in
Amsterdam there's more Haze varieties
than there is in
California I mean Haze is still all over
Amsterdam you know last I checked it's
still there and and like try to walk
into dispensaries in LA and get piff and
Super Silver Haze and original Haze and
Neville's Haze and five hazes and like
it's just not around cuz people don't
grow it CU people won't pay what it
takes to grow a you know 14 to 20 week
plant that yields less than the eight or
nine we
plant totally totally so many really
good points there I I want to quickly
follow up with with with what you just
said in mind what do you think is the
future of hom growing what do you think
it'll look like as time goes on because
I mean at the moment the trajectory
seems that more and more sort of small M
and pop businesses getting pushed out of
the market and just as a general
sentiment like I don't have figures at
my disposal to quote but like it seems
like less and less people are growing as
time goes by to a certain extent um and
bigger operations are popping up in
their place what does the future of
homegrown look like to you and as a
followup do you think that homegrown
will still lead the way in the sort of
changing Market innovation of like
strain popularity because I think that
there's still a strong argument to be
made that everything up until now has
all relatively speaking come from the
smaller grows like especially if you
look at like mac and then onto run and
of course all the OG and all that was
all in garages but like I guess you know
nowadays you could say well the popular
thing at the moment is kind of like the
rs11 and that sort of stuff and I think
you could still make a small argument
that that stuff even though those guys
do have a little bit more room at their
disposal it's it's still not glass house
you know it's not like that sort of
thing so from my point of view all the
new strains that take the market by
storm come from the small Growers and
that's kind of what you were saying in
the last answer and that they're
expressing this is what we want like the
effects and what not do you think that
that will continue or do you think at
some point big facilities will take over
and start bringing cuz you know
surprisingly we haven't seen a clone
take over the market where it's like
this was found at Glass House in a 1
million seed finger hunt or whatever um
I know a bit of a complex question but
I'd love to hear your
thoughts uh well I think plant plant
people are weird like that and that I
mean you know I grow a bunch of
different you know I don't have a a you
I just ran a house here in in um Ventura
County and but I remember last year I
sat down with my kids and we cro we had
35 different edible plants grown in the
backyard and some of them were really
scraggly and just surviving and and I
remember we had like six different types
of tomatoes and there's more tomatoes in
the backyard than there at the grocery
store variety wise right and you know
like a bigger more diverse variety of
tomatoes and and like when I go I used
to go to this little uh Nursery in West
LA um that had all these amazing
Tomatoes I'll use that as an example
because tomatoes also were heavily you
know um
bottlenecked um and all these varieties
I've never even heard of I've never
heard their name they look interesting
they got Stripes some of them are round
some of them are pearshaped some of them
are orange some of them are yellow some
of them are purple some are black you
know and you realize like there's a
whole whole world of tomato breeders and
tomato enthusiasts in this Horticultural
side that it's always going to be there
right and and then over the years you
started to see those varieties slowly
pop up in the market you saw heirloom
tomatoes come back you know for years
people used to think oh we can't afford
to grow heirlooms because they they
don't transport well and they don't you
know last that long and who's going to
pay you know $4 a pound for a tomato
when they can get them for a dollar or
two and it's like well there's lot of
people who will pay $4 a for tomatoes if
they're really good and so I think
there's this kind of like this plant
hobbyist passion thing that keeps the
genetic diversity going and luckily a
lot of those guys still even they even
work for commercial grows you know like
you meet plenty of Growers who have
insane amount of diversity in their home
and all this weird stuff that they could
never grow commercially because their
boss wouldn't ever let them do that
um but that's not going to stop them you
know um and and I do think that that
that that that that's encouraging and I
I that's you know and I say this a lot
you know and it's you know I don't know
where but to me K the Cannabis is like a
coyote and then it's super Elusive and
it's like you can't really train it or
capture it and it's really clever and
right when you think you've you know
figured out you know what it is or what
it's going to be or whatever it just
pivots and it becomes something else um
so I think that that's part of part of
the nature and the chemical complexity
is that we'll never be able to just rain
it in and it'll always take these
backyard enthusiasts and the
Horticultural side to keep feeding the
egg side you know hopefully um because
cannabis I think you know like there's
two tracks that we're on right now which
is one is exploring the complexity
around the the
human um plant
relationship you know re emerging out of
prohibition and people are trying
cannabis for the first time and all
these new Delivery Systems and all this
stuff so it's really complicated and
it's like can be many different things
it could be you know non psychoactive
even um and then on the other side is
just the very simple nature of cannabis
as a plant that's grown by people like
other plants that it's actually a pretty
fairly plant to grow grows in a lot of
different climates it's very elastic to
different ways of being cultivated and
you know indoors Outdoors little plants
big plants Vining plants bushing plants
creeping plants you know so like it
really wants to grow as you know like it
really wants to thrive but but the other
side of it the how and why we need to
have the plant is way more
complicated um and that's the thing that
that I I fear that we might lose and
that you know in this
reemergence that all these isolated
populations of people around the world
that created these this diversity you
know um pre-prohibition or up into and
through prohibition all of that is about
to experience the same dynamic as modern
agriculture right and cannabis isn't
even scalable like modern agriculture
it'll never be grown like wheat or corn
or
rice um because we don't need that much
of it for for drugs I mean if if we're
growing it for food or fiber for grain
and fiber then um then it makes sense
that it can be treated like egg but we
can't treat it like an Agricultural
Product we can't treat it like grapes or
Apples because we don't need to grow
that much so we got to be careful how we
put it in the Box it doesn't really fit
in the way other products do
you know so when you talk about Pharma
and big egg getting into cannabis it'll
never be those things you know um it's a
limited amount of of of this crop that
needs to be produced for people um drug
type you know so uh we got to be really
cautious about scaling it up and letting
egg and letting big companies move in
because in theory just a few people can
grow I mean a few groups could grow the
majority of the can AB for the world
because it's not like corn and rice
where you just need millions and
millions and millions and millions and
millions of acres to feed the bulk of
the calories for all of humans cannabis
consumption about how many people need
you know how much each person needs to
consume of this plant is relatively
small compared to the other things so
it's like we got to with because of the
smallness of it we have to have a little
bit more of a big picture about it and I
don't know if that that you know
speaks to what you asked but I mean to
me that's the the the challenge around
the diversity is that like um it's
something that's incredibly diverse but
you also don't need that much of it it's
a sub it's a drug it's a substance you
know it's not a staple like other big
crops um so so you know God forbid
someone should just mass-produce the red
delicious version of cannabis then it
just becomes one thing
you know and that could easily happen I
mean it could be mandated that way
through regulations that you know
cannabis has to be this because you know
whatever body decided that it shouldn't
be the other thing you know and we
decided it potency can't be Beyond this
amount it shouldn't have too much of
that or it shouldn't have too much of
this um and maybe that's maybe that
complexity around creating those
guidelines is part of the reason why it
hasn't happened because it's not alcohol
it's not as simple as just regulating it
based off of one thing which is ethanol
or one thing which is THC it became all
these other things and kind of CBD was
the gatekeeper for that just saying oh
my God it can be something totally
different and look how much that really
helped push the discussion forward um by
changing people's opinions on what it is
you know so we want it to we want to
have that diversity and that ability to
Pivot and that ability to change
opinions and to produce different
products and to you know um so yeah it
needs to stay diverse so it needs to
stay in our backyards and we need more
custodians and and Shepherds than
ever yeah 100% I can I can totally agree
with that and I guess as a as a quick
follow on do you have any thoughts on
what we might be able to do to help
Safeguard some amount of the genetic
diversity outside of just consumer
demand because like in an Ideal World
consumers would demand that diversity
and then easy fix you know um the
companies are going to do it but I guess
I'm interested in trying to think like I
don't even know if it's possible but is
there some way to try to help ensure it
stays around you know even in the
absence of that I'm not entirely sure
and as a as a quick follow on do you
fear that you know some of the big a
companies are really sort of of licking
their chops at the ideas of real
commercialized cannabis I I remember
when I was writing the questions for
this I I jokingly thought to myself like
you know do you think there's a
whiteboard somewhere in Monsanto where
they've already got a Terminator Gene in
mind for some uh you know maloi or
something like you know what I mean uh
what what are your thoughts on
preserving the genetics and and do you
think that uh we're going to go down a
dark
path I mean well well definitely I mean
I don't know I mean it's not I don't
think we're going on a a darker path
with cannabis than anything else in life
I mean it's just the nature of you know
the modern system right the modern
manuscript um so consumerism and you
know the way we engage with products you
know people don't always make the best
decisions with the food that they eat or
the cars they buy or whatever so we
can't expect them all to becomed
informed cannabis consumers and keep the
diversity alive based off of their their
consumption needs you know so it is
definitely up to us um you know to have
a little bit more play a bit more of a
role in that and I think that's why that
you know honestly the hom grower is
really important that way because the
pressures on um the agronomic side don't
exist so if someone's got some plants in
the backyard they don't really care if
they come in and the first week of
October or the last week of October as
long as they don't mold out or or all
the way into de December even you know
or you know whether they're in their
tent if it grows for nine weeks or 10
weeks doesn't really have a big impact
where like the CFO for your big company
is like might say nothing over nine
weeks you know it can never happen not
in this facility it's like you know um
so that is I think that's really
important and to to maintain that and
you know and that is happening I that
I'm not afraid of that at all um but
what what I do worry about is
the overc commodification of like the um
the inter like if cannabis overnight
became an international like let me back
back it up a little bit like think about
what would have happened to cannabis if
prohibition never
happened right if it just fell fell the
regular track because think about how
cannabis was is an ancient crop but
industrial agriculture was just getting
rolling as prohibition happened you know
and Industrial agriculture would have
happened to cannabis for the past 80
some years right so I think we would
have lost a lot of that diversity so
it's it's it's it's kind of like the
blowback of these guys who tried to you
know put cannabis in jail they ended up
opening it up in a way that they could
never imagine um in the marketplace now
the diversity in these land rais
populations and the diversity around the
world might have had a big impact from
prohibition but the marketplace
diversity I think was
was a big gift because it would have
been definitely you know it's just if
you think of you know when you when you
look at a a a a large field of cannabis
and you see some varieties that do well
and some don't to Big Egg they're just
like okay we only grow the ones that do
well regardless of you know what anyone
thinks you know we're going we're going
to move in One Direction you know and
that's how you end up with that kind of
bottleneck but
um
um in terms of moving forward
I mean I don't know it's it's really
hard to
see how big EG and the Monsanto of the
world could
really capture cannabis from could
capture the diversity and limit it you
know it's really hard it's like the cats
out of the bag um and I know like what's
an example I know like in the um Rob
told me this story years ago about the
the um the wine industry in the USSR
being
completely um bottlenecked because they
had decided they wanted to grow this
only you know one or two varieties for
Mass um you know for the the whole for
the whole USSR we don't we don't need
the diversity we want to streamline it
for distribution and yada yada um and
but it was the guys it was the gardeners
who kept you know vines in their
backyard that kept all that diversity
and were able to reinvigorate
the the wine industry after the USSR
fell um so I'm not really worried about
the diversity I'm worried more about
like the social experiment of cannabis
you know of like what and and you know
you see like gummies and vape pins have
definitely taken over um in a big way
because they're socially more
approachable and they fit into people's
lifestyles easier but I sometimes wonder
you know if if we're going to fit in
cannabis the right way back to that you
know why are we growing why is there so
much Afghan influence in modern cannabis
and not that there's a right or a wrong
way but is it um is it going to be
beneficial for Humanity in some kind of
way I don't know I mean that's a kind of
a lofty a lofty you know thought but
um I personally feel like there's um
that there definitely that there has
been something lost in modern weed you
know that there's just a little bit and
maybe it's maybe it's because Aroma and
you know loud cannabis has like become
so much more popular but um just some
subtle nuances that I think would be you
know
helpful no it's it's funny I hope no one
takes offense when I say this when you
said that it reminds me of like you know
when nii is proclaiming the death of God
you know it's like something's changed
it's hard to articulate but there's a
little something that's changed and it's
kind of
undeniable um look I I agree with all of
that and that is that is cool to hear
that story about the USSR and how you
know like there will be people much like
our listeners and ourselves who will
likely be be safeguards for some of
these genetics longterm but I want to uh
give people who might not have the
pleasure of knowing your backstory a bit
more information which will help ground
some of these answers a bit more so
after where I think what 1 hour deep
let's ask our our usual first question
tell me about your first experience with
cannabis um yeah I mean I I can't
remember my first experience because I
mean we my parents both found cannabis
early in their lives um my dad was from
Alabama and my mom was from Florida and
and they both found cannabis um as young
adults and decided to move to California
in the early 60s on separate paths and
met actually my mom and dad met um in
the middle of the night over a joint you
know because that was the world that
they lived in and um so it's always been
there it's always been a part of my life
it's always been somewhat
normalized I'd say some of my earliest
memories in life are watching you know a
a pipe or a joint go around the circle
I'm the youngest of six I have um you
know my oldest brother is 10 years older
than me so um consumption was just
normal all around me and and cultivation
to some extent as well so it was always
there you know and the smell was always
there and the people were always there
and the plant was always there um it's
it's just been kind of the background of
my life in a way and it was kind of the
the connective tissue with the community
that I grew up in was Cannabis and they
were back to the land beat ni um people
I was born in Big Sir California
1969 um and by that point you know there
already a little bit of a community
there one of the first places where you
could argue there was kind of a new
world
um uh cannabis culture and and Industry
a little bit people were cultivating and
selling and
celebrating um bigir had the the harvest
parties which started in'
67 or so um through family friends that
lived um my parents were living on a
place I think it was plaset Creek in big
Su and and they invited a friend to come
and stay with us and him and his family
in 66 or so and that was Patrick Cassidy
and we moved from plaset and then
Patrick um came up and started growing
um cannabis there and then by I think
67 started having these Harvest parties
where people you know could kind of
freely come and celebrate and they would
um you know it would be a sea of VW
buses and and you know hippies back to
the Landers and beatnicks and musicians
and all kinds of far up people who would
come to Big Sir and kind of feel
open um so that was that was where it
all started for me and then as a young
adult or sorry as a young child we moved
to New York City and then to Los
Angeles um but my older brother stayed
in big Su or moved back to Big by 77 or
something like that and um cultivated in
um in Big Sir for years so that was my
um my strong relationship with the plant
and the community and all that was
definitely founded in biger even though
I still live most of my life in SoCal
but my f part of my family was there and
that's where most of the herb we
consumed was grown and that's where
that's where it all started for me
wow what a what an incredible
introduction I mean it sounds like it's
been there the whole time which is
really cool your experience with it goes
so deep i' I'd love to hear first off do
you ever have any recollection of your
parents ever telling you of what they
considered to be really memorable herb
or you know what what do you think it
was like for them what were they
consuming was it import was it the early
stuff produc in California did they ever
tell you much about their
experience yes um well I had a very
close relationship with both my parents
and and we you know talked about
cannabis a lot um my dad was um you know
also imported a bit in the late 60s and
early
70s and um and grew and but actually
here's a funny story is I actually asked
my
mom um about the first time she consumed
cannabis which would have been in
Gainesville Florida in 1959 or 1960 or
something and I asked her like specifics
about like the joint and how big it was
and how many people smoked it and what
happened when they smoked it and I tell
you back to the potency thing her
description sure was of some people who
got really really high you know like
I mean they got they went through the
full you know the full just giggles and
wacky and then philosophical then
paranoid and all of that stuff off of a
little I mean between four people
couldn't had to be a quarter gram of
import you know flower from that they
got from you know their beat Nick friend
who knew guys at the Jazz Club or
something and um but I always thought
that was interesting because it wasn't
like like the story of like smoking um
you know 70s homegrown that was leafy
and barely got you high or something it
was like no whatever they smoked worked
um but you know but yeah the the the the
Big Sur was all about you know for the
most part it was all mostly Mexican
varieties grown there um into the 70s
and then you know with some Colombian
and Panamanian and then a little bit of
Thai and then by the mid 70s um the
African influence came came in from Malo
the corn cops in
7677 but um yeah that was it and they
were all I mean that was that was kind
of the that was part of why I had this
this big imprint on these narrowly
fridas is because all my early
introduction with Canabis was all the
not the same profile but some common
common ground let's just say you know in
terms of effect um so yeah um but yeah
we we um we saw a lot and and saw a lot
of cannabis import throughout my youth
too you know cannabis every you know if
people bought and
sold um from all around the world and
and people were often bringing in you
know things from from everywhere um you
know coffee tins from Hawaii
and not a lot I didn't see honestly I
never saw a lot of like brick weed and
stuff like that um until like my teenage
years when my other friends would
present flower that they found and stuff
but um saw a lot of uh interesting
different profiles you know just one I
guess one thing that would um was a big
imprint on me as the kid is how visually
different Cannabis used to be from
region to region and from you know from
variety to variety just visually
stimulating big big Spears and balls and
bright red hairs and orange hairs and
lime green and dark green and golden and
brown and purple and all that
stuff yeah wow I mean I can only imagine
especially when it was so sort of raw
and coming from the the land race spot
in many instances that would have been
really really cool I guess certainly one
of the uh frequently Asked fan submitted
questions from our patreon listeners was
many of them sort of asked mult like
many questions but they all sort of fell
into one of two um you know broader
questions the first one being what was
it like to grow in the Big Sir area
itself because many people commented
quite a foggy area right like it's high
humidity I'm assuming or just issues
with moisture what what was that like
and did that lend itself I guess a bit
to the fact that you guys were growing a
lot of sativas was that part of it and
then as a followup to that can you tell
us a bit about you know the faved Big
Sir hly weed ye yeah um well yeah
definitely people were growing all
sativas so that that susceptibility to
mold and mildew wasn't really nearly as
much of an issue but people were also
growing up out of the fog line you know
up on The Ridges where you could you
know get out into the sun made a big
difference um a big difference obviously
you know for certain varieties but um
yeah Big Sir holy weed is um it's the
story of stories you know it's it's uh
one of the few like um you know it's the
it's the aaal goals of the US you know
so it's it's filled with L and I am you
know totally responsible for part of the
misinformation that's been spread around
over the years um but uh I can give you
the the story The the the story as I
know it and then all the different
versions that are told which are all
much more interesting um but um
essentially Patrick Cassidy who was the
one who did the the harvest parties and
was really one of the first you know
commercial growers in California he was
growing flower and a friend another
family friend um said hey man your weed
is like holy weed you know and that was
it and so then that became Big Sir holy
weed and it was predominantly
Mexican um but the thing is is you got
to remember people didn't clone people
didn't really breed we can get into like
in a minute if you want to talk about
how CIA kind of came about because that
that book was written by family friends
as
well um but so there the idea that big
sir holy weed was a line or this
lineage it really was a class it was
really good weed grown and originally it
was weed grown by Patrick you know but
it could have been of various descent um
but then it quickly became such a
brandable thing that a lot of Growers
who grew in Big Sur were calling their
flower Big Sir holy weed and that
stretched all the way into the 80s and
all the way past Way Beyond when all the
different hybridization happened people
were still selling it as big star holy
weed um so
that's the truth behind it it's kind of
like an Appalachian it's kind of like
just Big Sir bud it's a good bud from
Big Sir you know which is also what I've
heard you know the Alaska Thunder [__]
story from some guys I met in up Alaska
they said that's the same thing Alaskan
it's good it's good herb from the valley
it's the manusa valley and this is the
you know whatever you know I don't know
um but so that is that is the truth and
what kind of the the story for me was
that when I when I bred sage in
Amsterdam and I brought um I found this
unknown hay
Afghan female and I didn't know you know
what it
was um and I C made the C and then I
decided I wanted to make some seeds so I
brought Big Sir seed and that big sir
seed was of African lineage it was
chamba um and I made the cross and so it
was this unknown female times this
chamba Afghan cross and then I did a
back cross and made a few made some
parents and stuff and so when some of
the first batches of seeds were sold as
I think it was labeled as Sage times Big
Sir holy weed so the story kind of that
that there was Big Sir holy weed in Sage
which is true because there's Big Sir
Afghan I mean Big Sir African weed in
sage and there's Haze in there and it's
all part of the Big Sur story it's all
part of the Central Coast story it's all
part of the killer weed grown on the
hill story but there is no lineage and
that's the main thing you know and then
to comp to complicate things further you
know friends family and friends were
growing under to get out of the fog they
were growing right underneath the
Franciscan
Monastery um and it's a Hermitage you
know and so that was another level to
holy weed and I perpetuated that story
by saying like Yeah The Holy weed is
Holy weed it was grown by The Hermitage
and blah blah blah so then over time you
start hearing this story about a monk
and this monk was a bunk named Perry and
he was at the Buddhist from the Buddhist
well the Buddhist Monastery thing in Big
Sir happened years later and it's at a
totally different
location totally has nothing to do with
it and you know and in the Perry thing
and the zakus purple it's like yeah it
was Mexican cannabis cuz the majority of
the Cannabis was Mexican in Big
Sir but the actual story of a guy who
sourced it and found it and preserved it
and gave it that's all just lore that's
all just made up and then there's
there's even African things that it came
from Olatunji the drummer and all this
stuff you know there's truth to it
Olatunji was a family friend and he
would play in Big Sir but he didn't
bring flow you know it was more of us
sharing these African varieties with
them saying look at this great Malawi
and Tanzanian stuff we're growing here
um so there's all these different
stories about the monk named Perry and
was he a Franciscan or was he Buddhist
and the African influence from Olatunji
all these things and and just the
reality is it was just a guy saying to
another guy you grow really good weed
you know and it's kind of like I think
that that's the same for Maui woi Alaska
[__] and maybe a bunch of other
you know aaal gold and whatever it's
like is it was it a breeding project
where someone created a lineage and does
that lineage last
today is a big difference from someone
saying this was great amazing flower
that you grew this time you know and so
it became just a thing and it still is
today you know and and I still you know
I have a a cult of our
that I selected out of my sage and I
call it Big Sir and I call sometimes I
even call it holy weed because it
embodies that it has that that that
signature that I remember as a kid of
that type of cannabis it has those genes
in there from that Haze influence and
from that chamba
influence um and it's amazing iy
uplifting cannabis so I'm happy to use
to throw the Big Sir on there but you
know there is no one thing called Big
Sir holy weed you know and the people
who went on to breed with different
things they legitimately got seeds that
were called holy weed and they did come
from weed that was sold as holy weed and
some of the guys who have lines today
it's great weed and it is Mexican
descent cannabis from Big Sir so it it
also deserves the credit of being called
holy weed um today but the actual story
of a guy and how it happened it's that's
just a it's you know as far as I know
that there's no no validity to it and I
can't find one single person that can
corroborate any of the you know the
folklore on online whereas the other
stuff I just grew like these were Big
Sir holy weed was a name from like back
to you know my earliest memories of
cannabis it's like that came along with
it so it was never like something that I
discovered or learned about it was just
part of your life you know and it was
never you know anything other than it
just being great cannabis from Big Sir
you know um but of a certain lineage yes
of a certain class yes of a
certain type yes and I think that's an
important thing back to the land race
thing and what we wanted cannabis to be
it is a very specific thing you can't
come up with an OG from from sorry not
picking an OG it's like one of those
things just a it's a great go-to but you
can't pick an OG and grow it in big Ser
call it holy weed you know just because
it was grown in that region because it's
not just cannabis from Big Sir and you
know but it it is a certain you know
chemical class you could say um but yeah
there's there's the the the online
stories are way cooler than just you
know the reality is usually much
simpler yeah isn't that often the case
well look that's that's so interesting
to hear that I guess I'd love to ask
given that you do see people referencing
it sometimes in breeding work and given
that it is something that's not very
well represented in people's minds just
for anyone wondering including myself
How would how would you describe I know
that it's a broad thing the holy weed
but the one that you sort of Envision in
your mind how would you describe it is
it is it like a plant that looks like a
haze plant and smells like a haze plant
to you is it do you think the Mexicans
were similar to the ones that were used
in Haze or they were a bit different and
it wasn't quite as racy how would you
sort of just describe smoking it the
smell and the effects for anyone who
hasn't tried it I mean I I to be honest
like then I'd have to really think that
if there if there was ever a holy weed
so like it's a spectrum right it's a
spectrum of the like I can tell you the
first time I grew what someone else was
was someone gave me in 94 seeds of biger
holy weed a friend from Santa Cruz and I
grew it out and it looked exactly like
what I remember cannabis from the 70s
being it was big giant green Mexican
redhair sativa plants and it was just
mediocre High though you know maybe I
didn't maybe I didn't select the right
seed you know I only G it out of a few
seedss but it was classic Mexican
California weed just big giant you know
Christmas tree
structure um and and to me I mean that's
why like when I say like Haze embodies
that in modern cannabis and a lot of and
that's and like to all the the breeding
work that's been done I I fully believe
that the seed producers today who have
big sir holy weed in their lineage got
it from people who got seeds out of
flour from those original things that
were called holy weed but remember it's
the original things it's back to that
you've got 100 plants in one bag and
next year there are 100 different plants
and next year there are 100 different
plants and next year there are 100
different plants so if you bought Big
Sir holy weed from 73 to 78 or
something it was never one thing even if
you bought it from just from that one
producer you know what I mean cuz for
one nobody breeding breeding you know
for one segregating Mal is really
difficult right so so like people who
were and when I was a kid nobody called
themselves breeders they just produced
seed for next year so everyone was
constantly producing seed for next year
and there wasn't you know I'm just
saying it wasn't what people assume it
is today you didn't have Grow rooms you
didn't have Chambers you didn't have
isolation you didn't have any of those
things to create lineages and it wasn't
you know David Watson wasn't producing
holy weed so there wasn't like a
concerted breeding effort over five
years to develop something so that's why
when I came to
Amsterdam and I had been smoking hazes
and Northern Light crosses and all these
stuff and skunk ones and then when I did
did the seed batch in my backyard um in
my Courtyard and I had the one little
plant in the corner that was literally 4
Ines tall maybe and it had less than a
gram of flour on it but I went down and
give it little sniff and it was just
like instant like time portal to my
childhood of that that Aroma that
profile that biger flavor and it wasn't
to me it wasn't being I didn't want I
didn't call it biger holy weed even in
my mind at that point it was just the
smell of my childhood of cannabis from
my childhood so it was like a a instant
marker so that's where I knew I was like
whatever is in this plant that's what I
remember and that's what I want it to be
for me so then it was just a matter of
you know finding some other plants to
cross it with in order to ra seeds but
that original female that unknown female
had it in there and I assume it was Haze
that was contributing to that because it
was unknown so that's why I say like you
know hay embodies that and so does so
does maloi and so does a lot of other
things that are out there that I still
encounter you know I love the African
haze from Ace um Ace seeds it like it
rocks my boat and when I smell it and I
get in there I'm just like that is the
smell the look everything of what I
remember cannabis to be as a kid um so
that that you know so that that's in in
in as much as I'd love for there to be
like a
stronger you know connection if someone
came out of the Woodworks and said hey
yeah I've got some seed that I got from
Patrick Cassidy's 1974 Harvest and you
know and that's what my big sir holy
weed is today then yes you could just
call that big sir holy weed and just be
just say it is you know but the reality
is is what you look at where and how
many people sold flour out of Big Sur as
holy weed for how long and what the
possible lineages could be it's
everything you know and you know so
that's that's just is what it is but but
the few things that the few things that
survived like Dolores Mexican variety
and chamba the African variety those
things were selected and developed and
kept somewhat isolated and they did have
that big sir holy that time capsule
thing from that period and those lines
were worked in used in modern cannabis
today and that's what's you know
contributes to the sage that I grew and
the breeding work I do today it's still
every selection I make is towards that
original profile so even though I've
crossed Sage with chamba I've crossed
Sage with OG I've crossed it with sour
I've crossed it with Asian fantasy I've
crossed it with a bunch of different
things that are all over the
Spectrum the thing that I'm selecting
for just because I want to stay in my
Lane because you know terpinolene is my
jam and I love that you know the
uplifting effect is I'm selecting for
that first sniff that I had in the
corner in the courtyard in Amsterdam in
1994 where I was just like oh my God
that's the
smell and it's the same thing I'm that's
that's what I want cannabis to be for me
and I think that some people might enjoy
it as
well I love that I love that as a big
fan of topen myself I'm I'm All About
that I wanted to quickly ask before we
moved on because the we had a few people
ask this one on the patreon while we're
talking about the big sir Holly weed
they they saw that episode of uh where
where you showed up to Jim Belushi's
cannabis farm people wanted to know did
you end up giving him some uh some big
so Hollywood is there any chance they
might be able to get it through his
brand at one point and then as a
followup you mentioned it earlier and I
I made a note to loop back you said oh
let there's there's a different story
about the progression towards sensia I'd
love to hear that in the area what was
that like transitioning from seeded to
seedless and how did that change the
game yes um yeah well the I did let me
just the the I did the episode with Jim
balushi which was a total blast and I
had a fantastic time and I you know I
love working with Jim and all his team
and I actually really appreciate what
they're doing you know they're they're
really um kind of rare in cannabis and
that they do see a big value in genetics
and unique profiles and that they kind
of want to differentiate themselves as a
brand around that which is pretty pretty
wild you know he he really went out on a
limb with the Colombian stuff and um so
that that was really what motivated that
in my working on that episode with them
was that like these guys are for real
they want better weed in their brand and
they also want to tell the story um um
and so yeah so I told the story on the
show you know it's a long story and it's
you know how TV goes so things get
edited down but I tried to just kind of
distill it down to the same thing I told
you that it's not just one thing um it's
kind of more a class or a region or or
or you know and yes I'm very much
working on getting um that into in into
um blushi farms for sure um because I'm
I'm super passionate about people
getting you know access to what at least
some people think is really you know
worldclass cannabis I do think that you
know even if it's in small batches
people should have the ability to try it
and so yeah I'm working towards getting
it's been a long it's been a long
journey you know with me with sage we've
been we've been dancing together for 30
years so I keep a catalog alive and I do
continue to do some breeding work and I
I think that we're going to see uh um
you know just like we're having this
conversation I'm having this
conversation more often that we're going
to see brands in the market and the
consumer slowly starting to ask you know
for for different options you know so
I'm I'm excited to try and make that
happen um and the uh what was the other
half sorry that question you oh CIA
yes so this is um CIA was a book written
in I I should grab let me grab a copy
off the shelf so I don't butcher this
really quick sounds
good
so sensia marijuana flowers it's a book
by Richardson and woods I have a hard
time with the names because they're not
real names they're aliases photography
by Eric Woods um marijuana flowers by
Jim Richardson it's a great book it's
the first time that I'm aware of and
others have
um agree that's the first time that the
the tech on pulling males was widely
disseminated that people didn't know how
to make seedless cannabis and um
obviously you know people had grown
plenty of seedless cannabis just because
the law of averages you know you flip a
coin you know you're likely to get a
heads pretty often or a tails and plenty
of people I'm sure just had a female in
the backyard and grew and smoked you
know seedless and I know it goes back
far into literature into you know that
we we we've known how to make seedless
cannabis um for a while but the in
modern world it wasn't something that
was widely known and even most of the
Imports CIA that people brought in
usually had some
seeds um but the story I was told was in
1974 or so um a batch of Tai weed
entered into to um big
sir and the people who purchased it were
like totally blown away at how seedless
it was and they um through the Importer
contacted the Growers and The Growers
basically told them the easy you know
pull a mail that's it simple simple so
um I'm not sure why the word cmia was
already known um and why there's not a
Thai word in the book um but as far as I
know that's where the authors got the
idea was from Thai flower and obviously
they'd been smoking s Amia and in the
market I guess that word was heavily
used already for seedless or less
seedless flow so as soon as they knew
how to do it they um they did it it has
a forward the forward is from um from
David Crosby actually of Crosby Stills
and Ash um and so anyway this was the
first time that they really you know
spread the word and um the far out part
is when they learned about it they knew
right away like oh we need to grow a
crop and photograph the crop and then
write a book you know it wasn't like
they were doing it and then they just
documented it it's like they literally
did they they grew this crop for the
purpose of photographing it for the
purpose of writing this book for the
purpose of
sharing um the concept of pulling males
so so as far as I know from all the old
Cali Growers and stuff that I know this
is where they learned how to make cmia
was from this one book and there were
some family friends um uh so yeah that
was a interesting little I just and I I
just learned this just recently a couple
years ago that it was thae flower I
never knew I always assumed it was just
Mexican flower that they had contacted
someone in Mexico and I know there's
other stories for how other people had
shared the knowledge and stuff but as
far as I know this book was the first
time in Bob and David also and Mel Frank
and all these guys they all they all
agree this was the first time that was
widely
distributed wow and I mean how how did
it change the landscape like for example
was there an immediate realization that
the value of the crop had gone up
significantly or was there like a year
or two of delay because I'm assuming
when you gave that story I I see it in
my mind perfectly someone just has one
plant in the backyard it's a female
they're sitting around with their mates
and they're like wow it was really good
this year wasn't it like not not exactly
sure why um was it the same thing when
they pulled the MS it took a minute
before they were like hey we actually
got something here or like how did that
go and and was there any other
unexpected repercussions or flow on
effects I mean I don't know I'd have to
go and get back and do some research in
the community but if from what I heard
it was around 74 and this book was
published in
76 so they grew the crop in
75 um and at that point by 75 people
were growing a lot of cannabis and big S
all over the place you know and so it
was just seated weed everywhere so from
what I gather it happened right away I
mean it's just like uh you know like the
internet turning on or something once
people realize oh no this is a mail pull
your males it became pretty quick
obviously you know people aren't always
going to be successful in doing that and
they're going to leave males that they
didn't you know know were there get
pollinated by their neighbors or stuff
like that but no I think it was pretty
widely adapted and not just by the
locals in Big Sur I mean it just it
spread around the world and everybody
quickly realized like duh oh my God is
that easy that's all I have to do it
just pull the males but then I'm sure
the big the next big you know thing was
like oh my god I've got to pull half of
my crop I got to plant half a crop and
then kill it like I didn't really think
it that way um so yeah no that was that
was a big thing and I'm sure you know
that that it's interesting though but
that happened right around the same time
that camp started ramping up and Big Sir
got hot and you know in actually in
1977 there was an article in LA Times
about the Harvest parties you know and
it was full you know colored pictures in
in the in the newspaper like hey these
hippies are just like growing weed up
here and having a big party you know um
so Camp got really heavy you know and
they started um busting people and
ripping plants out of the ground right
at that same time so right when when
everyone was kind of like learning how
to grow cannabis and getting better seed
and you know making their own crosses
and establishing their own little their
own little production they had to go and
run deep deep deep into the hills into
this new model of Gorilla growing which
is like was all about uh growing and not
it was no more it wasn't about botney
and horiculture anymore it was about not
getting busted just that was it right
100% so like it was like my first
memories of seeing plants like you know
commercial production I don't like to me
it looked like a field but I'm sure it
wasn't that big but it was definitely
rows of cannabis like grown in a patch
like all in one place in like the mid
late 70s but then by the just a few lat
years later you never saw that you just
saw a plant here and up plant there and
up plant here they were just scattered
around on the hillside with this you
know all this drip line connecting
everything and just the whole idea of
just kind of growing cannabis where you
could kind of tend to it like a gardener
or end to it like a farmer have it next
to your home you know next to your your
vegetable garden for instance that was
all gone and it quickly became you know
growing cannabis was about dressing up
in camos and going out in the middle of
the night and carrying chicken wire and
drip line way way way out into the into
the Backwoods in order to not get busted
which you can imagine like that changes
everything in terms of like what the
plant needs to be and how to grow the
plant what what type of plant to grow um
just everything changed you know
different that's that's where I can't
get over like this whole how much
prohibition shape not just the gene pool
but what we consider to be cannabis what
we want from Cannabis you know how we
interface and engage cannabis it's all
just either an artifact of prohibition
or blowback from
prohibition um so
yeah yeah I mean totally totally it's
it's hard to understate the impact it's
it's had isn't it I wanted to ask what
like you obviously grew up so heavily
surrounded by all of this what was the
stimulus for you to think I need I need
to head to Europe was it all of this
prohibition around you I'm assuming you
were probably near at the end of high
school when you started thinking about
going to Amsterdam what was that
transition like from being a kid
surrounded by it in California to
thinking I got to go to Europe um well
cannabis in California had gotten really
crazy in the 80s because of all the zero
tolerance laws and stuff so it became
less fun that's for sure I mean like
just there was the stress around it was
pretty pretty intense um but for me um
my childhood friend Adam Dunn had moved
to the to Amsterdam and you know he
would send me postcards and we would
chat and he'd come and visit me from
time to time and he was always just like
come on out it's insane you won't
believe it and was always kind of like
yeah you know I'm I'm uh thinking about
it one day I'll get out there and um I
also had a family friend um my dad was a
musician and back in Big Sir had a band
and they're called Big Sir light and
power and the guitar player was Al
shakman who was also um Nina Simone's
lifetime guitar player and Al was living
in Paris and I had um met up with alen
LA and he basically said come on out to
Paris and all he was outside of Paris
somewhere he said come on out and I'll
you know I'll be your mentor and I'll
teach you jazz guitar and you can come
and stay with me and um so Adam was
saying come to Amsterdam and Al was
saying come to France and I was kind of
wavering and then one day I just came
home and someone stole my my truck with
all my tools in it I was working as a
doing carpentry and stuff of the time
and the second I saw and I saw the truck
driving away and just like just like a
lightning Flash and like boom Amsterdam
I'm going I'm out of here
and I got a um um and I was 23 at the
time um I got a one-way ticket and I
told my friends and family I said I'm
going to be gone for probably a month no
more no more than a
year um and I end up staying for six
years um but anyway I came to Amsterdam
just to hang out and see the scene to
see what it was like um which was wild
um just Queen's Day you know oh my God
just the things the fun we had you know
all the all the old squat parties and
and uh you know just Amsterdam in the
early 90s was just a blast and I had a
really good time there for a few months
and then I went and hitchhiked down to
Paris in your classic you know American
on the road thing with a backpack and a
guitar and uh a big giant bag in nlees
hash you know I basically was like all I
need is a bunch of hash my guitar and a
backpack and I showed up and Paris and I
had been Comm I had been communicating
with Al via postcard and phone cards you
know cuz we didn't have cell phones in
those days and you know most Flats
didn't have phones even that my friends
had so we'd like get a phone card and
call people and I show up in Paris and
Al had moved back to the US somewhat
abruptly and I was just kind of stranded
in Paris with like no money and my
guitar and a backpack and just like kind
of like hm what what should I do now you
know I was I really came here to do
music and I just kind of contacted
Adam and um decided I had a met a girl
who was um working at ciny seeds at the
time Monica and I called her up and
she's like why don't you come up here
and just hang out and we became a
couple and within a few months I started
growing cannabis indoors and then a few
months later I started PL popping seeds
in the backyard and a few months later I
built up another little grow and you
know I was just I had settled and then I
decided I was never coming back I you
know I loved Amsterdam so much I decided
I would live there for the rest of my
life um and was found Sage which was fun
because it was something new and um all
that you know Cannabis Cup stuff was
going on and the culture was kind of
growing there was kind of a buzz in the
city it was this epicenter it was really
cool and Adam was well connected and new
people and started his hemp clothing
company um it's just a really exciting
time to be there and then prop 215
happened and California you know made
this big shift and I started thinking
about why I was in Amsterdam and you
know kind of missing family and missing
geography missing the mountains and the
coast and stuff like that and decided to
come back and try my hand at you know
doing what I was doing in Amsterdam in
California um which is kind of what
brought me back here and I brought seeds
brought sage seeds back and continued to
breed and just kept moving
forward let me quickly ask one question
before we continue on which is what was
the creation of sage like you know can
you take us through the steps of was it
was it planned was it just like a happy
accident was it the case that you pop
one of the parents and then thought oh I
got to work with this like how did it
sort of go down well it was after
growing indoors for a couple cycles and
you know coming from a com being a
California boy I wanted to grow outside
and I wanted to grow from seed so I
basically accumulated a bunch of seed
from random places it was all nothing
purchased never not a single I've never
bought a seed in my entire life um there
were seeds that were gifted to me seeds
that fell out of a joint that I was
rolling and I had a few of them that
were unlabeled but
segregated meaning like I would like if
something was special I'd wrap it up in
like a little rolling paper or something
to designate it from just being another
seed right and when I planted in the
backyard 100 or so seeds and in the
corner I planted in pots instead of the
ground a few of these
I think this might be special kind of
seeds um but one of those seeds didn't
grow very much it was just sitting in
the corner in too big of a pot probably
germinated late and was just
struggling um and that was the one that
I smelled and had the flower that that
smell and I right away luckily I'd
already you know I'd been kind of diving
in big into learning about how to grow
and got all the grow books I could and
I'd already met Rob and all these people
and so I knew about revegging plants so
I plucked off enough flower off that one
little plant in order to dry it and
smoked it and right away it was just
like holy [__] this is really special by
far the best thing out of the whole
backyard um and I started to rev it it
slowly slowly crawled out of flour and
reved and grew out the mom made some
cuts and did an indoor round and the
rest is history it was didn't have a
name for it at
first
um
and sold it I think I think at the first
time I sold it I sold it as Maui Mist I
think because the gray area had just
opened up the coffee shop and they
wanted to sell some but we didn't have a
name and it was similar to a haze or
a c mist or something so we called it
Maui
Mist um but it had that SA age smell
once again that not only reminded me of
this flower from Big Sir but it also
reminded me of Big Sir itself the The
Sage Brush kind of um chapparel smell
which is terpinolene is in you know
Salvia the sage plant um so um one night
I just kind of had this Epiphany and I'd
been reading you know and and meeting
Rob and meeting um and learning about
cannabis
um and really liked the a the um
afghanica as opposed to Indica because I
was always puzzled as a kid I remember
seeing products and grocery stores
called Indica there was like Inda rice
and it would say right on the label Inda
rice is a type of rice grown in India
you know explaining what Indica meant so
I always thought it was kind of puzzling
that all these plants from Afghanistan
were called Indica so once just smelling
sage and having this sagey smell that me
and Adam were talking about like oh it's
got the sagey smell I just thought of
the the acronym an acronym um sativa
afghanica genetic
equilibrium because it was it had a
strong sativa
effect um but it was chunky and it came
in under 70 days so it had the Afghan
influence on the agronomic side but it
had the sativa influence on the effect
so then I had a female an all you know a
female that was growing and you know by
that point um th seeds was already in
business and just the idea was like well
we should turn this into a seed line um
so I used the chamba um Afghan cross and
found a mail from that
and found a sage uh Sage times chamba um
female and a sage times chamba male and
I believe I back crossed that male
against the sage female
and from there I found I believe is
where the sage male and the sage female
came that would eventually used be used
to make the seeds for sage for th
seeds um so it's like uh it's 12 and a
half% chamba I
think um yeah I have the lineage
somewhere I I could figure it out but
but yeah wow is it's kind of like a like
a sage bx1 F2 almost by the sounds of it
yeah yeah that's that's about exactly
what it is yep cool okay and I mean Gosh
Look it's it's a a very popular strain
like people know about it I don't know
if you're if you know the numbers and
I'm not exactly looking for them but
like would you say that it was certainly
commercially successful or was it just a
strain that people happen to know a lot
about um I mean it when I was growing it
in Amsterdam it created a buzz cuz it
was something new and it was good and a
lot of people wanted to smoke it and and
there was definitely hype I mean there
was people you know trying to buy cuts
and stuff like that
um and then a lot of people who bought
seeds were able to find really special
varieties there's a lot of diversity in
there as you could tell just by looking
at that that cross um so there's a lot
to sort through let's just say that
right it's not a homozygous line at all
um but in that sorting there's a lot of
really magical stuff that all still
still kind of in that one spectrum of
that Sage class that tpine kind of thing
um so little pockets people found it and
it was really different and it was a
great breeding tool because it had this
kind of soaring effect and um you know I
I had more I had more luck with the
crosses I made with it than just the P
age just because um you know and I I
think you could say the same maybe for
th seeds like sage and sour really
nailed it and that brought both of those
worlds together um I've had some other
Sage sour crosses um from other people
that were really amazing um and the I
used OG quite a bit in Crossing with
sage but always selected for um Sage
traits um on the Kim on the on the
effect side um so it was a really good
breeding parent to bring um some of that
hazy sativa side into your hybrids you
know um so that's what you started to
see a lot of these you know the the
folos AG and um I'm trying to think of
what is the other one that's kind of
popular that was going around the
[Music]
um uh God it's a a rename um yeah I
can't remember but there's a there's a
there's things and I run into people all
the time who tell who tell me there's
things in their line that Sage is in
their line like I know Green b a lot of
his stuff has sage in it um I know all
the sour best [__] ever sbse that has
sage in it um you know so it became a
part of things more than it became
something on its own um and I think that
kind of also speaks just to the need
agronomically to create hybrids for the
market it's just really hard to stay in
the the later flowering world
um but to me you know to me sage and
Hayes and Jack and um Durban and train
wreck and all these things they're all
in this kind of trening class and some
of them work better for growers in some
ways and some of and also they've all
been mixed up by the way you know
there's there's definitely train wreck
out there that is Sage you know and
that's that's happened a few times and
that happens just like there's durans
out out there that aren't Durban and
there's Jacks that are Durban and Durbin
that are Jacks and stuff so that that
terpinolene signature kind of became a
you know a thing you know so I know
people who've used it to breed into
their other tpine dominant lines um just
because it brings I think I think the
one big attribute that Sage had in terms
of you know what it offered that Hayes
didn't was it was earlier flowering and
chunkier but still had that same soaring
effect
yeah nice nice and I like the way you
said you know it's sort of it's worked
its way into many things more than being
its own thing I think that's sort of all
you can really hope for as a breeder
really right cuz nothing's going to stay
around forever unless you made OG and
let's face it we're not all going to be
so
lucky and there you have it friends a
massive massive thank you and shout out
to Mojave for taking the time to join us
what do you guys think I thought it was
awesome hope you come back for part
two more knowledge bombs and wisdom to
[Music]
come heavy
days signing
out we'll see
you if you love this episode please
consider supporting both the patreon as
well as the websites of our incredible
sponsors if you're looking to transition
from combustion to vaping check out our
good friends at dinat you will not be
disappointed cheap affordable and
Incredibly efficient units likewise
check out our friends at Pulse sensors
if you want to make sure that your
garden is dialed in and you are tracking
all of the variables that are going to
ensure your next Harvest is the best to
date you got to get yourself a pulse
guys it's a Nob
brainer in order to ensure that your
garden is pest and pathogen free please
check out our friends at Copic they are
the number one in BIO predatory
technology copit thank you so so so much
for your
support likewise a big shout out to our
friends at Organics alive for all the
most incredible powdered organic
products usable in all systems both
organic and hybrid a huge thank you to
Organics alive we recommend them highly
please check them out if you want to
take your organic game to the next
level finally massive shout out to our
good friends at seeds here now they got
heavy days beans go check them out guys
I promise you will not be disappointed
theyve got all the latest drops the
hottest breeders fem Auto photo period
CBD whatever you need they're here to
help you out a massive thank you to our
friends at CS here
now and big love to the patreon gang we
love you so much thank you for
supporting the show they got Early
Access to this episode over a month ago
if you want to get extra content please
consider supporting the show you'll
score yourself genetics a whole bunch of
swag from our sponsors and so much
more so that just just about brings us
to the end of it for this
one big thank you to you for getting to
the end yet again and for the
support Big Love is always from your boy
heavy
days signing
off see you
[Music]