[Music]
[Applause]
what
hello and welcome again my friends to
the next episode of the podcast a
cannabis podcast for budding enthusiasts
as always this episode was brought to
you by our amazing sponsors
the one and only seeds here now all the
best seeds in the game
guarantee on both satisfaction and
germination why would you go anywhere
else
you're gonna go check them out i know it
likewise the one and only radio ridge
nursery you got an itch for some killer
clones don't have time to hunt them go
check them out they've got you covered
seriously all the best exclusive cuts go
see them right now
likewise a big thank you to the one and
only 420 australia and organic gardening
solutions holding down the fort down
under with all the best organic
gardening products and 420 apparel you
would ever need
[Music]
as always a huge shout out to our
patreon crew you guys are the lifeblood
of the show we appreciate you so very
very very much
[Music]
as always big shout out to the dragonfly
family spreading that organic
regenerative one love message
a huge huge huge thank you to green
sleeves merchantile the one and only
check them out for your design needs
they make some killer killer killer
graphic designs
you see it on body mountain organics
my new logo heck
what can't they do
our episode today is
the one and only ghost of always be
flowering genetics here to talk history
set a few stories straight and let you
know what he's got planned in store for
everyone
let's get into it
alrighty friends a big thank you and
welcome to the next guest on the show
the ceo of always being flowering thanks
so very much to ghost for coming on
appreciate it man thanks for having me
on here
not a problem my friend so first
question we ask people these days what
are you currently smoking on
uh right now we're smoking on some pk
sherb that we made so it's the malibu pk
with the reverse sunset sherbert
and before that some tricks by my buddy
grolo key uh gg4 mendo breath that he
hunted
wow interesting there's uh there's a lot
going on there so i mean first of all
tell us about the sunset sure how would
you describe the crosses you made with
that one
um i'd say the sunset sherb crosses have
all been pretty beneficial in terms of
what it added to the structure
it's a really interesting plant
probably the plant that i've been most
excited about since cookies and
i actually passed on it for a couple of
years because i wasn't interested in
hearing anything about it mostly because
i didn't really think that it would be
better than the cookies in any way shape
or form it just seemed kind of like
derivative
so i passed on it for a while until i
actually got to try a sample and
i was impressed by it it's got the
creamy kind of deep musky flavor and
it's a little bit less cookie doughy
dominant and
[Music]
i like the yield on it the structure on
it the growth habit super super proper
plant in terms of
how it grows and stretches and the
yields from it um
i'd say
you know it's probably
added a lot to the crosses and with the
pk being lower yielding
a little bit more finicky of a plant you
find that what the crosses of it produce
are hardier more vigorous plants
yeah that sounds really good and i've
i've got to admit i've actually never
tried pure sherbet that's why i'm always
interested to hear people's take on it
but to cross over the other side of
things you mentioned across to the the
pure kush i'm always interested because
there's so many different pure cushes is
the malibu your personal favorite one
so i i honestly think that a lot of them
are very very similar if not identical
i think sometimes when people see them
what all they're really seeing is just
different growers examples of a similar
plant at this point with ogs in general
which i'm sure you've seen a good amount
when you've been when you've been out
west it's very very similar i think
there's really only a couple of
different profiles that stand out
there's the more like gassy lemony one
like the sfv
there's the more earthy one like the
malibu and then there's kind of what you
find in um a good example recently was
like the black triangle from bodhi that
triangle uh 88 g13 hash plant
very very dank like what i call like a
traditional kush type profile
and the malibu and the topanga honestly
a lot of them when i've seen them
they're very very similar so i can't
really say
that there would be much of a difference
between them somebody who would probably
be better suited to speak on that might
be the doctor from archive
he might have seen more i mean i've seen
the malibu
um
when i was in san diego in like the
early 2000s and when i've seen the
tapanga brought up
very very similar in my opinion and i
know there's i mean because the
hollywood pk2 is what they're calling it
as well
yeah there's a there's a stack of
different ones i guess the thing i'm
most interested in is do you think that
the more lemon based ogs came maybe from
an s1 of say the the more earthy the
more pure kush type ones or do you think
maybe it was the other way around or do
you think they just evolved
independently
that's a good question i mean i i would
think that they came from the more
earthy ones just because i kind of feel
like that's the base of that genetic
so it would make sense to me that an
outlier might be the more lemony one and
the lemony ones um
are very very popular for a specific
reason because they have that they have
that gassy profile but they also have
that stick to your palate flavor
that pretty much cuts through anything
and so i feel like
it was probably an outlier of the
earthier cushes that people were
probably getting back in the day
yeah that certainly seems to make sense
and then so i guess to kind of bring
this little bit full circle a lot of
people often talk about feeling like
there's a cush component within girl
scouts and by extension
within the sherbs
do you see that yourself and if so what
type of kush influence do you think is
within the sherb
so at least with the girl scout cookies
i would say when you look at it and the
way that it grows it grows very very
similar to the sfvs
in terms of just the way the flower sets
the size of the flowers on them the
internal spacing on it and the long
petioles that you see on them if you've
ever seen like the og's grown or whatnot
they don't require a lot of plucking
because they don't they don't pull that
they don't put out a lot of leaves they
stretch a whole lot and that's similar
to what we first saw in the forum with
the sherb i could see it as well it's
just selected away from that to a plant
that stacks a little bit more is a
little bit tighter puts out fatter
flowers that the colas are you know
three or four flowers set together not
not kind of like what you see with the
sfvs or the ogs
and it's firmer the the branches aren't
as floppy
with the ogs you know they require a lot
of work because you know they they want
they want to get all kind of over the
place they require
a lot of maintenance on them
yeah okay and so overall are you put off
by these types of structures because
that's a common complaint we hear from
some people
um yes and no it i think it really just
depends on what it is you're trying to
achieve i mean a properly grown og is
one of the best flowers you'll ever see
so to me it's worth it and there's a
reason why it stuck around so long i
think part of why we stopped seeing the
ogs in the kind of volume that we used
to see them in is just because the price
dropped on the market
and so
you know it wasn't worth growing anymore
it was worth growing something that was
a heavier yielder that required less
work that was less finicky
so for me
personally i love a phenomenal og and
i've never seen a plant with better
structure let's say that actually
delivered the same type of flower
so if you could find it in something
that had better structure and growth
habits i would absolutely take it
but having never really seen anything
like that myself i'm you know i'm i'm
saying it it had it stuck around for a
long time for a reason and i know
inspector has done um some s1 work with
the triangle and the chem 91
and still the plants still look even
though he's got some that stack a little
bit better it looks like there's they
still have the same viny structure it
just requires a lot of maintenance to
them
yeah certainly so you just got to grow
it properly
so you raised a really interesting point
which is kind of on a very different
topic but i'd love to quickly go there
where you mentioned that although these
ogs were elite and they're amazing
flower people stopped growing them
because they kind of fell out of favor
and i witnessed this firsthand when i
was in the states whereby i had a bag of
what was meant to be some sort of like
exotic type of cookie type of thing you
know and it was grown it looked nice but
it had no turps had no flavor was really
quite bland but it looked pretty good
and then next to it was um a bag of the
the clone only headband that's the same
one that mr bob has so i know that it's
like a really good one and the smell was
just super piney
lemony gassy like everything you'd want
the flavor was on point and i'm having
this talk with people and they're like
yeah these bags would go for about the
same price and i was like what but like
the headbands clearly way better and
they were like yeah but people have
smelt that one before like they're used
to that smell you know
do you feel like that's a problem within
the consumer market that we can get to
this point where
shittily grown exotics are fetching the
same or more than like a really killer
tried and tested clone only but just
because of like a name and a hype thing
they're willing to go with the the
exotic one
yeah i mean i think i think we're
already there you know at this point
there's a lot of
what what people are terming exotics a
term that they're using pretty loosely
now
but there's a lot of those going around
and literally just just putting it i
mean honestly at this point just putting
it in the right in the right bag makes
all the difference
and there is there is a segment of the
market that will pay for that and the
the general populace doesn't really know
the difference at all
so the staples like i mean i don't know
if you remember the j1 i used to love
the j1
and it was a phenomenal flower really
really good high nice taste people do
not like jack they've seen so much jack
especially in cali that they they don't
want to see it anymore they're over it
so i think like the higher end market
they want i mean if you've noticed
there's you know
dosi docido crossed with gelato and you
know dosi doe cross with sherb and
that's really what people want i mean i
made something pretty weird
a couple years ago
and it has no traction
it's a vietnam black tie grand doggy
perp crossed with a grand doggie per
banana limon
that's amazing
yeah and that was a cross that took a
long time to make
i made you know i selected the limon
from i selected the limon mill
i hit it to the banana cut we had i
found a male in that and hit it to a
grand doggie perp female
then i found a male from that and then
separate from that i had selected a
vietnam black tie from ace and hit that
with a grand doggie perp male and then
selected a female from that and then
work together that female and the and
the other male
and uh
it's a whole lot of work in there and
really nobody really has any interest in
it i mean it's you know a couple of
people that i know that that that do
care about quality flour
they've told me they've grown it and
they've told me it's some of the most
unique terps they've ever seen
and they love it but
generally speaking if you put something
like that on the market number one most
people you try to explain all those
genetics to them
they they would just go right over their
head they would get a blank look on
their face
but if you just tell them oh it's girl
scout cookie cross with og kush okay
they probably know those things and
they're just gonna go for what they know
versus you know what something
completely unique and different and
that's not you know it's it's kind of
where we're at now where people will
take a poorly grown example of some kind
of exotic that looks good or photographs
well i mean honestly people are buying
things because they can take a picture
and post it on their instagram
so if if the headband smells phenomenal
to you in person has a great effect
but the purple punch whatever cross
looks good and they can photograph it
and put it on their instagram and get a
bunch of likes that's what they're going
to do
most people i mean that's what they're
going to do all things being equal
so
yeah no i i totally get that do you feel
like this is going to ultimately
negatively affect everyone in the
growers start growing out these strains
and we maybe lose some of these better
ones like objectively better but just
not demanded
i do
there's been a huge shift in terms of um
people cultivating varieties that are
photogenic
because they want them to look good on
instagram some plants don't photograph
well
no matter how you grow them like the
chem d is kind of is one of those plants
it doesn't photograph well it doesn't
really i mean it looks okay in a bag it
can be done right as it were
but it's never going to look like a
gelato sherb cross would look it's never
going to have that bag appeal it's not
going to have the purple tones to
photograph well
so there's a lot of genetics that are
getting lost off and i mean even even
when i've tried to share genetics with
people to help back up some of the work
they don't care because if it's not
something that they can immediately put
into production most people don't want
to do it and so there's there's really
it costs a lot of money it takes a lot
of time to back up all these genetics
and i know that's something that
inspector could relate to
it's a conversation that we've had here
and there about that just it's a big
commitment to do all that work and keep
all that together most people don't want
it i mean a similar example is a plant
we have called the lucy it's a chem 91
butterscotch hawaiian
very very unique terpene profile
not the highest yielder a little bit
finicky whatnot but it's you know it's
not something that i don't think anyone
in my circle has kept it around i think
one person that operates a wreck
facility has it
and other than that it's not a plant
that anyone really wants but
when i hit it with the tricks
and a friend of mine has grown them out
now
the owner of the facility came by and
when he was checking out all the
different stuff that they were growing
what he remarked about amongst you know
maybe
six or seven different breeders work
that they had going there was that the
patch of work that would that they that
had that had come from my work all the
strange plants that my friend had
selected independently
were the most unique profiled plants he
had seen and one one was that lucy he
said he never smelt anything like it
before and for me that's that's a big
part of why i keep those plants around
because although they're of zero value
to most people mostly because they don't
really know what they're worth they
don't really see the value in it they
don't understand that if you cross it
into something else you're opening up a
whole new gene pool like but if you just
hit gelato to docido
yeah you're gonna get a bunch of plants
that smell similar that give kind of
somebody in iowa let's say the ability
to grow that type of a plant and smell
that type of a profile
but at the end of the day you're not
really doing anything special you're not
really opening up the possibility of
anything unique i like to take things
from the far end of the spectrum and
combine them together
and that's i think where you're going to
find really really different plants but
somebody has to keep those plants around
and
you literally
nobody wants them you can't find people
that you could you'd have to pay people
to keep them around for you
if you can't keep them
god so many things you just said i just
so deeply relate to like
yeah i know what you mean and what i
wanted to first ask you because i got so
many things i need to ask you in
relation to that first thing the chem 91
butterscotch cross is that from bodhi or
rado
no so that's not rados butterscotch i
don't even i don't know the lineage of
his butterscotch this was made
by someone named poor white farmer
he was off ic mag years ago
and
i believe it might have been from reef
i believe the butterscotch hawaiian came
from reef and he found a male and there
hit the chem 91 and then somebody named
izurasta selected the clone
he passed it to a couple of our friends
on icmeg and that's how i ended up
getting it and i don't know that either
of them
are i mean they may still be alive but i
don't neither of them i've i haven't
seen either of them active in years
so i'm not sure um where where that work
lies but yeah no that's not from rado
i'm not even sure what the lineage on
his butterscotch is to be honest i don't
know if you might know what it is
yeah no i would probably have to look
into it before i say something incorrect
as i'm trying to
trying to vet some of the more random
things i say recently so i'll hold off
on that one i remember seeing a post
with that chem 91 butterscotch cross in
it and then i remembered seeing in that
same post and you also just mentioned it
that there was like a i think it was
cross to tricks
and yeah i crossed it to the tricks yeah
and so i wanted to ask you a little bit
about tricks i noticed that sometimes
you refer to it as gb six tricks what
does that mean
so originally i believe that when loki
selected the plant he got it as as
gorilla breath
that he did a project with gromer and
there was a bunch of work that came out
of that and that's one of those plants
and when he selected it
i think it was just the gorilla breath
six and he named it trix because of the
flavor profile on it um the way like the
wood like the kind of the smell that it
gives off
and so the shortened version is just gb
six tricks rather than gorilla breath
six tricks
ah that makes sense as a quick little
side note what do you think of our
friend groma you know i i've had a few
people come on the show saying well he's
very blatantly ripped off gage green but
then on the other hand people seem to
turn a bit of a blind eye to that and
you know friendly with him what's your
take on that situation
i mean yeah he obviously did so that's i
don't think that's up for discussion at
this point because though the work was
all based on the mendo breath and i
think he has a line recently that's just
another gauge green kind of rip i think
he took um
africa with a grateful breath or
something and started a whole nother
line with that
so but yeah i mean he you know it's
it's it's one of those things where it
would have been previously frowned upon
clearly not frowned upon now i'm sure he
made a whole bunch of money for himself
and he sells them at a low price point
because there's really no work involved
in them i mean you know i could take a
pack from you know archive right now and
do the same thing and people i mean
there's people who have done that
with with work that was put out with my
work so
it's kind of one of those things where
you know it's it gave people access to
something he did it in numbers he did it
in volume he cut the price real low
so
personally
you know for me no but
for people who are just trying to make
some money i totally get it it makes
sense it was there to be had and people
clearly support him and
i mean the work that's come from it
hasn't been bad
because you know it means a lot of it is
dosi dome mendo breath you know docido
from archive and mendo breath from gage
both
both you know made in collaboration with
norcal and that ogkb clone so
not really i mean not
not something that i would do to be
honest but
not mad at him either because i'm sure
he made a pile of money off it and is
still making a pile of money off of it
there's a lot of people out there doing
work with integrity that are broke
so
you know you can kind of look at it and
see really at the end of the day like
who's really winning there
it's interesting that
exactly what you said holds true in my
opinion the best clone that exists in
australia is a jelly breath clone from
in-house genetics and that's just um
docido cross mendo breath you know it's
just his version his feminized version
of essentially the peanut butter breath
from groma but yeah you can't deny it
some really nice weed but i just wanted
to loop back for a moment the reason why
all of this stimulated my interest
initially especially in regards to that
gorilla breath was that i had heard
rumors of other well-known strains been
given the same genetics and i probably
need to explain this a little bit
specifically i'd heard that smell boat's
rainbow ssog
was in fact just gorilla glue for mendo
breath and i'd asked him about it and he
was like what no way like neither of
those plants are you can't even see any
traits from those plants in this thing
but what it made me realize was when i
was hearing these rumors it was just
kind of like two really popular strains
thrown together it was almost as if like
people didn't know what a certain cross
was so they were like oh it's probably
like gg4 cross mendo breath like as in
like it was just two popular things you
could throw together and imply that
someone's just kind of chucking these
two popular things together have you
ever heard of any other strains
being called like oh it's probably gg4
mendo breath even though like it doesn't
really appear to be or anything like
that or is that just my own little weird
experience
no yeah i mean i'm kind of familiar with
small boat but i had never heard that
about that particular cross
i'm sure that somebody else has done a
gg4 mendo breath i would be surprised if
they hadn't um
i'm sure there's a gg4 docido out there
i could bet on that one for sure
the mendo breath you know it wasn't it
was they both kind of came at the same
time and then one ended up obviously
exceeding the popularity of the other
significantly in my opinion that being
the docido
i mean we actually
we actually were the ones that that sold
that clone originally that norcal cut
when that cut actually came out it was
through a delivery service that i had in
sf at the time and we released the
docido norcal cut the number six and the
mendo breath cut which was the platinum
and those you know one one really took
off which was that docido and the other
one didn't really trend as much was the
mendo breath so
really i think the person that's worked
with the mental breath the most
obviously besides gage has has been
grommer because he worked with it for a
long time it has to be years now
yeah i don't really know that anyone
else has really worked with it that
significantly
yeah well i mean i guess just to kind of
wrap up this little sag we've been
talking about what are your thoughts on
gage
uh i mean they're weird there's no
denying that i don't think there's uh
they're a little bit strange um
muscle i'm friends with norcal and
norcal and my buddy frost boss and my
buddy unknown prophet and myself we all
go back a long way in the bay area
the four of us
and norcal was how i came to know about
gage um but he's he's a really good guy
he he's open to working with a lot of
people
and he worked with gage in some way
shape or form
my understanding of their relationship
was that it was not very beneficial to
him and so in that regard to me not
really people that i'm a huge fan of
simply because if my friend says that it
didn't go right i know the kind of guy
he is so i imagine it's on their side
plus i've seen them caught up in all
kinds of all kinds of online debating
and whatnot um and people who debate
online are not people that i want to
associate with
so
the work is interesting they seem weird
and i personally have never run any of
their work besides the mendo breath
cuttings that norcal gave me
but i know a lot of people like their
work
so
you know i think i think one of them is
a flat earther that's a little bit
strange to me and then just the way that
they present themselves online is kind
of off-putting to me and the reality is
besides the mendo breath
i don't really know any of their other
work that i'm intrigued by
yeah that's an interesting point i mean
i'll i'll be honest there's a few of
their crosses i've seen that do catch my
eye particularly that high school
sweetheart one but
um i agree with you they're an
interesting crew and our friend michael
fong the flat earther he's another
interesting chap and
i wouldn't be surprised if one day we
get him on the show i think it'd be a
cool chat but anyway
let's let's take it back now we've been
having a good little detour here let's
go back to our original first question
which we normally start the show with
what was your first experience with
cannabis
wow
yeah
my first experience with cannabis was
with some friends of mine when i was
younger one of their parents was a
deadhead
and i was spending the night over there
and they stole they stole a little bit
of flour from them
and we sat up after everyone went to bed
and smoked it
laid down and had that typical first
experience where you're wondering like
am i feeling anything or what is this
um
everything went fine
didn't think anything of it went to bed
the next day woke up felt a little bit
different just thinking okay well
clearly it's not it's not what the dare
program and everybody else said it was i
think i was about like 13 at the time
and then i really didn't didn't smoke
much after that it took um a couple
years before i really got into smoking
because it didn't really grab me
and then
i remember
meeting with some friends
where i was living in miami at the time
and grabbing some flour from one of
their older brothers he actually had
some blueberry
and remember smoking that and being like
oh yeah okay like i get it now
and pretty much obsessed with that i
mean i think we ended up going to see a
movie at the mall and i
we were waiting for the movie we went up
in the parking garage to smoke
right before the movie i walked back in
there were some benches in front of the
movie theater i remember laying down and
telling them
when it was time to go in i said no i'm
good you guys can go i'm good
um and they told me like you can't lay
out here man you have to you have to
come into the movie theater so i went in
with them
um but i loved it i completely fell in
love with it it i mean it's a it's a
plant that you know it changed my life
i've been dedicated to this plant for
you know over 20 years now
and in spite of everything else any
little detours i've taken in life i've
always circled back
to the plant constantly it's it's i mean
it changed my life clearly just like a
lot of the people that you probably
speak to
clearly we've dedicated a lot like a lot
of time and energy into this
so yeah i've been i was kind of spoiled
though because i'd never seen
i'd never seen regs before and in
florida there was really only like regs
or like like like nugget you know it was
like oh you either had you either had
crippy or you had
rags
and
i i was spoiled because i'd only smoked
like i'd only smoke crippy i only smoked
like kind butter whatever you want to
call it only smoked like
nicer indoor flour
and then i remember the first time i saw
some rags we all we all faded in on i'm
supposed to be like i think like a
quarter pound and when my friends asked
me to fade in on it i was kind of
surprised by like the small amount of
money that it was
and when they showed up with it and
started breaking it up i didn't even
know what the seeds were i was
completely confused about the stems the
seeds all of that i tried to take one
hit of a blunt they were old and i said
no i'm good um i'm just going to hit my
pipe in my little jar weed that i
brought with me
well there you go and was that when you
say rags was that kind of like brickweed
or just like not as good as kind
brickweed brickweed pressed miami
brickweed
yeah well and so i know that back in
those days names weren't a big thing but
do you remember the first name strain
you ever smoked
so
my friend's brother would get blueberry
that was the first thing that i actually
smoked um
and then in florida there was a juicy
fruit which was like another one that
was popular i want to say the other one
was called orange crush
and there was like one more that i can't
remember off top but really there was
only i don't know how it is in australia
but um when in florida there you only
could really get from people that you
knew and if it wasn't like brickweed
basically out of like some suspect spot
um it was through the same kind of
contact and they just had the same type
of stuff
and so you really didn't have much of an
option
and so we would get a lot of that juicy
fruit that orange crush
i forget what some of the other ones
were
um
and then a friend of mine actually grew
some of the first stuff from seed i ever
saw which was they had brought back some
shishka berry seeds
and so that was that was like the first
actual something from seed that i where
i knew the people that actually grew it
that's cool okay so did you have like an
inclination towards spice of life at
that point given shisha berry kind of
opened your eyes or was that like an
afterthought
to be honest i didn't even know who they
were
um i was so paranoid about any kind of
online searching for anything at that
time
that i didn't want anything to do with
it and in florida if you knew someone
like you just you just didn't say
anything because the people that were
growing were so quiet about it
that you you just you couldn't say
anything about anything to anybody so it
wasn't even really it wasn't really even
a conversation that you could have with
someone to even ask questions about it
was more like here i've got this take it
you don't want it okay you can't have it
now because you took too long you asked
questions they didn't like it
so you just you know you had it was like
if you didn't grow up with certain
people you were just you were excluded
from certain circles you just weren't
welcome
so i didn't even know about steve or
spice of life or any of that but i have
i have enjoyed some of his work i like
the blue satellite from him
um
i would like to grow some shishka berry
at some point
it's kind of a shame because a lot of
that flour nowadays with the way the
wreck markets are moving here in the
states
they're not really desirable because a
lot of those higher terpene interesting
different varieties they don't they
don't test over 20 percent and consumers
in the stores that's that's what they're
really obsessed with is like varieties
over 20 percent
and you know if if something has a
really really unique terpene profile but
it tests 13 or 14 it's going to be
eliminated that's another thing that's
going to affect the gene pool going
forward is like this focus on commercial
breeding
is really is really going to change
what people are doing
i think it's interesting because
i think it's this the same situation in
the states but it's certainly the case
down under that there's this whole kind
of renaissance and explosion of craft
beers and there's this idea of like
people are moving away from just your
stock standard commercial stuff and
looking for that more boutique type of
thing do you think that'll ever happen
with cannabis or the current trend you
just described where people
are kind of a bit ignorant of what
they're actually looking for as a
consumer do you think that will continue
i think i think it might happen um i
think it'll take time and by then i
think we'll have lost a lot of the
genetics
there'll there'll be people here and
there that have preserved some things
there'll be some seeds that we'll be
able to pull from
but i do feel like there's a lot of
diversity that's getting lost and work
that's not being done
one day consumers might might be
educated enough
might be interested enough in asking for
that but currently with the way the
regulatory landscape is set up it's very
difficult to operate and i think that in
the future when we're able to actually
have interstate commerce so if you know
if a facility was located let's say in
you know arizona but it could ship all
over the country kind of like you know a
small vineyard might
i think you'll have more access to that
boutique market
the same way that the breweries do but
right now with the way it's set up and
you know just kind of having to operate
within a state and comply with the local
regulations and if you want to expand
into another state you have to set up
another facility
it's just not it's it's geared towards
rich people it's geared towards the
wealthiest people and right now what
they're doing is they're grabbing
the hugest piece of the markets possible
they're setting up all across the
country so they're you know they'll be
everywhere before they give the craft
people kind of a chance to expand and
oregon has a small craft market but it's
been brutal and oklahoma's about to go
through the same thing a lot of people
are popping up over there because it's
so inexpensive but what's going to
happen is is the same thing that
happened in oregon
markets are going to get decimated and a
lot of people are going to lose are
going to are going to lose what they've
invested not everyone is going to
survive that
but i do think that oregon is a place
where you might see that craft market
and you know i could point to brands
like resin ranchers
smaller companies that feed you know
they understand the market and they're
not they're not over producing they
could expand they choose not to
they found a happy medium and a way to
survive within that but they also had
deep deep roots in the medical scene
before the recreational market hit so
they had those relationships in place
they had local connections they were
able to make the transition and i'm sure
at some point you know if we spoke to
them they would tell you it wasn't easy
but they managed to make it work and
people know you know and our archive is
a good curator of local
kind of craft products in oregon if
people want to if you can get your
product on their shelf it says something
about your company
yeah right i remember when i visited the
oregon store a few years ago they
definitely had some nice flour there
something i forgot to mention earlier
when you're talking about j1 how good is
j1 i love j1 i can't believe it i love
j1 people people don't even it's maybe
it's me and you then
but people don't people don't seem to
care for it i think it's a phenomenal
flower i think it's resinous it's
flavorful it grows impeccably it yields
well i love the high from it i feel like
a lot of people they want the narcotic
high nowadays they have for years but
they especially seem to want it now i
don't know if it's just the current
state of affairs or whatnot
but
i think the j1 is a phenomenal flower i
mean i'm i was i grew that plant for a
long time and i was i was bummed when i
lost it
um i know it still exists i know some
people still grow it
and really i mean it's a jack profile
with better structure better flower
better finishing time better bag appeal
i think it's amazing i love it
yeah the thing i noticed about it is no
one breathes with it ever
that's true that's true um i would like
to at some point i definitely need to
make an effort to get that cut back in
the rotation but yeah if you look around
you don't see any crosses with it part
of that might be because i think people
wonder that if you put jack into
something is anyone gonna want it
and it's weird a lot of breeding is done
with that kind of intention like what is
the market gonna want
and for years you know i mean even even
before i started you know offering seeds
publicly
i just bred whatever i wanted i didn't
really think about what people wanted i
thought about what what i wanted to see
and
i mean that's that's why i've read the
stuff that i've made like
has nothing to had literally zero
consideration for the market at all
you know but i learned i mean i it's
easy to see like what people want and
what they don't want but i think i think
a plan like the j1 just if you tell
people there's jack in something
especially in the bay area the face
they're gonna make is not is not one of
approval
well that's almost like a bit of a good
little segue so if we loop back to
you were talking about how you'd started
smoking what was the progression like in
the transition from say smoker to grower
for you
yeah so i started smoking um floyd i
grew up in florida it's a pretty
difficult state to operate and i think
you know you find a lot of people in
this especially on the west coast that
were from florida because you had to
have a real passion for it and that's
something that that doesn't get tamped
out i mean at the time
um i was going to school in gainesville
and i was growing
i i had a friend of mine had started
growing when he came back from amsterdam
and when i saw it i'd seen a setup
before
i didn't even know what it was when i
saw a friend of mine took me to a
friend's basement in chicago and i went
downstairs
you know he said hey it's my guy he's
cool
whatever whatever he takes me downstairs
and i see
um a makeshift space i think it honestly
i think it had to be like two by fours
and some kind of plastic it wasn't not
anything fancy and he opens it up
and i see a bulb in there and some light
and some plants and in retrospect now
looking back i'm like yeah they were
they were pretty rough looking
but i didn't know the difference between
a metal halide and an hps whatever it
might be
and i asked him kind of some questions
and he was actually making seeds in
there he had a male in there and he was
actually making seeds which
totally random um that kind of surprised
me but it kind of stuck with me and it
made me think like wow you could just
you can just do this not having ever
seen anyone do it before it just i said
yeah this is something that you could do
if you just had a little bit of space
so when i got back to florida um i sold
a guitar and an amp that i had and i
went and bought a 400 watt light
and i set up a space at a house that i
was renting
and i remember padlocking the door um
you know if we would have some people
over here and there um then somebody
would say something about the smell i
would tell them oh you know we smoke we
smoke a lot of weed and they would
inevitably say that's not what weed
smoke smells like
um
but i remember setting up just a small
closet space with a 400 and i got some
cuttings from a friend of mine
i started growing them in there
grew them and it actually was some
reclining buddha by soma
at the time and i remember growing it
and
somebody that i used uh somebody i used
to provide
mentioned something about the cherry
flavor in the flower not knowing that i
had grown it not knowing anything about
it supposedly having a cherry type
flavor and i that really stuck with me
and it made me it made me think about
all the different possibilities that
were that were out there and i was in
school i didn't like it
i did not enjoy the whole school system
to be honest i thought it was kind of a
waste of time and money and a money grab
for the most part i think you know for
certain professions it makes sense but
in general for all kids to go to school
just
doesn't really make a lot of sense and
so
i was growing for about a year and a
half out there and i remember um just it
was mandatory minimums at the time for
any kind of cultivation there
so
like a single plant was you know
mandatory minimum i think it was three
to five years
and um
at that point i had i had a friend would
move to san diego
and so
in talking with him um and you know my
family they basically said like hey if
you're gonna keep doing this maybe you
should just move out west so you don't
go to jail and uh i packed up i sold
everything and i moved out west and gave
it a shot out there in san diego that's
actually where i got my first taste of
like real southern california like high
grade because i used to fly out there
all the time but like living out there
and being out there was totally
different you really got to see what was
happening and at the time there was a
medical scene this was after 2 15 had
passed
and
[Music]
it was very very different what was
happening out there they had clubs but
they were getting shut down and harassed
san diego is a beautiful place but it's
very conservative and
not very very cannabis friendly although
there is a large scene there but that
was where i first started seeing things
like the bull rider
the p91 the cat piss all that stuff and
um they grew some they had some afghani
whatnot and i just remember seeing just
the sheer volume of flour that was
coming out of out of the area in general
and it really you know it stuck with me
and so i had the chance to move out
there i gave it a go
um it didn't work out a friend of mine
got addicted to oxies so that that kind
of went sideways i don't know how much
people have spoken about that kind of
stuff but this business is not easy um
the lifestyle is not easy
it's a lot you know you might see people
that people think are successful but i
don't think people know everything they
had to go through and how many times
they had to try and how many times they
didn't quit
before they were able to see some
success i mean it's a tough business and
you know definitely that type of
lifestyle at the time it was not a
traditional lifestyle so you know
definitely pills and whatnot and
everything we're around
and that's kind of when oxy i think
we're starting to get a hold on people
out there so that didn't really work out
um i ended up
leaving everything moving back east
working again saving some more money and
then
i was kind of over it because i hadn't i
hadn't been to norcal i was kind of over
it san diego just reminded me of l.a
and miami crossed together and i said to
do that i'll just go back and live in
miami i like miami
and then
um some friends of mine were out in lake
tahoe and they invited me out for the
summer to go visit out there they lived
on what i call perpetual hippie tour so
they just you know work save money go on
hippie tour come back broke work save
money same thing over and over again
and uh i went out there to lake tahoe
and it was stunning it was beautiful i'd
never seen anything like it never seen
anything like it i don't know if you've
had the chance to get to lake tahoe but
it's beautiful stunning you know
impactful
and had a chance to go down to oakland
with my friends and i remember being at
somebody's house
at a friend of my friend's house
and they had told him you know this is
this is my guy been friends for a long
time so everything was fine with me and
him but somebody came by
um with a duffel bag and a bunch of
perps a bunch of perp packs and which
was you know huge in the bay area at
that time that was like around 2005
2006 and uh
i remember them
um you know doing whatever they were
doing with the per packs and then him
pulling out like a pound of purple keef
and saying like i don't know what to do
with this
and at that point that's when i chimed
in and said you know well you know i'll
take that and he didn't know who i was
he was completely thrown off by me the
guy sitting on the couch smoking not
saying anything saying i'll take that
and um but it just it was obvious to me
at that point that like i was in the
wrong place because
i'm in a city right now where people
have a pound of purple keith and don't
know what to do with it i'd never seen a
pound of purple keef anywhere like so it
blew my mind and i was like yeah i'm
coming back to oakland and so you know i
went home i worked saved more money sold
everything i owned and rented a
warehouse off craigslist
not not having ever seen it and
just moved out with two duffel bags and
you know bought some lights and got to
work out there and
kind of built up from there
i mean it definitely you know it wasn't
it was not easy uh to give it a run i
don't know if you if you spent any time
in oakland oakland is getting gentrified
now it's a lot more cleaned up as it
were but
still a rough city um and still you know
but a place a place that lives eats and
sleeps high grade cannabis in my opinion
i know my friends in socal might differ
but i think i think the bay area is the
epicenter of global cannabis not even
not even you know just in california but
globally and no knock on you know
humboldt or whatever the emerald
triangle all that stuff they do their
thing up there but if you really really
look at who's been making the waves over
the last decade
it's the bay area and if anyone has any
claim before that it's socal you know
with the og's
but since then
it's been all the bay area i mean all of
it you know the cookies
the gelatos the sherbs everything all
this stuff it's just been bay area bay
area bay area for you know probably the
last seven or eight years maybe 10 years
yeah 100
i mean there's there's so many things we
can touch on there the first thing i
wanted to do before we move past it you
mentioned the bull rider the p91 and the
cat pierced down in san diego sounds
like you were down there when matt was
kind of doing his thing matt riot were
you familiar with him at all or not
really i i was not i avoided any kind of
social interaction possible with people
that were outside of my circle
um i think it's a big reason why i've
managed to kind of stay out of trouble
a lot of these guys have had run-ins or
had you know people snitch on them or
whatever it might be or get robbed
and i pretty much avoided everyone
i was connected with one circle of
people out there
that had access to all of those flowers
they were born and raised in san diego
so all those guys you know had gone to
school there and so they you know they
all
they all had the local connections for
those flowers um and a lot of those
flowers i mean you don't see them
anymore like anywhere and even the bull
rider it fell off years and years later
i know people are out there now saying
that they still have it and grow it i'd
like to see it
to see if it is what it is i almost
think at this point you could just tell
people it's bull rider and them having
never seen it they wouldn't know the
difference
because it's just some afghani right
yes supposedly you know not having been
there for for it um that's my
understanding of it and you know it
didn't have the big the best bag appeal
or anything it was big flowers you could
tell it yielded um and there was also
there was a super silver haze that was
being grown out there in long beach at
the time too
um that was phenomenal i mean ridiculous
and there was a cali mist and i mean i i
kind of i kind of miss those days there
was some flower that you couldn't buy
like there was such a limited amount it
was already spoken for people would
prepay for the flower which is something
that i don't know that if young people
even like would understand what that is
like they would pre-pay before the
harvest so that they could have their
their share of that harvest
and there was a super silver haze that
was like that and the guy that i knew
who would get it he wouldn't sell any of
it he would only trade me so i'd have to
trade him like that this super silver
haze let's say that i would get for the
cali mist that he was getting and it was
just like a one-to-one trade that was it
like as much as i was willing to give up
that's as much as he was willing to give
up and
it was um you know it was different
there was just there was more limited
limited flower out there at the time but
you know i didn't i didn't know matt
um yeah seems like he he seems like he
was more social i mean definitely i
think he was into like the punk rock
scene and whatnot so
he was definitely out there um i was
hanging out with jamaicans and a totally
different type of scene in like mission
beach and pb out there
yeah cool okay and so then what was your
transition from going as just a grower
to then starting to make your own seeds
yeah so
so we were on icmag a bunch of us and
you know i had tried to buy seeds years
ago off like heaven's stairway or
something
they didn't make it i freaked out i was
in florida the time i said i'm not
buying anything else through the mail
i'm over it
and then i knew people that were buying
off off ic mag off uh seed bay and seed
boutique and so i said you know what i
said i'm gonna start getting some seeds
and i started just collecting some seeds
and sending some money orders here and
there and grabbing some stuff
and i actually the first thing i ever
tried to do was i took a male from a
pack of soma's reclining buddha and
tried to hit a bunch of things but i
learned a valuable lesson from that in
that like at all everything that i grew
from that was terrible it was all trash
and i did it to my bubble jack the east
coast sour and a couple other things and
they were just trash it was nothing good
came from that mail
and so i chucked all those seeds
whatever whatever with that and then
some friends of mine
were doing a lot of outdoor work and you
know we were talking about like how the
blue dream would go deep into november
it was a great plan for outdoor
cultivation but they wanted something
that would finish faster
and i had some williams wonder
from reef
and so um we popped those found a male
and hit the blue dream with that because
we figured all right this is going to be
a plant that is going to this is really
going to be a phenomenal plant for
outdoor cultivation it should finish
faster
from the afghani influence it should
still be resonance it should still you
know be real chunky hopefully pick up
some resistance to pm and botrytis and
whatever it might be
so we started that project and that's
something we worked on over a couple of
years just kind of in our own world
nothing to do with any kind of
thoughts towards vending seeds or a seed
company or anything
it was just something that we worked on
collaboratively as a group
and so we worked that for a couple of
generations and that's where that wet
dream plant came from and that was my
first like realization like okay like
yeah you can use a male but
they're definitely not all the same and
it doesn't matter what kind of female
you cross it to if the male is trash
like the work that comes from that is
going to be trash so we got lucky you
know we got lucky and the mail that we
used was really solid and from there you
know we did one further selection and
then i've done a couple of open open
populations since then just to kind of
spread it out and uh see see what kind
of variants we might find in there and
not not bottleneck the gene pool
so that's you know that was probably the
first actual breeding projects that we
did as a group was just a couple of
friends with just an intention to breed
something that would do better and
finish faster and at the time we weren't
even really doing the depths it was all
just the larger full season plants so we
just wanted something that would still
you know throw down big plants but
finish quicker
and what was your impressions of the
williams wonder strain that's something
we frequently reminisce about on the
show
yeah so i
we loved it um
some of the when when i was living in
chicago for a while i was staying out
there
for a little bit and um the packs that
we would get were the willys is what we
used to call them and they were coming
out of oregon at the time which my
understanding is like that's where that
variety was developed
and i loved it i mean beautiful
like electric green resinous flowers
large
like nowadays you know it would be hard
it would be hard to really find
something comparable to it but because
you know a lot of what's popular now is
like the candy stuff and the fruit sweet
stuff or whatever it might be
it was like a real hashy plant
um
but potent you know potent like the high
from it was what we really really
enjoyed it's beautiful beautiful flower
and that's something that i mean you
just you don't see it around anymore
there's like i i mean i imagine it might
still exist somewhere i like i think
inspect and i've talked about it there's
usually someone in the hill somewhere
holding something but they don't talk to
anyone and so you probably never see it
but that's that's a really old plant
that i just don't think that you see
anything like that anywhere else anymore
yeah certainly it seems like people are
kind of madly looking for any remnants
of it so
for the next little bit of chat i wanted
to touch on something which i think
everyone will be really interested to
hear the story about which probably a
lot of people aren't actually aware that
you were the person who found the forum
cut
that's true would you be able to give us
the backstory on that one
yeah absolutely yeah people have asked
for years i've just never like i said
you know i never really wanted any
attention for anything so
i mean i think people have uh people
have said that profit was the one that
gave it out and or my other buddy uh
frost boss
both of them have probably been
um both of them have probably been
involved in like the actual story more
than myself publicly
um so what happened there was we used to
have a get-together party and i see mag
party in vegas there was just kind of
just for a bunch of us together like
invite only we would like rent a house
and get out there and whatnot i i had
tried to avoid as much as humanly
possible um going to any of these events
just because why do i want to be in a
building with a bunch of growers
so i tried to avoid it for a while but
one of our friends had got into some
legal trouble
and i had helped him out when he got
popped and they took all his plants i
always have
um extra like just i always have an
excessive amount of edge plants because
you just never know when you're going to
need them and if you need them i'd
rather have them you can always chop
them down you can always do whatever
with them but you at least have them on
deck so when when our friend had got in
trouble and they'd cut down his garden
taking all his plants and whatnot i knew
when he got out he was going to need
some help
and so i hit him up and just asked if he
wanted anything i could help him out and
so i got him some plants got him
replugged and he said to me you know we
have this party in vegas you should
really come out
i hadn't really wanted to go out but he
talked me into it so i ended up going
out and i met uh frost boss and um i
don't think profit profit was there that
year
for the first one but i met frost boss
and i remember hanging out with him
and uh you know we were both from the
bay and he had told me about something
called cookies he said yeah man there's
something called cookies have you heard
of it
and i said nah i never heard of it and
he said oh man it's it's it's special
man you should check it out and i was
like yeah yeah whatever whatever because
i was growing nothing but sour and oh
geez at that time i didn't really have
any interest i mean sour noji had
reigned supreme for so long that why
would i be interested in anything else
to be honest like i'd seen a lot of
people come with other flour none of it
you know exceeded the towers or the ogs
so what what was the point
um
but he had told me about something
called cookies and whatnot and so when
we got back
he came by my house one day and in his
pocket he had a little smashed up nugget
inside a ziploc bag like a tiny tiny
little 0.3.4 nugget
and it was abused it didn't really look
that great
it had some purple color to it and
whatnot i didn't think much of it
i broke it up though i ground it up and
i put it in my volcano and so i i've
been vaporizing for a long time i do it
mostly because of the health benefit but
also because it's honestly the most
flavorful way
to experience flour in my opinion if
you're just about the terpene profile if
you really just want to know what it
tastes like you know that's gonna be the
best way to get that full experience so
i ground it up i stuck it in the volcano
i vaped it and instantly i kinda i got
what he was talking about
and
i started asking around um he knew the
people he's familiar and you know he
knows all all he knows that whole circle
he's from sf
but he didn't have access to the cut and
so cause i asked and he said yeah if we
can get it we should get it
and so i asked a couple of friends of
mine who were actually one of them was
the same person that i worked with on
the wet dream and
they didn't even know what i was talking
about they had no clue so i said
specifically i said it's something
called cookies
this that and the other ask around and
see see if you can find it
he asked a friend of ours he didn't know
what it was that friend actually asked
another person that they knew
who ran a hydro store in the emeryville
area
and he was married to an asian girl
whose family ran a grow spot somewhere
in that area
um
it turned out that although he didn't
have it
they did
and we asked about it and they said oh
you know we need we need like six grand
or five grand or whatever it was at that
time
um
and you know we kind of i think we all
just kind of looked at each other like
ah you know is it really is it worth it
i mean that's that you know it's a lot
of money for a cut
especially at that time and um we
decided that it was and he basically
said he could get a lower price if you
know if we gave him a cut so they they
gave us one plant um he took a cutting
off of it my other friend who put it
together took a cutting off it and my
friend who had
who had kind of put the whole thing
together through these other people he
didn't have a place to keep it so he
gave it to me and said hey hold on to it
because he knows if you give it to me
i'm gonna hold on to it
and so i remember getting it and ramping
it up and posting about it actually on
icmag at the time it's probably the
first post about cookies like ever
publicly
and i remember posting about it and just
saying hey i got this girl scout cookies
blah blah blah whatever
um grew it you know started growing it
out what not and it you know showed uh
my buddy frost boss and profit the
samples of it and it was cookies
um
and so we had it at that time and what
happened was i had a small get-together
at my house and i gave a cutting to four
different people
my buddy frost boss cut a cutting
profit out of cutting
and two other people that were there got
cuttings
and
at that point i didn't pass it with any
restrictions i didn't say you can't sell
it i gave it to them for free i didn't
think they were gonna sell it
i didn't really see what you know what
they would i didn't think that it would
end up going the way that it did
and what ended up happening was yeah
people started hitting them up to buy
the cuts people came up from la people
came from all over the place
cuttings went to a couple different
people from there and then
cuttings made it all the way to the uk i
know um i see mag people out there got
it got it through people that we know
out here
and it just kind of it just kind of went
off i mean it got to the point where
when people were typing girl scout
cookies in the search engine the ic mag
thread was coming up which is why they
made us rename it so we weren't allowed
to type girl scout cookies anymore we
had to type gsc
and at that point um is when people
started calling it the forum cut and it
started because people outside the board
and people amongst the board started
getting it
and it really just spread like wildfire
i mean then i think animal came animal
wasn't a thing at that time and you know
our buddy straight flame he would have
some insight into this but
in my circle with with these guys animal
didn't exist there was just cookies um
and as far as we knew
that was it i didn't there was the word
thin mint the word platinum none of that
had ever been uttered there was no
there was no differentiation it was just
cookies
um
and i think at that time is when like it
started to kind of gain popularity
and part of it i think part of the
reason why i think it did gain the
popularity is because it got out so much
i think if it hadn't got out
nobody would ever really seen it it you
know it would have been it would have
been some of the nicest herb nobody ever
got to try and to be honest like the
packs that they were growing were not
very good like the asian packs and the
packs from the guys in the city were not
really the greatest examples of cookies
i think it really took it getting into
the hands of some people who actually
cared about cultivating better flower
and once once people really put a lot of
intent into it they saw like wow you
know this is some really there's some
really high grade flower it's beautiful
you know
stunning totally different than anything
we were growing at the time
and some of the first cookie packs to
get to the green door came out of my
garden and i remember going in there one
day after i've been bending cookie packs
to them for a while and seeing like they
had like platinum cookies and i said
what's was platinum cookies and they
said oh that's that's your cookies we
just we just renamed it because there's
other cookie packs now coming that
aren't as good so they started putting
like regular cookies there and then
platinum cookies and then from there
came like thin mint and this and that
and i think the cookie guys even came
out and said that it wasn't real cookies
but if you ask around now like globally
speaking if people know cookies it's
it's that cut um
whatever whatever you know people people
i think it's kind of one of those things
where people might have forum and they
might say oh it's thin mentor it might
be this or it might be that i know that
there was a different group in la that
i've spoken with
some friends of my friends down there
that had a cookie cut around the same
time
and so around that like 09010
kind of area or yeah basically right
around there is when people started
popping up with some of these other ones
but there really wasn't any
differentiation at all an animal became
a thing i mean i saw the animal from my
buddy frost boss that's who i got the
cut from and we ran them side by side
they were a little bit different but i
honestly think that i think there was
just a bunch of s-ones of whatever
like whatever or or a bunch of femme
seeds
that that forum probably came from and
that all the cookies probably came from
because if you've noticed there's never
been a cookie mail ever
ever like and if you would think if you
had the most pop one of the most popular
strains in the last 20 years
you would be capitalizing on that by by
breeding with the male
but it doesn't exist that i've ever seen
and it's been a long time since since
that plant's been out so that's you know
i think that's probably
the majority of the story besides the
fact you know that there was all kinds
of all kinds of crazy things going on
with that cut i mean there was it got to
the point where it was it was just
everywhere and that honestly like i've
never really said anything about it but
that's something that kind of sat with
me a little bit poorly was that people
started using the term like whoring it
out and i didn't like that because i
felt like it was disrespectful i mean
it's something that we put out for free
i put it out for free you know we paid
for it and we put it out for free and so
for people to kind of like treat it like
that kind of left a salty taste in my
mouth i think it's why i really haven't
been a proponent of passing out a lot of
cuts i'm very very selective now about
where and who i pass cuts to
um and i i learned a lot from that
because i think also you started seeing
a lot of poor examples of the flower and
that that goes down to one of my one of
my uh one of my favorite hashtags that i
don't use that much but it it's
basically stop stop giving shitty
growers good cuts
because they make it look bad somebody
sees an example of it and then says oh
well you know i've had cookies and it's
not that good
no
you just had a shitty example of it it's
it's proper herb
like grown right it's beautiful flower
and it's look at the staying power i
mean it's been
it's the most significant variety since
og
and i challenge anyone to point out
another variety it's not perps either i
mean i love the perps and it was big in
the bay area but it never went national
it never went global
like it's a bay area thing you know
nobody in new york was asking for perps
like people did want cookies
no that's that's a really good recount
so i think the first thing i'd want to
follow up with is i'd always assume that
the forum cut was just like an s1 of
thin mint do you feel that that's maybe
not the case or what do you think was
the original girl scout cut that the
cookie fam had
yeah so i don't i don't think so i think
that if anything
probably in those like they had they had
and so frost boss um i've spoken to him
a little bit about it there there were
some seated packs back back then
um and he even he worked like deseeding
some of these packs and we think that
that's where the girl scout cookies like
seeds came from
um because i think what happened was
that there was i i've always said i
could be wrong and this is one of those
things where i'd love to see
i'd love to see it if i'm wrong or if
i'm not but at the time you know the the
ogs and the cherry pie were like what
was really really popular in the bay and
a lot of people had those in their
gardens and everybody knows that the
cherry pie is unstable and whenever i've
looked at the cookies that's what i see
i see cherry pie and og like i see i see
it in the structure i see it in the
color i see it in the flavor i see it in
the profile like all of the above like
that's that's what i've seen
um to me i think that
there was you know an accidental
pollination
and they grew some of the seeds out and
that's probably where their cookie cut
came from
i imagine that the forum cut came out of
that same pack of seeds let's say as it
were out of those same packs and that
they just grew it themselves
independently
and that's where we got that cut from i
could be wrong but like i said there
would the word thin mint had never got
uttered like that word did not exist
like that
that like that description of a specific
cutting was not a thing like my buddy
frost boss never said oh there's this
thin mint or there's this platinum it
was just cookies and after cookies came
like animal and that was it like it was
cookies and then animal and then i
started hearing people talking about
thin mint and all this other stuff i
think that may have been a reaction on
their part to try and say
hey we have something that's not what
everyone else has it's not the cut
that's going around we have thin mint
cookies and that's the cookie fam
version of it but i could be wrong you
know i would love to hear their
perspective on it if that's the case
like you know one of the things that
that does crack me up is when they talk
about breeding because if you bread it
where's the mail
like
and even if not what did you reverse to
make it happen they keep talking about
oh it's this and f1 derb and blah blah
blah it's like i was in the bay there
people can say whatever they want to say
and i'd love to have my buddy straight
flame clarify some points and he might
um
i've never seen it
you know and we've seen a lot of flower
and just
that's the bay area is very very tight
like in terms of like what's happening
and who's growing what like
people know what's going around like we
eat sleep and breathe it and so if there
was such a thing we would have heard
about it it's not a thing like and if
you like i said if there was this f1
derp and you used it to make this you
know generational flower
why not use it again
yeah like
where's it at
so with all that being said about the
girl scout cookies do you tend to try to
avoid working with the forum cut now
because it is so widespread and used or
is it just something you're not
particularly interested in working with
or do you have plans for in the future
how do you see the whole situation
yeah so i've actually
have my bread with it yeah you know i
actually hit it once and i only made a
few seeds with it i did a forum with the
sh with the sherb
um but i've never actually grown i
haven't grown them out yet
uh i mean i think initially when we
first got it like i just i had such
respect for people breeding that i just
didn't really feel like that was like
the thing to do
was just to like
run on it and just cash in on it and
whatnot so
just avoided it and now
i think generally
um
i think i'm just more interested in
other types of work there's so much work
that's similar to it now whether it's
the docido and whatnot
that i just don't really see
what i would do with it um
if anything for me you know as a plant
and of itself i appreciate it for
breeding purposes
it's not really the direction that i'm
looking to go in one of the things that
really surprised me about it was you
know we we'd all been told and kind of
the common thought was that oh it's a
crazy poly hybrid and whatnot so you
know you're not it's not going to be
stable you're not going to find anything
good in it it's actually incredibly
dominant in a lot of the crosses like it
really really comes out in the crosses
similar to kind of how the docido does
the cookie the cookies tend to really
really shine through in a lot of these
crosses
so for me
it's not that i'm avoiding it i've
actually thought about doing a femme
project with the forum i thought it
might be fun
there's just a lot of other stuff on the
plate that's kind of like looking
forward that i think are more valuable
you know in terms of in terms of what
i'm trying to do with my time
so i as much as i love it i think i
would include it in some projects but
not necessarily right now is like the
focus of what i'm trying to do um i
could see it being a part of something
but not being like the main piece in
everything
yeah okay
and so how do you feel about cookies in
general not just the various cuttings
but like the brand and where they're
trying to take the whole image of it all
i mean it's cool you know i see them i
mean there was clearly a split between i
think like the like like sherbinsky and
all those guys even amongst themselves
and then burner with the cookies brand
because i think that's just burner that
cookies brand
and um it's interesting what they've
done you know they've definitely
capitalized on it i have nothing but
respect for being able to go out there
and get a piece of something for
themselves
in terms of like what it actually is
like
i don't have a lot of interest in it in
and of itself me
um definitely can't knock the hustle
though i see them out there you know
between burner with the stores or
scherbinski doing his thing
some of the other guys they don't seem
as active um
i think pie guy and jacob maybe is a
little bit more active
but
i have no knock on it um
i've some of the work that i've seen
hasn't been great so i just kind of like
not really excited about it i mean i'm
sure you saw some of the work at emerald
cup like there was definitely a lot of
people there that had work that was more
impressive to me but as a brand
i mean there's no denying it they've
they've crushed it you know it's a huge
brand it's globally recognized at this
point
and you know whichever one of them you
know whatever piece you're looking at
they've definitely done something with
it that i think a lot of people whether
they want to admit it or not a lot of
people would have liked to be able to do
they just weren't able to tie all the
pieces together
yeah so they had something yeah and they
capitalized on it
they've certainly done some things well
for sure but let's talk about what they
could have done better what do you think
are some of the things they've fallen
short on
i honestly think that if they had all
stayed working together
and not maybe and you know i wasn't
there so i don't know but usually in
this business there's a lot of ego
people are used to being what i call
king of their own castles you know
they've all had their own warehouses
they've all had their own spots they're
all used to being their own bosses a lot
of them have never worked for anybody
else or even really worked with anybody
else in any kind of significant capacity
it's why so many of these relationships
fall apart in this business people don't
know how to communicate and set clear
expectations they're not professional
i honestly think that there's companies
on their way to billion dollar
valuations right now and if they had all
figured out a way to work together they
would be on their way to doing that and
you know i can't knock anyone i would
have loved i would love to see anybody
from the underground make it to a
billion dollar valuation one day and if
anybody could have done it it would have
been them i think that's probably the
biggest thing because it kind of seems
like burner just ran with it and he was
really like the least influential person
i mean he was working at the hemp center
as like a security guard if i remember
correctly and um
kind of just like
made the rap thing work and promoted it
and you know hustle hustle hustle then
definitely did a lot i'm sure no knock
to be clear no knock on his hustle i'm
sure he busted his ass to get where he
is right now
because a lot of people were in the day
at that time a lot of people had the
opportunity but like i said i think the
biggest thing
is
i mean there's been you know fallouts
between those people and so i think
that's probably the biggest thing that
kind of set them set them back and kept
them from fulfilling their potential i
think if they'd all been able to just
work together they would have really
achieved something special
yeah definitely so something i have been
interested in myself and i can't really
find a good answer is
was shibinsky a part of the original
crew it always felt to me like he came
in after
they found the girl scouts and then had
his little moment in there what's your
take on all that where does he fit in
the picture for you
yeah i think i mean i'm pretty sure they
were all friends because i think it's
pie guy [__] and sherb and i think i
think they were all friends you know in
sf especially it's like it's kind of a
like loose knit but very very affiliated
city like
people there's a lot of people that have
grown up out there they know each other
you know they're friends with friends or
you know they dated each other's cousins
or whatever it might be like people
people have deep deep roots in that city
and it's a very very small area and so
you know whether he whether i don't i
don't i doubt there was even really an
official you know there was an official
anything i think they all just knew each
other
and happened to be involved in some of
this stuff and
they probably all played their part in
it um from my understanding you know it
was the three of them it was pi guy
schrabinski and [__] that like were
responsible for that
and from there you know the affiliation
with berner who was like rapping at the
time
and you know did a lot of the promoting
and it's weird because people will shout
out burner as like oh yeah thanks thanks
to burner for the cookies or whatever
and it's like
[Music]
not really if you want to thank anyone's
probably one of those three guys and if
really if you want to thank someone you
could thank us because they didn't want
that cut getting out
they didn't want people growing it so if
people are growing it you could probably
really thank us
yeah no i i definitely agree on that
point and that raises an interesting
point in itself what do you think about
snowman the the last remaining cookie
cut that they feel hasn't gotten out yet
that they're still keeping under lock
and key
yeah so i've actually never seen it and
i would love to see it um i think it's
probably something that i'd have to ask
my my buddy straight flame about i think
he he would definitely know more about
it and my buddy frost boss would know
more about it
i've never seen it you know i've heard
things about it um
but
to be honest
i'd be curious to know like is it better
than the sherb is it better than any of
the gelatos like is it better than the
cookies cause
a lot of that stuff is kind of treading
in the same gene pool so you know i just
kind of feel like they're just on
opposite ends of the cookie spectrum
i would love to i mean if it's like a
gassier version of the cookies that
might be interesting
yeah so
sorry i was just going to say i spoke to
shah of
seed bank and he's got an s1 of it
because he managed to buy a bag off
one of the guys founds a seed in it and
uh pretty good s1 and he said it's just
like a much more og dominant version of
cookies basically that's what i figured
that's the only other thing that it
could be and i remember yeah that i was
going to say that i thought there was an
s1 somewhere
but
no i had never seen it so yeah but i
mean that doesn't surprise me i think if
you wanted to do that though you know
you could just reverse an og to the
cookies
and you would have that i don't think
that it's anything you know i don't know
i just i don't know if it's game
changing i mean does he sound very very
excited about that s1 or is it just
something that he's like it's good but
it's
neither here nor there
he likes it for sure but i think that
kind of touches on the point you raised
earlier in the you know at that point is
it really that different from docie doe
exactly
yeah yeah that's i mean that's that's
exactly my point like is it really
anything so like
if you had a male if you actually bred
the cookies
hit it to something like a vietnam hit
it to something like a burma hit it to
something like a guatemalan hit it to
something weird
now now we've got something
you know like if you hit it to three
different types of you know totally
different genetics and run through those
i think that's how you're going to find
something different i mean if cookies is
kind of what i think it is which is just
oh geez and cherry pie
um
what are you really doing that's that
different
like
yeah you know what i mean what do you
what do you really have if you're if
you're just hitting it back to an og
right
so
my next question on the cookies would be
i think you might have a little bit of
an idea but if you don't that's fine do
you know much about the story behind the
og kbb because what you find online is
just that supposedly the guy
og kushbreath just is like oh i just got
given it as gsc
but like i feel like there's probably a
bit more to it than that
yeah so he's as far as i know i don't
think uh o.g cush breath has ever really
spoken publicly about it
um so i definitely wouldn't want to put
words in his mouth i know norcal who is
friends with him
and you know i know as much as norcal
has told me
and the story of where it came from i
can't speak to it i do know how how it
got out i do know how it was given out
but where he got it from i can't say and
i i think that he got it as a cutting i
don't think he popped it from seed
so i believe that he got that as as a
cutting and it may have been from from
that initial batch that i think most of
these seeds came from
yeah because they're very similar you
know what what people call the thin mint
and the animal and even the og kb even
though the structure is completely
mutated and totally you know in that way
it's different the
bag of peel the frost
like the the flavor profile is very very
similar the style of the flower
very very similar um
i mean all i know about that is that it
was given to norcal as a favor
as a thank you for a favor that he did
for og kush breath and you know if he
wants to speak publicly about about what
that was at some point he can
but um i'll say that he did a favor for
him and as a thank you
um he gave him that plant he no norkell
gave that plan to several of us um
probably a half dozen of us
nobody kept it i kept it
nobody else kept it because
when we put it in the bedrooms it got
lapped by everything else when we sent
it into flour it literally got drowned
out i remember having to like lift it up
to get it to like above the canopy where
the sours were and everything else i
mean it couldn't keep up with form it
can it couldn't keep up with anything it
veg super slow
it didn't like to be over watered it was
slow to root nobody liked it
everyone let it go and it wasn't until
probably about nine months or a year
later when it started kind of getting
some traction that people started
hitting us up asking for it back and
norcal's general response was well i've
already gave it to you once no no i'm
not giving it to you again
so a lot of people didn't get it back
and i think you know a couple people got
it and it is out you know some people
have it but if you notice it's not one
that people produce large amounts of
flour of it's not one that you know that
you see commonly on a shelf and i have
seen certain producers in other states
claim to have it and when i've seen the
flower in the store it's it's not the og
kbb um
it's just not so i've never actually
seen it like commercially on a shelf
probably because of how difficult it is
to grow and how long it takes
but you know what's interesting is when
you see it crossed with the with with
the face off um in the dough
it doesn't show that i mean it shows
some of the mutant tendencies and you
see that in like a peanut butter breaths
and whatnot because it comes out a lot
in there but there's generally good
plants to be found in there so it's a
weird plant it's hard to pollinate i
actually made an og kb sfvnl at one
point that i've never run those seeds
it didn't make a lot of them it doesn't
have a lot of pistols and this is
friendly piece of advice if anybody does
have it and it's interesting pollinating
it
you're going to want to pollinate it way
early and it just does not have a lot of
pistols so it will not make a lot of
seeds it just it can't
and you're going to want to you're going
to want to adjust your feed you're going
to want to adjust your lighting and
whatnot to make it stretch a little bit
more and make it a little bit less dense
so the seeds have more time to fill in
and um
yeah it's a it's a really interesting
plant um
hard pressed to find an ounce of it
honestly like
only really the only person i know still
growing it is norcal
and mostly for personal projects and
whatnot things that he's working on for
himself but not really for commercial
production at all like i've been like i
said i've never seen it i've seen it
once on the shelf and it wasn't what
they said it was
yeah yeah i've certainly never been able
to try it unfortunately um i would love
to take a stab because i think i read
somewhere i think norcal wrote somewhere
the reason how he got that plant and
maybe you can yay nay that for me or if
you prefer not to that's fine but what i
had heard was that
uh og kush breath had like a grow
somewhere and he was like about to be
busted by the cops or something and like
norcal went to the grow and like took it
all down for him and was like as he's
doing it like the cops could bust in at
any moment type thing so very much in
danger himself but he managed to do it
and get it all packed up and so it was
given to him as like a thank you for
that because that's obviously like a
pretty hectic situation is that roughly
what happened
that is yeah that is exactly what
happened
um yeah it was a favor for breaking down
a spot
and
like you said you know anything could
have happened at that time um he was at
risk of getting busted there and so as a
favor as a thank you for doing that for
him he gave him that cut
and that's you know i know they've
always had they've always had a good
relationship over the years the two of
them so you know solid i mean norcal is
one of the most i'll put it on record
lorcal is one of the most solid guys
you'll ever meet in this business we've
been friends for a long time
a long time and
very very stand-up guy good good person
yeah good to know good to know okay so
my final question directly relating to
cookies for the moment is
do you think that there will be any
repercussions on the cookie fam for the
whole candy rain debacle or do you think
they're just gonna slip by and nothing
will ever really happen about it
i think they're gonna slip by and
they're going to pop back up again and
they're going to do something again and
people are going to forget that this
ever happened i mean you got to remember
there's other people not at their scale
and not at that price point that have
kind of had these issues and i'm not
going to i don't want to say anybody's
name or whatever if if you know if
you've been in this you've seen there's
a couple of individuals specifically
that have popped up dropped the whole
line had it be a disaster gone
underground and popped up a couple years
later and tried again um but the candy
rain debacle i mean honestly people are
such fan boys that i don't even think
they're mad
if anything they they kind of set the
standard for hey you know if you find
one that's good enough
and i mean those packs you know they
were significant amount of money people
lost a lot of time and energy into those
and
clearly you know there was massive
issues with them and so i think i think
people were just doubly upset the fact
that i don't really think they ever
responded to it publicly
i think they kind of just ignored it as
far as i know i think a big part of the
candy rain debacle was yeah people spent
a lot of money and they couldn't even
get them to germ
um
but they don't want to say anything
yeah definitely and i mean a little bit
of an insider scoop which may or may not
be publicly known but um jbz has 100
signed on to be cookie fam's
in-house breeder from now on so we will
certainly see some more stuff from them
in the near future yeah no i had heard
about that
um yeah no congratulations to him i hope
they caught him a huge check honestly
so i'm like i said i'm not mad at anyone
getting out there getting it you know
like good for them if you can get them
to cut you a huge check i think it's
easy for a lot of people to say oh i
would never do that until it's sitting
in front of you and then would you do
that
um
i was gonna just say there's a lot of
people making making the transition into
the recreational cannabis market doing
just that
because they don't have the capital they
don't have the access to the property
they don't have the connections so then
they're going to sign on with someone
who can who can take what they've built
and magnify it
yeah definitely definitely and if and
you know based on jbz's work like you
know for the most part he does pretty
good stuff you know hopefully that trend
continues in terms of what he does for
cookie fam
yeah i don't see any reason why it
wouldn't i think i think honestly i
think it i think it's gonna be good work
hopefully
okay well to get off something a little
less doom and gloom i did want to
quickly run this by you how do you feel
when you see like kind of i don't want
to say distant offspring but just kind
of offspring of the forum go on to reach
stardom like the one that comes to mind
is if you trace it back the gmo has got
the forum in it when you see that type
of thing and all the traction it gets do
you get a certain sense of kind of
accomplishment from that or do you just
don't really think about it
to be honest i i don't really think
about it much but but i always felt like
cannabis had done so much for me
that there was really nothing that i
could ever do to repay it and i'm gonna
be blunt and say something that people
don't really seem to say like i don't
believe in the cannabis community i grew
up
where you know people sold drugs i grew
up where people hustled like that's why
i've always like responded well to like
oakland and the type of mentality that
people have there it's a hustling
mentality it doesn't matter what they're
doing they're trying they're trying to
hustle survive and improve their
position
um
and so cannabis had always done so so
much for me i didn't ever really think
there was anything i could ever do to
like
to repay it in general like the i don't
want to say the community because i
don't really believe in that but more
more just so like
just
the world that it cultivates around it
the people that are in the space the
people that are in like tied into this
plant and all the different offshoots of
it
um and so to see the forum cut get used
in so many projects and just real and
like yeah and like you said to see the
gmo
blow up and a bunch of these other cuts
that have blown up because of it as well
if anything like
i'd say it makes me a little bit happy
because i feel like i have the chance to
contribute to like changing the course
of cannabis which how many people can
really say that how many people can
really say
that without this thing that they had
done
that
that they played a part you know in
literally shifting the course of
cannabis on a global scale
and you know with like you said without
that cut
making it to europe
um and mamiko making those seeds and
then you know skunk master flex
selecting that cut and you know it
blowing up in michigan before it ever
blew up out here
that was one of the first cuts that
actually you know in a long time that
actually started in the in the midwest
and came west a couple years later
it wasn't you know it was big there
before it was really big out west so in
a way i would say you know that it
stokes me because
to know that that would not exist if we
had not done what we did even as far as
getting the cut to europe
like if we hadn't done that mamiko would
have never made the gmo and if he hadn't
made the gmo then skunk master flex you
know they wouldn't have the han solo
burger
and all that other stuff that they've
done with that
so when you really look at it i mean a
lot of stuff when you trace it back is
from the forum i mean even sin city
seeds you know
i want to say
if i'm not mistaken i want to say it was
like blue power and forum
and they used that uh i think jbz used
that when they made the wedding cake
and yes definitely
yeah so that also would not exist
without that
i mean there's a lot of if when you
really really trace it back it's kind of
it's kind of like a horse or something
where you say
look at all these look at all the
offspring and all the all the
all the different plants that are
related to it that can be traced back to
it that wouldn't exist without it
i mean
to me it kind of stokes me because
really like how many people have
actually had a chance to contribute to
the cannabis scene at that level i mean
you can talk about chem dog you can talk
about a couple of these people
you know that i mean they were pivotal
factors in in these plants you know
getting to where they were going you
know bubba
um i mean the chems the bubbas
even the sours you know all of that
stuff and i mean with the ogs you know
you can talk about ghost um you know the
ghost cut
and uh some of that stuff at la i mean
if that stuff hadn't really gone where
it got you know like a lot of the stuff
from you know and from uh archive
wouldn't exist i mean face-off and all
that stuff from you know from those guys
down in socal and then you know the
doctor working with that and
just it's in it's i'd say more than
anything i'm grateful to have had the
chance to play a part in in this thing
and i think the biggest takeaway is like
you are just a piece of this whole thing
it's not nobody in this business and in
this scene or whatever you want to call
it
exists independently of everybody else
we're all connected to each other in
some way shape or form and some of us
you know have bigger you know roles that
we've played more more has gone through
us
than other people more connections more
networks whatever it might be have
spiraled out from these things that
we've done
but without you know all these people it
wouldn't exist i mean if i had just
given the cut to my if i just given the
cut to my two or three friends and they
hadn't passed it out
i wasn't going to pass it out not
because i had no interest in passing it
just because i or because i was against
passing it just because i just generally
avoided talking to people like in this
business no good comes from talking to
people
so just the more that you avoid people
the longer you'll survive
and
that was kind of my feeling on that so
if anything i would say that i'm honored
you know it's funny that the gmo is
actually one of the only cuts i ever
asked for and they told me they said yes
but they never got it to me
and they kind of just like left me on
okay whatever um so
i thought that was kind of funny because
yeah that cut wouldn't exist without
without the work that i had done i mean
i know true um in the uk and in spain
has worked a lot with the forum as well
he got that you know directly from our
circle i mean a lot of people can trace
where that cut came from back to people
that were affiliated with us so yeah i
would say if anything you know i'm
grateful and i'm honored you know to
have been able to shift
cannabis in some way shape or form to
have even been a part of it
yeah what a really awesome sentiment to
express and that's so kind of
coincidental you you reference true i'm
interviewing him in like 12 hours so
there you go random um nice he's a cool
guy i guess you vouch for him yeah yeah
yeah he knows me from the forums from
back in the day um he was affiliated
with some of our friends and that's how
he got that forum cut which i'm sure you
can ask him about cool you just gave me
another question i love it but something
you did mention which i you know a fan
favorite of the show personal favorite
of mine chem dog let's talk about it the
91 the various d's what are your
experiences with the cam dog do you like
it which one's your favorite give me the
lowdown
so i love the chem d um the first chem i
ever grew was the four
and it was you know bigger yielding you
know real solid threw down really really
well
but people kind of had got tired of it
that's actually one that i'm like bummed
that i gave up i know some friends of
ours in our circle still have it so i
could i could get that one back at some
point but for whatever reason it's been
like like the least favorited one out of
all of them um the d
is phenomenal and you know you talked
about the gmo and that's really part of
what makes it special i mean
the proper d
well done is you know what what my my
boy calls blunt weed or gangster weed
it's like it's
super potent incredibly tasty does not
does not have the best bag appeal in the
entire world does not photograph super
well um but it's just amazing phenomenal
herb just raunchy
beautiful herb i mean it's what makes
the gmo like
you know the gmo just got dressed up in
a better in a better bag necessarily or
a better shell from the forum but really
what really makes it is the chem d and
then the 91 is a beautiful plant the 91
and the d
are gorgeous plants in and of themselves
the 91 being more og
which i just i just love it i mean i
think it's an amazing amazing plant as
well and you know but they're they're a
little bit fickle the the d the d will
do better the 91 is a little bit more
fickle um
but i love them both i think that
they're you know they're they're staples
in in the cannabis scene in my opinion
and i don't think that enough people
have actually seen like you said all the
various d's and yeah there's the
non-variegated and this one and the
other one
we were lucky enough to get
the d cut from jj separately you know we
had had it as well
um but you know when we when we got the
one from jj we said okay well you know
this one is definitely the one if there
was any question there's not a question
anymore
and uh
it's a phenomenal plant beautiful love
it i mean if you've i mean you've tried
the gmo i'm sure you've tried the d
the the way that the profile sticks to
your palette you know it's really kind
of like cuts through anything else
yeah very very special plant and that's
kind of like a nice little segue on to
the next question which is let's talk
about a strain that i think will become
known as like the equivalent of the cam
dogs but for kind of the
2010 to 2020 period the mac you know
it's been so
used abused you know all the rest of it
what's your thoughts on it and do you
plan to work with it because it's
something i noticed is surprisingly
missing from your feed
yeah so i got the mac
um initially like when when when people
started kind of getting it i was pretty
excited about it i was like okay this
thing i've heard good things it looks
good um
i grew it
and i just wasn't impressed with it and
i passed it to a couple of friends of
mine you know people who've been you
know people who i have been in my circle
and i've shared cuts with for a long
time and
we mostly all agreed except for one of
us we've mostly all agreed that it's not
that great um it looks good
it has nice bag appeal
does not really have much else going for
it in my opinion i don't really care for
the flavor
i don't care for the high i don't care
for the growth habit
i don't like it i mean i think cap did a
great job marketing and promoting and
branding it i think he did i think he
did a phenomenal job by saying don't
give this to people who haven't earned
it and in that way he kind of made it
special
um i have seen a lot of the crosses from
it and so to answer your question um i
have seen a lot of the crosses from it
and they come out very very like what i
would describe as that jack lemony
profile i think it's from the colombian
in it
and
that's not really something that i
necessarily need to look for
or would want to look for and it seems
very very dominant in a lot of the
crosses
so for me
not really something that i intend to
work with
i did make i think i made some mac sherb
seeds but i have not popped them
and i don't really think i have any
intention to pop them at some point i
guess if one of my friends wanted them
i'd probably let them run it but
from what i've seen it's not really a
direction that i want to go down so
actually have a pack of the mac that i
bought you know in all honesty from the
first drop
um
[Music]
but it's one that you know i don't think
it's gonna stand up
i think it's you know gonna disappear
pretty quickly i mean if you've noticed
like there's not really a lot of hype
left around it right now although it's
crazy at the events when when cap is
there the line is like 100 people deep
or 200 people deep for it
so all the crosses and this that and the
other so i'll be interested to see you
know one of my friends does love it i
mean he he told me that i'm wrong flat
out he said he said he likes it
um but for me
no i've got no interest in it and it's
mostly just everything that i described
about how it breeds and the effect and
the high and the taste
all of the above beautiful plant though
photographs extremely well like a great
instagram plant if you asked me
yeah i would agree with that and the
thing about the mac which i mean it has
been said before but i'll bring it up
again is it frustrates me how no one's
talking about the fact that no other
serious legitimate contender keeper cuts
have ever been found from the seeds it's
like it's almost like the mac one is
pulled out of the aether and then the
seeds that are produced are almost
different because there's yet no one has
ever found a keeper especially a male
no
nothing that i have seen come out of
those out of the crosses that have been
like you know the the authorized kind of
crosses that he's done as well as some
of the work that other people have done
nothing has ever made any waves in
anybody's garden and so i think that
there's a lot of there was a lot of hype
around it
but
just kind of looking at what's come from
it it makes me think that it's not
really it's not really a direction i
would ever want to go in like i wouldn't
i wouldn't want to work it i wouldn't
want to sell it to people i'd i just i
have no interest in going down that road
i'll be interested to see if he keeps
working with it you know i don't know if
he's on to something else perhaps he is
um
but yeah not like you said nothing has
really come from those seeds and you
would think like i mean you know that
can't the same cannot be said for jbz's
work like
there's been a ton of work that that
people have found there's been a ton of
crosses the ice cream cake whatever all
this stuff that has come out
since you know since the wedding cake
stuff
that
people are you know people are like yeah
man this is really nice work i mean we
have a wedding cake sherb that i made
that's phenomenal i mean it's beautiful
it's gorgeous like
it was hard to pick a keeper out of
those out of those wedding cake sherb
seeds that we made and ran like there
was a bunch of them that were just
beautiful and i think that if i did the
same thing with the mac i think i
probably would have killed them all
so
let's let's jump back to those sunset
sherb crosses for a minute
when you test those crosses do you find
that this shirt tends to be quite
dominating or it more lets the other
parent shine through
so that so one of the things that i've
done which some of my friends have
disagreed with is i tend to make a lot
of crosses sometimes and even if i don't
release them or post them or whatever it
might be
i i like to do it and the reason is
because i've noticed that um
when something so somebody might say oh
the sherb is dominant and that may be
the case
but there are pairings where it where it
is not
and i don't think that things are
universally dominant so i don't think
that if you reverse a sherb let's say
and hit you know 20 different clones
that there that the sherpa's always
going to be dominant there's ones where
it shines out and there's ones where
where it kind of fades back and i've
noticed that in some different crosses
we did a
daigo walker to the u-dub and then we
did the sherb to the u-dub and the dagel
walker to the u-dub uh the [__] was
dominant and we did the sherb to the
u-dub and the u-dub was dominant
and so you know they both had the same
u-dub cut they had different donor
parents as it were
and
both of them responded differently to it
so you know with the sherb crosses i
mean what we see in like the wedding
cake sherbs is that there are some that
are wedding cake there are some that are
sherb and there are some that are 50 50
and i'd probably put them at about you
know 40 one way 40 the other and 20 down
the middle and the 50 50 ones are the
ones that i'm always most interested in
the ones that are more wedding kicker
more sure why would i select that way if
i already have those cuttings
so it just makes sense to me to try and
find something where it pairs well
in the case of the udub [__]
we did select towards the [__] only
because that grapefruit profile is
something i really like and it just was
kind of a finicky leslie like lower
yielding plant whereas the u-dub just
throws down these you know big fat
resinous colas on it
um and it's just you know it's hearty
and chunky and you know veggies well and
so selecting one like that with that
grapefruit profile you know was a real
real improvement for us
yeah okay well i mean heck speaking of
sherbet and grapefruit this seems like a
really good time to ask in the past we
had heard stories that it was possible
that the skittles cut was just a sherbet
s1 now given your experience with
sherbet do you think there's any
possibility that could be true
um
i mean
no i don't think so and and the reason
is because we have you know run a lot of
sherb and we've run a lot of sherb
crosses
and i don't think that the skittles came
from that
i haven't really god i can't say that i
really thought much ever about about
where the skittles actually came from
i mean it was such a weird wonky plant
that
i never really had a lot of interest in
it and i know it made a lot of waves as
well and people were really interested
in it but it kind of reminds me of the
lemon tree in a way where it's like this
is not something that like
is like game changing this is something
that's interesting but a flavor that i
would be soon bored of if that's all i
was if that's all i was consuming um
whereas with like a sour or a camera and
og
you know that's something that you know
i could take those all day and be
completely satisfied um beautiful
beautiful herb
i kind of put the skittles where i put
the lemon tree which it's an interesting
flavor
but i only want to see it as like 20 of
a cross as it were i don't really want
to see it as like the whole thing but
yeah to answer i don't think i would not
say
that the skittles was a sure best one
yeah it's i mean if you've seen the
flower it's just it's ugly it's like and
it's not just that they grow it poorly
it's that it's not really super high
grade herb in that way it's very very
tasty though and amazing for extracts
much like the lemon tree
yeah and what i found interesting that
you
kind of brought that point about the
lemon tree is i always find it very
peculiar how similar
the terpene profile is between sherbet
and lemon tree even though one's
obviously more orangey ones more
kind of more lemony but i feel like
there's this underlying similarity
between the two
between the lemon tree and the sherb uh
sorry lemon tree and skittles
yes um yeah if you asked me if you said
hey
the sk the lemon tree was an s one of
the skittles or or the skittles was an
s1 of the lemon tree which you know we
all think is just some
lemon uh you know lemon from basically
the santa cruz area that had been there
supposedly for years anyway
um and that's not you know that's not an
area i spent a lot of time in up in that
up in those mountains but
my understanding is that that's all the
lemon tree is it's just a rebranded
lemon cut that was you know popular in
that area for a long time anyway
and if you told me the skittles was an
s1 of the lemon tree
that i would believe
that would actually make a lot of sense
to me that's another one where like
there's never been a male
there's no male skittles
like
that i've ever seen you could correct me
if i'm wrong but i don't think there's
ever been like an actual male they've
crossed it with things and then they did
like the zoz and some other stuff
um
but i don't think there was ever an
actual mail of skittles
yeah i think you're correct on that one
interesting yeah i noticed that another
kind of older strain from around those
older days that i noticed on your feed
was the las vegas purple kush i'd love
to know how did you get it because you
don't you don't see a lot about it and
people don't often speak about it but
there are some people who hang on to it
so i figure it must have some value
what's your take on it
so that cut as we can trace that cut
back pretty far within within our
personal circle
and um the cut originally so so we
attribute that to cut that cut to
somebody named hydroson who uh passed
away um
he was the one that brought that cut
into our circle he was definitely a
character as most of us tend to be
and he had sourced that cut from some
people that he knew up in washington i
believe
and originally um another friend of mine
who is super underground he was the one
that actually got that cut for our
friend hydro sun and hydro sun brought
that cut down to uh to vegas and spread
it to our circle out there and from
there it spread it spread to some of our
guys in the bay area i always avoided it
because it grew like a bubba and i never
liked bubba at all
i had no interest in bubba i didn't want
to grow it i didn't like the profile
and the samples that i had seen of bubba
were kind of weak it was kind of after
the bubba had been grown kind of well
and it was kind of getting
commercialized and whatnot and so
just the bad samples i'd never really
been impressed by it
but that's a cut that i kept for a long
long time it's a beautiful plant it's
hearty
vigorous very very resistant
um i think i think inspector or i think
the doctor has come out um and back and
forth here and there and said that oh
it's a bubba ass one or something or
it's a weak version of bubba
um
and yeah for me i always thought it was
a great plant i know in our circle it's
always been very very popular it
definitely spread from there
whether other people were able to get it
through other avenues and maybe that's
where they acquired it i know there's
some people in the midwest we've spoken
to that have held it and grown it for a
while as well
i know that our circle and hydroson in
particular were responsible for
spreading that cut it's like i said it's
not a cut that anyone's going to have
any interest in today
it you know it doesn't trim up well
does not have a ton of bag appeal it
grows very very interesting um potent
flour
but you know who's to say um kind of
anything beyond that i just i believe
that it came out of a garden in
washington originally when we got it and
then we spread it down to vegas and i
think that's where it took that name
um and then from there it kind of spread
out but it is it's a cut that's kind of
that's known but it seems
unknown in a way as well i don't really
know that that many people outside are
like familiar with it so it's
interesting that you bring it up
yeah because it's kind of one of those
ones which does persist on but doesn't
get a lot of mention does it
no well we've we've definitely kept it
around i mean it has a place in our
circle and i think
people
certain individuals have an affinity for
it um one or two people in particular
that i'm thinking about that i think
there are just certain cups certain cuts
that they're going to keep probably
forever and that's one of those cuts
they just love it i mean
grown grown right you know they've had
good results with it i think one of my
friends grew in deep water culture
which spread uh sped up the veg and
increased um the yield on it so you know
he has a special place for it in his
garden always
and um yeah it's kind of cool to see it
continue to survive and persist i've
definitely done some work with it i've
done an lvpk sherb and a couple other
little projects with it that i think you
know
a lot of that stuff um a lot of the
seeds they just go to friends of mine so
and a lot of them they're not on
instagram they don't care about anything
they're just they're just doing what
they do and they just they just want to
grow
you know we all we've all just been
sharing seeds for a long time i mean a
lot of those sherb seeds i never made
them available people didn't really have
a chance to buy them they mostly just
went to friends of mine
yeah okay well i mean heck speaking of
seeds i've noticed that you tend to make
a good mix of both femme and regular
seeds do you have one you prefer most
and do you feel like feminized seeds
will eventually overtake regularity
overtake regular seeds in popularity
so
yes so
for years and years you know there was
the common thought that like oh you know
fems are unstable this that and the
other whatever it might be
um
you know that that kind of stuck in my
mind for a while until we actually until
i started seeing people doing work with
them and then kind of seeing what was
coming from it and i started to
understand a little bit more that like
not necessarily you know if if the work
if it was done you know unintentionally
or whatever it might be then yes you
know
especially some like the sours and
whatnot but if you do it intentionally
i do feel like
so i've seen a lot of regular male
female work and if you do a poor
selection on the male you are kind of
dooming that whole line everything that
comes after that is probably not going
to be good and really the only way to
know is to use the mail grow out the
seeds see see what comes of it and then
determine okay this is a solid male and
then probably go back and do another
line with them what i really appreciate
about the fems especially you know like
the clone onlys or whatever it might be
well i guess that the term is kind of
loose these days but basically like
selected cuts versus you know
just a general male or whatnot if you
take if i take a sherb which people know
and i cross it to let's say a skittles
which people know
you're kind of taking the breeder out of
the equation at that point what you're
really depending on is does this person
actually have these cuts
and so for me going forward
some of the work you know is going to be
more more focused on the fems because i
think that people really that's really
what people want i mean a lot of people
they don't really want to breed so if
you don't want to breed you don't want
to do the sex testing you don't want to
have to identify anything you have a
limited amount of space some people
stick to plant counts or whatnot and
wherever they are they would rather just
pop them they would rather say okay cool
this is you know gelato 25 crossed with
docido perfect like this will work you
know and you know gelato and sherb or
you know wedding cake and shirt your
take you're taking the breeder out of
the equation you're taking their
personal kind of
they're not able to influence as much
the process so you're just saying hey
basically thanks for having the
legitimate cut thank you for providing
these seeds and i hope they germinate
and
then you know basically your service is
done
um and that that brings up a point you
know for me as well which i don't know
if it's something you were going to ask
but
a lot of what's going on out there right
now it's people not working with
legitimate cuttings and i think that's
one of the reasons that i've been able
to do what i do
is because people know that if i say i
have something that
it's that it is that
and that's something that i've earned
over a long long time in this business i
think when people pop up now and they've
got no reputation they've got no name
they're not i'm honestly i hold inspect
in high regard um i was gonna say you
know like they're not inspected they're
not these other people not to put myself
with him
um
but if inspector says he has a cut i 100
believe it so when he did those triangle
cushions once and people were
complaining about the price i might i
was dying laughing because the
opportunity to get a triangle kush s1
which took him multiple attempts to
achieve from inspector is invaluable
and if you can't see that then you know
it's not for you
because you know that's that's a guy who
if he says he has something it is
exactly what he says it is and that's
that's something that's like sorely
lacking i see people popping up right
now and they're saying oh you know i got
the rumps or i got this or i got that or
you know something comes out and they
already have a whole line with it
and a whole reverse femme line to all
these other ones and it's like
who number one who are you
totally fine go ahead and get your money
but number two like
just like is it really
is it really what you say it is
and you know i think i think there's
there's a lot of that going on but for
me yeah i mean i intend to keep doing
some male female work
but that work takes longer and just like
that as a zo
people aren't really interested in you
know people people don't people don't
see the value of working something two
or three or four generations you're
really kind of limiting yourself
and from that kind of perspective people
more want exactly what they know so if
you say i've got a wedding cake and a
sherb they're very into that but if you
say oh i've got a vietnam black tie with
a grand doggie perp crossed with a grand
doggie per banana limon then you have to
explain all that to them you have to say
oh the limoni in cross was from swan
song seeds and it's a double sour diesel
[__] trowel
and you know it's crossed with the
banana but it's not the banana og it's a
sonoma cut that we had it's like banana
runs almost and then you know we made
that and then the grand doggie purpose
of chem d gdp from connoisseur back in
the day and you know but you got to
explain all this stuff to them and the
vietnam black tie is from ace most
people are going to be like who's ace
and what is that and what is all of that
like where's the cookies at
that's what that's
honestly that's what they're gonna say
so literally if i just do cookies to
cookies
people will buy that you know
fortunately for me like honestly i'm i'm
a little bit more difficult about
selling my seeds i don't really care if
people buy them or don't buy them and
that's not to be disrespectful of anyone
that's just to say like i do what i do
because i want to do it and
because i think it's going to be good
but when it comes down to actually
selling seeds why would you spend three
or four years on a project when people
are pumping out six projects a year
of just fems to fems you know
i mean people are literally going to
dispensary and buying a gelato 33 clone
and reversing it to everything else or
they're popping one pack of seeds from
somebody else and just hitting a bunch
of stuff and just renaming it
um saying they have this saying they
have that and i think a lot of that is
kind of what's going on out there right
now but yeah for me i'm i'm going to
still do some fem work the fem work is
tricky too you know an inspector i've
been grateful to take some time from him
um you know it's not they don't always
work i tried to do a high life reversal
barely worked barely put out any seeds
very very very
um frustrating that when that happens
and all you can really do is just go
back to the drawing board and just try
again you know and i know i know matt
matt sells some solutions and uh one of
my buddies uh chef ro from people under
the stairs he has another solution that
he makes and
you know we're toying with some
different things and some gibberellic
acid and whatnot in the mix with the sts
to see if you know we'll get the
intended results that we need
but you know generally it's not always
the fems aren't always guaranteed either
and so i understand you know like
like that's why i feel like they can
kind of command a higher premium because
and i think people don't understand that
like what it takes to back up so many
plants like the commitment that it takes
to keep such a diverse library it's
there's a lot of people that are just
going to the dispensary buying eight
clones and you know they start a seed
company and that's great and that's fine
and dandy they don't even keep any of
the cuts they just go back and buy them
again they hope it's the same cut you
know maybe they hope maybe they don't
care
um
but to back up the sheer number of
plants you know that i have backed up
over the years and the people i can
expect to back up
that's why i feel like they deserve a
premium that's why i feel like you know
it's worth paying them what they ask
because of what it takes to go into that
you mean you're not just paying for you
know somebody to make some seeds in the
tent or something it's like this person
has dedicated years to sourcing
collecting preserving transporting
moving you know cloning backing up
whatever it might be
and then tried to do these things for
you
but yeah no i'm always going to do some
regular male female work
and and some fem work i enjoy the fem
work honestly a lot of people want that
they don't
they don't care about breeding they have
no interest in males like they just want
to pop some seeds grow some flowers pick
a female and go from there
yeah i agree with just almost everything
you said you know like that that
trusting a breeder and not doing
the the kind of the the shady acts that
we see certain breeders like copycat
genetics [__] you big dan i hate you um
yeah that guy's trash in every sense um
but yeah you know and someone like
inspector on the other hand you know the
epitome of kind of what you can trust as
the gold standard so yeah i totally
agree and we're going to talk about some
azazel stuff soon because i'm super
interested in that like above all things
but i want to quickly ask you do you
feel like when you're converting a
female to be like the pollen donor for a
cross do you feel like
that causes any sort of stress like do
you feel like
the result of you doing that is
different from if the plant had hermed
out or do you feel like they're
essentially the same result
i feel i feel that they're different
um in my experience the plants that her
mouth as it were
tend to produce more unstable seeds
and when you intentionally do it it
seems to actually produce more stable
seeds but
i mean that could just be a matter of
the plant that herm that was initially
more prone to that anyway
so maybe maybe if maybe it wouldn't have
had anything to do anyway maybe if you
had sprayed the plant that was gonna
hermit it would do it anyway whereas the
other one is just less prone to doing so
um i've never tried both ways to be
honest um but in my experience i think
that if you do it intentionally versus
if it happens accidentally
it's
i feel i find it to be more more
reliable in my experience
yeah definitely i can i can back that
myself with my limited experience making
fems and so the follow-up question is
have you ever done any kind of more
weird breeding stuff with your regular
things and by that i mean like we often
refer to how dj short had many moons ago
referenced like that hermaphrodite males
were good males to breed with you ever
do any kind of left of field stuff like
that at all or you try to keep it pretty
straightforward
no i try and keep it pretty basic it's
it's it's a very very complicated um
game to play anyway
and
to try and complicate it even further i
would leave that to someone like dj or
some of these other people out there i
mean
the kind of work that that dj has done
is not really the kind of work that i
would want to do like i don't i don't
the kind of breeding that he's done is
different than what i'm interested in
for me i'm most interested in taking
like things that are
popular now
and combining them with things that are
you know kind of out of left field that
people wouldn't expect like like i did a
burma with the gb6 tricks and that's not
something that anybody's doing and in
fact when i made it uh loki um was he
even asked he's like nobody's gonna want
that nobody's gonna care about burma or
lucy or any of this weird stuff that
you're doing and i said it's fine people
will grab whatever they want they'll
grab docido face on fire they'll grab
this they'll grab that they'll grab the
peanut butter breath whatever it is
they're interested in it's totally fine
i do that because i like to do that and
that's you know i enjoy doing that's
probably about as weird as i get is kind
of combining some of these left field uh
cultivars with something that people
would not expect it to be combined with
of course
so when you are looking to select a male
what are the some of the traits you find
ideal in a male like would you have any
tips for the audience they love this
type of things like is there any sort of
visual cues or anything that you like to
go with
yeah so the first thing that i look for
is structure
um i like a plant that has what i
consider ideal structure i don't want
something that's too stocky i don't want
something that has weird internal
spacing i don't want something i mean i
have a specific type of plant that i
that i look to make and it's more geared
towards indoor cultivation i wanted to
have a certain amount of internal
spacing i wanted to have like proper
size flowers i don't want i mean
sometimes it happens but i don't want
like just giant spear colas like this
you know it's not 1985 i'm not trying to
grow something to put my forearm next to
it
um
i wanna i like to grow what i consider
like proper you know two three gram
flowers like on you know on a nice sized
plant so the biggest thing i would say
would be structure vigor
um
definitely like the leaf like how leafy
it is so when when something is
extremely leafy i think about like
what it's going to be to maintain that
plant and grow that plant and
at scale something requires if it
requires a lot more work it's just not
worth it
um
so i think a lot about that and then
also when it comes time to flower them
um let's say i've got you know 20 males
i'm trying to flower i'll eliminate the
first ones to show i don't want them and
you know i don't know if that's
something that other people have touched
on before but to me that's a sign that
something is like a little bit more
susceptible
to having intersex expressions a little
bit less stable
i want something that's going to show a
little bit later and i want something
that's going to be a little bit more
resistant so you know you can be a
little bit rough on them you should be a
little bit rough on them you should see
how they respond and it's it's tough for
me because i definitely don't like to
abuse them
but i think it's important to see how
they respond and to see which ones
really which ones kind of have the
widest bandwidth so that's something
that i think about a lot with plants is
how tolerant they are
and i feel like that's something that we
don't talk about as much like not all
plants have the same bandwidth and
that's just what i call it
they don't all have the same range
they're not all able to take the
temperature swings or the ph swings or
the nutrient imbalances
or you know whatever it might be they
don't all respond the same way and so i
definitely look for plants that have a
wider bandwidth if if the ph swings
during the feed you know and these three
don't respond well i'll eliminate them
because to me that says this is a plant
that has that needs a really really
specific set of conditions in order for
it to thrive
that's a plant that i don't want because
that's not what i'm looking for
and i feel like it'll pass those it
could pass those traits on so why would
i keep that plant
so mostly i would say that's probably
the biggest thing is just to see how
they respond to look at the structure i
eliminate the early flowering ones and
then you know i go from there one thing
i've never done that i'm actually very
interested in doing is to reverse a male
to see how it produces what the resin
profile is like
just a lot of those different factors
and i'm sure you've heard people talk
about doing that before it's been a
topic of conversation for years
i know that some people have done it
and i think that's a really interesting
way to kind of see which mail would be
worth going with and it's something i'd
probably like to do on my next project
yeah i think that'll get you some really
interesting results we've heard a few
people talk about it but it is still
very much like a bit of a
uncertain thing that hasn't been delved
into too much i did however want to ask
you in general
what are you currently working on what
are you excited for
yeah so right now i'm trying to figure
out what i want to do next we're seeing
a lot of the results from the gp6 tricks
project i had tried to do that high life
project which did not work out for me
um
not quite sure what i want to do i think
we may take one of the selections from
the gb6 tricks project to start a new
line from so one of the things we did
was that we kept a couple of lines for
ourselves and we didn't release them
one was the gelato 41 gb six tricks and
the other one was the biscotti gb6
tricks and so both of those haven't been
released
and i right now we're in the process of
hunting some of those um loki is hunting
some of them right now and i've got a
couple going as well
and i think if
what we're seeing we really like and i
think it would be an improvement to that
line and i think it might be a good
foundation for a future femme project i
mean things are moving so quickly that
it's kind of hard to say me personally i
would like to do something totally off
off
something totally off the reservation as
it were
um like some honduran or some guatemalan
or you know i've got a friend from
colombia you know they got me some seeds
i'd be interested in working some of
that stuff but you know i've you know in
conversations with my friends one of the
discussions we've had is basically was
just like yeah no one no one is going to
be interested in that and so there's the
part of me that doesn't really care and
then there's the part of me that thinks
well
like i do it for me but i also do it so
that other people will grow it and so i
have to consider
you know what people want i mean if i
just make something that is of only
interest a handful of us is it really
going to be impactful is it really going
to make a difference are people really
even going to grow it and if they're not
if the answer is no then
why
why make it or why make it at scale just
make it for myself then if i want
and grow it out if i feel like growing
it out
but yeah i would say right now we're
probably looking towards working on one
of those or probably a reversal i have a
wedding cake sherb that i really like as
well
but
sometimes i kind of feel like maybe some
of those things they've kind of had
their time and a thing that i forget is
kind of how far ahead of the curve my
friends and i have always been and
something that to us is kind of like
kind of like washed kind of like over it
as it were kind of blown out
still has a lot of traction i mean
people still buy a lot of wedding cake
crosses they still buy a lot of gmo
crosses they still want to grow that and
you know
back east especially like a lot of the
market isn't even really there yet
like they're they're still excited about
wedding cake
and you know wedding cake is something
that you know hasn't been popular out
west in in a straight form
for at least three or four years
i mean it's something that you see but
it's kind of like become like a it's
kind of become like a staple it's kind
of become like a thing that's around but
not something that people are really
really excited about so i think you know
there's there's some work that could be
done with the gelato 41 tricks that i
think would be good or the biscotti
tricks
i would like to work the burma tricks
potentially and the lucy tricks
um
and then maybe go back to do some of the
sherb crosses as well going forward
though
um i don't know we talked about a little
bit uh that azazel is something that i
think has a lot of potential in it and
everybody that's grown it has been
really really impressed by it but it's
one of those things where you know if
you called it apple runts people would
buy it but if you call it as is though
i don't know that people are interested
in it honestly and it's like do how much
how much further do i go down that
direction
yeah okay well i mean let's talk about
that for a quick second do you like to
kind of hunt and go down that route of
things that aren't exactly popular
because like as what we see with the
azazo most people aren't specifically
requesting vietnamese or thai
dominant weed these days do you feel
like as a breeder you've got to accept a
certain amount of kind of
commercial loss or just you know kind of
sales loss from the casual enthusiast
but that then in turn allows you to
pursue some of these more niche and
truly exotic lines
i i do feel that and
what i find is that the people who are
interested in my work are extremely
passionate
um so i think that i have cultivated the
right type of people
for what i want to do
but commercially it's not going to be
something that you know like an azazel
or vietnamese or a thai is not going to
be something that necessarily
is you know is gonna is gonna make a ton
of waves however that being said i mean
when you look at the mac
it's the colombian in it that that
really surprises people
um and it's what gives it that profile
that lemony profile or whatever whatever
you want to call that weird um kind of
my friend describe it like a like a
raspberry yogurt or something but the
lemon is what comes out all the rest of
it all the crosses so i think that you
know
i'm going to continue to do what i love
to do
i think that there is a group of people
out there that appreciate the work that
i do
and
i do it mostly because i love it i've
always done this because i love it and
i've been grateful to be able to do that
and i've always been the guy that
instead of just running one strain i've
run you know a dozen and it doesn't make
any sense to people and you leave a
bunch of money on the table and it's not
efficient it requires a lot more work
but
i've always done this because i love to
do it and so i accept whatever comes
with that which is yeah maybe you're not
gonna you are gonna leave some sales on
the table i mean we did some gmos ones
and they flew
this tiny tiny drop super small you know
but they flew and you know the vendor
that picked them up said that if i had
done you know a bunch more of them they
would all still go
but a lot of the other stuff people
aren't interested in you know if you do
i mean we did uh death star cherry pie
with the mendo breath uv wet dream
and you know people that have grown and
love it i mean somebody grew chem 91
mando breath uv wet dream that i made
and you know told me the herb was
phenomenal i mean they loved it but
it doesn't have what people want like
nowhere in there does it say gelato or
sherb or cake or whatever or breath it
doesn't have any of that in there
it's something i mean i guess it does
because it has the mendo breath but like
very very sparingly not in a way that
people would want it
so when you do
decide to go down this route of
exploring one of these lines which is
kind of more for your own interest than
for a commercial success so to speak not
that they're mutually exclusive but you
know hopefully you get what i mean is it
because
you have fond memories of some of the
components of these lines you're kind of
chasing that feeling of the old
vietnamese type strains or is it more so
that it's just a really interesting
combination of things you don't see
often
to me it's literally because life is
short
and i have zero interest in trying to
just make a bunch of money and do
whatever people expect you to do
um i'm gonna do what i want to do and so
if i have an opportunity to work
something unique and something different
that's what i'm gonna do
and you know that like i said the people
that that that doing that kind of work
attracts are the kind of people that i
want to be around i mean i've been
really really fortunate to connect with
a lot of really good people
um a group at new mexico that you know
super passionate about the work that i'm
doing and one of them is growing the
azazel and he told me i mean his
description of it was yeah super unique
um really really interesting uh you know
shorter quicker flowering but it has
that vietnamese high profile and that's
something that when when you show it to
people they haven't seen that they don't
even know what that is there's a whole
generation of people that i mean
honestly most of them haven't even seen
flower all they do is dab
so when you show them a proper flower
of something like that it shows i think
i think it could change somebody's life
to see something like that it could show
them that there's more to this than just
cookie cookie cookie cookie you know
there's like there's other stuff out
there
and
i think that you know that that to me is
valuable and the high is different the
effect is different the terpene profile
is different
and
i mean it's something that people
nowadays don't see like i was saying
earlier you know a lot of the herb today
is very very narcotic people are looking
for something to basically be a
substitute for a pill
and um
yeah they can find it out there but i
don't to me
it's not always about that
um i mean i've been i've been blessed to
smoke some really really interesting
flour
and
you know the effects from them can be
way way different and i don't know that
a lot of people have ever had flour like
that
yeah i would i would agree it's
certainly one of the rarer ones right
just not uh probably not last question
but the one before
you mentioned wet dream this is one i
wanted to ask you about because i
noticed the cult classics used it in
some of their lines would you be able to
fill us in on where you fit in with the
wet dream and where they fit in
yeah so the wet dream was a project that
some friends and i had done we started
it and i mentioned it earlier it was you
know from reef and then we hit the blue
dream and we grew it outside for a
couple of seasons
and then i had had some that i had um
flowered out i was gonna try and do
another i did
i was on the f3 generation of it and i
gathered some pollen
um from it to kind of further the line a
little bit more and i actually gave it
went down and saw my friend norcal and
gave it to him
at the time he was growing the dog's
waltz
and i liked it that was a great plant
very very interesting and so i said hey
i said do you mind hitting the dog's
walt and making some seeds for me with
it and he said yeah no problem
he has a lot of stuff going on in his
life so
he had that pollen
and at some point he connected with cult
classics because they they know each
other and he gave him he gave him the
pollen or he sorry he gave him he hit
the og kb and he hit the mendo breath
and he gave cult classics the og kb
seeds from from that project
um
the next time that i heard about that
because we're all pretty busy um
somebody contacted me and said hey are
you working with cult classics and i
said who's called classics
and uh he said yeah he's got a og kb wet
dream
line that he's releasing you don't know
anything about this i said not on
anything about it so i um
called norcal and talked to him for a
bit and he's like oh man i completely
forgot uh that you gave me that pollen
he's like yeah i'm working with him on
on the seed project and you know we're
doing the ogkb stuff and blah blah blah
this that and the other
i had never heard of him i had never met
him i would not have given him my pollen
this is a conversation that i have had
uh publicly i think with him at one
point
and um but because norcal is my friend
and i figured he would you know get
compensated from it
rather than cause a problem like what's
done is done i just let it go i had a
lot of other stuff going on a lot of
other things that i was working on
anyway so it didn't really bother me
um
then just kind of like and i don't want
to go too much into his personal issues
but i'll just suffice it to say that
like
they didn't necessarily it didn't really
work out the way that he wanted it to
work out um
not to in all full transparency not an
individual that i've ever wanted to be
associated with a person that i've met
one time and i've never had any interest
in further associating with him um i
never got compensated on any of that
stuff never had really any interest as
long as norcal was getting you know
compensated in some way shape or form
beyond that um you know i've seen a lot
of people run the work i've seen a lot
of people be excited about it it is kind
of cool to see that because you know
what they're most excited about is
usually the fact that there's no no
intersex issues that have been found in
those seeds the size the vigor the resin
production
the profiles
you know if anything i think it's a
testament to the work that my friends
and i did over the years with that
pollen that being said it was not ever
intended for a release nor did i ever
have any nor would i have ever worked
with somebody like him
it's just what happened and uh
from there i would say um at some point
he did give me a couple of the other og
kb uh wet dream seeds that existed and
he also gave me uh some of the mendo
breath uv wet dream seeds that existed
and so i was able to
you know keep those and i've used the
meadow breath uv wet dreams
in a line that i did and
you know other than that i would say
yeah it's kind of cool to see it get out
there he did a hell of a job with the
branding and the promotion but just as a
general human being he's not somebody
that i would associate with or would
ever want to be associated with
unfortunately it's a common sentiment we
hear in general when people
have this type of thing happen to them
but i guess on the more above board side
of things we see and you mentioned
earlier that you've been collaborating
with grow low-key in a few projects
do you plan to do more collabs with them
going forward and do you see collabs
becoming like a more popular option in
the industry going forward
i do i i could see people working
together more collaboratively
we do intend to do another project
together so right now i think we're just
kind of in the planning phase like i
said if he finds something in this
recent hunter i find something that may
be the direction we go down
we've shared cuts back and forth so
there are some potential lines in there
and then i also have a huge you know
collection of my own that i could pull
from if i was interested so yeah we we
definitely plan on working together um
he's another one of those guys he's just
a stand-up person somebody that i'm
happy to work with and be associated
with
and you know he shared that tricks with
me that's a plant that he hasn't given
to anybody else so it took you know took
a lot of trust in him to give me that
and to share it with me and to trust
that i wouldn't put it out there you
know without without without his
approval basically
so i'm definitely looking forward and i
do think that there is going to be a lot
of more collaborative projects going
forward um mostly because people are
just becoming more comfortable with
meeting people and kind of being out
there
and so we're meeting people outside of
our immediate circle than we would
otherwise associate with
and you know loki was somebody that i
met when i threw a farmer's market event
um we actually threw the first uh
cannabis farmers market in sf
and through a through a delivery service
that i had
and um he actually came out there he was
super humble he uh came and asked about
some balian flower that i had been
posting and growing
and i told him we were sold out because
we were
um and he didn't say anything he just
walked away and then he came back with
my buddy straight flame
and uh straight flame was like hey man
this is grow low key blah blah i'm like
oh man he was much smaller still at that
time but i said i said hey i said why
didn't you say that you know why did you
say you knew straight flame or whatever
who you were
he just didn't want to say anything but
i you know i had a stash of balian
flowers for all my friends and so i
pulled out of there and gave him a bunch
of stuff
um
but yeah a good guy and just you know
like like i said people are starting to
come out meet more people i had a couple
friends that didn't want to come to that
event because they were pretty sure we
were going to get raided
um
so
some people are definitely getting more
comfortable because since then a lot of
those events the farmers markets and the
sessions and all that stuff have
definitely popped up
and so when you do a collab what's the
ideal collab set up for you like do you
like it when say each person brings one
parent to the table or do you think it
doesn't necessarily have to work like
that is there a set kind of format you
like or just whatever flows happens i
think i think kind of whatever whatever
happens i mean for me he had a really
nice plant to contribute and i had kind
of the stable that we could pollinate he
also gave me a couple that we could
pollinate from his collection so i feel
like that was a really mutually
beneficial situation for both of us
i got to pollinate some cuts that were
in demand like the dubs garden peanut
butter breath
and
obviously his tricks and whatnot
and then you know he got access to a lot
of my genetics which you know i had
brought the gelato 41 and the biscotti
um and what not to the table so that's
you know one of the dev one of
definitely one of the positive sides of
just being who we are and where we're
from is just having access to all the
genetics whether it's the runts or the
gelatos or this or that or the other
like we've always been some of the first
people to have those
um so just being kind of first in space
and then you know getting access to that
and me being able to contribute some
things and him being able to contribute
from his side of the circle really
worked beneficially for both of us i
mean i have a project going with a
friend of mine right now that i'm not
going to get into too much but basically
i sent him some pollen and you know he's
going to pollinate something that's uh
you know super in demand right now and
so we'll see you know people are
interested or not interested regardless
you know we're always gonna we're always
gonna keep doing what we like
cool cool that that's interesting to
hear so
just to jump back to some things we were
talking about before
you mentioned that you know like a seeds
that you've used some of their work
along with connoisseur let's talk about
some of these older breeders who often
don't get a good mention like
connoisseur is a good one because
as far as i can see he's always done
pretty good work but doesn't frequently
get a mention what was it that drew you
to the grand doggie perps and what's
your general opinion on connoisseur
genetics
so i love the chem d and the gdp
um you can't you can't have lived in
oakland and not appreciate purple and
then the chem you know i really
appreciated the pairing i mean i i had
watched connoisseur ojd and them um
working for a while with really just
a nice collection of uk varieties um
like the church and what not out there
and um also some of the stuff from the
states
and it always just seemed like they were
doing in they had he had interesting
pairings that they were working and i
know that him and true work together and
they had a falling out which i'm sure
you know true may or may not speak on
when you speak to him
um
but i always thought that they did
interesting work and you know especially
the perps and the chems and i think they
were one of the first ones to do a forum
cross it may have been true actually
that was one of the first ones to do
like a forum cross and actually publicly
release it
but
i liked a lot of that older work you
know karma was somebody who did a lot of
older work he's he's still managed to
stay relevant and uh he's moving
definitely and doing some things out
here
and um
got some of the older breeders that kind
of you know are still out there ace and
them um doing interesting work
and um
most guys someone you know that he did
some c99 work um years ago that was all
really really solid old-time moonshine
work um stuff like that
that you know didn't really gain a lot
of buzz but it was you know good flower
i grew a bunch of that stuff and i
enjoyed it um i feel like there was just
there was more space back then to it's
weird there's like more breeders now but
they do there's less variety in my
opinion it's more people doing the same
[__] and less people doing
more unique work
i feel like back then there were less
people but they were doing they were
doing very very different work
i mean there was always like the dutch
seed banks that kind of seemed like you
could just pick one and swap them for
the other
um you know there was sag and martha
they were doing different stuff back
then there was some peak 19 and a couple
other things from them that were
interesting
but generally you know whether it was
scentsy or nirvana whoever it might be
they were all kind on the same thing at
that point
um even greenhouse or whatever you know
greenhouse had some interesting work
back then that people seemed to like i
didn't really grow much of it
um but yeah there was there was a lot of
just smaller kind of more underground
people that were doing it i mean even og
rascal was doing work back then people
forget that og rascal did work like that
back then
he does he doesn't put seeds out now but
you know i've definitely i've run some
of his work he did bubba blue moonshine
and a couple other things
um that people just didn't see you know
head and head was another one you know
he had some mass super skunk sour d work
um rez who i'm sure people have talked
about before is another one um
you know whatever whatever with the
situation and the whole story with him
but you know though the work he was one
of the first ones
you have to give credit you know he's
one of the first ones to put
a sour type plant out in seed form for
people and you could grow the seeds and
find something that was similar or
better
you know i grew uh res
4d the chem 4 with the sour or 4sd come
forward the sour
that was phenomenal beautiful herb you
know to this day that's something that
actually uh profit wants to work on i
gave him
a pack of the chem sours that i still
have that was another phenomenal
combination that he made chem d with the
sour inbred line that he was working
so there's yeah there's definitely some
older breeders uh swan song was one um
he was from the boards there was a lot
of there's a lot of people that people
are never going to remember
and he did this limon um and a couple
other ones and the limona is something
that i used in that as a zl it's a
double sour diesel [__] trowel
and it's you know it's work like that
that
if you weren't around if you didn't know
about it if you didn't really want it
you were never going to see it it's not
something you could just go and just
pick up anywhere you really had you
really had to want it you really had to
look for it
yeah
and i think some of the best gems are
like that and that brings us to the next
question perfectly where you reference
that you know you've used some of aces
work in your own work
would you
in general kind of subscribe to the idea
that with ace you know they're breeding
with this really kind of untamed more
kind of raw stock so it's inevitable
that you're probably gonna get some more
kind of wild stuff you're gonna have to
put in a bit more of a hunt would you
agree with that sentiment or do you
think it's it's just like most other
packs you know you probably find a
keeper in a pack of ten type of thing or
is it a bit more involved
i think it's a bit more involved it
depends which of their lines you work
with they have some that are very very
open very kind of wild and they have
some that have been selected a little
bit more with the mind of cultivating
them indoors or at least you know in a
semi greenhouse environment
um i think the vietnam black tie was an
example of that i had plants that went
you know 11 weeks 13 weeks 15 weeks
there was plants that just didn't want
to stop in there they were massive
and but i managed to work it and select
an earlier flowering one and kind of
tame it down but it takes some work and
that's not something that people want to
hear nowadays they would rather have a
candy rain situation
than than to actually put the work in in
my opinion um they want it done for them
most people most people do not have any
interest in that but honestly that's
where some of the most amazing
the most unique varieties are going to
be found i mean if you wanna really make
something game-changing you're gonna
have to come out of left field you're
gonna have to come with something
different
and
i just don't know you know that you're
gonna find that in you know crossing
gelato with docido like i just i just
don't see that happening i don't see
how that would happen
um
especially like i feel like a lot of the
older genetics are fading out so if you
really really want something different
you do kind of have to pull for
something from ace or and yeah i know
there's a lot of the people that have
popped up over the last year or two um
god i'm gonna probably butcher it but i
think it's like the iranian like seed
exchange or something like that
um those guys are out there gathering
wild seeds you know semi
semi-domesticated some wild you know
but that's you know those are gems right
there that's you know access to that
work is really special and i know that
my my buddy from people under the stairs
chef rowe has worked with some of that
stuff
and there's definitely other people out
there collecting it and growing it
because they they see the value you know
i think they'll always be those people
that want they want to grow something
different something unique but they're
not solely focused on cash cropping this
is like this is a hobby for them
it's not something that they're thinking
oh you know i need to get to a light or
three a light it needs to be purple i
need to be able to put inside a runs bag
um they're not thinking like that
they're thinking you know about a unique
experience and that's what you'll find
in the ace gear you'll find something
different you might not find anything
good at all
but if you find something nice
you're going to find something really
nice i mean i'm stoked to have grown a
bunch of those i don't think that
there's a lot of people that could ever
say that they have grown a plant like
that
and i got to grow it and share it with
my friends and show them something
really really unique you know and i'm
grateful to have had the opportunity to
do that to not be under this pressure i
mean i think about these commercial
facilities nowadays
the main ask is you know 20 thc x number
of grams per square foot you know this
number of days of flowering plants get
harvested when they're expected to be
harvested on a schedule not not when
they're ready not not when they're ripe
you know then they got to be tested then
they got you know they got to get
packaged i mean they get touched so many
times along the way that by the time you
get it it's basically been abused
um you know the the times of actually
being able to go somewhere and you know
chop a branch off of a line and put it
into a jar for yourself
you know it's those days are mostly gone
for people like most people will never
know what that's like most people have
never seen flower like that so how could
they appreciate
you know what really makes a special
flower special
yeah of course
just to kind of
talk about a different older kind of
variety i noticed that you had worked
with the super silver haze and that
you'd done some crosses with it are
there any other kind of older strains
from these years gone by that you would
like to work with and also what was the
cutting of super silver haze that you
ended up using was it one of the more
known ones or just one you'd found
no it's it's the known cut it's it's
like the multiple cup winning cut that's
a cut that we've had for a long time
um i love it it's it's a way to one that
uh kind of has a
i don't know a lot of people in our
circle they don't really care for it
they don't really appreciate it but i
love it and our buddy wades who uh you
know grew it for a long time as well and
won a couple cups with it he
he loves it we love it um people down in
la that get it through our friends
delivery service they love it
um
it's a beautiful beautiful cut you know
i've tried i tried to hunt some super
silver haze from like more recent stock
and i didn't find anything worth
anything in there
so i always revert back to that to that
specific plant
as far as like um
newer or older varieties as well that
i'd be interested in working in
i'd say i've mostly what i have access
to i've worked with if i could get
anything back that reminds me of you
know something different it would be
there was a plant called lavender and
it's not the soma lavender it's it was a
bay area cut it might have come out of
norcal i think it probably did
and um mad farmer actually works with it
a lot and the and the urkel and um i to
be honest like i've wanted to buy some
of those crosses but me being me i just
want i actually just want the cut
or s1s of the cut so that i could work
with it in the way that i want and not
have it as diluted
that's a plant that i would actually
probably like to work with that's one of
the first ones that i actually started
with in the bay area when i when i got
that cut
beautiful plant great profile perfumey
like
resinous
great full relaxing high to it
just a really really beautiful plant and
that's probably one that i would like as
far as any of the older cuts i would say
the romulan if it existed would be
something that i would be interested in
um the train wreck is one that i've
always liked that i know that a lot of
my friends are gonna listen to that and
just shake their heads but i like it and
you know i got to the bay after the
train wreck had already kind of blown
through and so i never really got tired
of it because i never really had it to
that level the j1 would probably be one
of those as well
i would say the super silver haze is
probably the oldest cut though out of
all those cuts
before that
not there's not really much else that i
can think of that i would actually be
interested in i mean i know we've worked
with some interesting stuff
the haze like the piff
is one that some friends of mine have
worked with
that's one that i would probably be
interested in as well
just because i would honestly like to
see s-ones of it to run through to see
what we find i think it would be a freak
of a hunt um
and then beyond that i mean i know some
friends of mine have talked about the hp
and that's one i actually just saw some
flowers of that was very interesting
very unique
different you know there was a sage cut
by escobar
that my friends have grown for a while
that's a pretty interesting one it's not
the sage from th seeds it's something
else
so that's a pretty that's a pretty
unique one i mean those are really the
ones that i seek out for my personal
kind of garden for the stuff that i want
to do
because really like you know like you
said or like i was saying it's like how
many gelatos and dosi dos and sherbs can
we mix together at some point at some
point it's just like
really like if that's what you're
looking for here we have this and it's
basically the same thing
yeah yeah i agree completely
so when you think about starting a new
project is it all kind of based on feel
or do you really kind of think about it
and if you do kind of put a bit more
thought and maybe
um kind of writing down your ideas and
whatnot what are what are sort of the
considerations that come into play when
you are thinking about starting a new
project
so mostly i think about
what what the intention is what the goal
is and if if like i'll give an example
is that like we have an orange sherb cut
that loki found it's phenomenal
beautiful flower but i don't want to do
a whole line based on an orange profile
so i won't pick that plant as the basis
for the project
i think about really like
what what kind of gaps can we fill in
that haven't been filled in before
and
it makes me think about that's why i
think a lot about those exotic pairings
because
to just take like you know let's say we
take this this gelato 41 trix and i hit
it to the gelato 33 and i hit it to the
run so i hit it to the apple fritter or
whatever it might be
what am i really actually doing
but for me
that's how i feel and i know i've had
conversations with some of my friends
and they say well you know that's what
people want
they want to see you know the mac or the
wedding cake or the sherb or whatever
they want they want to know both sides
when they see it
me
i don't think about that as much
although if i'm doing a collab with
someone i do need to consider that
because that may be how they feel
and so i'll be inclined to do a couple
for them the way that they would want
them to do which may be more
commercially minded and i'll do a couple
for me
that i think are actually going to be
more unique and a perfect example of
that is i did the green crack with the
gb6 tricks and people had no interest in
it
but i kept telling people like this is
going to be a phenomenal pairing and a
friend of mine is growing them now and
they're ridiculous and the same thing
with the lucy and the gb6 tricks
99 of people have no interest care not
about the lucy at all if anything like
kind of like you may have thought when
they see the butterscotch they think oh
is that from cannerado and they're my
god that might be interesting it's from
canorado
when you tell them it's a butterscotch
hawaiian and is you know from reefer man
and made by some guy named poor white
farmer all of that is
just noise to them they're not hearing
anything that they there's nothing that
sounds good to them there
and it's unfortunate because you know
out of a lot of these plants like the
lucy tricks the super silver haze tricks
the burma tricks the green crack tricks
these older kind of you know
pre 2010 whatever varieties that were
created by people with not a mind
towards commercial production
um
those are some those are some phenomenal
plants
you know they're like the pairing is
going to be really really unique so i
think when when i when i do something i
think like what am i doing
why am i doing it and is it just
repeating the same thing if i'm just
going to repeat the same thing then like
what is the point of it just make more
of the same to do that i'll just make s
ones
i mean if people really want that then
just take gelato 41 and just make s ones
and take a lot of 33 and just make s
ones just do all s ones you know just
stop reading at all just make s ones
and if that's kind of your thing do that
but
that's not my thing i want to make
something that i'm actually interested
in growing like i'm excited you know to
i'm excited when i see
like i've seen the lucy tricks and it
has the same butterscotch profile as the
lucy but way better structure way better
bag appeal
much improved yield
like
beautiful beautiful but it has a
distinct profile and my feeling is that
because this is being grown by a wreck
facility
when it hits the market
people will not have seen something like
that and that stokes me
whereas like yes people will buy you
know gelato 41 tricks if we sold it to
them
but they might not buy lucy tricks
but i think that if you can get them to
try that flower if you can get them to
try that concentrate
like
it will become something that they seek
out because like you were talking about
the craft stuff it's unique and there's
no denying something that's different
from everything else it stands apart for
better for worse it stands out
so i think yeah when i when i do a
project i think a lot about
kind of just filling in the gaps and
kind of moving in a direction that other
people aren't moving in no i don't
really honestly think about a lot of
people i don't really think about what
other people are doing at all
i mean i should consider probably what
the market wants but at the end of the
day what i have found is that there's
enough people that are passionate about
the work that i'm doing
that i don't need to consider
the people who don't want it
you know and if and like i said if i'm
doing a collab and they want me to do
you know for gelato 41 or runts or apple
fritter or something to involve those
varieties in there we can do that
but at the same time i'm going to go and
do my weird thing and across this burma
that nobody cares about except for maybe
three people
and
it's fine because it's what makes me
happy it's the seeds that i'm most
excited about when i see a bunch of you
know gelato 41 seeds and whatever in my
fridge it's like
it doesn't really do anything for me i
know they're going to be phenomenal i
know they're going to photograph well um
you know i know it's going to look
really good i know it's going to smoke
good and it's going to have good flavor
i know it's going to you know it's going
to make people happy
but
there's a lot of other things you know
they could they could grow jelly breath
or dosey lotto or whatever and it would
probably do the same thing for them
yeah i get the sentiment but uh i
certainly feel like you know man after
my own heart in terms of you know do
your own thing and just make the weird
crosses that you like i love that so
the next question i would have is i've
noticed that you've done a few crosses
using exotic mike's work where do you
rate that because i noticed that you
know exotic mike gets a lot of
praise from a lot of people but i've
also had a lot of friends like people i
know in real life i've seen it myself
they grow the gear out and there's a
surprisingly large amount of hermes in
the gear you know i'm probably going to
cop some heat for that but
you know where do you find his work is
this just an acceptable risk when you're
growing out these types of genetics and
where do you rate exotic genetics in
general
yeah so from from mike i've used the
cooking cream cut um which is you know
that cup winning cut
and so i've used that one it's a hash
monster people love that there's been a
lot of requests lately from people
for
four plants that will wash well and
everybody knows that that plant washes
really well
so i know that if we cross it you know
the result will be just that
um as far as like kind of where i rate
mike and mike's work one i've met mike
i've spent time with mike um mike is a
really really solid person it's like
super humble really really good guy
and you know you're not going to please
everyone
in terms of there being some intersex
expression in the work
i'm not surprised he works with a lot of
different plants there's a lot of cookie
stuff in there
even some of the sherb stuff and whatnot
is in there and he does a lot of male
female
regular stuff i think he's about to drop
a feminized line which would be his
first one
and so i think that you know from doing
that standard male female you run the
risk of of seeing some of that intersex
expression
i do know though that that there's
people that are like super fanatical
about his work
um he's got a lot of people that find
gear in there that they just love and it
may just be that that they find you know
some intersex expression but they find
some cuttings that they're like yeah
this one will work and then they run
with it
um
in that regard i think it's fine mike
charges what i consider to be a
reasonable price for his seeds so if
you're going to find some intersex
expressions i don't think it's the end
of the world because the prices he keeps
the prices very very reasonable
if you charge a ton of money and the
work is unstable i think that's kind of
where like i would draw the line
personally
and i also know that you know he's um
he's definitely willing to like work
with people i think if people have
issues and whatnot i don't think he has
any issue replacing it or being
communicative like if he's had problems
with certain lines which i don't know
that he has had a huge number of issues
like as far as like with like the
cookies guys where they just had to like
disappear and some other people that
whatever i don't feel like naming right
now
where they kind of just disappeared for
a while and pop back up with a new line
so i re i rate mike pretty well and most
mostly because just i've spent time with
him and he could have a huge ego and he
could kind of be an [__] if he wanted
to be
but he's not
he's like he's one of the most decent
people you're going to meet in this
business so that goes a long way with
with me like i said i think he's pretty
transparent with people about the work
that he's doing
so can we expect to see you working with
any seed banks going forward and if so
which ones like what would be important
to you about if you're going to be
dealing with a seed bank how would you
want to go about establishing that type
of relationship
yeah that's i mean that's tricky to be
honest i don't really know
that that's what i want to do
i've worked with one seed bank before in
a limited capacity it's not really
something that's like kind of front and
center for me
i have enough people that are like
interested in my work that i don't
really need to do that
and i kind of am cultivating a different
type of model
than other breeders like i'm not really
looking to sell
on a smaller scale
to just like you know all these
different people and i mean that's that
is what the seed banks do i do get
requests from people to list with
certain seed banks but
there there's some good ones and i've
you know i've seen some people that have
worked with some of them before but it's
not really something that i'm really
actively kind of seeking out obviously
the biggest things to me would be just
that it they'd be stand up that they'd
be trustworthy and they provide good
customer service i mean the last thing
you want is someone having a problem
with them that that affects poor it
reflects poorly on you for working with
them and i'm sure you've seen you know
there have been some some fly-by-night
seed banks or
questionable practices with some of them
you know in in all kinds of ways whether
it's paying vendors or you know not not
delivering the appropriate seeds or you
know tampering with the seed packs or
all kinds of things that have happened
out there over the years so there you
know there's some seed banks that
friends of mine have had good
relationships with um i know my buddy
unknown profit has had a good
relationship with seeds here now i know
my buddy green team has also had a good
relationship with them
so you know that's somebody that if it
lined out it would make sense but
i'm not sure that you know the work that
i do necessarily has kind of the
commercial profile that they might want
and as far as like promoting i don't
really do a lot of promoting i just kind
of post what i like and
you know
i just
i'm i don't really know that i would be
a good partner honestly for someone
because i don't really care to promote a
whole lot if you look at my instagram
it's really just it's just me just
sharing flower and kind of thoughts on
things that i like
and
mostly work that we've been doing or you
know promoting some of my friends in
their work
and you know just really kind of taking
what we had on the forum and just
putting it on instagram not really
trying to
you know create a whole thing beyond
that it's just it just kind of is
exactly what it is it's like these are
the flowers this is what we're growing
and i really use instagram as kind of
like a like a networking tool to be able
to talk to other people about you know i
really like facility design i'm
interested in environmentals i'm
interested in lighting i'm interested in
a lot of these other factors and kind of
just really improving that aspect of the
cultivation
not so much for like you know buy these
seeds and they're going to be here and
they're dropping here it's a lot of work
to do all that it's a lot of time and a
lot of commitment
um i find that i have better
relationships with some of the larger
farms and enough of my friends kind of
run these facilities
that
i don't you know they understand my work
they appreciate my work and so being
able to just kind of work with them
enables me to still do what i want to do
without having to kind of deal with
things on a smaller scale because
there's a lot of blowback that comes
from also the people i don't think
people think about that i think they
just are excited to work with a seed
bank
they don't think about okay the customer
service they provide or you know this
person this one person had an issue but
you're dealing with hundreds of people
or thousands of people so you know
there's issues that pop up and kind of
like you said people have had issues
with certain breeders and whatnot and
then it becomes like a whole online
thing and it's it's more energy than i'm
than i think i currently wanna you know
extend in that direction if somebody
wanted to do like
like a small amount in a limited drop or
something i would be inclined to do that
um
but not really like a full commitment to
say like yeah i'm going to keep
promoting and do all that stuff i've
seen people kind of get upset with with
seed producers too for not promoting and
not
tagging them properly and reposting and
all i don't i don't want to get into all
that's a big it's just too much to me
would mostly be like hey if you like my
work great you can carry it if you don't
care to carry it don't carry it it's
totally fine and um
yeah but i know like i said i know a
nonprofit has had a good relationship
with seeds here now and my buddy from
green team as well
and a couple other people that i know so
probably would lean would lean towards
working with them if that was the case
yeah
cool i mean it makes sense right so i
think we're now on to our last couple of
questions before we get to the rapid
fire ones at the end so a pertinent
question i ask all the guests what is
your preferred style of growing and by
that i mean are you an organic or more
of a synthetic guy how do you do it
so for outdoor cultivation i mean number
one i when it comes to like the organic
versus synthetics i don't really draw a
hard and fast line i think there's
products from both sides that really
make sense i know there's people running
like no-till or low-till organic gardens
with amendments and worms and they leave
the leaves and they do all that and
that's dope but indoor that never made
any sense to me i grew up indoor
cultivating so to me it's always been
you know initially was bottle nutrients
and then it was salts
just to be able to get the cost down and
at the end of the day like
i never really noticed a huge decrease
in the quality i have done like fully
organic like amended soil
and you know i actually like to do that
for final hunts i think it really gives
the plants an opportunity to pull what
they want from that but when you try and
maintain the soil and do all that in its
indoors it kind of becomes a pain you
need a lot more space
outdoor yeah the organic soil
like fish emulsions all that stuff i've
always been a big proponent of that
style of gardening for the outdoor
plants i think that they love it i think
there's really something really really
special about being able to cultivate
outdoors i love it
that's definitely something that you
know that i appreciate about having the
chance to spend in norcal is all those
years being able to grow outdoors
in spite of the fires and everything
else for indoor
i definitely prefer
cocoa usually is the preferred medium i
have a lot of experience in rockwool as
well rockwool is just cleaner um but i
kind of like i appreciate cocoa i find
it to be kind of like an in between
between like rock wool or some kind of
you know soilless medium or you know
um i don't know amended soil or whatever
it might be a pro-mix or whatever that
might be with peat with peat and whatnot
so i would probably say my favorite over
the years has been cocoa i find that you
know i can grow really large plants in
there
multiple irrigations per day and for
years and years and years it was house
and gardens uh house and garden
nutrients which i really appreciated and
you know now i find you know you can use
floraflex you can use veg bloom you can
use all these products
really a lot of people and this is
friendly advice to anyone who's
listening a lot of people are getting
taxed on their nutrients um at the end
of the day the nutrients are just one
component you can't buy your way out of
hard work so all the equipment all the
tools all the fertilizer whatever you're
spending all this money but if you're
not actually doing the work
i would take a low-tech garden with hard
work over
a garden with all expensive bottle
nutrients and whatnot it's just it
doesn't make any sense if people are
listening don't pay for water buy salts
if you're gonna do that
and if not buy amendments and mix your
own soil
yeah really solid advice so
do you have a favorite product you like
to plug at all
um
that's a good question
i would say as far as a favorite product
um
i don't really think i'm loyal to
anybody at this point i mean there's
some lighting companies that are pretty
decent
it's i mean god i don't i honestly don't
know i mean i would say
ah
man yeah i really don't know i mean
there's there's some products that i've
used but
no one that i would really recommend off
top i would tell people you know to
avoid gavita
um i could tell people what to avoid
more than anything do it um do it yeah i
would say avoid gavita avoid avoid
advanced nutrients
avoid water-based nutrients if you don't
need them like literally don't buy
anything that's that's mixed with water
buy fluoroflex because it's cheap if you
want
foliar if you need to
to supplement it
look at what the agriculture industry is
doing and that's you know stop buying
something just because it has a fancy
package on it i mean jr peters has a
product called stem very inexpensive
tons of micronutrients but if it was
bottled by advanced it would cost like
five times as much 10 times as much
um
yeah i would say you know look look into
the leds and you know compare the
compared the different technologies that
are out there there's a lot of people on
instagram right now giving a lot of good
information on leds and you know feel
free to reach out to the people and ask
and learn you know and see
learn you know about the value of an
adjustable spectrum light and
look at you know the cmhs you know and
consider consider you know how you're
operating your garden how you're setting
it up and
um yeah cleanliness you know probably if
i was going to plug a product it would
probably be bleach or something of the
sort
because
cleaning is fundamental people do not
want to clean they seem to forget that
we're basically like housekeepers and
janitors for plants at this point
so
keep it clean and um yeah i don't know i
would say there's there's definitely
companies that are worth avoiding out
there that would not be worth messing
with
and um yeah
yeah i don't know
good call so just to wrap up our kind of
growing questions do you have any
growing tips for the listeners or i
guess maybe more specifically do you
commonly see people making certain
mistakes with growing what's the mistake
you see people commonly doing
um
common mistakes overfeeding is a common
mistake
trying to buy their way out of out of a
problem that they created
there is no solution to hard work
pay attention
be diligent don't do something when it's
convenient for you do it when the plant
needs it
when you build your systems and you are
designing a space
consider all the various factors think
about where you're going and not kind of
what you can afford right now and where
you are and so as you design as you buy
as you build
um think about all of that and
prioritize the plan
like i said no amount of automation no
amount of cameras or sensors for this
that and the other is a replacement for
actually having experience with the
plant
there's a lot of people that have you
know horticulture degrees
and whatnot they think that they know
better than the plant they think that
they can look at a chart
and or meter or readings and this and
that and the other and that's that's
that actually is what's happening it's
not when you look at the plant
if you can't tell what's happening you
have not spent enough time with it
i mean i can if you walk into a room and
it feels wrong if it smells wrong if the
leaf feels wrong if the if the structure
on the leaf looks off if the general
like the general shape form or kind of
like the stance of the plant is off
something is wrong in your room
and i think a lot of people they over
light their gardens they overfeed their
gardens like
they do too much and pay attention not
all strains are the same not all
cultivars want the same thing
so
think about that when you're setting up
your garden if you want to design
something to be able to grow multiple
different varieties make sure you can
have different feeds on each bench or
each table
and keep it really really clean you know
i think a big mistake that people make
is like
they you know i mean you're only gonna
get what you put into it that's all
you're gonna get out of it if there's no
like i can tell when a person
has neglected their garden and i've had
people watch my garden before and i can
tell like they just watered it right
before i got back
and the plants you know have a little
bit of curl on the leaf or a little bit
you know they have a little they you
know they're going to dry back and
they're going to burn and i don't care
what they said i know i know exactly
what they did
um but yeah my biggest advice would
probably be just
you know don't be afraid to experiment
but don't change too many variables at
once either like you won't know what
actually caused the effect be patient
and think about what you're doing think
about whether or not you're trying to
learn to cultivate a specific variety
think about whether you're trying to get
experience with different equipment
think about you know whether you're
happy with you know b grade buds and
when it comes down to harvesting and
drying and curing like give it the
attention that it deserves when you run
something and put that much time into
something and you don't cure it properly
you don't store it properly
like
you're wasting your time you're never
gonna see the full potential of that
plan
and um yeah i would just say just you
know be diligent be thoughtful
and pay attention you know care and the
more you care the better the better your
garden will turn out and don't be afraid
you know to ask questions don't be
afraid to reach out to people you'd be
surprised especially nowadays how
helpful some people will be like i'm not
saying that inspector is going to answer
your message if you ask but he might
and you know i think a lot of people too
they
they want to
they want to be great they're afraid
they're afraid to make mistakes and
understand that all of us made mistakes
all of us have ruined a bat all of us
have flooded a room or you know inserted
a bulb improperly or whatever it might
be all of us have done it and we've done
it multiple times
and be diligent with your ipm be
diligent if you
if you think it doesn't matter and you
start taking a day here a day there and
skipping this or skipping that i promise
you it's going to bite you and it's
going to be months of cleanup
and
you that a little bit of time that you
neglected is going to come back to bite
you in the ass
every single time you can always look
back and see where you were lazy and it
will come back and bite you
yeah some phenomenally solid advice
right there for all the growers looking
to improve their game a bit so
last question before a little quick fire
round we can see that there are more and
more states coming online regularly and
we can also see that it's really hard to
find good flower in the majority of
these states like for example
you know in on the east coast in places
like mass like i can only think of like
two people where i'd be able to get good
flower from them and that's like mass
medical and then like chemdog slash that
guy from maine those guys are obviously
crushing it so i guess my question is
for people who are from these smaller
states just coming online is really no
established scene and i know i know that
mass has a bit more of an established
scene than most places but i digress if
you're from a state where there's less
of an established scene it's hard to
find good flower
what are some tips for
the kind of communities in these places
to just lift their game and produce
better quality flour and get up to
scratch with the west coast for example
well
i'm going to have kind of a defeatist
attitude i think about the recreational
market at least out east for a while
this market is going to be dominated by
by the big players by the people that
have the deep pockets
so if your goal is to try and produce a
higher grade quality flower
i honestly think that the best you could
hope for is probably like a cheesecake
factory level of flour
where it's good but anybody who knows
something phenomenal something truly
special will never be impressed by it
and the the big reason why is because of
everything that goes into it in terms of
how it's harvested how long it sits
um it goes out for testing then it gets
jarred up then it goes and sits on the
shelf there's just such a gap in between
that scene and when it actually hits the
market that the flower is just going to
be like degraded by the time a consumer
actually gets it so if you're used to
getting something really phenomenal high
end it's going to be really really tough
as a producer
there are states that are more friendly
i think maine is one of those states
that seems to be that like smaller
producers can kind of get more into the
market there
so that might be worth considering i do
think that you know
try i mean if you really really want and
you're really really committed to
actually producing for the market like
on the recreational side
you're gonna have to raise some capital
and try and make a run of it and be
willing to fight tooth and nail for you
know three four five years
and i don't know that there's a ton of
people that are willing to do that
because the biggest producers on the
medical side of the market
they're not going to want to make the
transition a lot of people i saw that
happen in california not a lot of people
have transitioned successfully through
64. a lot of people disappeared a lot of
people
are not made to exist in a corporate
structure they're just not built for it
it's a whole different beast of a
situation and i also think to be
completely blunt like the red the amount
that people get paid by these facilities
is not equivalent to what they were
earning so a lot of a lot of the most
talented growers are not going to want
to work for these facilities and i guess
a big thing is that like if you are a
grower
are you capable of operating in a in a
semi-corporate environment because
whether you like it or not that's what
you're doing you know you're analyzing
costs you're managing people
you're dealing with you know
unemployment and payroll and all of this
stuff that that's not why a lot of
people got into it
so
i think you know i think in a few years
after all of this settles there will be
an opportunity for some of these smaller
craft places to pop up and you know i'm
very very much looking forward to that
because i just don't think that it
should cost that amount of money
to and require that much security and
that much tracking and all of these
crazy things
to be able to you know grow an eight
lighter and you know have a small i mean
the equivalent of a small craft brewery
it just it shouldn't it shouldn't be
that much different from that
in terms of you know they don't have to
have security in front of their spaces
they don't have to have cameras in every
corner
they don't have to pay all these
exorbitant taxes
and they let them pop up pretty much
anywhere
you know for for us you know it's hard i
think for a lot of guys to make that
transition for a lot of people to make
that transition
if you can get enough people on the same
page you can try and make a run at it
but if you're looking to produce higher
quality i mean i don't honestly think
that we're going to see the level of the
quality of flour that we saw in the
medical days in california
on the rec market for a long time
i think best case scenario a lot of the
flour that's on the market is b grade i
think a lot of the oil that's on the
market is better because the oil is
processed so quickly and then it doesn't
get it's more
the bho that they're making in
california as an example from the fresh
frozen material it's a lot easier to
preserve it and bring it to market in a
stable state where it still has a really
really strong terpene profile and still
has a nice solid effect
if the flower isn't stored precisely all
along the way before you get it it's
gonna be an inferior product i mean i've
seen shops in oregon like that where
it's you know it's 80 degrees in there
and they've got the jar sitting there in
full light
and when you ask them you know if they
understand about oxidation and
temperature and the terpenes you know
and they they don't they had no clue
what i was talking about
so i think that you know for the
quality scene on the east coast i think
that there are people producing
quality flower but i think a lot of them
are going to stay medical a lot of them
are going to stay underground
and
i think there probably are some
facilities that are trying to produce
higher grade flower but at the end of
the day a lot of the people that are
bankrolling these facilities that's not
really what matters to them they're just
looking to grab market share make
revenue you know
they they just want to recoup their
investment and potentially flip their
business um
hopefully you know california will see
some brands that survive and exist i
know some people out there
that are doing you know that are fully
intending to do good quality work and i
think if a market could sustain that it
would be a larger market like california
yeah of course and you just raised a
really interesting point that i want to
touch on for a second there have you
ever met a bud tender who legitimately
impressed you with their knowledge
oh wow no
um
yeah even at archive i've met some
people that were like knowledgeable you
know and they were pretty passionate but
nobody that ever really impressed me
with their knowledge and this is no this
is no disrespect to anyone but if you
knew that much about this if you were
that passionate about this like
is that really where you would be
like yeah like the reason why i bring it
up is because i got sent an email and
there was some like event like for is
like the bud tender awards or something
and they were like oh would you would
you like to come and document it and
obviously they don't realize i'm in
australia but more importantly like all
i was thinking to myself is like
what would i be documenting like the
mediocrity like
i like yeah like i've
i'm disappointed by bud tenders
consistently it's like
just the most passe thing to do if
you're superficially into cannabis
yeah i had i had to explain so i went
into one dispensary i had to explain to
them i asked if they had any live resin
and they said oh we've got this and i
was like well that that's co2 and they
were like oh but yeah but it's live i
was like no
no like
i said that's not what i'm asking about
i said you have any like fresh frozen
material like bho extract i'm like
that's the only way it would be like
that and i had to explain to them the
difference and then one of them asked me
hey you know you know you know a lot
about cannabis like do you want a job
here and i i'm not not to be rude i
laughed
um
but not not like that but only to say
like no
like um this is my life is my whole
upset i don't have to get into it with
them but like
you should know that you should know the
difference between live resin and butter
and sugar and wax nbho and co2 it's
really not that complicated
like
all you need to do is care to educate
people but the reality is like i said
about the companies that are running
these places the bar is so low they pay
so little they care so little about the
training
and kind of helping build these people
up just like most companies they don't
really care about building up their
employees why would they care
so
they you know unfortunately most people
that come in what if you've listened all
they say is what's the highest thc thing
you have for the least amount of money
that's literally what people are
interested in
like
yeah that
that's it you know the the test results
are a whole nother thing you know that's
like
i mean
some states are more strict than others
but at the end of the day you know
there's been stories you know out of
washington and other places with labs
completely faking test results
and um
it's kind of unfortunate like we live in
a thc kind of dominant society people
really just only care about
the majority of the customers that come
in just care about the thc level
you know and if it's 30 it sells faster
if it's 25 it sells fast if it sells 20
great below 20 they're not super
interested
yeah it's it's interesting right i i
remember hearing that uh one of the
testing companies i can't remember who
it was not even if i remembered i
probably wouldn't want to say the name
but they were like you know you'd pay
for the test and then you'd also pay a
little extra fee if you wanted it to
test over like you know 26 or something
i was just like oh yeah cool
oh yeah
oh yeah that's i mean people people have
shopped around for
testing companies like to see
who will test higher because they know
that they'll they'll get a higher ticket
for that
yeah so
that's
interesting but also sad but
not unexpected given where we're at
anyway on to our last little run of
questions what i like to call the
quickfire questions so these ones you
know feel free to answer them as quickly
or as long as you'd like first one
what's your favorite weed that you've
ever smoked
wow
um
probably this the cali mist we used to
get in san diego in like early 2001
2002.
wow yeah that that sounds like a really
nice throwback
yeah it was phenomenal it was beautiful
you could smell it in the air no matter
if somebody was smoking or wherever they
were smoking it you could it was
distinct it had an incredible high
that was super clear you felt lifted but
clear no
no tiredness no anything to it really
really beautiful and then the other one
was honestly some some willie nelson
that they had at harbor side i used to
vend to harbor side and i went in there
one time
and they had bought a pound of it my god
i think they paid like six or seven
thousand for it at the time and when
pounds of sour were going for 36 34
significant
but they gave me some of it and the high
from that was phenomenal i mean really
really really special flower it never
made the shelf they split it up amongst
themselves back there
interesting stuff okay so on the
opposite end of the spectrum what's the
worst weed you've ever smoked and the
follow-up is what's the worst weed that
you've smoked that somehow got
commercial traction and other people
seemingly thought it was pretty good
wow the worst weed that i've ever smoked
was probably the brickweed i smoked in
miami when i was like 16.
um
since then i've been like no i'm i won't
do that um the worst weed that's gained
commercial traction is probably the mac
or the purple punch either one of those
yeah two two contenders that we've heard
before actually no we haven't heard the
mac we've heard pebble punch but there
you go a new one bringing mac to the the
worst commercial one but i see where the
merit is so the next one is if you're
stranded on a desert island you can only
take three strains with you what three
are you going to take
wow
probably
the chem d
uh probably
the tk
and
probably
like
the lavender
um or some something along that line of
the the old perps i'd probably say
because that that would i mean i'm gonna
miss the sour but i think i think if i
combine the 91 and the uh
or if i can buy the tk and the d i could
probably get something that i like in
there
love it and you just wave goodbye to
sativas at that point
hey
i'm on an island it'll be everything's
gonna be fine
yeah lovely
okay so the next one is
if you could have back one clone that
you had lost or a clone that you'd
wanted but were just never able to get
your hands on what one would it be
wow
um
probably that lavender honestly it's i
just have a farm space for it i've never
haven't had anything like it in my
garden since
it would probably be that that lavender
yeah it's a really special plan i've
been lucky enough to be able to smoke
some grown out by duke and it's uh very
very memorable
nice lucky indeed
so
on to our very last question if you
could go back in time to any place any
time frame throughout all of history to
presumably get some seeds or a clone
where and when would you go
wow
um
man
[Music]
probably colombia
i think i think that a lot of
interesting work has come out of there
and it would have to be before we
started traveling around the world and
polluting the genetic gene pool
um
probably some of the colombian and if
not
if not the colombian some of the asian
stuff
like something something out in thailand
or cambodia or laos i think would be
really really phenomenal flower all
things being equal so i'd probably aim
aim towards one of those
both kind of with the same intention
really looking for something with an
incredibly like psychedelic uplifting
type hi
yeah fantastic sounds like something i
would consider doing
so with all that being said do you have
any shout outs or comments you'd like to
make
um
i would say if anything i just want to
shout out all my friends i really
appreciate them i'm super grateful for
everything that they've done for me over
the years
good friend of mine who really helped me
a whole lot when i landed in oakland and
didn't know anybody and didn't have
anything
and really looked out for me and knew a
lot about growing knew a lot more about
growing than i did at the time and now
you know he calls me for advice um but
still one of one of my greatest friends
and i super appreciate him and then my
buddies from icmeg who i would not be
here without
my buddy stoney uh my buddy frost boss
my buddy prophet my buddy norcal my
buddy dz
um just all all the people that i kind
of came up with and that made
opportunities for me and gave me a
chance
when i was just trying to make a run of
it out west a lot of these guys were
born and raised out here
and you know they didn't have to extend
any hospitality or do anything of the
sort but they definitely gave me a lot
of opportunity
and a couple of my friends from chicago
um who
were basically the reason that i thought
that this was possible and
were the ones that it convinced me to
come back to the west coast after i
tried the first time and it didn't work
out
and gave me an opportunity and kind of
just plugged me with with the right
people and you know were always there to
kind of help me even when i couldn't
afford to pay them
um just really you know super grateful
and honestly for my mother and my
grandmother
who in spite of me being completely
insane in their eyes have always
supported me and encouraged me and never
told me that i was incapable of doing
something and that's probably the best
advice that i would give anybody who's
actually taking the time to listen to
this is that you are completely capable
of doing it if you of whatever it is
that you want to achieve if you're
willing to apply and work and work and
single-mindedly focus on something and
be be good people don't let people take
advantage of you and give give what you
get
some really really really really solid
advice there
so just again a big thank you to ghost
from always be flowering for coming on
the show setting the record straight and
for all the knowledge bombs
absolutely man thank you very very much
for having me i really appreciate it
another problem my friend
[Music]
well there we have it another fantastic
episode a big big big thank you to ghost
taking the time to come on today
sharing all the awesome knowledge and
insights
and a big big thank you for you guys for
sticking around
[Music]
my patreon crew what is up
as always a big shout out to you guys
you're amazing
i appreciate you so much
and you know who else i appreciate
seeds here now
radio ridge nursery
420 australia and organic gardening
solutions
these guys are the best sponsors in the
world
they do god's work in my opinion
go check every one of them out
likewise check out always be flowering
hit up ghost
get some of those seeds
[Music]
big thank you again to green sleeves
merchantile
love papa lucas my man
doing the best designs check them out
guys
big big big love is always dragonfly
earth fam check out that regenerative
message if you don't know what it is
it's time to expand
how you ready for another episode
[Music]
i'll see you for the next one
we'll see you
[Music]
you