[Applause]
foreign
[Music]
[Applause]
as always you're joined here by your
boys have you guys here from the upside
down library and as usual we want to
give a huge shout out to our amazing
sponsors who helped make the episodes
happen huge shout out to seeds here now
number one seed bank in the industry
guarantee on satisfaction not just
germination why would you go anywhere
else if you are not happy at the end of
The Grow hit them up they'll sort you
out no reason to shop anywhere else
likewise in order to get your crop
pumping on all cylinders at its full
potential you need to keep your garden
pests and pathogen free for that check
out our friends at Copic biological
systems everything you need to keep pets
and pathogens everything you need to
produce the highest quality crop today
if you are trying to keep spider mites
at Bay check out the spydex buy tools if
you're trying to get rid of aphids if
you're trying to get rid of aphids check
out the appy param they've got
everything they've got all the Predators
to keep your garden happy and healthy
corporate biological systems thank thank
you so much we appreciate you
further check out our buddies at Pulse
sensors for the number one sensor on the
market ensuring that a whole bunch of
parameters you may not even think about
are still in check so that your crop is
the best today if you want bigger yields
more resin check out pulse sensors from
attempts to a single room to a
multi-state operation get serious get a
pulse
and last but not least our good friends
at the patreon gang we love you so much
truly the lifeblood of the show if you
want to get early access to upcoming
episodes unheard exclusive interviews
and genetic giveaways twice a month
check out the patreon
www.patreon.com thepodcast we appreciate
you so much guys thank you patreon games
so for this episode we're joined bikes
both Umami and Harry from Umami Seed Co
at Turf hype Powerhouse here to talk all
about their upcoming drops
some plans for the future and some
thoughts on the industry
so without further delay
let's get into it
alrighty gang we're back for another one
and on this episode I'm grateful to be
joined in person by the dynamic duo
behind the Exotic turp Powerhouse that
is Umami Seed Co a huge welcome to both
Umami and Harry for joining us today
thank you appreciate uh appreciate you
having us on good to be here
thanks again so much for joining me so
what are you smoking on today
man right now we're getting into some of
the uh some of these new flavors but I
mean I'm most excited about the
well I don't know Harry what do you like
most I mean I like out of these whole
batch I like Samurai tears yeah I think
the samurai taste that's the most potent
of all of them
um that's the cold heat by swish so it's
got runs it's got triangle F2 and then
we cross that to our kind of hash plant
Fino that's kind of our washer so
yeah this it's strong but really tasty
so
incredible trying to bring gas back you
know we've had a lot of fruity flavors a
lot of funky flavors and now kind of
want to go back into some of the ogs
some of the cushes some of the cams
you know
create interesting mixes between sort of
the new
the new fruit flavors and some of the
old Funk and find something you know
just keep it interesting
that's really cool I love the uh the old
school meets the new school sort of
approach I noticed uh on your Instagram
you had a few uh label tags of some
different strains and there are a few
different ogs in the mix there given you
just mentioned that what's your favorite
OG cut oh man favorite OG
probably the lumpus headband right the
the underdog right the diesel that's
that was one of the first ones that I
grew
by myself that absolutely smashed and I
was like really proud to show people
that bag
you know because like OG was always
tricky to grow right I had a homie who
was up in Chatsworth who taught us how
to grow sfv and like at that time we
were feeding I mean we fed it [ __ ]
cool Bloom and cow mag you know like
nothing but nothing but yeah I mean the
thing just ate calm and that was the
secret right I remember like I was like
talking to someone and like lumpo like
overheard me talk talking about calmac
and he was like bro don't give out the
[ __ ] secrets you know like that's
that's the magic that's how we Crush
OG's because everyone else would grow OG
and they'd yield nothing you know pound
to light pound and a half these thin
little Twiggy plants it was still fire
but you couldn't get to like pack on
weight then the first time we started
pulling like two pounds of light like
you know 2.2 with you know straight OG
Cuts like that was that was one we were
really excited about it but the headband
Skywalker TK hardcore the hardcore which
I mean now I'm actually I hadn't grown
the hardcore until recently I just got I
like went and got all of my old OG Cuts
back and a bunch of other stuff so I can
like re-rework some of the flavors but
that hardcore
but it doesn't look like all the classic
OG's it's definitely a bag seat or a
hybrid or something but that one has out
of all the OG's as the most unique
twist
right like a lot of them are really they
taste almost identical they look almost
identical you can see the little subtle
differences but that one is like
it's quite different
yeah I noticed it's had like a bit of a
Resurgence I um I'm trying to remember I
think it's Nasha is a breeder who I'd
seen do some hybrids with the the
hardcore and it got me interested in it
do you think you'll do any
um seed releases using the hardcore
going forward
yeah 100 as long as the crosses come out
fire
you know the only problem I watched
hardcore in the past which now now that
like solvent extract is kind of gone
where it's gone
um I'm really trying to focus on
products that will grow like genetics
that will grow well in flower form and
then also will wash well right they have
the right type of resin and everything
else the hardcore I remember we washed
it got like less than one percent didn't
melt you know it was tough and I
definitely wasn't as good at making hash
back then as I am now like we didn't
know anywhere near what we do now but
you know that's definitely going to be
some work to get something that's going
to melt in a high enough rate where as
it might be a cross of Hardcore and then
find a dope Fino then cross that again
with something else right that's got at
least carries the flavor but then will
give us you know the yields that we want
yeah because I mean nowadays people are
upset if it doesn't yield like four
percent you know five percent in the
bags and then press at 80 plus percent
you know
yeah the the market has certainly
dictated some certain minimums around
um you know returns and what's going to
make it worthwhile out of curiosity I'm
sure we're going to delve down the
rabbit hole or concentrates and extracts
quite a bit just to start off what's
your what's your favorite type of
extract you know are you like a dry
sieve guy a bubble hash where what's
your favorite thing I mean I'll probably
get some Flack for it but like
BHO applesauce
yeah stripped straight up you know I
love rosin I love rosin but you know
pour one out for all the mono terpenes
that get lost in the water like you
don't get the exact same profile and you
know like some people would argue that's
better because some of those mono
terpenes are
you know they're not as good or they're
this or they're that but like nothing
captures the absolute Essence like a
butane propane blend super cold cold
cured like I always hated diamonds and
sauce because especially back before we
were using like cold hot Tech on nails
right where if you hit like a hot dab of
like rocks and Terps
Terps melt off the thca first yeah those
are supposed to be dabbed at the lowest
temperature right so it's exactly the
opposite right so it's not you know the
flavor profile gets totally screwed but
yeah blend that up and make some
applesauce like
all all day
yeah definitely I think there's a lot of
like sort of
um
I don't know mantras that exist in the
states that don't escape it outside of
the US and so I guess like
um you know yeah there are a lot of
people who don't like BHO here there's
like a lot of people who don't like Jack
Harrah here and train wreck and all that
and blue dream
um yet in the rest of the world we
haven't been so fortunate to have that
exposure and so I'm still like man [ __ ]
give me that Jack Herer give me that BHO
I love it
um and I agree some of the best dabs
I've ever had were uh BHO for sure so
that's really interesting to hear
um I wanted to ask because you guys do
breed for extracts and for Terps
specifically just as a general
recommendation I always like to ask
breeders this if I don't give you any
information about the buyer because I
know the answer is you want it you're
going to want to know more information
but I want to ask if you can recommend
one strain out of your catalog and I
guess by implication I'm sort of saying
like what do you just think is a good
all-rounder what would you recommend to
someone if you don't know anything about
their grow style but you're just like
those people would be pretty happy at
the end of The Grow what do you
recommend
um for like a recent release foam
probably you know phone smashes it
yields well it's frosty it's purple
um it'll do really well in the in a wash
both solvent and non-solvent stacks it's
easy to grow
you know like in terms of just like
grabbing some seeds and you know being
able to throw down round one without
really having to tweak anything too hard
like she's just a [ __ ] monster all
the fenos are just big and blocky and
Crush
and they all wash well because swish the
Fino that I reversed that one washes at
like four and a half almost five percent
um which I picked that plant because
it's super Iced Out purple Hello PM
resistant squatty quick you know
flowering time that one is done at 60
days like done you can go longer but
there's absolutely no point you get no
higher yield the flavors ultimately a
lot of the flavors like start to mute
out and change the longer you run them
kind of like Skittles if you're running
like Skittles yeah bro you pull Skittles
at day 53 yeah 50 some people even like
that's when you get the candy then the
longer you go the gassier it gets it'll
get the bag appeal goes through the roof
once you go like 70 days on Skittles
it'll be purple like it totally changes
but the Terps are just gone
I mean it doesn't last long by the time
you've cured it
that flake just starts to disappear
every day and there's no like
oh I've got the Skittles and curing for
like three months it's amazing like no
like it's you want to look like lawn
clippings
like straight up
because it's getting rolled up or it's
you know it's turned into hash like
you're not looking at it while you smoke
it flavor over everything that was my
whole thing I don't care about anything
else the whole ethos is Flavor so if I
get lost or I'm like trying to figure
out what we want to cross or where are
we going to go next
flavor I don't care about anything else
interesting we'll delve into some sort
of related questions a bit after I just
want to loop back quickly to the the
foam recommendation what sort of um
terpene profiles would people sort of be
thinking they might get out of that so
foam is
I mean I describe foam as like vanilla
stripper perfume Terps when you say
strippy you mean like like a solvent
sort of no I mean like a strip club okay
cool I mean that like Britney Spears
vanilla like really trashy
perfect cheap perfume like just if you
walk by you know I've never been in a
strip club wink wink
um but like if you walk by and you can
kind of Imagine like what that smell
mixed with like some sweat and like just
kind of some grungy it's also got like a
little bit like the soap is more like
cushy like the soap definitely doesn't
really smell that much like soap
um but it's a little bit more like I
don't know it just helps round out the
sweetness and like kind of the upper
notes that are more like perfumey
because any flavor that's like too
one-dimensional like you know for
example I'm not a huge fan of Jack or
some of those hazes because it's just
straight to paneling that's all I can
smell and you know like
that it's too one-dimensional I want to
be able to smell multiple things taste
multiple things if you hit it at
different temperatures you can kind of
change the flavor a little bit like it's
a little more interactive I guess
yeah definitely definitely I can
understand what you're saying and an
interesting Trend that I've only just
sorted to pay more attention to is that
I've seen and heard a lot about in
recent competitions that people are
submitting like blends of extracts
because it's trying to achieve what
you're talking about that more complex
profile sort of different
um sort of facets to the overall Turpin
profile do you think this is a trend
we'll see continuing have you heard of
this yourself uh yeah absolutely
um which we started doing that
I mean we'd always done it with like BHO
especially because we never had you know
like back in the Trap days we're early
in the Trap days we didn't have any
anything one flavor in bulk right and
that you always wanted to have a mixture
of stuff so usually in order to like do
any sort of sizable run it would have to
be a mix
um the problem with a lot of those is
like you lose
you know it's not like the whole is
greater than the sum of the parts in
this case it's usually just like this is
kind of like a little a few notes from
this or a few notes from that but it
doesn't work well
um but sometimes like that GMO papaya
that filthy papaya blend that's when you
start to blend especially like like I
don't know what it is with solvent
extracts but like the non-solvent
extracts is where the mixes start to
shine which we would see especially when
I was making water hash and bulk back in
the day some phinos wouldn't wash as
well right but if you took a Fino that
washed well and mixed it with something
that I didn't you could actually start
to make that wash like viable right to
spend the time energy flavors and then
you know you get like an interesting mix
yeah um and then if you have a bunch of
like sift or like you know water hash
that's dry ready to get pressed mixing
those in different ratios and kind of
like finding what ratios work really
well you can you know you have a
a whole new menu of flavors that are
cool which would otherwise take you I
mean a breeding project for me takes
like well over a year so like I could
take these two things and press them
three or four times over the course of
an hour and then we can taste all those
flavors and find out what's a cool mix
and what ratios work well or we could
spend a year and a half trying to create
that flavor like naturally
but I I like it I think it's cool you
know I think it
brings in a lot of creativity and you
know you can kind of like invent your
own flavor profile and if you never tell
anybody the exact ratio of what you're
doing now you have sort of a proprietary
recipe to make a cool flavor especially
if you're making it with like two
in-house cuts that no one else has you
know kind of sets yourself apart
yeah that's really interesting I mean a
lot of people are having a focal
discussion at the moment around how uh
people who've been in the game for a
while maybe we'll call them Legacy
farmers who are feeling like they're
being pushed out can reinvigorate their
brand and stay relevant that does sound
like an interesting way to do it do you
think that it's possible that
um that that someone could pursue that
or do you think you need to be a bit
more inventive than just that and try to
come up with a few different ways to
sort of stay
I don't want to say relevant but to to
keep your Niche from the bigger
companies
I mean I think there's so many different
avenues for people in the space that
there's no limits you know the only
thing that matters is if people like
what you're doing
so if you know if you can create an
angle and enough people like you don't
get to decide I don't get to decide any
of this the market decides everything
what we make what we release what's
popular What cracks off like it's not up
to me it's up to them
you know it's up to me to kind of read
the room and try and figure out my best
guess as to what people are going to be
excited about and I can help guide them
one way or another but ultimately we
make no decisions you know we're
absolutely the mercy of what people want
when and I just try to supply
my best version of that
I guess so there's plenty of room for
everybody yeah definitely definitely and
I mean and if we take that premise in
the other direction
with the Advent of Blends the first
thing I started thinking about is that
surely one day we'll have like a Jack
Daniels equivalent where it's like this
company that can buy bulk distillate or
whatever it is bulk material blend it to
consistently put out this mass-produced
sort of product that's like you know on
the palette or the affected sort of
consistent do you think that's a
foreseeable future or do you think
there's too much variation in the
cannabinoids to ever really be able to
put out something super consistent on
that level of production
no I think the consistency will be there
and I think there's plenty of people
that want that and seek that out and
that's fine you know like
people like let people like stuff you
know like they let Coors Light cool
you can have Coors Light and then
there's also plenty of like bougie more
exclusive different flavors like you
know if that if that speaks to them or
not like
they have the freedom to choose and you
know try what they want and if people
want that then like
great that's fine you know Phil's there
fills their needs but usually those
people that's your step like most of
those people should say most but there's
a good enough percentage of those people
where that's a stepping stone for them
and then they start to wonder what else
is out there what's different what's
unique and then they start to come in
you know like basically you know they
mature as a consumer right and then
they're like their flavor profile like
that they like starts to change and then
they start to open up into what's what
else is there right what other flavors
might might I find and then you know me
and plenty other breeders are you know
sitting there going come on like we'll
show you
there's a lot of flavors like every
flavor you ever thought possible
that's uh that's a beautiful segue
you've given me because I was gonna ask
you you were talking about flavors and
in the question before you were saying
you know what I'm not sure what to do I
just I revert back to flavor because
that's that's my whole thing
what flavor are you chasing next what
don't we have that you would like to
make if possible
I'm trying to find flavors
that I cannot describe with words and
that I've never tasted before
that's like the goal of every breeding
for me the goal of breeding project is
one
the crop hybrid has to be better than
both parents otherwise what's the point
and ideally I'm trying to mix and match
flavors that are going to create and
generate something unique and different
that can help set me apart where you
know people try that and they go it's
not like oh that's cushy or that's you
know that's got that's some Skittles or
that's got this or that's got like no no
like what the [ __ ] was that
I've never smelled that smell before
there's not words that I know how to
describe that smell that's what I'm
after that's the whole like Umami right
sweet sour salty and savory
Umami it's it's not it can't be
described with any of the other ones
it's that sort of
un you know it's intangible
like the the blend of flavors create
something new and unique and different
that you can't you know
you can only describe as like oh that's
it's almost a Feeling
yeah truly well you know what's
interesting is like
um research shows that feelings actually
start as a as a physical sensation so
you don't feel anxious and then get
tight you feel that you're tight and
you're like oh [ __ ] I'm feeling anxious
and so it's exactly what you said it's
like it's a physical stimulus that then
causes you to feel away
that's that's really cool I like that so
tell me a little bit about what inspired
the Genesis of umami what was it that
caused you to think you know I want to
start this company
well let's see I started growing in 2006
I always knew that I wanted to have a
seed company I thought that was it
anything like in early on in the canvas
game like it was either you were growing
or you were making hash or you were
making seeds I thought wouldn't it be
cool to do to start from seeds and make
your own product and make your own
strains and then make your own hash
create something new and different and
just having something to call call your
own so I the plan was always to make a
seed company I mean really there wasn't
you know I hadn't had enough time in the
game to really start and put my name on
something and be proud of what it could
be you know I wasn't good enough at
growing I certainly wasn't you know good
at breeding I was you know I still don't
really consider myself a breeder like we
make seeds we hunt seeds we do the job
but the whole point was find something
cool and unique and different so I gamed
up I finally had the skills to the point
I had the library you know I'd collected
seeds for a decade you know before that
and then the timing was right to start
the company and launch
we did
and you know it worked here we are
that's brilliant let me let's go back a
little bit then we're going to do it in
reverse order to what we normally do it
so then tell me your first cross you
ever made
was that intentional was it an accident
and what were the genetics involved
it was intentional
um I don't really know what it was it
was there was a family vacation in
Mexico
and then somehow seeds ended up in Salt
Lake City Utah and
we pop those seeds we really got my
homie's backyard
you know you spend that much time
growing the plants and then you have a
male and you're like well I mean
I'm not going to kill off the the mitt
like come on you know it's I spent so
much time and energy to get this thing
to this point
um so it was just some like open
pollination whatever and uh that was I
mean I was hooked [ __ ] the first
second those plants popped out of the
soil that was it for me you know I knew
I knew what I was going to be doing
but it was some Mexican you know sativa
or something or other
not good was that the first grow you
ever did as well yeah yeah nice okay and
then so let's fast forward a bit when
you got more serious about growing what
was the first thing you started growing
like say under a light
so the first ones we were growing under
a light were
let's see
it was a
um
there was a blue cheese by Cali brains
there was uh let's see what else we were
doing back then it was this one my buddy
gave me called it Hyperion which was
some
some hazy you know Indica hybrid or
something that was it smelled it tasted
kind of like coconut it was funky like
and the hash tasted very much like
coconut which was unique I've never
stumbled upon anything even remotely
similar to it ever
you know since then but so there's
there's still some flavors that I'm
looking for that I remember because I
like to think I remember every single
bag I ever smoked
nice one good memory like I just you
know that I remember what the flower
looks like I remember the flavor profile
I definitely remember a lot of them that
I grew that sucked you know that were
just
no dice like you know just like what did
I do wrong and you know now looking back
it's like hilariously apparent like just
how [ __ ] terrible you know I was at
cultivation early on and like we just
didn't know
enough back then you know it's a lot of
like Bro Science and don't do this don't
do that and we'll we'll do the same
don't worry don't worry but so you're
learning the ropes and you're starting
to refine your craft were there any
breeders or specific Growers you sort of
looked up to in those early days and
were taking advice from
uh I mean I always liked so like
Greenhouse Seed Co drop their like land
race you know
videos that they had right where they'd
go to the bush and Hunt
um and so like I was dming Franco like
way back when and he was always super
cool and friendly and like you know I'd
ask him questions and like he was but
she had no need to do any of that like
wow I'm just some [ __ ] off random dude
on Instagram like sending a DMs like you
know asking for advice or whatever and
he was always really cool and really
friendly
um so yeah definitely uh definitely
Franco from from Greenhouse
um
I mean Mr Nice was you know like it was
a lot of like the OG Dutch dudes you
know who were like going hard
um especially because like early on you
know some of the things I started seeing
was Mr Nice out in Switzerland right
running the old pillow play and they had
just the biggest cultivations you'd ever
seen at the time where you're like where
on Earth can you possibly do this you
know this is at a scale that is just
mind-boggling
um so that was always really cool to see
see some of those dudes and I always
thought I'd end up somewhere in Europe
you know building a company because I
was like well I don't see this happening
in the states right a lot of the
California dudes left you know DNA guys
were out there because you know weren't
really doing it in California
um and then luckily for me
you know the rules in California started
to shift where now we could actually get
like I mean it wasn't a licensed by any
means but we were covered under under
medical we had the 99 plant racks and
you know we were in counties where we
could grow you know at scale and that
was kind of the first time we started
running like big well not big but bigger
operations
yeah nice one and so after you had uh
started the company what was the first
sort of project that you felt really
helped establish your identity within
the public eyes where even you yourself
are like man we're like we're really
doing this so
my homies in Arizona
they own a company called grow science
which is a pretty big
cultivation outfit out in Phoenix and
they bought a bunch of my seeds for my
very first drop ever which went the
first drop went pretty well you know all
things considered I was a brand new
breeder you know like I had no
you know there was really no Legacy I
didn't like Leverage any of my other
companies or Brands because I wanted the
thing to stand on its own what was the
the mile or what was like the project so
that was a the mail was Mac mints
um and then I cross that to pretty much
everything so that was a thin mint
cookie crossed with the Mac Mail
that I got yeah so then I crossed that
with
you know the whole menu
um and the grow science had the Frozen
and eighth right yeah yeah we uh yeah
River cat posted a thing and this was
like back when they were doing drops of
like piece of grain and he was like hey
there's you know I'm doing a thin mint
drop of flour
go you know go scoop the flower and
there's also like some seeds in there so
like you know a whole bunch of eighths
were purchased and then ground up to
find like six or seven seeds and I
hunted those seeds then I found the mail
and then that was kind of what
kick-started it because it was a frosted
ass it's like just big giant medium
monster male I was like this is the one
we start with you know hit up cat we're
like is it cool if we breed with this
he's like yeah you found it in the seats
yeah like and so I said those we went we
went to work
wow that's that's sick so you know I
guess fairly safe to say probably no one
else really has a male from that
particular cross no no certainly not out
of curiosity how many eighths did you
buy like a ton or just like a couple
twenties three eighths wow yeah so most
of them didn't even have one too yeah no
we found like six seeds total
there you go that's good marketing from
cap yeah no it worked it worked out well
you know I like I couldn't believe it
and like I said I found that no I made
f2s and like I never released any of the
Mac mint stuff
um only only crosses but they were uh
they were fire you know we did the lime
souffle which was a Mac mint female
um that one smashed that one washes
really well
um what was that female like in terms of
like turbine profile and effect it was
like uh I always described the Mac Vince
as like gelato it's like heavy on the
gelato where it's very similar to gelato
um because it's got the cinnamon cookie
and it's got Max it's got Starfighter in
it but it's so it's pretty hashy but
it's definitely got this I mean I always
described it as like solventy but like
the type the exact type of solving is
like rubber cement so like if you you
know I don't know if they still use that
in school but way back when you know you
just like crack open that jar of rubber
cement and you just get hit with this
noxious
fumes so that was what I got I got like
chocolate and that super super nice
stringent
chemi like sour like yeah solvent Funk
so that was that was the that was the
third profile
nice yes
nice one and so where did you go from
there next oh man let's see what'd we do
after
so we did the Mac mint drop
and we did right and we did the key lime
that's right and then that I did then I
went to Femmes
um so I did the key limeade which is the
sunset sherb cross to the burning bush
cut of key lime pie so that was a quick
flowering purple super creamy kind of
soapy little skittles-esque
um but that that that femuron I hit to I
don't know I think that menu was like
10 or 12 strands
um and that stuff still sought after
like people yeah 710 Labs runs a bunch
of those yeah 710 has a couple of those
like on the menu
um I mean a lot like that was one of the
first big femrons that went you know
really really well especially because
here in the states like people don't
like
Rags at least like they they could they
could tolerate red seeds back then but
you know like probably sell like 10 10
or 20 to 1 Femmes to regs so I really
wanted to like go back and focus on
um Femme seeds although when stuff is
when you find a really amazing male it's
just like
you can't do it the disservice of never
you know making any seeds with it so
when I found zuchi and like kantuchi and
some of the other ones it was like okay
obviously I'm gonna do we'll sprinkle
drops of these in in there
that's nice I wanted to touch on that
specifically because I noted you do as
you mentioned do both regular and firm
seeds do you find yourself gravitating
more towards one than the other just on
a personal level and as a follow-up do
you think there's Merit to some of the
age-old criticisms of Femme seeds you
hear no I think a lot of the
I think a lot of the anti-feminized seed
crowd is uh
either
just parroting a lot of you know this
narrative that they've heard in the past
that's not really rooted in in science
um
and you know to some degree I think if
you constantly if you go you know Femme
them down the line I can see how
it would make sense that the genetics
could shift maybe in a way that's not
like ideal because that is about as far
from the natural order as you can get so
for me as a breeder I'm always going to
do like I usually I'll never cross two
whatevers and just do the seed line like
the the pollen donor is something that
I've made and worked like or found like
you know something unique to me period
um but I'm never gonna take like
something that comes from a femme line
and then Femme that again like yeah and
then fem it I hit it to another clone I
like to inject a male in there like and
I've got a couple males that I like that
I work with you know that I've worked
with for a long time so I know exactly
what they're gonna do right and like a
good male I mean one of my buddies
always says a good male is literally
Priceless because
you know I know I know what kind of
Finos we're gonna find I know what it's
going to do I know what progeny is going
to look like so then we'll hit that to
you know something that's cool
find it female in that generation and
then that can get reversed but like I'm
not doing feminism
yeah yeah interesting I we had a an auto
breeder on the show recently flying line
research he's cool dude he's in his
Terps as well and he he said this
analogy about orders but it sort of
applies what you're talking about he
said it's like a zipper light you sort
of unzip it and then zip it back up and
when you Femme stuff you're sort of
closing it and zipping it up and hitting
something else to it is like unzipping
it and opening it and I sort of have
been thinking about that analogy it's
it's cool I wanted to um ask because
it's a you may not have too much
thoughts on it but we do talk about it
from time to time on the show a lot of
some some people still have some
question marks around the lineage of
Skittles you know it's still there's
there's obviously that you know grape
grapefruit sort of thing that you hear
but then there's still like a strong
amount of people who believe that it's
like maybe a sherbet S1 and the fire
loss test said it was a sherbet S1 and
so that's like I've never really been
able to get my head around that because
it's sort of my gut instinct is like
doesn't seem like a sherbet S1 to me but
then you've got guys like inspector from
CSI Humboldt who just does like these
big hundred seed Vino hunts of like
sherbet s1s and he reckons he finds
plants similar to Skittles in there
what's your thoughts on the lineage of
Skittles I mean the terp profile is very
similar right they're they're at the
very least in the same neighborhood if
not on the same street right
um the structure wildly different wildly
different I've grown I've grown both I
have both
um I've grown a lot of sherbert hybrids
I've grown a lot of skills hybrids I've
not seen as much crossover as I would
have thought
um there's the structure is so different
and like everything you cross Skittles
to I can almost immediately identify
whether or not it has Skittles in it
because of the leaf structure because of
the stack the the stem structure like
it's it sticks out like a sore thumb at
least you know to my eye but with sherb
crosses I don't see that as much
so
I mean could they be related absolutely
are they probably but what are the
actual genetics
who the [ __ ] knows
I agree some things will will probably
never actually find out
so while we're talking about Skittles I
noticed on the website you have an array
of interesting mothers many of them
incorporating Skittles it got me
wondering what's your process like of
acquiring mothers do you have like if I
had to guess I'd say You must have these
like vast networks where you can get new
and emerging clones or have I got
something wrong what's your process you
seem like you got new stuff all the time
yeah no there is a there's a vast
Network
um
you know like-minded
people who are always chasing like the
newest flavors and you know I've been
fortunate enough to be in space for long
enough to have you know friendships with
you know a lot of Legacy dudes who a lot
of them are like just as excited about
getting them to me as I am about getting
them because they're like hey I got this
new one like what are you gonna do with
it you know so uh yeah a lot of those
genetics like I luckily I don't have to
go looking for them so much as like they
find me which also helps me to know like
okay this is
clearly something people are interested
in so this might be worth a look right
yeah and what sort of things impress you
about a plant in terms of if you're
thinking about maybe breeding with it is
it mostly about like the flavor profile
and structure presented in front of you
or do you want to breed with it a few
times and sort of see how it breeds like
what what are your considerations in
general I mean the number one thing is
Flavor as always so all the any new cuts
that show up
they get run you know at least once or
twice to kind of pre-vet
whether or not this is something I'm
even interested in you know goofing
around with because some of them you
know they have a bunch of hype somehow
and you know I grow them out it's like
no like for whatever reason you know and
it might not necessarily be because
sometimes the flavor can be really good
but it's not worth some of the grow
characteristics right like Skittles is I
mean it's a unique strain because it
sucks
grow it is the worst plant in the world
it grows so slowly you basically just
don't water it at all and somehow it
lives yeah twice as long five times as
long yeah you know and like people
wonder I've never done a like an exam I
never I've never released a skittles
cross like direct Skittles cross and I
probably won't because one a ton of the
progeny are going to grow like Skittles
does and people you know don't love that
style of Rogues it's difficult and they
yield low and they take forever but
um you know hybrids of it you're able to
kind of bring in some of that like I
like I like the terp profile that it
brings on you know especially with the
crosses like it's a little creamy
and it just helps like round out some of
the other like more harsh intense
flavors where also some of those harsh
intense flavors are too one-dimensional
for me where you're wanting something
else you know either on the exhale or on
the back end or like something else
you're just kind of like
you know make it a little bit more well
I mean literally to make it a little
more palatable
you know to be entirely honest
yeah no I I agree with you there and I
just sort of looping back to that point
you made about growing stuff out and
thinking God how did this get big if I
had to Hazard a guess based on your
Instagram I see a fair few memes about
Oreos was that one that maybe fit into
that category for you guys all right I
mean you know it's just when a ton of
people are super excited about something
that I don't really find that
special or unique at all I think it's
kind of fun to poke a little fun at
Oreos
um structurally I mean it looks visually
it's peeling right but it has and I mean
I was really surprised to learn that it
actually washed pretty well but there's
no flavor
you know so for me if I ever found a
female like that or you know I got I had
access to the Oreos cut but I would
never breed with it just because it has
it's the antithesis of flavor you know
and there's plenty of people who argue
like oh it's got a lot of flavor you
just haven't had a good batch yet and
like I've tried
a fair few from dudes that you know I
consider to be some of the top growers
in existence and it was good but it was
not special
you know and Life's too short to smoke
something that's just good
I want something that's cool I want to
remember that experience
I feel you that's a good one one of my
favorite quotes from past guest on the
show skunk VA I've only got so many lung
breaths in this lifetime I'm not gonna
waste
um yeah so I mean I was interested to
ask because a lot of your menu comprises
these really sort of cutting-edge new
genetics that like most people maybe
aren't even familiar with yet and um I
was wondering do you have any soft spots
in your heart for some like maybe unique
old world flavors like for example you
know you mentioned you're not a fan of
Jack Herer all good
um you know are there any other things
because I noticed you did um some collab
hybrids where one of the parents in the
mail was Soma's lavender and I was like
oh that's that's a bit old world that's
kind of cool is there any other old
world flavors you're like that's
actually a pretty good one
um yeah I mean I like so the the
Affinity that a lot of the people that
came up before me like probably five ten
years before me have for Hayes right I
don't have that because I didn't like I
missed it but I have that for OG it
cushes and so when I got when I like
dived down deep onto the cushes I got
more into like some of the Afghan stuff
and you know some of the
um like you know stuff from the Middle
East ultimately and so yeah gani like
especially those like really hashy like
you know
coffee funky like land race I mean the
the black
right like uh the blackhead or not the
black Haze it's um cute blackheads no no
no no black domino black Afghan oh wow
yeah yeah yeah yeah the black ass yeah
the black half he is like because the
fruity affees I was like yeah they're
good but they're they're a little that
coffee one yeah yeah I like the like
really deep hardcore subtle flavors
where you like you know most people are
only gonna smell one thing which like
maybe that's how the haze aficionados
are they can actually smell all the
different dimensions of that I don't
either I can't or I don't have that
ability but I can with some of the lower
end stuff and I mean like not lower end
quality I mean lower end on the flavor
and like you know those really
earthy chocolate coffee funky flavors
where you're just like I don't know like
it's hard to describe because you start
getting into like every time you smell
it you smell something different you
start to pick up different notes and as
you smell more things in the world you
start to have like a better reference of
like
you know smells which is why I describe
things the way that I do because those
are those are things I've smelled and
that's you know your set memory like
that's what I pick up
that's cool while we're talking about
smells
you and Harry were kind enough to bring
some nice little jars for me to sniff on
say let's talk about these for a little
bit so is this the the current release
the next release when can everyone
expect to be able to get their hands on
the next drop and then after we talk
about it a bit I'll um we can talk a
little bit about the smells so I think
probably January that's where we're
going to start dropping dropping some of
these we've got
I mean there's a lot slotted for release
um what we try and do is select the bet
you know just the ones that would like
the most fun and cool and relevant for
that for that Friday right which
normally do we'll do a series we'll do a
drop every Friday or every other Friday
for you know four Fridays or six Fridays
and then you know plan a couple weeks
and then we'll do some other drops but
like I want to keep it like fun keep it
fresh and then make sure that you know I
mean best case scenario is where the
drops actually sell out like day one or
in the first week which is fun
especially for the buyers because now
you've got something that no one else
has and there's only I mean I only do
one batch
there's only like one big drop and then
once all the seeds are gone they're
they're gone so do you ever remake stuff
or it's all one time
never remake anything nice okay yeah one
big batch which could have you know
however many hundreds of packs sometimes
it's small I mean some some of the
crosses like they don't they don't make
many packs they don't make many seeds
you know it drops as little as like 10
15 20 packs and those sell out really
really quickly which is great but you
know then they're gone just kind of sad
and I've decided to not remake stuff
because there's not enough time
to go back to something there's so much
more to like dive in and discover I'd
rather keep looking for something else
something cool something unique
yeah that's interesting it raises this
point of like do you think the market
would actually allow you to let's just
say you you were testing some seeds you
made and you find this plant in it
that's like the equivalent of Skittles
before Skittles like it was like wow
this is totally different and you were
like we've got to breed this into a Pure
Line do you think the market sort of
allows breeders to do that sort of
project where it like takes longer or do
you think it's just too fast paced like
you're just going to be left behind if
you tried to like do a like a Pure Line
sort of project
I think there's a lot of breeders that
have
stuff like that on their menu and they
have you know they found tried and true
varieties that people like and they'll
keep making those and remaking them and
there's nothing there's nothing wrong
with that especially if they find
something cool and they really want to
focus on on that
um that's great but there's enough
people who are doing that
you know I would rather continue the
exploration to find something new
something different something better
you know that's what makes me that's
what makes it interesting for me you
know if I just had to grow the same
thing over and over again it'd just end
up like a job you know it's the reason I
like walked out of my sales job way back
when you know I was doing this and I was
doing that and one day I was like
[ __ ] this you know I'm out and I moved
up into the woods that was that
that's great I love it all right so
let's talk about this the first time
we've got uh
uh bath house now I did want to ask you
about this obviously has the bath water
in it which is a very unique name and
description obviously an homage to the
infamous Bel Delphine gamergirl bath
water but I was wondering what's the
Terps on that one what's bath water
smell like
I mean
It's A Hard One to to like describe what
the smell is of bath water it's
definitely like gassy and funky but like
I mean you know
imagine what Dell you know whatever her
name is
um imagine what her dirty bath water
might smell like like
that's that'll get you close enough
you know because it is gassy it is Cushy
it's creamy but it's definitely it's got
this weird like soapy like kind of you
know not the GMO Bo like it's more of
like a sweaty like gross shirt you know
I got it like a I don't yeah it's hard
to describe like not quite hockey bag
like I don't know if anyone's played
hockey but those bags have
a unique ripeness to them after uh a
couple weeks
nice one I love it I mean it got me
wondering in general what what are some
of like the more weirder smells you've
come across while Fino hunting Fizz the
Fizz yeah Fizz is one of my favorites
um the
oddly enough the compound apples and
bananas kind of smells a little bit like
the Fizz does but the Fizz is the
loudest grape chemical
I mean it's it's fizzy it's acidic it's
like you know the feeling you get when
you like
put your mouth into a soda cup it's too
fizzy and a bunch of the Fizz goes up
your nose like that's how it makes you
feel when you smell it it's like really
like it leaps out of the jar and then it
it will stain anything you put in it
like any jar if you mix up like a couple
buds in a jar like they're all going to
taste like this like forever the jar is
gonna smell like fizz forever and like
you can crack a jar like a year plus
later and it's still reeks there's very
few flavors that actually hold on to
that kind of a smell and that doesn't
like because usually those kind of
intense jumpy Ones Will mute out
relatively quickly but this one is just
I mean it seems like it will stay
forever
yeah wow that's cool like uh one of
those ones that just yeah overpowers
everything but not not Tangy something
different oh it's it's too bad I tried
to Fem it twice and out of like
I mean the Run we did how many seeds did
we get in that bag in total out of that
whole run oh 50 50 seeds all pretty in
like 10 different varieties some some
had none seeds some had one some had
like four yeah it was like four lights
worth and it was like ten seats it was
oh it sucks so bad it's like that maybe
the pollen just didn't did some things
just don't film well it's just yeah
really hard to Femme certain varieties
for whatever reason it's it just doesn't
work sometimes it's true we got a lot of
theories about why but it's like I don't
I've I've had plenty of femerons
absolutely flop and you know you're like
excited about something and then you're
like I said it takes about a year at
least from when you're like cool here's
what we're gonna work on to the point
where it's actually ready to release
maybe a year and a half
um so yeah when when a run fails you
know you're immediately three to six
months
behind that again
meanwhile everyone else is crossing
because it's not like that I'm not like
the only person in the network right
it's the network so a lot of my friends
competition it was like I mean
technically we're competition but like I
like you know I like everybody
um they're all working on their [ __ ] too
at the same time so it's kind of like
Who's Gonna Get You know who's gonna get
there first with something that's
actually like solid
because anyone could just make a cross
and like just film something and drop it
and whatever that's that's cool and
that's fine but who's gonna like bring
something to the table that's actually
like different and special and unique
well yeah I mean you're sort of getting
towards this topic I was hoping we could
touch on which is that there are a
number of uh Growers and smokers in the
community who feel like in a sense we're
sort of backing ourselves up against the
wall in regards to the genetics we use
do you what's your thoughts on this take
do you think it's true
to some degree sure you know
um I think
part of that opinion is a very narrow
view of
everyone in the Cannabis space who's
breeding for making seeds in any
capacity where they're like yeah you're
looking at a small subset of that entire
population that is absolutely doing tons
and tons of poly hybrids and all this
other stuff but that's because that's
what people want right like I said
there's a lot of that we don't get to
make the decisions like you want to have
a business that actually like works and
pays for itself and hopefully like keeps
gas in your car and like gets your May
to be and let you keep doing the thing
you have to sell seeds right and like so
if that's what buyers wanting then you
know a lot of people you kind of have to
run down that that line or at least like
close enough where you're still going to
be around but there's a lot of people
who aren't in the like standard breeder
you know like when they think of canvas
breeders there's a lot of people who are
not in that space publicly at all who
are doing all kinds of other work so I
think in terms of the global genetics
like there's no issue but if you know
like a small network of Growers is
growing the same thing and hyperizing
the same thing like yeah they were gene
pool might not be that great and then
growing it with the same nutrients under
the same lights same media having all
the environment the same wondering why
the pound price is going down that might
be a slight problem but you know I still
have a ton of land race stuff that
I I mean I I don't know how many fridges
I have full of seeds now but it's a
quite a few because we've just been
collecting genetics from everywhere
always in trading and trying to find you
know new and unique stuff and I'm I mean
luckily we're I'm upgrading now
um I'm gonna have a a small 7 000 square
foot spot for hunting and popping like
just straight old school like I'm gonna
germinate everything in my library and
try and find some cool cool old stuff
because a lot of it is getting to the
tail end of its like survivability you
know those haven't been stored or at
least I don't know how they were stored
before I got them so
you know the germination rate on a lot
of the stuff might not be very good if
at all so it's kind of time to start you
know hunting those seeds and if we find
something cool open pollinate make
bigger population you know preserve all
that stuff but it's not going anywhere
yeah that's cool would we ever see like
any cool F1 hybrids with like modern
verses like maybe land race or heirloom
or something oh for sure yeah that's
absolutely in the plant
that's really cool probably not until
25 realistically it's going to take it's
going to take time
yeah
sure you know
and then so I guess just the sort of
final question on this discussion Point
people have this comment that they'll
say everything like sort of feels the
same do you do you think there's Merit
to that or do you think there's still
like quite a bit of diversity within the
sort of range of effects you can get
from the the current varieties that are
really popular
I'm not the best person to ask on effect
because
listen for me it's flavor is the number
one and the older I get the busier you
know it's like there's a lot of stuff I
would like to smoke but I you know it's
not something I can do in the day and
still get you know get everything done
yeah
um but no I feel like there's still a
very wide variety in effect
um from a lot of different flavors and
sometimes I get bummed out when a flavor
is like really good but it affects me
like
just my body chemistry or whatever
affects me in a way that I'm like well
this I really want to smoke more of this
but I physically can't you know and then
there's other flavors that are like I
could smoke this all day but I don't
really want to it's not that great yeah
sure sure so I mean sort of on the other
side of that topic are there any
varieties you think that you would like
to use maybe from your library stash
maybe from other sources that you think
would inject some sort of fresh blood or
reinvigorate things a little just
because they're a bit different
um yeah I said I'm trying to pop a lot
of a lot of this land Ray stuff what do
you got you got like some cool malays
I've got a lot of stuff from Africa a
lot of stuff from Afghanistan
um are we I've got a bunch of stuff from
Nepal yeah I did recently get some land
race from Japan nice one it's apparently
I've got to grow it out and like you
know I promised a dude I would grow it
out and do an open pollination and make
more of the genetics um because there
was a there's a lot of hemp in Japan
yeah but there's not a lot of like wild
drug cannabis and I mean for a lot of
people would say there absolutely is not
yeah my homie has been has spent a lot
of time in Japan
um and he his buddy lives I can't
remember where exactly they were saying
they live but there are there's a drug
type of wild cannabis in Hokkaido which
is the northernmost Island Japan uh and
they were
I can't remember how many what do you
say like it was like a three-day hike
yes or something some like this was like
bushwhacking to get out to these like
wild Fields
um and they would you know the homeboy
would always collect as much as he could
shove in his bag and then bring it back
and then when people would go and you
know hang out or whatever he'd always
have this like wild herb that they would
smoke and that was you know this crazy
Japanese
sativa or some sort of hybrid who even
knows what it is and there'd be snow on
the ground and the plants would still be
able to be alive when you get there to
harvest them still be alive in the snow
full of seeds apparently the bricks
content was through the roof so there
was somehow they didn't freeze right my
theory is always if the because I've got
some varieties that like bleed red and
you know having high levels of
anthocyanin and bricks in there you know
the theoretically acts like an
antifreeze so the cells won't actually
burst
that quickly so some of those could well
and survive like Frost and freezing
which is pretty is very uncommon because
most plants if you freeze them like you
can put clones in the fridge for a
surprisingly long time but if you put
them in the freezer the cells burst and
they die
you can cry I'll freeze plants though
interesting I did want to talk about
that so like you know tissue culturing
and germs so utilization is on the rise
within cannabis do you foresee a time
when that may surpass like the demand
for seeds
possibly I think the
I've never
actually done the synthetic seeds I've
seen you know they're it's not very
common that people make them and the
cost is probably prohibitive for most
people especially now maybe in the
future that'll become more more common
as long as it's relatively simple for
the Layman or just a grower to go from
that step to actually having like a
plant that's growing in a pot because
the the amount like you have to know
exactly what you're doing to pull a
rooted clone out of tissue culture and
actually get it to survive early on and
that's that's not
it's not common knowledge and I would
guess like 95 of even you know Growers
would mess that up to the point where it
just doesn't make any sense to spend any
extra amount of money on something
that's like yeah it's definitely better
in terms of plant Health sterility right
no bugs know this no that but it just
the other the level of knowledge needs
to be you know at the next step next
stage which is it's very reasonable we
get there in the next 5 10 15 years you
know even the like the lowest
you know then even the newest employee
in any space would probably have
some of that knowledge if it becomes
more you know it just becomes more more
commonplace and then it's just yet uh
like everyone knows how to cut clones
it's not you know you could look it up
in five minutes and they'll be a simple
enough explanation but right now for
tissue culture that that does not exist
yeah sure and while we're on the topic
of dirty clones and pathogens and
whatnot on a on a personal note for you
guys have you had much issue with
hoplate and virus have you had to clean
house or have you guys been able to get
through relatively unscathed uh we've
been very fortunate yeah we do tests a
lot
um the entire mother stock gets tested
I mean it used to be every two weeks but
now it's pretty much once a month which
I mean it just kind of got expensive to
do it every two weeks uh to be quite
honest but we do work with the lab uh in
Utah that's really really good and they
test for pop latent lettuce sclerosis
and a couple of the other ones but yeah
we've I've never actually seen it in any
of my facilities which is very very
lucky it's kind of a nightmare
um not kind of a nightmare it is a
nightmare and it's it's put a lot of
people out of business quite frankly you
know it's tough
it's not we're also really careful about
it our scissors are always sitting in
hypochlorous acid all the time we have
hypochloric acid in a spray bottle that
gets sprayed on everything tools
autoclaved they clean everything with
chlorine like alcohol doesn't kill it
chlorine's the only thing that kills it
yeah heat doesn't kill it um but yeah
we're very very careful and my
quarantine process like when you know
say we have the network to get stuff in
part of the delay is that it takes me
like three plus months
to get it cut out of my quarantine into
the main area where it can then go on
and you know enter like any of the
breeding programs but it yeah it takes
quite some time and I'm hoping to speed
that up uh because now I've gotten like
I mean I do all my tissue cultures
in-house like we do everything ourselves
uh and we're slowly getting back to the
point where
I feel confident enough that we can just
you know
throw everything into TC as long as it
comes back with a clean lab test like
for pathogens then then we're good to go
so we'll probably shorten that down
though yeah nice streamlining things
then while we're on the topic what style
of growing do you guys lean towards more
are you salt guys organic what sort of
medium you prefer give us the lowdown I
run it's a blend
um just organic and synthetic hybrid has
always been you know I always think the
best of both worlds grow everything in
rockwool
it's easy simple I always make the it's
a dumb joke but you can't spill a rock
wool Cube you know because I started in
the soil like most people I ran cocoa
and then once I started growing in in
rockwool it was just
it made more sense it was easier it was
quicker I don't want to spend a ton of
time worrying about the pots or the soil
or this sort of that you know cleaning
up messes like I want to be able to
focus on
the plant itself or like you know some
of the other aspects but still keeping
that organic element and bringing it
into Rocco yeah and I still maintain
some of the best weed me or anyone ever
smoked was
OG Kush grown in the grossest rock wall
you have ever seen because it was filled
with all kinds of organic crap and this
and that and salts and for some reason
like that's that's the magic so we run
it's a product called exotic AG it's a
salt based
um product it's got a bunch of different
biostimulants as well and then my homie
Jasper has this company more and they do
it's uh like a archaea bacteria so it's
kind of like I mean it's like any
beneficial but it's found in um
free bacteria
um and it can survive like 98 degrees C
and like two pH and so it's like it's
just a [ __ ] shit's bulletproof yeah
uv's the only thing that kills it so it
doesn't take over the planet but it yeah
it eats it eats the algae off the rock
wool so it keeps the Rockwell clean
keeps the lines clean it's gangbusters
just chelates everything but yeah the
flavor the flavor on the Blended organic
and synthetic is the only like that's
the win period you know just straight
straight salt grown is it's still good
for the first like five days but I don't
know what it is about the shelf life but
it just drops and some stuff will hold
longer than others but I've never had a
run without you know some sort of Bio
stimulants that was amazing and still
tasted good you know weeks after you'd
chopped it down
yeah nice one and look crop steering is
like the trendiest word in the industry
at the moment what's your thoughts on it
do you think it's just going to become
like super commonplace and if you're not
doing that particular style of
production you just like sort of get
pushed out of the market
um to some degree yeah like it's it's
scientifically sound it's it's highly
functional it keeps the root Zone in the
right conditions keeps the moisture in
the right conditions it keeps the EC in
the right conditions it you know it
saves a ton of water
it makes I I do it with everything it
makes the most sense like it's you know
I mean cannabis a lot candles people
like to think that cannabis is super
unique and special and no commercial AG
you know has any relevance to it because
it's its own thing but like that's you
know I think that's a little naive
like there's a lot to learn from large
commercial operator and if that if it's
functional and it works well then it's
great people can overdo it like anything
yeah look I noticed that you guys offer
consulting services on your website so I
wanted to ask you what some of the
things that you think people commonly
get wrong
people over water their plants
um people to feed their plants to high
EC their light is too low their
environment is off I mean it's you know
like you can look at a room and diagnose
five things that are wrong like in one
and a half seconds right it's not
it's very obvious and a lot of people
they just don't they don't realize that
all of these things need to work
there's certain proportions I guess you
would say that everything has to be at a
certain level and if you change one then
the others need to be adjusted
for that you can't just change one thing
and have everything else work well like
it all works off of itself and off the
other things so like
if you have too much light your plants
need more fertilizer because they can't
eat the light well enough because they
don't have enough nutrients but then
they also need CO2 right it's just it's
balancing at yeah it's the interplay of
them all together one thing is out of
whack you know it's like a
um what if some gear in the cogs what's
that phrase like a spanner in the engine
sort of thing yeah like it's it's a kink
it's like a race car the faster you
drive the higher chance something could
go wrong but the higher performance you
could possibly have you know there's
plenty of people who don't do anything
crazy and they come out with great crops
driving nice and slow in a Honda Civic
but if you want you can really crank up
all those parameters and get a race car
it's just chance you're gonna crash man
at the end of the day there's only so
much carbon to go around right so you
want to grow the biggest frostiest
terpiest like pick two
you know like you can't you can't have
it all
and what what sort of an increase did
you personally see when you switched to
this style of production like how
dramatic was the improvements
I mean a lot like laughably so I mean
we've started to see yields that
I mean I wouldn't believe it if I didn't
if we didn't have to legally like put
those numbers in a metric you know like
no one's no one's inflating their
numbers into metrics you know what I
mean right so when you start running
some of these and you're like okay we're
casually getting 75 80 like 90 grams a
square foot on these plants and we used
to do the pounds per light math way back
when and we're like we're in like a five
pound range now which is just absurd on
a 5x5 yeah 25 square foot which is back
at least when I was running Des or HPS
everything was on a five by five we
didn't do four by fours until we started
getting into LED
well yeah that was going to be in my
next question was that have you guys
swapped to LED yet and I suspect the
answer is yes so the follow-up question
is what do you think about the people
who are discussing and saying like oh
it's not good I'm going to swap back do
you think they need to dial it in more
or do you think that the older lights
may have something over the newer ones
the older spectrums well there's there's
kind of two schools of thought a lot of
people are of any impression that some
of the older lights had more or a
different spectrum that contributed to
different flavors higher yield this that
the other
um so it very well could be that the LED
technology is not caught up or has not
found and mimicked the best Spectrum
just yet
there's also the possibility that so
epigenetics is uh you know a thing in in
Plants where if they're grown under a
certain environment or they exhibit a
certain stressor they can change a
little bit where ultimately a one Fino
could suffer you know
uh shift and then it will Express itself
differently moving forward and forever
basically one gene turns off and another
one turns on so it's also quite possible
that some of these varieties that were
grown under that started to adopt more
to that Spectrum like some of the older
strands which is in the older ogs where
you know you're throwing them under a
new light they're not going to perform
as well because they've become
accustomed to This Light having been
under it for I mean hell 20 30 years
yeah no I it's interesting because I
think we haven't really explored that
epigenetic aspect have we and you get a
lot of anecdotal experiences from
Growers and breeders in the community
who say you know vegging a plant
outdoors for a season pulling it in
before flower can sort of revitalize it
so I mean it's it's there is anecdotal
evidence out there of people saying that
you can Revitalize and I think every
grower can uh relate some anecdotal
experience to a plant that's
deteriorated in some less than ideal
conditions they may have come across
themselves
I wanted to know though in terms of your
room right
let's just say you've dialed in all the
aspects and on paper everything's like
dialed in
where where would you what sort of
things do you think help differentiate
producers at that point because
obviously it's not all homogeneous you
know you still get variation from grower
to grower
um what sort of aspects do you think
come into play at that point is it is it
down to like the type of LED Spectrum
versus the the other guy's LED Spectrum
or do you think there's tiny differences
we may not pick up on
I think the magic is you like for I I
have a basic template right that I use
for pretty much everything and the point
of the template is not to exclusively
use the template but when you're running
different varieties it's to identify
what changes in the template need to be
made
so that you can grow this plant to the
best of its possible you know that's its
best potential right so some are going
to need a little more food and a little
more light or someone need a little less
and you know some are going to need to
be watered less and it you know there's
it's not it's easy to write like the
crop steering recipe it's easy to write
that down and say this is what you
should do but if you follow that exactly
the way that it's written the chances of
you finding a ton of success or you know
not super high it's going to need to be
tweaked a little bit so the best Growers
are the ones who know what to do know
why what they do Works they don't do
redundant things like that's really
common you see people use especially
with fertilizer and nutrients they use
the same
like two different bottles of the same
active ingredient like the same thing
and you're like
what are you doing like what is why why
are you doing this yeah you know this is
the same right what what like yeah look
so people who have
who know exactly what they're doing know
why they're doing it and can actually
make one change at a time and see the
adjustment because if you change like if
you run the same experiment more than
once you want to make a shift you have
to only change one parameter because if
you change more than one you don't know
which one of those things it was and
it's really hard to do experiments on
living plants because no two runs are
like exactly the same
it's definitely it's definitely
something where it's hot I've tried to
explain this bill it's hard to do side
by sides with plants because you have to
do them in your same facility like even
if we both took a clone from the plant
today and took them to our respective
locations and went from there like
you're getting all this environmental
change it's so even if you do them in
the same room and you have two tables
that are side by side
it's not really a side by side because
the the airflow's different airflow's
different so you know like there's just
it's literally impossible to have it be
an exact one-to-one match all these
variables do make a meaningful impact on
the plant long term doesn't it yeah so
you have to do it at a scale that's big
enough to actually take like an average
that's kind of the only way that makes
sense right that's as close as you're
ever going to get is where you've done
because if you're only doing a few
plants here or there like you don't have
enough variation so you just how do you
minimize the variation well have like
enough of a population that you can take
you know your average and see if they're
different enough and if they're not then
you know it depends on what you're
looking for whether it is or it isn't is
you know that that's the only thing
that's relevant
nice nice well
let's get off the um the growing segment
for a second and let's take a sniff of
these jars we I mentioned it earlier and
then we just totally moved on so let's
start with the bath house I'm gonna take
a big half of this
I get a lot of old school OG and by that
I mean not like TK but like maybe more
like ghost or something it's got more
earthy pininess to it maybe even a touch
of like that eucalyptusy
um really nice Cush
yeah to me that's like super nostalgic I
love that how would you guys describe it
I definitely get gas you know it's got
no sweetness which there's a few ogs
that have a little bit of like a sweet
aftertaste
um or on the sweeter side I always
preferred you know
pine tree salt water gas like just that
deep this is the bath house by the way I
can't remember if I mentioned that we
have a swish that would mean that was
part of the reason I picked swish is
because it was just funky Gap and it has
like a little bit of fruityness to it
which sometimes comes through on some of
them um but it's not like sweet fruit
um it's hard to describe
more of a
like a diet fruit leather is that even a
thing
yeah like a half is a sugar-free sweet
fruit leather that's not made with fake
sugar
no I I love the fruit letters
the next one I've got here how do I
pronounce this I don't know how to say
the second word London fish oh London
beach oh I just I didn't I didn't have
it lined up probably I was like oh shoot
London [ __ ] cool I like that so this
one's got more going on
so that's the one in pound cake 75 by
the swish yeah if you know you
definitely get a little bit of gas but
it's more
eucalyptusy more like almost Citrus but
not Citrus like a bit of like nasal
flaringness yeah there's definitely like
a bit more to it but it's like um
different angles to the smell because
yeah there's gelato lemonade uh I can't
remember what the other crosses with the
London pound cake
um
but the yeah the lemon comes through a
lot yeah the The Lemon Diesel has always
been one of my my very favorite strains
like we grew that way back when and it
was always super funky and unique and
different
it wasn't very gassy it was like at the
time we couldn't really sell it because
it was cushy enough it wasn't like OG
enough it had like a you know a
different Funk to it
um back in the day everyone just wanted
gas like 50 different OG's on the menu
you know comes in waves right I feel
like we're getting back there so I mean
on that note next one we've got is the
Geisha breath this one's interesting
it's um it's got a few different things
in it the Me Breath TK cherry pie
gorilla glues wish I definitely get a
bunch of this wish the gorilla glue and
a little bit of the meat breath and the
TK really unique sort of smell it's like
it's cushy but it not so much gas here
but there's a lot of other
like sort of aromatic and earthy notes
in there I can't put my finger on them
at all which is
unusual for me we said it kind of smells
like the dragon fruit refresher from
Starbucks I haven't had that
um yeah it's kind of got that like
sourdy
um edible makeup
what do we call it animal vanilla
smoothie yeah it's like a sourdie and
then a softer part the animal smoothie I
like that because yeah that gorilla the
gorillas fire and then yeah the Cherry
Pie on this I mean there weren't a ton
of Finos on this the Cherry Pie Terps
came through which was
kind of a bummer
um there was a few but it was a little
it was too light but the meat breath the
meat breath TK for sure comes through I
mean the Cherry Pie comes through even
like visually it comes through
although this Stacks crazy hard it's
super purple it's a giant purple Spears
it's iced out so I mean as far as
production goes it crushes and then it
did I mean this Fino did like three and
a half percent or four somewhere in
there like almost four percent which is
you know for rosin production does
really really well but for flower
production this one bangs and they're
super super potent like super Stony all
this stuff on that note do you pay much
weight or consideration to
the ability for your strains to be
purely flower produced or is there more
focus on the concentrate potential so
like maybe the flowers are like you know
not as great as we want but like it it
produces incredible concentrates so like
that's the goal like how do you see that
one uh the best ones you can find a
phenol that does or you can find more
than one female and like I'll select a
hash female and then I'll select a
flower Fino that that's my favorite not
all varieties will do that but some of
them you can actually find really really
really good flour flour Finos which they
have this my homie Watson Dustin who did
the uh the cold heat he always described
it as like a rosebud sort of structure
um I like to think of it more like uh
what's that [ __ ] called
um
brussels sprouts where you just have
these giant fully shaped nugs growing
off this plant and instead of having
this one huge homogeneous Cola which you
can't break down and when you do it
looks terrible right but if you have
these like perfectly shaped flowers that
just go all the way up the stem I think
that's kind of my ultimate favorite but
those are they don't wash as well
because they're dense they don't open up
so sometimes especially you find these
more they really look like older kind of
sativa ones where they're bigger they're
more open they're a little airier which
not structurally or visually appealing
for like most people but in terms of
hash production they bang if you're only
ever going to grow this for hash or grow
them hot a lot of CO2 I want them to
Foxtail I want as much surface area as
possible so we can get big numbers on on
the watch where no one cares what the
flower is going to look like it's only
ever going to be released as hash
yeah incredible and what sort of
varieties do you recommend for anyone
who's listening right now who wants like
a really good washer specifically out of
your catalogs maybe from the upcoming
line I mean I know they're all designed
to wash well but what do you think if
someone is like dude I I get the flower
I immediately turn it into heads like
what do you recommend cheetah chew
washes really well the Terps are super
fire I love the cheater chill
um anything with that Lemon Diesel in it
is killer it's got this
lemon honey mustard peppery it's it's
funky it's a weird smell uh but that one
washed it like a little over four uh
yeah the cheating shoes banging super
purple gorgeous flower I've got a collab
up in Washington right now so that's
going to be coming out actually people
who are in Washington state will be able
to go get flour and hash of the the
cheetah chew here very very shortly
the other one would be the the gummy
that jelly Zona Zoda so both jelly
donuts is a huge washer that Fino that
we crossed is a monster and the Zoda
that Fino of Zoda that I picked is
another another washer four or five
percenter so that one did
what was that that was five or over five
yeah it was big big washer a lot yeah so
gummy will come out in January we
haven't set a date yet but
January I think the gummy is my my
personal favorite of them they're all
they're all amazing of the five people
around but yeah the gummy hits that
sweet spot for me it's like it's got gas
but it's got a lot it reminds me in some
ways of
um the pine Soul cut of go gog from
Bodhi it's just like it's like gassy but
it's got this interesting beriness to it
that comes out here in a unique way
where it's not just like through the
middle it's almost like around the size
it's like gassy in the middle and then
like this sort of more sophisticated
perfuminess around the edges I I really
like the gummy a lot yeah the gum is
kind of like a like a acidic acai kind
of you know Berry Floral
you know grapey Skittles and then gas
biscotti gas biscotti gas
which is interesting because the Zoda
cut that I that I use for all these
crosses is uh the most offensive
dead animal
like
yeah rotten dead animal
at a truck stop that like had a bunch of
you know oil spilled on it and it's just
it's it's ranked and it's weird and it
smells nothing like any of the parents a
lot of the parents were a lot more
fruity floral and kind of Sherby and
kind of berry and then I was like I was
almost certain that that seed I'd [ __ ]
up cleaning the seeds and it had gotten
you know just from something else and
then I grew it and I looked at like the
photos like at the structure of it I was
like well I mean it's definitely
you know it's definitely soda like no
question but this was one of
I don't know it was like a hundred and
hundred plus females that I looked at
and this was the only one that smelled
anything like this
it was also the washer so it was kind of
an easy choice
yeah I wanted to know I was looking
through your Instagram and I was sort of
trying to get a sense for myself of like
what's one strain would I guess you
would be most known for so to speak and
I thought the Zoda it appeared enough
that I was like maybe it's in contention
what strain do you think most represents
the brand just in terms of like the
Public's perception what do you think
people most associate with you guys thus
far I think Zelda for sure
um Zelda's one of the the heavier
producers that's in you know in rotation
at the most
you know wrecking bed shops and most
Growers that was you know relatively big
release
um I mean I saw a seed pack of Zoda at
auction cell for like five grand
which is awesome it would have been
super awesome if they shared some of
that with me but hey you know
the fact that it went for that which is
outrageous is yeah [ __ ] awesome
yeah look on that topic I noticed on
your side there's probably only about
three or four strains that are in stock
by the looks of it I was wondering do
you find it hard to keep up in terms of
seed production matching the demand yes
yes I do it is very difficult
um
yeah you know the The Feeding Frenzy
that can sometimes occur is awesome but
it's hard to keep up with and trying to
make enough
I mean really like having since I have
to test everything and I'd have to grow
it out and then I have to have it tested
by the tester Network like the release
said it takes me a year a year and a
half to do the release and 95 get cut
and if not more yeah well
maybe yeah 95 90 95 of the stuff that I
make just doesn't make it for whatever
reason because it's not
it's not good enough it's you know if it
say I get a cut that makes it through
quarantine makes it into rotation I grow
it out it's like cool enough that I
think maybe this will maybe this will do
well we'll make the crosses of it we'll
grow some of them out and then if
they're kind of like I mean either they
get discarded entirely or they get
thrown back in the fridge for a rainy
day like well maybe we'll come back to
it in five years whatever and then stuff
that hits that everyone you know
everyone on the round table is excited
about that's what makes it a release
nice one and do you think that there'll
ever come a time where you'll look to
ramp up the production or do you think
you'll always sort of keep it this small
scale sort of vibe
I mean probably ramp up to some degree
just to keep like as as the market gets
bigger I want more people to be able to
have and smoke more in unique different
Terps but I do like
that you know the community of people
who grow Mommy it's like a smaller group
of people who really you know appreciate
what I'm trying to do and I think part
of you know like I'd never got into it
to make
this giant mega seed Corp that is just
gonna bang out the same variety over and
over and over again that's it's been
done
there's people that want that and that's
great but I want to make you know we'll
keep it relatively small
plus you know at one point I had like 30
employees and that was uh it was really
hard that was insanely difficult now
it's you know being Harry a few others
it's a lot easier to manage you know and
having
direct access and functionally doing all
of the work makes more sense especially
if I'm gonna put my name on it like I
don't want the company to get too big
where we like create something and I
never grew any of it then it gets
released and it's just like you've lost
you've lost it you know
the Personal Touch
of it you've lost the
yeah it's just not for me not for us
yeah sure thing look you mentioned a few
times that you'd done some co-labs and
maybe even some in the future what
collaborations do you have coming up and
what sort who are some breeders who you
want to do some collapse with
let's see we've got some more super seed
collabs coming up
um I think we've got a couple Tiki
collabs in the works what else we have
going on
the super seed is going to be the next
one to drop social soda yeah super seed
Coco collab which I love I love super
seeds they're
we've done them for a long time tell me
about that is it Seattle soda yeah tell
me a bit about that strain that one's
out of control fire it is it's kind of
like a sherb esque sort of purple I mean
it's a it's uh the UV perp
um and so delicious which is another
cross that the holy made which has got
like it's funny it has train wreck and
like lemon haze in it but it doesn't I
don't get any of those flavors from it
um but it's definitely yeah the Seattle
soda is like a cushy grapey
it's definitely fizzy it definitely has
that like not it's not got the same
grape tarp that the Fizz has because
that's like grape gas this is more like
grape cream like uh
like a grape creamy chapstick or
something it's got this like and yeah I
don't know if anyone remembers those
like old flavored chapsticks it doesn't
have that chapsticky waxy bit but it
does have that definitely like kind of
artificial grape with this uh I mean
it's acidic right it's very like
prominent in the nose
you feel it like right up in your next
your eyes you know like it's all up in
your sinuses
that's cool and so when you're doing
collabs do you ever consider like
working those lines forward or is it
generally more of like a one-off special
thing because like you know like the
fans can't really get it from you know
the hybrid you can't get it from either
Camp individually it has to be the
collab or do you think that if you found
something cool you'd like you'd just
work it Forward yeah yeah for sure
because I would never for me it doesn't
make sense to make the same crossover
again but to make an F2 or a back Cross
or any of that like that that's still
open game
you know I I think that's it's different
enough it's not exactly the same thing
so in terms of like my sort of rules for
Umami that I like to follow that doesn't
break a rule and it still helps to
inject something different and unique
and you can still dive in and hunt and
find if someone wants that exact same
pheno they could find or if they want
something else I kind of draw the line
at s1s
I'm not really sure why I think I've
just
yeah okay like I wouldn't do a Zoda S1
for example and that's I if we did I'm
sure they would well seed banks tell me
all the time I should do that because it
would do really well but I'm that's not
I don't know that I'm not interested in
that I'm not excited about that you know
and I haven't done it enough where maybe
I maybe if I do it and I find some super
awesome phenos and it's like what have I
been missing but there's so much you
know there's so many other things that I
want to work on that's definitely on you
know on the tail end of
projects that we might uh we might go
forward with
sure sure a back cross is far more
interesting to me yeah I can I can
understand where you come from with that
one for sure before we jumped into the
interview we were talking about it and I
had it as a question so we may as well
jump into it now but I wanted to ask you
about your thoughts on sort of the the
conventions of naming strains because I
notice a lot of your Australians have
the words are or z in them because you
know relating to the parentage do you
find it hard to come up with names do
you think you're gonna find it easy or
is it just getting more infinitely
harder to come up with names as each
sort of year goes by
depends on the the hybrid to be entirely
honest sometimes they the name just
materializes comes to you it's perfect
you don't even really have to think
about it it just presents itself I wish
that was the case more often because
normally there is a lot of effort
expanded on figuring out a good
applicable name for the thing that is
unique
doesn't step on anyone's toes hasn't
been used before and
you know you like early on it was always
like someone crossed uh black I think it
was black uh
Black Widow and Jack Herrera and they
called it Blackjack because right so but
eventually we ran out of the ability to
take both of the you know some
combination of the name and there's only
so many things that you are even
remotely creative or like sound you know
interesting enough to use so then we
started doing a lot of the Z stuff
because people and really I was a little
against it early on so I'm like well
that's kind of dumb like you know
whatever everyone's using the Z I was
like well it
you know from a scientific perspective
it helps for people to have some
familiarity with what is in the thing so
if there's a z in there
really it should have Skittles in it to
some degree
um but I think that's been like I did
that more than I like so now I'm really
trying to get more creative on naming
but it takes
a village literally so we'll have like
10 or 12 people hang out smoke The
Strain talk about it look at the
genetics dive into the you know long
history on the genetics and really like
try and identify something that's unique
and cool but it's so hard
it's a hugely and I mean on the other
end of it
how do you feel the name game affects
the commercial success of a strain do
you feel like a catchy name is sort of a
fundamental part of a strain really
getting traction with the broader
community
absolutely
absolutely it does and some of them
especially if it's a smaller release
where I like a name because it's funny
like bath water for example you know
like will bathwater sell at a shop
possibly and one of the thoughts what
we're naming stuff is like hey if if
this is on the menu at a dispensary
is someone ever going to want to smoke
this
it has to you know like the name has to
be
good enough that someone's interested or
appealing in some way you know I think a
lot of even like a lot of strains that
are really really good they kind of fall
off or you just end up renaming them
yeah definitely look
you have such a variety of unique
strains in Your Arsenal I wanted to just
like basically interrogate you on a few
of them to find out more because I'm
just genuinely curious so
um kiwi sure grab my eye on your website
because I think you sort of said like
it's maybe like a backseat or something
like people aren't 100 sure what that
one is but I think you've made hybrids
with it
um do you know do you have much info on
that one
I think you're talking about that was
from Tiki is that kiwi shirt cut and I
think that was from the tiki Club so
when we gave him our Sushi he headed to
a clone only okay yeah I wasn't sure
because yeah I sent him my zuchi cut
our mail and then yeah yeah he had a
bunch of his clones and he sent me one
of his females and I reversed it and I
made the Femmes and I sent him a mail
and then he made the rags that zuchi
that zuchi male is bulletproof tell me
about the zuchimao I've heard the name
before what's it like as a strain
so zuchi is let's see how to best
describe the tsuchi the zuchi is a
monster and I don't I never was a big
fan of any of the females in that line
that I found they were really good but
nothing blew me away except the male the
male is this big monster stacky giant
Cola making male that like I'm sure
you've seen males that have like a lot
of little bananas and they're like kind
of sparse all the way up the top this
makes giant bananas out of all of the
pollen sacks like it makes like full it
looks like bananas made of little tiny
bananas it's the craziest thing ever and
it's just Iced Out from tip to toe yeah
so when I found that mail
I actually misidentified it as a female
first time because it didn't look good
it didn't have any male traits
whatsoever when I was sexing the first
population I was like okay cool and then
I threw it in to a room
um to test it out for flowering and then
it turned into a male and I was like
looking at it was all Frosty it was like
well
we're definitely keeping this cut you
know that's going to be a definite win
because I've been running that
generation for a while so that one
started back on the original release of
the Mac mint male pollinating all my
stuff I found a male Froyo which was the
Mac meant by the sunset sherb so it
started started enactment that I made
for Froyo
then on the Froyo mail that was
crossed a tube biscotti that became
kentuchi
and then I crossed that to Skittles that
became zuchi
and then I found another male from that
crossed that to ailments that became
swish
and then I found the female from swish
who made the reversal so I've been
working on that male like population
since like 2016 2017. so I know
everything about it like
it's easy to pair stuff now because I I
know exactly what it's going to do yeah
I know exactly what the females I'm
looking for are and it's I guess it's
Bulletproof that's cool that you've like
continued on the project in that regard
you got me wondering in general do you
have a specific process or traits you
look for When selecting a mail or is it
more like a certain one just sort of
speaks to you
um
it definitely speaks to you
they a lot of people think stem rub is
something to go off of
kind of gone back and forth on it I
don't think it's really
like it doesn't give me enough of an
indication one way or another I've had
plenty of things that had no stem rub
that came out really really good and you
know the other way around as well
um selecting males for me primarily was
vigor
structure
no signs of flowering in veg any
Autoflower tendency is gone I can't do
anything that has any like hardcore
Autoflower tendency in my because I'm
not growing out of flowers not viable
for me so none of that
structure like I said I mean structure
so like veg structure and then flower
structure like what's its stack what's
the stretch look like and then
ideally this doesn't all not always the
case and not necessarily indicative of a
male that's kind of you know when you
Awards or you know destroy destroy chef
and just be [ __ ] killer is uh Frosty
Frosty males because I've had males that
have tested
seven nine ten percent
which they're iced out there's tricones
all over them have you ever tried to
smoke them no I would probably die I'm
deathly allergic to pollen I've had
um what's hay fevers I was a kid yeah
yeah so all pollen I'm allergic to and
then cannabis pollen I uh I have to wear
my like big giant respirator that like
covers my eyes too and I'll wear like a
tie deck and then I will literally like
walk that hole after I'm done
pollinating or like cleaning seeds or
whatever I'll walk that whole rig in
like under like a shower and I'll like
rinse myself down and try and like knock
the pollen down after having taken a
bunch of like Benadryl or whatever
because it'll just yeah I could never
smoke a male I would probably die yeah
look understandable I um I had a few
more unique females I wanted to ask you
some questions about I wanted to ask you
about the lemon pepper that sounded very
unique lemon pepper is super fire so
that is a I didn't make that one that's
a cut that I got from my homie from the
network
and the lemon pepper is one of the only
strains that smells exactly like what
lemon pepper smells like it's super
super floral and this like lemon mustard
Funk that also is really really peppery
it doesn't have hardly any bag appeal
it's like a really ugly plant which is
kind of unfortunate because the Terps
are out of control but it breeds really
really well and probably 75 of the the
progeny look amazing but you do get like
25 percent that are ugly as hell they're
big but the lemon berry what we made out
of the lemon pepper the the cross that
we did the ugly one was the tastiest one
the ugly yeah the lawn clipping one like
I I saw the Fino I discarded it I was
like this thing is so horrible looking
it's the ugliest thing ever but I had a
couple ounces so like everything else we
dried it threw into bags and then yeah
the lemon Dairy number three
how I wish I I'll find that Fino again I
just gotta hunt through the seeds but
that was
the ugliest I mean literally look like
lawn clippings like it was horrible
looking and I didn't trim it and we
smoked that stuff and it was
amazing like the most lemon like actual
lemon
people describe Jack as lemon I kind of
get like a little upset about that
because I don't like there's a lot of
strains that are like lent like true
lemon like lemon peel yeah like not like
the sweet zesty but the like more like
funky lemon yeah like bitter with the
pith and all that yeah
that's interesting you got me wondering
what's the most memorable terpene you've
ever smelled like when you think in your
mind like what's just if I say what's
the craziest term so you know what I
mean like what jumps to mind for you
first there was a The Strain way back
when I don't actually remember what it
was it was some diesel cross uh but it
tasted exactly like dryer sheets
exactly like dryer sheets and I had like
maybe two grams of water hash that I got
at the emerald cup and I smoked
the tiniest abs of that for like six
months
I will look until the day I die and find
that same turp profile again but
like if you just crunched up a bunch of
dryer sheets and started chewing on them
that is what it tasted like it was
amazing
so weird so delicious
interesting and it gets we sort of get
into this territory of like do you think
that the strain's name should at least
try to accurately represent the flavor
profile or do you think like it doesn't
really matter
um I think I don't think it matters that
much I think it's very difficult
to not make it
if you only Chase those types of names
that will make more sense on the
description than everyone like a lot of
the names are going to be really the
same because a lot of the flavor
profiles are pretty similar so like how
do you differentiate the thing
it's it's tough you know we need to have
the more people get into
like higher end products and like one of
the things legalization in Vegas did
which
is kind of interesting is that they have
mandatory terp testing on everything so
a lot of people they won't necessarily
only look at the Canterbury profile
they'll look at the terpene profile and
like though the the terpene profile is
about as unique as anything else like if
you wanted to map genetics you can just
as easily map them with their terpene
profile ratio as you can with like their
jeans yeah or at least like you know for
for our purposes it's close enough
so I'm hoping we have like enough like
Flavor indicators or something else that
people could look at and say okay I have
kind of a good idea as to what that
these are flavors that I like so I could
make a selection based off of those
parameters not just based off the name
yeah look that's really interesting like
the way the Market's going to evolve to
influence the way they select things and
I noticed on your website you had
something really unique on the pineapple
soda description you sort of talked
about the different flavors you get from
your puffco at different temperatures I
actually thought this was really cool it
was kind of Novel I hadn't really seen
it before do you think providing this
extra sort of focus description maybe
Focus towards like concentrates given
that's what you guys breed for
um do you think that'll become like a
more normal thing going forward or is
that just like a fun little thing you
did for that one that was Harry yeah I
mean we try to incorporate more of the
hash before the seed drops now so like
all these flavors in front we already
have them in big hash production because
we want people to know exactly what it
can do what's a reasonable hash number
like how can you move forward so
yeah having that and then yeah some
things definitely have different flavors
depending on the heat that you hit it at
so like between 400 Degrees to like 550
might be a totally different experience
and like you might be able to really
taste it more at the 400 but that higher
heat can give you like some different
flavors you might be missing in a
different way depending on like what
temperature those Terps burn at I'm
assuming but I mean have you noticed
that oh yeah that definitely different
Terps have different boiling points and
if they flash off too quickly then you
only get
some portion of the the total chirping
profile so temperatures is very
dependent
um on Flavor I guess I should say flavor
is very dependent on temperature
yeah look definitely and you just
reference like you know having these
strains in production before the seed
drops happen what's your sort of ideas
on the breeding in sorry on the testing
landscape in terms of do you just prefer
to do it all in-house do you ever give
stuff out to the public and say send us
your results and do you think it's
possible to test everything in the
current breeding landscape because a lot
of other guests have sort of said it
moves so fast like maybe you can test a
few things and be like you know what
this male seems pretty solid but
sometimes it might be hard to test
absolutely everything where do you fall
in terms of your beliefs on testing
well the product has the name on it
right a lot of that
like the brand I want I always want the
brand to have integrity and
so if I'm going to release something
we're going to drop something it has to
be
it has to have integrity and it has to
have been tested and it has to you know
sort of fit within the the values of
umami Terps and so we test everything we
release
ourselves myself and you know in-house
we also send it out we've got like a
pretty big tester Network on Discord now
uh and we've got a good set of people
who are really really capable and really
you know able to give us an accurate
look at what
someone who might receive a pack of
seeds is going to experience so
that's very helpful to know how they're
going to do because sure I bred them uh
we're gonna be able to grow them
really well
will someone else who doesn't have the
same setup doesn't have the same
knowledge
it's going to grow in a different media
it's going to grow under a different
light like I they need to they need to
be workable for enough people where then
we can release release something so
yeah everything gets gets tested
and ideally we do everything in-house
forever
which
it's I mean there's a lot to do so you
know I don't as long as it all gets
tested and I have multiple people
running it at you know at least a large
enough population where I know there's
not going to be any major issues
because I don't see how you can last in
the space if you have a major flop you
know if you do a drop and everything
harms and there's a million problems
then like
was it worth it to do the drop
or would it have been worth it to maybe
wait
six months a year and then do the Drop
Like is is being first with the latest
whatever that important and for us it's
not
plus I I can't because I have to make
you know a hybrid or create something
else and then run the you know grow them
out which why it takes like a year and a
half before we have a release but then I
have all of 2023 and the first two
quarters of 2024 already mapped out
so that's why when I was saying some of
those land races aren't going to come
until 24 25 because that's the next
available time they can come out
that's interesting I like that it's
mapped out you've definitely got to have
a goal to be able to reach it I wanted
to ask specifically you know you guys
have got an impressive uh 28 Cup wins
what's it like to have that level of
competition success and does it result
from you guys submitting stuff or is it
from like people who have bought your
gear and then they've submitted it so
I'm actually really proud to say that is
all collaborative works with people
growing Umami genetics and then
submitting them to shows and winning you
know and that's I mean that's the
coolest thing ever right the one that
they can take something that it's very
proof positive that what I've worked on
some of those flavors are awesome
because I like them but does the
community like them are they workable
enough that you know someone's going to
grow
there's a lot of different people that
make seeds there's a lot of you know
there's a lot of Great Cuts out there so
that had enough to stand on its own to
make it through anyone's selection
process of staying around and then be
the entry and then be the entry that
took first second or third it's like
it's killer
that's amazing so I mean on that note
what advice would you give to someone
who's sort of interested in getting into
breeding how would you advise them in
terms of like you know what to do and
what not to do
just start
just start making making crosses make
hybrids hot seeds find something cool
probably give them out at first see if
you can get some people to grow them for
you yeah you know find I mean it's going
to be easier if you know someone who has
like any sort of scale who can grow who
can help get you off the ground because
it is I mean unless you have a ton of
money uh it's not an easy thing to break
into especially now where the demand I
mean the requirements for people
producing seeds or people running
genetics are so high they've never been
higher they want
biggest strongest frostiest terpiest
that and you're just like you know to
you have to have you have to start with
those genetics as well right you can't
just find whatever [ __ ] off gear at your
local dispensary and then like make a
cross and think that that's gonna like
run like you if you want to put your kid
and you know if you want your kid to be
a D1 athlete you better make sure like
you're a D1 athlete and your wife is a
D1 athlete
yeah genetics definitely probably the
biggest factor in the sort of success of
a newbie grow so on that topic what
genetics excite you what do you want to
get into next
well I'm kind of diving back into some
of the old the old school right I got a
lot of the OG's back
um we're popping a lot of land race
stuff trying to find
I mean there's there's sort of this
homogeneous structure and terp profile
that has become
you know
very popular now which is great signal
for me to start to shift away from that
and find something else I've always
tried to find like our own lane
still close enough that it's you know an
easy
uh easy move for people to go from where
they're at to you know where I want to
be
um but the last thing you want to do is
go like too far left or too far right
where you're just like super excited
about some flavor profile and like no
one else is
which is fine for small projects and
like just for for you and your friends
or whatever but if you actually want to
impact like
the the space right the whole because
it's a global Community right I mean
that's 28 event like worldwide and like
10 of those are in South America or
seven or in South America that we you
know my homie we're doing a collab with
uh Suga seeds and they've been winning
every event that they enter
which is you know there's not as much
competition down there
you know and having West Coast genetics
certainly certainly helps so it's going
to be exciting when there's a lot you
know higher level of competition and we
can still you know compete win and it's
fun the events are fun
no you touched on an interesting point
because it's like it's one thing to make
a cross but then it's another thing to
actually have people want to grow it out
and want to grow it out maybe around the
world and I guess you're giving me a
good opening to ask this question
because I do want to ask you like do you
think you would ever breed something
without cookies in it in the sense that
like do you think like a project like
that could really succeed or do you
think like these days like it's sort of
you're not really playing to the market
so to speak
I mean
to breed something that doesn't have any
cookie genetics in it at all is
I mean there's still plenty of crosses
that I've you know that I've made that
don't have don't have cookies in it and
I've got so there's fridges full of
stuff we've never released because it
wasn't necessarily the right time the
market wasn't in the right place uh
you know that said there's how many you
know it eventually becomes a backbone to
some degree right just like OG like some
of these other like you know oh is
anyone gonna stop breeding with like
anti genetics or like you know
eventually when you go all the way back
I I wonder in 20 years is it going to be
like NL or it's like nl's just in
everything it's just accepted it's yeah
right it's just like I I think we're
just it's too early to be able to look
back and go oh that's just the new
paradigm that's just because there was
probably a bunch of afghanis got wiped
out by no and people were probably not
happy about it but now it's just like it
is what it is and when cookies is
however many generations back it
comprises
what percentage you know very very small
ultimately
you know you can get that down to 20 you
know 20 of the genetics five percent of
the genetics it doesn't take that long
yeah true true and then it's merely one
small fraction in you know this big poly
hybrid that's just like a structural
component or something almost yeah so I
wanted to ask you I've been weirdly
feeling not weirdly but like it sort of
surprised me I get the vibe that like
Sunset sherb and gelato are like making
a comeback do you guys get that Vibe am
I out of touch or is it the children
um I always like sure the Sun the sunset
shirt was one of my favorites of all
time for the first time I smelled it
still one of my all-time favorites
um I will smoke that
forever
but
I don't know here what do you think
people are getting more back into
I think it's just been around and it's
gonna stay around it's just it's such a
good flavor profile especially for
someone who's just getting into cannabis
like it's almost like having them smell
of Tangy when someone doesn't really
know like they can only describe
cannabis as smelling like like weed like
they like I don't know it smells like a
plant but if you can give some like a
real like Tangy orange you're like oh I
think I can smell the orange in that I
feel like with like a good gelato or a
sherb when you smell that bag it's like
whoa I can actually smell some like
sweet like candy like this is different
this isn't this isn't just weed you know
so I feel like for that reason it's just
always going to stay around but I also
love shirt like
I mean there's troops maybe a desert
island strain for me there's Staples and
the people people get to decide what
becomes a staple and what falls out
yeah fully fully while we're on the
topic of gelato I wanted to ask you
Lemon Cherry gelato another like hot
name in the community a lot of people
talk about it just being runs but then I
talk to other Growers who are like
actual Growers and they're like oh I've
grown them side by side they look a
little different what do you guys think
well I've grown The Lemon Cherry I've
grown white runts
two different cuts of runts pink runts
I mean who's to say what is actually
what you know there just becomes too
much like it's like the game of
telephone where someone passes the cut
and then it's it's this and it's that
and so like I've seen I've seen cuts of
Lemon Cherry that were not the cut of
Lemon Cherry that I ran like the cut of
Lemon Cherry that we have is this like
kind of the more prominent ones from you
know we got it from the bay like my
homie up in uh
the Grass Valley and I've grown them you
know like I said two different cuts of
runs one looks very similar to The Lemon
Cherry and one looks nothing like it
grows totally different different stem
structure different Leaf structure
different flower structure
um but it's so hard to tell plus if you
grow it in a different environment with
different feed the you know physically
it'll look different they they'll appear
to be they could be the exact same cut
and they'll look like wildly different
females so it's just so hard to tell
could be could be the same thing yeah
interesting I wanted to ask you guys
about like your thoughts on the lag time
between like strains being released and
then like maybe when it actually starts
to get some public traction I think this
is sort of exemplified by the fact that
Leafly just recently announced that um
JB's he's jealousy was like that clone
of the year or whatever and I thought
that was interesting because I remember
jbz did like the huge clone drop of that
it was like about a year so I was like
okay so you could sort of say it was
about a year you know or sometime
between that between like it getting out
into mass circulation and then the
public being like this is it so would
you agree that like you're reckon 12
months is about the time lag from sort
of when you maybe start getting it out
there to when maybe the end consumer is
starting to maybe get hyped and and
what's your thoughts on that time lag is
it like does it make your job as a
breeder harder
I think it's some strains will come out
like they come out of the gate hot and
there's no there's virtually no lag time
which is you know not not always the
case but some come out hot some I think
you know 12 months is probably or like
10 to like 10 to 15 months is probably
your average but what's interesting is
you see strains it'll be out for like
two or three years for like four or five
years and then all of a sudden for
whatever reason back one they blow up
that and you're just like what hap where
where did this come from this has been
around and now all of a sudden it's
hype and everyone's after it
um so it's kind of interesting to see
like some of those get rediscovered what
had been you know they've been in hiding
which sometimes it's just coming up with
a clever new name and
some fancy logo and you know some bubble
letters but
not always I betray rs11 will be the
next Leafly strain of the year that was
the next big clone drop by that gang so
I wouldn't be surprised if in a year
from now it's RS 11. right should uh it
probably will you're right hey
so on the tail end of the questions I
wanted to ask you are there any breeders
you haven't worked with you're maybe not
necessarily friends with heck maybe
maybe they don't even breed anymore
they're like super old school any
breeders you like wish you could do
collaborate with or like use some of
their work
um sort of like you know fantasy
football style question
and it's it's so funny because they say
you should uh hustle hard enough until
your Idols become your rivals
which you know is is a true statement
um
and there's
I mean there's a lot of breeders in the
space who've like contributed like a lot
but once I got so like five or six years
like if you ask me that question like
early on in career I would have been
like oh this person this person this
person this person but maybe it's just
kind of silly and like
I just the more I get into like my own
my own gear and like finding like my own
stuff there's so much in there that like
I haven't had the proper time to really
go through the rest of the fridge and
hunt all of my other flavors and you
know
find something new and different in in
that in that category but
I mean who who like for you who do you
think would be
would mesh well with Umami Terps
yeah I don't know that's a good question
about who you know if we could just tap
on the shoulder and ask him because
we've been lucky enough to do collapse
with big you know big names
um the Stravinsky collab [ __ ] crushed
that was awesome
um yeah you know Tiki super seeds I like
collabing with people that I I know and
I've worked with in the past you know
who are super cool
um
I like soulfire's gear I'd do something
with so fire so far would be cool like I
mean you know might like [ __ ] you
know we have a couple cups but like
[ __ ] hell no one has more Cups than
exotic Mike he's got that cups for days
and they've been in the space since
forever you know he's he's a g
um
that would be you know I don't know
maybe that'd be kind of cool like
those are some solid answers
I think that's cool I I wanted to ask
because I'd be curious to know
I'll get an answer from both of you
what's your favorite strain for head
stash
Fez it's just it's so unique and so
different than anything else it doesn't
grow very good it doesn't look very good
like got kind of a strange structure but
just the smell when you break it down
it's like
yeah like fresh
fresh cherries but like injected with
CO2 somehow
uh I mean I like the Fizz I like cherry
pie cherry pie is one of my like desert
island all time all-time favorites
cherry pies gas super heat the Fizz is
kind of like cherry pie it's similar but
it's like a more intense cherry pie yeah
it's like it's more cherry pie than
cherry pie dude I love cherry pie dude
that's cool to eat uh yeah more grapey
but mine right now is probably the uh
so my homie hunted this cut of poison
gushers which is the F1 derb by the
gusher and that one's out of control
like some of the most Umami Terps of all
time and then I crossed that with swish
so we call that poison with a z which
you know I don't know if we'll release
it as that because I'm kind of getting
sick of
going down the Z Rabbit Hole too with
too much but the poison
um right now I mean right now it's just
PP number six yes
Pastor poison number six right so pp6 is
my my current favorite right now I love
that all right now something that's
maybe going to be a little left of field
but I love doing this
um what's something you're passionate
about or a hobby you've got outside of
cannabis what do you like to do when
you're not with plans I play golf yeah
yeah
I [ __ ] I got I mean I played golf
growing up but I played Just For Fun you
know there was a course by my house that
was like University course it was like
seven dollars to play like nine holes
and we'd just go and you know have a
good time smoke weed and like hang out
and do whatever but then yeah I got back
I don't know
all right 20
14 2015
I like went to Roger Dunn and got like
fit for a set of golf clubs and like I
just got so hooked uh so yeah I love
being outside I bring the puffco Davin
hitting you know hitting some golf balls
it's fun time
that's beautiful what about you Harry uh
I'm a fly Fisher so oh nice one grew up
in Utah grew up fly fishing mostly for
trout and then recently I got into salt
water fly fishing so go to the Bahamas
once a year and do saltwater fly fishing
there it's fun he's being humble he's
like you know professional level of fly
fishing him and my dad like I I've gone
with them a bunch and they are both they
they leave me and my other brother in a
different boat because that's like look
if you're going to be in this boat like
we're running and they they'll catch I
don't know 50 fish 60 fish me and my
youngest brother will catch like two
like
that's brilliant I love that I love that
maybe two probably one between the two
of us right follow-on question what's
your favorite meal oh
I I mean I'm like kind of simple I like
steak Yeah like yeah steak and potatoes
and what like what do you get to cook to
medium rare no black and blue yeah yeah
okay yeah like a filet black and blue
like all day every day yeah respectable
just something simple you know Simple
Man you grill it on fire like a baked
potato like yeah I think Harry I think
like Japanese style Ramen probably be my
number one right now like some pork
chashu and soft-boiled egg
yeah definitely my top five is ramen
brilliant brilliant whoa look that
brings us to the final five questions we
ask everyone uh so the first one being
what is the single most memorable
experience you've had with cannabis so
it doesn't necessarily mean like the
strongest dab you've had but just like
maybe you're at a concert and like it
just hit right like you're like what's
the most memorable thing to you with
cannabis
so when I first moved to California I
was living in Utah and I was growing and
trapping and being a goof and I you know
pushed my parents to the Limit and they
were like you need to get the [ __ ] out
like go to California maybe like we
don't know what to do with you so leave
so I just got into California and I
spent my first night out here and we got
a bag of OG Kush seventy dollars an
eighth from my buddy's homie and I
remember waking up on the couch at this
place in Orange and I was smoking out of
this like stupid pipe that had like a
like a lion or something on the front
like one of the like kid dumb you know
like a leopard Panther I think it was a
black and it was just weird but I was
sitting there smoking this pipe and I
was just like okay
this is going to be great
like this is this is going to work this
is what we're gonna do
and I didn't I didn't have it all
planned out at the time but like that
was the first moment where I was like
okay I can I can kind of start to see
how I want this to go
that's awesome I love it Harry what
about you so in college I lived in the
Caribbean for a semester I sold bed
sheets to people who came in on cruise
ships
weird time but um I lived on St Thomas
really pretty Island
um so got a bag Master Splinter was the
name of my drug dealer there never
learned his name but just give him a
call you home yeah drive by he'd just be
sitting in a lawn chair out front walk
up dime bag 10 bucks good to go
um and then we went up to like the
highest point on the island and just
smoked a joint up there but
I don't know just yeah just hit right
like you said that's amazing I love it
all right on the other end of the
spectrum okay all your homies are hyping
up this strain you're like oh [ __ ] can't
wait to try this finally comes around
super unimpressive how did people rate
this what strain is it for you
blue dream
yeah the blue dream I was uh
I was unimpressed
what's up I was a little upset I was
still hooked on oh geez so the blue
dream was kind of meh and then we got a
cut of double dream
which was basically just Blue Dream 2.0
and uh
still upset about that one I love it but
it yielded well and it paid the bills so
we kind of had to you know
had to run it that's it that's it
I don't want to keep hating on Oreos but
I've seen some Oreos hash that looked
incredible and someone was hyping up and
I smelled it and I just got
um
what do we call it uh Lacroix like
YouTube Oreos is kind of what I
described like hint of hint of Oreos
um and the flower the same way I saw the
jar sitting there and I was like oh I've
got to get some of that yeah look at
that yeah and then I remember smoking
and just being like oh this like Obama
yeah sorry to Oreos lovers nice all
right something you referenced earlier
uh I'm gonna drop you off on a desert
island you can take three strains what
three
oh okay let's see we're definitely
taking an OG cut I'm not gonna say which
one because you know I don't want to
it's too difficult but an OG cut
um definitely taking either Fizz or
cherry pie and then probably
oh that's I mean honestly like I've been
smoking on this rainbow belts 2.0
recently and
I could probably smoke that hash
every day until I died it tastes it's so
overpoweringly soapy and weird and it
gets me the same weird that's as close
to the dryer sheet terp as I've found
like definitely in the profile of
cleaning products but yeah it's I always
joke like I thought Skittles or you know
rainbow belts tasted like if you made a
butter croissant but used Dawn soap
instead of like water in the dough like
it's just it's got this really creamy
delicious but just soapy like well soapy
well there you go
um I'd say probably the rainbow sugar
which is a cross we did a Fizz so it's
got those same kind of fish Terps but
it's got maybe like a little more Stony
um
probably like something like a rainbow
belts or the Skittles just because
that's such a unique flavor I'd want to
have
and then
I don't know what for my third one
um
yeah maybe like an OG like a Larry OG or
just something like totally different
yeah something green I love it I love it
all right final question for each of you
guys you go to time machine you can go
back anywhere Anytime Anyplace you can
get either seeds or a clone where you
gonna go what are you gonna get oh I'm
gonna go I mean how long do I have
because I want to do the whole hippie
hash Trail I want to do the old school
[ __ ] I want to smuggle a bunch of hash
in the surfboard I wanna I wanna do all
of the things that I always read about
you know like my parents friends doing
and just going into parts of the world
that are like absolutely inaccessible to
this day and tasting and finding stuff
that is definitely extinct at this point
like and maybe it's
awesome and maybe it's just like oh yeah
we have all these flavors today like
this wasn't you know like because part
of the scent memory you like fan you
romanticize flavors I don't know if
you've had this where like you don't
have something for a long time and then
you try it again and you're like oh man
it's just like
it's not as good you know it doesn't
taste as good like is it or did you just
like romanticize it and make it better
in your head and it's I mean it's hard
to say
so Emily and Harry
yeah I
I really don't know
um
can you go to the future with this time
machine I guess so why not
um I probably wrote kill skunk I
probably just want to know like is it
something that everyone just
romanticized and they thought really
smelled like that and we do have it now
or is everyone just lying now and it's
something that did exist and is now gone
so I mean Lupa told me it spelled like
like a dead animal skunk he was like no
it didn't he's not skunk one it wasn't
this fruity sweet skunk he's like it
smelled
like legitimately it smelled like a
skunk like a dead animal and I've only
smelled a couple things that were even
remotely similar that were like diesels
and like some sours that Zoda is about
as close to dead animal scone because
I've gotten that that zone is 16.
um
that I would I would want to smell that
actually something that was verified
because that's the that's the mystery on
the you know everyone claims to be that
I Am The Keeper of the skunk you're like
I don't know about that like I wish I
wish Whoever has it they're not on the
internet you know there's some old dude
living in the woods like
don't have the internet some guy offline
for sure and he's just sitting there in
his backyard smoking his roadkill skunk
without a care in the world
that's it right so I think that just
about brings us to the end of things
were there any comments or shout outs
you want to make
oh man yeah so uh shout out exotic AG
fertilizer shout out more shout out to
clean bio our Testing Lab
um shout out to who else Harry Neptune's
seed bank shout out to Neptune Neptune
seedbank.com it's where you can get all
our seeds let's see
yeah shout out to the podcast for having
us on you know [ __ ] yeah I appreciate it
sad to be here excited to meet you in
person which was cool because didn't
know we get this chance so you can hang
out and take some dabs not a bad way to
spend your uh your afternoon
100 it's uh it's a good recipe in my
cookbook a huge huge huge thank you to
the dynamic duo behind the Exotic Turf
Powerhouse that is Umami Seed Co uh so
again Umami and Harry thanks for joining
me yes sir thank you
thank you
there you go friends what do you think
huge shout out to Mommy and Harry coming
by having a chat sharing all their
knowledge and a huge thank you to you
for making it all the way to the end as
always big shout out to our sponsors if
you want to help support the show go
support our sponsors CT now guarantee on
satisfaction not just germination check
them out the hottest breed is the latest
drops they've got everything you could
want and more Copic biological systems
you know you love them
they got all the best pest and Predator
predation technology to keep your garden
pumping on all cylinders you want the
best powers today check them out
it's better to keep your garden
intestine pathogen free guys get on top
of it before it's an issue Copa
biological systems we love you so much
a huge shout out to my friends at Pulse
sensors if you want to get the most
resinous heaviest yields happiest time
if possible get serious get a pulse
sensor make sure your room's guarding
accordingly
huge shout out to the patreon gang as
always
[Music]
and that just about wraps up for this
one guys thanks for joining us
I'll see you for the next one
we'll see you