hello and welcome to the podcast
cannabis podcast for budding enthusiasts
this episode as always was brought to
you by seeds here now
only place to get your seeds only place
to get your addiction filled best in the
game guarantee on satisfaction not just
germination and speaking of best in the
game 420 australia organic gardening
solutions another two killers
go check them out
on this episode we are thankful to be
talking to the man on the million seed
finno hunt himself breeda steve here to
talk about terroir genetics history and
what he's up to down in south america
let's get into it
alrighty so a big thank you and welcome
to another veteran of the scene the man
behind so many famous strains breeda
steve thanks so much for joining us
thanks for having me and thanks for your
hospitality when i was in your neck of
the woods this year
yeah no problem at all so
first question we've been starting the
interviews off with lately what are you
currently smoking on
well
a little selection i had just rolled up
a bud of skunk number one for a little
nostalgic smoke
and it reminds me even the feel in your
fingers breaking up skunk it has a feel
you know i find like it's a very soft
silky even though it's a tight nug or
maybe a tight nug it still breaks up in
your fingers like it if with my eyes
closed sometimes i think i would know
that with skunk number one just because
of the feel of the bud
yeah no i i can kind of relate to that
i've never tried a wide variety of
skunks but i think i know what you mean
it's
yeah okay well my first question would
be
what's your opinion on terms of the
skunk now versus when you were first
experiencing it
you know it's an old standby and it's uh
such a building block of everything out
there or many of the things out there
and
i just like
i've found the last couple years that
i've been going back to the strains i
remember from when i was younger and
just starting out 30 years ago and i
think i'm still kind of nostalgic for a
taste of that old northern lights or
some scout number one or something
like they are classics for a reason you
know and i sure love trying the latest
and greatest from everybody too
but uh
there's a reason those ones are still
around is there
you know they have character
yeah of course
and have you personally noted any kind
of variation over the years because i
think that's the comment that often gets
through
yes sir the nlic today
isn't as uh
it's just not the same as the first ones
i've been exposed to there's there's
some similarities but there's some
definite differences and
you know within any population there's
some variation so
you can imagine how many northern light
seeds got sold over the years and spread
around from seattle before they were
even being sold in seed companies you
know so i think there's a lot of
variation even within nl5 there would
still be
a lot of
uh
you know recognizable but different
of course and so do you think that the
nl at least maybe we'll say nl5 just so
we've got a little more of a talking
point do you think that it's it was a
line which had variation even when it
was originally released or it was more
of like a clone type of thing
i think there was a fairly stable line
and uh but
i don't think it uh
you know clones can have
sports which is mutations through
cuttings which is why
you know pinot gris pinot blanc and
pinot noir were all the same seedling at
one point and they shared the exact same
chromosomes but there
was a mutation in the cuttings which led
to the other two
they're not even sure which was the
first one in that case but i mean with
northern lights that could be the same
thing where you you get some clonal
variation over time
but
mostly you don't a clone is a clone
in most cases you know it would take
millennia for some of those tweaks
happened like they haven't been affair
over time the uh
you know selecting from seed when you
grow a pack of seed you always have one
favorite of the bunch maybe you have two
favorites but they're never all
absolutely unmistakably the same you
know
regardless how stable
the line may be it's not
uniform like a tray of clones
so
the
everybody can pick a little different
one and of course every environment that
it's grown is different even a different
water source anything can change like
you can really taste the difference
between bc hydro and ontario hydro
largely because of the hard and soft
water
so i mean it's uh
the environment is half the genetic is
half of what you end up with but among
the you know within the environment
there's lots of variation and within the
genetic there's at least a little
variation you know
yeah certainly and you just touched on a
topic i always love to talk about but
really we get to genetic drift do you
believe that it exists the consensus
we've heard so far is a lot of people
don't think it exists within cannabis
but you kind of just hinted that you
think it may
well if if it does it's it's a very slow
process you know so there's some clones
that have
you know that i know even have been
around for 30 years so i
do i see a massive change in them not a
massive change but sometimes there's
some slippage or the introduction of a
virus or something you know where the
like with grapefruit grapefruit was a
cutting i got in 94
and it had no name it was called the
people i got it from called it the only
thing worth growing
so as and i always thought they picked
it too early because i thought their bud
was sweet but it was always really long
red hair and just not quite finished so
i said i really want to get some clones
of this and try to grow it out and it
was i got some in the spring my first
year in vancouver and put them out on
my balcony and flowered like 20 of them
out there i kept one under a light in my
closet to veg when i my first place in
bc right after university and uh
it smelled like as it ripened and got
truly ripe well beyond the long orange
chairs all over it once it started to
swell up and you have swollen calyxes
and you could smell it was just like
scratching a ruby red i called it sweet
pink grapefruit because it when it
really finishes it's got
unmistakable
you know sweet pink grapefruit
smell
and it carries into the taste is a bit
but not as much as in the smell the
smell is really obviously sweet pink
grapefruit so it was really nice to find
that but and i shared that cutting far
and wide anybody that calls it
grapefruit got it downstream from me
because i appended that name to that
found cutting
the um
but do i see different versions of
grapefruit from different corners for
sure and some people i've talked to have
been calling me seeing if they could get
one
because the ones they've had have gone
to [ __ ] and mostly is that they have
tobacco mosaic virus whereas other
people that have had them the whole time
and they're perfectly healthy so it can
pick up a problem on the way
and in different hands even and then
that gets passed around and people think
oh this has fallen apart now and it
could be from a variety of factors but
the uh
but do i think it's going to morph into
a different looking plant like pinot
noir and pinot blanc that's pretty
extreme you know considering they have
the same genetics and the genetic drift
between those
is uh
not that they weren't born from the same
seedling
but they had drift through cuttings and
and that's a
mutation known as a sport i don't see
why it couldn't happen in cannabis
except for the reason
that typically cannabis is an annual
and
people like a vine finds our captain
cloned and passed on and so i think it's
more apparent in something that's been
cloned over a thousand
years rather than something that's been
cloned over ten
you know
yeah i think
it would become much more apparent over
time those different clones
but i think
out the gate you know you're not seeing
genetic drift on cutting
from the same mothers or growing those
into mothers and growing their cuttings
and mothers like i think you could go
quite a few generations
all things being equal not not including
the introduction of a virus or something
that causes it to degrade you know
yeah and i mean you bring up a really
interesting point there because i i
can't remember where i read it but i
believe it said that there had actually
not been any laboratory confirmed cases
of tmv and cannabis and i was
immediately suspect when i heard that
like what do you think of that claim
well i don't have a laboratory but from
the
the symptoms that i've seen always
described as tmv
do seem to take down a plant whether
it's actually tmv or not i've never
verified in a lab but i've seen most of
us have seen those
leaves with the wavy yellow splotchy
um color of plants that seized
they ceased to be healthy after that you
know
so i don't know if it's actually tmv but
i know the cannabis community identifies
typically they would identify that
um
pathology you know
htmv yeah of course that's just what
that's what we think of as and are we
right beats me i've never actually seen
it under an electron microscope or
anything
i am not the the guy with the experience
in the lab so i'm happy to learn
something if we can dispel a myth with
uh science that's a great thing
but
do i know i don't know i haven't seen i
can't confirm or deny
yeah i mean heck maybe if nothing else
it's a good reason to not have tobacco
around cannabis plants
any excuse
so something i wanted to quickly clarify
from the little story just earlier on
you mentioned
is it the case that that cutting you got
was
what you refer to as i'm not sorry what
you refer to was it the case that that
was grapefruit or the sweet pink
grapefruit because i believe if you look
up the genetics sweet pink grapefruit is
listed as grapefruit cross unknown
strain
well there's some truth to that because
the first plant though i definitely
tagged spg for sweet paint grapefruit
and as i was sharing it with people and
showing them from the 19 buds that i'd
grown out there was um
everybody was like wow that's super
candy that's super sweet and it really
had a very sweet sweet flavor
and the bag was unmistakably grapefruit
so the first cross i made with those
was with a jolly rancher male
and you haven't heard of that probably
maybe you have but it'd be uh
unusual so that was the very first
release of spice of life was jolly
rancher and it actually changed the name
from the original i had read that
um
in a creek near the house where i spent
my formative years i've never
conceived that i grew up but the where i
started growing my first five years
outdoors i would save a little bit of
seed
after the first couple attempts and then
i thought okay
when i moved to bc i had i called it
medway madness because i grew it at
medway creek
and i had my midway madness seeds
and
when i got to bc i just had a few film
canisters you know for personal use at
that time
i was always people were always smoking
my homegrown with me because i would
never sell anybody's a bud everybody
would want to buy some of my home groups
it was exceptional but i wouldn't sell
it because i said look you know this is
exceptional what am i going to do with
your money go replace it i can't so when
it runs out it's gone so i said the most
i'll do is share with let's share some
with you when we get together but i'll
never sell it to you because i can't
grow enough for everybody and once i run
out i can't replace it so i said once
it's legal maybe we'll revisit that but
those seeds i just had because i made
two or three film canisters probably at
that time
and i had a one-page
how to grow your own you know gorilla
style as i did
and i would give anybody that was
bugging me to buy a butt i'd say
here i can give you a one pager of
instructions on how to do it and i can
give you 20 seeds to go get started and
when you get her figured out pass it
along and show some other people how to
do it and give them some starting
material you know so it was
just a straight hobby play is what i got
into
and then when i was moved to vancouver
having been from london ontario
originally i used to
go down to mark emery's city light
bookstore and buy two live crew or high
times or whatever the government was
prohibiting so i really
like to support his civil disobedience
efforts and once he moved to vancouver
he just coincidentally was also in
vancouver with hemp bc
and he was selling i think three
varieties of seeds
and they were northern lights northern
light haze and northern light haze
hawaiian that bc seed company brought
over from scentsy to fight recall
and the police raided him and busted him
the first time for selling seeds
and i went down to see him
the next week or something i just popped
in we didn't know each other very well
or anything but i said hey remember me i
just you know into that pot rally you
had in london
i said i see you got busted selling
seeds if you're gonna
keep going with it i'd like to donate
film canister seeds to you
and i remember he peeled the top off him
and said those are coconuts
they're freaking coconuts because they
were really big seeds they were like
small peas really they were fat seeds
those jolly ranchers so he said well
what do you want to call them and i said
i said well i call them medway madness
and we're like yeah nobody's going to
know what that is and big
the midway means nothing outside of that
ontario so i said
i thought about it for a little bit and
they're very tangy it was a tangy herb
you know a little fruity and tangy and
but not overly sweet and i said
jolly rancher you know so we put those
first ones out as spicy life seeds
jolly rancher
and
the jolly rancher
got the mail from that was pollinated
later or pollinated the sweet pink
grapefruit cutting and that first
f1 of those was called sweet pink
grapefruit so there's both a cutting and
that first round of seeds that was
called sweet pink grapefruit
and then the second time i crossed the
grapefruit
led to the sweet skunk which remarkably
has no skunk and the story's been told
but i'll share it with you again
while i was in vancouver my first order
of business moving out there was to
collect every single cat bang i could
find
and bring it and get seeds from anywhere
i could and just really look at
everything because at the time bc was
the only province in canada with nobody
in jail for growing
and i wasn't worried about selling what
i was growing i just wanted to grow out
a lot and look at it and i had 1500
plants from seed in my backyard in the
summer right in town
they would get to be a meter high or so
before i really started spinning them
out i mean it was a bit crazy and i had
14 lights in the basement at that time
so people and i'd have a live uh music
for once a week
and have big parties there it was just
stupid but uh
oh the second time i had uh one of the
guys i got cuttings from because anybody
that was selling cuttings i said i'll
take some bring me some
and uh he brought me two trees one had
an orange dash of spray paint on the
side and the other nothing and he said i
think this one is big skunk i think this
one is northern lights but he wasn't
sure and i'm like for [ __ ] sakes you
couldn't just write an n on one of them
or something you know
like because
he just used them
i took these plants and i labeled them
what he thought they were
as they grew out
it later became apparent that they were
reversed and the but even worse the more
on he picked up these cuttings from
one of the trees the one that i thought
was big skunk turned out to be a male
and uh i had like 20 these cuttings i'm
like oh [ __ ] great but but it had
been growing in veg so
vigorously i was like wow well this is a
real neat plant i was really loving the
plant
and then when i saw it was a male i
wasn't loving it quite as much but i
thought well i'll kill most of them and
keep one because it is super vigorous
and the stem smelled really had a
gorgeous aroma on the stem
and so that you know obviously in
retrospect turned out to be the animal
haze but at the time i thought it was a
big skunk and uh
i
made a cross of it with a number of
things i every year basically i was
taken the best male i found out of my
initial years of just collecting all the
females i could growing them out side by
side
and then any males i found i would
usually toss but if it was outstanding
for any reason i would keep that male
and let it hit a room of like my
favorite five or favorite six females
going at the time
so that was how the sweet skunk was done
was that mail n l hayes mail on the
sweet pink grapefruit cutting
and
when i
brought it out in the seed catalog and
took it down town to him bc i was
calling it big fruit which would have
been okay
it should have just stuck with big fruit
but mark was out of skunk at the time
and he said well because the father is a
skunk pig bud he's like i'll call it
sweet skunk so he just changed the name
on the catalog that was the only time
that happened where
i released the scene with something and
then they you know
the vendor
changed the name and the catalog was
just what was
you know my ad space in cannabis canada
magazine at the time so they just edited
the name from big fruit to sweet skunk
so that sweet skunk name just stuck
because that's what it came out with
right away
and
when i grew it out
what became
famous as sweet skunk now
was the cutting of one particular
recessive so i drew out 500 of those f1s
and
498 of them
looked like northern lights as i'm
pretty sure the grapefruit cutting was a
really early version of northern lights
the guy i got it from it had it 17 years
who got it from somebody else that had
it about that long who brought it up
from seattle and it was already old so
this is a
several decades-old cutting when i got
it and that was a long time ago now so i
mean
it's probably
50 years old or something if
if you think about it
but when i grew them out it was mostly
northern lights looking plants
really quite stable even the shockingly
so which really confirms that i think it
was a grapefruit it wasn't early
northern lights and then the um
but the two recessives that showed up in
the room were like hazes and they were
removed to the corner
they weren't obviously going to finish
at the same time as most of them so they
got shoved to the corner
and while they were very similar looking
haze type plants one of them was just
like if i have to pick a favorite you
know and i would ask my friends to come
down and rub them and not tell them what
i think and i say if you had to just
pick one of these which one do you like
more
and everybody picked the same one i like
more they're like i guess this one is
just a little bit sweeter smell you know
and they were both exceptional and and
so that cutting
i shared it far and wide because you
know a lot of people are really into
protecting cuttings and i was more of
the mind like i hate to be the only guy
with this bud i would really like to see
everywhere i go people pull this out you
know so i really wanted to make sure
that you know i knew lots of growers
wouldn't want it because it's 12 weeks
to flower and they're used to it but i
knew some of them would get the
appreciation of it and go you know what
even if you go 12-14 weeks it makes up
for it because of the stretch
and uh there's a pretty good yield of
fluffy sativa-like buds if i can still
say sativa without getting slapped but
the uh the
beauty of it you know
is it just smells gorgeous and it's
because it's a stretchy
you can throw that [ __ ] into
trays for rooting on 12 hours
you don't have to keep the cloning
lights on just root them on 12 hours and
then put those straight into flower like
six and a four or six by six so 36 of
them in a four by four area if you like
to grow lots of little ones if you put
36 of them in a four by four area
you will have
36 cricket bats you know they just
they just stretch up into big
fluffy glorious you stretchy buds and
they just smell incredible so people
when uh
you know when standard
good indoor in town was maybe 200
announced that would fetch 300 an ounce
according to my friends that were
selling because they would be growing
you know
grapefruit or i'm trying to even think
of what people were going back and there
was a lot of big buds it was really
it was an amazing time there were some
people growing some really fantastic
herbs but most of the people aren't ever
growing a lot of fantastic herbs that's
it's the kiss of death of popularity
like at one point a grapefruit perfect
example
it was highly sought after when it first
was showing up as really good quality
product and it was tasty and visually
appealing and everybody's like wow i
can't get enough of that grapefruit you
know the people that were growing it
commercially and exporting it doing a
good job we're making a good name for it
but of course the cuttings get spread
around everybody eventually and then it
becomes the lowest common denominator
because if everybody's growing it
and in the case of vancouver at that
time
um
the vietnamese were growing a lot of
lower grade bud picking everything at
six weeks or whatever and just banging
out and once though
once that strain got out into the wider
world or that cutting
it was the kiss of death because it was
it started out super popular
and
that would be the kiss of death because
once it got popular
everybody's doing it and once
everybody's doing it now it's the regs
or the beasters you know because it's
not being done
with the attention to detail required to
make it special so when the first when i
just give it out to a bunch of really
good growers because i want to see them
grow it you know and i give it to
beginners anybody's starting out i want
to see them get growing some sweeter
herb it helps but the name gets dragged
through the dirt when too much bad
commercial gets attached to it and then
nobody wants to see it they're like oh
yeah you know a few years later once
everybody have it it was just be
synonymous with shitty weed you know oh
no no we don't want more grapefruit and
then now that sort of flipped around
again as people are kind of missing the
sweet flavors because everything's been
on this pungent kush kick for a while
and very piney
strong
aromas
and uh punchy herb but not necessarily
really a pleasure to smoke
yeah yeah it's definitely interesting we
i think we've been on the fuel
binge for a while now so to speak with
the ogs and all that
variety is the spice of life as they say
and uh i always like i would i never had
one that i thought oh that's the only
thing i want to smoke for the rest of my
life you know i always say boy i sure
want that in my library or my cellar of
jars for the rest of my life i always
want to have access to that flavor do i
want it to be the only flavor [ __ ] no
[Laughter]
yeah no i can agree it's like i like
shiraz but would i give up pinot noir to
drink shiraz forever no no no no
well both can i have both you know
yeah definitely and it's it's crazy how
many parallels there were between that
many story that story told and kind of
the australian scene in that you know
even right now the vietnamese are the
ones
pumping out the beasts in the same
fashion you described and
i'm even um personally toying with the
idea of maybe giving raspberry mummy out
to a few people but i'm fearful of
exactly what you said like just becomes
synonymous with [ __ ] weed
what happens i mean it's cool it's still
good to get it out there because anybody
can have a chance to grow good weed if
they've got good genetics without them
they don't even have a chance right yeah
so i like to get the genetics out there
but it's always disheartening when you
see a piss poor job done of it and it
because it reflects badly on you to some
degree because people think
oh yeah
you know i talked to this one young
american kid recently that works for a
big pot company and he was on a
conference call with some other people
and trying to explain how he was a real
pot expert and whatnot and i
he says
so what strange did you breed and i was
like well like sweet tooth
and he's like sweet tooth
he isn't that the beasters and i'm
cracking up i'm going that's what a frat
boy that looks at booth packs says you
know not a grow expert
if you're a grow expert that's not what
you say you say oh that looks like this
or you know whatever you might have
some valid input but you say isn't that
just the beast i think
that's the booth pack oh my god you know
shopping fat boys you know you just
you just lost me as far as any
credibility with what you know about a
strain you know but if if all you know
is the beast it's because you've just
been looking at the shitty weed mask
people are selling you garbage
yeah it's it's crazy how many people who
are just i call them professional
smokers and they think they're like
you know
like the guy you're talking to basically
anyway so what i wanted to touch back on
for a sec was you mentioned sweet pink
grapefruit and the original grapefruit
clone possibly being in northern lights
what do you think is the origins of that
like just a worked afghani type of thing
that's what we've heard thrown around
before definitely
i mean beyond that i have no idea but
there's obviously it's afghanica that's
that's uh
i don't know what else exactly and i'm
sure people do i'm sure it's already
been sequenced and explored it's
probably in that uh
violence
yeah the finals galaxy
i bet you they have it i mean i just
haven't looked at stuff lately i've not
been keeping up i'm just trying i've
just spent the last couple years getting
my ducks in a row to get back into being
able to breed in the wide open field
scenarios again
and that's really
to me if i'm not doing selections and
fields
i'm not getting my money's worth you
know i have to pay too much to do it
inside to get polluted results the way i
see it because if the plants
become incapable to survive outside
because they've been living with
crutches so long
they'll never run again you know so
yeah i want to have them
you know where the strong survive
because uh
nature can thin out a lot of you and it
really is a numbers game you know
every time
you're planting seeds
regardless of the source
it's a bit of a lottery so the more
tickets you have the better chance you
have of winning and
you
you don't find you know out of 100 siege
you might find one twice as good as you
found out of 10. but out of a million
seeds it might not be twice as good but
even if it's 10 percent better it's
still a vast improvement you know
so
really the uh
the ability to start
large numbers of seed and grow them in
the open exposed to the elements is
priceless as far as doing selections it
does have to work for you you know
you're going to find out in a hurry
which ones can't stand up in a windstorm
and if you're not worried about that and
you you're happy to stake all your
plants that's fine but i may that may be
a condition for me if i need the plants
that stand up on their own two feet
because i'm not planning on staking a
thousand square
kilometers of them
i want to have plants that are resilient
and when i started breeding
in vancouver on a full-time way
i would do
a selection a year outside
for a generation and then i would do two
generations selected indoors
so
before long the plants that i was
working with and the lines i was
developing
were great for indoors and most people
grew them indoors but they were still
decent outdoor plants and uh
and that was always really neat to see
for me because i've always just grown in
canada at that point
and that i would find amazing tropical
plants like
out of seed from barbados i got what uh
turned out to be original colombian gold
that i've never seen as pure since and i
made two crosses with those i had males
and females and stupidly i didn't keep a
pure line of it because i thought oh
nobody will ever want these are 16 weeks
and
so i used
um actually the same dad as the
sweet skunk
to make a tropical treat line i had
tropical treat one and two and then i
used the pollen from the colombian gold
on a dutch tree
and i believe that was tropical treat
one and the other one was tropical tree
too and then in switzerland later
i made i used uh
i'd grown them out a couple lines and
crossed them later with uh sweet skunk
and shishka berry with each of the lines
and called those tropicana one and two
and i think richard from heaven stairway
cornered the market on those but it was
really amazing to me even from the first
tropical treats was to see customers
that ordered these plants through the
magazine back then
and grew them out in northern australia
or hawaii or in mexico or
palm springs or somewhere infinitely
warmer than where i was
and they could see the real potential
like i would see these plants as four
foot skinny little things under lights
and then i would get back the customer
photos
of guys with these 16-foot monsters just
like holy [ __ ]
you know it was so cool to
see that and the
you know it's really been amazing you
know in ourselves included like with
online cannabis community we've made
friends all over the world that we share
this
you know amazing if somewhat
controversial hobby and we've been much
maligned and persecuted for it and we
grin and bear it and we keep pushing
onwards and even with uh
you know when we put our personal lives
at risk and at stake
and um
i have nothing but respect for the
people doing it right that's for sure
yeah definitely i mean let's just take a
step back for a moment and fill everyone
in because i'm sure a lot of people are
hugely interested in what you're doing
right now as i am what was it that first
inspired you to start thinking about
moving down south and doing the big
things you're doing now
well um
i had basically taken a
sabbatical from cannabis work as i was
getting really
fed up with the industry and there was
getting to be a bit of a pogrom
happening where we were working in
switzerland so we just decided to close
up shop and uh take some time to
reevaluate what we're doing and i
decided you know what i was a lot of the
seeds retailers because i never did
retail i was always just selling
mainly to distributors even who would
then sell to shops and sometimes the
shop would or shops would order directly
maybe in a country where there wasn't a
distributor
um
so i really just operated on the
wholesale level with them
and
that
degree of insulation was really good for
peace of mind and security
but on the other hand i started having
to deal with a lot of [ __ ] in people
putting you know starting to print fake
packs and putting other seeds in it or
their cheap version of it or whatever
and just like
i am so see and i got and selling
knockoffs of them from other
unscrupulous seed companies
and then i got to be at one point i had
a look right around then when [ __ ]
was getting to be a real headache and i
was like there's not a single one of my
customers left that doesn't sell
knock-ups of my seeds on the next page
why the [ __ ] am i doing this it's just
you know i said until you've got
some
protection like any other plant breeder
i'm going halfway around the world
building out facilities for indoors
field selections greenhouse production
without selling all the pot by the time
all the time but if i just grew grass
for sale of weight it would have been
easy quiet made more money but i was
always into how much can i roll back
into r d because it was to me it was
just that's my addiction is the r d i
want to keep growing that having some
money is good but it's not to be all and
end though for me maybe for other people
that's different and that's their
business and i don't care i don't judge
anybody that just wants to grow for
weight but for me i just want to spread
seeds and i want to sprout them
consecutively generation after
generation
and see the development towards the
ideal of
the examples that i find most attractive
and you know you cannot you know you're
only in charge of
your own taste you know so
if people like stuff you know that is
calibrated to my taste that's great then
we we're on the same page if not
whatever you breed your other ones i
don't
it's to their own there's absolutely
there's no right or wrong when it comes
to your palette because your palette is
your palette and
i find um you know whether i'm reading
wine reviewers sometimes they'll find
one so they like wines i don't like and
that guy always likes wines i do like so
maybe i'll follow what he's doing better
and it's the same with with grass some
breeders are gonna breed stuff that
appeals to certain people
and other people are gonna be more
attracted to stuff from other breeders
but i think overall
you know
it's really fun it's it's just like
music almost it's like there's music
but how many kinds of music are there
you know even within one genre of music
which is your favorite band you know so
there's
it's really uh expression so
we find the herbs that appeal to us the
most
and uh i just feel privileged to have uh
indulged myself so long in doing so and
having took a long break from it which
my children were young at the time too
and i wanted them to have a
you know non-controversial
upbringing as i was
leaving europe and going back to the
dark ages
and
and that worked out fine i'd do
something else i really enjoyed and
his head was stoned the whole time so it
was really not a huge sacrifice to take
a break from the industry all that time
and as i watched the various
programs roll out in the canadian regime
i would read through them the day they
came out whether it was mma rm and pr
acm pr than the cannabis act
and
i would lose interest by the time i read
them because i would think
um the mma er came out when i was gone i
think so it never really uh
even while i was gone to mmpr came out i
remember reading it on my computer in
switzerland
and i was looking at do i want to come
back and set this up by the time i'd
read through it i was like now this is
designed to fail this is a joke and
there's no way i'd want to work under
those conditions and if i can't grow
outside or make cash [ __ ] i can't be
bothered and
so
so it had zero appeal to me to build a
jail to work in you know so the
then the acmpr came out and it still
didn't allow an outdoor cultivation so
it still lacked interest for me
and it was softer than the mmpr but it
was still nonsensical and now
the latest
the cannabis act that came out october
17th this year
has allowed open the door for outdoor
applications
so now it's starting to get more
interesting so i'm having a serious
thought about canada but about five
years ago even one of my friends
that was a an academic
he'd been really trying to get me
interested in doing an mmpr and i kept
saying no no no no no no i don't want to
bother with this [ __ ] let's wait till
you see something better and so we ended
up making a company just for studying
the opportunity and on the different uh
regimes around the world
and we really were just doing our
homework and
and keeping our eye open and staying
patient and
when i saw the first draft of the
columbian regs come out
it was like they read the mmpr
took a black marker to most of it and
cut it down to 12 pages
so it was like
oh this is way better you know this has
some appeal and it involved outdoor
as an option and i and it ticked all the
boxes because i'd always wanted to grow
on the equator as well not for a
research station that's very important
to me
and
i love the tropical terps far more than
the afghan based ones and i would love
to drive a combine pulling down sweet
skunk you know
for a square kilometer a day you know
that's fine let's do that so i really
wanted to to scale up to plant
equatorial fields by doing a lot of
selections down there and
in the constitution of columbia people
are allowed to have 20 plants
um as a personal supply and that's
you never ever hear about anybody
getting hassle for their 20 plants
um
sometimes people would pool them
together the regs weren't really clear
on
whether or not it was per household or
per person and they were deliberately
vague as many regulations are so that
they can be interpreted
by the authorities as they wish
so the um
but so we ended up putting a few names
on a property not where we're getting
the license
and just doing a test plan you know
trying out a bunch of stuff
while we're waiting for all the
licensing process to go through
and
even from the beginning we were we went
down there when when we saw this
initially is a 12 page regulation i'm
jumping all over but
the 12-page first draft that intrigued
me so much and i said i want to shake
the handle whoever wrote this
i got down there
um
august
2015 or 16 2016. i guess
we'll players together
two two and a bit years ago august the
um
the
through friends we got invited to go
and present in the congress of columbia
meeting with
the
lawyer who's a very intelligent woman
that wrote that first draft and she was
a lawyer for senator juan manuel gallant
and later we met with him separately and
uh you know both really sensible people
that want
you know sensible drug policy really and
once their first draft came out
it expanded beyond that
initial 12 pages but when they tried to
implement and gave out the first couple
licenses
it was um
around
january that year
and the opposition and government had
never got a chance to look at it or
debate it so they put the brakes on it
so
it really did hurt the very first people
to apply because it put them in a
holding pattern for
quite a long time
um
[Music]
but as after the opposition had a
went through it
tightened it up as they saw it and made
it a little more controlled and awkward
for the rest of us then it was still
allowed to be implemented
the current government is less favorable
towards cannabis than the last one
and things aren't moving quite as
quickly down there as they had been
so
that was why i picked it
but and we really made to that we're the
only company there to have registered
genetics actually where we made history
to be the
registered the first genetics in the
history of the country so that's kind of
cool i'm very proud of that and i'm
happy that we'll be the first ones to go
into production with them shortly
um but i'm not as excited about
production like my partners and other
people are they're really they see the
production part more than i see
you know the value in doing the genetics
work and not just because it's not just
monetary value to me it's absolutely
selfish pleasure
but you know what it still works out
good for the production team too when
when i increase the efficiency of
whatever we're trying to achieve
so if we want
high thcv strains well
let's bump them up from 2 to 20 percent
or you know if you can do that you just
made 10 times the production without
getting another hectare you know
so
so there's so much importance in working
with genetics and nowadays with greater
legality and more and more jurisdictions
there's so many really qualified people
with skills far beyond me in molecular
genetics and whatnot that are able to go
to town and work on some of these things
and some of the things they work on may
not be things that we like and some of
them may be
but
there's no
substitute for nosing your way through
the place you know if you're if that's
what you're looking for if i and i
follow my nose i really want the most
aromatic varieties for whatever the end
goal is whether it's a higher
cannabinoid content i'm not gonna
i just don't want to grow ones that have
the smells i don't like and i find
probably half of the aromas in cannabis
i don't like in whatever combination you
know
like then some it's a thumb totally puts
me off and some totally turns me on and
there's
there's some middle ground but uh
there's a lot of variety in cannabis
aromas there's far more than in wine i
forget the actual number of compounds in
each but it is a substantial difference
like a factor of 10.
um
yeah wow so i mean i've seen a lot of
photos on your instagram feed over the
past say a year or so and you like to
use this tag the million seed vino hunt
is that the goal billion seed search
yeah well what i've actually
working on doing right now is planting a
hundred thousand seeds a month
so
i could do more than that given the
space in hands and materials
and that's no problem and once uh
but a thousand seeds some 100 000 seeds
a month that's a good working pool you
know
most breeders of any sort be pretty
happy to do that
and yes it's been a year that's a
significant you know you've cracked a
million in a year
well over and
so i put this million seed search
hashtag out and said anybody that wants
to contribute to this
and send me some of their seeds to try i
needed a minimum of 75 but now the rigs
have changed i need a minimum of 100
to plant
them out for characterization
and what i'm offering in return is
everybody that
contributes seeds to this million seed
search
i will
give them back a detailed grow report
from that latitude and altitude
and i'm taking it to other latitudes and
altitudes within columbia lona have 11
test zones so i have my main farm in one
and then one hectare test zone with the
national university
in the other 10 zones
so that's just in colombia so if the
seeds are make it to colombia they will
be fully tested and you'll get a full
report from all these different
scenarios
and
i will also
welcome you to come down and check
everything out for yourself
and come for your visit and
other than that i told people if you
don't want to contribute seeds just send
me your wholesale list and we'll buy a
bunch of you so i really want to try and
look at everything out there
and
if i can't get everything out there
that's okay i'm not gonna be sweating it
too bad because you know i'm looking at
tons
yeah i'm not missing much if anything
i'm not missing much
yeah i mean
it's a huge undertaking to say the least
i mean i i don't know anyone who's even
attempted such a thing on that scale
yeah that's it you have somebody has to
to go for it you know you have to
to dream it before you can do it you
know when i start talking about doing
stuff like this people that don't know
me well give me
you're a dreamer man you'd never be able
to pull that off then two years later
even when i got to switzerland i
remember
you know i got there
whenever it was it was june i think it
was a little late to get set up for that
summer
but i was making grandiose plans for the
following year and i remember uh getting
a visit from this guy gypsy nirvana
from the uk and he came over
and uh he wrote a little thing after his
first visit going all this guy thinks
he's big [ __ ] he doesn't have anything
planted yet and he thinks he's gonna
have all this going by next year
and he's like we'll see we'll see then
he came back the next year he's like
holy [ __ ] god at everything he said
he was going to
and it's just a matter of you've got to
dream it before you can do it you know
and you have to tell yourself this is
what i'm going to do i'm i told myself
i'm gonna get set up in a legal scenario
to plant fields of grass on the equator
as soon as i can i don't really care
about breeding northern grass anymore
not i mean i'm interested in it not as
interested as a tropical stuff because
the perfumes have more high notes and
not the
not the stank that the kids are into
these days but it's they're only into it
because they've never had the
opportunity to try some spectacular
equatorial grass
maybe unless they live in hawaii or
something right
or australia
the uh
i got that one don't worry
no i mean i picked up on that little
reference don't worry
yeah
um
i loved uh i gotta say i loved your
grass it was the nicest i tried on your
land for sure
oh thank you i'm i'm sure there's
probably better but i'm glad i could
hook you up with something
oh it was really nice so most of the
other stuff i tried from the guys
brought me with one or two exceptions
but a few other people brought me stuff
but it was usually too chemi to smoke
like i really remember rolling
i roll into big fat paper because he
gave me like a half ounce and i was
leaving like the next day from that town
and i was like well i know don't give me
all this and i really made him take it
back he didn't want to take it back but
i said i'll let me keep
a little bit but
i just felt bad for him because i'm like
surely he can find somebody that
actually wants this because i remember i
rolled up a big fat joint and i lit it
and i took about three big puffs on it
and i looked him in the eye and i
flicked it out the window
and he's like
what'd you do that for i said i can't
smoke that grass man i'm so heavy
my lips are still burning from the first
few puffs i was like i just can't smoke
weed like that
and he he was just holy [ __ ] you're
serious and then i pulled out
something else and he was like oh yeah
there's something else and i said yeah
so he's he was impressed with what i had
i had more from another friend that i'd
met the day before in the same town
and i gave and i gave it to the guy with
the kemi reed and i said why don't you
take this home and smoke it because i
can't finish it before i leave tomorrow
so
anyway
you stood out absolutely
oh thank you i appreciate that i do want
to loot back to the start because all
this talk of holland and all that we
should probably go back to like canada
and you know how did you really get into
things there and then how did that
transition into then moving to
switzerland
okay
i started growing my own gorilla style
two plants here three plants there
back in southwestern ontario near london
in middlesex county
and the grass i would pull back there
still to this day is up there with
anything i've had from anywhere in the
world
so
i was quickly sold on i am not buying
any more grass i am growing my own
because what i'm growing is better than
what i could buy
and
it was really just a straight home-grown
play from the beginning five years of
that and uh
been going through university and
decided at the end of university i'm
going to move once i'm done
i'm going to move to dc because it's the
only province in canada nobody was in
jail for growing
so it was
attractive that way i never wanted to go
to jail for growing and
i moved out there and
[Music]
really took my hobby breeding to the
next level and ended up taking it pro
so as i was in vancouver i had opened
um
us grow shop
where we had lights and fans but only my
organic soil mix or organic fertilizer
and we had both
a system for people to grow organic
cocoa mix with steve's special blend and
worm castings and whatnot and then we
had a water system that was pure
aquaponics so i'd uh i started growing
aquaponics when i very first moved to
vancouver actually it was the first
closet i even built i built a quick
aquaponics system because i'd always
wanted to try that out and i think that
was the first cannabis grown aquaponic
which is the best of my knowledge but
he um
i kept doing it and then
and it was astounding the results when i
moved into the next house i was in i was
i made a literally a mickey mouse system
that had a mickey mouse shower curtain
where the water trickled under the
rubber mates and drained back into the
rubbermaid with the goldfish in it like
i called it the mickey mouse system
and uh
but the pot that came out of it was so
stunning
that people just lost it they would just
lose their [ __ ] and they would say what
the hell did you do to grow this it's so
different than anything else we smoke
and when i tell them they were just like
seriously and the puds were brought hard
it wasn't like you were sacrificing
weight you would get the same the plant
would turn out the shape it's supposed
to if it's healthy the whole time and
the light's dense enough and it packs in
its nodes and
the aquaponics just made it burn to a
white ash a clean white not even gray
it was stupid how clean it burned and so
i was a huge fan of that and i thought
for indoors or greenhouse i would
if i ever set up another indoor
greenhouse i will only be doing it
aquaponically put it that way
and the um
but other than that i really get a kick
out of growing straight into a field and
i'm mending the soil sure i'm not above
adding some
dolomite lime bone meal or back one or
molasses
any
any assortment of good organic goodies
the
but that was it so i was doing this
aquaponics and that was getting
attention of any
any of the pot raiders they would come
to the city for a visit and high times
would want to come to my house and tour
my gardens or whatever so various
various ones from andre grossman or red
rosenthal or jorge cervantes they would
all come through
there was a annie
i'm trying to think of them all but
there
there was at least four from high times
that used to come through vancouver once
a year writing an article so they'd come
and look at whatever gardens
we were doing with the latest strains
and
in the technology that we were using and
whatnot and the aquaponics system was
always quite popular they it was dubbed
guppy ponics i believe in one of the
magazines maybe red eye magazine with
nick from the uk
um
so as i was doing that place
ed rosenthal was about to go on a
consulting gig to switzerland for these
three brothers that had one of the maybe
the biggest commercial grow operation in
switzerland
and he invited me along
um and said how would you like to
co-consult on this gig i have in
switzerland right now and i said
sounds like a blast let's check this out
so we went over there and i realized how
legal legal can be
like you could go to the supermarket and
buy trays of cuttings
right beside the dusty millers geraniums
peppers and tomatoes they had trays of
white widow trays of
compulti hemp they had
they must have had 40 or 50 varieties of
cannabis just at the front door of the
grocery store
for 7.99 a clone or something like that
and they had the same little plant tags
with a picture of the bud or a picture
of the plant and on the back it would
say plant in full sun well-drained soil
heavy feeder
you know it finishes in 120 days like it
was just normal it was boring it was so
normal and and these three brothers one
of their four farms was a cloning
operation
and they were cranking out a shitload of
clones like a hundred thousand a week or
something what
i yeah and i had another partner because
they were supplying not only to the
grocery stores but to all these
commercial warehouse growers or
greenhouse growers that were buying them
20 000 at the time you know so it was
really industrial they had a couple of
delivery trucks with shelves in them
and they had robotic transplanters it
was amazing it was it used to be a
poinsettia operation and when the
when the poinsettia business in
switzerland lost its trade protection
there was a free trade agreement through
the eu that included moroccan
poinsettias and even though switzerland
wasn't part of the eu they had part they
had some trade agreements with them and
it literally knocked out the subsidies
for this poinsettia farm and the guy
this little man
nothing to do with graff
just didn't want to lose his
multi-million dollar greenhouse
investment you know so he rented it to
these three brothers and they cranked
out this clone operation
it was a marvel to behold back then and
that was 1999
and today it would still be cutting edge
so it was pretty cool to go over and
consult in that operation for two weeks
and then the weekend in the middle
they'd suggested to us
you should
check out
other parts of the country what not so
we went and explored a bit actually no i
think it was a on the next next time i
came back that i went down i thought i
was gonna be up in that area because
after the two weeks there i was like
i'm coming back i'm gonna have a farm
this is that i'm shutting down my whole
life in dc and moving here to get a farm
to grow it wide open legal like tomatoes
i'll happily pay my taxes and be a good
citizen just let me do this and i was
learning to come back and go
so i called my wife and told her to
start preparing and then i came home
here for two weeks to bc
and went back over and after the first
few days her first week up in the german
side where it's a little you know can be
drizzly and gray and
you know it's all
german food and german speaking which i
don't speak german and
it was okay i was there sitting
with my german book the first week or
two saying i should study you know
really trying to learn some german
and then the one weekend my friend said
have you ever been down to to chino i
was like no is there a scene they call
it and i said no this is it's the nicest
part of switzerland we always go there
for our holidays it's south of the yelps
it's all italian and it used to be part
of italy and the food's all italian and
it's really nice you're gonna love it
the weather's better i went down there
that weekend check it out and i called
them and say
i'm not coming back i've got all my
stuff with me we're going to have an
office in an operation down here i'm
literally the sunshine alone is
justification of me not doing this an
hour outside dessert this is the smart
place to do it it's different climate
it's a better climate and they got no
argument from them because they said oh
that'll give us an excuse to come down
there more often they love to go for
their holiday weekends
so i set up down there
and uh had a good run of it for a while
and then things turned sideways there
when
sadly
um
the the pope
came down on it in a nutshell and what
happened was most of the people were
growing there was no law it wasn't that
can that switzerland legalized cannabis
it was that it never made it illegal for
growing
it it made it illegal to use it as a
drug and to sell it there were no hash
bars like amsterdam but there were
fields of it along the side of the train
full of white widow or white shark you
name it
it was grown wide open and it was sold
wide open in pot stores they would have
go stuck to the roof in the front walls
of the stores you know it was ridiculous
and on the
sidewalk of
chiasso which is
a town there's como and chiasso como's
in italy in gyasus in switzerland and
there's a border on the main street
basically so the if you walked from the
italian side into the swiss side there
were pot leaf sandwich boards all the
way down the sidewalks for the first
three blocks probably
and people would walk over and buy
cannabis and walk back to italy and the
the italians actually had to change
their laws
because
they had the border guys were forced to
charge anybody they found with it
so they actually reduced that to they
could let anybody go with five grams or
less
without charging them so
that was their big win at the time
but then the people would just walk over
every day and buy five grams and they
would walk back and the border guys
would just
roll their eyes and wave them through
because it wasn't what are they gonna do
take five grams from fifty thousand
people every day
just not happening right
so but what happened was an
investigative reporter from rome
he came up and went into one of the
bigger shops
i won't say whose shop or whatnot but
the
but they had him
he had a hidden camera and microphone
and he went in saw that we asked to see
some samples how much a kilo is 1500 a
kilo for this frosty greenhouse grown
bud you know dutch varieties and he's
he said
oh it's such a shame that we can't get
this in rome he says i could make a
fortune if i could get this in rome at
this price and the and the shop owner
said
hey at this price we offer 24-hour free
delivery to rome
so that played on the tv
and then the you know the flood of kids
smoking dope on saint peter's square
pope was pissed off about the weed and
he called the prosecutor in the region
told her if you're a good catholic
you're gonna round these people up and
do a big inspection and even if you
can't
legally shut them down make their lives
hard and the pope came down on it that's
really what the higher-ups told us my
lawyer was friends with
with the lady or knew her from school
they were in the same law school and
i had she didn't even know about our
company but she came down on it because
my lawyer called her because we had a
problem with a thief that kept breaking
in and this thief was renowned in this
neighborhood and i'd caught him and beat
him up a couple times i was like if i
catch him again what am i going to do
like i just i say i want to stop myself
to protect them so i said
get this thief arrested we're tax paying
company we're doing everything above
board there is literally
no reason not to use them to put them
away except we didn't know
they were just
lining up the ducks to do a big round up
of the industry and when he brought us
to her attention
she's like oh i'm glad you told me about
them because we're just about to round
up 99 pot companies and we'd never heard
of this one if we didn't have a sign
all the other ones were growing and had
retail stores where they were selling
the product
not joints or hash mind you but just
bags of crafts sakety profu mate and
so she wanted to do a roundup inspection
of us we're not doing anything illegal
we have all our stuff in order because
we're a seed company and seeds are
you know unmistakably legal and they're
being exported to only legal countries
the federal
government gave us
rebates on our annual employee taxes
paid and everything
is if you were considered an export
company and 70 percent of your
production was exported ours was 97 of
our production was exported
then the swiss government gave you huge
rebates on all the taxes you paid over
the year so we were really totally above
board and not hiding anything so we were
quite uh
quite perturbed when they wanted to do
this inspection and whatnot but we let
them go ahead and they get to see
a mountain of what did you do with all
the flowers after you take the seeds out
of them we compost them where do you
compost them in the compost pile
there's literally a mountain of bud
composting with seeds sprouting out of
it like a chia pet like it's just
okay so that's what all that bud looks
like yeah so we were able to show them
everything so we didn't have any legal
troubles but i just thought if you're
gonna start being a hassle
i don't need this [ __ ] you know
so and then i was just happy to wrap it
up at that point and we had a lot of
seeds produced and stashed too so we
could
just ride off that for a while so we
shut down the company i actually sold
the facility to shanti baba when i left
and i was in spain
and then sadly they
when i had a disagreement in a friendly
disagreement so i said i'm just gonna
leave if they're gonna be dicks about it
and he said oh they're just trying to
scare away you cowboys it was his words
exactly but then a few months later they
picked them up and stuck him in a
dungeon condemned by amnesty
international it was like a 400 year old
mendrizio dungeon
so i felt super bad for the guys he's
the nicest guy i remember writing him a
letter back back in the day but i hope i
was aware of him i haven't talked to him
on a dog's age
but yeah so that was sort of how
how i got
through it in canada
in switzerland out of switzerland
and then uh starting up again now in the
tropics
yeah wow what an adventure
it's been wild and now and this year's
really going to be something because
um mexico has just come around
saint vincent jamaica we've been getting
invites to other parts of the world
throughout africa even asia
including china and thailand but i think
i am going to focus my efforts this year
predominantly between um
colombia mexico and canada
and may do
um i've been offered 20 acres in jamaica
and 20 acres in st vincent
so i'm tempted to take those up because
island time is always a good time but uh
mexico is such a hotbed of amazing
cannabis evolution different valleys in
mexico i've always been intrigued by
you know great oaxacan and the first
time i was ever in mexico
was when i was 16 which was a long time
ago
and the first mexican bud i ever saw
that wasn't brickweed in north america
the first mexican bud i saw in mexico
was gorgeous frosty purple bud from a
little mayan guy
and i was totally
blown away i was 16. it was like i was
just starting to see frosty bud you know
i was like 14 15 16. you were seeing a
lot more
brickweed from mexico or jamaica is what
we had
commonly in canada at that time and a
lot more hash and oil
because as an import scene and those
pack a little better
um
the local production wasn't really
catching on yet the people were growing
mexican or jamaican seed and it wasn't
always working out too well
so by the time people started growing
modern hybrids like skunk or northern
lights and modern at the time
it was a
real eye opener you'd be like whoa
this is what it's supposed to be like
now i get it you know
so they were like and we and this is
from here we don't have to import this
[ __ ] you know this is great so
we just had time to go to town and learn
how to do it
and me and my friends all got into
putting a few plants out and helping
each other maybe one of them would have
a place where we could keep a light and
a few mothers and start some cuts and
then we would take them out
so it was uh you know we all grew our
own but it was still a team effort but
it was fun and and you know that that
was a good time i totally
always will have found memories of that
and the people that got pinched you into
that at the time will not have such fond
memories of it because if you got caught
with one plant back then you were
getting
general time
and it still just turns my stomach to
see
the
people that think we should be in a
[ __ ] cage because we have better
taste and herbs than you know
yeah you know what i mean like i mean i
saw
the repression of this not just it was
not obviously just in canada you see the
whole world how many millions of people
are banged up for this bloody tasty herb
it just made me insane and i always
thought too that the best way we could
fight back was teaching our friends to
grow their own and teach and telling
them teach your friends to grow their
own and really get a strong culture of
that going so no matter how they
you know shut down the borders or
whatever they want to build a wall we've
got the goods [ __ ] it it doesn't
we don't need the we don't need mexican
brickweed coming up here by the bail
we've got kind bud here ourselves and
that's
satisfying but i think
to this day in the majority of countries
of the world
the entire
system the [ __ ] system
is trying to make the plant extinct
and at that point there wasn't a country
in the world that wasn't trying to make
the plant extinct
and when you think
what right does one specie have to make
another species extinct that's the
ultimate in hubris you know and i just
thought this is
just unacceptable and i'm thinking not
on my watch
i'm going to do everything i can to
preserve these plants and spread them
around and i'm not going to be alone
doing it
but it really was the people that were
committed to doing that early on
that
there was a really good feeling between
people that felt the same and you were
happy to share you know
and it wasn't a matter of hoarding and i
can see as it becomes legal people are
going to want to maintain an advantage
of having proprietary genetics and stuff
and i'll be the same too but at the time
it was really more a matter of
preservation
and that we didn't want to see this get
lost
and they were thinking how much
government spent flying around spraying
stuff and
pulling out plants with helicopters i
always thought you know
if they can afford to fly around the
country pulling plants out of corn
fields and backyards and cliffs and
you name it you're thinking what do they
need our money for they've got way too
much time and money on their hands if
they can fly around the [ __ ] world
ripping herbs out of our yards
you know or the bush like how much does
that cost that's insane and when i it
really put me against government and
that's never changed you know i've just
lost
you know any shred of respect for
governments
when they persecute cannabis users
and
i just
you know
but that's probably going to be lifelong
even when they grudgingly legalize it
but on shitty terms i'm still not
impressed you know
so i think well it's still better than
some places where you mean at least
canadians
smoking a joint in
most municipalities aren't going to have
a trouble but like in canada
it's you know changes in every
municipality right now so there's the
feds let the provinces do what they want
and the provinces tell the
municipalities you can kind of do
as you see fit as well so
in one sided town where i am
you can't smoke in public the other side
you can smoke anywhere
you can have a cigarette
so it's not a consistent open
legalization it's not a simple legal
like tomatoes legalization like i'd seen
in switzerland when i moved there and
that was the most beautiful to see
that you could grow a field of weed
as many as you wanted
without any regulation
concerning licensing or anything like
that it was the end use was the issue
and as seeds was my end use and i was
growing research crops that was fine i
didn't have a bong bar
i wasn't selling blocks of hash to you
know their kids at school
i was simply growing a field of weed
picking out my favorites
sampling it as i would
and i mean i'm a real hash smoker
it takes a lot of weed to keep a real
smoker and melt you know it's not
something you can do with four plants
which the canadian rigs currently are
permitting and in bc you can only grow
four plants if your neighbors can't see
them if your neighbors can see them you
get six months mandatory minimum or
something stupid like it's
it's so far from a rational legalization
i mean
i know it's worse than australia and i
think you know i hate to be bitching
when we've got some ground covered
but it really is one of those cases
where
it's far from good but i'm sure it's
good from afar you know
yeah i mean
you having been here and maybe a little
bit of exposure you know what do you
think is the way for australia to move
forward given we've got nothing so far
really
well all you need is nothing they don't
need to do anything other than return it
to its original state as part of our
[ __ ] planet you know
the regulations are what destroy it the
it wasn't a problem before they
regulated it you know the regulations
are where it went downhill so i'm a real
free marketeer i would be happy if i
could
pull up at the side of the road and buy
untusted buds from the hippies that live
there but if
if somebody else wants to walk into a
pharmacy and get something that's
verified organic and third-party tested
to be free of contaminants i have no
problem with that some company maybe my
own will exist to fill that need but i
don't think it has to be because let's
face it how many of us have ever ever
had verified clean bud
it's clean because it's generally clean
and and if it's contaminated you can
smell it you open a bag of weed with
mold in it you don't need a test to tell
you it's moldy you can smell that moldy
weed as soon as you open the bag you
know
there's and there's degrees of tolerance
so in canada
cfu's
colony farming units the limit with
health canada's 50 000 cfus
per gram
now i don't know and i've been asking
them repeatedly for a solid year or two
what is the tolerance
for cfu per gram
on cigars
because if there is a [ __ ]
discrepancy between what a cohiba can
have and what a reefer can have
we've got a problem
and the the canadian rigs clearly favor
tobacco health canada's absolutely shat
the bed on this one because they've made
it impossible for a gram of weed
to equal a gram of tobacco price wise
because they've made a flat tax of a
minimum a dollar on every gram
so they don't tax tobacco that way if
they did tobacco in canada would be as
expensive as it is in australia
because holy [ __ ] i was surprised to see
how expensive cigarettes were in
australia
yeah right that's the real nanny state
at play there yeah but can it but
canada's protecting the tobacco lobby by
ensuring
even it's not even a question of low thc
or anything even if i had low thc hemp
flowers they would still tax it a dollar
a gram which makes it virtually
impossible
in british columbia at least it varies
in canada a pack of cigarettes in bc is
20 in ontario it's 25 so it kind of
varies by province how many cigarettes
are in a pack i think in australia there
were 30 in a pack
but
in bc
a pack of cigarettes is
in the neighborhood of
12 to 17 dollars so it's creeping up on
you know it's somewhere between 50 cents
and a dollar a smoke but not quite a
dollar a smoke
but that's the kitten caboodle
if it was 20
hemp cigarettes
it would be
twenty dollars excise right off the top
then the price of the product plus sales
tax
so they're absolutely ensuring if i want
to sell
joints
for the same price as cigarettes they've
made it mathematically impossible
and there is no reason
to tax cannabis
uh you know a treatment of cancer for
more than the cause of it
you know it's absolutely asinine so they
just uh
the canadian government just pisses me
off endlessly as i'm sure yours does to
you yeah i mean the thing they say to us
which i'm not sure i imagine the
canadian government would do the same is
that they say that they're going to tax
more on tobacco maybe they don't do it
in canada but in australia they say
we're going to back a tax tobacco harder
because that's how we can still be able
to offer um you know universal health
care because we're covering all the the
burden on the health care system of the
smokers
that's all the tax crap my my australian
doctor father-in-law
explained to me
who is actually a lung doctor and dealt
with nothing but people dying of smoking
diseases his whole life
and he straight up told me
he said smokers cost the system less
because they die younger it's the people
that are on life support dragging it out
from 80 to 90
that have you know a bunch of little
ailments that are in to see the doctor
three times a week those cost the system
a shitload not the guys that die of
strokes at 50. you know
yeah i mean it's i'd love to see the
figures behind it but yeah i mean the
taxes
you just check it out do the math on
smokers die younger and the elder
seniors cost the system the most
yeah yeah definitely
so seniors getting old that should be
illegal
yeah okay
i mean i'd i'd love to get that one
for getting old the older you get the
more you owe
should be encouraged to die young for
the good of society
leave a pretty body
[Laughter]
something i wanted to ask about is you
referenced it earlier and you can feel
free to be a little bit ambiguous or as
specific as you like but i've noticed
there are a few company
there are definitely a few companies
that
offer like you know what looks like your
work and sometimes it's a bit ambiguous
just to see like
is this them doing a knockoff or whatnot
and so i've got one specific i'd love to
ask about is do you have any
relationship with alpine seeds because i
can see they offer a whole bunch of
never
there you go because they offer a bunch
of sweet grapefruit stuff like femmes
bxes stuff like that and it looked like
it was more on the legit and just due to
how deep of an offering they had for
sweet pink grapefruit but i guess at
this point you're just used to it you
know being the game like that
yeah this is an interesting point you
know is i have been
you know in some eyes a hothead about
this over the years but i really have a
fairly
simple understanding of the way this can
work good for everybody
when i share
or sell
genetics
like a seat let's say sweet tooth for
example if i make a cross and i call it
sweet tooth and nobody else is called
their cross sweet tooth you know that's
an original
seed cross and its original name for it
if you take those and make more seeds
with them i only ask that you give them
a new name because the seeds you have
won't be the same as mine you know so i
say i don't mind if you want to call it
dente dulce and put in bracket i made
this f2 a sweet tooth or whatever you
know
but call it something else because it
it confuses people down the line and
this is what really happened a lot with
sweet skunk too actually but the uh
that sweet is a good example
it's uh
they're all good examples i mean it's
happened with all of them as soon as
your seeds popular
people are making knockoffs of it that's
a given the uh
there's you know it's the
only seed breeding in the world that
couldn't be protected with breeders
rights
so
so it was an easy thing for unscrupulous
hacks to just start chucking pollen in
their closet and calling it a popular
name but the letdown for me was that
that the vendors would carry them i
would feel like you know what i want to
stop supplying these people that are
selling knockoffs of the seeds i work on
because i promote them i get them the
exposure
into the cup or whatever and then the
next week everybody's selling it as
their own and you're just like for
[ __ ] sakes people have some
have a little respect and have a little
dignity and [ __ ] give your seeds an
original name because they're your seeds
i'm happy if you credit them and say
where they came from
i don't really care but if you want to
i'm happy that shows respect and that's
cool and i did the same thing when i was
making seeds as i would always list to
the best of my knowledge the origins the
real origins because
we were preservationists as well we have
a duty to
carry things on accurately to the best
of our abilities considering even record
keeping was a liability when i started
growing i didn't even like keeping
pictures i had a couple polaroids
which i hopefully i still have but from
way back when
but
you didn't keep a roll of pictures of
your grow rooms because when people were
in court the the cops would say well
here we've got photos of all this crash
you've grown and that would usually
against them so you you were
covering your tracks to keep no records
so it was really a verbal
oral tradition
um
so you know
accuracy and as a breeder you know
accurate labeling is everything if
you're not doing accurate labeling it's
crazy so it just makes
you don't think i know we can't call
your switches already called these ones
you know so it's uh not just marketing
but it's really
it makes me crazy when i see people
growing
her me sweet skunk it wasn't my sweet
skunk but it was somebody's
something to get [ __ ] would self some
sweet skunk and then everybody would be
going i like sweets gonna put a turkey
it's like no it wasn't [ __ ] hard
until that [ __ ] started selling soft
ones you know
so
it really dilutes
your work when people sell their work as
yours you know or mistakenly close like
easily mistakenly close but like when
people were making i think i gave bodie
hill online for blockhead
years ago and say you know and somebody
made up they understood my point i said
if you called it square dome
and put block head back cross you'd have
no problem i'd be [ __ ] sending you
christmas cards that's super cool
but if people can mistake yours for mine
then it becomes an issue down the road
when people start getting stuff that's
not representative of what i put out and
they start blaming me for it
what are you going to think right
so
that's you know neither here nor there
you know an egregious example was it
still is uh
barney's
barney's farm in amsterdam there was no
barney's farm when they entered sweet
tooth in the cup
the sweet tooth they entered in the cup
was grown by a dutch grower who bought
the seeds in vancouver and was actually
growing sweet tooth
i was at the same cup
unloading a pile of sweet tooth as free
samples
my seed
sweet tooth was all the rage and the uh
and so the coffee shop at barney's won
the cup of sweet tooth i was very happy
for them i knew it was our sweet tooth
then a few months later they come out
with barney's farm
and a seedline called sweet tooth
that they made up you know whatever
heritage they used was totally unrelated
they didn't actually make it with the
sweet tooth from me they took
their own cross and just called the
sweet tooth and it looked nothing like
it it didn't look like the bud they
entered in the cup i mean
it was just painful to see
this blatant name ripoff you know and i
just thought that's just shameless and
uh
later they came out with shisha berry i
see they had a new release i saw online
somebody sent me a link they said here
check this out barney just released a
new strain called shishkameri
that's funny because i seem perfect for
making that mid-90s the same crop i made
the sweet tooth swiss with the same dead
and all
but it's a new strain at barney's now
and there's it looks like it should be
descended from shisha berry but their
sweet tooth doesn't even look like it's
descended from sweet tooth it's just a
blatant step on the name
and the sad thing is is now there's
gonna be
people growing out barney's sweet tooth
and thinking it's sweet tooth or sharing
it with people and they're going
hey this is a sweet tooth and they're
like this isn't very sweet you know
what's the big deal with sweet tooth
sweet juices and all that it's like
you've never even had the real sweet you
know so it's a bit painful
to see these people abusing it and
that's one thing i look forward to in
legalization is i haven't released
anything new since like 2003
and
i've been working on things for the last
few years and i'm really excited to
bring them out but i'm not going to
mention the name of them
until i can sue people's asses for
[ __ ] knocking them off you know
so that's it it's uh and that
gives
more
viability to the business of setting up
r d centers for seed
you know if if you're out there
going to the ends of the world to plant
fields and
you know do it where you can legally and
whatnot it means leaving your comfort
zone sometimes
and it's called work but when uh
people that are in their bloody
apartments making
knockoffs in their closet
and then
they just can't end up with the same
retailer i just didn't want it i won't
deal with the
the retailers that have
a bad um history
of selling knockoffs
i just pissed me off too much and i
would really like to come back out with
seeds once i can sell them direct
and cut out the middleman
and bring really good quality good value
seeds directly to people but it still
would be
you know another division
and at this point a i'm not ready to
release them
and b
i'm just gonna decide closer to the time
because i would like to have direct
retail and know that they're not getting
a switch in
bait and switch practice like even at
many of these other resellers
they might keep stuff up that looks like
it's available when it's sold out
i mean there's people pretending to be
selling seeds they bought from me 15
years ago for 15 years i know they don't
still have those seeds
but they're saying they do because when
you send them money to order them
they're going to send you a replacement
you know and say oh actually we're out
of that not not well we've been out of
that for 14 years
and it's still on the menu
you know like there's just so many
grease balls
in the business that i was like i just
can't do it like this i gotta wait until
i can do it openly illegally again
because there's just so many greasy
people to deal with and the sad thing is
now that it's legal again
and they got all these stock temps and
whatnot
it's almost greasier now i think in a
lot of ways it's actually
gone downhill i've seen the caliber of
people involved in the alleged cannabis
trade they may just be involved in the
paper trade but they consider it the
cannabis trade because they're not
actually
qualified to do anything in the cannabis
trade
so these bloody paper pushers
are really greasing up the scene and
it's it's at the point where you know
you don't even want to go to a cannabis
convention in canada
because of the greasy low life
industry players these days and
like of the first 15 companies there's a
13 of them
hired a lobby group to press for the
arrests of bud tenders and dispensaries
because people
were exercising
their power of choice and deciding that
the pot from the local unlicensed
dispensary
with several magnitudes of quality
better than what they were ordering
online from these licensed corporations
and those and not all
but most of those corporations lobbied
for their arrests
and i'm very pro-choice free market
person if people think they're getting a
better product from somebody i go nuts
buy it from them
and if they think your product sucks
they shouldn't be a captive market for
your shareholders
you know and
if you have to cage your competition to
succeed you're a piece of [ __ ]
and that's those same companies most of
them
lobbied against
field grown pot outdoor
they lobbied um
against homegrown even
because they really wanted you to have
to buy their 17 grams of over dried
flavorless bud
and most canadians that have sampled
weed from the legal producers
they've
found
i would say no more than five that
anyone likes the weed from
the rest of them people just constantly
complain and it's a dance because
they're only allowed to belong to
two lps at a time the patients belong to
the lps so they have to put their script
with two lps and that was an increase
from one
so they have they're at the mercia and
most of those lps were really get into
the business wanting to serve the wreck
market and the med market was just an
excuse for a little while
and they've left their patients hanging
as they've put the weed out to the wreck
market and the
the government was ultimately failed
in its uh attempt to create a legal
industry in a timely manner they wanted
to protect the kids and get rid of the
black market
and make sure that the supply was safe
and tested and all these noble
pursuits
but what's happened is
you know the organized crime is the
government
it is a lot of the kleptocracy we live
in with the corporations
joined at the hip with regulatory
capture with what's happening there so
you know those guys were lobbying
against outdoor growing because they
knew it would make their their flowering
facilities into white elephants
and
it that's just not the way business is
steering government we've got a problem
and it's you know ready to cage us
rather than concede losses to a better
competitor which was the black market
was kicking their ass all over the place
so you know and the legal market also
failed
to come out with edibles and extracts at
the same time as grass i understand
there was maybe some strategy
politically behind that and that they
didn't want to lose getting grass
through
on the first wave because those in
opposition were absolutely adamant
against shatter and edibles right the
children the children
and uh so i do believe there was some
strategy probably but they in all the
states that legalized it they did it all
at once you know
so it was a little disappointing to see
that uh lack of follow through here
um
yeah the other point i did i swear i had
another point
on the
no i'm enjoying it all one thing i
wanted to just quickly ask though
because it was just you mentioned it a
minute ago
if you did you know get that direct to
customer or even if it went through a
trusted middleman however you end up
doing it would that mean a return for
spice of life seeds or would it be under
a different banner
and that's a good question and it might
even be a couple of brands
you know it's a possibility there's a
good you know of course it would be fun
to bring back spice
but um sometimes a new project needs a
new name too you know so
i'm uh open to doing both even i'm just
not gonna say it because i'm away a
little ways away from that another thing
that i'm actually considering that you
just brought up is spice of life
verified genetics so i was going to
offer a three level program essentially
for producers for me to verify that
they're growing
what they say they are
b
that it's an approved quality that i
think these guys
are doing a pretty good job of this and
the third level being spice of life
brand or their breeders steve buds or
however we want to dress it up
and say these these guys are doing it
exceptionally well i would be happy to
call it my own it's [ __ ] good you
know so if i the people i meet that i
believe can do that i'm offering them a
chance the producers
that i think can do
the same quality of grass consistently
that i would
totally respect and i say i would supply
you with genetics forever i'll just keep
sending you new stuff as i want to
release it
and
there's no upfront costs but i would
like residual 10 cents a gram
on the production of breeder steve
brands let's say and i would have
consistent packaging for them to get
so that it was exactly the same from
anchorage to auckland you know and
anywhere in the world if you bought
breeder steve brown buds you knew it
came in this package with this security
feature
you know and really have us
and then have an annual party
where the licensed spice growers can get
together you can swap seeds we can have
uh
lots of fun but we'll have definitely
have an annual party for a get together
and i'll encourage this sort of network
of spice growers to share amongst
themselves
because if it's so nice when you have
favorite flavors that you know you can
reliably find a good version of it
consistently wherever you go that just
doesn't happen in cannabis yet you know
so i think that would be
you know something to achieve if we
could do it
so
that's been on my mind
more and more recently because
there's a new window for introducing
genetics into the canadian legal system
right now it used to be that they
original originally there was a window
where they could bring in
no questions asked genetics for the
first
x amount of lps
after
a certain date they closed that down and
they could only buy and sell what they'd
had brought into the system
between each other so they were all
selling each other
clones for gouging rates usually
like 50 you know here give me 15 grand
for
um the genetic and then
a clone for the 10 000 clones you need
and don't give them to anybody else in
the big contract it was all just
okay
but then they're all growing the same
thing like literally every single lp in
canada grow shishkaburi
but the sad thing is
it's a pretty pathetic selection they've
got i think i haven't seen any of the
lp's do
do a really nice job with it i've seen
it growing out like frosty and full
and i think
i don't know it's just not there's a
another shisha berry clone going around
the black market in bc making fruity
gorgeous fat frosty nugs it's it's twice
as nice a cutting as the one in the
legal system so that's kind of too bad
but at least there's a room to bring
that other one into the legal system
because
under the new cannabis act
new growers and new licensees are
allowed to bring in
genetics from wherever they want one
time so they have to declare them all
at their opening of their license you
know okay here's what i have and they
have to provide evidence that they have
you know if they've got
these hundred clones and these hundred
seeds or whatever
so there's going to be a because they
realize they need a fresh influx into
this
very closed-loop
system when they
they don't understand the importance of
of genetic diversity that's a
understatement
but
the point i was trying to make earlier
when i was pitching about the how they
could have done that licensing a little
better when they failed on the roll out
i just remembered
was they've spent
over 20 years licensing growers to grow
without ever licensing them to sell
so all they would have had to do was say
and every single one of those growers
wants to go legal but they don't want to
have to open a public company to do it
to meet a bunch of asinine expenses
and uh
just let those growers
submit pot for third party verification
if you must
and call that licensed you know hey you
passed the batch cleanliness test you're
in you get to pay taxes and they would
all jump at the possibility so while the
canadian media frets about the canadian
great canadian pot shortage
pot has never been more available or
less expensive in this country than it
is right now
you would be astounded man you can get
pounds of bud you would like
for under a thousand bucks like 600
bucks 400 bucks
but you know
yeah it's so cheap here now
it's so cheap and the people that have
are absolutely
let's call them gormless
they
they still walk into a dispensary and
pay 15 because they don't know anybody
that even grows pot or haven't tried to
themselves
but if you have a bunch of friends that
are growers
the going price
if you have any fresher growers you're
literally gonna be able to get nice pot
these days
for so cheap
whereas they go into the dispensary or
go online to order it from the ontario
cannabis store or something and they're
panned
like there's plenty of cannabis in the
15 to 17
gram range and i think there was some
that was even higher
and i'm not opposed to there being
luxury items and charging a high price
for stuff that's fine but it shouldn't
they shouldn't uh you know there's no
ceiling on price but they put a on
upwards price but they put a ceiling on
downwards price you know
so you can't go through the floor
and make something actually really cheap
like if i could sell a pack of
pre-rolled joints that were a gram each
same as a pack of cigarettes
for five dollars less than a pack of
cigarettes or even a dollar less than a
pack of cigarettes all in
tell me that wouldn't be appealing
to many smokers who are very price
conscious they would say boy oh boy i
can smoke that nice organic grass
cheaper than i can smoke cigarettes
would that encourage people to smoke
more nice organic grass rather than
cigarettes i think you would
call me crazy but i think people are
very sensitive and if they're given the
option to enjoy bud and i know there's
no reason we can't grow
fat frosty full ripe buds
and have them like cobs of corn
and there should be no reason you can
drive down the highway pull over at the
side of the road and talk to the farmer
and
pick out a pick out buds from all the
different bins you like you know we're
hanging up hanging up there but they can
be like cobs of corn it doesn't have to
be expensive you could have 12 big one
ounce cobs for two bucks as long as you
can grow it in the wide open like that
yeah i was doing the math on doing an
outdoor in canada
um
and
in southwestern ontario only because bc
can't grow good outdoor but it can grow
good outdoor but in some places but it
can't grow great outdoor bud the only
place in canada that you can grow great
outdoor bud is in southwestern ontario
and it's the same
latitude as northern cal and southern
oregon 42 degrees
the the reason that makes a big
difference and people
you know would know
in almost any agriculture whether it was
grapes or cherries or peaches
the harvest starts down south and the
harvest moves north
so they harvest their wine in california
in august and in bc maybe in october you
know
oregon and washington in between so the
the harvest creeps north now part of the
reason for this it's the same with grass
is
that
grass most grass or not all but there's
exceptions to every rule but most of the
stuff we grow these days is photo
sensitive varieties so it stays in veg
when the days are long it's triggered to
flower when the days are short hence 18
and 12 typically inside and 12 12 for
flowering you know
and
the thing is
in the northern latitudes or the higher
latitudes because for your case they'd
be southern latitudes but the higher
latitudes have such a long day in the
middle of the summer
that it seems to take the plant longer
to snap out of veg and go into flowering
so say where i live here is like
you get days that are 18 and a half
hours of daylight whereas 10 degrees
further south like in southern ontario
they might only get 16 days hours of
daylight in the longest days
so those plants that have never got to
18 and a half hours they've only got the
16 hours it's less of a leap for them
to go into flower
so in bc
10 degrees further north i find the same
plants going into flowers slower so by
the time they do the light is getting
weaker
much and much
quickly you know the light is getting
weaker every week so the buds that are
finishing under that weak light don't
look as good there maybe a little
leafier and not as full
whereas in southern ontario
i would pick the same plant four weeks
earlier
and it would be way riper you know so
it's really something to see the
difference between those two zones and i
think
once more people realize that people out
west have no clue and when people do
realize the difference in quality
i think uh you're gonna see
indoor places going out of business in
three to five years it's really just how
however long it takes them to license
enough outdoor back in southwestern
ontario if they never license enough the
indoors will still be in business but if
they license enough indoors will be over
because we could have full melt dry sift
for the price of flour
you know versus
growing flowers indoors you know this is
silly we don't grow coffee in canada in
greenhouses we buy it from where coffee
grows well we don't same with sugar you
know we do great maple syrup but we
don't try and do cane sugar up here
so there's there's cannabis that works
here and that's and most of that is
really just going to work best in
southwestern ontario so with the outdoor
market my plan as i come back in the
circle
is to release 10
ounces
untrimmed
before tax
and just tops so all the smaller buds
would go for extract
and then just the tops from the end of
the very top and then the tops of the
top ring of branches those tops
at ten dollars an ounce
that's cheaper than what most lp seem to
be selling grams for these days they're
very in the neighborhood you know i
don't know the actual stats on whatever
these are selling grams for because i
don't buy grams when i don't buy from
lp's so
i'm not saying i wouldn't try a few
there's
i would say two of them whose spot
looked worth trying
but uh and there were some positive
reviews and then there's another three
where i'd see some positive reviews but
they didn't look all that good and i
just thought they probably just have
lower standards than i do
but i'm not saying they're all bad
because it looks like there's a couple
of decent ones and that i'll give them
that the
but the outdoor will make them all
irrelevant because the outdoor can grow
back there
is this good or better than any indoor
as long as it's done well you can still
screw it up outside i'm not saying
everybody's outdoor in ontario is better
than all indoors that's not what i'm
saying but you know what you're doing
you can grow better but outdoors there
than you can indoors and
in a good year too you could have a crap
here but you know there's always
exceptions to the rule but for my money
i'm
backing outdoor southwestern ontario for
both flowers and extracts and i totally
think i can do it at such a fraction of
the cost
and by the math i did a few years ago
and i can't remember exactly how i came
to the number but i had estimated that
the country consumes five to six
thousand acres worth
considering
flower extract edibles you know all
all sectors
that five or six thousand acres would
saturate the market in canada
and it's
it's a lot less
than uh
some people think but that's a lot 5 000
acres of grass
and
you know with the columbia project i'm
looking at going a lot more than that
i'm starting out with less than that of
course but once i've acclimatized things
i want to work with for the ends i want
to achieve
i was really my plan is to get it up and
i will leave it alone once i can get it
planting harvesting and processing two
square kilometers a day
that's my goal for
the equatorial project because i want to
come out with vitamin thc and vitamin
cbt and vitamin cbn and have these
things made so inexpensively
that people stop looking at them as
you know a rare drug for the rich
and just start looking at it
as a necessity for everyday people and
all walks of life at any price point i
want i want to make it as ubiquitous as
you know aspirin so that you see
you can get a reliable your aspirin is
aspirin whether you get it in sydney or
stockholm it looks the same it tastes
the same it is the same right and it's
and it's affordable the poor people
they don't say uh some days they might
but
overall
many people can afford aspirin
and
i don't think you should have to be rich
to deserve aspirin
you know that's just it shouldn't be for
the top 10
of the wealthy world
it should be for everybody and
and cannabis always has been from the
beginning of time it's been the poor
man's herb it's been the herba kings as
well and the kings maybe got the
dragon's tears pressed from the edges of
their hatches
but they and the poor people might be
boiling stalks
of low-grade
plants
but it's been there for everybody and in
the middle east in asia in africa you
name it cannabis has been there for
human history for so bloody long
and the absolute goal of politicians
that feel they have a right to
to
persecute us for its use when it's one
of the basic human foods you know it's
it's everything
it's
you know i don't have to tell you people
if you're listening to this show you're
in the pot i know that
and if you've listened this long you
might be as crazy as me
well one thing i wanted to quickly ask
is you've made it pretty obvious that
you're into growing organically but i
wanted to ask what is your opinion on
hydroponic and salt grown weed in
general do you think it can ever compare
you know what i've i've certainly done
it all and
and my best hydro i did uh
you know
totally enjoy it and unleash the hell of
it but it was using really clean pure
nutrients too the most of the bottled
nuts that come with coloring and all
that
i generally find that there's even with
a two weeks of people flushing them in
that i still find they maybe by the end
of the joint jointer halfway they start
to get this plasticky smell almost
there's just something i don't like
about it
whereas and i'm not saying all organic
grass is done well either because it can
be over fed organic and not burned too
you know there's not a guarantee of
quality that it's organic
but i never find the most exciting weed
not to be organic let's put it that way
and i think you can grow fantastic hydro
with with if especially if you're mixing
your own salts and whatnot and you're
really cognizant of
leeching them for a totally sweet fade
that they are burning really smooth and
you get a true varietal flavor of each
variety you're growing because there's
no terroir and that's fine if you want
that pure varietal flavor water is a
great way to go i like it with the
aquaponics because i find
it it's still that clean
but a little bit more life to it seems
to bring out
more flavor
and more
layers even uh more subtleties
it's
there was a study a long time ago i
remember reading in tom alexander's
growing edge he was the guy that
published sense amelia tips until he got
busted and since amelia tips really put
me on the organic path for my second the
second time i ever grew hot first time i
grew up i read a book like a grower's
guide or something and then
by that winter before the next spring
i'd found
since emilia tips in like used magazines
at the head store somewhere by them all
and you'd read all these great blends
from these old oregon hippies and that
and be like oh i gotta up my game and i
could be adding a lot more organic
components to the soil and what it came
to mean to me was
that if i
fed
one or two things to the plant
it was very apparent in the smell and
taste of the grass
if i used a little bit of a lot of
things
none of them dominated the smell or
taste of the plant now case in point
plant
is what it eats it sucks up what it eats
and some people will
be skeptical of that and that's that's
fine my experience is it's [ __ ]
obvious if your nose works because i had
a friend
the guy i was just meeting at the time
actually been we're friends for a long
time since but
he came into my apartment
and to show me a half pound of weed
and
he was a friend of a friend and he came
in
and before he even pulled the bag out of
his backpack
i said do you grow with fish
and he said
what i said refrigerator i said do you
use fish emulsion
because one of my friends
at home was growing with straight fish
emulsion and his weed smelled like the
shitty ass bottle of fish emulsion it
totally came through in the smell of the
weed but you smoked it and so i asked
this guy because i it just smelled like
my buddy's weed because i could smell
weed when he came in but i could smell
weed with fish
and not live fish but dead fish and i
said this to him right as he was
reaching in his bag to pull out the half
pound he's pulling out the half pound
and his eyes go wide he says and he goes
kind of white he's like
why did you say that and i said i got a
friend that grows with fish emulsion his
weed smells just like yours and he says
i put a fish in every
hole you know he was just he was just
he's like nobody ever you know people
just have to go wow that's beautiful
that's great grass
you're the only person that ever said
your weed's fishy you know and he
couldn't believe it so we hit because
you know it was just an honest remark it
wasn't wasn't trying to be a dick i was
just being honest about it you know and
uh
but it's so funny the the way the plant
really carries whatever it's like when
you stick celery and red dye in your
soda you'll turn red you think of the
grass the same way is it will pick up
you know it's built out of what's
underneath it right it's not just built
out of thin air
so the
another time the
from the first year i grew
i had a plant that i used
um a bag with steer manure
and that steer manure
wasn't composted that long and later
that winter when i was reading about
how well composted it had to be and it
couldn't smell still and it should break
up really soft and it shouldn't be wet
and sticky and smell and i thought all
the [ __ ] i used was wet and sticky and
smelled but i didn't even think about it
until a non-smoker
at my girlfriend's house she had
roommates non-smoker came into the room
and said
what is with that weed you're smoking it
smells like manure
and they were dead serious and they were
pissed
and i thought i was funny because i was
naked i just laughed but i went and had
a shower or the next morning or
something had a shower and when i walked
back into the room it hit me because i
just smoked a joint in there and my once
i had a shower and cleaned out walked
back in the room
he's right it totally smells like manure
and i realized that was because that
wasn't composted well enough that manure
so then i got really adamant about
finding the oldest compost i could find
and really becoming a bit of a compost
nub
and that made
that next year that pot that i grew the
second year having done my homework
after that first year
it was so good i measure everything i
see to this day against it you know and
it was just so [ __ ] good and it was
one of the things in about 17 things
mixed in the hole but one of them was a
generous helpings of 100 year old
chicken compost from a chicken shed that
just got torn down and had been exposed
to the it was just like ground
soft sand almost it was really we had no
smell it was kind of spongy and then
hundred years they had a chicken coop
there they hadn't had chickens in it for
about 10 years and tore it down and just
been rained on
for a couple years and it was so good
they were really really exceptional buds
that i'll never ever forget
the year before the first year i ever
grew
i
had already done a bit more homework
than my friends locally
and one of them
his parents were okay they lived in the
country and they said you can start some
here let's take them away to plant them
so he said okay
so i had a soukretz tin with 2 000 seeds
from jamaican weed i used to get
in cans from montreal from jamaican guys
there and
i had those 2000 seeds and i i went and
planted them in trays and we
transplanted them into little four inch
pots and we left them like that and then
after once the time they were kind of
2000 knee highs then his mom started
going that's a lot of little plants i
want you to start getting those out of
here
and so the one day i popped over to go
grab one because they were just starting
to sex
and there was one
that was really starting to
show like a little cluster of pistols on
top and it was just the furthest ahead
of anything in the female department and
i i just said i'm just going to take one
you guys can have the rest of them and i
took that one plant and dug a hole
and planted it at the creek near my
house and that was the first plant i
ever grew and that was from jamaican
and
it was the only one of two thousand
seeds probably that even finished
the rest of them probably wouldn't
finish in canada but that one just
happened to be a real early one a
relatively early one and i've never
smelled or tasted it again
until a couple years ago
when i first went to columbia and
i visited some plants in a friend's
place near bogota and greenhouses but
the very then i flew
to uh rizzarelda
um
it's another department
and that's a area that's known for punta
rojo so i thought
oh i'm gonna see some punta rojo
visiting farms in the hills here the
first farm we showed up at
i saw this plant across the yard it was
a little shorter than the one i had but
it's always 12 hours there and i knew it
was the same flat from it from across
the yard before i could even smell it i
said oh my god that looks like the it's
the same structure that first plant i
ever grew and same coloring in that and
i got closer
and it totally was and i could rub it
and smell it and they're just like
full circle you know i never smelled
that i got whiffs of it in things but i
never smelled that plant again
until i went to colombia and it totally
closed the circle for me because it was
like
holy [ __ ] that's the first bud i ever
grew is punta rojo and of course lots of
colombian seed ended up going through
jamaica
so there's no doubt in my mind that that
first columbian stuff i had it may not
have been pure
may have been
mixed with other colombian things or
jamaican things but it may not have been
it could have been
pure food but it really that one
expression at least
it blew my mind so it was really fun to
to see that and and again as you get
older
it's not always about you know
you only want the latest and greatest
you get nostalgic for flavors you miss
you know
and hey it's not the strongest one punta
robo it doesn't doesn't put the hurt on
anybody just a nice light social smoke
light buzz
but very pleasant tasting and definitely
you know you get stoned from it
you just maybe don't get as stoned from
it as you might from something else
that's 30 thc
but then again it's a question of degree
because me with that 30 thc people are
smoking pinners of
and
not the same bats or smoke into that
other one either six and one half a
dozen and the other you're still high
everybody's happy
yeah for sure it's it's hard to compare
right i just want to quickly jump back
though too the genesis story behind
sweet tooth because i remember when we
were able to hang out you told me and i
was like man that's such a cool story i
need to get you to tell that one again
specifically the the blueberry mail you
were using
yeah so the
so
of the
1500 plants i had in my backyard that
summer
and
i am going to say that was 1996 and it's
a bit fuzzy back then but i do believe
it was 1996 that summer
that i
did this big selection in the backyard
and
of this uh
dj short blueberry seed that mark henry
had given me
i think i had five seeds or six seeds or
something and
the females were no great shakes i never
even kept one but the
the
male
there was one male
that had a hard purple top it looked
like a cluster of dark grapes pointing
up
really tight balls
but the amazing thing about it was it
had chromatic resin as they shawn like
all bearings with a metallic chromatic
look to them they weren't clear white
amber cloudy they were ball bearings
they were just shiny metal balls and
i've never seen that before and i don't
think i've seen it since
to see that
real real metal sheen on those strikes
and so that plant and and visually it
was stunning with the green leaves
dark purple flowers metallic resin
glistening all over it i've never seen
that present on the mail either
and when you squeezed it
you know it reeked of blueberry jam
it smelled so good of blueberry jam
and
i had one of my three grow rooms in my
basement
set up that i wanted to seed so i was
just gonna take the best male from the
backyard that summer and go down and
pollinate those and that's the one i
chose and that the top bud of that plant
i actually dried
with my coffee cups in the kitchen
and then i smoked it in little bits in
my bong because it was delicious it was
like liquid blueberry pie filling with
every long hit it was the most delicious
male i don't think i've even smoked
other males that male it was like
i'm smoking the top
and i left the side branches
to take took into the room in the
basement that had plants
four weeks in or something that were
and that male went off a week or two
later
and pollinated that room so though that
male was responsible for fathering sweet
tooth
shishkameri blue domino
plum bud
there was a fifth one but i can't
remember
those four for sure
and uh but sadly i didn't rejuvenate the
male and keep it because i was really
thinking of it at the time more as a
backboard
because the other ones i wanted
to
preserve
those plants
and make
that cross to the the mothers
to really try and stabilize
a plant
representative of grapefruit for example
you know and every i would try it with a
different
outcross
before i did the back cross to see which
ones i could
get to making basically a pure sweeping
grapefruit essentially that was three
two three that was a cubed version of it
so
once you back cross it
twice you square it the third time
you've cubed it and assuming the mother
you're working with to begin with is
somewhat stable by the time you've cubed
it you've got a pretty good
representation of it it's not exactly
the same but
it's uh gonna fool most people even
myself sometimes i'm sure i would find
uh sweet two threes that would be
absolute ringers for grapefruit but most
of them were pretty much
pretty much like grapefruit
and any recessives you got were obvious
because of the blue you know so
it was a fun one to do that with
um
and i remember the first time i met dave
watson he came up to me at the cup and
he asked me he said you read sweet 2 3
to be homozygous he says i lurk on
overgrown cannabis rolled those boards
he says i see what's going on but i
don't post or talk to anybody but he
says i've been watching and i see that
you made a homozygous strain and until
that one the only other homozygous
stream was skunk number one he says why
did you do it
and i said
everybody's got a plant
that they want to get reliable seeds
from but they can't because they've only
got this mother so i want to give them a
reliable backboard that they can make a
cross with
and then
weed out of the cur the following
generations you know because they can
see okay
this one looks like my
you know muslim bimbi not like sweet
tooth so i'm gonna take keep taking the
ones that look like them all in bimbi
and after a couple generations they'll
have weeded the sweet tooth out if they
want you know but they'll have
reliable seeds of their mullen bimbi
relatively speaking right
so i just wanted to put something out
stable of course it's easy to knock off
stable seeds they're stable but you and
that's why most seed companies of all
stripes whether they do corn or tomatoes
or grass don't release stable seeds
because a they're a lot of work and b by
the time you get there anybody can copy
them but for me it was like i wanted to
put that into the commons
and have people able to use it
you know to do their original work with
you know
yeah it wasn't
so when i see people that are
just making knockoffs of it i'm like
you're missing the point you know this
is useful genetics for you to do more
than just knockoffs with you know
so
i think a lot of people would realize
that you know the this was segueing into
kind of like how you had that joint
experience with dj short and most
notably producing the blue satellite
which has gone on to have a huge cult
following what was your recollection of
that experience oh that was really fun
yes so actually the first blueberry i
ever grew out was that mail
and while it was in flower
dj was visiting vancouver and came over
to my house and actually uh was able to
see it in person and he was like you got
a sweet one there and of course he
looked a little a little put out like i
was banging his daughter or something
but
he was okay with it you know he was uh
he was okay with it it was fun and uh
there was some mutual respect here i'm
not just going to make blueberry
knockoffs that's not what i'm trying to
do here right so i knew you'd appreciate
what i was doing and
and we both
you know felt the same way and i've seen
this with other breeders as they say
why'd you get into breeding cannabis you
think we just want to make it easier for
everybody to grow really good stuff
because we all believe that there's a
conscious evolution
waiting to happen in humanity and it's
just a question of getting enough tasty
joints into enough hands that people
that
you know
it wouldn't normally uh
break out of the mold might be tempted
to by something that just smells
incredible they taste incredible and it
shatters their
their preconceived notions of
the world around us but so what happened
was
even we both believed in this potential
evolution of consciousness through
better cannabis for the masses
and when i got over to switzerland and
got set up and
i was doing it over there
he got in touch with me and said
hey i really love what you're doing i'd
like to come for a visit and discuss
some
some business making a deal i said sure
come on over so
him and his darling wife came over and
stayed at my place for bed and had a
look what we're doing
and said he brought a contract with me
for me to sign
and
said he um
[Music]
that we should do some releases together
for him to get royalties off of
that's awesome so i said that's awesome
i'm honored honored that you're happy to
do that with me you know so he sent me
over or brought with him at the time i
can't remember but he got about a number
of seeds into my hand including
this unreleased berry sativa line
um the only one he'd released was his
blueberry indica line so the
blueberry sativa was really interesting
one they had the squiggly leaves that we
think of as tmv as lots of blueberry
does um whether it's dmv or not who
knows but the
but there was that one and there so
there's the blueberry sativa there was
the
moonshine
her blue moon shined
um
an old flow
and
maybe a blue velvet i but i might have
just been the moonshine the blueberry
sativa in the old flow and those were
kind of his main
three old work lines
of seed that was old and not getting any
better
and needed to be grown out
to do stuff with
so he
i said okay let me check them out and i
grew them out
and of the flow
there was the most diversity in the flow
but my very favorites weren't the ones
with the nice yielding buds but they
were this one with little popcorn nugs
and it really
totally smelled like chocolatey nepalese
hash it totally had that nepalese hash
aroma to it and the nugs were no bigger
than popcorn there was no
top bud to speak of
the top bud you could see if you look
straight down on it you'd see a couple
of calyxes
and a cluster of leaves curling upwards
like a rose
and from the side the bottom of those
leaves were all
mauve
and
the insides would be dark green
but it really looked like a rose and it
smelled like chocolatey hash
and i called it rosebud
and i hid it
with a sweet the same
male as sweet 2 3 if i believe
bx 2 bx2p1 the
black rosebud was my favorite flavor
of any i called that uh
that stuff we did together i named it
the joint project
so i said okay we'll do the joint
project and i thought well i'll do that
with dj maybe i'll do that with some
other breeders and sell them under my
joint project
online
so the blueberry sativa
only
two of them popped
and they were both females so there was
no male to use again unfortunately would
have been nice
and because we could have kept something
going with that but i used those two
females
um both in a room with sweet tooth three
pollinations
and in a room with shisha berry tree
pollination and made uh
blue satellite one and two is how it
started out and then
there were subsequent generations of
each of those
but not very long and and relatively
small amounts they never did a really
big production of those seeds
so they were always just
a small section of an indoor room but
never a whole green sweet two three i
made
in a whole greenhouse the same with
louis legends ultimate indica
and some blockhead i made some seeds in
really large amounts once i knew these
crosses work out really well
we should make a shitload you know so
then i would do
literally like 100 kilos of seed or
something of the line if i really liked
it and then
if i was still just in the early stages
of it i'd consider it dating kind of
like not gonna marry her just yet but
we're gonna go out again
and uh
i would spread them around the spice
testers and that too and see see what
the what happened but the blue
satellites were well received and they
were
not everybody loved them and there was a
lot of variation in all dj stuff you
know and he'd tell you himself there's
lots of variation
he never worked
he is the absolute opposite of dave with
skunk number one his skunk number one
was bred to be homozygous the blueberry
was made
to maintain populations
so it was always a population seeding
that he'd been doing and never trying to
dial it into one pheno so that's like
when you the two blue satellites were
quite comparable one was a little bit
sturdier and uh nicer than the other one
but the flow
there was
really quite a few distinct phenos it
was uh
like looking at an adventure mix almost
which was always popular to me that
rosebud stole the show and the
moonshine
was neat we did the same cross with the
moonshine with the
sweet tooth bx-2p1 and that was
moonshine rocket fuel the moonshine
rocket fuel was out for a little while
too but again it was kind of a one-hit
wonder
i think it got bought up by like one of
our customers so it was maybe only
available through heaven's stairway or
one of the retailers
so it wasn't widely represented like
just strawberry three or three two three
those ones got to every country they
were selling seeds in large volumes so i
mean there was so much shishkambari in
spain you still see very in spain
you know in places it was funny i had
when i had the blue domino
in that first crop
i had a customer
in ottawa
that uh really liked it early
and sort of was one of the first to
throw out the four and said oh i really
like this blue domino so he bought the
rest of it and i never made another big
batch of blue domino it was just that
first f1
and
he bought the whole i might have made
enough too but he bought the whole batch
of whatever
domino blue domino was out so it was
only available from this store in ottawa
so people in other parts didn't know it
at all but if i went to ottawa i'd seen
like 20 different growers with it and
just blow my mind to
see how regionalized some of those
strains were just because they weren't
released widely
so it would have been interesting if
there was more of it to see but if it
stood the test of time but it may have
stood the test of time around ottawa but
nobody in vancouver's growing any blue
domino i'm sure because it was all sold
in ontario
yeah well something along that note
which has been of interest to me is i've
always wondered what was the land race
or maybe not land race but the afghani
that you used that went into shishkebari
like and because i think i read
somewhere that you actually line worked
it for a bit or is that not true
yes it did it was actually the only
um
line of only seed lines that i released
with two mothers
so
i would usually well every other one i
did was one mother and one female you
know
whereas with the shishkaburi i had
two
workhorse
afghans one probably an afghan hybrid
but
very much on the afghan side
but you see different afghans some have
a little more slender leaves some have
the real webby ones and then there's
some that are just kind of thick medium
most of them are kind of the thick
medium
um
they tend to be thicker leaves and
thicker plants
and the leaves are even thicker they're
not a thin leaf they're a thick leaf
like cardboard
but they're chunky plants they form the
basis of all indoor growing genetics and
they add yield to anything that they're
crossed with typically so
afghanis are
you know
they are to indoor what white is the
rice you know it's like
the uh there is a red line and yellow
line the red line had red petioles on
the leaves
it was a little more rounded top and
chunkier bud but a little stouter
and the yellow line
was quick to yellow as it got it went in
to fade faster so it got very yellow as
it was getting ripe and it was pointier
and it was a little taller and frostier
but still had that real
raw
mulching leaf afghan aroma and both the
red and yellow were fantastic hash
producers so for i was really into
screening hash
when you grow seed crops you get a lot
of hash as i the one thing about growing
a seed production crop that i love is i
get to smoke every resin gland i grow
and still have a commercial crop without
selling a single resin gland you know
i get spoiled with hash and collecting
it over time i know some people think
hash from seeded plants isn't as good i
know other peoples that think it's
better
it's personal preference i don't think
it really matters anybody nobody
complained that hit that melty bubble
but the
but those plants have really large resin
plants and crossing them both at the
same time with that blueberry
you know in a good
chunk chunky rose of it if i had maybe
five types of weed or six types of wheat
in that room for that pollination so
there was a substantial amount of it
um
on that f1 at least and then it was only
more after that
they were so popular
the uh
the blueberry really elevated it so you
were still getting a big fat chunky
frosty bud
but you would get
some more fruit in it and some more
color like instead of just being
all the same all of the green color it
would have streaks of purple
and instead of just smelling like
mulching leaves it smelled like
a little subwa perhaps but very much
fruity
you know so it was totally elevated it
and still was a good commercial option
and the thing that any seed producer of
less times have changed but back then
most growers really only interested in
commercial seed the guys that were
growing for their head were they were
still out there but they were in the
minority so i prefer to breed stuff that
tasted fantastic or had a nice uplifting
kick
but most people really concerned about
yield and time and it's and bag appeal
because they're commercial growers so
any seed company at the time realized
that the market was for commercial seed
and shishka berry every year would
probably be 80 of the sales
because it was the top yielding plan and
people want the big heavy thing you know
and
it to me it was not my favorite flavor
of grass but it was one of my favorites
for making hash
it would yield maybe three times the
hash of the same amount of sweet tooth
trim
wow
and the glands would stack up in higher
screens like you have a 220 work bag
and then you got your 190 and 160 and
everything underneath it the 190 would
melt it would bubble big shiny bubbles
like it was the resin glands were
humongous on that i've never seen bigger
resin glands than any other cannabis
actually so i did the red and yellow
lines the f ones
i kept them going and
crossed them back together along the way
and uh
shishka berry three
which was released from switzerland
was a bit of a representation of
all three parents in one
yeah okay so it's interesting you
touched on that consumer point because
when i was looking through the spice of
life catalogue so to speak
i like something that caught my eye was
donk and the reason why was because of
the fact that like one of the parents
was like kind of more of a cash cropper
type of thing from the description was
that your attempt to kind of offer a
more commercial strain
yeah the you know what that was uh
there was a couple of spice releases
over the years very few but a couple
that were done by a friend of mine you
know or different friends so one early
on i had a friend
that did one
[Music]
call it was a cross of mighty might and
heavy hammer and we called it heavy
hummer so that was the first one that
was just lucida i hadn't grown but i
left out under my catalog because it was
from one of my best friends and i said
yeah that's pretty cool let's put it out
there because he wasn't going to start a
seed company or anything and then the
donk was sort of the same thing it was a
friend i had in the kootenais and i was
out visiting him and he was like hey i
just crossed this he's like what do you
think i was like i was like you know
what people love giant buds so let's say
we put it out let's do it so that was
one that i didn't read but i released
okay cool do you ever did you ever
consider trying to make a strain purely
to suit the consumer market or you're
just like look if something ends up
yielding big that's cool
well
the consumer
were the ones buying the big stuff from
the growers so the the home growers that
cared a lot less
they might buy something like rosebud
now i put i don't remember exactly but i
figure shishkaburi was listed and the
grams per meter grams per watt kind of
thing a little bit you know on the
higher side
sweet tooth in the middle and most of
them in the middle whether it was the
blue domino or blockhead or other things
the
but the rosebud
i think i put on a
dismal for yield
instead of you know heavy medium-heavy
medium i put dismal beside yield on the
description of it
and people would say what does dismal
mean i say
maybe 50 grams of square meters 70 grams
a square meter it's like oh my god
that's nothing why would i grow that i
taste it you know
if you're lucky enough to smoke vagina
but you're like oh [ __ ] i would grow
that for the rest of my life just for
myself nobody's ever gonna become that
to sell until it's wide open legal and
they can afford the economy of scale but
a lot of the best tasting grass is the
worst yielding grass
and that doesn't compute with the indoor
grower in a prohibition scenario because
they don't have the luxury of finding
the luxury buyers that will pay extra to
have something exotic
they have to have something
you know good looking generic bud it's
got to be fat frosty and green that's
the basic parameters of what they need
to sell
they can't advertise it in
you know rich and famous magazines so
that arnold schwarzenegger can buy a
thousand dollar grams of it
because it's that mark is not there yet
when it's wide open legal and it can be
like an auction for domain roman econ
tea
like how many people get to drink a
bottle of romani domain romani conte not
very many you know they don't make a lot
of wine and as a result your supply and
demand dictates that that [ __ ] is
expensive and it's a luxury good you
know
yep without a doubt like that too where
you think geez there's only x amount of
this bud now the people that think you
can grow high quality bud
indoors
are missing the point it's like they
think you can make high quality wine out
of wine kits
it's not high quality you you might be
okay with it but that doesn't mean it's
actually high quality
you know
it's um
there's more to it than just
consistency
the best tastiest things like that
have a year on it
because they're not consistent year to
year
they're a product of that year
and the year the
the vintage of the harvest is
it's as important to outdoor
you know as the variety you're growing
let alone who was growing it or taking
care of it and
who was making sure it was cured well
and dried well that year you know
like the same vineyard in france maybe
there for the last 200 years making
fantastic first growth in bordeaux that
the winemakers changed every 20 years
over that time you know the vineyard's
still this famous thing it's not the
winemaker at that point it's that land
that land
expresses
the that variety the best
and that becomes
recognized with time
and some of that time
is uh you know we're we're at a true
renaissance in cannabis right now it
really is a mind-blowing time if you're
a cannabis lover to be alive like i've i
can remember when i was sort of started
campaigning for it as it were when i was
like 14
15 in high school debates or whatnot and
just talking to everybody well cannabis
has to be legal it's just not fair it's
a verb it doesn't make sense it's part
of the planet like it just struck me as
evil and wrong from a very young age and
i never wasted a day not talking about
it with people
but to think
nowadays it blows my mind i was walking
into dispensaries
like a year or two ago and i'd see
you know electric joints like pre-filled
disposable oil pens with sweet tooth in
them and you just like
if you had told me that in 96
you know i would have believed i always
believed cannabis would be legal but if
you had told me i'm gonna walk into
stores one day and people that don't
know me are gonna try selling me pen
electric joints full of sweet tooth oil
i'm just gonna be tickled pink you know
i couldn't believe it it was just
like holy [ __ ] this is
it's a whole new paradigm
yeah totally
something that has come up in the last
few episodes which you just touched on
is
the idea of terroir and more importantly
how can we in this modern age establish
new appellations for cannabis what is
your thoughts on that
well they're gonna it's a excellent
question and
i think it is certainly an
underappreciated aspect of is part of
cannabis that seems obvious to me but i
know plenty of people you know they're
still
learning their varieties and they would
rather have that well leeched hydro and
taste of pure varietal character
absolutely got no problem with that the
but the thing that is
increased in the plant
is in the territory
it really brings out
more
and it adds something to it
in a good way or a bad way you know so
some places don't have a great tarot
wire for grass some places do and some
they're just different
and places with limestone and with a lot
of lime in the soil tend to give you
limier green buds that are sweeter
limestone sweetens grass is sweetened
soil people that's how they describe it
sweetening soil limestone sweetened soil
and you see it sweetens grass
the different ph affects the grass
a lot of people will turn it down at the
end in the hydro system so the plant
shuts down and stops taking up so much
nutrient speech to their own there's
lots of ways to what you're trying to
whatever you're trying to do but
i
i know between ontario and bc grass the
same varieties i can generally taste
which province it's from even if it's
grown in rockwool
and that's to do with the water not the
soil
the um
but you know if you think of a one
design race is a good competition of
the captain's skills or the skipper
skills they're all racing the exact same
little sailboat
and
there's no
technical advantage it's really just the
experience and skill
of the captain and with a clone it i
would like to see competitions like this
whereby
grower gets the same clone
and they might be in different scenarios
but they're all going to bring you back
a different bud as a result
and if you take the same clone say you
took a clone of your favorite mullen
bimby madness and you planted that
in one part of jamaica another part of
jamaica another part of mexico
somewhere in california somewhere in
oregon somewhere in ontario i guarantee
you
you're gonna be able to tell the
difference you may not know where
they're from but so you're going to be
able to say wow this one really tastes
different than this one
often i find it is even clay like if
there's some clay in the soil you can
taste the clay
in the herb
and it is apparent and you know this
brings me back to
uh another sesh with dj short early on
maybe the second or third time i met him
and the first time i'd smoked his bud
was that the milk veg at a cannabis cup
in amsterdam
and he'd brought or sent over
a few a few of his buds from his
backyard
and when we were smoking a joint of his
flow and it was the first time i'd ever
smoked a joint to flow
and he rolled this joint up and passed
it to me and
i took one puff of it
or maybe even on the dry tote maybe
before i took a puff of it
um he might remember if somebody wants
to ask
i had the profit whether it was dry or
lit
and i said
it tastes like beets
and he just looked at me and smiled and
he says i grew that in my beats
wow
you know
it comes through whatever you're putting
it in comes through so that flow had the
terroir of beets because it was touching
beets it was
coexisting with them and feeding off of
them potentially you know it was wrapped
around the beets
and it came through in the mud and it
was the first tasting note i gave him
was hey it tastes like beets and and
it did for a very good reason so he was
quite
um surprised but and he pulled out his
flavor wheel had been developing and
we realized
we were
both really into taste
we both we both loved good cannabis
flavors and he's a really zen man and i
always enjoyed his company i haven't
talked to him in a dog's age
it wouldn't hurt
um yeah that's interesting i mean if
people haven't picked on it picked up on
it thus far
clearly a bit of a wine connoisseur
what was it that uh inspired you to get
into wine and what's your favorite type
well wine is a
parallel universe to cannabis they're
both
sort of mild flavorful intoxicants
and
that enhance everyday life you know i i
enjoy wine as much as i enjoy cannabis
probably are damn close
and i wouldn't really say i have a
favorite type but i like wine that's
clean not dirty and i like it and some
people don't mind a little burner than
that in it i'm more
technical i like wine to be very clean
and
i do like
to try varietal wines i also love having
blended wines you know there's not a
right or wrong that way and it's not
even a red or white thing i appreciate
every wine on its own merits whether
it's a riesling or a chardonnay
or a pick pool or a column bird you know
my favorite white i had in australia was
a column bird
from uh primo winery in mclaren bale i
believe that was my favorite white i
tried in australia and i was not
expecting that much fruit from colin
bird i don't think anyone in canada
grows it i was actually thinking of
planting some
the uh
but yeah i really enjoy wine and i
really get off on learning about it from
people that have been doing it more than
me and
i've been doing uh quite a while 15
years i have made real wine
and
[Music]
that's half as long as i've done
cannabis but i've been doing it a lot
more the last 15 than cannabis so i
would say at this point they're fairly
even as far as terms of appreciation go
and understanding
the
the thing is i've got one friend who's
got a vineyard of different clones of
pinot noir and he'll make a matrix of
barrels with really high-end french
barrels but you'll maybe use
four different forests with a couple
different toast levels
and you'll have like say three sets of
those
of so there's three sets of the same
barrels
and then he'll take the three different
clones of pinot noir and put one into
one set of barrels one into the other
set of barrels and one into the last set
so you might have clone five five five
and
702 right there remember the numbers of
the clones for
the pinot but the
but the difference between each of those
pinots is apparent but when you frame it
in the different oaks it gives you a
different perception of them too but
after you've tried them in all the sets
then against this matrix of them that
it's really a lot of fun tasting and we
end up taking breaks to smoke a joint
and we end up blasted at the end of it
we listen to music and it's all fun and
we really have too much fun in our wine
cellars but the uh
but the flavors is what it's all about
to us and we both love the nose and the
taste and
as you get to do it you can
once you've done it enough blindfolded
you could recognize those different
pinot noirs now most somalias which
people think of as real wine experts
they couldn't tell you what clone is in
that pinot noir
you know it's a next level of
appreciation you know
they can tell you it's pinot noir they
can probably tell you the producer the
country the vintage
but can they break down what clones are
in it
you know
there's always somebody that knows more
than you you know so it's really good
when you can
when you're humble enough to accept that
and
lucky enough
to learn from those people you know
it's no point come out thinking you know
everything because you never learn
anything after that you always keep
learning and if you enjoy stuff
you know it's hard not to because you're
obsessed with it
yeah certainly certainly
so just out of a little personal
curiosity what's your favorite red
that's what i'm into
oh you know i don't have one favorite i
i rotate between between them like crazy
like i
i get uh i don't not like shiraz but i
get tired of it quick
and really good you know i never get
tired of lackluster pinot can't take it
you know
the uh
but
i've been drinking
more south american one lady because
when i go down i take some wine with me
as gifts usually but i like to drink
some south american stuff when i go out
in the restaurant so i'm always ordering
carmenere or something like that i do
like carmen year
and i really love
like if i had to pick
one fine wine
which is kind of what you're asking
i think i would take brunello to
montalcino
which is typically fantastic examples of
san jose
and it gets one of my favorite
characteristics
is red licorice when they smell like red
licorice
and some of my best merlots even they'll
smell like blackberry licorice like the
purple licorice
oh my god if they smell like red or
i'm in love i have roses too and
brunello's one i often get red licorice
and roses those are the noses i want
from red wine most of the time you know
i'm open to black cherry and you name it
but but overall
if i had to pick one like if you're
saying what's your favorite say if i was
stuck on the desert island i would want
a seller full of 97 brunellos
i was in switzerland when they came out
in 2002
and they were divine and i was supposed
to stockpile a bunch and save it for a
long time and or sell it back to my
local wine merchant and i drank them all
way too
young i could have anything back give me
a seller full of 97 montalcinos
there you go well i mean on a similar
point of you know high-end qantas
products i wanted to know your thoughts
on recently we've seen a small amount or
maybe you might say a little more than
small but an amount of controversy
surrounding the recent sale of 100
eighths in the states do you feel like
there's room for the extremely high-end
cannabis market or do you feel like
we're forever better
i think i think it's not even the tip of
the iceberg yet because the very best
producers
historically
could not make themselves known to the
wider market people saw something
where'd you get that i can't tell you
you know
but once everybody's able to know
then the forces of supply and demand are
going to drive the price of the best
stuff up and 100 each is the tip of the
iceberg man for sure
and i've got nothing against that if it
was the only price for cannabis i have
something against that
but if you can go and buy a 20.8 beside
it if something's still decent
i think that's fair that's okay there's
only so much you know let the
let the consumers decide if nobody will
pay a hundred dollar eight it'll go away
you know
yeah well that's exactly what i've kind
of been thinking and the underlying
point of the discussion that i think
gets missed is that no one who bought
these eights was forced to
that's right
that's a free it's free market and free
will whatever you want
but maybe one day i'll sell 100.8 but
before i do i want to sell 10 ounces
there you go well something which i
think is an interesting aspect of the
whole discussion is that there are some
people who say that
we're forever as a market so to speak
gonna be bound or we should bound
ourselves by the fact that to certain
people this is medicine do you think
that that argument is going to be able
to stand the test of time or it's a
little faulty
i'm all for producing dirt cheap
medicine and i'm putting my money where
my mouth isn't doing it the
i'm there's a big difference
between
people that need the molecule as
medicine
and people that want the sexiest bud
you know you can have medicine in a
you know a non-descript jar
it doesn't have to be
the sexiest bud it can be a dropper it
can be a pill it can be a potion
you know a cream that you rub on your
hands
people want to buy
boutique bud that's different than the
medical market do medical people deserve
boutique buds absolutely but
if they don't learn to grow them
themselves they're going to have to
learn to pay for them
and if if they're not happy with just
the raw ingredient because mass-produced
field grown will make the medical
compounds very very affordable so if
medical is your thing
probably a tincture works for you
right
yeah
so if tinctures can
my plan for first world pricing is
i can keep somebody medicated on field
grown tinctures
for a dollar a day
retail
so if all the patients
can be covered for a dollar a day
that's gonna work for all but the
absolute poorest humans you know
it's going to work for most of the
humans that have access to any sort of
pharmaceutical
you know
yeah definitely if you can buy it
you should be able to buy cannabis and
it shouldn't be reserved for the rich
but that's not to say that boutique bud
can't be for the rich that absolutely
can be and it always has been
yeah definitely
so just to wrap up our kind of little
discussion of talking around the world
the different terroirs and whatnot
as we've referenced a few times already
recently you were down under and you're
also in a few other places what was your
impression of the various cannabis
scenes and places where you stopped in
well i can tell that there's an
appreciation
amongst many aussies for cannabis
and there is an absolute ignorance about
it by the majority so democracy is greek
for oppressing minorities i believe it's
the translation but that like
but the but as a minority cannabis
lovers in australia face an uphill
battle because they have a
very authoritarian regime descended from
the queen
and
they
really are not nice about cannabis in
australia overall
and you and many others recommended i
don't travel with any even domestically
which i never even think about in canada
i just threw it in my bag and the way i
go but um
down there you guys told me not to
travel domestically with it and i didn't
and i'm glad i didn't because everywhere
i went i heard the same thing say oh
don't bring it in your bag you won't get
there with it
so it was uh it was kind of hard for me
and a little bit sad to go back to
seeing it
um where people were
had to be a lot more covert about it
still and it took me back in in a way it
was kind of a an amusing nostalgia but
it was disappointing at the same time
because i know there's
solid people keeping it real
case and point yourself
but you know you still gotta mind your
p's and q's to not have the neighbor
turn you in you know
it's all uh
it's hard you know in the world you
think of people getting death penalties
for cannabis and stuff it's just too
much you know why do people feel that
entitled to rule us i don't get it i
don't uh i don't consent to be ruled and
happy
definitely
so
one thing i wanted to quickly ask you
because i should have said it earlier
but it slipped my mind you mentioned
blockhead and i think you you know kind
of talking about boating how he was
using the stuff
one of the things i found interesting
about that was i think a lot of people
would have got exposure to blockhead
through snow lotus because i think that
you know got a lot of traction
so yeah how did you feel about that when
you realized that there was that was
incorporated and then it was taking off
in its own right the snow lotus so to
speak
that that i loved that i love i want
people to use them in their own stuff
that's what it's for
and i want and i love to see their
recognition when they say hey i mean
there's snow lotus it's half blockhead
and a half whatever else
that's cool that's cool this [ __ ] i got
no problem with that even if you want to
make straight up lock off knock heads if
you call them square dome
and put block head in brackets say i
made this from a block head back
crossbar that's cool too i have no
problem with that it's just when if i if
there's a potential for customers to be
confused down the road
which they have if they have the
authentic one or they've got this next
version of it you know
that that can
that leads to confusion that bothers me
i've got absolutely no problem and i do
wish the
guy all the best because i know when i
didn't talk to him ever directly but i
know his uh
his friends
were speaking for him and were
apologetic and and said uh
don't worry the guy's gonna discontinue
that he'd give you the rest of the cs
but i don't want anything from him
i'm happy he doesn't have to stop
selling them i'd rather you just change
the name and you can still call it
blockhead back cross in brackets it's
what it is that's fine
but call it something that identifies it
as yours so that when other people get
it
they don't see
oh well this isn't the same as the
blockhead i had the first time or
whatever you know i'm not trying i'm
really not trying to be a dick about it
i just want people to you know it's
really cool when they respect the
origins of what they're using i always
tried to do that myself but i always
gave stuff an original name too
because what you release is yours
yeah not mine you know
so i mean on the topic of blockhead i
did want to ask it's one of those ones
which also has or at least online it
commonly says that it uses an unknown
strain as one of the parents are you
ever tell us a little bit about that one
it was the same father as the sweet two
three dx2p1 which is the most stable
male i had for
hitting anything and really a vigorous
specimen it had very thick dark green
leaves it was pretty much impervious to
mildew it was just a real champion of a
dad that one but i used that one on a
product 19 which came from a american
grower
named seuss
and he was in vancouver for a while he
came up from oregon and he had
a couple of his own strains and he kept
them close to himself and he sold the
bud downtown once in a while and some
people would get a seat or whatnot
and um
this one guy that claimed to have done
some trimming for him
owed me some money and he
came by and said well i don't have that
money i owe you but i got paid in seeds
from trimming for seuss so he says if
you want i would uh
i could pay you back in seeds and he'd
owe me money for a long time i didn't
even know if the seeds were really from
caesar
i just said you know what let's see what
have you got but so i just took the
seeds in lieu of the dead
and i didn't grow them out in canada but
i took them with me to switzerland
and there was two kinds there was a bks
which was like big korean skunk
and i never actually did anything with
that i think the seeds got stolen even
the um
and the other one was product 19 or p19
for short that was the unknown mother if
anywhere says it was unknown
it was the p19 product 19 or project 19.
i was never clear on it you just always
called it p19 whether it was project or
product i wasn't clear on
but it was really weird dude the guy was
a super weird dude
and i was always under
you know i was always wondering
if it was the grass that made him weird
or if he made his grass weird because
his vibe because he had a weird vibe to
him but his grass did too so you smoke
his grass and
it was really
strong but almost off-putting for a lot
of people and i know people would say i
smoked that i was looking out the
curtains like paranoid and winging out
like some people really got a wig out on
some of the streams so it was really
unusual stuff and it was totally
unrelated to everything else in my
stable and so i planted those and i
found one really sharp mother out of it
that i liked better than the rest
and
she was a big chunky frosty thing and it
had a very unusual aroma
almost uh vinyl
like you know sometimes a reasoning has
a vinyl smell it was very similar to
that it had this uh
you know kind of an artificial
and the
and the quality of the resin was very
unusual too it was extremely greasy
and when you made bubble hash from it
it actually
would when you put the hash on the
drying screens
it would melt through the drying screens
even if you put it on like a 15 when you
went to pick it up it was stuck to
whatever was underneath it
and you just couldn't handle it unless
it was frozen it was really the
greasiest resin i've ever seen
it was really unusual
and it was always a certain color like
um
yeah bizarre but it was strong and it
definitely uh
it put the wig out on a lot of people i
think
it routinely i've never had
tested in the lab but i would see
growers in the states that had access to
testing
and they would post results of it
cracking 30
every time basically every time i saw
uh
a block heads analysis it was over 30
so that's you know not extremely common
and it particularly wasn't 20 years ago
yeah okay i just wanted to bring up a
comment made by one of our past guests
char bud of 707 seed bank i think i've
seen you even you know kind of briefly
interacting with him in the comments but
he's
um played with the block head a little
bit doing some various filial projects
and whatnot and a comment he made which
really grabbed my attention was he said
all of breda steve's stuff
you grow it outdoors but it looks like
it's indoors and he said it's like all
these strains are like that and you just
you never see that across a lot of
breeders have you heard that comment
yourself and if so like why do you think
that's all the time
and i know why that's the case and i
told you earlier was uh i always do a
selection round outside every year and
then two inside
so there was always
every year every strain was being
selected to work outside
but it was also selected twice more to
work inside
so
most breeders don't take the effort to
do selections outside
and that their plants don't work outside
yeah okay that's interesting because he
said that it was such a benefit because
you know like he said a bit
tongue-in-cheek but he said you know
like he could pass it off for like much
more at dispensaries because they
thought it was indoor
constantly you know what i've seen this
so many times and i hear all these
people
especially today too now that canada is
going to allow outdoor and all these
people saying yeah but outdoor socks you
i was like [ __ ] you couldn't even tell
the difference if i gave you some proper
outdoors you wouldn't have a clue
because it looks just as good and it may
taste even better you know so
outdoor bud can be hey bud is but if the
plant is healthy and reaching its full
potential there's literally no
telling if it was indoor or outdoor if
it was abused outdoor it looks like
outdoor if it was grown somewhere where
it doesn't really work it looks like bad
outdoor but if it's somewhere where it's
happy and
and acclimatized
there's no reason you would ever know
what's indoor outdoor and the people
that tell you that or simply haven't
experienced that
yeah totally
all righty well that brings us to the
tail end of the interview where we've
got our little quick fire questions so
first one i wanted to shoot you away
what's the most memorable weed or hash
or concentrate you know anything
anything with cannabis so to speak most
memorable experience you've ever had
with it
that's a tough one man
that's a tough one i think i can break
it down a bit i'll say the most
memorable weed was the second year i
grew at northern lights that stuck in my
head and calibrates my bud forever
the nicest hash the most spectacular
hash i ever had that i made
was
incredible blue satellite the blueberry
sativa mother the full melt i pulled off
of her
looked like tiger's eye that gem
you could see into it like rays of gold
into this amber chunk it was so
spectacular i did have pictures of that
a long time ago this tin i had it in it
was really something i've never seen
hash that looked like that before or
since
that blew me away
the biggest the best hit i ever had
was
at the legends of hashish at the
lebanese restaurant in amsterdam
and dave pulled out his uh
old afghan hookah like a traditional one
that was really like a family keepsake
it was maybe 200 years old or something
like this it was a very uh
very ornate
beautiful hookah with a solid wood
pipe stem on it and the bowl
he loaded up the bowl
as he does
with a
full full melt dry shift and it was like
seven-year-old hayes resin or something
like this an absolute full melt
and he literally packed
cramps of it into this pool and it's a
room full of hashmakers and hash dealers
and hash lovers and we've taken over
this restaurant
and he goes sets up the thing and he
says
who's gonna help me like this and nobody
in the room
wanted to stand up and go over and hit
it and he said come on guys who's the
[ __ ] stoner here who's hardcore come
on who's gonna help me light this so
he's ready with his wooden matches
to light this big stinky bowl of
haze melt
i remember going i was embarrassed
because nobody would get up there all
looking around like no way i'm not going
to light that thing they were all you
know happy to smoke little pipes of it
and of course it was a really
extravagant hit and everybody knew it
was going to be a lung buster you know
and gonna drop them
and that was one of
one of two times in my life i had
temporary amnesia from cannabis and i
went and i said i [ __ ] it i got up went
over to the middle of the room
crouched down took the wooden stem in my
hand
and
he he's like okay give it a big big hug
get a couple of big hops to get the
thing going
okay
i take a big lung busting blast off of
this thing
and
stand up and
bust along for a second and go back to
my table and sit down by the window at
my table and i'm looking out the window
at the sort of amsterdam street scene
outside going by
and a minute later or so
i look at the people at my table and i'm
like i don't know who any of these
people are
looking around the room but i don't know
who any of these people are and i was
looking out the window
going [ __ ] i don't even know where i am
and then i was like
what's my name and i couldn't remember
my name you know like i literally
couldn't remember my name and i knew it
was that i was just really stoned and it
was going to pass
but it was weird because i really had
this genuine temporary amnesia from that
one blast of light in that damn hookah
that was a legendary hit i will never
forget that that was i'll be eternally
grateful to dave for that bloody hit
because it stoned me to the bone
and it was great but i mean after five
minutes or something you know i just sat
there quietly nobody realized i was kind
of tripping out they must have assumed i
was tripping out but you know once i got
going a few people went over and took a
puff off it dave was puffing away on it
he's hardcore
but man oh man i was lit from that and
after you know a couple minutes i
started like okay i know where i am now
i can drink the beer
chill out you're good but that was a
blast man
so for the grass
um hash and best hit
was there another question
yeah it's it's a follow-up is dave a cia
agent
well he probably puff toughest of all of
them if he is
i would uh
i would not say he's a cia agent i can
understand
why some people are suspicious of
americans that get off lightly and
disappear into foreign
scenes
i can see the issue and i think many
people facing what uh
these people are facing in those
scenarios
would probably
do what they had to
to not die in prison
but i really don't think the guy's a ca
agent
well there you go that answers the
question so next one
the opposite end of the spectrum instead
of the most memorable experience well
maybe it's the same question in a
different way what was the most
memorable worst experience
so i'll tell you one that
one that pissed me off was when i was
younger
and i was
18 or 19 and i was traveling around
central america for winter
and
i was on an island keycocker in belize
and there was a rasta about my age named
jimmy the lion
and he
had some nice bud from orange walk in
corazon northern belize he was out at
the island and
i said hey man i'll buy some of that
butt off and we can all smoke it
together because
i was visiting backpacking first with a
few bucks and they were poor locals
i said let me buy some that butt off
yeah and we'll just smoke it together
because that's nicer than a lot of the
bohesian but i'd seen
so
i told them i said listen because it's a
small island and there's a cop riding in
circles around on a bike checking us out
suspiciously wherever you went
and i said
let's go to there was a palapa at the
end of this dock it was a private dock
that was on ours we just went out there
we sat in the rafters with his radio and
i said let's put all the weed into one
big joint we'll smoke it then we're
going into the beach to do some fishing
and then we barbecue fish over coconut
husks with a grill popped up on four
coconuts and the lime tree behind us to
squeeze lime on the fish
and i'd give another rest a few bucks to
go get some rice and eat grape coconut
and we'd boil the rice so we'd have like
this rasta cookout going on the beach
and
we were smoking a joint
and i said put all the weed in that
joint so that if the cop comes by we can
ditch the joint and nobody has anything
on them you know
and
he he told me okay i put it all in this
big fat joint we would roll it in banana
leaves because you couldn't get papers
and the banana leaves or almond leaves
weren't too bad even if you got them the
right to age
but
the this cop drive by it looked like a
kid on a bike he must have been like 18
or something
and he had his shorts and a camo t-shirt
and a black beret and i was like was
that that one of the cops and he's like
yeah then i'm like swat the joint out of
their hand because there's about five or
six of us there was a few hippies from
california in that circle and a few
locals
and as the cop drove by he was looking
at the joint and then looking at me and
just staring me straight in the eye
because somebody was trying the
californian dread was trying to pass me
the joint and he was talking to people
on the other side of him and he was
totally oblivious to this little kid cop
on the bike riding by us on the beach
and i and so as soon as the guy got past
a bush i was like he's gonna come back
so i swat the joint out of the guy's
hand
and with my left toe i pushed it into
the sand and that cop was running right
back over with his gun out
you know he didn't have his kind of he
can't run him back over yelling he's
like hey you need me to go get the gun
because he was saying something about
him you know go get the gun if he didn't
cooperate because we're all bigger than
him and he's like you all got to
cooperate with me
he's going off to us
so he goes around
and he comes straight to me and searches
me first and the only thing i have on is
a bathing suit with my room key in it
nothing else and i'm standing on the
joint and so he's checking my pockets
and he goes okay so what did you do with
the joint i saw you were going to have
it i was like i don't have a joint and
so then he went around the circle and
checked everybody
and jimmy the lion still had a bud in
his pocket that he didn't put in the
joint and uh
so they busted him
and dragged him into their little shitty
one-room uh police station kind of with
the cell underneath it
and
he
i i was a couple doors down at that
little
hotel i was staying or hospital whatever
and all night that guy sang bob marley
songs through the bars
and it kept the whole island awake it
was but i was i just stayed there the
whole night just feeling like so bad
that this poor bastard is hauled in and
now you know they may take him to the
jail in in belize city which is a real
shitty shitty jail
and i thought this nice young rasta guy
for one [ __ ] herb stock you know
and i just
i've that has always been the worst buzz
kill is when you're enjoying a beautiful
buzz with wonderful people and really
having a good environment and then the
man comes in and kicks sand in your face
you know and it's like [ __ ] you guys i
really have no respect for the law
and it's
just because of pot laws
yeah totally
okie dokie so next one if you're on a
desert island you can only have two or
three strains what would you pick
um
yeah real original colombian gold
maybe that rosebud
and uh
the sweetest of the sweet tooth
the the real sweet sweet tooth had a
real grape candy taste like grape
lollipops almost
you see it they
i had friends from california that
thought it was great bait when they came
to visit me one time they're spoken and
they're like this is just like grape ape
it's been around a long time and i was
like well this is a new cross but i can
see if maybe he has similar parents or
something
and uh
my favorite sweet tooth is actually some
of my favorite herbs of all time there's
a real sweet tooth there's nothing
sweeter like just for straight up
brought your teeth sweet flavor that's
it and it didn't have any
other characters that i didn't like some
herb that's a little bit sweet might
have some kind of rot
or
other smells too that i don't like as
much but the best meat juice were my
favorite for the candy flavored herb the
original colombian gold is my favorite
for a real
high cherry note
and like an absolute succulent perfume
totally love it but if i had to take a
third herb i think the mother of that
rosebud that little popcorn flow
it just was like chocolate and you never
have
grass i had a couple of chocolate herbs
but nothing that chocolate it was real
hashy chocolate taste it really reminded
me in the police temple bowl the real
stuff so i think those three would be
diverse enough to satisfy my palette if
i could only have three
in okie dokie it's a good selection so
if you could have one strain back that
you'd lost over the years which one
would you get back
oh
that's a good question there's been a
few
but i think it wouldn't be
a strain per se but a selections i've
had of a stream that were
the only time i've seen true sterile
females
i really regret losing those cuttings
those i had
seeds
there was a release i had called tight
skunk that was a
ryan's killer
was the bag seed mother we call it
um
and when i grew out the ryan's killer
which was when eights of pop were forty
dollars in vancouver twice a year this
one guy came out with some that was a
friend of a friend
and she was selling
uh herb and she sold this other guys for
40 but when this ryan just came out from
lower mainland
it was 55.
it was like wow 55 and then why they're
like well it is very nice she's like
it's super strong
try something okay it's
really different too it had a real
sandalwood smell and taste so everybody
in my house got an eighth and they all
found a couple seeds
and
they gave them to me so i sprouted them
and i got six plants up all three were
females three of them had pistols and
three of them had no pistols
and the ones with no pistols would not
take a seed
covered in pollen with males right all
over them
they would not make a seed so i actually
had the perfect example of sterile
females now i've heard of a number of
people have messed around trying to make
them
through various techniques
and they're generally trying to induce
polyploidy
and
i've gone back in my mind a million
times about what people were doing back
then
and i've got a pretty good idea how to
get back to it and it's a little
different than what most people are
trying
so i don't want to say much more about
it because i feel like it's like a great
arms race right now that whoever comes
out with the sterile female first wins
because what that does for outdoor
cultivation is nothing short of
evolutionary
is
if you've got a problem with hemp in
your neighborhood which many canadians
do they can't grow outdoors there's too
much hemp around them
if they had if we could uh induce
sterility
into their plants
without otherwise making them different
it would be a huge game changer and even
indoors producers will have a hermione
i've seen
you know customers of the biggest lps in
canada complain about getting seeds in
their bud
come on people you shouldn't still be
selling cd bud if you're not trying to
sell cd bud
so it would be really easy to correct
that for all of them i could take a
cutting from anybody and send it back to
them sterilized in a few months the only
difference in the bud would be that it
didn't have any pistols
so that was really an amazing plant to
find
nobody i've ever talked who's ever seen
a similar one obviously whoever else
grew those seed saw it but probably
didn't realize the significance of it at
the time as i didn't because i had only
been
growing for less than 10 years at that
point and i just thought hey i've just
never seen this before but i'm sure i'll
see it again and i never saw it again so
i really really really regret
letting those go
but i'd left that the house where i had
them
i sold the leash to a friend and i
wanted to move to another house out on
the ocean which was gorgeous but when i
said listen i'm going to move out there
i'll sell you the lease on my place the
grow room set up all the plants are
there equipment it's all yours
so i told him the place that i left
and i said i'm going to come back in a
couple months when i get something else
set up i'll come back and get cuttings
and everything and when i came back he
cleaned out like half the stuff
like and he lost them he's like oh i
lost this and i lost that one two years
like
oh no i said [ __ ] i was just killing
myself that i didn't spread it around a
little bit more
because the streams that i was so proud
of early on and shared far and wide
they're still they're still around
they're more far and wide than they ever
were because people have shared them in
an ongoing way
so like this sweet skunk
you know there's so much sweet skunk or
grapefruit in bc
let alone in the west coast
it'll never be gone because it's out
there
you know it would be like trying to get
rid of oxygen at this point there's so
much of that you're just never gonna get
rid of it yeah no totally okay so on to
our lucky last question if you could go
back in time to one place to collect
land race seeds any place any point in
time where would you go what would you
get
[Music]
i think
i would go to equatorial africa
i love the good african equatorial
strains there's congo nigerians and
angolans and i don't think they've
changed that much
in the last thousand years you know
maybe they have but i don't know they
they uh
they really have uh some amazing aromas
and a little different effect being that
they're a little higher in thc than many
other places
uh i yeah it's not that i need to go
back in time i just need to go
and travel through some of these areas
that i think still hold amazing land ray
stuff you know
like if you go to angola the chances of
everything being polluted with blue kush
are pretty low
but if you smoke angle and i know
friends in bc that grow angolan it's
fabulously delicious it really is and is
up there with some of the asian ones but
i get a little bit better even than like
burmese and vietnamese and that i tend
to like the africans
just a hair better than the asians and i
like the asians but i love the africans
so that's where i would for land race
collection that's where i would want
anything from equatorial africa
yeah what a fantastic answer
so with that being said did you have any
comments or shout outs you wanted to
make
well shout out to everybody that ever
supported me in this endeavor and uh
your encouragement's always meant a lot
i would have done it for my own selfish
pleasure as i said i love to do it but
you know
the vindication i felt from all the
people that ever helped me along the way
my gurus
that mentored me and took me in
to a degree like it wasn't like they
became my parents or anything but you
know i got a lot of good advice from
some really good people over the years
and uh
i think you know as one out of the blue
i would take that tom alexander from
since emilia tips i brought up earlier
because i never made the point out of
that when i wanted to make was they had
a study following sensamelia tips he had
growing edge and they had the study i
remember reading
that showed that organic produce i think
they did it on tomatoes the study
that it provided they had an organic one
and a non-organic tomato
and
the non-organic tomato had the primary
flavonoids of a tomato you could tell it
tasted like a tomato it was a tomato but
the organic stuff grown in compost and
whatnot had developed secondary
flavonoids so they were able to quantify
the
improved flavor in the organic produce
through the appearance of primary and
secondary flavonoids
that study
confirmed what i felt that the organic
pot tasted better and i always thought
organic
you know your backyard tomatoes taste
better than those pink ones at the
supermarket
and really
you know shout out to tom alexander for
sense amelia tips and then onwards and
growing edge and the science of people
growing kind but
and especially you know i've gotta thank
anybody that ever bred seed in this
planet before me because we all stand on
the shoulders of giants you know and
i really
you know have nothing but respect for
guys like dj short
and even
um watson what he's done with skunk and
robert connell clark you know without
his book marijuana botany i'm sure i
would have been off to a much slower
start but that was the second grow book
i ever read
and that uh
really blew it up for me and brought it
into perspective and i'd read it after
you know
the first year i grew then i got some
books and that was one of the very first
books i got and
i read it and look at the drawings of
the different lines and think
wow there's so much cannabis to
experience beyond
you know the scentsy catalog
so it was really a treat
it was really inspirational robert
connor clerk i really
felt a debt of gratitude to him for
his excellent work and he's done a great
job
um i'm sure there's lots more people i
could thank but this has been a very
long show already
and i'm sure you're all ready to go roll
another one
that's a good little sentiment to end it
on so thank you so much british steve
for coming and dropping all the
knowledge and all the awesome history
hey it's been a pleasure thank you again
for your hospitality it's a pleasure to
call you a friend my friend
thanks to british steve for taking the
time to sit down and chat with us and
thanks to everyone who made it this far
with us as always please go check out
our sponsors support them 420 australia
organic gardening solutions and seeds
here now you know best in the game
finally if you feel like you're a real
fan you know feel like you're like the
keeper finno of a fan
maybe you're gonna go check out the
patreon
[Music]
until next time
la la la la
[Music]
you