[Music]
hello and welcome to another episode of
the podcast a cannabis podcast for
budding
enthusiasts as always you're joined by
your boy heavy days here from the upside
down library and as usual we want to
give a massive shout out to all of our
incredible sponsors who help sure the
show continues to happen seeds here now
number one seed bank in the industry all
the hottest breeders the latest drops
everything you can look for and more
whether you're after indoor outdoor
feminized regular autoflow they've got
everything under the sun to keep you
loaded on all the hottest genetics
producing the most fire Bud you've ever
had I hear they've got some incredible
lines from heavy days still in stock if
you want to go check that out make sure
to do it before it's too late big shout
out to CT now we appreciate you so much
likewise if you want to produce the best
bud to date you've got to make sure your
garden is pumping on all cylinders and
for that we recommend our good friends
at Organics alive they produce the
number one powdered organic products
that will ensure your next crop is the
absolute best to date people are picking
up cups all around the globe using their
products which is the highest Accolade
you can get hom Growers just like you
producing not only their best Harvest
today but award-winning Harvest what
more could you ask for they've got
Solutions whether you're in veg
transition flour they've got
micronutrients macronutrients absolutely
every product you could want ferments
and more check them out guys Organics
alive your number one stop for all of
the highest quality organic inputs to
make sure your Harvest is killing
it likewise you got to make sure your
garden is pest and pathogen free to
ensure that your plants are happy and
producing the highest quality Harvest
for that we recommend you check out our
good buddies at copit they've partnered
with us for a long time and we have no
doubt that if you use their products you
will find they are the absolute best in
the game you've got to check out the
spidex vital plus breeder sachet these
are an absolute game Cher it's the usual
spidex vital you know and love that's
going to take out any spidermite
problems you have but the breeder sachet
allow a continuous sustained release of
these beneficial Predators into your
garden ensuring that you don't just have
one big burst and surge but instead
consistent rate of release truly a game
changer I expect nothing less from the
experts at copit biological you know
these guys are world leaders they're not
just in America they're all around the
world and for good reason they are the
Pinnacle of the game if you're after
biological Pest Control check out copit
number one thank you so much for the
support the final piece of the puzzle to
ensure that your room is killing it is
our good friends at Pulse their senses
are second to none industry leading and
just recently they announced the pulse
Hub what more could you want an
integrated unit for all of your sensors
to ensure that your garden is automated
and tracking all of the variables you
may not be consciously aware of from VPD
to ppf dupoint temperature humidity so
much more you've got to get yourself a
pulse sensor guys it has revolutionized
the way I grow flow and increased the
tpping content the cannaboid content the
yield so so so much more shout out as
always to our friends at Pulse senses
likewise if any of you guys have been
listening to the show you know that I am
passionate about helping people
transition to vaporized options if
they're considerate about their
respiratory health and for me dap are
the world leaders in this dap helped me
to transition from bongs to vaping and I
tell you what I've never looked back
their unit is the most potent the most
highly replicating of a bong hit I've
ever come across and through their
incredible munit I was able to success
get off fongs a few years ago now truly
one of the most Innovative and
interesting Vapes on the market using a
totally different design to others you
have found please check out dap I
promise you guys if you've tried vaping
before and felt like it didn't quite cut
it check these guys out you will not be
disappointed massive shout out to dinat
thank you so
much and last but not least we want to
give a massive shout out to the
incredible patreon gang without you guys
we could not continue to make episodes
if you want to get Early Access to
upcoming episodes exclusive content just
on the patreon including the likes of
mean Jean Bob Hill bod Tricom jungle so
much more be sure to go check out our
patreon we give away genetics every
month to our supporters along with
artwork Vapes sensors so much more
please check out the patreon guys I
promise you you won't regret it you'll
get your money back in swag for helping
support a show you love thank you so
much to everyone from the patreon we
appreciate you so greatly
[Music]
on today we are joined by none other
skung VA here to talk all things Lucky
Dog seedco along with the newest Venture
he's a part of the grateful Head a clone
bank and genetic repository some big
aspirations so without further delay all
righty gang welcome back on today we are
thrilled to have a longtime friend a
prolific grower and breeder The Man
Behind Lucky Dog Seed Co and a part of
the newest Adventure I'm sure you've
heard of the Grateful head a big welcome
to skunk VA for taking the time to join
us today how you doing I'm well how are
you good to see you good to see you too
I'm well I'm well as always I want to
know what have you been smoking on
recently uh lately I've been smoking a
lot of uh live rajin uh you know deep
carbox related in my pens that I've been
buying you know so I've been on the I've
been busy so I've been smoking Jack's
cleaner of all
things wow yeah it's really nice yeah
I've been growing it a little bit it's
really ugly flow it's just it's not
pretty at all but it makes incredible
incredible live rosin you know so I put
some in the toaster oven and you know I
was trying to find some devices for the
uh live rosin pens that we we sell here
at Lucky Dog cannabis and you know I
chose I took like 40 I took like um 40
grams of the liary R I made and melted
it in the toast oven and put it in the
pens to kind of test out the devices and
you know passing them out to the
employees and my friends and smoke it
myself so it just tastes so damn good I
did have to I did have to keep it in
there a little bit longer to kind of
mellow out the extra energy side of it
it's a little woo you know so I kind of
got a little bit of that to come out of
it when I just kind of left it in there
for a little bit longer decar box just a
bit longer you know um and yeah so
that's what I've been smoking and then
on the on the uh the flower front I've
been smoking a lot of uh sour band I
know we've been we had a nice crop of
that here I've actually been smoking a
lot Jack herrer rolling joints to that
so that's like my morning time thing I
go out in the sunshine get about 15
minutes on my face and smoke a little
Jack Herer and then usually at night
it's something like deserty I like to
have like a deserty thing at night um oh
and then uh uh another one that we're
that we're gonna that we have over here
that I've been loving is called triple
Burger skunk M Flex nice yeah and uh
someone passed me a CET up here and some
live rosin of it there and we also have
been dabbing that and it's [ __ ] it's
really nice really enjoying that savory
flavor I hear it's got some sort of Kim
in it I'm not I don't really know the
lineage of it but it definitely tastes
like it's got let's just say kemi in it
you know it's got that savory it's got
GMO GMO there you go yeah I said you
nailed it with the chmd yeah it's it's
it's nice though I like it so we're
going to be rocking now in here too um
yep that's about it that's so cool to
hear you've been uh getting into
concentrates I got to ask you some more
like are there any other sort of
standout strains you've put into the
pens and you reference with the Jax
cleaner like was it that it was like a
bit racy in the way like sativas were
when you say you were trying to Mellow
it cuz it's really interesting you don't
hear about
people say oh you put anything into a
pen it just feels like an Inda um so
that sounds like you were getting more
of that sativa expression yeah I it was
my first time decarboxylating the live
Rod of myself and I you know at first I
just let it go I was trying to get every
little itty bitty bubble out of it so I
think I let it go for like probably way
too long um and then so it kind of just
naturally happened um but I did have
some of the the rosin that wasn't
decarbox and I I did a dab and I was
like that's a different feeling you know
it was way more racier um it wasn't too
much but like I said uh you know I don't
I don't smoke that in the morning the
pen is kind of throughout the
day sure so you you were saying you
mostly use the pens through the day I'd
love to know have you ventured much into
the world of like hash dry C anything
like that or you sticking mostly to like
the more concentrate esque no we we have
been making we've been setting aside a
little bubble hash when I make the I
make all the live RS in here um just
don't have anyone else to do it you know
um but so yeah I always set a little
bubble aside I love having a freeze
dryer man it's kind of a new thing for
me it's like I wish I would have had
that all along you know so amazing it's
amazing to come back the very next day
and like pull out some dry hash bubble
hash and you know melt it up you know so
yeah I've been keeping I've been doing
some tits some purple full stack we did
some red dog that one came out really
nice not a big yelder so it's probably
not going to be something in rotation
it's one of ours the lucky dog uh
crosses that we made um we found a
really nice one it's it tests around 29%
THC whatever that means to anybody but
it's got this beautiful flavor to it
like this almost like green weed flavor
to it that's kind of rare these days um
and it's got this incredible like
relaxing effect um the people who come
in it's been really popular like our
last drop the ones that we're flowering
out here have been really popular our
most popular as diesel poison and red
dog we can't we can't grow enough of
that all of a sudden and they're kind of
surpassing all the the botiques and the
old chims that we have and you know some
of my old classics that I've got um
which makes me so happy I love that you
know people that don't know anything
about lucky dog or really even Kim dog
or like any of the stuff that goes any
of the history or anything like that
they'll come in and they'll buy stuff
that we've selected from our own you
know crosses and it just it really
validates what you're doing you know it
really does CU it's like there's no bias
there there's no you know
preconceived notions at all it's just
simply you know this is the one I like
and they you know they asked for it
they're bummed out we don't have it so I
made I did a little bit of that some red
dog like said purple full stack and
Diesel poison we did some pull dog there
the skunk dog cross and uh the tits GMO
which you know always makes some really
nice [ __ ] rosin or bubble hash and uh
that's about that's all I can think of
right off the top of my head it's really
not that much but oh and uh we have one
called
um um dog roller that we made that one's
in is is also in rosin form too that's
like a heavy duty strong
Inda so yeah I feel like you're selling
yourself short you're like that's that's
not that much it's like there's a
plethora of killers in that mix there so
sounds like you got some good
concentrates on board I guess I want to
ask given you're trying all different
variety if you had to pick one as your
favorite which would you go with
currently the out of the ones I've made
uh that I currently have I'd say
probably the tits it's always been my
favorite ever since I smoked it as far
as concentrates goes it just it's good
any time of the day generally I smoke it
in the day time but um you know it's
it's it's just got that it's got the
flavor it stays in your mouth It Coats
it it just stays with you makes your
mouth water and it's just got the nice
high you know it's a really rare plant
it's got it all you know so I'd say the
tits that always is going I'm going back
to I got one of those uh
puffco the pipes what do you call them
the proxies you know and so you know if
I'm feeling saucy you know we have to
worry about inspectors here so we can't
just walk around with those pipes in her
hands around here you know what I mean
it's a legal cannabis business so that's
why the pens come in handy of course you
know it's not something that we prefer
it's just something that we kind of it's
a a ways to a means you know um but I I
do like I do like smoking the the tits
rosin out of that thing it's really nice
you can really get a good good flavor
the full the full flavor comes through
with no water in it and such you know
that's awesome and and just to loop back
you were mentioning with the flower you
having Jack Hera and some Sour band
sounds like you're starting to gravitate
more to the saever end of the spectrum
or is it just in the
daytime no I am actually you know as
I've gotten older it's just uh I'm not
sure if it's because I wasn't so exposed
to it when I was you know you know 20s
and 30s just too much chem around me not
to say that it doesn't have sativa
qualities we I don't know it does but um
but some of these I just didn't have
access to and um maybe I would have
enjoyed them back then but yeah I do
gravitate towards them I like that Upp
feeling you know the older I've gotten
I'm 51 now and I like that that
energized feeling it it does me well and
I like that brain stimulation you know
um you know kind of creativity you know
problem solving kind of effects I love
that you know I like to see things
differently I love when weed does that
to me so I get that a lot from the
sativas I smoke and I I do like them
been breeding a lot more sativas too you
know that was going to be my next
question tell me about it well you know
like the pull dog for instance that's
definitely you know in the diesel poison
the diesel poison has just been like a
big surprise like we just pack we uh we
took one pack 13 seeds germinated them
grew them out we could have kept three
of them but there was one that just you
know the the problem with breeding with
anything that's high in terpinolene is
of course I think we've talked about
this before it dominates everything you
know um you know a lot of people that's
what weed smells like because that's all
they remember when they from the times
they smelled weed you know but uh so
when you're able to make a cross because
it's a great it's a great flavor it's a
great smell it does like it does a lot
of things to you I don't I can't even
explain it but um to be able to have
that in in a strain in the flavor in the
aroma but not dominating and you can
have like you know different smells
different flavors on the back end and
that's what this does it's really cool
you know and uh you know we we pulled
that one off it's a huge yielder you
know it just wrecks you people love it
and so I would say that's you know
that's one of the ones that I'm thinking
about right now U but we also did the
pull dog with the skunk dog it's
definitely a sativa leaner I mean the
skunk dog itself is just by itself is uh
it's got almost medicinal benefits when
it comes to things like ADHD you know
it's so focusing you know um I've had
people com into the shop here I think
I've told you this before where you know
that's why they smoke her because they
have severe what they call
ADHD and you know certain strains can
really lock them in and and change their
day when it comes production and and uh
we've had people give us feedback like
that on on the P dog um so you know and
I enjoy those now too I used to be kind
of scared of those because I don't
really want to like have a heart racing
you know like like neop panic attack
feel but nowadays I don't know if I
enjoy it or if it's just different but I
I kind of enjoy it you know yeah I know
you do too well you know what I've
thought about that a lot because you
know there was a time where if I had any
of these sativas I would just feel feel
profoundly anxious and not enjoy it at
all and my conclusion I've come to is
that I think over time you learn to
harness that feeling and use it as like
you feel energized and productive you
know whereas in other situations it
feels like almost a bit crippling um so
that that's just my anecdotal sort of
musings on it because I have thought
about that like why did it used to make
me anxious but the same clone nowadays
it's like o
perfect that's a I think that maybe
that's a good point uh for me too
because you know maybe when I was
younger I I
certainly I'm I'm I'm I would say I
don't want to say I'm busier because I
physically maybe I'm not as busy but
mentally I'm busier than I've ever been
in my life and so maybe It just fits
better with my life now because of that
whereas when I was younger I'm at home
you know I got my bed rooms you know and
growing the weed hanging out with my my
kid my little kid you know and maybe
maybe that's what it was maybe it's just
that you need to have the right kind of
day to have that kind of smoke in your
life you know production wise definitely
definitely and you know what the
listeners are probably sick of hearing
me say this but uh what you said about
the diesel poison being like
unexpectedly popular uh is is really a
sentiment I'm always mentioning to
people which is that that notion that
people are burnt out on Blue Dream or
Jack har or train wreck um it I really
don't think it applies outside of
California because the majority of
people and they're just not exposed to
it so I I see people in Australia all
the time growing Durban Poison S1 Blue
Dream S1 train wreck S1 because they're
very much interested in it so yeah I
think it it mirrors what your sort of
experience is that like there are a lot
of people who are still really into
turpening profiles and love the high and
think yeah this is for me I would agree
with that I didn't mean to cut you off I
I would agree with that um yeah
California Market's different than all
the others I've I've been exposed to a
mid around um I don't really know what
it is you know it's a big place with a
lot of people and they do Drive markets
outside of the room you know uh but but
I I've had that here I was surprised
when I came here I was blown away
because I've never really seen that and
then when I came here and opened up shop
you know people were looking for the
sativas and they still are you know and
so we and intentionally grow more and
more of them you know the traditional
classical classic sativas we grow more
and more of those because that's what
they want you know which is it's not
purple weed you know like California I
don't know how it is today things can
change but when I call back there it's
all about the purple weed is it purple
I'm like I don't know maybe how cold is
it but yeah I I agree with that I agree
with what you said I think it is I think
it is an outside California thing which
is literally
everywhere there you go well look I
guess the next question is would you
ever consider maybe developing a male
that's like you know hybrid
sativa I think we have we we we selected
a Kim Fuego that seems to pass on the
best parts of the sour diesel when it
comes to those effects you know um we've
done a lot of we just finished doing a
lot of crosses with those we're going to
test them out see if they landed where
we want um but that's that's that's kind
of what we've been doing you know uh we
definitely are are developing more m
here um slowly but surely you know uh
but we're trying to expand what we're
doing we know of course we're Kim dog
based here we always will be it's just
the way it is but um but we have we have
started to do that I would say I feel
pretty good about the this next line
that we're going to be coming out with
as far as the that Kim fuo mail that we
selected you know the Kim fuo has been
up for quite a while was probably the
most popular one I've ever I've ever
made as far as what I can see um and so
decided to kind of look into it a little
bit more uh been collecting clones of it
been selecting more females of it um and
have gone through a few males so we just
we're literally drying a bunch of flour
seated flour right now and we're going
to start testing them out later this
summer we'll start popping them wow
that's exciting I've I've had a few
friends grow some Kem fuo out and
they've all loved it so that's that's
really exciting I guess I'd love to know
are there any uh particular crosses in
the mix that you did that like you know
you I know that like when I make seeds
you know there's like say you make 10
crosses there's like there's two in your
mind where you're like oh I'm really
those are the ones I'm keen on tell me
what are they for
you well honestly I've been through this
and I try not to do that because I
disappoint myself you know um I did some
red Lebanese hash plant crosses and they
were phenomenal but there was a little
bit higher interex traits than I pref
you know so I've uh I've thought about
kind of because they were really they
were they were off the chain but I got I
got hung up on what I saw as far as I go
it wasn't wasn't terrible but it was you
know when we stressed you know what we
did with stress we just use Mo mostly we
use what I've learned is that when you
find those it's mostly rootbound plants
you know sometimes I can't get heat to
do it you know excessive heat but I can
get a plant and a solo cup to do it you
know and so I I we you know we were
testing them with smaller pots and we
did find that um basically if I find two
and like say you know 30 or 50 I don't
really have numbers on that but
somewhere in that range that's too much
for me um you know but we have thought
about putting those out so anyways I was
so I had such high expectations on that
one that I got really disappointed when
I saw that of course I never released
the stuff um so I try to stay away from
that but we did just make a [ __ ] ton of
crosses I'm trying to think if I had a
favorite if I could pick one
um I don't know man like there's so many
we just did a bunch of different stuff I
mean I even have to get the list out to
tell you it's like that you know there
there's like 26 different ones that we
re rocked you know but I did like I did
have a lot of problems with the banana
OG that's kind of a outside of my realm
and we started to do a little C like
Crossing with some things we've made
females we've selected of our own stuff
like the dog roller
um the uh the diesel poison like I
mentioned the pole dog you know things
like that we're starting to cross into
that and see what we find there maybe
there's going be some good [ __ ] there
but um nothing really that I feel like I
just try not to fall in love it's like
you know I I get I can I can go I can
get all emotional about something pretty
quick so I try to check myself and you
know play it out let things just kind
of you know and try not to have too high
of EXP expectations bigger low you know
yeah certainly certainly I always think
to myself like I'll have a few favorites
and maybe one or two of them will pan
out to be what I hoped and maybe the
others don't and then there'll always be
one that I wasn't particularly invested
in that proves to be like one of the
really good pairings and so I guess it's
kind of what you're saying you know like
it's just you can't really call it
either way no because I mean you more
more times than not I get surprised you
know like this is not one that I had a
lot of Hope in and then boom there it is
you know so I kind just stay out of that
you know learned to do that with many
things in my life even with
this there you go and I wanted to ask I
saw I believe in your stories or
somewhere that you're looking to retire
the bx2 male and upgrade to the bx3 only
tell me a bit about it you know it just
it it came down like this like I kept
them both because I when I made
different crosses with each one you know
the same cross but with th each uh male
you know sometimes I would find better
qualities or and traits in one versus
the other and often sometimes it was the
bx2 that was that had the the better
traits and so I figured well we better
keep it around but it wasn't that it
wasn't like that big of a difference and
as time went on the more we did that the
more we looked it really was like it
became like obvious like we've moved on
from it you know so we just we retired
it is she he's gone now we don't even
have him anymore we decided to put him
down so um it just maybe a little bit
too like overthinking it um and then
after that was over it was like well we
don't really need this anymore so let's
Let it go you know I crossed with the
Kim sis and you know I couldn't tell
which one was better I felt at one time
that the uh the the bx2 was better and
so I kept that one that was probably the
one that made me keep it the mo like
that was the one was like oh I think you
know I like this better so I'm going to
keep this but you know time and space
and like space is a big thing and we
just don't have room for it anymore we
we want to put more males in so um there
was nothing really wrong with it it was
just like it just kind of was like
what's the point you know so I I decide
to retire it you know no that makes
sense and I guess the the next question
is do you have any plans to make a
bx4 well I've made a bx4 um and then one
that b
2009 was it
2019 when I was still in sowa County we
had the fires come through really close
and we had to be evacuated and I was i'
just taken clones of everything to
replace all my mothers um and the
evacuations became
mandatory and where I was living at the
time it was like at a very high vantage
point in snow County I could actually
see the fires which as a bird flies
maybe 20 miles away maybe not
and you know when those when those um
what do they call those things the uh L
Diablo is that what they call those wins
L Diablo winds come through they can get
so strong this happens quite often I
think it's happening right now in
Northern California um when it hap when
that happens and it happens you know
September October the wind gusts can be
so dry the humidity can drop so low and
the winds can be so powerful that they
can do this phenomenal I figur what they
call it but where the fire jumps from
Treetop to Treetop and it can spread so
fast at that point that you know you
really literally have to keep an eye on
it you like the evacuations make sense
when that kind of situation arises
something they can't predict um so we
you know I grow weed so I stayed put
during the mandatory evacuations no
power you know the power's already been
off for a few days before these
evacuations come uh because of the fire
and luckily for me I had everything
rooted in rockwool and so I I what I did
is I set up my RV with my sunlight my
Skylight I put the Clones in I you know
I don't put them in there because I have
a generator but I have a spot ready for
them in case I have to blaze really
quick I fill up the art this is like
something became like um you know a
regular occurrence you know something we
had to do all the time set you know put
all the finance you know all the papers
all the important papers all the photos
the crystals the CD collection all in
the RV
and waiting for us to evacuate and then
I put the RV in front of my location and
then I would hide the generators between
you know behind the RV between the house
hiding them from the street because it's
a mandatory evacuation we're not
supposed to be there so we would go up
to the top of the hill on foot and we
would watch and see how the fire is
doing we could also see if any Authority
law enforcement or fire department was
coming up the hill um because we're not
supposed to be there and then we would
shut the generators off we also had
solar uh battery so we could have all of
our lights and refrigerators and you
know our refrigerator and stuff on but
no grow lights and we would shut all
that [ __ ] off before they got to our
street you know it was a [ __ ] CAD
Mouse game um so it went on for almost I
I believe that time it was like 10 we 10
days you know it was a long time um
there's a lot going on you're not really
you shouldn't if you drive away from
your house you can't come back that's
another thing you know so once you leave
you can't come back you once you leave
you have to be ready to not come back um
so food all that water all these things
you know you have to be ready for that
and when that happened I I didn't lose
anything except for the bx4 that I was
working on um I didn't really get a lot
that feedback on it yet I didn't find do
a lot of testing with it I did cross
with the headband and we released it at
that Harvest uh cup and
Worster uh was it that year I think it
was that year it's right before
but anyway um so and then once I lost it
I just kind of I kind of haven't gone
down that road so um you know with what
we're doing next there's going to be a
lot of Clone only released and I'm
working constantly on you know the back
you know in the background of my life
I'm just working on an IBL Kim dog IBL
and it's kind of like I feel like it's
GNA maybe never happen or it's going to
take the rest of my life to make it
happen and so the bx4 was part of that
um we we are getting ready to go through
all the rest of the bx3 seeds that I
have uh to select females and maybe to
take the Fe the male one more step I'm
going to spray the male I'm going to
spray the males that I select and kind
of figure out what we got from that do
maybe do some testing here with the lab
the local lab here um tpin
cannaboids um once we reverse it if that
seems like a good idea at the time but
right now with everything else going on
it's just kind of like on a side burner
you know there you go and I I wanted to
ask I've seen some cool crosses popping
up in your stories like some some
pollinated moms for some upcoming
projects I guess and the thing that sort
of grabbed my attention the most was
there was quite a few mums in there that
were like new to the Arsenal and I I
wasn't necessarily expect them to pop up
and I think I saw just a bit earlier
there's a grape and cream cross chem dog
bx3 tell me a little bit about some of
these new moms that have joined the
ranks
so yeah uh what we have driving right
now is we have the Four Kings
OG all right we have 501
OG then we did our 88 G13 Kim
selection uh then we've got our banana
OG that's a new one for us here we had
it a long time ago but now we've got it
again so we cross with the black
triangle caps Frozen
lemons kind of so so on that one carbon
candy that's a new one for us we we had
a selection of Kim cornelian that's our
Cherry P pie Kim and dog
cross um we have a kimorn 13 selection
in there like I said we did have a lot
of our own Selections in there um so
that's our Airborne G13 cross with Kim
bx3 uh we did our chewy that's our runch
a white runch cross with our Kim dog our
selection of that deep end butter which
is a fresh my buddy Gabby you know Gabby
we've talked with him before he gave
that to
me um our diesel poison selection then
we did our dog beach selection that's
our Virginia Afghan Virginia Beach
Afghan cross selection the dog roller I
mentioned before and then we've got our
GMO root beer everybody loves that one
so we got that one in there Gorilla Glue
number four we have a gorilla glue
number four that was recently taken out
of uh off a gen zero cut so that's super
duper like healthy and vibrant so we
went ahead and crossed it the gate the
grap G gas the grapes and cream it's it
I don't know if you heard of that one
it's it yep that's uh I believe it's an
uh exotic M I think yeah I believe it's
Exotics yeah we like that one we got
that one from Gabby as well Joker 31
figured why not we did the Killer Queen
you'll be happy to hear labomba number
two I believe that's another one of uh
Exotics I'm not sure no that's a
compound yeah and then we had a uh my my
lady found a nice selection of Larry
OG by sfv
Og so we got that one in there and then
Larry unicorn we've got that one in
there I believe well we have uh one of
uh uh Tommy's uh Local H in there that
we have the Mac one actually took the
pollen looks like we got quite a few
seeds off the Mac one we tried that one
and then the next one we took the the
classic the Maui woi NorCal goey two
Classics right there on a row and then
we took the orange tree which is one I
got from Gabby and he uh he got it from
a guy Mark we know a amendo Cino from
Green Brothers Farms give him a little
shout out there because I know he loves
that orange tree and then orangutang
titties another EX itics I believe
correct me if I'm wrong pull dog number
six that was our 4% TPS selection uh 29
30% on the THC Total so we put that one
in there and then my lady made some f2s
of the Punchy
bler uh so we selected an one of the one
of her f2s put that in there purple full
stack purple
Panther and then we had a selection of
our raffy dog which is our apples and
bananas
cross
um rs1 why not and then we did another
one at Tommy's Screaming
Eagle and then we did a lot of like
increases you know um popular ones like
we did uh uh some gorilla fum um what
else do we do I think there was another
one I'm trying to think of we did we may
have done similar diesel poison I'm
sorry diesel therapy East Coast Sour
Diesel
and
slaps that was from Gabby and then we
did the slice have you ever heard of
that one that was one that I think Tommy
made Calo right yeah Calo and his skunk
mail and
then we did a strawberry diesel we're
hoping we can put some more P pump oom
into that and ton so the Talon's been a
nice one that one's like a 7% uh yielder
on the the lot on the fresh frozen yield
wow really high Yi
famar I believe that's also exotic I'm
not sure I have to check with Gabby on
some of those those are cuts that he all
that he passed to me he loves his exotic
doesn't he he I guess he does yeah I
he's got a you know his library is
surprising knowing him you know I don't
know you know he's uh he's turned me on
some some new [ __ ] I like that yeah very
surprising unexpected but he's turning
me on some newer newer school stuff you
know and then another one for my lady
her selection of triangle Kush by
Irene and then that's and then we did
the White Widow the Sharon cut we did
yeah a lot of people have been asking
about that one so I figured we we'll run
that one I believe there's some other
ones but those are those are all the
ones I can find right I mean while we're
on that topic before we transition
what's your thoughts on the future of
flower do you feel like demands growing
falling where do you see
flower I don't know if I have a good
perspective of that but my perspective
is is that it's the same as it ever it
was that there's some people who just
want cheap weed to get high with and
there's some people who you know want
The Connoisseur Grade weed um I think
that when you have those two types of
consumers I think you're always going to
get more exposed to the one who wants to
save a few bucks on a Friday afternoon
before their weekend you know um so they
have the most joints possible to smoke
during the weekend but there's still
that you know we get people out here
that come to the shop that fly from you
know pretty far away and we happen to be
part of their trip you know here at
Lucky Dog you know Boseman Montana is a
um it's a tourist destination you know
Yellowstone Parks here um for the
summertime and then in the winter time
we have some great skiing snowboarding
here at Big Sky and briger bll and so we
do get a lot of Tourism here that's
basically the industry that that the
town has if it has one this area it's
not really just this town but this area
and so you know just uh funny little
story about that so in February this guy
I think he called the shop he found the
shop like on Google you know called it
up he talked to my employee Sarah and he
he's like hey do you guys have any Kim
dog and she's like well you know we
don't really keep that it's hard for us
to keep that on the Shelf it sells out
really quick um but we have a little bit
are you coming by today he's like no I'm
in Connecticut and I'll be there like in
a
month so she's like okay so he she says
we have like a half an ounce of it
that's about it though you know and so
he's like will you save it for me and
she's like yeah let me ask uh let me ask
you know the boss so she asked me I'm
like yeah of course I mean that'd be
interesting if he actually shows up and
gets it so let's see what happens so he
did he comes back like you know a month
or he comes like in a month and you know
he brings his wife and they're on
vacation they're going to go
snowboarding or skiing or whatever and
you know just check out the hot springs
and you know just go have some Montana
moments you know as we say here and uh
and stop by the shop and got his got all
laced up with gear you got the hoodies
and the shirts and the [ __ ] bought a
bunch of flour him and his wife did and
and I I remember just looking at his
wife and she was like what the [ __ ] she
was just looking at like I just kept
catching this look like what are we
doing like this is what we came for you
know and he gets his half ounce of Kim
dog that we put away for him you know it
was the last bit we had and um so he
that all happens we take pictures it was
a big deal and then just yesterday
coincidentally just yesterday we get a
package in the mail and it's from this
fella and uh and so he sends us he had
like these tie Dy made he was a 49ers
fan like myself when we were talking
about that when he was here and he had
these tie-dyes made with like a pot leaf
on it and and then the rest of the
backgrounds Red Gold you know like the
49ers color and then he wrote a little
note saying hey you know we're both
49ers fans and I appreciate the you know
you guys saving the weed for me and
here's shirts for everybody there was
like five shirts in the thing you know
and so like that's awesome we get a lot
of that you know so my perspective is a
little skewed because of stuff like that
you know um but so but I would say on
The Daily like people just want to like
they just want to relax they want the
effect of weed you know they want to I
don't want to break the bank on it
although the weed is about as cheap as
you can you know as you can [ __ ]
produce it and sell it for but um I
don't know I think it's about the same
if anything there's more people
smoking um I'm not even sure if that's
true actually but in my perspective
there's probably more people smoking and
they're probably a different customer
than I've ever been around they're just
they're just want to get their their
herb and they want to like you know
enjoy it and you know kind of that's
their thing and they don't want to spend
a lot of money on it so if they want to
get like older weed or Smalls as you say
you know then they'll take that if it's
at a discount then there's people that
just want the best you know so I think
it's the
same yeah totally look that's that's an
interesting perspective for sure and I
guess as like an extension of that where
do you see the price point going do you
think we've hit the rock bottom with
quality flower whereby it's going to
start to pick up again or do you think
there might still be a little more to go
what's your
suspicion I don't really know if I know
I don't know if I have a good view for
that but I would say that what I think
when that comes up is that you know
indoor cannabis which you know is easily
more you know popular or more desired or
whatever than than anything else any
other way you can grow it that seems to
be there's a bottom to where you just
you can't produce it you know there no
matter how much you grow there's only so
much you can produce at a certain price
I mean you can go the more you produce
the more efficient you are the lower you
can you know um you know the lower the
price can be when you sell it but you
know I think there's still the bottom I
mean you still have rent you still got
electricity you still got those things
so I I just I don't know how close we
are to that but it feels to me like
we're pretty darn close you know um I
don't know I I I think we're pretty
close to that we've dropped our prices
but now we've literally you know I I'm
embarrassed to say this but we've
literally succumbed to the cannaboid
levels being the price point so now at
Lucky Dog when you come here you can get
what when when the THC levels are here
you it's this much when it's here it's
this much when it's here it's this much
you know I tried to like fight the power
as you say and tried to educate the
customers but I'm just one guy you know
the numbers mean everything to the to
the folks who smoke they just don't they
don't know it's our it's our
responsibility to educate them but it's
not as easy as it sounds it's easier
said than done does that mean that like
some of the more Legacy strains like say
like your Durban Poison your chem dog
like it's sort of not economically
viable to grow them now because they
they're going to be in the lower tier
even though it doesn't reflect the
quality or the
demand well the Kim dog is always around
29 30% so that one always goes off the
shelf whether or not you've ever heard
of it before people gravitate towards it
so um but Legacy strains indeed like we
were we've been pushing uh you know we
keep bringing up but the Killer Queen we
have that one it's a really nice string
you know and we've been pushing that on
people and they'll they'll come back and
buy it but it's like 18 20 21 percent so
people don't it's that initial
gravitating you know like if you just
were like if if people could just pick
up weed and just smell it and be with it
for a minute you know the way
traditionally we always have been then
it might be different but they're just
looking at numbers and they're looking
at a jar with weed in it you know so
they don't gravitate towards that stuff
you have to kind of push it on and not
really push it but kind of you know turn
them on to it really um you know it
smells great so just take a smell of
this but we always tell people here like
listen it doesn't matter how much D it
has nothing to do with it we have
strains that are 18% it'll [ __ ] knock
your socks off compared to you know the
latest one you heard about that's at 31%
it's just it's not that simple um can we
explain it to you no nobody can because
we haven't really studied it to the
point where we understand it but we tell
them what we know we tell them that you
know the different levels and
combinations of the cannaboids the
different tpin you know the combinations
of them they all affect the THC and the
way it interacts with your brain but you
know at some point like we're just like
talking to a wall you know just to be
honest you know like it's just there's
only so much we can do to kind of push
back on that you know it's just it's
that's the way it is you know like the
states
regulate based on THC percentages they
just do so if that's the case then that
has to mean something to the consumer
and it means something but maybe not as
much as they think it means and so they
still grab gravitate towards the higher
numbers you know like here in Montana
which you know this is Montana like this
isn't like your standard American Market
I understand that but here in Montana
like even on the wholesale level now
it's trickled to that it's like you know
look at this amazing Wei was the COA and
you're like well here's the COA like
yeah I can't sell that you know so it's
kind of sad I think it's kind of sad but
we're never going to stop we're always
going to have all those they're going to
be here you know we love them they
deserve to be showcased we're not going
to like fall in line and just grow high
percentage thcs you know we're not doing
that here so um but truthfully it does
matter you know that's just being honest
it does matter to to bottom line it
matters you
know something which is sort of like the
50 to 100 Year extension of that
question that I've been thinking a lot
about recently is do you think that you
know say in 50 or 100 years we're going
to get to a point where sort of like
where the wine world's at where there's
only really like 40 well-known great
varietals that are grown and there's not
really much great breeding going on do
you think we'll get to that point with
cannabis or there'll always remain a
demand for a much greater diversity of
offering I think I think that that's
where cannabis and wine grapes differ um
there's certainly a a wide variety of
flavor in the grape you know the wine
grape world for sure there is um but
there's generally I don't know how many
strains that you know wine grap started
off with maybe you know but you know how
many how many different flavor profiles
of cannabis have I think cannabis is
different because of the flavor I think
I think it separates a little bit I
think it's more of a um you know a wine
maker can change the flavor you know
like
soil terar can change the flavor of wine
you know cannabis is different you know
we grow it indoors you know we both we
generally use some semi-sterile Medias
when we grow it doesn't have a lot to do
with it the plant itself does all of the
with certain environmental inputs and
and um other inputs I think that
cannabis can demonstrate different
flavor profiles strain by strain but
generally the strains themselves with
the variety of so I I I actually don't
think so I think that we're going to
probably have more strains we want now
and we probably have more strains than
we want going to the Future even more I
think that's what separates cannabis and
wine grapes is that for whatever reason
there's just a wider variety of flavor
in cannabis than Wine you know although
there's a lot of variation wine grapes
and even wines grown year to year
different regions are grown all those
things but cannabis is more it's simp
it's simpler I guess you could say it's
like this strain tastes this way this
strain tastes that way and they don't
taste anything alike but they're still
cannabis they're both cannabis right
yeah definitely no and that's that's
actually a really interesting point I
hadn't considered that yeah the
diversity of uh flavor in cannabis
certainly makes it a distinguishing
thing before we move on to the Grateful
head which we'll jump into in just a
moment I wanted to ask one last question
which is that almost everyone I've
spoken to who makes or sells seeds in
the past say 10 episode has mentioned to
some effect that it just feels like the
demand for feminized seeds is ever in
increasing have you considered doing
some fem work for the public or at least
have you had any thoughts on it you know
we we actually have and we've uh
collected some pollen here stored it um
definitely not against it but um I don't
think I have any fresh ideas when it
comes to feminized seeds that aren't
already being done you know um but with
that being said we are definitely going
to focus on making some feminized seeds
this year um we're actually you know STS
spray is you know it's pretty it's
pretty standard thing but you know we
have our own that we've mixed up and we
sell over at at uh breeders direct
seedco um so you know we we uh we're
definitely going to be selling some
femin we're going to be producing some
this year we haven't we've produced only
enough for us to do a little testing in
inhouse um we need to get through those
and pick which ones that we're going to
put in production but you know we we um
there's nothing against them they just
there's nothing really there's no new
ideas there not that I have any fresh
ideas with regular seeds but uh it feels
more fresh than you know just taking two
clone ones and Crossing them uh in a
feminized Manner and selling the seeds I
mean I think there's already enough of
that out there so it's not something
that it's not like a big passion M I
don't feel like it might pay the bills
but it's not like something that I'm
like oh God I can't wait to see what we
can come up with do you know what I mean
sure so it's it's not like a fresh idea
to me
um you know I've grown some feminized
seeds out I my experience I've never
been like super duper thrilled with it I
don't really agree that it's a way to
like um making s1's I my experience and
and and watching others that have made
them and and growing their stuff I don't
really feel like that's a great
preservation method I don't really feel
that way I feel like that tissue culture
um you know uh synthetic seeds you know
I think that's a clonal seeds I think
that's more how I would prefer to do
genetic preservation now we're starting
to look into like Cryo Storage which is
really complicated stuff but um I'm not
afraid of complicated stuff I love
complicated stuff and you know to me
it's like at making feminite crosses a
like I said there's not really some you
know like amazing idea of creation that
I have more than what's already being
done making s1's to me it's like I'm
very like um data oriented logical
oriented like that's for preservation
but then when you look at it yeah it's a
method of preservation but it's like a
last resort now in 2024 for me and like
you know 2010 it would have made a lot
more sense for preservation reasons but
we have the Cannabis has now entered
into the mainstream agriculturally and
now we have real methods to preserve
genetics long term we don't need to do
that you know so with that being said I
I uh I do get a lot of questions about
that and I you know we have all the
tools here we have all the genetics here
we are going to make some some feminized
crosses and some s1s um definitely some
Chim dog family s1s that way you know
when you get your Kim dog s ones you get
them from the Kim family and stuff but
um you know that's kind of how I feel
about it it's doesn't inspire me at all
you know it's just like um it would be
meeting a demand but it wouldn't do much
for me other otherwise other than maybe
pay a bill or two you know sure know
that that's understandable you've got
some other projects and let's dive into
it I mean the last time I spoke to you
you were really passionate in talking
about getting a lab going of your own at
that time it wasn't this current
manifestation of the Grateful head so
I'd love to know how did you sort of
progress since that time to where we are
now and get involved in this current
project and tell us a bit about
it um well so of course getting into it
like I told you before it's uh it was a
personal thing you know when you have a
lot of when you have a large library and
anyone out there who has one will tell
you it consumes your life um there's no
vacations there's no you know there's no
going away out of town without a lot of
you know problems that you have to solve
before you even leave and um you know
that's fine but as time goes by it's
like gez man you're getting older you
want to go have a life so storage is
really important like I said we have a
lot of cultivars here that we'll never
leave our hands we'll always take care
of them but they're not really popular
at the time maybe they will be popular
we don't also don't really care if
they're popular they're just they're
Standalone genetics that deserve to be
preserved and that's what we do that's
something that I'm known for that's
something that I'll always be doing it's
I I can't help it I'm I'm like a weirdo
about it I'm like a collector or
something you know so um so naturally
like tissue culture um is a way to do
that so and that's like the basis of it
and so that's the motivation and like
I've said before I went through a lot of
I talked to a lot of lab operators about
their services and see if there could be
some sort of partnership and I just
couldn't get past the parts of I just
couldn't feel it you know I I just maybe
it's ridiculous but I couldn't feel that
connection I couldn't feel that I
couldn't feel that honesty I couldn't
feel like that real true let's work
together for the plant um you know
probably overthinking it probably I'm a
hard ass but still so I decided to take
it on my own a long time ago you know
well not a long time ago but years ago
but it's a process so you got to teach
yourself and I took courses I took
training um I actually took my training
in Northampton which is where the Kim
dogs he was popped coincidentally uh it
turned out to be
coincidentally um you know learned how
to do you know synthetic seeds learned
how to do noal tissue culture learned
about the Cannabis and plant aseptic
practices had some background on that
because I'm you know I've got a little
bit of myology under my belt for my own
personal growing and then um and then of
course Mary stem harvesting uh which is
kind of the Pinnacle of that for me so
and then and then learning about
hormones plant hormones how to how to um
manipulate plants with hormones cannabis
plants so um that's where it started and
it's like okay now what all right now
you got to get the lab going so here at
the shop you know we we had a mother
room we shut the mother room down rented
another spot across the parking lot here
now that's the mother room which is
better size for the mother room and
turned the previous mother room into a
tissue culture lab and got into it
started doing it and started to find out
that it was a lot more to learn than I
even knew like yes we're clear of hop
and vroid here but there's more to it
than that the the pathogens that are
really you know the ones that are really
preventing you from seeing the choid
potential the turpine potential and just
the the the growth potential like the
the Vigor is you know they they fungal
end endites there's bacterial endites
and those things are systemic in
cannabis some of them are beneficial to
cannabis and some of a lots most of them
are not and you know plants picked this
up over years and years and years of
storage in traditional manner
traditional cloning um traditional just
mother rooms you know bringing in
mothers mothers leaving there's all
kinds of [ __ ] that goes on that we don't
even see stuff that we don't even have
names for really and so as I started
putting all my library into nodal tissue
culture I started to real because you
know just just to like kind of make some
understanding of that is that you know
if you're free and clear of hopl and
vroid and you know other more serious
viruses or but really hopl and vroid and
cannabis um you know then you can just
skip the marry stem harvesting
theoretically and just jump right into
um noal tissue culture where as opposed
to taking the Mary stem and in case
anybody doesn't understand this the Mary
stem is at the apical point of a plant
so the very new shoot that pops out the
very first shoot in any brand in any
location has what they call a merry stem
at the very tip and the merry stem has
got all the genetic um the genetic code
of that cultivar however it hasn't been
connected to the vascular system of the
plant yet so those pathogens that I talk
about the endites the the bacterial
endites the fungal endites and any
viruses or viroids hot plade and vroid
they haven't crossed over into that
material yet so what that means is that
if you harvest that successfully and put
put it in vitro in tissue culture and a
sterile environment to grow um with a
nutrient-rich you know Ager then you can
grow that plan out from something the
size of a pen head um you know it's it's
almost too small to see with your eye
and um it takes some time but it'll grow
out of that you know we we can
manipulate it with hormones to grow from
that if that happens and we're
successful once those Sho start coming
out after time we can subculture those
into other
um uh sterile environments and keep the
root system off of them but still
multiply them once again um you know
manipulating them with with hormones so
I don't didn't really feel like I needed
to do that I started putting my library
in so I started doing nodal tissue
culture which means I'm just taking a
plant and I'm taking a node and I'm
getting rid of all the material I can
off at leaf and leaving just the the
smallest part of the node and then I st
St iiz that surfac because I can't
sterilize it internally but I sterilize
it on the surface with you know bleach a
bleach solution some people have used
ethanol but 10% 15% to 20% bleach
solution 15 minutes agitating is usually
considered enough and then you put it
into your you know all this is done
under sterile conditions you put it in
your sterile medium and then you can
grow it it'll start growing and we've
all seen that I think most people
understand what that is now so what I
found out is is that even though I was
free and clear of vroid which is you
know a piece of RNA um I did have like
any plant will have that's you know any
amount of time years old especially 30
years old is going to have some
bacterial indites in it or maybe even a
fungal so I found that out what does
that mean it means that so okay when you
do any kind of like you
know um aseptic practice you know like
when you do any kind of like tissue
culture or if you're in micology and you
and you've done anything like that you
know within a few days if you have
contamination you know you'll see the
contamination growing on your media um
what a bacterial a systemic bacterial
ight will will will demonstrate you
won't see it for two three four weeks
after you've determined your culture is
uh contaminant free um so like I said
that was something I wasn't really
prepared for and what what that what
that made me realize is like even though
I don't have I'm not dealing with hop
late and vroid here at the time knock on
wood um you know there's other things to
deal with and so even though you don't
have that vroid those other IND fights
are what are making you or or or what's
your what you're seeing in an expression
of your plant that is not what it used
to be you know declined choid declin T
declined tpine levels those types of
things this more finite you know of the
what's going off the plant you know when
you put a plant into tissue culture
there's a couple things going on first
off if if you have if you successfully
initiate a PL in tissue culture and you
don't see any you know fungal growth and
then eventually you don't see any
bacterial growth well and then you don't
grow any Roots um on a plant because
that's how it is in tissue culture when
you're multiplying well the plant has
time and by the way this the growth is
slower we can even slow it down with
cold storage which is really beneficial
when it comes to um AAL um repair DNA
repair of a plant so when people say oh
these plants you know they came from gen
zero tissue culture look how much
vibrant they are look how much vigorous
they are wow they're growing faster than
all these other plants including the
Clone the traditional clone plant of the
same strain well the reason why is
because you know the plant has had time
to repair some of its DNA something that
you know I don't think humans are very
adapted doing but plants are plants are
plants are so adap aable like it's
beyond you know we don't even understand
the the adaptation qualities of a plant
like we don't even appreciate it yet you
know we don't even think about it but if
you were able to look back through
history and the evolution of plants and
you know how they've come from the
beginning of time to now you know it's
it's fascinating it's really amazing but
one of the qualities they've done is one
of the qualities that a plant has is it
can repair it's it's alals basically and
and kind of repairs DNA but also if
you're able able to outgrow any of those
indites you know one example is you know
when you take clones you know people who
take lots of clones will understand this
you know sometimes you'll get like this
brown slime on your CL your roots you
don't understand where it comes from
doesn't make any sense well that's a
fungus and sometimes that fungus isn't
even in the air oftentimes it is also in
the air but it can also just be systemic
in the plant and when that plant that um
cutting pops out roots well those uh
those indites go to work and they start
propagating and then so you're starting
to see a fungus there so that's what I'm
talking about like that type of stuff
you can eliminate those things with with
uh you know quality tissue culture
practices you can and that's kind of the
goal so when I when I to back what I was
saying so when I discovered like oh man
there's more to this than I thought I
was like I'm gonna have to take my whole
library and put it in the mar like
harvest the Mary stems I didn't think I
was going to have to do that because you
know we test here um at the facility we
have the we use Tumi and now we use Tumi
glow so we can test right here in in in
house for hop late and that way we can
get regular testing and you know just
make sure you know we do bring in new
clones so we have a a protocol for how
they come in and you know the time
period before they can be tested and the
time period before they can be
introduced to the main population and
you know I'm big on redundancy so I keep
we keep the practices here as if we have
problems because we you know just
because we don't have hop Lon here
doesn't mean that other things can't be
spread so we use the same
protocol for sanitary conditions
regardless of you know what's going on
with the library regardless what the
testing tells us the testing just tells
us where we're at you know it doesn't
give us like you know I've see people
out there they go oh I just tested my
whole crop and I don't have to worry
about this and this and this in the
protocol and I I disagree with that
because a we don't you can test a plant
several times before you find out it
actually comes positive because the way
hop plate and vroid uh spreads around a
plant um you know it starts at a at a
wound usually um more I think more often
than people realize it actually comes
from the root system sharing W water
runoff so you don't always know you know
like you can you can make the wrong
guess as I say when when you make that
decision so it's better to keep the
protocol in place regardless what the
testing is you know the people who come
in you know my guy Ginger grower who
goes and takes some Cuts he doesn't know
if I have a negative or positive you
know we always we don't have any
positives but there's no need to tell
him because I don't want him to get
comfortable around you know the plants
because he has a false sense of security
about it you know which can easily
happen and I can't say for sure either
because if we're bringing new plants in
even though they go through the protocol
hoplon affects different affects
different cultivars differently so just
because it grew super fast in this Maui
dog doesn't mean it's growing fast in
this whatever you know so some plants it
hits them really hard and fast and some
plants they can you know I mean Sour
Diesel I've seen this with my own eyes
um you know it can be severely infected
and still produce Cham noid and still
produce tpin you know at high levels it
can be really difficult to just know
that you have it you know and so even
though I've never tested that particular
plant um for hop plate and virid
positive or negative I would say that
you would probably get you know you'd
get different results on the tighter
levels you wouldn't you wouldn't you may
not know not every test May able to pick
it up and you may not even test the
right spot the tests are getting better
you know now we're testing the roots um
which I think is you know a step in the
right direction you know it it's better
to understand how things work as opposed
to guessing you know and there's been a
lot of guessing and now we're starting
to understand things that you know hop
plate and VI starts a part of the plant
and then it goes to the root system and
then eventually it spreads to the new
growth and then from there it spreads to
the older growth you know but not always
that's just how it usually works so the
point
is just do the protocol you know clean
your scissors clean your hands 10% at
least it's okay to use 20% get yourself
some scissor sharpeners that's going to
dull your scissors you know take the
time you know sanitize your hands give
it a full 60 seconds why not think about
what happens if if something goes wrong
it's worth the time you know so I'm
getting a little sidetracked here from
your question I understand that but uh
the point is is that um I built the lab
here it's functional we're doing what we
got to do but then once that door opened
and it's been I've been working on that
door for two two plus years now as far
as you know when I when I do something
you know for for cannabis and my career
I make sure understand it top to bottom
you know I make sure that you know it's
easy to go hire someone who can do
something for you or understand it for
you I that doesn't work for me I don't
sleep at night with that I sleep better
at night if I understand top to bottom
and then I know the right questions to
ask I have the right answers when I'm
ask questions and so that's what I've
been spending my time doing you know and
I've been learning a lot and then that's
kind of What's led to what's happening
now you know because I realized that
even though I try to do everything
myself and I try to keep everything
inhouse like I just described it just
doesn't always work out that way
sometimes you need a team sometimes you
need people around you who have the same
goals in mind and you know that's kind
of where my life is at right now I've
that Paradigm of it's okay to have a
team not just you know not just people
that are hired you hire to do what you
need them to do but like a team of
people that are thinking the way you
think that are approaching problems the
way you approach them it's very valuable
you know cuz because not any one of us
is dealing with this on our own and it
will only get dealt with as a community
you know um it's bigger than people
realize it's more rampant Than People
realize the faster weed goes into this
legal space the more education is going
to be required to deal with the things
that we have to deal with such as hop
plate and vroid and there's going to be
more pathogens that are going to be as
detrimental or more detrimental than
this so we have to like we have to be
prepared to meet those challenges and
this this is like for me hot plate and
vroid and watching how it's affecting
folks in the world and the potential
damage it can do to a business to you
know a cultivar um it's just like
training wheels for the next thing you
know it's like get the protocols get the
right frame of mind and especially the
right team around you to be able
to be prepared for what's coming next
because there will be something next and
it may not be as simple as you know
cleaning it up with the Mery stem tissue
culture remediation you know so I think
I think I got off track there but you
know I think somewhere there was an
answer you did predict my next answer
which was going to be asking you do you
think there's going to be another virus
in the future and the answer you said
was yes so before we jump back to where
we were I want to quickly ask you I've
heard anecdotally that that after a
particular genetic under goes meristem
tissue culture just again anecdotally
people say oh you notice it's better and
the number I heard was like maybe like
15% better in terms of like across the
board not in one particular aspect so
you know like maybe it's more vigorous
and maybe there's a bit more yield and a
bit more turs and just sort of you know
like 15% better have you would you say
that it's more than that it's about that
what's your thoughts when you
that it's all relational to where you're
starting from um you know if you've got
a plant I think the Gorilla Glue number
four is a great example right I from
from what I gather that was a big
culprit of of sick plant getting other
plants sick it got spread around really
quickly at some point years ago and I
think that a lot of
people spread around that hot blade and
virid at that point you know so so to
use that one as an example it's like
night and day I I would say
50% um I didn't have a lot of experience
with it before I had some but not a lot
before we got the clean version we have
now that's basically a uh came from a
gen one you know um but it's night and
day it almost doesn't seem like the same
we same weat like you'll show it to
people who tell you that you know
Gorilla Glue was always one of their
favorites oh I remember the gorilla glue
and then you show it to them like what
is this and you're like this it's the
same same one you know so I think maybe
on an average I don't know if I could
answer that but I think the potential is
is much you know much greater than that
you know it all depends on where you
start from if it's if it was a you know
sort of sick plant or sort of not well
or maybe not that oval plant maybe maybe
the difference isn't that big but
generally it's it's like night and day
you know like it's it's The Vig is is
completely out of control you know I you
can see it on the the you know the the
stems you know you can see it on the
stalks you can see it like it's just
vigorous more lively it looks like it
looks like it was just popped right L
not that long ago from a seed you know
that's just what I've seen and just as a
quick followup how would you compare the
difference between say doing the noal
harvesting versus meristem is there
quite a big difference when you go to
that meristem
level so not necessarily because like I
said if you have a generally clean plant
and then you initiate it noly uh it's
you're not going to you know you're not
going to see a whole lot of difference
when it comes out that plant was pretty
clean when it came in so you're not
going to see a lot of difference between
a merry stem gen zero and let's just say
I don't think that's a real term but a
nodal gen zero you know uh plant that
just came right out of tissue culture
but let's say that plant you know
because when once you're in Mary stem
you know really you're just mostly whe
when you go through tissue the tissue
culture process you're eventually going
to get rid of all those fungal and
bacterial indites like I was saying
before the Mary stem is more for going
in the marem is more for just like um
you know remediation it remediates you
know all those fungal bacterial indice
but also more importantly that's the the
only way that we have currently to
remediate from the viroid you know the
viruses so it's kind of like comparing
when you're talking about the way you
described it like apples and oranges but
at the end of the day you know it's
going to be about the same because the
the genetic repair that goes on and then
also the cleaning up of the endites the
bacterial or fungal that's going to
happen with the with the nodal too um
the Mery stem we would just cut to the
Chase and just do that anyway even if we
didn't have the vroid because it's an a
quicker way to guarantee that we're not
going to bring any of those bacteria or
fungal indites into the culture do you
understand what I mean does that make
sense yeah definitely definitely
definitely so well I mean just to
quickly bring us back to where we were
how did you essentially get involved in
the grateful Head Endeavor how did it
all start because you you've told us it
was on your mind well you know that's
funny you say that because I believe
that we kind of manifest our reality you
know um I'm one of those that believe
that we talk things into existence that
we think things into existence and so
yeah this is on my mind constantly for
years and I've gone through a lot of the
labs and you know I won't mention any
names but you've heard of them all and
they just couldn't make me feel
comfortable with who they were what
their goals were and you know how that
would affect me in a partnership with
them and so I like I said back to what I
was saying like I tried to go at it my
loan and sure I could do that but it
seems like it's bigger than that so
while I'm thinking about this I uh I
like to post on Instagram like when I
open up my Instagram feed it's mostly
Laboratories that I'm that that the
algorithm wants me to see it's not it's
not the pretty flower there's that too
but mostly it's Laboratories techniques
any know it's outside of cannabis it's
you know patunas and Bonas and you know
fruit crops and all kinds of [ __ ] like
bioscience like you know Agricultural
Science is fascinating to me as I've
gotten to this point in my life it's
just it's kind of where my you know it's
just what interests me you know so plus
with the tissue culture thing the
algorithm knows what I'm thinking at
least it can figure out what I was
thinking yesterday you know how it is um
so I like the post of a fellow uh and he
he immediately hit me up I was like we
should talk and I was like all right so
I called him up and that's not you know
me that's not something I do it's hard
to even get me on the goddamn phone but
I called him up and we just hit it right
off and uh you know he was pretty
forward and invited me to to join the
the cause and um you know I I kicked the
idea around it's it's you know the last
year I've gone through this year last
year and a half I've kind of gone
through this paradigm shift in my own my
own Universe you know is uh I used to be
like you know I've been collecting
clones and you know taking care of them
and you know spending every resource I
have to make sure they're safe even
sometimes the last [ __ ] dollar to
make sure that the plants are fine
forget about me and my you know so
um you know it's a big deal to me and
you know like I've gone from you know
these things are so valuable how do you
put a price tag on it how do you sell it
to someone else you know like how do you
like like like what what use does that
have you know like selling a genetic to
someone you know like selling a clone of
of a clone only that you can't get to
someone like what use does that have
I've I've always kind of felt like that
was no real use to that you know um yeah
they're going to go off and make a bunch
of money with it but that it like is
that really is that really all it's for
and my mind was like no it's not and so
I kind of always tended not to share
genetics clone only is not to share you
know you know my library with folks not
to sell it you know even though I could
at any time I just chose not to and over
the last year I've been kind of watching
the industry and kind of watching you
know one by one breeders start to sell
their you know breeding clone you know
their uh se you know their selections
and you know then
you go out on the internet now and
there's like clones everywhere you can
buy them and then so my girlfriend
started buying clones from people
because I'm such a anal person that I
wasn't even like sharing with
her and uh you know next thing you know
there's hop L and virid popping up and
you know now we're dealing with that and
trying to like you know protect the
library from that I'm like God these
then you call the company up and they're
like we don't test for hopl and virid we
don't we don't have the money for that
what do you mean you sold the Clone for
$500 you know the money for that it just
blew my mind how careless some of these
clone sellers were being you know I just
was like oh my God now this we're going
to drop to this [ __ ] level now and so
over the course of the last year and a
half I've just kind of come around to
the idea that you know what maybe maybe
it is a good idea if we do it right you
know maybe it is a good idea if we are
good stewards of the plant and soell
clones that are clean so genetics that
are clean and like well taken care of
and verified you know there's that too
like you never know what you're getting
and at a fair price you know um
something that makes sense for us H
keeping it for so long and holding on to
it and all the resources that we
committed to the library but also you
know to making sure that the guy with
the tent in Texas can like I I mentioned
to you before can afford it and get that
[ __ ] headband or whatever the [ __ ] it
is he wants in his tent you know without
spending you know Breaking the Bank
spend thousands of or whatever it is so
as I'm coming to that kind of paradigm
shift in my head and just different way
of seeing things this whole thing
happened where I liked this post and
this fellow you know reached back to me
we're on a phone call we're talking
about it and I just of course my first
like inclination was kind of to push
back and like you know JK be be careful
you know like people say things and but
it just I just kept it kept fitting
together like a puzzle every ation so
over the course of like two months we
started talking and you know like quite
often about it and I was taking it very
serious the idea in my mind my personal
life and I was bouncing off my family
and you know the people that I trust and
care about their opinions and I decided
to go for it you know I decided to enter
into an agreement with the company and
be part of the uh you know part of the
board of directors on a company and it
just once that happened it was like a
bowling ball as we say just started
rolling down the hill there was no way
to stop it you know um and it it's like
it's brought me such a relief from the
pressure that I was putting on myself
about this that you know there's been a
lot of great things that have coming
from it we haven't even you know we're
just getting ready to do our first drop
this summer um August 5th but you know
in my own personal life just the mental
pressure it's taken off me knowing that
I'm around some men uh who feel the same
way that I do about all this completely
understand like where we're coming from
when it comes to the plant and
protecting it and like what it means and
you know even the guy who approached me
you know he had like I I don't want to
overp speake I don't know the exact but
he had like say 152 200 cultivars that
he did that did get infected well you
know what what's the protocol say it
says throw them away start over right he
chose not to do that he reached into his
back pocket and he reached deep and he
went to a lab and he got his whole
[ __ ] crop remediated and like I I
have so much respect for that you know
that's what I would do I can say that
that's a whole different ball game to
face that reality you know and he did
that and like that that um that had an
impact on me uh dealing with this
gentleman and so I realized that I'm not
the only one and that there's other ways
besides doing it yourself so I join
joined forces and you know here we are
now now what's happening is like we're
you know now we're trying to keep up
with what we what our plan is like I
said it's like a snowball just growing
down the hill 100 miles an hour We're
just trying to keep it up you know keep
up with it so it's like the most
exciting thing I've been part of since I
can
remember and um you know that's that's
that's that's where it starts you know
so it's all brand new this all just
happened since April and you know I feel
like we've been doing it for years
already you know just because of all the
details and work we're putting into
it that's that's really exciting to hear
I I mean we're going to have to talk a
whole bunch more I guess the first
question is I'm sure people have maybe
seen some of the other content you've
done out there but if not uh I'm aware
that you're doing it with buddies of the
show Dutch blooms and Kevin JRE can you
tell us a bit about some of the other
people involved and what each person
brings in their capacity so to speak
how's how does it all work
logistically so that's pretty much the
basis of it it's we're all collectors
we're all you know long longterm like
cannabis enthusiasts collectors and you
know just people who love the plant um
so you mentioned you mentioned Dutch
blooms you mentioned Kevin I think you
know folks have had some exposure to
them and you know Kevin is an amazing
human like I I uh of course knew who he
was um but now I've gotten really I've
gotten to know him to a degree being
part of this we meet every week and we
discuss our plans and kind of our ideas
and I mean it's it's like a wildfire
like when we get together like we take
the smallest little notion of an idea
and within an hour it's blossom into
this giant Garden of a of a of an idea
you know it's it's insane and it's all
because we've been around this plant for
so long we've been around cannabis for
so long and we've been involved to
different degrees um so you know
generally saying speaking we all have
our own personal libraries that we've
thrown into the collection um there's
there's one person that um that you
didn't mention and that's the guy I was
talking about his name is is Steve and
uh we've gotten to know each other and
he's an amazing guy man he really is
he's he's uh he cares about cannabis as
much as plants as as much as anyone I
know and it this is kind of his brain
shot and he kind of brought us together
you know um he's a good networker and
he's got good ideas and great energy and
he's kind of brought us all together and
um you know made it to where it it's
like it feels like a team like he he did
it the way we all feel like it's like an
equal team you know and it is and so
it's the four of us um there's a few
other people involved you know we have a
CFO and you know we have a lab partner
um that we have that we're doing all the
the culturing and Remediation at it's a
big big Endeavor it's really a big
project you know um and lucky to have a
lab that that has taken on that work um
you know when you find someone that can
do this kind of work they have a you
know usually a pretty extensive
scientific background and this
individual does I would imagine there's
lots of Avenues in life that a person
like that could take a lot of
opportunities and and um has chosen to
work with cannabis is kind of admirable
to me and so um we're lucky to have that
of course you know things are always
moving they're always Mo you know
motions are always have have happening
um so we're all being in cannabis we're
all accustomed to that so every time
there's like a bump in the road that we
see we have like a million ways to deal
with it and the best part about it is
it's not on just one person you know
it's a team like you know no one person
has all the ideas no one person has all
the solutions or answers but when you
put some people together that I you know
this is my experience when you put some
people like that together smart people
who you know are engaged in what they do
and they care about what they're doing
and they have passion for what they
doing [ __ ] magical things happen it's
almost like it's like I said before like
speaking things into existence like that
on steroids it's like wow look at this
it's just growing so fast it was all you
can do is say wow this is just meant to
be and then you know the motivation I
think for a lot of us is you know how
it's being done wrong everywhere just
across the board and by people who may
not quite
quite get it I don't know how to say it
you know just may not quite get it the
way some of us do and I think that only
comes not because people are so
different but because of experience uh
around it like seeing what can be good
and what can be wrong and being able to
kind of navigate those those things when
they come up I think we're all adapt to
that and very good very good at dealing
with that um and you know you know me
I'm I'm a hard ass you know I'm a I'm a
purist I'm a and I don't like to [ __ ]
around I'm not trying to like you know
but cannabis is going in a certain
direction and you can either kind of
ride ride that you can kind of hold on
or you can not it's up to you and I'm
trying to find ways Within Myself to
make it better for cannabis in general
based on what I believe but not just
hiding behind my keyboard or my closet
bitching and moaning about what's going
on you know what I mean but as opposed
to like as opposed to that kind of like
influencing it changing it maybe having
a positive impact on the outcome and I
think that we're all all of the Grateful
head and the the people who are involved
with that myself included we all have
that in our back of our mind always you
know um that you know it's better to
work within a system to change it to
make it more better as opposed to just
sitting on the outside screaming and
pounding your fist and saying it's not
good enough you know and I've been on
the outside doing that to some degree
but I've always known it's better to be
on the inside doing it and I feel like
the grateful Head has an opportunity for
us to do that like you know we are going
to be providing gen zero clones we have
a library it's almost 600 cultivar clone
only deep and it's growing fast that's
the thing that you know um talk a little
bit about is that the the part that's
snowballing the fast is the library you
know because of the reputation I think
that some of us have that that we have
individually it's kind of a it's kind of
added
to the kind of the the validity of the
mission that we're on when it comes to
cannabis and the you know genetic we're
we're genetic dealers basically you know
like that's what we do we collect and
deal genetics that's what we do and um
there's a lot of people doing that and
there's a lot of people doing it just to
quickly make that quick dollar without
any regard of you know tomorrow or seven
days down the road or seven years down
the road and I think that we kind of
have a for some for various reasons we
have a little bit of a vision of that
and I think that we're able to kind of
apply that to what we're doing today and
that's what I'm involved with this
because I see a lot of that you know I
don't have to make excuses for people
they're already on the right page from
for from my point of view you know what
I mean so um you know it's it's growing
fast and it's going to be it's going to
be big we have already I would probably
guess the biggest
genetic repository of clones forget
about gen zero forget about tissue
culture forget about the remediation
forget about all that just in globally
and um we're going to be able to sell
these clones legally to basically
anybody uh the way we have it set up
with our licensing here um not going to
get too much into that but we are
basically able to sell clones to anybody
that has a phytosanitary
certification
agreement um globally and certainly
anyone in the United States so the way I
described it is if we can legally sell
you a clone we're GNA you can buy a
clone for us and our library is
extensive so our first drop is going to
be um it's between 40 and 60 we had 60
pulled for it 60 different cultiv ours
pulled um it's a matter of production
about if we meet that number and we're
getting we're getting some feedback and
data on that this week um but I think
it's closer to 60 uh we just want to
make sure we have the numbers we're only
going to have about a th clones
available on the first drop these are
all gen zero they're partially
acclimated so when you receive your
clone you're not going to have a lot of
work to do acclimating it um it's pretty
straightforward we have a nice sop for
that we're going to have we're going to
surround you with instruction just in
case just to give you the best possible
uh outcome but it's um it's going to be
they're going to be rooted viable there
just needs to be some small acclamation
these are stero plants coming out of
each row with roots you just got to you
know it's going to be specific light
requirements specific feeding
requirements and specific um you know
humidity requirements for the first
seven to 10 days you know um I I
couldn't be more excited I'm so pumped
about it I feel like I'm part of
something bigger than myself and I love
it you know that's awesome to hear how
excited you are I mean there's so many
uh interesting follow-up questions I
want to ask you I guess the first one is
as you mentioned there's this like vast
library of genetics contributed by the
various people you just mentioned uh
who's handling the lab side of it are
you guys doing it in house are you
partnering with someone you trust who's
going to be doing the culturing and
making the Clones the culturing has
already been going on for years now um
the intake is uh ongoing and it will
always be ongoing um because we're going
to be trying we're we're trying to not
just take existing libraries but we're
trying to find ways to leave the door
open to new cultiv ours you know some
sometimes you know as you've noticed I'm
sure most people in C know it's like the
next greatest thing doesn't always come
from the biggest known breeder you know
you know oftentimes it's freaking bag
scene that someone finds in their their
Garden you know it's just the reality of
it so we're developing ways to make part
parterships with breeders known and
unknown alike to make sure that we leave
the door open for that material to come
in and also that that person who
provides that material is compensated
properly for the material you know um
and those are things that we're
developing we don't have any like we
don't have anything to discuss about
that yet but that is like at the
Forefront of what we're doing it's it's
not so much what we have we do have that
and it's it's that's the the wheel
that's turning now but it's the future
you know like the next thing the next
genetics the next big thing the next
Trend you know the ne and then you know
on top of keeping like the old school
the
classics um around and available to
people who some people have never
experienced and now they will have an
opportunity experience now as far as the
lab goes um one of the things about uh
collecting genetics I think the key word
for collecting genics is called is
redundancy right that's how I've kept
things alive and available all these
years and and somewhat healthy state is
redundancy so we don't we have a main
lab we're going to be working out at
Connecticut because of the laws there uh
they're very favorable um as far as
working
under so we're not we're not under FDA
regulations the Food and Drug
Administration of the United States but
they're the ones that set the rules for
hemp
uh regulation in the United States hemp
is is uh legal 100% in the United States
um states have the opportunity to do
nothing about that and then if that's
the case the fda's regulations which are
strict um they Su they they take place
they they um they go into effect you
know that that's the rules that you're
going to be working with when you
propagate sell hemp or hemp products um
if you are in a state that most States
United States have added on top of rules
of the FDA hemp guidelines um and so
Connecticut is one of those states that
has um but however they've they've been
very favorable to hemp in that state
there's some states that are you know
more concerned about synthetic uh choid
and are trying to overregulation
kind of overstepped a lot of their
regulation uh mandates to try to
regulate things that aren't really just
him you know so Connecticut is one of
those states where they've been very
friendly so we do have a lab there um
and it's it that that lab works with a
lot of different plant cultivars but
they've housed remediated and stored and
multiplied the cult the LI the existing
library that we have like I said intake
is ongoing so the next step for the
grateful head is redundancy meaning you
know um we're we're developing other
labs we're thinking about here in
Montana here at lucky dog but we're also
thinking about you know maybe it would
be a good idea to have our Connecticut
lab St place it's there that's like the
main spot but then our redundancy could
be a West Coast you know a mountain Zone
a central zone um so that way we can cut
down on shipping time to uh have higher
success rates through shipping you know
a lot of times when you you send the
Clone through the mail there's you know
you never know what's going to happen
you know like someone could just leave
the shipment in a in a van and it could
get cooked there's not much you can do
about that so if you can do what you can
to cut down those shipping um Lanes
times you know and also have uh
redundancy in your in your project um I
think that would be useful so that's our
next step you know so the lab is in
Connecticut and you know we don't really
talk about much more it is it's kind
like the safe house as so to speak and
the thing that we're focusing on now is
the redundancy like where's the next Lab
going to be where's the next lap going
to be and you know how do we build it
you know how do we make like a um you
know like what plan would wait that like
work here here and here you know like
what do we really need to get it going
what do we really need to have it in
operation and production and let's focus
on that you know so that's we're already
at that point where that's the next step
you know um I said it's growing a lot
faster we expect it's going to be a
pretty big um demand once we release and
people start to see the product that
we're providing and the library the
extensive library and so we're already
trying to think about the next step
because we can already see that we're
we're going to outgrow ourselves pretty
quick here you
know okay so you do you plan to always
just have all the labs in house so you
can have like your own Sops and keep the
sort of consistency High
yeah um the IP is shared with you know
our our lab that's been developed it's
been shared with us to a degree we're
developing you know basically our own IP
based off of that and and a lot of other
input and that will be something that
belongs to the Grateful head um but yeah
there won't I think I think there's been
a lot of discussion about that and I
think going forward we've realized that
a partnership is great but it's just a
stepping stone to what we really need to
do and that is exactly what you said we
needed to be inhouse you know full
control of the IP full control of the
the process um you know from from A to B
A to Z I mean you know what I mean like
the whole thing um I don't we've you
know it makes sense to have those
Partnerships and we're going to be we'll
have those Partnerships along the way
but you know we've we've come across we
actually know a lot of you know we we
have a lot of resources in that space in
the uh you know biotech space uh plant
Tech space and so like as we've kind of
let this idea Blossom we've realized
like we have a lot of resources to where
we can kind of build a team inhouse like
you say and let and rely on that to do
the production and Remediation and and
so forth so yes we we plan on keeping it
inhouse right now we're in Partnerships
good Partnerships you know but um but I
think think going forward we're going to
be the next step and the next step after
that we're going to be inh house you
know that's exciting and look as you
referenced earlier sounds like there's
going to be a huge amount of demand for
this and it's probably going to sell out
quickly I've heard mentions of August
being when the first drop might occur I
took a look on the website there wasn't
any real specific info when can people
expect to be able to get their hands on
these our targeted date is August 5th um
we think that you know there'll be like
a twoe period between August 5th and um
you know August 20th 21st where the
plants will be available uh that's a
pretty Sol that's that's a set in stone
time frame like we can't get around that
you know whatever we have when that
happens that's what's for sale uh that's
what's available so um that is the time
now as far as the website goes like we
the grateful Head the the hyen grateful
hyen head.
I believe is what it is I don't think
yeah and uh so that is the place where
you'll be able to order your clones
we're going to have all the forms of
payment available and um the list is not
up yet like I said we want to make sure
we have a hard number before we offer
anything on the list we have thought
about doing a
pre-sale um that may or may not still
happen I'm not sure um generally speak
generally I don't think that's going to
be something that's going to be you know
a reality
and we're going to have a deal on this
first drop if you buy four then you'll
get a fifth for free um so that's going
to be kind of sweet we think that's
going to be a nice kickoff to it the
Clones are going to be priced this round
$250 for one gen zero clone sent to you
we're not selling plants we're selling
genetics we if and we are going to spend
plenty of time explaining and showing
and demonstrating why that's an amazing
deal you know like uh one little trip to
our lab with a with a phone camera and
you can see exactly why that's going to
be an incredible deal you know and
that's only if you can't IM if you can't
you know put you know imagine all the
things that have gone into this cultivar
being safe and clean and ready to go uh
brought to your door um besides that you
know so that's kind of the deal so yeah
right now we're going to have a pre-sale
but all the every when the list is
available we'll make announcements on
Instagram the website everywhere we can
to make sure everyone knows you know
where they can go grab their their
clones you know sure and look the
question that I'm sure everyone has on
their mind is will people be able to get
their own chem 91 or are there some
plants that will remain off the list
nothing from my libraries off the list
um you know there was never a point once
I once I went to the flip the switch in
my head you know it was never going to
be so we're going to be doing fun things
like we're gonna you know have like a a
Kim family collection that you can
purchase you know like a box set kind of
um not on this first drop but on on on
you know uh drops down the road we'll be
doing that we're going to have clusters
you know like say you're a um say you're
a business and we we can come and check
your Market with you we can assess your
Market basically your library your
existing Library your existing sales
your cultivars and then we can provide
you clusters of plant to kind of hit um
you know different
zones uh in cannabis you know like you
know like candy gas you know those types
of things you know we can break them up
for you um you know Legacy we'll throw a
legacy in there for your connoisseurs
that kind of thing so we're going to you
know one of the things that we're going
to be doing is for commercial customers
we're going to be kind of helping them
you know kind of guiding them through
their own Market space to help them
figure out what will work and what won't
work with you know with trying to to you
know um limit any kind of
uh um you know Conformity like any kind
of uh redo like you know try not to
saturate too much candy you already got
enough that try this this will work in
your candy Market Watch What Happens you
know like you know we we all one of the
things that we all have is we have like
a sense of that like we kind of been
around long enough to see the trends
come and go and so it's not that
difficult for us to identify them when
we're giving the data when we're
presenting the data and you know of
course we have accessors we work with
that can help with that too so um no the
Kim 91 will be available uh right from
my library um not on this first drop
just because uh there's a there's a
process to this and the pipeline was
already going but there's going to be a
lot of cool [ __ ] like my whole library
is going to be there one of the cool
things is is um one of the best things
about being in with this as a breeder is
this is going to free up a lot of
resources for me to get back to
selecting seeds something I you know I
never have enough time with it's always
on the back of my mind it's always in
the front of my mind it's something I
think about when I wake up is how you
know it's what's I mean isn't it like
what's more fun than feno hunting I
don't think really anything is when it
comes to cannabis that's the most
interesting thing about growing cannabis
to me is when you get to go feno hunting
I rarely get to do that you know um so
I'm looking forward to that when I get
this Library buttoned up and it's not
100% my responsibility financially and
otherwise to take care of it then I it
allows me to free up so that means
there's going to be a lot more to cultiv
ours there's going to be a lot more
genetics for us to go fine and present
to people those will all be included too
you know um there's a lot of things that
the world hasn't seen that are in our
libraries that are going to be available
right off the bat you know that's really
exciting and I guess if I push you you
still can't let us know any of those 40
ones that might be up front I want to I
want to throw my guess in the ring I
reckon TK's got to be in there we have
two TKS in there
oh guess we got the swamp boys we got
you know Ricky's TK and then we got the
the the traditional
TK so the Swamp Boy TK and then the
original TK I guess or whatever you call
that one huh I wonder what that is cuz I
thought Ricky was the one who found it I
would have thought his would have been
the original that was one of the
questions I had when I saw the list I've
learned a lot about stuff I didn't know
about coming AC you know about clone
only's being involved with these guys
like I'm getting schooled daily I have
to listen you know I that was one
question I asked I like wait a minute
there's two yeah there is and uh you
know uh I I can't wait to check out the
Ricky TK because the Swamp Boy TK
because I've heard great things these
guys are telling me it's like a they've
seen people getting 3.8 pounds of light
from it and I'm like what that's not the
one I got you know so yeah I can't wait
to grow some shill in this Library too
that's another thing being involved is
like having having all these different
clones that you know maybe I've heard of
maybe I've dreamed of but right there my
fingertips I'm I'm [ __ ] excited as
someone who likes to you know make
crosses and do a little breeding here
and there you know it just opens up a
whole new world just for me myself and I
you know and that's that's a great
example right
there yeah and that was going to be one
of my my questions you know given you've
got this new collaboration where you've
got access to this range of genetics are
there any clones now available to you
that you were sort of always eyeing off
going oh I would love to have run that
oh my God there's so many of them man
like I should have a list in front me to
answer that but yeah there's a lot of
them um there's one that caught my eye
that that they have is uh that I don't
know who brought it to the table so to
speak and you know that's the other
thing we don't really um right now we
have it all bunched up into one list and
you know we're still trying to sort it
out in different ways you know kind of
like how many different ways can we
organize this to where someone can click
on a link and they can go oh yeah you
know because it's so extensive it
doesn't it's not very useful just to
scroll through it you know like you need
different ways to kind of filter it out
so we're working on that with the
website so ways you can filter it out
with all these different categories um
but there's one I think it's an nl2 the
red fenale that I cannot wait to check
that out I don't know where it came from
but I believe it came from Seattle at
some point of course but uh um but I'm
looking that one caught my eye and I
that's the only one that comes to my
mind when you ask me that you know
there's a lot though there it's it's
extensive it's insane you know it's like
you gotta like you got to sit down with
this list when you look at it because
it's a lot you know and it's growing con
it's growing at like a pace that none of
us expected you know so and and like how
quickly do you estimate your ramp up to
full production where you're offering
say a good majority of the
library right now uh the the plan that
we have in place will be producing for
sale for uh a thousand clones a month
right now and that may change upwards
depending on demand but right now that's
what we're to of this you know the
process to get these out of tissue
culture multiplied rooted partially
acclimated on time
it's a it's a pretty you know long
process so you know it's a it's
basically on the production side like a
three-month lead time you know so these
are the ones that we're going to put on
the on you know on the list in three
months okay now let's start the process
you know so um the goal right now is a
th clones a month starting in August wow
that's exciting and and like I got to
ask do you think you might ever foresee
a day where you would consider shipping
like the marem in the AAR or do you
think it'll always be like a clone
that's a good question um yes so we want
to be able to provide our material to
you know people in many different ways
um we're going to have males you know
breeding males we're going to have males
that are we already have plenty in the
library uh there'll be more um I'm going
to be committing some males to that part
of the library as well and then you know
one of the things that we would
encourage people to do is take your
clone and then put it back in you know
culture it put it back in a subculture
right um and if we do get enough um so
what that means is like so I don't want
to take this clone out and expose it to
to the world of pathogens I want to keep
it in vitro so I can at my own house or
my own facility I can keep this going
well you could take this clone put it
back in the vitro it's barely out of it
um and then you can continue to to uh
multiply it and then you can provide
yourself with clean clones constantly
clean gen one clones all the time uh so
if we find interest in that yes we will
be providing cultures on on plates
actually uh for people who have that
skill level in order to know what to do
with those and how to handle those um
every which way we can think of to
provide these we're we're going to
implement uh like I said even males you
know like breeding males that people may
want to breed with like we're not
the door is going to be completely open
that's the idea like this is a
decentralized um genetic repository like
we're not holding back we're not we're
not interested in you being a returned
customer we're only interested in you
being a happy customer you know we know
the joy people get when they've been
looking for you know such and such
cultivar they've they smoked it you know
20 years ago 15 years ago or just the
other day and they just want to grow it
themselves we're here for you that's
that's you're our you're our person you
know we want to help you with that you
know like that's we know the joy of that
and we want to bring that joy and that's
big part of what we're doing here and uh
so if we find that there's people who
want to have material provided to them
in vitro then certainly we'll do that
you
know that's exciting as well to also
hear about the the males that will be on
offer I guess soon enough you'll you'll
be offering absolutely everything I had
a I had a really good fan submitted
question that I wanted to ask you and
they were sort of thinking look I'm
planning to buy one of these clones do I
need to scrub my medium first you know
because obviously some of these viruses
and endites can exist within soil and
other mediums do you think if you're
going to go to the effort of getting one
of these clones it's worth just cleaning
shop getting a new medium or do you
think oh looky probably safe just to put
a clean clone
in you can certainly well I mean you it
depends on what we're talking about I
mean if we're just talking about a
regular grow room there's no reason why
you can't just put it in there um once
you take a clone out of vro and you
start multiplying it outside of uh
aseptic conditions whatever's going to
happen is going to happen however dirty
or clean your girl room it's going to
happen it's not it's basically like it's
like hitting a reset button you know
like you're going to hit the reset
button but that doesn't mean you're
going to be golden forever Still Life
Goes On
um I always I when I think about in my
mind I think about it like cassette
tapes this may be I might be too old for
your audience here when I come to this
but back in the day when we had Grateful
Dead tapes you would get the recording
on a DAT a digital audio recording right
digital um that would come from a taper
that was tapped into the soundboard or
even their own microphone then they
would take that tape and they would
record that onto a cassette tape that's
gen one right then if you did it again
it's gen two you can hear the sound
quality diff you can hear the difference
between gen one and gen two and then we
would put gen one gen two you know
however many gens it was from the
digital recording we would put that on
the tape and we would uh you know put
that on the tape so the listener would
know what the quality is that they're
listening to so I kind of related to
that in my mind um you know the data is
still there you know the information the
genetic information is still there but
the further away you get from gen zero
no matter what it also of course it has
to do with how clean your space is how
clean your practices are those are
always going to be in in play but it's
going to pick up things along the way no
matter what you know now if you think
about like the Kim dog I've had it for
30 years now so if you think about that
how much crap has the Kim dog picked up
along the way I mean 30 years is a long
time but then you hit the reset button
and so tomorrow with the with the the
Gen zero clone that you get from the
Grateful head now you started off off
you're 30 years ago right potentially 30
years ago so now you have a whole we
already know what 30 years of can do to
the Kim dog we still got it we still
love it um we love it so much and so
much times but we can't we can't say for
sure that it's changed the whole bunch
since day one but we know it has you
know um so it's the same thing it's just
like hitting the reset button you just
erase all that time in between and it's
literally just that you know um so I
wouldn't say you have to do anything
special the only thing special you have
to do is follow this sop and the
instructions we're going to have a nice
little video we're going to have the
information that comes with your clone
it's going to be on the website we're
going to beat you in the head with it
just because we want to make sure you
have success I've sold you know I've
been around people who've sold clones a
lot and I've seen some of the issues
that come up with just traditional
clones being shipped and and provided to
people on mass and you know it it's like
you have to be aware like when you're
been doing this as long as I've been
doing it there's a lot of things you
just don't think about that a person who
hasn't been doing this long comes across
right like just things that are second
nature to me like things that are
obvious you know they're only obvious to
me because I've been doing it for so
long and so someone who hasn't they're
not so we're just trying to make sure
that all the things that should be
obvious to you will be you know part of
your plan once you receive your clone
and what to go forward like I said it's
just a matter it basically think of it
like this you have a rooted clone but
you're going to treat it like it's an
unrooted clone for seven 7 to 10 days
you're going to acclimate it slowly over
7 to 10 days even though it's Got Roots
um you can also you know you can also
treat it with trichoderma and other um
beneficials to kind of inoculate its own
immune system these plants are babies
they come out they don't really have an
immune system that's why we have to
acclimate them you can speed the process
up we'll have the instructions in there
you can you know put some basic you know
stuff you can get at any grow store
sometimes at a hardware
store to inoculate the root Zone to kind
of defend it you know the theory with
inoculation is if you occupy the state
the space with beneficial you know fungi
bacteria then that's a space that a
pathogen that's detrimental can't exist
in so even on that basic level right
there you know we can we have ways that
we can avoid any problems um but these
are partially acclimated which is
beneficial and you'll have about seven
or 10 days where you have to keep high
humidity low light low EC feeds and lots
of observation you know but this your
baby so it shouldn't be no problem we're
going to give you stepbystep
instructions and lots of support along
the way you know like as a followup uh
it's sort of a similar question in a way
but maybe a bit more um of a real issue
where someone added a follow-up to that
first fan question which was do you also
need to be wary of popping new seeds in
your garden because you know like hoplon
virus can be transmitted via seeds as
well do you think again you need to be
careful of that if you're going to try
to start clean with these clones I don't
really think you need to do anything
different um you know than your normal
protocol when you're avoiding that like
if you pop
seeds seeds have there's still the data
is still out on hot plate and vibrate
transmission of seeds it certainly can
be transmitted but we you know we don't
have a we don't have an actual study yet
that we can refer to but the numbers
range between you know eight% to 40% I
think is the latest I've heard of
transmission on seeds depending on if it
was the mother or the father I think if
it was the mother I'm just I may not be
correct about all this like I said it's
not all in concrete yet but I understand
that if the mother's infected the higher
it's a higher rate of transmission than
if the father was infected
of course more than likely you know uh
just you know of course the mother would
be the one that's more likely infected
than the father but that doesn't mean
it's always the case so um I would say
that people who are conscious of hopl
and vroid and it's and it's damage um
are already careful with their seedlings
you know making sure they're not
possibly transmitting anything that was
on those seeds until they can get it to
testing which you know you can do as
soon as you have Ro fruits nowadays um
we used to have to wait till we have
true leaves with pedals and then we
could you know take the pedals and then
test those but now we don't even test
the pedals we're uh testing the roots
now um so I think that if a Seedling had
hopl and vroid you know in transmission
when it was created I think that you as
soon as you have Roots you could find
that out if you were concerned about
popping seeds in hopl and vroid as long
as you understand that you can test that
seedling pretty early on think there's
much concern there you know as long as
you're willing
to follow your protocols if you have
them if not you need them um once again
you know that's bleaching your material
I mean bleaching your uh your uh your
tools scissors pruning scissors
bleaching your hands 10% minimum for a
minimum of 60 seconds so you keep your
scissors in your bleach water 10% I like
to do like 15% just to give it a little
extra why not um
and you can go up to 20% and but the con
the uh contact time of 60 seconds is
crucial um and then another thing that
I've noticed a lot of people have not
been you know privy to yet is the runoff
water so you want to make sure that
you're not sharing water from one
plantlet to the other regardless if it's
a Seedling a clone you know plants it
doesn't matter if you think I mean not
even if you think you just don't want
water from one plant plants run off
exposed to another plant's root system
so when you're cloning that can be
challenging if you have multiple strains
or if you're have seedlings uh in you
know seedling trays same thing you know
that that presents a problem that's very
difficult so um one trick I've learned I
should throw out there is uh you know
those groan uh taller orange they use
the a I don't know if you have those
there but anyone in the United States is
going to know what I'm talking about
they rise up above the the seedling flat
um and they keep them separated then you
space them out every other um cell
you'll use and this not a bulletproof
you know solution the best thing to do
is to keep each plant in its own tray
but that's not always the you know even
here at the facility we we have
different strains in a single tray but
then when you water them you know we
used to like just flood the trays with
water easy enough drain it out you don't
want to do that anymore you know it's
been years since I've done that it's
been years since I've had that uh you
know that easy way of watering my clones
so what I do now is you can take a
turkey baster and water each one
individually um that takes that takes
more time and all this takes more time
of course um but one thing I've learned
is you can take that tray out and I'll
put it like on a on a metal wire rack
over a sink or some other kind of catch
pan and then I'll Water it from top down
with with a a drram seed waterer so
that's like a a a shower head but a
really small one meant for seedlings so
it's less pressure and then I'll just do
a top down so all the runoff just goes
right into the vessel that's a quick way
of doing it use a lot more nutrient
solution but hey you know it's a lot
cheaper than remediating for hop late
and virid or even dealing with the
nightmare of it um that's a trick I've
learned that I I can share but as far as
what you're asking your your listener
asked about the seeds I don't really
think there's anything special you need
to do here you know I really don't you
just you always want to have the
protocol you want to always act like you
have hop plate and virid even if you are
pretty sure you don't because you're
never 100% sure you don't it can show up
in Plants weeks after you've tested you
know like you can testing um you can
test a plant hotl en virid it can be you
know plants can outgrow it it's a tricky
thing it's not it's not something you
can see it's not something you can you
know have any kind of sense of you just
have to assume it's there it's it's like
electricity you can't see it but you're
not going to go touch that thing you
know you have to treat it the same way
you have to you have to develop your
protocol I mean I'll be happy to help
that's something I always think I remind
myself I should do is kind of make one
for people to share um but so you know I
don't think there's anything special
about C you don't really have to do
anything special you know just I guess
the reason I say that is because you
should already be doing whatever it is
that you have to do to keep your space
clean you know you want the best chance
for Success you know like use
bleach you should be on top of it
already I like that I like that all
right well look I got one more question
before we jump into some of the final
ones before we wrap things up and I
think it's a good question actually one
of our listeners wanted to know do you
have any predictions on how the launch
of the grateful Head might affect the
seed Market and I myself thought you
know some people might have a knee-jerk
response and think oh everyone will be
able to do their own TK cross great but
I also think the opposite is true as
well everyone now has access to a super
rare maloi that they maybe otherwise
couldn't get and you could get some
really unique offerings coming out
because people have such a greater
access to genetics have you thought
about this you have any predictions
what's your thoughts well I'm you know
as you know I make seeds it's you know
one of the things that I do so I have
thought about a lot um even before the
Grateful head and you know I've we've
all seen this trend more and more clones
becoming available maybe because of the
hemp the farm bill act allowing plants
to not be cannabis anymore now it's hemp
um because you there's no THC in in
Plants um but colone lonies have been
you know I've seen the trend where more
and more them are available like I was
saying earlier the thing is is um you
know how are the producers doing it are
they are they you know are they
selecting things to produce that are you
know what they're supposed to be you
know um are they are they using clean
practices you know to make sure they're
not you know it's a big responsibility
to start selling live plants to people
because you could potentially wreck
their world with a disease I mean you
could you could really mess things up
for humans and for you know regions of
[ __ ] cannabis um so I I have thought
about that so I would say that the
availability of
clones has definitely affected seed
sales I I've seen I've seen a few
breeders kind of uh closing up shop I
believe recently in the last few weeks
you know I can't say that it's related
but I assume it is um but on a larger on
a larger picture I'd say that it's
actually going to help because you
know breeding is not centralized it's
there's not it's not Coke and Pepsi you
know um breeding is is vast I mean
anybody can create amazing [ __ ] [ __ ]
we see it all the time we see people all
the time come out of the work with
amazing you know uh you know genetics to
sell and Seed form uh things that
they've created things that are unique
um so I think there's going to be more
of that I think that the grateful Head
is going to further
decentralize uh genetics um not only in
Clone ones that we offer but also the
Creations that come from people being
able to obtain clone only that were
previously unobtainable for them you
know that were unavailable to them uh
for whatever reason
so I I've thought about this a lot and I
really do think that it's going to open
up the doors
to I mean I'm sure there's going to be a
lot of people who breed and sell seeds
who are going to you know wish that this
kind of thing wasn't happening but it's
one of those things where you know the
writing's already on the wall we didn't
put it there it's already there and this
is where we're going this is just the
next evolution in cannabis um you know
five six seven eight years ago you know
people weren't sending clones like this
they weren't doing that but now it's you
know you turn on Facebook or you turn
you know Instagram or even Facebook you
know I don't go on Facebook but uh I had
a friend I had to wish happy birthday
and I went on there and I was bombarded
with uh you know clone selling
advertisements you know you know so it's
like it's everywhere it's becoming
mainstream and um I think as far as
breeding goes this is going to open up
the door to more unique breeding
projects because you know from my
perspective I I I guess I kind of appli
to that um you might have like a great
idea like you may have smoked a cult of
art you know a friend hat or you know
smelled some weed that someone had or
whatever and you're like gez you know
that kind of gives me an idea like if
you took this and did that and then
crossed this that might be something
amazing like that was that's the thing
I'm looking for that would make this
project that's kind of you know in the
back of my head like in my dreams in the
back of my dreams come to live but you
know to go get that cultivar or to hunt
it down to be part you know to get it
into your life that could be a process
and along with that so I think that when
you eliminate that part and you can
allow someone just to Simply thumb
through a library their creativity can
get sparked I know that like I said I
apply it to my own way of thinking and I
I think that it's just going to open up
the door to more interesting I think you
know we have you know cannabis's you
know is really kind of you know it's
it's like you know we we we could use
more variety I think you like it seems
kind of weird to say that but but
honestly even with all the different
cold doors we have there's there's
really there's a there's some C there's
categories that kind of dominate this
the space and they're not that different
you know they're there and then even the
stuff that the older schools like the
chem stuff like it's not that different
from each other you know like um I think
that it's going to kind of make a whole
new categories I really think that
there's possible it's going to make
whole new categories of flavors out
there you know but I think that the guy
you know who's passionate about cannabis
who's you know got the day job and he's
got the family to tend to he's got the
tent I talk to guys like this all the
time selling seeds to them you know I
constantly am always emailing these
folks answering their questions and like
to me they're the ones that have the
most passion you know they're the ones
that have the most like you know heart
in it and I think that they're the ones
that are going to bring us the next
[ __ ] amazing thing and that's that's
why we're trying to keep a contact a
connection a relationship with those
fellas and ladies because they're the
ones that are going to bring the next
thing to the table and we want to be
part of it you know we want to help them
show what they do and what they're
capable of and what they've done to the
world you know so I don't think it's
gonna I think it's gonna change the seed
game but not in a bad way I love that I
love that so now I'm going to turn the
tables on you you have to pick just
three clones for the rest of your life
from the Grateful head collection what
going to pick my God let me go just give
me a second all
right that's a long list dude all right
from the Grateful head collection you
say huh yeah that's it well I want that
swamp boys triangle cush in my life I
can't
wait
and that Northern Lights it's a Northern
Lights 5 number one stone fruit red feno
so that's number two that was quick
quick number two huh and
then I'm going I'm going to go with that
Cheetos ah unexpected I like
it yeah because I just I it's been a
minute and I want to I want to see some
of that cat piss stuff you
know so there's too much pick three is
hard but I'm gonna say those there you
go I like it I like it okay um next
question is have you had a chance to
taste chem dog after being through
tissue
culture yes I have yep and it was
different it was phenomenal it was
really there was another layer that I
that I've been missing that I've missed
over the years that was there you know
and I mean that was a while ago that was
one of The Inspirations to get involved
with you know my own library before all
this stuff that's happening now um like
wow this is real like I I've told you
before like I started messing around
tissue culture in like 2006
we we had no idea the potential of it we
just didn't know in cannabis you know
and
um um and that's where it's at that's
what's amazing um that that's uh that
that that's kind of one of The
Inspirations that was like man this has
got to happen like there's something
more here you know when I first started
this like I never when I first dabbled
into TSH I didn't even consider you know
all the benefits to the plant's Health
you know it seemed to me more of a way
of a storing
transporting you know simple [ __ ] you
know stuff that it's really nothing to
do with you know um tissue culture's
been around for over a hundred years um
every banana you eat comes from tissue
culture lots of the fruits you eat
strawberries you know all these things
are propagated
orchids um lot more and more things are
being you know house plants all house
plants are you know it's just a really
efficient way of propagating at the base
and then more advanced there it's a way
you know a lot of plants don't it's not
necessary to keep them around forever
you know like you know I I don't know
about bananas and strawberries and such
but you could probably replace a lot of
those things if you need to um cannabis
isn't like that you know there's certain
colds that you cannot replace and well
none of them you can really replace and
so the ones we love anyway and so when I
discovered like the the Vigor the the
the the flavor coming back you know all
that stuff the the aroma you know and
Kim dog was the one that turned me on to
that of course because I have the most
experience in my life with Kim dog so in
my mind's memory I have a timeline of
you know whether I can perceive it at
any given moment doesn't matter it's
there of like where we started at what
we fell in love with and what we're what
we have now you know so when I
experienced that you know the Vigor of
of of a plant that came out of tissue
cult have been cleaned up in such a way
I mean it was night and day I mean it's
it's it's a big difference I mean it's
you can't deny it it's unreal you know
and it's amazing it's like a time
machine it's like going back in time
you're like wow and what a miracle you
know like you can't do that with humans
you can't do that with animals you
certainly can do with plants and that's
what we're doing yeah what a beautiful
and Powerful sentiment final question
for this one how are people able to get
in on this drop they need to check the
site daily is there a firm day how we
doing
it so you can check with uh uh any of
our Instagram accounts we're going to
make sure that we're the announcements
will happen there so skunk
orva um then we have uh at the Grateful
de I'm sorry let me start over atthe
grateful Head
LLC that's our Instagram page for the
company you can check on Kevin's you can
catch Uh Kevin jre's Instagram you can
check on Dutch bloom Dutch unor blooms I
believe it is we'll make the
announcement you know in a uniform way
when it's time when we we'll make the
announcement when we have the list to
look forward to we not GNA we're not
going to just drop the list on people
the day it needs to go up for sale we
want to give you enough time to kind of
thumb through the list and you know make
your plans to make sure you don't miss
out or anything like that so uh sometime
at the end of this month um we'll make
an announcement about when the sale will
happen the Clones are all in the um the
production part is going smoothly we're
at the part now where we have roots and
we're beginning to do
acclamation um you know you want to get
them to a certain size where they can
ship we're not we're not going to be
sending you like little tiny plantless a
lot of people been ask me that question
um I've been getting that a lot you know
they've gotten tissue culture plants
like little tiny like sprig of a plant
these won't be like that these are going
to be more substantial like clone type
plants um tissue culture plants are
coming from vitro stero condition so
they're not exactly like a traditional
clone but they're going to be more
substantial than a lot of times what
people have seen um but we're on track
and we're not going to say a date
because these are plants we want to make
sure that we don't stay to a timeline we
stick more to the plants you know the
needs of what the plants need so um I
think in the next two weeks I don't want
to overstep my my boundary here but I
think in the next two weeks we'll be
announcing the list as we get the
numbers counted in and then and and then
August 5th is still our Target date um
and then it'll be about a two- we period
uh before the plants are no longer
viable for sale
anymore that is incredible both in
practicality and in the excitement sense
I think that just about brings us to the
end of it for everything we're going to
chat about today any comments or shout
outs you wanted to
make I don't think I have anything man
just I'm really glad to be back with you
and congratulations on your life and uh
and all the stuff happening and you know
can't wait to release these clones man
I'm so excited I've never been so
excited about something for as long as I
can remember that's really exciting it's
palpable and look it's it's something
that's going to be a game changer for a
lot of people and I'm sure as it evolves
we'll see the uh the full the full
extent of it all so as usual a massive
massive thank you for coming on for
sharing your knowledge a longtime friend
prolific breeder grower The Man Behind
Lucky Dog seeds and the newest venture
the grateful Head a part of it I should
say a big thank you to skun for taking
the time to come on the show today thank
you buddy I appreciate
you and there you have it my friends I
hope you enjoyed it a massive thank you
and shout out to our friend skun VA for
taking the time to join us
today and a massive thank you to you for
making it this far and for supporting us
I appreciate it
deeply if you love this episode please
consider supporting both the patreon as
well as the websites of our incredible
sponsors if you're looking to transition
from combustion to vaping check out our
good friends at dap you will not be
disappointed cheap affordable and
Incredibly efficient units likewise
check out our friends at Pulse sensors
if you want to make sure that your
garden is dialed in and you are tracking
all of the variables that are going to
ensure your next Harvest is the best to
date you got to get yourself a pulse
guys it's a
no-brainer in in order to ensure that
your garden is pest and pathogen free
please check out our friends at copit
they are the number one in bior
predatory technology the spidex vital
sachet have been a game Cher the slow
release of spidex vital will make sure
that your garden is spidermite free
copit thank you so so so much for your
support likewise a big shout out to our
friends at Organics alive for all the
most incredible powdered organic
products usable in all systems both
organic and hybrid people winning cups
around the globe with their products
it's no surprise because the quality is
second to none a huge thank you to
Organics alive we recommend them highly
please check them out if you want to
take your organic game to the next
level finally massive shout out to our
good friends at seeds here now they got
heavy days beans go check them out guys
I promise you will not be disappointed
they got all the latest drops the
hottest breeders fem Auto photo period
CBD whatever you need they're here to
help you out a massive thank you to our
friends at seeds here
now and big love to the patreon gang we
love you so much thank you for
supporting the show they got Early
Access to this episode over a month ago
if you want to get extra content please
consider supporting the show you'll
score yourself genetics a whole bunch of
swag from our sponsors and so much
more so that just about brings us to the
end of it for this
one big thank you to you for getting to
the end yet again and for the
support big love as always from your boy
heavy
days signing
off see you
[Music]