hey there gang this is your boy heavy
days
giving you a big thank you for coming
and checking out this episode
i just wanted to let you all know that
we have a patreon over at
www.patreon.com
forward slash the podcast if you enjoy
the show and would like to continue to
help make it happen
head on over and get access to a whole
range of goodies
including early access to episodes bonus
patreon exclusive episodes
and extra goodies like shirts stickers
giveaways and a whole lot more
thank you so much to everyone who helps
support the show you are truly the
lifeblood of it and you help us to keep
the wheels turning so that we can
continue to bring you the content
you enjoy now let's get into the episode
hello and welcome to the next episode of
the podcast
a podcast for budding enthusiasts
[Music]
this episode as always was brought to
you by 420 australia
your premier lifestyle and apparel store
as well as organic gardening solutions
your one-stop shop
for organic gardening on this episode
we have the man adam dunn himself
it's been a long time in the making and
i hope everyone enjoys this one as much
as i did
here we go all righty so a big thank you
and welcome to a man who needs little
introduction from this scene
the podfather himself adam dunn thanks
so much for coming on the show
hey thank you so first question we start
everyone off with is what was your first
experience with cannabis
oh that's a good one actually um so
let's see i
got to try to piece together the actual
years
i was in fourth grade
in california i used to go to a school
called wonderland elementary like
famous wonderland murders all happening
around there uh
very rich area my mom was going out with
uh
robert downey senior actually at the
time right so
uh his sister robert downey jr sister is
named alison and she was like
basically my babysitter at the time and
she was a terrible babysitter and she
had no
no feel for it and her thing was to just
she thought it'd be fun to get me really
blazed
and you know i kind of i grew up around
weed a lot so i
wasn't like unfamiliar but at the same
time i kind of never
ventured into that world and uh
so she basically was smoking a joint and
kind of like passing it to me
and i remember not thinking anything
happened at all like i was just like
yeah nothing happened right and
but then like about three or four days
later
when we were talking about it i always
told her i said yeah i didn't feel
anything it didn't it was she's like
what did you think and i was like
i don't know i didn't really feel
anything and she was like you didn't if
you saw yourself i remember telling her
telling me
like how high i was you know because i
was like
super hyperactive and running around
crazy
on it but not crazy crazy obviously but
like so it is kind of interesting
because now as an adult
you know a lot of people get really like
mellowed out when they smoke but i've
always
had that thing where i kind of got more
hyped up from it in a sense you know so
i
kind of felt like it was in my chemistry
or something but yeah so it was so it
was basically robert downey jr sister
which makes it kind of ironic these days
because
you know if you want to go on sort of
drug royalty right yeah wow what an epic
story
yeah so uh yeah it was a so it was kind
of a wacky one and then you know later
on like when i was about 13 i really
uh it was funny between when i was 13 i
quit smoking weed
for about two years because i was
totally into the military i thought i
was gonna
go into like i was in civil air patrol
and i was planning on going in the
military so
between 11 and 13 i kind of like had a
little
like a sash there basically for a few
years because then after i smoked with
her i kind of would smoke every
you know she'd give me hits here and
there and then i started to kind of
get her get into it a little bit but
then i i kind of had a twist at around
13. i was like nope that's it i'm
quitting
like i went through a quitting field by
the time i was 13 i was already quitting
it was kind of funny
and then i and then i started up again
when i was about 15 so there was like a
two year
two year period there where i didn't
smoke
yeah okay so there's a few questions
that i'd love to ask i mean the first
one
you kind of touched on it do you think
there is any truth behind
that whole idea of like people not
getting high on their first time like do
you think it's just a case of not
knowing how to inhale properly or
not i think it's just not recognizing is
the key i mean i think that's the
you know because what i always tell
people is you know when they like
especially people who've never smoked
weed before and they have this sort of
pre-disposition to it like they're like
a preconception where they're like oh
it's
you know it's going to make you lazy or
it's going to make you hungry it's going
to make you this
that and then if you uh
don't know what to expect actually
cannabis is very mild as we know
you know what i mean it's mild and yet
intense and powerful in its own way too
but the first couple times you do it
so it's you're expecting fireworks you
know it's not like an acid trip or
something like that where
you know okay if you don't you know if
somebody takes acid and they say i
didn't feel anything
then they have a completely different
chemistry let's say you know what i mean
but with weed because it's such a subtle
thing
you're kind of like ah you know maybe
you just didn't notice it and then the
second or third time you do it you
really
tune in on it it seems like you know and
and a lot of times i think it's your
what people see
in you and what you like you know how it
is when you think no one knows you're
high kind of thing
and then the minute somebody sees your
eyes are really red oh what are you high
and then that kind of like
triggers it where now you feel high
because someone
noticed that your eye so i think that's
probably the reason
yeah interesting i think i think there
could be some good truth in that one
if we just fast forward a moment to when
you first started growing
what was the situation like there
so um well basically when i lived in uh
rhode island when i was about uh 16
i had i bought a phototron actually so
i'm one of those guys
and i bought two phototrons out of high
times
and i was living with my mom i was
living with my mom at the time and
single mom we had a house in jamestown
rhode island
and i basically built a little room in
my basement and i remember like
kind of like built this room in the
corner and
i had zero carpentry skills at the time
so i kind of just slapped up some really
makeshift little thing and then i put
these two phototrons in there
and followed the instructions and
realized that it was way too small for
what i was trying to do like i put six
plants in that tiny little thing
and then cut them out and i remember i
had some hawaiian seeds at my mom from
some weed that my mom's
and her friends were smoking at the time
i had some like thai seeds
and i had some
some other random something mexican or
something and it was just like
so there's some of them are just
ridiculous they took up they grew so
fast
and i remember they were if you're not
familiar with the phototron that the
medium that they use is sphagnum moss
so it's very wet and there's no drainage
at the bottom of those units
so literally when you turn on like six
fluorescent lights in a little tiny box
and then you put a bunch of water at the
bottom it it ends up
turning into like a vapor trap and so
the whole thing was just dripping down
the sides and
and so i remember uh this is kind of
funny too
i woke up in the morning with my mom
waking me up
and she's like adam adam your plants are
on fire right and i was like
in a half asleep and i was like huh like
just like what plants on fire and then
it was like it hit me like oh my god my
plants are on fire and i ran out of the
house
and ran downstairs and they were just
like a melted blob of plastic
because they uh the dripping of the
water going down the sides and ended up
into the bottom of the where the sockets
basically were
and shorted them out and ended up like
literally almost burning you know could
have burned my whole place down
so i was like my first attempt to
growing was a complete and utter failure
and the phototron still to this day i
mean they've sold
so many of those units and it's like
i i was probably one of their first
victims you know what i mean like i was
like i was that that that kid who
ordered this thing online or not anyone
online
ordered it in the magazine and uh you
know when i got the box i was like
can't be the unit this box is way too
small you know what i mean
it was like i guess i guess it is and
then i put it all together and it was
smaller than i thought and it was less
robust than i thought you know but in
the end uh
it did get my fever sort of going and
the cool part was i put that little
i put that little room together and then
i realized uh
that that was the way to grow i put a
light in the room and actually grow
in the whole room you know and so that
was kind of like the
the beginning of the fever for me
okay i think that was in 1980 that was
in 1985.
oh wow it's kind of interesting the
whole phototron thing it's almost like
people look back on it with almost like
this uh positive reminiscent view where
they're kind of like oh yeah the
phototron i got done by that too
right well that guy julian d demarco the
guy who owned that company
he i talked to him many times because
when i first ordered that phototron i
think i was probably
wave maybe two or three because i i mean
i'm sure it's been a few years out but
it hadn't
it was still the original hand drawing
of it it was like there was no photos
and it was like the way that the photo
of it looked it looked like
like so much more action was going on
and then when you actually got it
and you turned it on you're like wait a
minute there's no air moving through
this thing and
there were so many things that needed to
be addressed you know what i mean but at
the end
it the one thing i can say is that it
did at least
get me excited you know what i mean i
think the only thing he taught me was
probably internodes because that was his
whole thing his whole thing was about
internodes like literally he was
focused so much on that like internal
length and then
how many internodes and and it was like
okay but there's more to a plant than
internet
and uh yeah it was a it was an
interesting time uh
also that the two phototrons that i had
one was mine one was my friends
and i think i'm not sure which one
actually melted but it basically they
melted together into a big blob
and so we ended up uh
getting two more replacements and we
didn't want them i told them i just want
my money back
but he ended up sending me two
replacements which i ended up training
for a snowboard at the time
so it was like one of those like you
know those classic moments i don't know
whatever happened to those other units
so
yeah cool so one of the most asked
questions i've received to you know
shoot your way is essentially
what's the backstory on the bubble gum
how did you get it you know in this
context how do we go from that first
grow to you having the bubble gum
okay so uh when i lived in amsterdam in
90 um i had a friend
uh who came through
uh and basically i was working at the
hash museum at the time i just started
working at passionism in 1990 i guess it
was
and so i'm standing there one day and
this guy walks in
and i grew up a little bit in rhode
island when i was that's where the
photon thing went down when my
grandmother was it's kind of where my
grandmother's from
so i from new york originally but then
later on
when i was living with my grandmother i
i kind of
got a lot of friends around there and i
kind of forced my mom to to move there
at that time
and uh so i was very familiar with that
rhode island accent and that rhode
island sort of mentality
and this guy walks in and he's like i'm
like where are you from and he's like
i'm from rhode island
you know and i'm like oh right i'm from
rhode island too and something about
rhode island which is like
it was it was like a i don't know
i always think of it as a place to get
in trouble you know what i mean like
it's just because i grew up there so it
was like it was always like that was
like
the worst place to to for weed like i
always had this
and so i was like oh you're from rhode
island and i kind of just
i don't know it was weird like i felt
like i had to protect him from getting
in trouble or something and i was like
yeah
he's like what are you doing here he's
like yeah he came here to learn how to
grow weed and i'm like oh wow that's
cool i
gotta i'm just trying to put together a
grow and he was a contractor from rhode
island so
he's really good with building and and
we basically took this apartment
he came over to my apartment i let him
stay there with me and
we built this grow room together and i
just designed it
and basically all i had to do was make
coffee and he would build it for me like
i'd literally he would he was one of
those guys who was
kind of uh like difficult to work with
because he wouldn't let you do anything
you know like he'd be like all right
give me that except for like maybe hand
me a tool or
do this or do that but for the most part
it was like i remember i would leave i
just like leave him with a bunch of
materials in the room and i'd go and
make coffees and come back and he'd be
like
lifting up a thing by by himself and you
know just kind of one of those dudes
all around kind of construction kind of
guys but he didn't really know much
about
growing wheat so he brought
seeds from rhode island with him and it
was actually called chewing gum
it wasn't called bubble gum it was
called chewing gum and it was because
so he was getting these c he basically
he was getting weed off of a guy
who was from illinois and the guy and
the fun
the funny part about that whole story
was over the years like i had always
thought he said indiana
right so i was so i put the word out
like
that i got these from indiana from a guy
from indiana
and then later when this whole indiana
bubblegum thing came out
it's a little bit of a so for me it's a
little bit of a mystery because
i know i met guys from indiana who had a
variety called bubble gum
when i called it bubble gum it was only
we changed the name from chewing gum to
bubble gum because we didn't
think like it just didn't have a good
sound to it it's like chewing gum is
something that ends up in the bottom of
your
shoe bubble gum is this is what you put
in your mouth
you know what i mean so like chewing gum
is just kind of
because the reason he called it chewing
gum was the fact that he would he had a
bar
called the church house in providence
and he would stick a bud
underneath the bar and literally just
see what people's reactions would be
because he'd be standing there and then
people come and go
what's up dude you smell that and he'd
be like no i don't know what you're
talking about
and then he'd kind of feel him out you
know what i mean if he thought they were
cool he would
hook him up and it was just literally
like his little trick that he played
and when i so he had 135 seeds that he
had collected over
a couple year period and basically this
guy that was selling him the weed
occasionally he would have seeds so you
either gotta
i think it's either a herme or something
but basically the guy was also
super like protective of those seeds
like if you got one he'd give you 10
bucks back on the next like if you
brought him like five seeds from your
bud you'd give your 50 bucks off your
next ounce you know i mean he was that
protected he's like just bring him back
i need them all
and so my friend was like no victor was
like
nah i never gave him anything back i
always kept him so
he came over brought those seeds and him
and i basically we didn't grow those
seeds for a good year like we
we were growing everything else like i
worked for scentsy at the time so i was
bringing home seeds from scentsy and i
was trying clones and i figured i'm in
amsterdam this is the land of plenty
what can i what could
you know can't bring sand to the beach
right so
so then i uh after a year when
like at one point victor was working on
another room and he was for somebody
else and he
uh was biting down on a pvc on like a
irrigation line like he's trying to pull
one out with his teeth basically
and he broke a tooth and he didn't we
have no insurance because
we're americans living in holland and
he's victor's about 10 years older than
me so i guess at the time he was
probably about
40 and or maybe a little younger 30s
late 30s or whatever and uh so he
basically had no health insurance
and but he was like but he did back home
so he flew back home
to take care of his teeth and while he
was gone i'd sprouted
a bunch of seeds so i sprouted
the most of them i think in the
beginning we had 135 seeds and i
i selected out of about it was around 60
65 in the beginning
i went through and i had narrowed those
65 down to seven
and the seven were classified by
size um so basically a
being the smallest and uh
so a b c d e f g up to g let's say
and um i also had a male selected at the
time too
and only on my second round so i took
that i did it i crossed
i did some inbreeding on that first
generation so i made some seed
uh but unfortunately then my room got
broken into
um all my mother plants got killed
uh and stole and my clones got stolen my
clones got stolen my plant my other
plants got killed
and they literally took the door and
pulled it right off the hinges like
they lifted the door off the hinges and
uh
just so my door was just standing there
next to my place nothing in my house was
gone or met like taken just literally
like they went in
went straight to my room they took my
light bulbs it was really weird took my
light bulbs
and took my [ __ ] ph
meter so i was like my ph meter my light
bulbs
my clones and my mother plants and my
mother plants were cut
and the clones were gone and so and the
clone and the mother plants were cut and
taken like they put them in a bag and
took them
so crazy part was at the end of all of
that i went through everything and i
found
so the uh the
c so uh the middle right
in the middle the number three or c
depending on how you
remember i classified them but uh the
middle so it was like not the smallest
plant not the biggest plant
somewhere in between so in a way they
kind of like at least out of all the
things they did because
actually this the biggest plant wasn't
as potent as the
smallest like it literally was like the
smaller ones seemed to be more potent
um and so i narrowed it down to just
that one plant and then i got really
paranoid
as you would be if somebody just stole
all your [ __ ] and all your work
and so then i took the the
that bubble gum and i gave a clone of
that so basically i re-vegged the plant
because it was like
the lowest branch it was not cut and it
was cut but it was just like
there was still a little nub left so
then i re-veg that plant
uh gave a cut to tony from soccer mother
seeds
and i gave a cut to simon from serious
seeds because we all worked together at
the time that's at scentsy
and so if you look at the so if you look
back in the kind of history of all these
these people the bubble berry from tony
was the direct first round from what i
gave him that bubble gum and then if you
look at
simon from serious seeds he has which
are kind of like to me was a little bit
of a
this was a little bit of a confusion for
everybody was that and then simon
continued selling bubble gum seeds but
his were sativa dominant and mine were
more indica dominant and there's a
there's been a few like back to back
grows that
people have done like there's a german
magazine i think they did one one time
and you can really see
pretty obviously that we're we have some
shared genetics in there but definitely
different directions you know
so like one goes in one direction one
goes in the direction um
but but that whole thing was like a
complete
kind of it was like the introduction to
me to the whole industry and it really
showed me like how
when you have something because i
basically what the problem i had was i
wasn't
sharing it with anybody because i was a
little bit nervous about that in the
very beginning because i worked for
scentsy
and i saw how things can go wrong you
know in the in the cannabis world
and so when i figured out i had
something that was special because
everybody was like
this bubblegum man this is this is
different you know and really to me it
wasn't that different it was actually
like
real good american weed because it had
that real thick
deep kind of uh deep
lingering afghan kind of quality
compared to
a lot of the fruity stuff that they had
in europe in holland
and so to me it was just like yeah this
just smells like america you know i mean
i'm just smelling good old american weed
strong and then uh but it was so unique
to the dutch
market and then that's kind of obviously
where
uh you know turned people against me in
the sense of
breaking into my place and really showed
me like the
the lengths that people will go through
if they can't have it you know and
that's
that's kind of what a lot of the
genetics are nowadays is if people can't
have it
they'll you know they'll they'll figure
out a way
so i think you kind of alluded to it do
you think that
that whole break-in was more of like a
very specifically targeted thing as
opposed to like a general break-in
oh 100 100 it was like you know and
that's the thing is like i was
one of the things i've probably over the
years that because
out of all the breeders i think i'm one
of the more open books
because i've always had a shop you know
at a retail store
at that time i didn't i'd have one but i
was working at a retail store so here i
am working at sensei seeds
you know everybody knows kind of who i
am
and at that point in time you know the
thing is that amsterdam has a real
underbelly to it which you don't realize
when you first get there a lot of times
people get there and they're like wow
this place is beautiful
and so quaint and nice and it's like
yeah
it's also run by you know gangsters and
people who really are pretty deep in
and you know when when there's a huge
market of illegal drugs being sold
then there's always going to be that
side going on you know so
and cannabis whether you know people
think it's legal or not is it's
not when you're talking about wholesale
and when you're talking about how you
know people
uh view it when it comes to like
importing large amounts of hash or weed
or anything so
you're definitely dealing with some
unsavory characters at that point
yeah okay abroad so i'm
sorry so i'm 100 so i'm 100 sure it was
based on the fact that i didn't
allow cuts to go out because people were
people were asking me you know there was
like i'll give you 5 000 for a cut
like no once people offered me that much
money i knew there was a reason you know
i mean it's like
no i don't think i want to give this out
you know and so
it didn't didn't like i said it didn't
take long you know it took maybe six
months before
that happened and then what happened for
me which was a bit of a problem is i
thought i was going to be smart and not
sell seeds and or give out cuts
obviously and then that was the way i
was going to figure out who
stole my stuff but in the meantime simon
sold seeds and tony sold bubble berry
and
you know people started to put on almost
any menu you went into in amsterdam
somebody would have bubble gum on the
menu and i'd go and check it out and be
like that is not
that's not it you know what i mean so it
was one of those first
indicators of how the name game gets
flipped and
if you got something that's popular it's
going to get either stolen and or just
renamed to your or you know the work
that you've done
so and i also find it ironic that the
whole indiana bubblegum thing because
what was funny was over the years
so in the beginning for over 20 years i
basically said
that i that came from indiana then only
like five years ago my my friend who
actually gave me those seeds
told me he's like no it wasn't indiana
it was illinois and i'm like oh
illinois so i don't know if by me
putting up so then when i put out
the so now what's funny is that people
will
kind of always want to work around you
you know what i mean so when people
talk to me about bubble gum they go oh
no no no i got the original
i got the indiana bubble gum and i'm
like
okay well that's got nothing to do with
mine actually because when i
i've grown the indiana bubblegum and
it's very it's a good yielder and
everything but it's definitely a
completely different animal you know
yeah okay interesting and so a broad
characterization we've heard recently in
my opinion is that
the scene kind of started in america in
the earliest days
moved to amsterdam during the period in
which we're kind of discussing and then
shifted back to america
would you broadly agree with that and i
mean if so you kind of appear to have
followed the trend as it moved
you know was that something you
definitely did um
not at all and and that's what's been i
mean yeah this last time yes but not the
obviously i had nothing i had nothing to
do with the first wave but definitely
and i can't say i had anything to do
with the second wave but i
saw the second wave coming and i
basically timed it
this one perfect and i felt like for the
first time in my life i've actually
ahead of the game you know what i mean
but yeah when in i 100 agree
with that idea and the thing is that it
wasn't
it wasn't there was no real scene to
speak of
except for the underground scene and you
know like
people on tour with the dead or whatever
they're there in cali there was a scene
because there was
you know harvest parties and stuff like
that and the first
the cannabis cup was inspired by the
harvest parties in california
so so yes in that sense the when you
think of the industry and when you think
of the
the cannabis scene i always i always
compare it to
even though i'm hardly a surfer but i'm
like i always say like i'm i'm literally
like how a surfer is so dedicated
they'll fly all around the world just to
catch waves
i'm kind of in the same way on a
cannabis wave on a long-term
sort of sash you know what i mean like
my idea was like amsterdam was the big
waves of the 90s you know what i mean
and now it's like a
puddle compared to america you know
america's got
literally gargantuan waves now you know
because in the beginning
like when i first moved to amsterdam uh
you know thing about theirs is a lot of
small gardens maybe 10 lighters
you know are you are you're considered
decent sized gardens
and those are 10 600 watt lights most
people are like four to six lights and
little tiny apartments with very low
amperage um and then you
but there was big gardens there that
never very hard to do in america
and now it's completely reversed you
know like like in holland
you won't find any greenhouses anymore
hardly because most of those are all
being
you know checked and it's kind of like
now how we're in a totally different
world too where
you can google earth anything and count
the plants in people's backyards you
know what i mean like
but the idea of growing gorilla growing
is pretty pretty
pretty lost to this day you know i think
this is the last year california is
going to be able to get away with what
they've been
doing for the last 50 years you know
yeah by that you mean having you know a
few extra numbers
well yeah what they're doing now is
they're like uh yesterday on the show i
had um
kevin jodrey from wonderland nursery and
he was
explaining to me how they basically have
been using
uh you know like real-time google earth
which is what the police have
compared to what we have which is last
year's google earth
and they basically have been doing two
week interval
checks so they look at a place they take
a photo of everything they basically
scan
everywhere so they scan all the all the
farms
and then they look at a two week
interval and they can see how much
biomass is basically being grown on each
place you know what i mean because they
can sit there
they can set the uh the photos to like
look just at the foliage that's there
and they can basically see
like sit there and they can count
numbers and they can also just because
they know
that there's uh almost 9 000 farms
illegal
like illegal farms in cal in norcal that
are registered
with their address you know because at a
certain moment in time
everybody goes under the radar you know
and they they don't bust you right out
of the gate they wait until it's the
perfect opportunity
and so this whole year what they did now
is they just sent out letters i think he
said 10 days ago
it basically went like cease and desist
letters so everybody's getting these
letters
and have to make major decisions so
there's going to be a lot of farms
shut down this year and a lot of people
are going to realize that
you can no longer do the you know 2 000
pounds in your backyard it's just not
happening
so so yeah it's going to be a big shake
up in the cannabis world just because of
mostly because of legalization you know
that's just the way it is okay
and so if we just jump back to the dutch
scene for a moment quickly
yeah a sentiment i've heard a fair bit
is that
even beyond say some of the legal
changes which may have you know been a
bit of a catalyst for you to leave
some people express the idea that
there's almost a bit of a
a need for a change in the community
because i've heard a lot of people
express that it's a bit stagnant over
there regardless
would you agree with that and i guess
the flip side of that idea is that
that's not the case in the usa it's the
well the thing is that when i when i
lived in holland
what i realized was you know our
customer base was
americans coming to holland to
experience freedom you know that was our
that was our literal customer base we
did not sell seeds to
dutch people i did not i sold a few
seeds to english a few seeds to french a
few seeds two italians but no dutch
no hard like zero packs to dutch people
and
and so the scene there was always
foreigners
who were coming over here who coming
over to there to to experience freedom
and now
america's in that in that zone and the
thing is
it's going state by state you know what
i mean so what's happening here is like
already states like colorado that have
been doing this you know
started in 2009 legalized in 2012
have now got all that under their belt
it's gotten to the point where now
people here have the same exact
sentiment as they do
with what you're saying about in holland
wherever yeah it's kind of dead in the
scene
it's still here they're still and and
everything has improved as far as like
the shops that were just a little hole
in the wall i have now
upgraded and the same thing happened in
amsterdam like if you go there now
the shops are nicer than they've ever
been you know because that's been always
a big complaint about holland is like
you get there and you're like oh man
this place is so small and inconvenient
and there's no air conditioning in the
summer and it's
cold you know there's like there's all
those little things and everybody's so
like back in america we would have this
and now they have a chance to do all
this
and they're not even they're a lot of
times dropping the ball even on that
like
the biggest problem with colorado is
they don't have a social scene
you know figured out properly and if you
look at
other places that haven't got the rules
yet they have a better social scene
because there's no rules so it's really
like
legalization kind of destroys
that that
sort of exciting side you know and
that's what happened in holland earlier
because
pollen's never been legal it's always
been tolerated but only the only people
that were really interested in it
was the uh was the foreigners it was
like
the dutch are not involved in their own
scene so like
that's that's the reason why it's so
dead over there is that
they're not they're not really into it
you know it's really weird like
as far as they've had this golden goose
in their hand the whole time and then
they just
kind of forgot about it and didn't
didn't uh
didn't act on it properly and now here
is kind of similar but it's more of a
legal framework where the more legal it
gets and the more
stiff and difficult you know the problem
with colorado is we're not allowed to
have
any kind of activities that are cannabis
related like you can't have an event
and say come to this cannabis event
because the minute you do that you're
under the scrutiny of
the the man and then the problem is you
can't get any sponsors that have any
legal
things going on because they'll lose
they'll lose out because they'll say
they'll come to them and say
oh you can't sponsor this event you're a
registered dispensary you know it's like
really so dispensary can't read can't
like
sponsor a cannabis event that makes no
sense you know what i mean
and and that's kind of uh that's a bit i
think that's a bit of the problem it's
just kind of
we're coming out of the underground
market where
you know the first time you go to a
party and it's all cool and relaxed
it's because there's no rules probably
you know and that's that's the
thing that kind of kills it and so like
with all that being said was that part
of the motivation
for you to start the adi um
yeah you know that the whole idea of uh
of doing my own
event like that was was based on the
the type of listeners that we had on the
show and the sort of the core people
that were involved
were a lot of breeders and and so i kind
of
what i wanted to do was not create
another event that was
based on a million categories and trying
to make it so that we're
you know everybody wins it's like more
like no you know what kind of going back
to that old mentality of
of how you go we know say you go to a
party and you got good weed in your
pocket
you're gonna you're gonna show it to
anybody and everybody
and smoke everybody out just to prove
that you've got the best weed right then
that's kind of like stoner
101 right that's the first thing you
learned like okay
i'm going to be the guy who has the best
wheat now the minute someone else has
better weed than you
you sort of slip that weed back in your
pocket quietly and usually skulk away
skulk away and go home you know what i
mean like literally i've got
situations where i didn't have good weed
on me and i didn't even want to go to a
party i'm like you know what i can't it
can't be me
i can't go hey so in a way like stoners
and i always tell her it's like if you
want to know who this
big stoner and the group's going to be
it's going to be the kid who loved
show and tell you know what i mean like
when he went to school oh it's
show-and-tell day i'm going to
bring that medal from my dad from the
war and tell the whole story or whatever
it's that kid because he always wants to
have the cool thing and be the more
you know the the coolest thing in the
room or something and i think that's
kind of where
the most simple way of putting it but i
think that's kind of like a classic
stoner
the way you figure out who they are
perfect so i mean if we just take a bit
of a step back from the adi
what initially inspired you to start the
adam dunn show
um well actually that came out of uh
when i first came to colorado
uh 2009 2010
uh john doe radio who's tim martin
he was he's been doing the show for a
few years and he basically
i didn't you know i was never much of a
podcaster i didn't even understand what
podcasts were back in the day i was kind
of like well
podcast like whatever people listen to
those you know i wasn't ever
i wasn't even focusing on it but uh he
invited me on a show
and i came on the show and it was like
you know one of his best shows as far as
here i was just talking away and you
know i didn't realize that people
forgot that people might be interested
in that you know and uh
so i ended up going back on his show
three four five times
and uh there was a moment when his show
kind of peaked out because he had his
own little issues going on
mostly with alcohol and stuff and he was
like getting drunk on the show
and getting all pissy with his with his
people and like
complaining about his his uh his the
sponsors on his own show you know i was
like you can't do that right
so basically i was realizing that he
like he actually got taken off the air
on the air like
like live on the air getting taken out
by the police
because he had broken into the studio
and got all
drunk and locked himself in there you
know so it's one of those crazy stories
so basically i saw this like like and i
was kind of bummed because i'd liked
going on a show
and then i told them like hey you know
what i'll do a
wednesday show because that was his slot
it was a wednesday slot and i was like
i'll take over your wednesday slot and
just do something
so i did a show called cd wednesdays and
uh
i figured my original concept was like
well you know i can just pull out my
my phone and just call my random breeder
friends and we can just rap you know
what i mean because then it's like
it's you know straight to the source was
the idea
and uh so i did a few of those shows and
with
zero format and just kind of was winging
it
had some people listening to it um
and kind of realized that it's you know
for me
i always had a store and i was always
talking to people and i was always
educating and trying to like help people
out and so i kind of feel like this is
an extension of that
and uh so it felt real comfortable and
really
felt really easy so it's one of those
things where i just kind of stuck with
it
and then at a certain point i realized
that
i may want to just throw my name on to
it to help
kind of people know what the show is
about because it keeps it really open
because one of the things
like when i meet somebody they're always
like so what do you do you know and i'm
oh
it's a hard answer it's a hard thing to
answer because yes i breed and i make
seeds but i also have a clothing company
and i also have always had usually have
a glass gallery and you know they have a
lot going on so it's really hard to
pinpoint it to one thing so that that's
where the the concept of just calling it
the item done show came in because i was
like you know what this could go into
any direction so let's
let's just leave it at that you know
it's been it's been really good it's
been one of those things where it's it's
good to have an outlet you know and it's
also good to
to uh stay sort of relevant that's one
of the things i realized in this
industry it's quick
you can quickly become irrelevant if you
have no if you're not really putting the
energy into it
and i always think you got to you know
especially in a group situation
someone's got to take the initiative and
i feel like
this is just another step and what's
funny is i'm sure you've noticed it too
where
it's like being a dj a few years ago
maybe 10 years ago if you were a dj it's
sort of like
okay you know now everybody's a dj or
so-called dj but
but like same thing with podcasts it's
like right now i feel good that i
actually did it when i did it because
now it feels like everybody wants to do
a podcast and
you know i i i i'm definitely everybody
should try
but it is kind of hard to to
keep it rolling if you try to stick to
only one subject
yeah i can definitely agree on that i
think i also get asked a lot is
people will message me and say oh yeah i
want to start a podcast
but they won't know what it's going to
be about they'll be like what should it
be about and it's like i don't know man
it's got to be organic like you got to
do it about something that
you're passionate know about you can't
tell someone to do a podcast about
because then otherwise you would have
already done it right if that's if you
have the if you have the greatest idea
for a podcast
but it's not what your subject that
you're involved in it's going to be
pretty hard to even
manifest that one you know yeah so i
mean you kind of touched on it but
do you did you ever envision the adam
dunn show to be
like of a specific format or did you
really honestly just think
i just wanted to be free-flowing
whatever comes from it comes from well
you know
well you can actually if you follow the
if you follow it you see like you know
one of the things that
that made the show sort of more popular
and
and it's a shame that it's not still
rolling was that i had mitch
had mitch jonas on board for a good year
or so and
your plus and he really helped me format
it a little
better in the sense of he brought a
little more structure to it
um it's one of the things that i've
noticed is that
like like for instance i mean we all
listen now i listen to you know
not a lot of podcasts but i listen to a
few like everybody i listen to joe rogan
and i think he's it's funny because i
watched it in the beginning i could tell
that he was very similar to me were kind
of like
a lot of he likes a lot of subjects he's
a little all over the place
he also you know he has this guy that
helps him out and then he really is
winging it half the time and that's kind
of where i i always felt like i'm much
better when i'm doing that than when i
get a little bit too much structure in
front of me so um
but by having mitch on the show he kind
of helped me a little bit we had like
time slots and you know he had it all
figured he mapped it out
um but i feel like it's uh
it's there's an evolution to it and i
know there's going to be another wave
because
at a certain point i've had i've had a
lot of people approach me about doing
other
stuff and i'm kind of like oh i don't
know it's hard if i gonna work for
somebody because i've never had that
for the last 25 years or so i haven't
i've always
been the boss you know and so that's a
really hard uh
like someone asked me to do with what
they want me to do and i'm gonna i'm
gonna always say no
at this point because i uh i just don't
know if i could do that
totally out of my element creative
freedom right
yeah you know and it it is like my
favorite my favorite shows to put out
are the ones that i don't
i come out of there feeling like wow i
didn't even know half the things
like it's just i learned so much on my
own show you know that's
that's a pretty cool feeling there's
times when i
i'm like well if i learn something then
i can only imagine that the people who
listen to it must have been
blown away even more because they're
really not knowing the
both sides of it yeah so i think a
question i'd love to ask
a lot of people were kind of wondering
you know why did mitch take a step back
i one thing i had heard was that he's
actually not so
heavily involved in the cannabis scene
in general anymore is that
true um no he works for dark horse
genetics now so he's still in the
cannabis world i think
you know the difference is that uh mitch
was a straight edge guy
back in the day you know he was
literally the guy who would go
not i'm not going to say he would go and
beat people up but he was like literally
part of the crew
who would cruise around and be like
hating on people who were taking drugs
you know what i mean so he literally
turned his thing around 180 when he got
into weed
whereas you know i've never been that
guy i've always been a weed guy so
there was a little less of a like long
term like i have to be a weed guy for
the rest of my life and the thing is
he actually quit smoking weed for a
short time he didn't
quit completely but he quit when he when
he quit the show he quit smoking weed at
that time he had a
point in his life where he felt that he
needed to uh
center himself and take care of his
family that's really what i mean and
mitch's
mitch's uh like it's like like like we
were talking about earlier when it came
to
putting the show together and you know
he had it all pre-planned and typed up
and ready to go so when he sees
that you know it's because for him
not to say that it was about money at
all but he really couldn't
put the energy into driving down from
boulder to be on the show
to then not get paid enough and when we
really struggled when it came to
sponsors and keeping people on
point and and paying their bills and you
know i'm sure you've
kind of seen that side of it all and
it's one of the hardest i mean
the thing about podcasting is it's very
hard
because you could sell out and go to
sponsors that have nothing to do with
you and make more money but
we really only wanted to work with
products that we like and you know
things that we really could stand behind
because it's
you know very easy when you use
something and you like it to tell to be
enthusiastic about it and then people
you know believe you obviously because
you're like hey i've been you know
been using this thing for two years it's
awesome and then compared to like
oh yeah and if you want to get the
mailchimp contact mail you know that's
kind of where it's
it it's uh it's hard as a podcast person
so he
so i think with with mitch it's it's a
little bit of uh he's also very much
uh moves on with his things and keeps
rolling
uh i'm i'm the kind of guy who really
has a hard time letting go and giving up
i'm terrible about it like sometimes
even when it's not productive i'll just
keep rolling with something because i
feel like
nope i said i was going to do it i'm
going to do it till the end you know
what i mean
so we just have different different
personalities like that
but you know we're still in contact
everything's cool it's not like there's
never there was never an issue it was
always just a
i think a change in his his uh direction
but i've also told him i said listen if
we ever get like a real deal
you know that actually is somebody
paying us to do what we're doing and not
us
having to figure it all out for
ourselves then i'll i'd love to have him
back and hopefully he will you know
he was a great i mean that's the thing
is when mitch was with me i really
like i could let him run the ship for a
bit and i would just be able to throw in
my
two cents which would be always the
goofy or stupid side of everything so i
didn't have to take myself too seriously
now all of a sudden i feel like
well i can't just be the goofy guy you
know what i mean i gotta actually
buckle down every so often and try to
get to the bottom of certain things you
know
with people with guests and stuff yeah
you know i can i can totally relate to
that sometimes i feel like
i'm focusing um so hard on what people
are saying so that i can maybe come up
with a follow-up question
that i'll often come back to the
interview and just be like
i don't remember them saying that like
you know what i mean yes exactly now i
have that all the time where i
sometimes i have it where i'm in the
middle and i'm thinking of the next
question
and i totally blanked out what they just
said and i'm like oh no
where where were we actually
i know i understand so on the topic of
the show
who's been you kind of your favorite
guest over the years
[Music]
um well you know uh i love having
i like having passionate people on like
the guy that had on yesterday kevin
drawdry from wonderland
and i really love i love for some reason
i love talking to guys from new england
like uh ron wallace from the giant
pumpkin guy that i've had on the show
a few times and he's now a sponsor of
the show he's one of my
favorite guys to talk to just because
he's such a knowledgeable guy when it
comes to
soil science um he's like
he and he takes it so seriously and and
he's
creating world record you know pumpkins
out of this out of the situation too so
he's been one of my favorite guests um
non-cannabis like i would have to say
um let's see who has been really cool
it's actually like
dj shorts really cool to have on the
show because he's also coming from the
heart and he's uh
he's he's a real uh
you know like a lot of times when it
comes to i think a lot a lot of it comes
to like experiences too
one and the uh dragonfly earth medicine
are also great people to have on the
show because
there's two of them as the white you
know husband and wife team
and super knowledgeable
and are sticking by their guns you know
what i mean and that's kind of what i
like i like people that are
have been doing something and they got
they can relay to the listener
stuff they can do that can not only save
them a ton of money
but also make them healthier and and
give them a give them a
an avenue to be able to take care of
themselves that's that's kind of my
i feel like what i feel like the service
of the show is to is to give people
options outside of the
i'm just going to sit here and hype up
some brands for you because
they paid me to do that you know that's
kind of that's what a lot of the
podcasts i've noticed have been you know
yeah when it comes to growing when it
comes to growing because there's so much
money to be made in in
in products you know and so people are
always looking for
ways to promote their products and which
is fine and i'm totally down with it but
it has to be for
what i said earlier it has to be stuff
that i'm backing because i like it
yeah okay and so one question i thought
that you'd be the perfect person to
answer is
who's someone who you think has maybe
not due to their own fault but you know
just kind of flown under the radar over
the years who you think should get some
more credit maybe as a breeder or
any facet of the community i guess
hmm good question um
see over the years myself i don't know
uh you know it's been one of those i
think that
one thing you notice in this industry is
that uh
people that that you know do it for
do it for the long like do it for the
long haul i gotta think about this
question this is a tough one um
i think a lot of people is the opposite
i think a lot of people got way too much
credit in this industry
where you're like hey if you want to try
some names
no no i don't want i don't need i
i don't need to i don't need to throw
throw shaded anybody but
uh the you know the the thing i've i
mean one of the people
i think that a lot of our people are
forgetting um
is ben drunker's my old boss which uh i
mean he
he stuck his neck out when when it was
like you know if you think about a guy
like him who
made it possible for so many people to
to start their own businesses i mean
that's the one thing with ben if if
you're not i mean he's literally like
he's the dawn you know i mean he is
truly
the dawn now he's not that he's never
been celebrated by people he has and
a lot of times it's it's it's people
trying to get something out of him but
but i really feel like that guy took
more risks in this industry than almost
anybody
he was arrested like 30 times or
something like that and you know he's
he's had balls of steel he's taken
you know one of the greatest stories i
heard of him my greatest i use a lot of
it but one of the stories i heard from
him that was just shows you the kind of
guy he was
is there was a guy who um came to the to
the uh hash museum at one point and he
was a
he was from uruguay and he was a friend
of another person who
was like showing him around uh in europe
and they had their wallets stolen or
their bags or something like that and so
his passport was stolen he had no money
and uh he uh
so i guess ben had given him ten
thousand guilders was about five
thousand dollars at the time
so that he could get him get home to
uruguay because it was really expensive
for tickets and take care of himself and
everything
and then that guy turned out to be the
president of uruguay
the recent one the guy the really cool
president they have
uh and you know just to show you they're
kind of like you know someone throws you
ten
000 bucks you're gonna remember them
forever you know and so
i'm sure ben has some extra special
credit down in uruguay now but just like
he was just that kind of a guy you know
what i mean
and and uh over the years so many people
including myself have like started
underneath him
saw the light like wait a minute you can
sell seeds and people will pay for them
oh my gosh and it's something you love
this is great so he kind of like
showed everybody what to do and you know
since he
was the birth of serious seeds the birth
of sacraments the birth of
th seeds the birth of uh so many other
ones after that too and like you know
just
if you and now of course uh
you know he lives in malaysia he's got
his own island so this guy's doing
pretty good i don't think he has anybody
has to worry about him not doing good
but he definitely
i think is because we're getting to that
point now where america is taking over
uh people think of dutch genetics as
being like
not inferior for some reason and i'm
like ah
you know they were the gatekeepers of
all
genetics for so long and they
did a huge service to the world because
if they didn't do that if they didn't
step up to the plate
in the 80s we would have lost it all you
know what i mean because there's so much
uh that got at least had a home in
amsterdam you know and then could get
filtered out of there and get sent back
to america so
so i think he's he's probably the the
biggest influence influencer that
gets the least amount of credit these
days you know
and what would you say to people who
claim
that the uh downfall in quality from
scentsy is
kind of on his shoulders um
no it's um i mean it i know exactly when
it went downhill
because it was it happened right when i
was there so basically in 1993
uh right about the time when i moved
to so 92 between 92 and 93 they they
bought out
um they bought uh neville's
entire collection right so neville was
trapped and he had to get take he had to
get smuggled out of back from he was in
australia
uh and so when they
did that they basically bought his
entire collection so that
you know to finance him got him back to
amsterdam
and about a year after that
maybe two years after that that's when
they
so marcel who was the main grower at the
time i don't know who's who's going for
for scentsy
right now but there's a guy named marcel
and he was the main grower and this is
where
the dutch lost the plot a long time ago
is that very few of them smoke pure weed
they almost always come up with tobacco
and i figured that out when i first got
there i was like wow and that
seems like none of these dutch people
really know anything about weed like
they all just kind of
oh it smokes it's good you know what i
mean and i was like
but don't you notice that this one has a
much better flavor you know i was always
like
trying to figure out the nuances and
because i didn't put
tobacco in my weight and i realized
quickly like wow i could you know i
could
you could rise that rise to the top of
this industry really fast just
just based on the fact that you're
really into what you're doing you know
what i mean
that you you understand the medium that
you're in
and so marcel who didn't smoke was the
main grower
he took over all of neville's work and
he had no clue what he was doing and he
did not follow the instructions properly
and that
things got haywire you know so then when
neville had to come back in and clean it
all up so that was kind of
the original mistake and then i believe
you know it's pretty hard to maintain a
library
for 30 plus years and not expect there
to be some deviation from quality
and then on top of that you take into
effect that
you know i think the other problem that
they had
was dutch are very arrogant people they
can't help it it's just in their
blood that's just the way they are you
know what i mean so they have a hard
time
uh taking a taking criticism and be
believing that they're in the wrong in
any way shape or form so when it comes
to like breeding and stuff i believe
that
they may not reach out enough you know
what i mean to to get people to
keep them in line because they feel like
they know what they're doing
so yeah i think that arrogance is maybe
what came through a little bit and
that's the thing in holland now they're
desperate for
for american genetics that are fresh you
know and everybody's looking for
something new like if you go there now
every shop owner is like oh adam adam
adam we want
the best of the best can you get it you
know i'm like no you know
like those days are over for like you
guys can figure it out yourself
but i think that's just the way it is is
that people are
uh they always thought they had the best
weed there
and what i always noticed when i was
working like anybody who came into my
store
i had the same discussion over and over
and over again like anybody from
california
or from anywhere that was like cannabis
like had a good cannabis culture already
was like hey i came to amsterdam i
haven't smoked any good weed you know
and i have to like bust out something
and be like we'll try this
oh okay well you're the only one you
know or something like that and i'd be
like no no there's good weed here you
just have to know where it is
and again very similar to what happens
in america now
and it will happen in in australia and
it will happen anywhere that it becomes
legal or
or fully accepted because
whenever there's quantities the quality
is going to go down you know
just just and there's going to be so
much out there that you're going to have
to filter through
to get to the good weed my first shop
was called cia
and that stood for cannabis in amsterdam
and then
i broke up with my original partner and
decided to change the name of the
company at that point to kgb so we like
we're like all right we're not we're not
cia anymore now we're kgb
and uh that meant but that was an
acronym for no good bud
in amsterdam and you know it was
obviously tongue-in-cheek because it was
one of those things where what do you
mean there's no good weed in amsterdam
it was like no no no we know
good weed in amsterdam it's like oh okay
and it's the same you know sort of the
same now in colorado people come here
and they're like oh there's no good weed
in here it's like there is good weed
here the problem is most of the stuff
that's in the dispensaries
has to go be touched seven or eight
times before it actually gets into you
you know what i mean so the handling is
what [ __ ] it all up and it always adds
yeah wow so many things we could talk
about i think the one which piques my
interest the most
can we go back to the early days at
greenhouse where you
are in and shanti were working together
what was that like you know what's your
opinion of those guys as breeders per se
like you know put aside the personal
stuff you think they're pretty good
breeders
i think shanti's a good breeder for sure
i mean aryan aryan is a real
aryan is the epitome of what i just said
which was the dutch are so arrogant that
they don't know what's there's out there
because they're
they're so convinced that what they have
is the best and they're the best and so
therefore they're the best you know and
you're like okay
but uh you know he and he was kind of
more silver spoon kind of guy
didn't have it as difficult as i mean
shanti was
was taking big risks and growing in in
africa in places that were
much more intense um totally respected
him
when when we met and uh i didn't really
do much work with them i kind of like i
i
you know we were all in our own camps i
i uh it's funny because my friend
ran aryan's uh clone operation for him
you know at one point
and uh you know i'd go by his house and
shake my head
what are you doing working for this guy
you know i mean you're like we're
working for the enemy now this doesn't
make any sense because we were all our
own
in our own camps at that time but you
know and and there's you know
as much as people think we have bad
blood between breeders and stuff it's
like
for me it was a different thing we both
were shop owners we both had
our seed companies and my little pet
peeves with aryan were
more my biggest pet peeve with him was
was the fact that
what i i i felt like we were getting
kind of slapped in the face
just because we were foreigners because
we came there in 93
well i started my first company i got
there in 89 but we first started the
first company
in 93 and
about 94 i believe rn came into our shop
we already knew each other because i
used to hang i knew him from sensing
stuff so it wasn't like we didn't know
each other but he walked in with a group
of people
and they were like looking around and
all anything that i had that was seed
related they wanted it so they grabbed
all my catalogs from all the different
companies that i was repping and then
they on the way out said by the way
guys you can just forget about making
seeds because i'm about to
flood the market and make them not
making so you'll never be able to keep
up you know what i mean and i was like
okay and then he came out with his seed
company within maybe what like
three four months after that and the
right away i was like wait a minute
why does it say since 1985 on the top of
this thing
because we're in 1994 and this just
started
today you know i mean so this doesn't
even make sense
and and then uh he literally said you
know i confronted him on it the first
time i could i was like hey what's up
with this since 1985 stuff because
i'm pretty sure you did not exist when i
got here you know
when i met you you did not even have a
shop at that time and so
and his story to me was that well you
know i was watering plants from my dad
in 1985 i had 2 000 plants i had to
water every day
and i was like that is it should say the
and this is the funny part is
he always would bust shanti baba's balls
and call him
the water boy you know so i was like
and so i was like hey wait a minute
aren't you just a i should say water boy
since 1985
right and he got so pissed off yeah so
that was like you know that was
that was my little pet peeve and it's
nothing personal it's just i feel like
you need to be honest about some things
when it comes to like your starting date
that's that's kind of basic right you
know it's like
if you're you're going to tell people
that you're breeding since 85 but you're
actually talking about watering plants
since 85
well that's like i could say i was
growing a phototron in 85 but i would
never you know i'm not going to include
that into my
my data my starting point of thc's so
that was my little pet peeve with him
and then of course it was just the
the the idea that you know
like everybody says you know you buy
cups well you don't really buy
cups but you do buy cups it's a
different way of buying cups it's just
when you if you rent if you rent the
hall
that the cup is in and you supply the
hotel rooms for the people when you do
all that well
you're going to win a cup you know what
i mean so that's kind of what his angle
was it was just more of the
the obvious way it wasn't there was
never like a here's ten thousand dollars
give me a cup it's pretty much
let me buy you ten thousand dollars with
the stuff and so i was always felt like
kind of like a high school thing where
you know stoners versus the jocks that
was when i was a kid that was the way we
we our mentality was and here we are in
the cannabis world and i'm still felt
like i was back into that
high school feeling and i was like wait
a minute so now
i'm back on that but shouldn't the
stoners be in charge of the stoner thing
but again we were kind of like back on
that
[Music]
classification or something yeah
that's um that's an interesting one i
think i think there might even be a
written article out there kind of
talking about what you mentioned and
the way aryan has obtained a few cups
over the years by interesting means
but something i did want to ask you is
sadly you know franco is no longer with
us
what do you think that means in regards
to their output of new strains
well you know i mean the thing is they
they
definitely lost a good guy because he
was he's what kind of
grounded them with cannabis again
because at least you had somebody who
you know smoked a lot of weed smoked a
lot of hash
had her very um was very into it and 100
kind of you know because that's what you
i mean that's the thing about
anything there's passion out of them
yeah
yeah for sure you know you know out of
like out of the whole crew
you know it's like he was definitely the
one that kind of connected
with people better and uh
you know i really think it's it's a sad
it was sad because the
the timing of course is the thing about
you know it's never there's never a good
time of course but it's also like
just as this whole industry is about to
explode you know uh
to lose somebody like to lose out on
that it sucks because you don't get a
lot of things i'm sure you wanted to see
um but you know i think
they'll they'll you know the thing about
them is that a lot of times there's not
a lot there's was never enough
vetting with a lot of their strains you
know there's a lot of times when
something was hot i remember when train
wreck was a good example where
a guy brought train wreck to amsterdam
he gave me a cut of it
and when he after he gave me a cut he
said aryan i just offered him
like ten thousand gilders for the same
or euros for the same cut
and i was like do what you got to do man
you know like
if you want to sell it to him go ahead
but it kind of sucks because i thought
we had this deal like you were gonna
bring it to me and we're gonna work
together and we're going to
make some something from it you know
and so in the end i know he didn't give
him the train wreck he gave him
something else and quite
called a train wreck you know and aryan
ran with that ball so hard and
uh kind of put his own foot in his own
mouth when it came to the whole thing
because he
everything he described about it didn't
make any sense you know what i mean
he was talking about fat leaves and
sweet plants
and and just all these things that were
like no that doesn't smell like train
wreck you know if you had said
silvery colored leaves and thinner and
short and
fast and kind of a you know mentholated
something smell then you would have been
like yeah that's the train wreck you
know what i mean
so he kind of like there wasn't there
was always this thing of like
if i just pay somebody a bunch of money
they're going to give me the real deal
and i'm never going to have to you know
and i'll be and i'll be the guy you know
and i was always like
it helps a lot if you're if you're
involved and you actually know what
train wreck was before you put it out
there so in a way like he really kind of
like [ __ ] himself up there where
even describing the seeds didn't make
sense because if you bread with train
wreck you realize it always produces
small seeds just the way it is
it doesn't matter what you do like if
you're i mean maybe if you crossed it
with certain male you might get bigger
seeds but what i've noticed is
always when i was making seeds of it it
always came out quite small and dark
and so he was explaining them as these
gigantic and luscious seeds and so
as a breeder you're like wow that
doesn't sound like drainage again you
know so there was
i feel like that's that's you know
something they can learn to maybe do to
improve their selection but it's a lot
of the i mean a lot of companies are
gonna a lot of companies just don't care
at a certain point though too because
their numbers are just so high you know
so while we're on the topic of selection
what are some of your preferred methods
for selecting a good male you know do
you have like a go-to
it like a lot of people say you know
they love the stem of good stem rubs a
really good indication to them what are
some of the things you use
um i mean the the late flowering males
that have uh i mean obviously smells
important that's your first thing first
thing would be smell that's how you kind
of like
even decide to think about it after that
it's a lot of visual cues um
later flowering ones are better that
they don't put
they don't finish out too quick um the
uh
trike development is also important um
the uh the uh like bulletproofness
you know and also what i look for is
like a rubbery quality to them like
sometimes you get like papery plants and
sometimes you get rubbery plants that's
kind of how i would judge them
and the papery ones tend to produce more
harsh and not such
nice plants that burn kind of weird and
the ones that are more rubbery
tend to be more like they burn slower
and oilier and they
have a vibe to them so usually go for
like a male that has a
kind of a rubbery quality to it um
resilient
uh late flowering
trikes help usually and uh
yeah you know what else is uh i mean i
haven't done it too much i've
but the uh you can some
if you take if you do like collodial
silver treatment and kind of
try to flip them to get an idea of what
they might be like as a female
um haven't done that a lot though that
that's a more recent development which
i've done in a few rounds
just because it was like oh well [ __ ] i
don't really do feminized
normally but it is a good way to test
the uh
to test the sort of the ability of the
plant to
resist hermaphroditism in general you
know so like if the plant
is easily flipped where it just
instantly goes then it's almost like a
bad sign you know it's like a
that shows you that it doesn't take much
to to convert that plant into to make
that plant go herby on you
and that's as a male i mean that's the
thing is with males it's really about
numbers though too like a lot of people
they bank too much on one particular
male and unless you know it has been
tried and true
it's actually better to uh sort of
uh hit up hit up like
one female with say three or four males
maybe even five males
and uh keep your numbers small on your
original
round and then go through all of those
because
people think a lot of times especially
when it comes to males too it's like
you know they're really really focusing
on the females and then they're like oh
okay
but i got one male and then they're
going to use that on everything and it's
like there's a lot to
it's 50 of the information you know i
mean so if you're
if you're not 100 sure that that male is
a stable one you're kind of
shooting in the dark at that point yeah
okay that's actually a really
interesting idea i haven't heard before
but it certainly makes a lot of sense
yeah well the thing is it's a lot like
you know if you like i heard um i heard
that
like the cookie fam is trying to find a
male and they've gone through like 1500
males to try to they're still not happy
with anything and that's kind of the way
you have to be you know i mean you
really have to be super duper
uh skeptical when it comes to males
and the problem is a lot of times people
like the key is to flower them out
completely
before you select them and that's really
hard for a lot of people to do because
they usually are
are trying to
use the original time that they flower
it like the very beginning of the
flowering to use that in a breeding
project and usually what i'll do is keep
my mails completely separate have a
whole room full of males
and let them go really till the end
until they're like
withering almost and then you can kind
of get to the point where you can really
see the
blood structure of them and then you can
collect plenty of pollen to do
a small run you know and then that way
the pollen that you're collecting is not
the root because the problem is
in the very very first flowers to go off
is not as is not the best pollen you
know
that pollen is is usually not quite
matured enough
and it's kind of like a pre-flower thing
and so i usually wait until
they're really like dumping dumping
dumping then i'll collect
a little bit of pollen from those and
then use that on my first round
that's and then once i know though if
it's a different story if i know that
like if
it's a male that's tried and true i'll
put the plant in the room
to make seeds i don't brush those like
if i'm doing production i let the plants
just do their thing
way better results than trying to do it
by hand you know but if i'm gonna do a
test run like when i'm
trying to figure out a meal i'll do all
those by hand because it's
it's stupid to try to make ten thousand
seeds just to
figure out that they're not good you're
like well that's a big waste of energy
so that's kind of the idea from the way
we do
yeah okay and so i mean that's another
interesting idea with the
the immature pole and haven't heard that
one either but one i want to kind of
look into myself
the question i want to ask though when
you do do your pollinations
do you put the male and the female in
the room together from day one or do you
like to stagger
no i stagger it usually um it depends
though like if it's a
normal like eight or nine weaker then
i'll stagger it by about a week
if it's um like a ten or twelve weaker
then i'll stagger it by about
two and a half three weeks um and but
then you know what i'd usually do is
uh like there's there's certain plants
so that i know that i just have to have
done it a few times i'll be like you
know what
i almost do the opposite i'll have to
flower the male before because if i wait
two if i try to put them in the room the
same time they'll end up uh
coming in late pollinating late and then
you end up with a lot less
mature you end up with like a whole
bunch of those half the seeds of the
flat bottoms and white seeds
and you know that's just driving that so
in a way i'd
i tell i'd rather be on early than late
like i hate it when the
when they get pollinated and they've
already hit on like say four or five
weeks
there's just not enough time you need a
good six
solid weeks to produce seeds you know
what i mean that's how i feel like if
there's less than six weeks i feel like
i'm undercooking them you know yeah for
sure
and so on the james bean interview he
referenced that you might be doing
a little project in the future whereby
you're
releasing some pollen in combination
with a few different crosses is that
something that's still going to go ahead
it is but not as quickly as i thought
actually
um that i had i had uh
my one of my one of my projects get sort
of stifled in the middle of it uh
i lost uh i lost a particular place
just like we do to the man himself
because like a lot of my breeding
projects
all my breeding projects are underground
still you know what i mean because i
don't
trust any i can't do it in a facility
because of the protocols are so extreme
that it's just
how am i gonna get you know i can't even
work with my material because all of a
sudden
every little gram of the material
whether it be seed or stem or whatever
is all
being organized and classified so so i
do everything
still on the underground which puts me
at risk and unfortunately the
that particular project which is called
everybody loves bodhi
and i i took some bodhi body had given
me um
a tester of something that he hadn't
released yet which was
uh called jasmine cat piss it was a snow
lotus hybrid
um and i got a really
consistent batch like everything on it
was just like the males and the females
looked almost identical
um so i took two males i only had 12
plants to begin with
or 12 seeds to begin with and out of
those 12 seeds i got like nine plants i
believe and then
from those two good meals and then the
rest a couple males that were a little
bit
wonky but uh ended up with this one male
short fat trikey for you know really
decent little plant
um and that male i managed to keep the
male i was lucky because even though i
lost the the place
uh because it's colorado they like they
let you
they left 36 of the smallest
clones basically they they took
everything else so they uh
but kind it's always funny because when
you're like compared to what it used to
be back in the day they take everything
right take all your lights take all your
plants take everything
this time it was like they took all your
plants but they said oh you have a you
have a
you have a medical record you have a
medical card for 36 so we'll leave you
with 36 but we're going to leave you
with the smallest 36
and luckily one of those was the mail
that i was going to use for the pollen
my mate
but but there's not enough time for for
this particular round so
um yes the idea on the everybody loves
bodhi project was
to do um a sort of open-ended breeding
project and then that way
whoever i was going to do a short amount
like i said maybe maybe
30 of these and then the idea would be
you have a bunch of f1s
a a few less but a bunch of
f2s and a couple f3s
and then the pollen that i used on the
original f1 crosses
so that way you could take that project
and go backwards with it a little bit
and go you know
the idea would be as breeders you buy it
you have all these seeds to go through
and you have the original pollen off the
male that i use so that you can always
go and use
your own back roses
i thought it'd be fun because i wanted
to because bodhi's
way of growing or way of breeding is a
little bit um i wouldn't say it's
different but he definitely
kind of does that on his own he has this
he does everything to f2
and then he leaves it at that and then
you as a
grower get
kind of like you're to me it's sort of
like you're in the middle you know i
mean you're not quite there you need to
go
like f1s are a little bit more explosive
f2s are a little bit more uh
you start to get into like camps eight
you know you have
the two different you'll have more
phenotypical
exp well you have less phenotypical
expression as you would in the f1 but
you'll have
groups you know that are more defined so
i kind of just thought
so it's kind of like a different way of
looking at it and the idea was that
you'd have to buy the whole thing you
know i mean you buy
so you you buy the uh a couple hundred
seeds at one given time so you have
these projects that are then i wanted to
i mostly wanted to do it to see what
direction people would take them you
know
that way and then tell everybody these
are all you can use
all this stuff do whatever you want with
it i'm not gonna
not trying to isolate
it and tell you anybody you can't use it
because also is from bodhi and then i
wanted to give 25
of that to the charity of bodhi's choice
which he
chose a group from oaxaca uh there's a
place down in oaxaca
which uh he would hand deliver the the
check
so we're gonna do it but i'm probably
gonna do it next year cause
it's one of those things where you can't
can't release that kind of a project
without
feeling like it's uh it's where it's
supposed to be
yeah and do you see this as being a
common thing in the future because we
have seen
a few little pollen releases here and
there is this again
oh yeah on board the next wave well you
know i think it's definitely going to
happen because the reality is
um that is that like when i do whenever
i
have a question and answer thing at a
seminar or something that's
one of the main questions is selecting
males and
because we've all shared all these
common female plants over the years
very very few breeders share males and
if they do
it gets usually it's like so for
instance like a good example
is the g13 haze male that soma uses on a
lot of his crosses
he gave that same male to dna who then
used
it in a bunch of their crosses who then
gave it to paradise seeds he used it in
their crosses who gave it to
you know everybody like every uh
delta nine used that same male and a
bunch of their crosses you know it's
just like kind of like
and so for me that was like completely
off limits i was like i will never use
that nail because then we're all
you know we're all in the same boat
whereas the females had no problem
everybody can use the same female but as
long as there's a different male in the
mix it
kind of puts everybody in their own
direction so i think that's been kind of
the main reason why everybody hasn't
been doing it because they'll kind of
want to keep their
their thing unique but i also see that
people are willing to pay because you
know half a gram of pollen is plenty
you can do a lot of damage with that so
you know the market will dictate where
it goes and i just think there hasn't
been enough breeders out there to make
it worth it but nowadays
since everybody's a breeder just like
everybody was a dj you know it's like
everybody's a podcaster i just happen to
be all three right
um but yeah it's like it's kind of the
uh
it is kind of uh inevitable that that's
going to become
another baseball i think you know who
else is doing that was um dj
short son i think was doing a jd yeah
yeah something i was interested in those
i've been thinking about this idea a lot
and
obviously not quite entirely related to
the pollen idea because probably a lot
of
more new breeders so to speak aspiring
breed is going to be people interested
in that
as for like top end breeders already
selling seeds
they're probably less likely to be
buying that pollen but
the question remains you know given you
just highlighted how males from other
people
do get used do you think it's it's a bit
of a stretch to call yourself a breeder
in that situation because
i think fundamentally when you break it
down being a breeder means there's some
form of selection involved
so if you were just to use a male from
someone else you didn't select it
and then like a clone only like where's
the selection taking place
yeah no i mean again that you're a
replicator at that point that's what i
used to that that was my other little
joke i used to do with aria and i was
like ariane you're not a breeder you're
a replicator you know because that's all
you're doing is
replicating other work that other people
have done um but i kind of feel like
that is uh
yeah that's a different class because it
again it's it's like the um
it's like the meme where i forgot
exactly how it goes but it was like you
know
i need two like the guy that was under
the car and the game and he's like i
need i need two packs of this and
like whatever and stickers and and i've
done less you know i've made a seed
company out of less that's kind of where
we're at where
you know and that's one of the things
where you notice you see people's gears
turning when they're when the first time
they're understanding like
that people are paying money for these
beans and
oh well if they're paying that much
money then i should do this you know and
that that's definitely not the
inspiration that you need
the inspiration should be you know you
you want to
uh you love the plant enough that you
can
yeah take the energy to to
waste a bunch of time and and to get to
a point and that's that's
it's never on the first round you know
what i mean that's like that's one of
the reasons also why this whole everyone
loves bodhi project i'm like
okay i'm not i'm not as content
yet with where i'm at you know i want to
take it to the next level what i am
going to do though is
a line called sagemaster select which is
the the bigger picture
um i'll have my first round of uh
of things coming on the uh at the
emerald cup
so i'll have six crosses i'll have six
crosses i have a male
uh sage male that that we selected here
from
uh that's like a green onion it's got
like a green onion
flavor to it uh that imparts on
everything which is really nice
and it's kind of a it's kind of like
somewhere between garlic bud
and onion flavor which uh is a little
a little bit different than the original
sage which has more of a sandalwood vibe
but it's amazingly vigorous
uh and i've just did six crosses well
i've done a bunch but i did a bunch more
but i got six that have selected out
that i'm gonna or
on that i'm gonna bring into uh the
hammer cup this year
yeah awesome so one question that we got
sent in a lot was and one i kind of
looked into was interested in myself
on the thc site it says um that you guys
have won a few cups with the underdog
kush how does that one differ from
lumpers underdog is it is it different
it's different it's different yeah um
yeah
john and i had that we we as a moment in
time a classic where you know we
we didn't know each other but i kept
hearing from people like yeah lump was
mad because
you know the underdog thing and i was
like oh okay that was actually
uh because i i had okay here
it's it's a weird it's a it's a it's a
it's a weird one too so basically i got
underdog from uh
from jj and aj about nine years ago
and i got it with i got guava cam
underdog corey haim cut
and so it's two different star dogs this
the regular star dog and the cory game
cut and lumpa
i think lumpus is like a sour kush
cross more and it
so he and he named his underdog cush
and then the problem was that okay so
ours was just the underdog
and then my partner doug in amsterdam he
he basically put kush behind anything
that had og in it or kush
because the customer base in holland
like they just all
that was the hype word of the year you
know gosh if it doesn't have cush we
don't want it
so because when he called it underdog
people didn't get it you know uh
yeah so it was really like a named
put on it to for selling points more
than and not just because
it had cush in it but it just was or it
didn't even have cushion it was
underdog which that's and that's the
funny part about the whole
when i first got kush and i first got
sour which was in
about 99 uh i brought him back from
from from the states and i brought it to
amsterdam
and when i got there i had wrapped them
i'd put them into groups and i'd wrapped
them with
uh one of those uh garbage bag
things you know little zip ties and uh
i'd wrapped them into two groups and
then i wrote on them
and just didn't know how you know how
small that area is i'm like wrote with a
permanent marker like
og on one and then sd on the other one
and when i got there i couldn't [ __ ]
read them quickly i could not read i was
like oh what
oh i don't know which ones are which but
i'll figure it out then i grew them out
and
they're damn close you know what i mean
when you don't really know what's going
on like you have no idea
had zero and the funny part was that our
uh that soma had completely [ __ ] up my
head when it came
to the to the diesels because he had
came up with his diesel which was
purple and grapefruit smelling and just
had nothing to do with sour diesel and
so
i'd only heard about sour diesel even
though my friends who were the ones who
were growing it back in
the states that i met when i was in
amsterdam
they never brought it with them they
were always scared to fly into amsterdam
with weed you know
and so until 99
until i actually went and got the cuts i
didn't ever try it so
i flew back i got the cuts flew back
grew him out
and it took me like a good two runs
before i was 100 convinced like this is
sour diesel
that is the kush um now i can see the
difference obviously and now it's like
totally like i
now i see when other people don't see
the difference but
um the whole underdog story got a little
bit confusing too because
there was um
uh you know there was like that version
that he had he put out and then
i guess those guys lost like aj and jj
and everybody lost
that original one and so
when i put out then when i finally got
jj
to look at the underdog that i had he
claimed it was the corey haim cut so now
it got really confusing i was like wait
a minute i had the korean cut and i had
this star dog and i had the guava so i'm
like
god so it got a little confusing so i
was one of those yeah i think that
to this i mean i know that they're
totally different plants but people will
be confused
for eons to come i will never get that
will never get totally separated on me
just because i've been losing the
original underdog and then
lumpa having his version of underdog and
then
th seeds europe which i kind of have to
separate because
i'm not involved directly with what
they're doing i'll send them
i will send them stuff and uh they can
work with it every so often but i'm not
like
on the inner workings of a lot of the
things and like for instance that
underdog is the same
cut that i left them with so i know what
i left them with
and yeah but to this day
yeah now it's just hard for me to know
because until i can get them to
get me that back over to here and be
able to show that to aj or
jj and aj and have them confirm whether
or not
it is or it isn't but you know i think
also there's a little bit of the
hoping i don't have it you know i mean a
little bit a little bit like i hope he
doesn't really have it still
whatever it is the thing we have was
really really good and that's why he
keeps winning
out in europe and stuff also yeah so i
mean
there's certainly been some whispers
that the
clone which goes around as the you know
original sour
is maybe not the original what's your
thoughts on this one
um well you know interestingly enough
next week i'll be hanging out with the
bro
and i'm trying to get the bro to come on
my show and the bro is really like the
key to the whole
sour story because he was one of the
financers of the
of the whole project back in the day
because it was literally
um you know a bunch of guys who are kids
really when you think about it
um and then my friend who is the bro who
is kind of like guiding them you know
and helping them uh with this with that
project and
basically by paying overpriced amounts
to them
at all times just to keep it in-house
you know
um they still have the cut of off the
original
which they're getting analyzed now so
that we'll have a baseline
the cut that i have came from from hal
who's the guy that worked for them
or what kind of he's the guy who popped
the bean the original bean
and when it comes to the sours like for
instance that aj's put out i think is
different
you know um it's
it might be an f1 but it's definitely
not exactly the same um
yeah i think for the most part most
people haven't seen it lately you know
if they haven't been if they weren't in
new york in the 90s
uh to the you know late 90s to the 2000s
early 2000s then they probably
have seen a version which is not the
original i'm more than convinced
yeah that's a sentiment i've heard
expressed commonly
a question yeah do you want to run but
it's also hard but it's also hard
because of the fact that the sour was
never a stable plant to begin with you
know
stability was never it's its highlight
it was never its focus
so like the fact that it would throw
nanners
and uh be very hard to breed with and
get a lot of
kind of i had a bunch of batches that
were seeds that were
you know very low germ rates things like
that
so i don't think sour's ever been one of
the the most
stable cornerstone plans to work with
and it you know
it came as a mistake so it's part of the
deal you know whenever you're
uh working with material that came from
from
mis from a great mystery in the sky then
you know there's
it's hard to decide whether or not
that's going to be the longest or not
even decide it's hard to
to rely on that as being a super stable
thing long term
yeah so i'll go to questions and i think
there's a little fantasy i think there's
a little fantasy
too when it comes to sour diesel though
as far as like when you're
17 years old and you're at a concert in
new york and you're super blazed and you
smoke something in this
best thing you've ever smoked and now
you're in your 40s
and you smoked a ton of wheat in between
that
you may take you may in your mind have a
little bit more
uh you may think of that as being a
little bit more of a
amazing thing than it really was or
different than it really was you know
yeah fully so a question i do want to
run by
in relation to one of the industry
heavyweights that you made the mk ultra
so when i first heard that catatonic
was you know had mk ultra in it i was a
little bit surprised because
when you look at the overall cross it
just doesn't really seem to jump out on
paper
i don't know if you've seen it but since
then the guys who may have come out and
said
like oh no we got the genetics wrong
it's actually these other things
did you did you kind of suspect that
from the start or were you kind of yeah
i was a little yeah no i mean part of me
was like great
this is awesome i can't believe it but
then a part of me was like well i
just don't see how yeah no 100 agree on
that because i
the thing is when it first came out okay
so resin seeds which was um
the the
son-in-law of soma alex and alex is like
notorious for
for flipping names and doing crazy stuff
like that so i wasn't
so i already was a little little
concerned when he first told me that
that's what they used because also i
felt like he
uh he knew that if he said it was
something of mine
that it would be uh
well if like he could he could say that
would make me excited for instance which
i was at the beginning i was like wow we
actually
had meetings with bayer you know over it
and stuff it was like one of those like
we're gonna
like all of a sudden it was like wow
this could be the next big thing right
um but part of me knew like out of the
gate that
it was like having a kid you know i mean
it's like when you have a if you have a
kid and it's not your kid
part of you will accept that as your kid
just because
you get into it you go into that drive
you know what i mean your body oh that's
it this is my kid
you're gonna deny it in your mind if you
accept it you know what i mean if you
don't want a kid you may never accept it
but
it's sort of the same idea where this is
you know somebody tells you that your
plant produced something that is now
being considered by bayer
pharmaceuticals because of the fact that
they're looking for the next big cbd
project or something you're like whoa
this is major news
but it also when we when we went to that
meeting i totally was like i would never
work for pink i would never ever want to
work with any kind of large
pharmaceutical corporation this is
horrible you know so
kind of part of me is happy that it's
not involved just because
it's not yeah i wouldn't say i wouldn't
say i'm happy that but
it is kind of like people whoever
whatever genetics it's responsible for
need to be
clearly you know get the get the
reputation for it because it is
going to send a lot of people on the
wrong direction if they're going to buy
mk ultra seeds
hoping to find the next catatonic mother
plant you know what i mean
they're going to be probably mistaken
you know
so i mean while we're on the topic of
cbd plants and kind of breeding programs
if you if you were to do some cbd you
know offerings
what would they be in regards to the cbd
to thc
chemotype because a lot of people think
that that's kind of where the real
magic lies you know in that ratio yeah
i mean really like so in nature
if you leak so if you have a field of
ten thousand or a hundred thousand
plants and you let them just cross breed
and open pollinate
if you had say for instance you had a
lot of high cbd plants in that in that
field and you had a lot of high thc
plants in that field and you let them go
a couple years in a row and they
continuously cross bred open pollination
like that
you will naturally end up with a pretty
much a one-to-one ratio
and i kind of feel like that is the the
most
homeostasic sort of part of the like
that is literally the balance right
there the perfect balance um and
everything else is adjustments on that
scale
so some patients might need a two to one
or they might need a ten to one you know
maybe but usually
most of the magic happens in a
one-to-one and that's just
that just seems like it should be that
way anyway because of the fact that
you're like okay well that makes sense
because
uh we're talking about
entourage effect and the fact that they
need it's like
very hard when it comes to like what
percentage do they need so like if you
and it's very rare too very few
conditions are
super negatively affected by having an
equal ratio
sometimes not working as effectively but
for the most part it's
almost most people are thinking cbd is
like this
cure-all and they're both equally
they're both thc and cbd both equally
are effective
thc being more effective than most it's
funny too because in the beginning
everybody thought thc was the
godsend sort of miracle thing and then
then all of a sudden cbd is and now
teach he's bad
and you're like no it's all pretty good
and then on top of that you get the
combo where it's like
when when they're both there is when it
all works you know
so yeah i'm pretty sure one to one is
your magic that's like harlequin's a
great one-to-one plant
um and that one is like if you make
anything with that plant
and you give it to a patient it almost
always works
yeah okay and so what are your opinions
on
phylos and the way it's kind of
interacting or should i say
altering the way kind of certain
interactions or crosses are going down
between breeders like for example
maybe you would do a certain cross in
your mind but then the fire loss reveals
that
you know one of the parents isn't really
what you thought it was maybe it's no
longer an ideal cross you know
how do you think all that plays into the
scene net positive i've heard some
people who are a little bit against the
whole phylus thing
yeah i mean i'm 100 positive on the fact
that it's
just good that we can have this
knowledge i think you just can't take
anything
you you also gotta look beyond
the numbers and that's where i get
scared when people are breeders and
they're like
totally only working off my loss it's
like okay but
uh take into effect that
you know sour diesel was a mistake kush
was a mistake they were all mistakes you
know what i mean and they were all never
bred
on purpose for anything and whether or
not they
the numbers would have made sense is you
know that's
like who knows but uh
yeah i think you gotta like be happy
that we actually can create i mean i do
like the fact that they created the
galaxy
there's a few things in there that i'm a
little bit like hmm okay well that
doesn't seem to make any sense but it
also
opens up a lot of things where you're
like well yeah we knew that all along
and now
at least this is making this so we know
that's for sure
um my problem with philos i guess i
would say i have a problem because i've
been on the show a bunch of times i love
them
you know but the what i can see is a
problem with people is
is the intention everybody's a bit
nervous about which is like okay
so what are you going to do with all
this info and that's kind of where it's
a little
we're in a weird zone now because we've
been so anti
um writing things down as growers and
breeders you know it has been like yeah
just keep it all in my head you know
because
you don't really need to have something
written down that says you were growing
in that
facility five years ago you know or
something like that but
so we've always been a little bit more
underground keep it in your head kind of
thing
and now everybody's like information
junkies and i feel like you can you can
overload it to the point where you don't
have
that information irrelevant at a certain
point because you're like
it doesn't matter if it still tastes
like [ __ ] right so it's like if you take
these two plants put them together and
get the perfect
balance of all the cannabinoids that you
were looking for but
it tastes like ass right then what's the
point
so i think it's a good thing tools are
great
just use them wisely you know and
would you kind of express the same
sentiment for labs and then all you know
like the
it's not so new anymore but being able
to test the sex of seedlings and whatnot
is that the type of thing you would look
into as a breeder or are you still more
so just like you know i know much more
hands-on
i'm still much more hands-on and i'll
use test results
more or less if i feel like uh
i need to confirm something more than
anything and nowadays i mean it's it's
if you have access like if you can have
a
gc in your in your facility and be able
to hand off samples to somebody who
that's what they do all day and they
love to do it because
the lord knows i don't but if you can do
that and and
give somebody else the opportunity to
help you sort of move forward
yeah that's i think it's a good thing
but um
when it comes to
like like you know i have guys who they
run through all their stuff they'll do a
thousand plants and they'll just look
for the one or two
percent that have super high terp out of
the gate
and then focus on that and if you're if
you need to do that yeah like if you if
you're
trying to go through some large numbers
but also kind of feel like
you know can't like the whole never
judge a book by its cover and if you
have seeds
and you go through them all there will
be some strains that just produce
ugly ass seeds that look like [ __ ] you
know what i mean and
if you went on all visuals then you then
you'd also lose out and i think when
you're doing the testing
you know if you're if you're
able to hone in and save yourself a lot
of time that is worth it
but if if it's if you're not if you're
if it's not
if it's not that critical and you i
think it's still better to kind of go
through everything by hand
and give everything a chance
yeah of course so i think you might be
missing out you might be missing out you
know
yeah yeah that's and that's that's a
sentiment i've heard expressed by a few
people who i
you know regard their opinion quite
highly and one of the most memorable
quotes i heard was that
you know like we're not we're not
dealing with tomatoes it's not like it's
so uniform you can just
weed out the runts as soon as they
appear because a lot of the times the
runs are the best ones
yeah yeah yeah exactly and that's like
literally like sage is a good example
uh uh that was selected off of the
well i have to start my car up because
yeah running out of power on the phone
um but like sage was the the selected
the original sage that we
selected uh my friend mojave
uh had it was just like the smallest
plant in the room
it was like kind of in the worst spot
but it had the most amazing smell
and he really like focused on that like
okay well i'm going to run this one
second round and when he did it the
second round it you know it was in a
better position and veggies a little bit
better and it wasn't like
it never was like a was never about it
being like the biggest plan it was very
vigorous but it wasn't necessarily the
biggest
and then uh you know turned out to be
the winner out of the whole thing and if
you'd gone by
the fact that it was the runt of the
litter at that point it would have you
know never made it to the fruition
yeah great real life example so
i think that you know there's probably a
few people who fall into this category
as you but
having had access to arguably some of
the best stuff
especially you know during the early
years a lot of people would kill to have
stock from that time
out of all that stuff what to use stood
out as like some of the best stuff you
know you
probably don't have it anymore but was
there anything you grew back in the day
and you just like in your mind you're
like damn that was
that was the killer yeah there was
actually
sadly enough it was the one of the first
things i ever grew
uh when i when i worked at scentsy when
they did that transition
which was in 91 i believe it was or
around 91.82
when they did that transition it was
they basically bought
they had all of neville stuff they
brought that into the
they brought that into the mix and i was
cleaning out the drawers
and i uh so i was cleaning up the
drawers and then i
found this pack and it said four and
more and
most people are familiar with four-way
which came out
90s which was a four-way indica hybrid
they had come out with a thing called
four and more which is a four-way
sativa hybrid and uh
so i took uh that pack and grew them out
and this was like
again like the first indoor grow that i
had under my like
i was growing for them at scentsy but
this is like the first one at my house
and
every single one of them is mutated
right every single one so it's like
they had um buds growing on the stems
buds growing in the middle
of the leaves you know the kind of
things that now are it's no big deal you
see it
one you know once in every couple
thousand plants
but at that time it was like whoa this
is crazy
um but at the same time i wasn't really
recognizing uh
the fact that even though it was like a
sativa it was growing like
pretty much like a pineapple it was
small had very little stem to it it was
all mutated and weird
had a weird color to it too it was like
a brownie kind of gray color
and it was so it wasn't very vibrant
um very little hair like had almost no
hairs on it
so then when i harvested it i just
wasn't really thinking i kind of cut it
down harvest it hung it up
and then when i like the first time when
i smoked it
it it was like pure haze you know so it
was
one of those things where i was like the
the ultimate right
where you know grows like a little
pineapple indica
solid bud has literally
buds growing on the stems and everywhere
so just the vigor on it was
amazing and when i started to smoke it i
was like holy
[ __ ] that is like a pure haze taste you
know what i mean it's like
i kind of remember like looking back at
the stump
and then smoking the joint and looking
back at the stump and being like i
probably should have like
not cut that down i should have probably
kept that plant and i never to this day
i've ever had anything like that where
the combination of the growth pattern
and the fact that it had such a
extreme sativa like hazy flavor
and yet uh and yet uh
you know probably would have been the
easiest plant to grow in like a sea of
green method or something at that time
but again you know and and that plant
that four and more was
that was i think the last pack
ever because when i opened up the drawer
and found them they were like oh wow i
didn't even know we had that like yeah
you can take that home with you and i
was like
sure i took it home grew it out and sure
enough never get and plus even if you
could get a pack of those i don't think
you'll ever get that particular female
just because of the fact that it's a
four-way hybrid
so the fact of knowing which direction
it's actually going in is gonna be
pretty hard
yeah wow it's like the the what actually
say it
the the predecessor golden ticket
yeah exactly like just like wow this is
like
just came out of left field i just
remembered such an
it was such a contrast of what i was
expecting because when it was growing it
didn't really have a lot of smell it was
kind of like low
low on the totem pole but it really
popped out when you burned it was like
wow
ding like whoa what's that's coming
that's getting me
like so differently than i thought and
so
do you think there was any kind of
secret to the success of all the gear
neville put out like was it really as
simple as just the stock he had to work
with was that pure or do you think
he really was like you know a pretty
phenomenal breeder
he was i mean the thing is he's a
breeder uh he
he like a little bit like how simon was
too simon from seriously simon's a
falcon breeder you know what i mean and
so when you're breeding animals first
you kind of already have that baseline
figured out
and then i believe part of it i think
part of it was the fact that he was a
junkie you know and that he had a real
hard head and he really
had to really work for him so i kind of
think that was
part of the deal was you know like
i'm not you know junkie junkies are
driven people you know
they're they're 100 driven because they
continue
down the road regard you know with
nothing's going to stop the mentality
and i
think that that may have added to the
that with the combination of the fact
that you know if you're used to taking
heroin
that we'd better be strong you know no
messing around
there's no messing around you know if
you're a proper junkie
you know and he was always striving for
the best i mean he blew himself up
making hash oil
you know way before he he was the first
bow [ __ ] you know like
before there was even botox exist
or one of the first in our industry you
know so i feel like he just
that that driven force and being kind of
coming from that side of
the of the of the world is basically
making you
uh yeah made himself plus he like what's
interesting too is like uh
i met people from everywhere that he had
met
and it was like it just it was funny how
every time i meet somebody i can tell he
really like
he found the best grower you know what i
mean he found the best grower in seattle
then he found the best grower in
california then he found the best grower
from wherever you know i mean he seemed
to like to have a very good eye for that
or a very good nose for that or whatever
i'm not sure which senses you'd
do to find these people but you know and
luckily and now it's a different world
so now we've
you know we have it's easier to to find
and to meet these people whether it be
online or in person but
back then like so i had friends from
seattle that neville had come to
and traded them for genetics
in the late 80s you know and so
so then it's like okay well he really
went on a mission you know he wasn't
just
waiting for people to bring him material
so the dedication of going out to
find it and i'm pretty sure he he uh
filtered everything himself and
probably passed all his tests you know
what i mean like that's
and that's compared to like now where a
lot of people it's all hype and
you know oh it's i need to have that
tahoe cookies i'm gonna get that
yo gonna get the tahoe cookies because
everybody says that's the new hottest
thing you know what i mean and that's
totally different than
somehow getting on a plane back in the
80s and
going to seattle and before there was
internet and finding people who
connecting with those people you know
that was uh
some energy the energy put in required
probably created but the reason why that
came out of it was so good
yeah wow and i mean was that seattle
trip do you know is that the infamous
northern lights one
yeah that's where you got all those
lights from exactly and so um
because a couple of those people moved
to amsterdam uh in the
early 90s and part of it was what was
funny was okay so one the one guy that
actually
got neville some material and traded
with him he got the original
silver pearl from neville so it was
north it was a nl
um early pearl skunk cross and
so he brought those cuts that he had
selected from the seeds he got from
neville he selected
cuts brought that cut to amsterdam in 91
and then uh we were selling it through
katsu
as five-way um because
nl skunk being a three-way and uh
early pearl um so that way we were
calling five-way at the time because it
didn't have a name
and then uh they bought the collection
off of neville
and it was called silver pearl he had
come up with a name at that point
and so yeah so there was kind of a like
and then neville was shocked that we had
this
like how the hell did you get the thing
and then he saw our friend and was like
oh okay well that makes sense
because it's one of the few people he
actually gave to
yeah and so i mean over the years
you must have seen a million ogs a
million cookie cuts you know come and go
which of the cuttings out of those two
classes specifically which stand out to
you you know what's your og that
you know the one the one you smoke if
you got the choice
well you know i mean og or the original
one was was
i mean still to this day the
quintessential of og for me
um but in the uh after the fact like the
the k the king's kush which was an og
that
basically we've renamed to
um ricky's brothers coach rbk
was like uh was snoop's favorite
back in the day and ricky's was snoop's
manager and i met him in amsterdam in
the 90s
and uh so when he would come over when
they would come over on tour
snoop was always pissed off because
there was never any kush right he was in
amsterdam he'd be like
this weed all sucks and so i was like
well if you told the manager if you can
get me a
cut of whatever he likes i'll make sure
he has it when he's here
so then we managed to get a cut off of
his brother which is funny because
him and his brother didn't even get
along anymore but he somehow managed to
get over to his brothers get it cut
i when i came to cali he gave me the cut
i got it back to amsterdam
and then the first time that i first
time that i
uh had a couple ounces for snoop he was
in a sh like he couldn't even
wrap his head around the fact that i had
the same kush that he had back
in america you know what i mean and i
figure if snoop's seen enough kush too
so he if
that was his favorite i was like okay if
that's your favorite then i
will uh make sure and i'll make sure to
have it for you you know
and then it now has been renamed snoops
kush and a bunch of different names but
we still call it rbk
because we like the idea of ricky's
brother's kush
it's kind of it's kind of ricky bobby
somewhere between a ricky bobby
and uh but that uh you know i was
literally at one point like we should
just start a whole trailer park seed
company and everything will be a
billy joe bob's cousins kush and jimmy
jo
you know whatever because it's because
that's kind of where we're at nowadays
where a lot of people take kush
i mean how many people have taken kush
and put their own name to it or or
changed it or whatever and that's
um but to me the original kush the ogre
which is what i
brought back to amsterdam was really
like
the picture-perfect one it's the one it
i mean it's where mk came from
and it's kind of where i feel like
that's that's
closest to the source at that point yeah
the show and so how do you feel about
all the current kind of drama slash
i guess ethical questioning going on
around the idea of
breeding with other people's stuff and i
guess specifically do you feel like if
you've bought a pack of seeds or
if you've just obtained them through
whatever means are you just cool to do
whatever you want with them at that
point more or less
i mean yeah yeah to a point i mean i i
here i am the guy that sells the seeds
so of course you know it's it's
it's a double edge for me i'd rather
i'd rather that people did do that but
then also gave credit because that will
help build up the other person's
reputation as a company
when it comes to people buying two packs
of this
somebody's gear and then crossing those
together and selling those as their own
that's a problem you know what i mean
um and and and to be quite honest taking
a pack of my seeds
and a pack of dna and crossing those
together and thinking you have a new
seed company or is also
a little lame you know what i mean and a
little like it's not not
really thinking outside the box the key
what i've always told everybody over the
years is the way to get respect i think
in this industry
quickly is to bring something to the
table which is unique
and then you can always collaborate with
everybody on that
point you know what i mean like so for
instance you know sage is what i'm known
for so like i feel like if i bring sage
into the mix and someone else has
something that's special and we take my
male or my sage or my female of my sage
and do a cross
that's that's me putting my flavor into
the into the
on you know putting it in there if i
take
somebody else's thing as a breeder and
then i take someone two different other
people's
it's i can't really do that now it kind
of pigeonholes certain people but it
also
what you notice is the best breeders or
guys who like really stick to their guns
and
like for instance again simon is one of
the better breeders out there from
serious seeds because he has
six varieties you know and he's had the
same six he's added like one or two
varieties in the last couple years but
for the most part he's had the same
varieties for year in and year out
are they the same no some of them have
changed over the years but
it's very similar to um
if you're breathing if you're uh looking
at like
improvements to the strain if it's an
improvement
then we should do that but if it's not
and that's the hard part too is we're
talking about annuals that we
have turned into perennials you know and
it's not really like certain plants are
not just not
pre-ret you know they're not designed to
last 20 years but somehow we've managed
to do that
and over the years though the best
people or the best breeders are people
who realize they have a problem and then
they'll
fix it you know bring some new blood to
the table and
add some extra zinger into there into
whatever they're doing
yeah and so if we take a look at kind of
the offerings from th seeds
there's there's quite a few which would
be you know contestants to be kind of
the poster child because they're all you
know such hits in their own right
what do you consider to be you know the
the one you stand behind the most i
guess and you know not trying to
be biased i mean you still say it's
still sage for me because of the fact
that
i always felt that sativas and you know
sativa is a
overly used word let's just say narrow
leaf drug varieties
are are the uh kind of the adult weed
you know the adult can the adult
cannabis as you
as one would say but now the the
sophisticated old-school smoker the guy
who actually
um has some more experience than just
what people have told them and what
dispensary they've gone to
those are always those sativa-based
things that have that like
unique cerebral quality to them and then
um i feel like things like mkultra are
nice but they're also just
they're just a mirror image of us of a
kush with with a little bit of a
difference
and so that that's nice but it's not
something that i feel like i'm standing
behind 100
as my end all i always thought like
like a good question i'm sure you've had
is always be like well if you were on a
desert island and you had one
particular plant then then for me it
would be sage
yeah okay so it's that everyday type of
wheat
yeah and it's a lot of it's due to the
fact that like um
you know sometimes you won't smoke it
for a long time like just you're on this
other tip for a while and then you go
back to it
it's literally like like putting on a
glove or something oh wow this
i get that instant vibe where it's like
why the hell haven't i been smoking this
the whole time i haven't been running
around trying to solve this other stuff
and it's just has that long-term sort of
quality which
which i think is a rare in a way because
everybody's always looking for the next
best thing
yeah so show everyone uh sorry
a question everyone has to answer on the
show what's your favorite cam dog cart
uh chem d oh yeah
yeah i think so for me it's the most
deep
funk you know kim 91 it seems to get a
lot of everyone seems to love cam 91
too but no i can't believe definitely
yep so one a question i should have
probably asked you a bit earlier when we
were discussing some of your stuff
the snow but this is australian speaks
my interest because it's so
old there's not a ton of information
about it
what's the backstory on it well
so i got it from a group in oregon that
came out to amsterdam from oregon they
brought me snow bud
they brought me um the predecessors
to the chocolate chunk like the the
the female side of that one um it was
it was just a real unique um
like the it was more the shape of it was
kind of a lot to do with the
the name behind it because it it didn't
have like a peaked bud like how
how sours do and stuff it had really
like a rounded
almost like a there was a plant called
citral back in amsterdam that was very
similar
in its structure so a very wide top to
the bud
um yeah just a real for me it was a very
like uh
like the the lingering qualities of it
was what i really liked about it like it
compared to the front end it was more
about the back end on that thing
and super strong like just really
we we were calling when we first got it
we were like we caught we were going to
rename a dick in the dirt because
it's kind of like you just brought you
really like got you really really high
and really
intense yeah wow
and so any plans to work with that going
into the future
um no i mean i i've lost all those
genetics years ago actually the funny
part was that the acorn which we made it
from
uh what we made from the snow bud uh
that that we found we found it again
uh my partner found it in mallorca
was a guy down there who bought seeds
from us years ago and he's just been
running with that particularly like the
whole
island smoke snowboard lovely smoked
acorn
and he's like you know so it's hilarious
he owns a growth shop there so he
basically made all the cuts and
supplied the island with cuts and so we
got that back
about a year ago so i have but i haven't
got it back because it's in europe still
but i would love to yeah definitely if i
can get the cut back over to this side
uh
this one it was one of my favorites back
in the day for sure
and so what's a cut that's maybe not
really that widely distributed but
you wish it were you know you wish it
would appear in more crosses or that the
public were more aware of it because you
know you just think it's awesome
um well there's a plan there's a thing
out here
which i just kind of started to work
with um
and then kind of got off that i don't
know why i'm
actually now that i'm thinking about i'm
like maybe i should go back and get on
that
but oh i know exactly why
boric is looking like it literally i
felt like the the wind got kind of
sucked out of the sails when i first
came to colorado um
i was made aware of a string called
tange out of here
um the colorado tange and
it's like a blackberry flavored
really deep um kind of somewhere like a
flow very like like if you didn't know
and you've had flow and that one back to
back you might think it's the same plant
but when you grew them out you kind of
you definitely would see the difference
so there was something in the flavor
profile that was very much like flow um
but it had this uh yeah it was just an
intense plant
and we were growing that a lot when i
first came here and i was also
i made some crosses with it
but it just didn't but then then the
problem was that the tangy became so
popular and i just felt like
i can't really promote tangent tangy
after all the diesel issues
after all these like because it feels
like whenever there's confusion on a
strain it doesn't help anybody it
doesn't help either or you know it's
like
you just get people calling tang tangy
and people calling tangitans and
mixing it all up and then all of a
sudden it's like you're you're kind of
like
taking each other out you know what i
mean in the wrong way you know i mean
not
not not on a quality basis but just
based on confusion you know
so i think we just kind of it's because
i actually had packaging made for
tange and then in the end i just like
sat on it and
and then and then i don't see anybody
part the only people that are growing it
now is
uh derek from incredibles and that's who
i got the cut from originally like he's
like the last guy standing it seems like
but but that particular plant was uh one
that i
had thought when i first came had so
much potential and i thought that was
going to be the next big thing
and in the end it didn't work out and so
do you have any other lines that maybe
you've done throughout the years which
were really good but for whatever reason
they never quite made it to market and
you know maybe looking back you wish
they had
um you know i did like a bunch of
cambodian crosses and
laotian crosses at one point someone
brought me some seeds
um the problem was i really felt like
there was no
not a big market for those racy land
like those were super racy sort of
sativas that
didn't grow necessarily pretty plants
like very dark and kind of
spotty but now i feel like everybody's
more open to the idea of land races and
and almost like they'd appreciate that
difficultness you know like i actually
had one recently i was at a show and
this one guy came up and it was like the
first time
i think i've ever heard anybody say it
but this guy came up and he's like hey
what is the most
difficult thing you have to grow you
know and this guy was like oh well
this one's kind of a difficult plan to
grow
like usually it's never that it's
usually i want the easiest
biggest highest yielding most thc
everything you know there's never
there's nothing but this guy was asking
for
because in his mind it was like the most
complicated ones are the most rewarding
ones which
is true you know to a point but it's
also hard if you can't get past the
point of uh being satisfied how you're
growing
yeah so just to change topics up for a
moment
obviously besides the adi which of the
current cups
do you feel you're you know kind of most
happy to throw your weight behind slash
you enjoy
going to because i think there's only
two there's only two well there's
actually three there's three that i
would do
and i and they're all like coming up
right now so uh
the golden tarp awards which is uh
november 18th so next week
and that one's actually if uh i don't
know if when you're going to get this
posted but
if if you're you should definitely take
a look at it and maybe if you get a
chance
if this comes out before and anybody
gets a chance to
uh they're doing a completely
transparent online of the entire process
it's a one-day thing on the 18th
but they've got a professional system
set up like an nfl
camera system where they have cameras
set up everywhere with the testing
with the with the judging with the
the award ceremony everything is based
on multiple camera angles and you can
just
go for free to your phone and like link
into them so
they're taking it to the next level as
far as transparency but also
it's you know 250
entries one winner no there's no other
there's just one so it's kind of very
similar to our idea where it's like not
no categories no
nothing like that just who's got the
best weed
you know so like that that one's awesome
emerald cups obviously the the
sort of crowned i'd say that's that's
the best event
by far in the world right now when it
comes to cannabis just because of the
location location location right you're
in norcal
so you're talking about the best to the
best when it comes to growers and then
i'll just have to throw some i'll just
have to give my friend my friend props
because he's
he's taking it to heart he's he's on the
east coast and
next week is also another cup called the
cannabis all-stars
and the fact that they are on their
fifth year
it's in a tiny little town in rhode
island and yet they still
have like method man and red man and big
big talent coming through
and they it's it the quality of the
cannabis is good and also
they it like rhode island actually
smokes more cannabis per capita than any
state in america right now so it's kind
of like
and i grew up there so for me it's
always funny like i'm like well i
thought i was the only
guy i didn't realize anybody here was
smoking weed but apparently
everybody is smoking weed there so
it's interesting you know you didn't
mention any of the high times ones
because a lot of the sentiment
expressed these days is there it's
almost as if
the event comes off more as though it's
trying to be like a music festival as
opposed to like a cannabis event
do you agree with that
yeah well you know the thing is i've
been involved with the cup since 93 so
for me
it's like i watched it i watched it from
uh
from like organizer point of view in the
very beginning and then from a
uh and then from a punter sort of view
and then from you know and just saw how
it was kind of like the same cycles over
and over again where
people get real excited they get
involved they get screwed they move on
next when they can they kind of didn't
feel like they i don't feel like they
they nurtured their their people enough
and they kind of went for the went for
the kill every time on money
um you know and it's also like i've
watched them saturate their market and
over
overdo it and do too many cups in too
short a time and
really burned out a lot of people like a
lot of people i know you know it's
they don't even bother going to them
anymore so so i feel like high times uh
you know they've done a great job over
the years at least keeping the fire
going but the problem was they're now
it's they're turning into what they've
been against the whole time which is the
corporate kind of mentality and
and they've kind of moved on to that so
there's enough it's good though because
it opens up it opens up for a lot of
these smaller events to
to shine a little bit when i think
there's a
there's a sort of peak point where
events just burn themselves out
and uh it happens with every trade show
it doesn't matter if it's cannabis or
not it's just
there's always going to be a side
project which goes on which is
more real you know the real people are
involved because it's
it's uh because they don't want to be
involved with the big
corporate-minded and it happens in
fashion it happens in
electronics it doesn't matter there's
always going to be another
event that comes around and absorbs the
the energy of that event and that's
that's kind of where i think it's at
this point so
yeah sorry i was going to say you know
obviously being the host of a show i'm
sure you get your fair share of
criticisms about the show in the
you know email or whatnot the same way i
do you know the thing i get most notably
is like the show's too long and people
just get bored halfway through it
which yeah i'm sure yeah i can see the
same thing with me because my shows turn
out to be
two to three hours every time and i
can't but i can't squash enough
into that point besides i have a hard
time where i'm like well
you know i can't even i can't even uh
you know
but but i i'm like one of those guys
where i have a hard time
i mean i don't have a hard time but like
i hate when people criticize
the stuff i do obviously i mean nobody
really enjoys that but
i'm also happy to to take it to heart
sometimes
and you know it's the same thing i got
guys who say
uh adam i hate to listen to the done
show that guy can't even get a thought
out you know and i'm like oh i thought i
was
throwing out too much stuff but i guess
i'm not i guess you know
and and you know and sometimes there's
little things where you're like oh
i mean i remember the first criticism i
heard was and it was funny because i
think everybody who
um listens to themselves
has their own critique on their own
voice or their their cadence or how they
deliver stuff or whatever and the very
very first one was
i don't know who this i don't know who
the hell this ray romano sounding guy is
but he's annoying
i was like oh great so now i'm sounding
like ray romano and i was like yeah i
kind of get that i
kind of see what he's saying you know
what i mean and again like i think
what you can do as a if you're in in
this kind of an industry and
the worst thing you can do is get onto
youtube and look at your comments
because
you're almost always going to have the
haters in that world but then again you
know you're not successful unless you
have some haters in the world
yeah so with all that being said though
you know
the longevity speaks for itself what has
been in your opinion
you know the secret to the longevity
overall of both the show and the career
even
you know even if there are there haters
out there
i think just being uh authentic and
you know and true to yourself in a sense
i mean that's kind of the key to
i feel like that's the key to success
now because we're in such a
um sort of insta
insta world you know everything's
instant and everything um
is not authentic anymore there's really
like an authenticity
lack of authenticity in this world and
so
when something's good everyone jumps on
that bandwagon you know what i mean and
i feel like
this industry is no not any different i
mean we're definitely
you can run around and be a hype guy and
jump on everybody else's
thing but i feel like if you're just
true to yourself and really authentic
you're gonna last a long time and
what's funny is i've been totally uh
that's been totally confirmed to me
recently i read an article where i was
talking about millennials
and because the millennials are
are oh that's they're always looking for
something that's real now because
there's so much fake in the world and
that's
something we didn't really have as a
when we were growing up i mean
everything was
not that everything was real but seems
like everything was a little bit more
authentic because it wasn't like
like now if you get on the internet it
might take you
10 minutes to figure out that you're
what you're reading is absolute and
utter [ __ ] and you might be totally
sucked into it you know what i mean but
but this whole idea of of putting layers
of [ __ ]
out there yeah wasn't so
prevalent before you know i mean before
it was a little bit more like yeah it
was hard to get to the
to find the knowledge but it wasn't
because you had to
click you weren't getting clickbait
thrown at you you know what i mean and
nowadays it's like
the uh the idea of being
24 years like this is our 25th year
coming up now
and so when you're into those ranges
once you get past 20 years it's kind of
like
like any career at that point you're
like i guess uh you know
you you uh you either and the thing is
it's way easier to be authentic than it
is to
to try to change all the time because
it's kind of like
you know trying to like if you just
imagine you create your entire company
based on a lie then you're
you're you're you're like
take for example saying you started in
1985 you know
how can you you know you can't really
what do you do when you have your 20th
anniversary and you're
only but but everyone starts questioning
like well how could you be 20th
anniversary you just started four years
ago you know you know i mean it's like
to me that's like it makes it harder as
a
to be in the industry long term you know
because you're always now you're
now you're you're always defending
yourself you know so i feel like just
being authentic and just sort of you
know real
and and one of the things that's nice is
that uh
i'm glad i'm where i'm at at the age
that i'm at because i'll be
i'm like 48 right now um
yeah i i think it would be too hard to
be coming here as a total new
new guy and try to create an image in
your own thing i think it'd be quite
hard so
kind of glad where i started when i
started because uh
it's not so hard to to last if you've
been around that long you know
because it just gets easier in a sense
yeah yeah you got that name recognition
as well so i mean we're on the on the
tail end of it all now
this is the last question it's a little
bit more i mean you can you can go along
if you want but
a little bit more short answer based um
so this one actually might require a
little bit explaining but i saw you
answer a question somewhere i think it
might have been in the facebook group
somewhere like that but basically
someone said how come we don't see a lot
of 100 hemp clothing and then you said
oh it's because it's actually like quite
hard to make 100 versus say like a blend
would you mind elaborating a bit more
about that i don't think people are
familiar
sure uh well it's mostly cost
restrictive you know like uh
say you can make 100 hemp products
and i and we've we've sold them over the
years um the problem was it was always
a combination of cost restrictive and
also
i don't think people are as familiar
with that
high that high of quality material to
begin with because one of the things
that takes
so for instance linen is a good example
like linen
is not fashionable right now it's not
because it takes
energy to actually wear it you can't
wash and wear linen you know what i mean
you have to actually take care of it
a little bit like cast iron skillets
take a cast iron skillet compared to a
teflon pan they probably sell
100 000 teflon pans for every cast iron
skillet these days but if you're
a chef you're only going to wear you're
only going to use cast iron skillets
because
that's what real cooking's about but
it's also going to last forever
it needs to be treated constantly
and so with with hemp clothes with hemp
when it's 100
it's not going to be wrinkle free you're
going to have to
iron it every time whereas when we mix
it with cotton we can actually get
pretty much wrinkle-free material um
hardly needs any
any maintenance and people are more used
to that and the problem is if you if you
hand somebody an item which you just
paid more money for
and now you have to take care of it more
it's almost like so against the grain of
the
the modern way of thinking now
everybody's well if you
if you pay more it should just take care
of itself right you're like actually not
so
so it's kind of like one of those things
where just people aren't really ready to
to pay the amount that they have to pay
and then on top of that
learn a whole new learning curve of how
to take care of their clothing
um which you know it's funny as a as a
to be in this industry for so long and
then like
never would have thought that i would
have ever been into fashion and into
clothing and
and the nice part is that because we're
a hemp brand
we're really focused on what we do and
so like our materials
over the years have like now we're doing
7 hemp on the outer
material of our jacket so we've actually
increased it as much as we can
and keeping it in line with what we've
already done
if you know what i mean yeah i know
that's your tagline but i'm just going
to throw it at you
we've got to keep it in there so i mean
if we take a step back though
what was kind of the inspiration to
initially start the clothing brand in
general it obviously pre-dates a lot of
the other currently popular clothing
brands like cookies and all that
sure we literally um
started selling hemp clothing in 1993
after i quit working for so i was
working when i was working at scentsy we
used to sell a shirt that was called
stoned wear and probably
people some of the people who listened
to this probably had one of these it was
like the original hemp
jean shirt right long sleeve jean
shirt thing and it was like had a really
cool patch and it had really cool
buttons
it was quite thin the material it wasn't
really like super robust but it was the
only hem product that
that we sold and so we sold tons and
tons of these shirts and then when i
started so then when i
left scentsy part of the reason i left
is because i was really into the idea of
selling hemp and they didn't really have
the inspiration that i was
seeing to get more hemp products and
there wasn't really a lot available at
that time
so then when i so then i left there
and literally ben drunker's like got me
you know kind of came
got me over by the doorway and was like
hey you know good luck with everything
and you know hope you can find that hemp
you know and it was like he had just
started hempflex at the time so he was
about to start growing him because of
his frustrations of
that there wasn't enough hemp around you
know and so
uh in the beginning i just sold other
people's hemp clothing and it was like i
was getting
some pretty wonky stuff and it was like
i was forcing myself to wear some of the
gear just because i was trying to
promote it you know i had like
overalls that were too short in the legs
and kind of goofy and just weird weird
weird stuff that i wasn't really
thinking was like fashionable and
and then we um was working with a
company called thc
that had some italian hemp that was
beautiful like italian processed
hemp products that were amazing and they
had 100
but the problem was again they're there
so the quality was there everything but
the prices were just
outrageous they were over 100 bucks for
a pair of jeans and this is back in the
90s i was like oh my god a hundred
dollars
you know and i was like well this is you
know 100 is 200 gilders so it's like
we're trying to charge 200 guilders for
a pair of jeans
and people were just like you know
couldn't get their head around it
so then we started making our own
products and but
uh you know we imported all the material
from china
and the 100 hemp was always very rough
and very
burlappy and not conducive to
making good quality clothes so we
actually
did a we actually had a bunch of 100
stuff made and it was like
looked more like the flintstones you
know what i mean like as far as just the
the threads coming out the thickness of
the thread and stuff
um but now we could do 100
and we might get the price to a point
where people might be willing to pay for
it but
um we still feel like the blends are are
you know an easier way to get people
interested without them
because the worst thing is to have
somebody buy something
and then to me like the most on eco
thing is when you buy a
some clothing and you don't wear it
because when for one reason or another
like you open up your
if you open up your your your closet and
there's a bunch of hemp gear in there
that you never wear where you're not
really
helping out anybody are you you know but
if you have something that you wear
until it's fallen off your body because
they're wearing it so much then that to
me is the most eco
minded so even in the beginning like
when people would be like yeah but your
dye's not eco and it was like
we tried that we actually worked with
some eco dyes and
they ruined all the other clothes that
people would have so they would never
want to buy your clothes again because
they bought that shirt off of you they
put it in the laundry with all their
other stuff because that's what they do
even though you put on the label washed
separately
they don't listen you know what i mean
people people just don't listen people
are yeah
people take it they throw it in the
thing they treat it like everything else
and if it doesn't work they'll never do
it again and so that that that to me is
a
the kind of you know the the stickling
point a sticking point between
doing 100 help and doing a blended
blends of him
yeah makes a lot of sense so
what is your preferred growth style
synthetic or organic and why
um oh 20 organic um
you know i i i was a victim of every
single
over-tech way of growing when i first
moved to holland it was all
about hydro i was in the land of hydro i
wanted to build i didn't even want to
have soil i wanted i didn't even want to
have
medium i just wanted to do aeroponics i
was
a general hydroponics distributor
between 95 and 97
so i was like introducing general hydro
to everybody
i was totally all about it you know i
was like uh
and then at a certain point i remember
just like throwing all that [ __ ] away
and going back to soil and realizing
like oh my god this is so much better
for
for just all around flavors making seeds
i would never make seeds on hydro it's
always on
soil you know so it's just the mineral
contents a lot
it i just feel like the connection
between the minerals that you get from
the soil compared to what you get from
salts
is so much different like just vibe wise
and then when you're making seeds
you know you really there's a lot of
there's really no formula on the market
that's made for making seeds it's always
you know you're growing or you're
flowering that's it there's different
you know pregnant women don't need the
same food as
non-pregnant women you know because
their bodies are going through changes
and the baby needs something different
than the mother needs and it's the same
when you're making seeds you know so i
feel like
when you grow us organically there's
going to be a completely different shift
the way the plant needs but it's all
available because you just you give them
everything they need compared to like
trying to you know and now over the
years i thought oh maybe i should make
like a synthetic
food for making seeds that'd be cool but
i also think
some things you can't fix you know or
you can't make better than nature so
yeah and ever since doing my show i'm
now more now
no tills come into my world and
that's so much more satisfying and
the inputs that go involved and also i
have like a
farm here in colorado so i'm living in
the middle of nature so the last thing i
want to do is
grow synthetically and uh and not be
able to utilize everything that i'm
doing and what i'll do is
you know use a raised beds for all the
old soil and stuff and
recycle everything properly it's just
it's a much better feeling and i
i only eat organic food now and i'm
pretty much you know
i'm over i'm over all the idea of of
uh of synthetics
yeah almost really you know so a bit of
an interesting question
what is your least favorite strain
throughout all of history that you've
sadly had the pleasure of trying um
yeah you know to be quite honest one of
the ones was the
psalmist [ __ ] diesel was because it
it tastes
terrible like it has like the it has and
it got such a big amount of hype in
holland
it was the the hot ticket item you know
what i mean and it was just like it
never delivered like it smells really
good
it looks really good it tastes terrible
and it just doesn't get me high you know
what i mean so that was one of those
strains that it just
took me it it always it just it it was
like a
huge disappointment like if anybody ever
says like something oh dude
oh look i got diesel and i'd be like
sour no
it's almond i'm like oh and that was
like so i think that was one of the ones
and i wouldn't say it's the worst
variety but it was the least sad it was
the
the one that bummed me out just every
time like bums me out
yeah what about your favorite of all
time
favorite of all time is nothing that any
of us have ever grown it was a tie
it's a 1985
purple tie that kind of flooded the east
coast for a little while and i actually
met
the one of the main guys who brought it
in at one point where i
was we were talking about you know back
in the day and old times and stuff and i
was explaining and he's like oh that
those are the loads i brought into
into rhode island and i was like oh
those were amazing it was just like this
super slow burning purple tie thing that
was like tiny little buds
and just amazing and yeah you just don't
see because you know and it probably
wasn't from thailand i'm sure it was
from
it was probably ocean or something but
for the most part it was uh
um you know most memorable
thing that i've ever had yeah wow
okay so lucky last question if you could
go back to
one place in history and geography to
collect land race seeds where would you
go and from what time period
um probably in the same region like in
leos um basically every vietnam vet
out there always has the best weed
that's always been the case like it
seems like in america like wow this
needs america amazing where did you get
it from i was just vietnam vet
and they always and the thing is that
everybody there would always tell me
that
the laotian weed was psychedelic you
know
i mean and these are people who took a
lot of psychedelics so
they wouldn't they wouldn't say it i'm
not understanding it you know
um and i feel like that that
would be probably some of the more
unique things out there because it's
such a hard plan to grow too so it's
like
a lot of hermaphrodites a lot of issues
like that so
so i think um but it still would be
great to find something out of there
that was
super electric also that kawhi electric
was one of those ones i wish i could get
my hands on
and that's something that i've heard
over the years from friends which just
sounds so amazing but i i actually went
on a hunt for it
around 2005 but i met people who grew it
and i met people who
knew the guys who would go to the power
lines and
collect it and etc but but it never got
a chance to actually try it
yeah wow i mean i guess we can only hope
it pops its head up again
with that being said any shout outs or
comments you wanted to make
um well you know um shout out to the
chat gang out there if they're listening
to hopefully they're listening to your
[ __ ] your show i will focus
to make sure that they do so shout out
to buck russell
and all the guys and who made it made
the who made the uh
chat gang a real thing which it's been
quite it's quite cool to have a
dedicated
crew like that you know i'm sure you got
your own
you must have your own dedicated
listeners
i don't know so basically shouting you
out
thanking you um
you know obviously shout out to my
beautiful wife
as i end every show and my little kid
and
my my mom and the whole crew is just
hanging in there with me because
it's been a struggle you know it's one
of those things over the years of doing
this um
you really you realize that you know not
everybody has the same vision that you
have but
if they hang in there with you and then
stay to the end and they might
get to enjoy all the things that we're
trying to make out of this and
right now it's just trying to find our
way with this plant and make it
uh you know benefit everybody in the
long run
and not get not get eaten up which is
you know it is it is in a way but at the
same time i feel like there'll always be
a piece of it that'll
shine through yeah what a great
sentiment to end the show on so thanks
again so much for coming on the show
hey thank you man it's been awesome
[Music]
so there we have it guys i really
enjoyed it
i hope you did big thank you again to
adam
a big thank you to our patreon gang
these guys are seriously
collectively mvp my favorite crew of
people ever
as always 420 australia and ogs
[Music]
and all you guys
i'll see you
la la la la
[Music]
you