hello welcome to the next episode of the
podcast a cannabis podcast for budding
enthusiasts this episode as always was
brought to you by 420 Australia the
premiere store for 4/20 lifestyle and
apparel as well as organic gardening
solutions your one-stop shop for organic
gardening this episode we're grateful to
be joined by inspector who's the head of
two companies as well as a true veteran
of the same get set for some County
history breeding tips and what you can
expect in the future from here we go
alrighty a big thank you and welcome to
a man who heads not only one but two
breeding companies inspector of CSI
Humboldt and parts of the Emerald
triangle thanks so much for coming on
it's good to be here so the first
question I like to ask all breeders what
was your introduction to cannabis I'm
definitely a second generation you know
grower breeder etc etc my dad you know
started way back in the 70s he was
growing indoors in the late 70s and you
know he he showed me his grow rooms back
when I was a little kid you know was
smoking my face when I was a little bit
young you know I don't remember that but
you know pass me the joint when I was
911 you know and you know I was
definitely a water in plants by the time
I was 8 years old for my uncle
not so much my dad on that on that one
but yeah I started pretty young awesome
and so you do you remember any of the
strains that were let you know when you
can first kind of remember things
because obviously you're not gonna
remember 8 but you know like maybe when
you were 14 15 German what they were
growing well when I was 18 the very
first cutting my dad gave me was
Northern Lights that he had got from
some of his buddies who I think brought
it down from the Seattle area
but before that he had the strain
I'm not strained but he had this cutting
that had come from either the Portland
OR Seattle area back in the early 80s
I'm thinking like somewhere between 82
and 84 and a man he swears to this day
that it's the best stuff ever but I I
remember when I was I don't know how I
was pretty young
some some time between 8 and 10 he
opened up his hidden grow room and I
mean it was it was the most gorgeous
just 16 cush plants in this 6 foot by 6
foot room under a thousand watt metal
halide and I mean to this day you know
I'm looking for something that looks as
gorgeous as that you know definitely
something cush and that he received as a
no-name plant from you know the Portland
Seattle area but he was told it was bred
for 80 degrees and 80% humidity now this
is where it gets a little weird but he
always harvested it at 28 days flower
okay right
but outdoors it wasn't even ready until
like mid-november you know but anyways
uh so you know with that said it was a
no-name strain but roughly about 1989 I
think he got this other cutting after
he'd lost that first one from the cave
junction area in Southern Oregon and
this plant kind of looked halfway
between an OG Kush and above Akash and
this this cutting was called Uriah he
gave me that plant in the mid-90s and I
held it along with you know cousins and
family and friends up until the early
2000s but uh you know that's another one
of those ones
just got lost a time but it it smelled
and tasted exactly how weed is supposed
to smell and anytime something anything
comes even close to it it's like oh
that's a keeper the ones that have come
closer like my bus one bomb threat
I rain like a phenotype of purple dog
purple dog blood which is a Oracle x
chem 91 and even some of the like
triangle cush times or khals they they
hit that you know just that is what weed
is supposed to be I don't know just just
from my earliest memories anyway yes
that's so interesting you just touched
on so many points we'll have to dive
into first one do you think that that
strain which you know you kind of hold
is the benchmark do you think that was a
predecessor to you know the Bubba's and
the Urkel's and all that or do you think
it was the other way around like it had
already been blended together oh it was
definitely I wouldn't say it was a
predecessor but I would say that you
know possibly some of the oh geez and
bubbles and stuff maybe just share
certain you know lineages you know yeah
okay pop and so this might be wrong but
when if we just go back to how you
mentioned I think you said at 18 you got
to see the grow room and you saw you
know the 16 cush plants was that the
defining moment for you where you kind
of were like this is for me mm-hmm
that's a good question I don't know if
it was a defining moment but you know I
think I was casual I was honestly I was
casual into the growing from the time I
was 18 until the time I was about 20 I
guess 21 and then I kind of had to make
a decision you know pursue you know a
real-world job like I was doing or you
know go full-time growing and well
Danette awesome and so what was the
first strain you bred and what caused
you to decide to breathe well I mean you
know grown between 94 and the early
2000s you know there was definitely you
know accidental things and we you know
me and friends and family started the
seeds and everything but then around
2002 I had kind of a a little mutant
activity going on with the purple
article I had this 12,000 watt room and
I had roughly I think nine oh maybe it
was a hundred and 108 plants of Oracle
and a couple other things in the room
and one of the purple Oracle's branches
basically turned full Mail okay right
yeah I mean you got over a hundred
plants and they're all females except
for this one branch and a turn totally
male and so I took that male branch and
I pollinated a bunch of stuff with it I
pollinator comb a dark glass ones made
trainwreck articles and a handful of
other Furcal hybrids and I grew a me and
my cousin and you know some other folks
grew a bunch of those seeds out and I
there was killed her stuff in those
seeds you know and that was about two
years before I got on online I came
online in 2004 and then I really started
you know learning like you know oh wait
hmm you can turn them into males you
know so it sounds like things were
fairly self-directed well with that
being said though were there any
breeders you were keeping your eye on at
that point and thought like oh I like
the stuff these guys are doing before
2004 I mean I'm just a emerald turtle
kid living in the backwoods of Humboldt
in Trinity County
[Music]
yeah we didn't have in I didn't have
internet myself until roughly around
2004 yeah you know so I didn't even know
what a breeder was no okay so did you
just you just work with your own stock
from year to year
oh yeah yeah all the stuff I inherited
from my dad and his friends and other
friends yeah so awesome and so if we
fast forward I think it was in mid 2000s
you decided to start CSI or was it even
after that in like 2010 maybe I I
started CSI three years ago yeah that's
what I thought I was like was it 2014 I
thought I read yeah I mean I
I'm breeding a lot of the same stuff you
know I Brett over 10 years ago
I'm skinny I didn't yeah I didn't start
the company and start retailing until
three years ago yes so I mean I guess
the question some people might be
wondering is why did it kind of take you
so long to get into the commercial game
I mean honestly I was I was just grown
my outdoor crops and just occupations
and having fun for a good bit and also
you know every time I checked into it um
I looked into doing the whole seed thing
and every time was just like you gotta
sell them overseas and UK or Spain or
something and then even legally getting
the money you know for um it was yeah it
wasn't easy so I was just like nah too
risky for me at the time anyway yeah
okay and then I guess just to have a
distinction what was the reason for
starting parts of the Emerald triangle
like why did you want to have the two
separate brands for people who are aware
ones for the feminized line ones for the
regular line but did you just kind of
get the idea that oh the feeling that
like they wouldn't gel together as a
brand so just
oh so to be honest I always wanted to do
pirates of the Emerald triangle that was
kind of you know the name of you know my
buddies and me and you know just what we
did around Humboldt and Trinity in
Mendocino even but when I started up a
seed company like my closest friends and
my ex they liked CSI humble / pirates
they didn't think pirates was marketable
I was like okay I'll just go with
pirates or CSI sorry and then you know
as time went on I was like well I still
kind of want to you know do my original
you know idea of pirates so I just kind
of segregated them yeah you know and so
if we just kind of jump back to a while
ago you mentioned the bomb threat Bubba
this is interesting you know archive
also uses this one as a mother how long
has that one been around for I actually
was under the impression I'm probably
wrong but I thought Fletch popped that
one but it was you oh yeah I sprouted it
wasn't even a large seed pop I sprouted
a 20 of my bubba kush s1 seeds back in
2006 the basically from the same
breeding that obama cush came from and
that my buddy popularized up in a
Portland Seattle and everything but uh
yeah I popped 20 seeds and it was my it
weirdly enough it was my favorite
commercial plant of the bunch a had kind
of like a lemon-lime you know type of
thing my favorite plant out of that
bunch was this lemon heads candy above
s1 number 12 but nobody could grow it
after the first seed run I mean it was
just a horrible plant to grow and so
everybody who I gave it to lost it real
quick
the bomb threat though it ended up
sticking around and people liked it hmm
I didn't even keep it for a long time so
I probably didn't have it for two or
three years and then I realized
everybody had given it to still had it
and absolutely loved it and then I got
it back and you know but yeah the reason
a lot of people think archive sprouted
it is because I entered I entered bombs
left bomb threat flowers that I grew and
I think 2013 through archive seedbank
through you know
Fletcher's company and then it won third
place at the High Times show that it was
entered at so you know even though I
grew it you know he got kind of the
credit for it
you know bum oh well I mean oh so good
nowhere is there awesome so I mean in
terms of the Bubba if you want to dive a
little deeper into a question I always
get asked is like comparing the Bubba to
the Oregon Afghani I'm not sure if
you're familiar with it
but a lot of people who like hint that
maybe Bubba comes from not Oregon
Afghani but I always got the impression
it was the other way around
do you have any kind of opinions on that
one I would probably agree with you I
honestly think more than likely the
Oregon Afghani comes from Bubba but then
on the flip side you know the organ a
fee could be its own thing because there
are a lot of plants around the mo of
triangle that have that similar you know
look and it's just old Afghani type
plant you know yeah and so do you know
much about the history of Bubba before
you know Matt or you know if that is the
truth are you kind of going on at this
point I I tend to believe the story as
far as a Matt and Josh Josh the yeah and
so if we
that is a bit of a segue I got told the
other day that someone was like ah the
og that Josh brought to the scene was
ghost og and I was like no I thought
that was triangle and they said oh yeah
they're the same thing and I was like I
thought they were different what do you
think on that well it's a little bit
calm complicated but the way I read it
is there what would what Matt brought
from Florida is a bagsied I would assume
most likely from triangle cush so
imagine a triangle cush s1 that they
brought you know over to the Southern
California area and then the ghost is
basically just the cut that you know
Josh or them you know their people sold
to Oregon kid who sold to ghost which
it's weird calling it ghost even though
it's really just the Josh D cut you know
or the Matt Burd Matt Berger's cut you
know so so it's not the s1 you don't
think or it may be as far as like s1 of
TK or of TK sorry yeah I would mention
it's s1 because that's the way the story
uh you know plays out as far as Matt
Berger saying you know they got some
seeds in the back you know and I've met
a lot of people who you know grew or
bought triangle cush back in Florida
around the whole Orlando area and the
greater Florida area you know back in
the mid early 90s yeah so it definitely
was was there yeah and I mean that seems
to make sense to me because the the
triangle to me it doesn't have really
any hints of lemon in it and and the
ghost is quite similar in my opinion but
how did we make that jump from there to
the you know like the real heavy lemon
pie no geez we have now like commonly I
hear the idea that it was s ones led to
that and I can totally believe that but
I the one thing I struggle to grasp is
where did all that lemon
come from I just struggled to believe it
was recessive Lee in the TK is I think
maybe some kind of lemon male came into
the story for example maybe to make like
sfv or something along those lines right
well kind of take it like this I mean
when is one Bubba I mean you know you
you don't hear anybody saying Bubba
tastes like lemon lime or you know lemon
heads candy and yet just out of a simple
20 pack you know I pulled both those
types out other my buddy grew out 35
just a couple years ago of my fresh
batch and he found you know a lemon-lime
one and he also found one that was just
super fruity just like you know berries
and such you know yeah so there's a lot
of stuff hiding and s ones you know or
even s twos that you know come out you
know when you grow out you know the
seeds okay it's not it s ones are never
replicas of the mother cup you know
so just as a general question I was
thinking about it last night and I was
kind of struggling to find a clear
example of where there was an S one that
was better than the original plan and I
was wondering do you can you think of
anything that jumps to mind whether it's
an S one that's clearly better than the
parent I honestly most people who smoke
bomb threat think it's better than its
parent
I've got Mendocino Purple's s ones that
are definitely better than the parent
I've grown Arkell s ones that are better
than the herbal so most most lines so
far that I've done you know definitely
have individuals that are easily better
than you know the parent tissue okay so
and do you think that comes down to the
quality of the breeding like does good
feminizing practices affect the end
quality of the seed you know I was
actually just listening to your podcast
with them at riot yeah on some of my
stuff and I I'm one of the firm
believers that
I do not think you can change the
genetics no matter how the feminised
seeds are created I think if it's
accidental I think if it's you know on
purpose you know STS clear little silver
you know gibberellic acid I think you're
always gonna create the same exact seeds
no matter what you you really can't
change base DNA genetics I don't think
but okay you know I look I live in the
backwoods so you know and so like I mean
with that being said do you think then
that we should try to avoid the stigma
around like her me seed so to speak
because something I I've always noticed
is people will call like let's say bag
seat you know so it's like unintentional
male flowers on a female causing seeds
so people will call bags it's s1 but
then they'll also call like a properly
made feminized seed and that's one I
always thought you know should should we
call them the same or call them
different I guess in your mind they're
the same thing right there's just no
difference the only thing with bag seeds
that throws a shadow of doubt is there
there's always - two or three
opportunity you know options really they
could be s ones they could be feminized
hybrids you know one plant harmed on to
another or they could be random stray
pollen from a male plant so you really
don't know with backseat a hundred
percent unless you really know your
plants well you know and you're
responsible for those bag seats if it's
from some random bag you never know yeah
you know okay so are there any clones
that you've worked with that you would
consider to be like really highly
recessive and maybe not ideal for
feminizing in that they might make some
or is ones and the quality of the S
bonds is really good but as soon as you
put that pollen onto another plant it
just the results aren't as good that's a
good question
you know I don't know if I even ever
thought about that before oh
a lot of times I don't even point people
to s ones particularly because most s
ones in my experience you know tend to
have like forty or fifty percent like
recessive genetics themselves and with
the s ones you end up with generally
close to 50% of the population just
being weak and inbred you you definitely
get some strong you know good quality
plants but it's all with just pure s
ones it's almost like a throwaway so a
lot of times feminized hybrids work
better with an out Cross than they do
with an a swan so I don't know that's
not exactly the question but um you know
no that's awesome
and so I kind of like the follow up to
that is a lot of people will often kind
of say that the plant that's being
turned into the donat the pollen donor
will tend to be more dominant in the
cross as a rule of thumb do you find
that's the case or it's still just down
to the individual plan if it's like a
dominant plant in crosses and it kind of
regardless of if it's the donor pollen
it definitely varies and this is
something I definitely want to work on
more myself because I've I've done a lot
of opposite crosses like where you take
say you reverse bubba kush and you
pollinate purple Arkell and other times
you reverse or coal and you pollinate
bubba kush you know a lot of the
breeders like say sam skunk man you know
he'll say you know um they come out the
same but or kill avoid the question but
honestly i don't know you know i mean i
really want to run out like large
hundred or thousand lots of these seeds
of these reverse crosses because even on
the small level i've done them
you know it almost seems like they
produce different results depending on
the pollen donor so it's it's definitely
variable that
I don't know if I can fully answer that
question for sure
ya know I definitely would have to
disagree with the Sam on that one for a
few reasons I mean I'm pretty sure DJ's
short throughout the idea that he said I
always prefer the more sativa of the two
plants in Mike Ross to be the female so
straight away like he's agreeing that
there is something to that idea and it's
not just irrelevant and then more so I
was thinking about that myself because
I've kind of toyed with that idea myself
with just some kind of pollen and I
found that I definitely got better
results doing it one way than the other
so then it got me thinking well was it
the case that you know the way that
worked well was the way that's better or
was it just the case that when I did it
and I got good results I just did a
better male selection that run and so
the results came out better right
there's a lot of variables so it's it's
I think there definitely needs to be
some more scientific you know they're
regimens to you know say yeah now and
that question for sure okay and so I
mean if we just kind of jump to a bit of
a different topic for a moment we were
talking about the air-cool before the
pit for some people at least the Urkel
was like the oldest cut they have in
their library when did you get the Urkel
and as a follow-up what's the oldest cut
you've got in your library I got Oracle
around 2001 and pretty much the whole
family and everybody everybody I knew
had this Oracle you know around that
time it was the number one most popular
strain in California and beyond you know
for a good five five plus years their
oldest cut I still have the Humboldt
snow or the snow I got that back in I
think 99 I had a bunch of older cuts but
I lost all of those in 2002 so I think
the snow is the oldest one I still have
so I think I read a part from you I mean
you've already made the snow hybrids and
there
about to be released soon but I remember
like when you very first started doing
it you were like oh yeah I'm making
these hybrids I don't think people will
be so interested in them but I'm just
doing them for me mostly why do you
think people really interested in the
snow like do you think it's like not
really desirable compared to today's
stuff or it's just not fancy you know it
ain't no purple punted ain't no you know
gelato or you know wedding cake you know
it's it's not all these designer you
know hyped up things it's just old
school you know there's stuff that you
take one to hit too many back in the
late 90s and you're puking and the
gutter so how would you describe it for
someone like me for example who's never
had purists no I like is it kind of like
a sweet strain looks pretty frosty on
your Instagram yeah it's it's a frosty I
just described as like a frosty hash
plant a little bit piney skunky hashey
um just kind of old-school flavors and
originally the snow actually uh I guess
came from the Eugene area you know I've
even heard it potentially being related
possibly like a sister cut to Trinity
and then you know both of those possibly
related to four-way but that's just you
know things that I'd like to iron out
with some folks and actually see if any
of that pans out Trinity's an
interesting one I don't think we've ever
really spoken about it on the show but
the thing which caught my eyes besides
you know like the ambiguity of the
genetics and the name or whatever it a
lot of people comment like it's gone
downhill over the years it's sometimes
it throws manners apparently and some
people say the flavors not quite what it
used to be I'm always interested in cuts
that have degraded verses cuts that
haven't would you consider it to be one
that's really degraded and would you
still work with it I guess
you know I've never floured out the pure
serenity I've recently been given a cut
of Trinity that may or may not be
the original I seem to you know it
definitely looks like what I know of as
the original so it's definitely one that
has potential for you know s ones but
then again if it if it actually came
from far away then four-way might
actually be a better bet to you know dig
into and see what's in the genetics yeah
interesting interesting and so if we
just jump back to the oka we were
talking about in a moment do you have
any ideas about what the genetics may be
we've heard mad farmers speculate that
on the father's side it was maybe a
predecessor to Northern Lights - do you
know anything along those lines or
anything in general you know I've always
heard since early on after I got it
there was a couple things I was told
when I got it one that came off a bell
Springs Road and Bell Springs Road is
basically a back road between humble
Humboldt County Garberville and
Mendocino County and you know I honestly
I want to dig up Tom Hill one of these
days if he's still alive I'm pretty sure
he is but you know because a lot of his
genetics came from this cat named the
chemist
and I kind of almost wonder if this
chemist isn't responsible for merkel or
isn't you know once or twice removed
from somebody who's responsible for this
Urkel because people people said that it
was a Pakistani time skunk number one
and that was kind of like you know
almost called common knowledge you know
around southern humble you know so could
be true
you never know but I'm I'm running out a
bunch of pine tar pushes right now and
there are definitely a lot of plants
that resemble Merkel s worms so yeah
what can you tell us about Tom hill in
general I mean I don't know if you're
aware Mean Gene last episode said that
the chemist is Tom Hill's dad I don't
know if you knew that I didn't so I
thought that's cool and the other cool
thing too that is his arm anyway what
can you tell us about the pine tar
project there's some photos on your
Instagram it's a hard one to come across
I had a few packs of x18 and they didn't
germ so I was mighty impressed when you
got I think you said 230 out of 300 or
so yeah yeah so what's the goal with the
pine tar and what can you tell us about
Tom Miller in general well just just to
recap on the the pine tar cush so last
time I actually saw Tom in person was a
couple of years ago at the golden tarp
Awards and he promised me he he had a
thousand seeds left at the pine Turkish
and I told him you know the work I was
doing at the time and he's like oh well
you know I'll give you my last thousand
and you can do a big open pollination
and since then everybody I know and you
know who knows Tom including myself he's
pretty much dropped off you know that
the we'd grown planet so I you know I
was I was left to basically round up
just a bunch of pine tar cush seeds from
you know the community essentially you
know yeah but uh wait did I lose the
question no no and then what do you hope
to ultimately get out of the ptk project
I just think it's a quality pure pure
indica line so I mean the thing I've
been doing for the last few years at
least is just preserving and reproducing
all these you know just pure lines I've
done you know Colombians Burmese the
Pakistanis trawls
you know the pine tar is now a handful
of others so it's for future work okay
and how do you think and compares to
these other strains we've had a few
people say that
they've heard the pine tar pretty much
blows most of his other work out of the
water
especially the deep chunk which is
interesting because it you know it's got
such a cult following because it looks
so cool and it's pretty interesting but
at the same time it's pretty bland right
deep chunk by itself is definitely
boring I think there's good qualities
too deep chunk III reproduced that one
as well from some of his old 2003 stock
but the the pine tar yeah definitely is
one of the the ones out of his lines
that you know has definitely been one I
wanna I've been wanting to preserve for
a long time
the x.18 as well I've grown a little bit
of that out a couple times and every
time it produces some really nice just
you know landrace style plants so
nothing that you know people really want
these days you know yeah but you know
stuff to build on okay and so I remember
watching you interview with Kevin Joe
tree and you mentioned that the ogk
beefy no comes out in aerica less ones
about ten percent of the time so with
that being said do you feel like there's
a bit of Urkel energy KB or just a
common lineage between the two oh I I
definitely think that some part of if
they're telling the truth and everything
the cookies family I definitely think
there's some Arkell in the Durbin f1 you
know okay and so so do you think that
that is the case like do you think they
really know what they've got I get the
feeling they probably don't and day yeah
that's a tough one they might or they
might not you know I've got buddies down
in mindo who known them since they were
kids and most of those guys think they
don't know exactly 100% what they have
what they're working with yeah okay well
I mean maybe a more underlying question
do you think
they may not know what it is do you
think they were the ones we're like
operating the room where the seed was
originally conceived or the alternative
stories they got bags of it and they
were just the ones who popped it yeah I
think they're probably responsible for
but that's more more you know folks like
me and Jane you know downer Mendo would
definitely know more about that then you
know you know where where I was up in
Humboldt okay you know the back Trinity
well the other little popular idea at
the moment is that some common ancestor
of the cookies or possibly even just the
straight parent and it it's an s1 is the
cherry pie cush I'm not sure if you've
heard of it do you have any opinions on
that one whether it is possibly in the
you know the bloodline you know it could
be and and cherry pie is supposed to be
a granddaddy purple times Durbin f1 or
something to that effect right yeah I
think the one that is kind of getting
tatted at the moment is actually
apparently different to just straight
cherry pie and they call it cherry pie
coach even though I'm short a pie gets
called a pike wish by accident but
apparently it's different and the story
that's going around especially from the
gauge green crew is that you know Girl
Scout cookies is just an s-1 from this
plan and apparently if you grow this
plan it's a little bit self evident
interesting well yeah I know the plant
it was the one Tim Blake was growing
yeah and the other psi crew yeah yeah
yeah and then of course Alan I forget
your name Pattinson oh but how do some
yeah yeah I mean I've heard his story um
yeah I don't know yeah I was gonna say
with that being said just to go back to
oh gee KB do you think ogk B is like an
S one of Girl Scout cookies or do you
think it's maybe one of the original
seeds from the original stock which is
kind of the other story that goes around
yeah you know I've always thought you
know
was just s1 or whatever whatever but I
met this fellow a few weeks back up in
Portland
his is uh he went by the handle oh gee
cush breath yeah right you know and he
he's the guy that you know he's the
source of the OG kv clone and he swears
up and down it's the original sentiment
so I don't know yeah I've read a story
for him saying in his way as he popped
the seed and so there's like okay but
yeah I think that's maybe where that
that second story I mentioned got
traction because if he did pop the seed
well then yeah who knows anyway just
maybe a last little question on the
cookies thing will you ever consider
doing like a cookies s1 project and the
reason why I bring this up is because um
you know you got to give it credit it's
been around long enough that you kind of
have to consider it like a really elite
clone like it stood the test of time
it's still around right so you know will
you ever do that okay so this is a
little bit embarrassing
alright so I kind of took a break from
the internet for about three years from
2008 to 2011 and I stayed out of you
know any you know weed this that or the
other I enjoyed a little break and then
I'm when I came back it was like cookies
cookies cookies cookies like what the
[__] is this cookies yeah like what
happened you know I mean everything was
cool when I left so I come back and
there was all this hype and I was just
like oh hell with this you know this
stuff you know I I got a cut of the
forum the forum cut of cookies grew it
out you know it was nothing special then
I grew it out a couple more times and
probably the third time I grew it out it
was just like damn this is some really
fricking good weed and honestly it's
taken me a few years to you know wrap my
head around it but I'm like if there
wasn't all this hype
around the cookies I would honestly
think it is some of the best weed I've
ever you know grown and smoked so I kind
of wrap my head around that just this
last summer and I was like you know what
I don't care who I'm doing for I'm doing
it for me so actually right now I the
the form cut which is actually you know
my favorite one that I've grown so far
and I'm just making me a bunch of you
know 4ms ones and then hybrids just you
know because every single Girl Scout
cookie hi where I grow has really good
stuff in it even though you know you
definitely have to weed through you know
all the unstable ones out of the bunch
but you know once you're through that
there's really good quality plants out
of all the ones I've grown so yeah yeah
you know fantastic and so what type of
female
would you consider ideal to be like the
receiving end of the pollen from the
girls get you know what's the type of
plant that you think pairs well with the
Girl Scout you you know right now I
don't know because I haven't I I
probably have I don't know four or five
at most I think something that is kind
of similar to like the stature of
cookies like an OG Kush or kind of a
like the old family Purple's the Urkel
oh geez that I have some of those I
think would blend really well and kind
of keep that structure up and that
popcorn look because my favorite plants
are always popcorn plants which just you
know gaint
nuggets you know along the stems I don't
know yeah it's how though that's how the
old ones I grew up with work so how do
you think they got so small sounds like
a bit of a weird question like the
nuggets but like I look at all the
predecessors that are thrown out there
as possible Girl Scout cookie parents
and you know for example og cush you
know similar structure a small little
golf ball he knows but it's like they
took a markedly step smaller in the Girl
Scout cookies and it's like I don't know
it just seems like an odd tray like it's
which is recessive genetics or whatever
but yeah it just seems odd that they got
so small but so potent like do you have
any ideas about how that happened like -
selection or lottery ticket combination
type thing or yeah it could just be a
well then again you know who's to say
because you know the form cut which is
probably the most widespread one has a
small little popcorn I guess but the og
KB and The Thin Mints I don't think
whether they're the same or different
they're not as small as as the Forum
right yeah so just some form of you know
recessive recombinations you know
especially if you think maybe it's a you
know an s-1 or possibly s2 whatever and
so that's an interesting point you just
mentioned s2 we've seen more breeders
come out using s wands as mothers but
we've even actually started to see
people use s twos as mothers do you feel
there is a risk in doing this or do you
feel like maybe if you choose to do it
you just need to test the progeny harder
as a breeder if your doing so like what
would be your recommendations as a buyer
would you be like buyer beware or no go
for it you you definitely get more
uniform results using s2 s or breeding
with s ones you know so III think the
further you get like s1 s2 maybe even s3
you're gonna get tighter and tighter
phenotypic you know variation I've seen
it myself when you know I I do a
feminized hybrid with just the mother
plant and then I do a feminized hybrid
with s1 s1 selection the phenotypes are
a lot tighter and you know some of these
guys like good old Sam skunk man you
know they're they're not gonna be
advertising all over the place but
they've said it you know I mean those
guys are you know breeding stuff - s1 s2
s3 s4 s5 and that's how they're you know
isolating exactly what they want out of
the plants you know but then you got all
these people who are running around
like a hoe feminize is bad and it's like
why is that you know guys who have you
know the broadest you know experience in
the game you know being like this is the
way you do it you know yeah okay
and so I guess with that in mind do you
agree with the idea that there is an
increased risk of hemorrhage with
feminized seeds you know that that's a
tough one because pretty much every
single land race I've ever run it has
plenty of hermaphrodites I mean even Tom
Hills pine tars X 18s deep chunk you
bring those inside all of those have you
know a good percentage of hermaphrodites
you run out any regular seed
oh gee cush chem dog this that or the
other you give them a certain level of
stress they all have hermaphrodites you
know the the feminized seeds definitely
have their share it definitely gets
worse if you take extreme her Aphrodite
like say something that breeds strong
hermaphrodites like Girl Scout cookies
and cross it to another extreme
hermaphrodite you know like Girl Scout
cookies x Sour Diesel I mean I see
companies every day selling seeds just
like this I'm like how are they not
getting 110% hermaphrodites you know but
people still under certain circumstances
are getting you know great plants that
don't have the herm problems out of them
even off the worst hybrids yeah you know
and so maybe this one you may not know
the answer to because it's kind of a bit
abstract I guess but in terms of the
Girl Scout cookies where do you
attribute the hermaphrodite traits back
to you do you think it comes from like a
possible OG side and then it's just been
kind of aggravated in this situation
there's definitely a strong
hermaphroditic trait in OG Kush and it's
not even so much that the og cush itself
because I run tons of different OG Kush
clones and I've never really ever
had some problems out of them but when
you breed it you always get you know
anywhere from ten to twenty percent and
if you have a you know a little tent
with you know a bunch of light leaks or
hit them with you know extreme you know
doses of fertility you know you're gonna
end up with even more than that you know
yeah so the og is definitely a one
proponent but Girl Scouts seems like it
might have a couple a couple things in
it you you know how the the general
recipe Durbin f1 times Flo Rida og is
supposed to be Girl Scout cookies well I
bought a I bought a little sack of a
Durbin f1 off of Cookie Monster down in
LA earlier this year and man that he
pulled it out of this bag and I ain't
seen more bananas in a bag it was like
whoa that's one harm strain so I don't
know you know it's like there's so many
people who are like apart or
peripherally a part of cookie fam that
to me it's almost hard to know who's
what you know like there's there's the
people who you would consider the main
you know like burner and his crew but
now it's almost like no no no they're
not cook you fam it's like it's the
sizzurp guy and you know these are the
Cookie Monster and all that and so to me
it's almost just like man it's almost
like just so muddy it's hard it's hard
to know what's up you know right I think
the core fan was like s flux capacitor
[__] and then and then burner of course
as hype man yeah I mean like what
happened to PI go out for exampie a
still there
I don't you know in the original stories
they were saying like hey he's the one
who knows the genetics blah blah blah oh
I tried to stay out of it for so long
but you know Dragon you I do I know I
have curiosities myself you know so you
know I've got some experiments I've
to be running hopefully this winter if
things work out yeah well the thing I
always thought to myself is why doesn't
someone like just them just regular
Durbin - Oh JEE cush and see what comes
out because the you know that must give
you some hints right because if the f1
part of that Durbin f1 is really a
mystery will may be doing that cross
would maybe help a lude or I don't know
I mean I I run this German for a long
time and man I have a hard time maybe I
just need to run the og KB and the Thin
Mints but I have a hard time seeing a
lot of Durbin at all in Girl Scout
cookies I mean Durbin is extremely high
enter paneling and that's the smell you
get out of train wreck Jack Herer you
know that kind of stuff so that doesn't
seem to be a strong component to Girl
Scouts in general yeah this may be gonna
be a bit of an unpopular opinion but I
always fan Girl Scout cookies to have
like a certain licorice and a seed
component to it but then when I got to
smell the Colorado turbine I was like
this doesn't smell like aniseed at all
to me it just smells like really sweet
and like that's it like you're not
getting any licorice don't get nothing
and if I just smelt that I would have
been like I don't think this is a part
of cookies right right and that's the
thing - the most popular clone of Durbin
going around the u.s. is that one in
Colorado it it's actually everywhere
it's kind of weird I've gotten multiple
cuts of it it's the same thing you know
it's it's just high turpentine
I mean it's extremely high at tests it
like between 4 and 5% tor panel yeah
well and just that one toast yeah yeah
most strains don't even test at 1% for
all their terpenes
yeah yeah yeah it's a pungent it's
really really pungent right so a
question I was interested in probably
should have asked her back at the air
hole part I might even cut it back in
there
for me I was really surprised by how
thin leaf coal is and I guess just in my
mind I was expecting it to be a bit more
akin to like a barber because of you
know like the real indica medicinal side
of it do you think that this indicates
there's a lot to be said about thin leaf
indicas and you know like where are they
now type thing well I mean that's a
really good question so back to the you
know the the pine tar pushes that I'm
running out right now pack and and even
to go into like the Pakistani Street
rolls that I work with and work with you
know via canna Biogen these are all you
know Pakistani indicas you know whether
it's pine tar you know the [__] rolls or
X eighteens or whatever but all of these
are more thin leaf to indicas they're
not that broad you know hash plant leaf
or that deep chunk leaf I've got a male
pine tar right now that looks almost
identical to herbal and then I've got
another male that smells just like Urkel
so I'm like ooh you know future projects
we'll see yeah interesting and then
would you ever consider maybe trying to
like recreate like local for example in
the sense of using a few strains which
you saw different characteristics in it
but not ones that you thought were
specifically a part of the oak or make
up almost like a rock star thing yeah no
absolutely I mean it you know hearsay
has it that you know Arkell is a
Pakistani times a skunk number one right
so I mean I've had UK cheese since oh
five you know I'm like well why don't I
just take one of these select you know
pine tar pushes and cross it to UK
cheese and see what pops out you know
yeah that'll be really cool right you
know and that falls exactly ended a lot
of stuff that you know really kind of
entertains me is I like to recreate
things and see you know how things
combine and blah blah blah so yeah
awesome and so last kind of question on
the air call what is the difference
between the Urkel and the men dope herbs
there are extremely different the men
dough perps comes from my buddy down
there in Mendocino he sprouted the seed
back in 1998 you I'm I'm sure you know
his handle on IG not so dawg
but uh it came from he got the seed from
this old man out of Colo sprout the seed
and you know it is a very unique plant
to me it looks like kind of a an Afghani
type it has that kind of Afghani broad
leafed look to it
I've s one day I grew s ones you know
back in 204 grew a bunch of s worms a
few years ago of it and it doesn't seem
like there's really any sativa in it um
as far as the S ones go but there's just
a lot of unique terpenes just you know
stuff I haven't seen in any other plants
you know um yeah okay but uh and so it
is it's not going well it's very
different than herckel oracle tends to
be a cold dependent like it needs a
little cold a little bit of cold
temperatures too purple up whereas the
Mendo purple it has more of a natural
purple to it but the s ones of them and
no purple have an extreme a percentage
of those have an extreme natural purple
almost a black just from the start of
flower now a fantastic I think I've
actually spotted a few photos of that
one on your feed
yeah really dark if we just gonna jump
topics for a moment I wanted to ask you
about all the pure cush is going around
right now it seems like they've gained a
bit of traction recently there's there's
like the should cut the LA pew are the
top hangar I don't know how to say it's
a suburb in Cali I'm sure yeah there's
all those different ones I've heard from
a few people there similar slash the
same what's the differences and
and what is it when they say pure cush
like to me it brings like TK to mind you
know like like no lemon just cush is
that kind of what it's like or not
really yeah you know I'm with you on the
whole pure crush thing my buddy got this
pure Kush clone back in 2005 and gave it
to me it came from Orange County
some big warehouse grower had paid
$5,000 for the cut and I've had it ever
since and it's just an OG Kush it's it's
a good og cush it's more of a earthy
Hashi OG Kush no lemon or you know all
that no pints all but a lot of people
really like it but it's no relation to
the Bubba s type plant that Suge Knight
you know has his or hat as pure Kush and
then on top of that there's a bunch of
clubs out of like Malibu or whatever to
paint Topanga Canyon pure pushes that
aren't even the same cut as the one I
got back in Oh five and these didn't
even pop up for another what five plus
years after that hmm so I mean it's one
of those things where you know you could
try to figure it out or you could just
yeah just maybe right just to quickly
clarify something do you think it like
is it the case that the the sugar cut is
actually from Suge Knight I just thought
it was just like named after motive oh
um okay so back in 405 um there was this
there was this guy on canvas world not
sure if he was on overdrove but he was
he was having on a canvas world and he
he he got this cut that was originally
labeled pk
and he actually called it uh maybe it
didn't even have a label because he
actually called it bubba kush at first
but then he found out it was a PK and he
was calling it purple kush and then he
was like no it's not purple kush then
you're real able to piss cush
and then he was like no that's not it
and he was like okay it's pure crush
they told me now it's pure Kush he did
some breeding with it and blah blah blah
and sold seeds on a cannabis world you
know by a heaven stairway so it was just
a dude who used the handle Suge Knight
okay nothing to do with ya yeah I think
he's too caught up with his [__] with
biggie to be brief yeah yeah but you
know there's there's still some cats I
think who talked with them you know cats
like cats like rude boy and you know
grow hard but a rusher if he's too much
in the game anymore though yeah it's
interesting how so many people have
almost ducked out when it would seem
like it's the right time to put your
head up right right yeah so a bit of a
maybe a controversial question what's
the deal with purple punch winning at
chalice which is a little bit of a while
ago admittedly but everyone I've spoken
to says that strain has no potency it
looks great sure but [__] and then
it like it's winning cut like jungle
boys or winning cups with it and stuff
like how does that work for you do you
do you write it better than what other
people do like okay so all purple punch
is is um you know you you forget some of
the names on them right all it is is oh
gee Kush terms are essentially yeah
right you know and I just grew out you
know well over a hundred aji cush times
herbals you know that all the oh geez
had different names but all the Urkel
was just the same I had purple punch
phenotypes in there and what those those
plants are is they're extremely frosty
and extremely pretty and just gorgeous
plants with you know decent smells and
everything but yeah they don't exactly
you know have the punch a lot of times
when you have a lot of entries into a
cup and people are having to smoke all
those entries you know just one after
another you know bag appeal
and you know that kind of thing is gonna
really weigh out a lot on that
competition yeah you know and so and so
do you think that there's almost an
inherent flaw in the way that cup
judging is done these days in that you
know that's just like the judges are
just overload like for example we're
trying to run a little cup in Australia
at the moment and one of the rules we're
having it's all online but one of the
rules we're having is that the judges
are only only allowed to try one sample
each day and so people have been like
that's such a good rule oh and it's like
and it just doesn't seem to make sense
why they wouldn't do it in the States
it's like is it is it that poorly
organized that they can't get the
samples out early enough or like what's
the deal just to commercialize and they
don't care about it or too many entries
a lot of the time and yeah really
honestly you got it right there they
they don't care I mean I love the
emerald-cut you already know yep but how
can anyone judge 400 500 600 entries in
one month you know the media I mean you
you can kind of break that down unto you
know there's a lot of stuff just not
even getting tried yeah you have to
assume right right right it seems though
like whatever's like hit number eight or
nine if the day is just a blur so I mean
in general though do you get concerned
about that because I brought this up in
a previous interview given like seed
sales are affected by if Australian wins
a cup is that not a little bit of
concern to you given that things which
maybe shouldn't be winning are winning
and likewise things which you know
you've made which I may be really
phenomenal like they just get they slip
through the net type thing right right I
think eventually the real quality stuff
will kind of you know rise up and you
know it just might take a little bit
longer you know you know kind of a
word-of-mouth style versus you know
everybody you know just oh it won a cup
let's go get it you know yeah I mean
stuff like Irene horrible bag appeal you
know
um you know nothing to look at all but
everybody who smokes it she's like you
know we you know yeah that's what I
wanted to ask you back because the Irene
has got a lot of traction recently I'm
again archived he done a few hybrids
with it I believe you have as well it's
it's one of the two the other one was
the FCAT of OG I noticed that the F cut
in the Irene are quite unique you work
with both of them what do you like about
them and why do you think we don't see
them so much in other people's work well
Irene for example as extreme at least
for a long time she was extremely
hoarded and a handful of years ago I got
her from you know you know by a couple
friends from Rudeboy
and I just I didn't even think nothing
over you know I was just like whatever
and I threw out in my yard you know in a
200-gallon bed and grew out and it
wasn't even till you know late in the
fall about mid-september when I was like
ooh what's this you know because she was
just smelling something fantastic she
didn't look like nothing special all the
way up until there but then you know I
gave it to you know obviously I gave it
to you know doctor from archive and a
couple other people with rude boys you
know permissions of course and that's
where you know they started making the
hybrids with it and you know a little
while after I followed suit but uh she's
just a really really good quality smoke
I mean she's nothing to look at
whatsoever and she has this weird mutant
trait where she rose nuggets on her stem
P deals so you try trimming it and it's
like all the nuts all fall off with the
stems when he clipped from Hawks and it
is it is terrible she's she does have a
lot her prose in those departments but
man she is some good smoke you know so
and what
the F card the folks there the FCAT I
mean III i-i've called it fo G Kush you
know FA you X you know but uh early
early on that came from daintiest og
from icy mag and you know they they they
called it some of my buddies named it
the FCAT because they were like oh it's
just a fake Oh G so f stood for fake and
it was just a quality cut I mean the
first time I smelled it I was like ooh
this is some of the best smellin you
know og I've ever smelled and it was you
know grown grown by daintiest himself
when I first smelled it but uh it
definitely breeds a little bit different
than some of the oh jeez a lot of the oh
geez kind of be tall and lanky just like
a normal og whereas this one it breeds
kind of smaller and shorter so okay I
don't know squat yeah yeah so what og
cut in your opinion is kind of the most
underrated one you know like what you I
person I love Larry and I feel like it
doesn't get enough credit at times right
I've never tried the Larry myself I've
kind of wanted to but I mean I tend to
mostly stick with the triangle cush just
because that's the one I believe is you
know the one that started it all and I
figure if you can you know reverse that
one you should be able to pull out all
the other Oh G pushes out of it you know
I'm just s one style so you know and
when I breed with the the triangle cush
compared to the others I tend to get you
know the broadest spectrum of you know
phenotypes whereas with a lot of these
others it's like a lot narrower and
tighter yeah so and so yeah I don't know
if you're sorry going I'm just gonna say
I don't know if it's you know underrated
at all it's just you know my preference
for for The O'Jays yeah
okay and so what do you think
predecessors the triangle you know what
was that strain that Matt and Josh got
the bag of weed oh well the triangle
cash that I have came came from big
Ricky he gave it to you no doctor from
archive and then doc gave it to me but
that that cut a big Ricky cornbread
Ricky he claims you know he's had that
since 1992 and that predates you know
Matt Matt and Joshes you know oh gee and
he claims he got it as a cut you know
yeah um so I mean he's essentially the
one to talk to but you know some of
those stories get a little hazy a little
bit yeah okay and I mean but if you had
to speculate what do you think the
parents of the the triangle would have
been I've heard that you know just like
some land race possibly like where how
do you think Knights a bit more refined
than that
it very well could be just like a
Pakistani sativa hybrid I don't even
want to get into the whole sativa thing
because you know I'm no sativa expert I
like them but I don't have the time to
post something like takes 24 weeks yet
but uh I'm definitely uh definitely like
a Pakistani a sativa you know and so if
we just take a jump now from kind of the
ephemeral Femina has chat over to the
regular stuff you know it's dive into
the emerald parts of the Emerald
triangle stuff what is the next project
you're looking to do under that line you
know what's the next Mauer you're
looking to work with oh that's a that's
a good one
I've been trying a few different things
I definitely want to toy around with
some pine tar pine tar kushai bridge for
sure you know be and then I'm you're
spending the time to you know grow out a
huge lot of them and then I'm gonna be
directionally from from this you know
this lot but you know we'll see where
that goes I might toy around with a some
orange
orange type stuff I've been talking to
some buddies and we're looking to put
together a nice old-school orange
cornucopia so to speak so you know but
uh no I haven't made any long-term plans
quite yet okay
and so that orange one you just
referenced I've kind of noticed citrus
in general is like orange citrus
especially is very on the up-and-up even
beyond just tangi we're still seeing
things like Clementine being used quite
regularly in modern crosses with that in
mind do you think there's something
about the citrus terpenes which
specifically the orange ones which
allows it to kind of work as a flavor of
the month more so than other things and
what I kind of get by that is is I find
that like let's just take typical tangi
slash Caleo type turbans I find that
they're sharp like a sword like they cut
through things and it's like if you had
a bag and it's grown well you can have
just one but of you know that type of
stuff in there with a whole bunch of
other stuff and it just it cuts through
the rest and so in that regard I kind of
think like it's good that like you know
it's a good flavor of the month because
it's got these characteristics which
suit being flavor of the month you know
it's really loud and obnoxious and
people get a big blast out of it
you know do you think that that will
persist on beyond this fad because it's
kind of like Caleo was around then it
died out and then tangi came back it's
kind of revitalized it do you think will
fall off again or it'll stay more
present this time I think things kind of
move in circles right um so you know
like the purple cush is and the purples
and the grapes you know they had their
heyday and then they fell off and then
they had another heyday and then they
fell off and I think it's probably you
know the same with the oranges and the
bananas and this and that that's and
others
me personally I I would like to have all
the flavors in a seed form so that you
know it doesn't matter you know what's
popular today or tomorrow or the next
day you know I can always just be
oh well pop you know hundred of those or
a hundred of these you know so you know
on one side I definitely breed for the
public but on the other side I'm always
breeding for myself okay you know and so
what type of genetic base would you want
to use to kind of get those orange
fibers into across as far as like the
well for one there there's a good three
or four clones that circulate some of
them probably held pretty tight that are
all just extremely orangey old-school
clones have been around for twenty
thirty forty years well I've already
played around a little bit with the
80-77 Caleo cologne which dates back to
roughly about 1980 and then there's some
other ones that some of some of my
buddies hold that are definitely strong
orange types and I'm working with some
other cats who have some old-school I
guess you know orange Caleo seeds so I
might you know just try starting there
and see where that leads me do you find
some of the current modern orange
hybrids are a little lacking in potency
you know most of the orange strains seem
to be a little lower you know on the
potency tip for sure I honestly don't
think I've come across anything just
super orangey and super potent at the
same time so yeah interesting
interesting and so if we just jump back
to the work you're gonna do with the
males do you want to specifically look
to just breed with heirloom males
because that's already a trend you know
if we look at the previous Pakistani
released you did maybe I should Morris
you have a bit of a thing for Pakistanis
you know who got the PT K and then your
original releases can we expect more
Pakistanis or maybe different land races
or
just modern males even I definitely like
to lean towards the heirloom land races
but uh you know quality inbred you know
older lines are definitely a potential
as well one thing I think even just a
like a Redux or something uh I I almost
think that if you take a strong trip in
Moline mail like I found in the the
Pakistani Street Rawls and if you cross
that with you know some type of Caleo um
I think that Turpin alene added to the
orange actually is one of the
ingredients to kind of almost spike that
orange pungency you know through the
roof okay they're not interesting yeah I
had a feeling the terpenes definitely
played some role in that especially if
you consider like if we just both agreed
that orange terpene weeds Gentoo tend to
be a bit lower well that may be a good
indication that terpenes play some
bigger role in that all a follow-up
question to the previous one I wanted to
ask though is did you ever get like
weird questions or funny looks from
people giving you called it like for
example you'd be like oh this is the cam
dog f1 the purple local f1 because while
it is correct in the naming sense it is
a little bit ambiguous for what today's
buyers are used to and while someone
who's more experienced probably wouldn't
have an issue with it I think some
people were probably like is just Buick
M dog or like you know something like
that
you know I mean I get tired of the name
game I like a lot of us do and yeah for
those I almost just wanted to breed them
for myself and start from a starting
point where I can just call them f1 f2
f3 is that fours back cross ones etc etc
and I figured you know if people already
are gonna name their keeper cuts
whatever they want you know which is
kind of commonplace
his days so I was just like I'm just
gonna get lazy on this and just f1 just
calm all F ones and you know the the
lineage is right there on the package so
it's you know no no dispute what it is
but yeah yeah I definitely there
there was a small handful of nit pickers
being like oh how can you call another
clone f1 I'm like you know come up with
your own name yeah I don't care what the
name is it's an it you see what it is so
that's an interesting point you just
mentioned about people naming their
favorite clones I'm certainly guilty of
that myself but I think the one little
caveat I place on myself is I only do it
if I feel the clone is not only a keeper
but also quite unique from what you
would typically get from that stock so
it's almost like a little bit of its own
thing in a certain regard right and but
but like it's still muddies the waters
because you've got someone like me who's
like fanatic about making sure things
are listed correctly and all that
because I'm you know I deal with how
muddy that gets firsthand all the time
but at the same time I can understand
you know like me having a name for
something and then maybe if in
afterwards I put brackets like you know
whatever like the actual genetics it
might be confusing for some especially
people who are as a fanatical like maybe
they just pick and choose which parts
they want to say it is or whatever do
you think that's a practice in general
we should just avoid and find some
better way of you know like naming our
favorite clones or whatever or do you
think like on the whole it's not that
damaging I guess to the whole name game
considering where we're at ya know I
think it's tough I mean I'm a nitpicker
myself when it comes to lineages and
history and changing names and stuff so
yeah I mean I've I grew up with that
kind of stuff where you know early early
on we you know there was a train wreck
and then you know five years later
somebody else is calling something
different train wreck and then they you
know give up hundreds if not thousands
of clones and all of a sudden everybody
you know knows that there as train wreck
where as we knew something else as train
wreck so
the name gameis is it's definitely tough
I mean yeah there's no there's no right
answer to it and just out of curiosity
in a previous episode Bob Hemphill
mentioned he's had train wreck so long
he's just like so over it now he's like
so sick of the turret profile has that
happened to you as well he says it
happens to a lot of people yeah yeah I
mean I definitely go don't I almost ever
go for my my train wreck bag but I still
you know have sentiment
you know cinnamony alley that word yeah
for for train wreck you know it was one
of the earlier ones I think I got it in
like 99 we were buying sacks of it you
know back in 1994 you know it was
actually different 99 1 but you know but
uh yeah you can definitely get tired of
some things but I try not to throw the
ones I like to away yeah yeah I think he
actually expressed a similar sentiment
what I would be interested in knowing
though is what do you think the genetics
are of trainwreck because everyone I
feel like it's almost people don't want
to guess because they're like oh well
you know trainwreck was just a name for
the style of breeding where you just put
it all you know like the one mile around
all the females and just let it go and I
get that that's cool but I still feel
like the people in the know would be
able to have some kind of guess of what
it is you know like I've heard you know
it's like a three-way hybrid of land
races or something like that like what
do you think you you know um considering
the fact that you know the one that you
know spread out from Arcada in the late
90s is not the same one I I kind of tend
to think that it might have been almost
the terpene profile that you know if you
smell that turpin allene you know it's
it's the same Terpening that's in durban
poison you know so I I kind of wonder if
it's just not oh you smell that and you
think oh that's train wreck because the
earliest dated train wreck literature
that I've come across is from 1982 in
Mendocino County Wow that that that
dates it back you know yeah I mean it
was nothing but landraces and trainwreck
you know oh yeah so and so it's just as
a bit of a curiosity question as far as
you're aware what's the oldest clone in
existence oh I'll give you a hint if you
want a few people have said yeah
probably Romulan yeah I don't even know
how how old Romulan is or even how
available legit piece of Romulan is
because Romulans one of those ones that
kind of got screwed up a lot you know in
the whole BC scene where they started
yeah they started putting out a bunch of
hybrids as Romulan and so everybody has
a hybrid of Romulan another call and
Romulan yeah you know but uh does that
one date all the way back to Mendocino
and the California blue indicas I've
heard it goes back to 69 down kind of
what you said does hold true cuz what I
heard was the case with so basically
there was a guy and he was kind of doing
his own thing for ages and he had got it
off Romulan Joe in 69 and then when like
you know the internet came about he came
back so I think there's a whole lot of
room in that timeframe for things to
have changed as you said but in saying
that you know I got a few good friends
who they're pretty confident it's the
real deal and so you know who am I to
say otherwise but um yeah as far as I'm
aware the cut was lost so to speak to
the masses and then it was just this guy
who popped back up and was kind of like
oh no no I got it and I've just been a
hermit for the last thirty years or
whatever so yeah like if it's true shout
out to that guy yeah yeah yeah no I
actually was a kind of curious to check
out that cuz that cut is if if I'm not
mistaken the original Romulan cut is
kind of almost a length
your plant with popcorn nuggets you know
kinda like OG but a different looking
plant for sure so I mean I've heard a
lot of people say that the pnw hash
plant is the source of a lot of really
good cuts potentially the the same hash
plant that Nevel originally used in the
seed bank to create a lot of his lines I
think I've seen that you've got that one
or you had some experience with it
what's your opinions on that I'm not
gonna say I have that one I have an old
hash plant from up in the Seattle area
Pacific Northwest but also there's a
bunch of hash plants up there you know
like the u dubs and all those so it's
definitely one I can't you know trace
back to ok and say for sure this is you
know the one or whatever but III know
whatever whatever Nevel
you know collected and worked with was
definitely a quality piece for sure yeah
and so do you value like his stock as
the high stuff you could possibly get
like if someone said to you I've got a
pack of the seed bank I've got a pack of
SSS C and I've got a pack of Bo gear you
know brothers of the eternal love which
one would you pick I'm probably tend to
go at ball yeah and so what out of this
stuff would you be most interested in if
you could get it I just mean you know I
like the original sources Neville's
seemed to be like a collector who came
over to the US and Bowl seemed to be
like not so much collectors but
essentially collectors who collected
from other you know those sources of
origin so Neville is like a step removed
from where you kind of want to get the
you know the stuff from and all mental
stuff was all you know hybrids anyway
yeah yeah he didn't do pure lines
another thing which I was interested in
is I had heard that some of the bowl
stock with hit and miss which I thought
was interesting because it's like if you
thought about it you would you'd swear
that it's got to be the most under
at point so to speak where you could get
seeds from at least commercially in the
Western world do you agree that it would
have been hidden miss or do you think
nice it should have been all fire no I
definitely had missed because Land Pure
Land race you know seeds are extremely
variable and amount of breeding that you
know it has actually been done on a lot
of them is is is not it's not very
selective you know at least from what
I've seen you know so yeah I can
definitely imagine you know just based
off my own you know land race you know
preservation runs you know there's
there's a lot of garbage and then you
can you know find good stuff but it's
not what most people want it's it's also
why I don't sell any of that kind of
stuff because even though people think
they want it they really don't want it
you know they grow to a ten pack and
they're like oh [__] pirates you know
the helling all you know reads this crap
okay so and so how do you ever consider
maybe taking a very select stable
phenotype from a land race stock you
found and maybe like doing some hair
swans on it seeing how stable it is and
releasing that where it's like look you
want the land race Afghani here's a
somewhat refined but still undiluted
version of it
right well even better when I take a
land race and actually grow out a
hundred or two hundred of them or even
something you know as a simple as a
Preserve you know you know heirloom land
race like pine tar cush my my step one
is always to do an open pollination
where I take all the boys and I
pollinate all the girls and then I I
when I do that I also make my selections
for the next round and I pull out all
the select boys and all the select girls
the best of the best of those big lots
and then I directionally breed those so
it's you know it tightens
a lot and gets rid of the garbage and
for you know you know for next
generation if I sprout those seeds it's
gonna be a you know a lot more uniform a
lot more quality and then you know I can
go from there you know with multiple
generations to really isolate quality
it's all about selection that's all
breeding is okay so I've got a bit of a
hairy question which might be hard to
answer might be easy people often talk
about if you were to get landrace
genetics yourself you'd likely have to
do some you know refining some culling
all of the usual business they mention
my question is in relation to a lot of
Southeast Asian land races people will
always say expect some hermaphrodites
what would you do though if basically
every female you had showed
hermaphrodite traits have you just like
hit the losing ticket there or is it
possible to breed those together and
then in the f2 s to try to find
something which didn't have afroditi is
it just like you know not worth wasting
your time if you can't find semi-stable
nests in the first generation right I
would definitely say open pollinate just
like I do already all your females times
all your mails and then grow out as
large of a lot as you can and pull out
the least hermaphroditic out of the
bunch and then you know breed further
with those and oftentimes if you know
you narrow it down like that then you
can out cross it to you know something
else that's probably more stable and
they get into the f2s of that and
actually pull something out that you
know potentially won't have the problems
so if people take a glance back at those
earliest seed bank magazines often
there'll be a little comment saying are
inbred for four generations or something
along those lines is that the type of
time frame you should expect if you're
gonna try to embark in such a product a
project or is that the time frame to
expect if you want to do it to the
highest level because a lot of people
will say that you know like the early
year was phenomenal and some also works
because it was done properly is for
generations like overkill to the point
where like you're going to have a really
really good product or just the standard
well honestly a lot of the old ones they
they pushed F wands like they searched
you know line a and line B they either
used a clone for you know the mother and
then searched you know through a lot of
plants for you know the mail and then
you know they released F ones a lot of
times you know oftentimes it all depends
on how how well it's bred you know
between you know f1 and f4 whether that
f4 is quality or garbage you know and
unless you grow them out that's the only
way to tell yeah and that's kind of I
guess a point that complex me for a long
time you know back in the day
theoretically there was the least amount
of information about cannabis breeding
around of course there's general
breeding philosophies which are up
liable to cannabis and never was
utilizing those but what I struggled to
understand is like you just referenced
someone takes an f1 take it to the f4
usually it's [__] by the f4 because they
haven't done good selection along each
step of the way and so it's correct and
so like it's hard for me to believe that
a certain amount if that didn't happen
with Neville because it's almost like
what he was just like all like extending
it to most breeders back then you know
it's like what everyone took things
several generations it was always an
improvement at each step they seemingly
did it you know that you didn't take
them a year to do each generation they
seemingly did it probably like you know
each 3-month cycle they progressed a
generation yeah and so it's like were
they like gods of selection like how you
know what I'm it just seems odd because
I've got some Apollo 13 F fours and I
got some f1 and it's just like night and
day difference and I so I can't help but
feel like a similar thing must have
happened to a smaller degree maybe right
right and a lot of times breeders aren't
selecting from very big pools at all I
mean I've read how you know certain
breeders you know are only selecting
from ten seeds that at a run I'm like
well you know that's it's not much
that's not right
reading right there I mean I could do a
lot of work if I'm only doing from 10
but I like to work with at least a
hundred and if it was a perfect world
yeah thousands would be real nice yeah
you know and so I read an article and it
says that you really go ahead this is
gonna sound funny but it said you're a
really good interview because you're
able to articulate your thoughts on
males quite well and I think honestly
that's probably the question most people
listening to this show are interested in
you know how would you describe your
ideal male you know is it dependent on
each project and more importantly what
characteristics to you good
characteristics that you look for Oh
I mean I'm fairly simple with the boys
ideally I'm looking for something that
you know puts on some Frost is stinky
and usually that's kind of a benefit to
you know if they're frosty you can
actually get you know some of their
touring terpene profiles off of them
I've got buddies like with a 707
seedbank he and I think archive might do
it a little bit too but 707 he he
reverses all his males with floral so he
can really get a good solid you know
smell on you know what they're like and
kind of get a better look because it
reverses them and makes them kind of
more of a female plant but yeah
frost emails you know stink emails and
then bottom line is uh you know grow out
the progeny and see what happens and so
I guess it goes without saying because I
mean you just mentioned it you think
that resinous males are good or maybe
superior to others do you believe though
that the the terpene profile you get off
rubbing those trichomes is pretty much
what its gonna pass on or there'll be
some variation or it may not have any
correlation it really depends it depends
if the
if those terpenes are recessive or
dominant you know I've had some males
that are extremely dominant and then
others that just you know go right
underneath you know and the and the
females chirps you know pop right out on
top so it's extremely variable yeah okay
and so how do you feel about the idea
proposed by both there's a lot of
readers actually a bit like notably DJ
short and Tom he'll throw their weight
behind it that the idea that there may
be something to males that also produce
a few pistols in terms of them being
like quite good males you know like I
guess what you would say males showing
intersex traits of being a female you
know how do you feel about that
honestly I I definitely don't agree that
males that show intersex are are better
I think Sam skunkman said the best you
know a hermas or her it doesn't matter
if it's a female her or male her and
I've seen plenty of male Herms you know
and a lot of people I don't think even
spot the the male Herms out because most
breeders I think killed their males two
to three weeks in the flower and don't
even flower out the males and a male is
just like a female he's gonna herm
a lot of times between six and eight
weeks in the flower and also a male is
gonna tend to frost up you know six to
eight weeks into flower just like that
female you know I mean so a lot of
people they kill their males before they
ever frost up before they really get
their terpenes you know fully you know
developed and so they never really know
what they're breeding with you know so
and so you know I'm sorry going oh no I
I mean I I tend to you know oftentimes
let my my my male plants flower out like
a full eight weeks or more you know just
to see what
what they produce yeah just out of
curiosity have you ever seen a male
plant - a similar thing to a female
we're like at the end of the flower
cycle it'll produce some intersex you
know like nodes in order to maybe try to
self-replicate or do you think that's
more of like a deeply ingrained female
trait as opposed to a male trait oh yeah
yeah yeah no that's why I was saying a
lot of times the males go don't put on
pistols until six weeks or further in
the flower yeah interesting in any few
were to get some of those seeds created
on the Maya pistols and you pop them
here what would you expect the offspring
to be like you know I've never sprouted
them and I've got at least three lots of
seeds that are male x males in my fridge
some of them I've had there for quite
some time and if we're gonna you know
we're gonna believe guys like Sam the
skunk man who was actually sprouted he
say he seeds and grown them supposedly
they come up with something like 25%
female plants and then 50% kind of inter
inter sex male plants and then 25% male
plants but I haven't personally sprouted
them so so as like maybe a smaller
breeder who doesn't have like oh not not
you but as someone else who doesn't have
a lot of facilities maybe they're just
toying around with their let you know a
few tenths or whatever is there any way
you could recommend being able to hold
on to a male and being able to flower it
out the full length without just ruining
your crop that's that's tough I mean
when I do it I either am doing my open
pollination and so I just leave the
males in the room for the whole time and
just take care of them to the end or
other times I have pulled out all the
males and basically just filled a full
you know 4x4 tent with something like 80
or so males
and you know just kept them you know
going in little six inch square pots you
know for eight weeks you know it gives
you that idea of what yeah you know what
you're looking for but yeah as long as
you have an isolated space it's not near
the females it's just fine
okay and I mean you just kind of
mentioned an interesting topic we've
asked a few different guests what in
your opinion is the ideal way to feed
our hunt and so what I mean by that is
is what's the smallest size pot for
example that you think you can run a
plant in and you still get an accurate
representation of the plant but you know
like it's fairly small and you can fit a
bunch of them you know and do some good
hunting yeah I think the smallest I'd
prefer to do is probably about like a
two gallon a two gallon pot which you
know the two gallon errs I use you can
put 36 on a table any smaller than that
and I don't know if you're getting
enough of a representation and you're
gonna lose quite a few because of you
know plants drowning out and just being
too small to keep up yeah yeah yeah and
so something people will probably notice
if they check out your Instagram is
you're a fan of running like the beds
with the buy all the same strain in the
bed are you like a big advocate to this
do you think people really need to start
doing it themselves would you think it
just happens to suit you and you know it
might not work for everyone beds
definitely have their pros and cons I
generally have way more stuff than I can
handle
and I don't have a big crew to help me
so I need you know stuff to be as easy
as possible and so you know for me you
know running 10 or 20 beds is like
running 10 or 20 pots you know I mean I
only have to water 10 or 20 you know
versus hundreds and hundreds of pots you
know so it's it's definitely a necessity
for you know somebody who's not running
a big crew or anything yeah okay yeah
and do you find
the plants will try to out-compete each
other if they're not of the same strain
because that's an idea that gets thrown
around a lot but I've never actually
toyed with it myself where you know
people say oh if you run if you run all
all seeds from the same strain like
they'll just they'll exist harmoniously
but if it's two different strains
they'll fight each other and you know
one will come out on top
do you think that's a bit of an
overstatement no no if you have
something fast growing in the beds yeah
and something slow growing yeah the the
the fast growing rooms are gonna blow
away the others I always try to kind of
match what I'm growing in my beds I
either do a full bed of just you know
one one type or I you know just make
sure that they're planted so that you
know nothing's gonna get you know
drowned out and sure even still you know
they're still seedlings and plants that
do get drowned out from time to time but
I'm always ruining you know 16 25 36 you
know or more per bed so you know I get
most of them to come out yeah I was
gonna say it looking at um some of the I
believe it was the purple Urkel TK
hybrids or something along those lines
though they were all really uniformed I
was so blown away impressed I was like
[__] like I was not sailing it would
have been a challenge to keep that going
happy ok right I mean luckily I've had a
lot of experience doing it so some of
these runs just you know you throw them
in you try them two weeks later and they
just do it all themselves
so yeah awesome Anna and just a quick
little curiosity question do you co2 at
all I think that it's fat it's full an
awful lot like I think it used to be a
lot more of a bigger thing than it is
now like where do you sit on that one I
have I I toyed around with it 20 years
ago a little bit but I I've never I've
never really used co2 at all and you
know when when I was commercially
cropping inside I mean I was still
pulling you know two two-and-a-half
upwards of three pounds of light even on
some of my seed runs you know
I'm growing straight from seed I'm I'm
hitting two two-and-a-half pounds of
light so no co2 passive passive intake
just active exhaust and no air
conditions the air conditioners or
nothing like that I'm also on the coast
so you know it's cool in my neighborhood
okay and just to clarify for everyone
are you an organic guy you have a bottle
guy where do you sit on it or how do you
do you feel it affects the end product
ultimately oh yeah I'm organic and I'm
extremely simple I really don't use
barely any bottles at all
I mix dry amendments into my beds you
know like fish meals bone meals or like
fish bone meals Cal this that the other
and I just mix all that stuff in you
know at the beginning of each run and
then I water with plain water as simple
as it can get and basically I'm prepping
to do you know a really big indoor
organic grow in the future
that's going to be automated so that's
what I'm working kind of my my my setup
towards you know just automated organic
pure water you know yeah Kapus yeah
after my heart so with that being said
do you find that the end product is is
dramatically different like I'm of the
opinion that you know I guess anything
grown to the highest level is going to
be really good but as a general rule of
thumb I find organic even if it was
let's just say you had a strain and you
only consider it to have been grown to
say 80% of its potential and we have two
buds one organic one synthetic or you
know like bottled nutrient type thing I
believe that if it's not maxing I think
if they were both 100% well grow and
they'd be pretty similar but if we're
just talking to say 80 percent or less
than 100 which i think is the realistic
situation most of the time it's not
grown absolutely perfectly
I think the organic one wins out by a
fair margin do you agree with that or do
you think maybe
the more of a closer race than I'm
giving it credit honestly I think
sometimes some of my buddies stuff that
combine organics and chemicals you know
tend to tend to be a little more pungent
and almost a little more tasty than just
pure pure organics like I do years ago I
used to do a chemical organic you know
thing and I I think I it definitely came
out more pungent when when I was
combining the things it was I was
definitely getting high yields back then
I'm using a lot of bottled this is and
that's and all that kind of stuff but I
I haven't honestly done a side-by-side
trial to really I think that would be
the best bet you know just side by side
same environment same everything but you
know keep one organic do one you know
chemical and then you know see what you
know really uh your taste buds tell you
in anime you know how you have an
organic snog you know are you happy to
try whatever or you know why would you
get down on some jungle boys stuff I'll
try some stuff even even if I don't know
where how it's grown I think we we all
tend to take in and buy stuff that
hasn't been you know done the best so
from time to time so I'll try a variety
of stuff
so let's change topic for a moment get
to subject near and dear to my heart and
probably most people who listen to this
show chem dog you are actually probably
one of the I guess to the public one of
the lesser known aficionados but for the
people in the know I think a lot of
people know that you are probably one of
the foremost cambogia experts especially
in regards to how they grow being able
to compare them between each other often
I hear people tell me you know parts of
the skunk VI story which I'm very
familiar with and they'll be like oh
yeah and skunk VI posted online an
inspector was the guy who vouched for
him and was like
that's the chem dog and I went and
checked the thread and sure enough you
are the first person to kind of chime in
and be like yep that's definitely the 91
and so yeah you know why don't you give
us a quick little rundown on your
history with the chem dog and how you
kind of got in twined in at all yeah
that was an accident right there so
basically it kind of stems from Jason
Kings canna bible that came out early
2000s and he was raving about this chem
dog right and so it was kind of on my
list you know if I ever came across it
you know I'd love to check it out well
you know come about 2004 2005 you know I
got a chem dog cat you know from one of
my buddies and doing research on it it
didn't look nothing like a chem dog you
know at least what I believed to be you
know legit chem dog and then uh I was
talking to my buddy set at 7:07 seed
bank and he was like oh well you know
I've got the original chem dog from
skunk VA when I was like a little sweet
you know and so you know he basically
gave me uh you know the chem dog he had
gotten directly off of skunk ba and
skunk VA you know he was on overgrow
background 2005 and he had posted
pictures up and I think G was on there
and G was like yep that's the chem dog
so everybody you know who was pertinent
to the discussion had you know pretty
much validated skunk VA is chem dog as
the one you need so I was like that's
the only one I want right there and then
when do you sent a job ransom seeds and
Joe brand started the one through four
you know I I told my buddy at the time
you know hey you know run down to Sonoma
and you know give me some cuts off those
seed plants because he'd been talking
them so he did that and he was all
excited about this that other chem dog
red and all I all I wanted was that chem
dog one through four and so I got those
and then when you came out to to do his
2006 tour you know he gave you know
multiple buddies the the chem dog D in
the chem dog sister so I got those you
know from obsolete and then I also got
another chem dog D from Joe brand but
essentially you know by 2006 I had I
think what seven different chem dogs you
know all from you know the sources and
so you know I grew a long out well you
know and so how did you kind of go from
having grown them to being more kind of
what I consider to be the man who a lot
of people think is possibly the only
holder of like the one - the one and two
because I think you the only one who
really put up like detailed descriptions
and photographs of the one and two and
everyone's always really interested like
do they still exist and because there's
kind of a bit of a vacuum around that
general discussion I think people just
assume like our inspectors probably got
it well it's kind of funny because when
I ran those four out Joe brand he
sprouted the seeds and he groom out that
summer in 2006 he really only gave the
one through four to two people me and
this this other cat down around the bay
I think who's actually turns out his
buddies with you know some of my buddies
down in mindo but anyways so there was
only two people who ever had the one
through four aside from Joe brand and
anyways when I ran all four of them out
I wasn't a huge fan of the number one it
was kind of kind of a more hazy thing
more sativa thing just flew fie buds
didn't really have this small profile
that I really cared for I really like
the two though
had like cushy popcorn nugs on it had
out like a bubble gum diesel smell to it
it was really nice anyways so I gave I
think at least three or four of my
buddies um the chem dog to cut and then
I kind of right around that time or a
little after that time I kind of just
dropped my entire mother collection and
took like a three year vacation a little
sabbatical well when I came back my
buddies are all you know they all had
the chem dog too and I get it back and I
grow it out and I'm like wait what the
[__] it's not you can come dog too you
know I had scrapped the chem dog one or
so I thought well as soon as I grew it
out I I knew I was like oh man and every
single buddy I had given it to same
thing so I had accidentally given
everybody chem dog number one and nobody
had chem dog number two so to this day
we still have chem dog number one but
nobody's seen chem dog number two since
about 2007 2008 so but the the chem dog
number one is kind of unique
I mean it's extremely high in Mersin it
tests that I think upwards of like four
percent nursing which is really strong
for just a you know a monoterpene or
whatever they call it and it's 12 12
plus weaker just as potent as any of the
other chem dogs but uh yeah it hasn't it
hasn't really gotten too widespread
since since Joe grant starts routed that
seed and I think pretty much anybody who
has it got it from from me or you know
one of my buddies who I originally gave
it to okay and do you think the chem -
is most likely just gone in general or
do you think maybe someone's got it it's
definitely gone I mean I made a couple
hybrids with it back in Oh 607 you know
chrome chrome grew the chem dog -
crossed a deep chunk that I made I think
in oh seven but uh yeah I'd say I'd say
it's safely gone okay and then sorry I
guess the big ultimate money question is
what do you think the genetics behind
doula
like chem dog yeah where do you think
the chem dog comes from I think Kim dog
is just I mean I'm my uncle grown-up he
was a professional photographer and he
kind of traveled the world a little bit
collecting seeds taking pictures then he
brought a bunch of those home and so
I've got you know he passed away in the
80s the mid late 80s and so I've got all
these pictures that he took uh you know
these pure landrace in the COS and
sativas and everything that he grew out
and the Kemna any one is very similar to
some of these pure land race in because
that he had in the early 80s and you
know I wouldn't be surprised if it
wasn't something pure like that or maybe
even just you know some type of Mexican
you know indica or you know some type of
sativa indica hybrid you know from the
early days back in Oregon because you
know Joe brand is adamant that that came
from you know those pounds came from you
know Southern Oregon area so you are one
of the few people who I know still has
contact with Joe brand what can you tell
us about Joe be you know what's he doing
does he plan on pumping his head up
again he wants to he wants to he's
trying to get his life back together
that's for sure you know so uh hopefully
it works out and he doesn't get caught
up in things again you know you found
he's definitely been through a rough ten
years that's for sure so if we just jump
back to the feminizing for a moment you
versed on the fair few lines which one
in your opinion has the most
treasure locked inside of it which maybe
isn't apparent on face value like you
know if we reference the the bubble you
mentioned earlier it has that lemon lime
in it you know I guess that's not really
a self-evident that's locked in there by
any means what what in your opinion yeah
the greatest treasure trove Australian
2s1 I guess Oh see that's a tough one
because I really love a lot of s1 Baba's
they're extremely unique some of the
URLs they're they're rare but there's
some just pure grapey you know I don't
know just potty just really high quality
ones in there but overall my favorite I
think and this is just a personal thing
is the men dos Mendocino purple s ones
there's so much variation in those so
many different terpenes it's it's
extremely variable and in the S ones
with so many different plants and just
expressions
it's definitely bar none my favorite
even though it's not you know even
remotely one of the more potent you know
ones out of the bunch yeah no worries
and so I mean we heard from Bob Hemphill
in a previous episode you know that not
so Doug was the guy who popped the seeds
do you know if it's true that he
initially actually got two seeds and
there was a male and he may or may not
have culled it yeah okay so when I met
not so dawg
he actually hit me up on Instagram and I
had known some of his you know friends
and acquaintances and buddies over the
years and turns out we died we'd even
been to the same parties down in like
Sonoma and Mendocino and stuff but we'd
never met and anyways he hits me up on
our Instagram and he's like hey you know
I'm gonna sprout a seed blah blah know
I'm like front from probably almost 10
years ago I had met some kids who
actually knew him and they had told me
his you know story way back then and I
was like you know
didn't you have a male and a female you
know and then the male who accidentally
got killed when a light fell and lopped
off its top and he's like how did you
know that story well I got a weird
memory and you know I'm uh you know some
of your friends but yeah he's like I
didn't tell them almost anybody that
story and yeah anyways so he knew I was
legit I knew he was legit cuz his story
was like just added up you know all the
way so yeah we've we've uh DS ever since
that's also and what do you do you think
it's pretty safe to say that Maya would
have been something special also it
could have it could have it yeah and so
what do you think about the idea of if
you pop feminized seeds and you find a
full-on nail so it's not like a female
that shows male tendencies but it's just
a straight male and you can't find signs
of a female what do you think the guy
that plan is like is it safe to treat it
as if it's a male like if you wanted to
breed with it would you go ahead or you
know I'm in a tough position with that
one because I have grown out literally
thousands of feminized seeds that I've
made and I still have yet to find one
single legitimate male I've followed
other people who have supposedly made
the same exact s ones and eswin hybrids
and they've pulled like multiple males
out of their stuff so uh I honestly
think you know ninety-nine point nine
percent of males found and feminized
seeds are from pollen contamination
basically there's male pollen somewhere
and yeah that's where the males come
from in all my growing of s ones I found
what initially sextour sextoy oh and
it was obviously a Pakistani hybrid and
I had done a Pakistani pollination in
the room the round before and I had I
thought I cleaned the room proper but
I'm pretty sure you know obviously I
missed one gray Nepal you know and then
another time so that that right there is
pollen contamination the other time I
had a bomb threat feminized hybrid
sexing as a male and about two weeks in
the flower it was all balls and then it
just started putting on hairs you know
went full female after that so that is
just an extreme hermaphrodite so out of
out of thousands of films that that's my
experience with males and I think Paulin
contamination is is the majority of the
males that people find but who knows
yeah I mean it certainly seems like a
plausible explanation while we're on
that topic like I guess you know kind of
underlying issues with see production
how do you feel about the rise of the
more large breeders who I guess
essentially have the market and the
resources to outsource their seed
production gee do you think that this is
we're entering like a bit of shaky
ground with that or do you think that
quality control is not likely to suffer
from doing so I definitely think there's
a some definite pitfalls with that I
mean some of the stories I've heard and
I'm sure you've heard plenty of them to
a lot of these big companies they don't
make their own seeds and a lot of times
you see people grow and some of their
seeds out and it is not even remotely as
advertised you know they're pretending
they're using or they're say and they're
using this cut or that cut or the other
and it doesn't resemble anything what
they're saying you know as far as
progeny goes I mean I don't mean
personally I don't believe in the
outsourcing at all myself but I know
most of the big companies do
would you have exactly the kind of
scaling up your operation to have like I
guess a bigger crew involved or do you
always want to keep it reasonably
hands-on yourself I think as long as you
know I have a good oversight on
everything I could probably you know
handle handle doing it with the crew and
as things you know progress at least
here in California
I'm definitely needed you know gonna
need to go that way I mean I have a
small crew now but you know ideally you
know you neither quite a large crew to
go through the kind of numbers and you
know doing as much of the research and
development as I'd like to do so
definitely gonna need you know a handful
growers and you know just workers and
all that kind of thing to to do a
project like that yeah okay and so you
know we've mentioned a few times in the
episode already like the terpene content
of plants I'm noticing that terpene
content seems to be quickly overtaking
in terms of like consumer preference the
idea of like THC percentages you know
it's like first THC percentages come
around people got hooked on that idea
now terpene percentages are out you know
more popular people seem to be late
gaining traction readily like the idea
of let's get real high turbine strains
do you think that this is going to be a
lasting trend or just more of a fad
thing because I guess the underlying
kind of idea is that
at the end of the day as much as the
numbers of THC values you know may be
boosted or detracted from the popularity
of certain strains people still kind of
agree that you know like it's just about
smoking it and like that's kind of the
best measure at the end of the day do
you think that will probably apply to
the terpenes as well or you think it'll
be like a lasting thing I think it'll
last at least very good Wow especially
considering a lot of the higher terpene
strains people are using for
concentrates and so you don't even
necessarily need that high of a THC to
make a
you know high THC you know potent you
know concentrate and then so then all
you need really is your you know high
terpene you know content so I think
especially the way you know everybody's
going with you know the flavors and all
that you know it'll stick around for a
good while I think indeed buy into the
whole flavor game I love flavors you
know otherwise you know I wouldn't have
a hundred different you know cut sitting
there my mother so I you know I love
oranges grapes you know apples you know
I have a all skunks me all the others
you know so is that something you strive
for in the breeding like if you were to
kind of list the main attributes you're
looking to breed when you do a project
like you know like good structure good
yield you know all that type of stuff is
a good flavor profile something you
highly value or not necessarily
definitely my to my two criteria
generally are effect you know and not
necessarily high THC but just quality
effect for you know my chemistry and
then you know flavor you know
so aside from that I I don't breed first
a sturdy fast-growing big plant you know
none of that kind of stuff
I want flavor and effect and everything
else if it falls in it's cool if not you
know I got what I want
you know and so currently what plant is
the best example of that for you you
know what's your favorite plant in terms
of flavor and affect my favorites in the
last couple years have mostly come out
of the the herbal hybrids
I love phenotypes a lot of the oh gee oh
geez times Arkell
I like the chem dogs times Urkel and
there's a couple others uh offhand I'm
not
thinking of right now but uh those are
definitely some of my favorites over the
last couple few years yeah yes I mean
given you've done so many purple Urkel
hybrids and public push hybrids what do
you think is your favorite crosses
you've done out of all of those ones you
know out of the Bubba's what do you
think Baba paired with the best out of
all the ones you made and the same
question for the Urkel the Oracle
definitely triangle cush that one just
spit out so money just you know you
unique and just tasty phenotypes that's
uh that's the easy one with the Bubba
there was a handful of them what was
that one the Bubba um I like the bubble
bubble gum that one had a lot of nice
ones it's been about three years since
I've run all the lumps out so do you
plan on restocking either the bubble or
the purple cool feminized lines in the
near future because I noticed when you
did that I think it was earlier this
year possibly even restock the lines
that was like the second batch he'd made
of them kind of so he's like at a third
in the work so to speak oh I I haven't
restocked any and I just have you know a
supply of what I have um yeah and I
don't plan on remaking any any of the
hybrids a lot of the ones I even you
know sell aren't you know aren't
original they're not even anything new
you know other people have sold the same
exact ones I'm mostly making these for
myself and then you know I put them on
the market you know for other people too
but uh I I don't plan to remake any of
them at most I like to you know go
through large populations of the s1 and
then I might you know make an s-1
feminized hybrid that kind of refined
you know the hybrids and maybe cross
those two you know some of the better
ones that I liked from each round but as
far as just remaking ya know okay are
there any special factors that go into
determining if a strain would be
specifically good for reversing so is it
just the case that you just pick the
strain you want to reverse and that's
the one you want to reverse and that's
it or is it kind of like you look at a
whole bunch of strains and you think
well there's a few characteristics in
this plant which would make it good as a
donor specifically well just start to
start with CSI I definitely kind of went
with trident cruise I'd reversed the
Bubba in 2006
I pretty much reversed herckel in 2002
you know just with the accidental thing
you know and saw what it could produce
and really liked the results so I was
basically building off a stuff I already
knew and had already done so I I knew it
was quality stuff you know with the with
the future future lines it's definitely
uh you know some of the ones I reverse I
definitely might not even release
because they might not produce you know
but I hope they would you know yeah okay
and so if we just jump back to the labs
for a moment where don't lab sit for you
do you use them at all not not
interested in the percentages do you
feel percentages are just overinflated
at the moment my buddy works for one of
the more legit labs and he well his lab
tends to test a lot lower percentages
than some of these inflated labs that
most people want to get their stuff
tested at which is one of the reasons
why I don't generally you know use that
as a proponent of my advertising
campaign because something the test you
know for me at 20% well
test another lab at 25 or you know 26
percent so you know I definitely take
all that data because through it through
my buddy you know we test all the the
cannabinoids and the terpenes but uh I
don't exactly you know release the data
because you know all that yeah
secret sauce so how do you feel about
the whole kind of increase in popularity
of like getting everything file or
sequence are you a proponent of it are
you against it I've heard there's kind
of two camps on the whole idea right um
I'd like to get some things follow
sequence but you know Philo's approached
me a few times over the last couple of
years and I've been adamant I mean
they'll test anything I got for $300 a
club I'm like hot pan for you know you
to tell me what I heard you know you
know honestly they don't even have a
complete system because I'll they don't
have the base clones to begin with on a
lot of things I mean unless they have a
legitimate you know chem dog 91 to start
their galaxy with unless they have a
triangle cush to start their oh gee cush
galaxy you know yeah if they don't have
the core tissue that's responsible for
all these hybrids then they don't have a
galaxy you know I mean I've got a bunch
of tissue you know the the 91 the TK the
you know the Mendo purple the the
original Oracle you know all of which
you know can can be at the core of
certain galaxies but if they're you know
galaxies don't include those they're not
gonna be accurate you know and so I've
heard that there was certain people who
feel like you shouldn't get it done
because if you get the sequencing done
you lose the ability to like patent or
you know like claim ownership over the
plant because when it's in like the
public domain
it's you know it's no longer yours to
claim have you had anything like that
and and if it were true would that be
something that put you off it or do you
think that you know like the idea of
trying to claim ownership of a plane's a
bit silly
that's exactly kind of how I feel I mean
I know there's definitely cats doing
that and I think it's ridiculous you
know but you know how it is you can't
stop progress and so how do you feel
about I guess you know the somewhat
controversial subject or just the
controversy this idea has been
surrounded and in that seeking
permission to bring you the strain from
someone else before you use it you know
how do you feel about that do someone
have to heat you up if they want to use
one of your mails for money Australians
in like a strain that they're gonna then
go and so or where do you sit on that
whole issue it definitely is a matter of
respect you know I definitely appreciate
it you know I don't view it as necessary
I don't look at my seeds as possessions
especially if they're sold but even if
they're given you know I'm very adamant
on if I give somebody something and you
know there's restrictions or anything on
it
I'll tell them straight up but uh you
know otherwise people are free to you
know work with gifts and especially
bought seed to their heart's content I
just think you know um it's definitely
respectful to ask ask breeders and you
know the sources uh you know approval if
you want to work with their stuff yeah
okay and so just to play devil's
advocate what would you do if you wanted
to use a mat let's just what would you
do is tell me he'll hit you out and said
hey hey I just changed my mind on the PT
K and I actually don't want you to use
it do you think at that point you know
that respect should go so far as to like
caning the project right um that would
be a tough one that would be a tough one
I would definitely respect Tom and and
and his wishes for sure
you know because
you know I just think that's how we
should all be you know ask for you know
the ptk my number one goal is just for
preservation of the pierc'd line I mean
that's above and beyond anything else
that stems of it is just a bonus but you
know honestly I think Tom just as an
example is is one of those people who
kind of understand he doesn't hold any
of those lines as his possessions I
think he he views them as he was just a
keeper of those genetics for for his
time I mean and that's how I view things
you know we're all just keepers you know
for fora
you know as long as we are a keeper and
then it needs to go on to the next
person you know yeah but you know
there's plenty of people who are you
know opportunists and you know they get
ten seeds from somebody and it's off to
the races to make that next hybrid or
just reproduce it and sell it you know
yeah yep you know I saw the funniest
made the other day it's like I was like
a guy like trying to start a seed coming
it's like I need kind of Girl Scout
cookies and a ten pack of seeds and it's
true yeah it's good one so who are some
of the breeders who you really enjoy the
work of or you know you really think
highly if their work and even maybe go
so far as to be like their stuff is you
know like I feel they follow similar
ethics to I do and I would even be happy
to possibly do a project with them
because I could meet I die on that right
I mean I'm not shy about you know my
favorite Raiders and I like to consider
my favorite readers friends I'm
definitely a huge fan of Bodie I mean
he's he's he's one of the best in my
book Mean Gene
you know he's rock solid you know if
there's a spot where he could make an
extra buck he's gonna tell you the truth
and lose that buck over over that dollar
which you know I definitely can respect
so you know guys like that who just have
that you know integrity and just honesty
and just you know they're not just
looking out for that dollar and
themselves um those are definitely the
you know my favorite readers and the
ones I you know look up to yeah okay and
so and if you were just a grower or free
or maybe a better way to put it is if
you lost your whole collection as it
were seeds clones everything and all you
had to name was like you know like 150
bucks so basically you can buy like one
packet of seeds which pack would you try
to restart the Empire do you drive a
hard bargain
one pack does this include I don't have
any friends anymore no no it's gonna
help yeah you should have a vodka oh so
well huh oh shoot that's a really good
question um mmm
oh shoot no no no good was like I'll go
it's like some gelato times wedding cake
no money quick yeah then I can afford
more back
that's pretty the best answer ever so
kind of relating what would your advice
be to a newly emerging breeder more
specifically when should someone feel
comfortable to not only release but that
they can feel comfortable charging for
the work and you know like no and I'm
not talking about like you know you just
make some seeds and give them to your
friend like that's cool but like when
should you feel confident that you have
done the adequate work to be able to
approach a seed bank and be like look
you know you know maybe you could
consider the stocking my stuff and I
feel like it's of high enough quality
you know like you should they wait a
certain time like or we know what what's
your advice in general well just from
what I've seen you know at least in the
present present time you you know I'm
not gonna stop anybody from breeding or
you know creating a seed
company or gone with it you know with
even limited experience just because it
seems these days that's more about
branding you know than anything else but
in the future hopefully the bar gets
raised to where you know you actually
need to really be a professional grower
one and really have a strong
understanding of the cannabis plant and
you know how it breeds and you know what
to even look for when you're doing
selections you know hmm in the future
and so do you think breeders who come to
the market with like you know one parent
from top dog and one parent from Pirates
of the Emerald triangle and I've made a
whole bunch of f1 guys do you think
that's like there there's a place for
that like or do you think people should
be like looking to you know maybe do
more work than that like and more
importantly I guess my other question is
do you think that it's a bit of a
cop-out for someone to maybe develop a
male and by that I mean like it's not
just an f1 maybe they've even taken it
to the f2 or like made an f1 and cross
it to another one of their strengths you
know like they've got some ownership
over it but then they've just got that -
like 10 cloner emily's and that's their
whole offering you know like how do you
feel about that I mean in in in today's
world I think it's you know par for the
course you know it is what it is it's
not ideal but there's cool stuff to be
found and you know lots of the hybrids
and some that you wouldn't even think
you know would turn out you know really
well so yeah I definitely have a
different perspective than I used to I
used to have more of a purist idealist
perspective and now it's like well
there's 101 ways to do it and you know
it's up to the consumer to choose you
know who they want to support yeah okay
and so last little question for this
segment if you could only hang on to one
and you've kindly got which one just one
yeah if you want you do 300k hello if
you're giving me three I'd probably hold
on to triangle cush Kim dog 91 and three
still lemony
I like or Kalam endo purple both but uh
I'd probably I'd probably have to stick
with the Mendo purple
hi Daddy edges the echo yeah I mean the
circle breeds better but there's there's
a lot of potential in that Mendo so yeah
yeah well somebody I think that's
something maybe a lot of people wouldn't
necessarily think off the bat mmm-hmm
it's also personal preference not
everybody's gonna share it yeah okay and
I mean just out of curiosity do you find
one is more indica leaning than the
other or they're both about the same Oh
in the ER Cole is definitely more indica
the the Mendo purple is more of a
daytime type of thing oh really
um yeah it's just it's it's terpenes are
just you know we next bunch of questions
were once submitted by our fans first
one what's your preferred method for
selfing I guess they mean you know like
thiosulfate so colloidal silver what's
your route I always do silver
thiosulfate just because it's easiest
you only have to spray them two or three
times at most versus colloidal where you
pretty much have to scram every day or
something like that and what time period
do you spray the plants because I know
that some think which kind of varies a
little bit like you spray them before
the other females get in there during
usually a lot of times you have to spray
your target female about two weeks
before so you have to flower her
two weeks in advance of the rest of the
plants spray her at trigger you know and
then when the other plants get in
I generally spray spray her again and
lately I've been doing a thing where I
tend to spray every ten days so just to
make sure you know she she stays a he
yeah so if you if you spray when you
trigger you're not gonna be getting
pollen until about five to six weeks
into flower generally but if you spray
two weeks in advance you're getting that
pollen between three and four weeks
which is you know I do yep yep okay and
so have you ever did you keep the Dyna
plant completely segregated or have you
found that it can be in the same room
and you give it a spray and it doesn't
have impact on the other plants in the
room yeah I just make sure not to get
any of the spray on the other girls yeah
yeah and it's just fun same room
fantastic so de femme Anaya seeds have a
place in breeding as mothers in order to
create rag seeds from there oh yeah oh
definitely I mean you know I don't want
to give out all my trade secrets but I
mean half the reason I you know reverse
my lines is so I can isolate my favorite
parts of each plant so I'm looking to
you know pull out my favorite you know
examples of a plant through the S ones
and actually breathe further into the
future you know not only with you know
s2s and everything but you know with
regular seed out crossings with s ones
and s2 s so okay I definitely think yeah
and I think we've already kind of
touched on this but just now the point
home what is your favorite camp well for
for raw power and smoking I think the D
is really good but for
you know a purist and from an idealist
perspective the 91 is the only one I
really you know one a long-term breed
with because I think it's the original
mother source of all the camps it just
as a follow-up from myself do you
believe that with the right partner the
chem 91 could produce some seeds which
rival its potency or do you think that
in itself is kind of like the one in a
million in terms of its potency and it's
quite unlikely you'll get stuff as
potent from it in seed form well if you
think the chem D is if you think the
long lines it is it's a most likely a
feminized hybrid of the ninety-one
itself it's a lot stronger than the
ninety one a lot of the chem 91 hybrids
I've personally bred they test higher
then the the original chem 91 so I think
you know there there's a lot stronger
potency held within this genes and
generally is expressed through the cut
it so yeah okay and so we touched on
Humboldt snow would be - oh yeah do you
happen to know the origins of it Jose
well on the the guys I've been talking
to seem to seem to seem to think that it
originally came from the Eugene area up
in Oregon and they're saying that well
it's it's essentially the the same as
Oregon snow but they they're they're
saying that it's most likely a bag seed
another essential a a bag seed but
possibly like a feminized hybrid or
selfing of the Fairfax for way I'm
looking to you know kind of look into
that a bit further myself but it seems
like it has a lot of potential and I've
had I've heard multiple you know stories
from multiple sources
that seemed a point in you know some
some version of that direction so yeah
awesome I just want to also you know add
to that the Fairfax far away of course
it's a basically a Pakistani Afghani
Indian crossed to skunk number one so
it's three landraces and then skunk
number one so yeah yeah have you grown
it out no not yet but I'm looking
forward to yeah oh that's a have you got
you got so you know someone who's got it
cuz it's definitely around yeah yeah no
it's definitely around ivy with it also
awesome because what's interesting about
that one is Bob Hemphill had said that
in his opinion he felt the four-way had
degraded over the years more so than the
chem 91 and
however before the four-way was popped
in 95 I think he said and so what he was
trying to get it was like it had
degraded more so in less amount of time
have you got any experience with that do
you have any cuts which maybe aren't as
old as the chem 91 but in your opinion
they've degraded more significantly than
it has in you know a shorter time frame
you know most of the old cuts I have are
fairly solid except I don't know that's
a whole different discussion with the
whole dud thing I don't know if people
are referring to kind of a dud thing or
if they're just talking about you know
lesser degradation I think they'd be
like that just as time goes by the end
product is just not as good as it once
used to be even though it's been grown
quite well right right yeah i don't know
i don't know i mean the the snow i've
held for almost twenty years still
produces the same exact you know you
know quality that i remember 20 years
ago yeah I think maybe let the caveat
that's placed on that conversation is
that it's totally dependent on like how
the plants are stored so if you're like
a cash crop up and you don't really put
much time or effort into your mother
room it's just literally serving a
purpose of like taking clones you know
what I mean like
years like those kind of neglected
conditions is what leads to it whereas
you may just not see that whatsoever
because you don't put them in those
conditions whatsoever
right right oh my mom get treated a
little rough okay maybe there's hope for
all for all of us out there who need to
improve our mother stations right so
next question what information can you
give us on the big bad Baba
which one's the big bad but quickly I
think it's is it one of your crosses I
think it's like Kim D yeah
hi ROG Kim D it's crossed Oh Baba it's
just a just a high quality you know
hybrid of the three that I've give away
for free yeah it went under another name
okay it went under another name the fire
oh gee Kim D and I just give it away for
free because I had the seeds and it's
quality but I don't exactly want to give
credit to the fellow who it came from
okay all right so next question when did
you get your Baba cot and who was it
from and what do you think Baba is
exactly genetically okay so I got my
Bubba in 2005 from my buddy 707 C bank
he goes by the names CRS skunk and sha
bud you know on the various forums and
he's been on the forums I think longer
than I have so I got that from him in
2005 and he's had it since at least 2000
if not a little little earlier than that
Archive got the same Bubba from him as
well and a handful of other cats and his
was sourced you know down around the LA
area from a glassblower buddy you know
17 years ago and I I believe it's you
know
just straight from you know Josh and
Matt's you know
extended circle down there didn't do
believe that whole story that the
parents was a straight court Baba and
they crossed it to the og or do you
think that's maybe not entirely accurate
I think that's probably it is accurate
is anything I mean at first I didn't
believe the story and people I knew who
had met that like Matt you know or like
ah he's full of [__] but then you know
um you know as time went by and I saw if
you will you know other things that led
me to believe different I definitely
believe you know it's a simple story and
it doesn't have a lot of ro BS it's it's
it's almost too honest
um armed in my closet under the stairs
you know so you know okay and then it's
a real sorry little follow up ones that
was out of your Baba hybrids have you
found any which on the whole stay quite
true to the Baba but get rid of the
horrendously long veg time mm-hmm
stay true to the Bubba and I want to say
so because Bubba the Bible hybrids tend
to segregate in two different directions
they're either about fifty percent of
them are like Bubba which you're not
losing the veg time there and then the
other 50% tend to you know grow a lot
more vigorous like the mother plant that
they came from and they tend to have the
mother's char paint so you know faster
drone Bubba not quite yet okay maybe one
day yeah so I've never done a back cross
using feminized pollen so you know let
you make like a feminized cross and then
you hit one of the offsprings of that
with the same Poland you use to make the
feminized cross I think I have
let's see so I I did Obama Kush
basically Mendocino purple cross to
bubba kush and then i well i didn't name
it obama cash my buddy up and tie guard
he named it obama cash
hey thrown him under the bus right there
but anyways so I took that clone and
then I pollinated it with Bubba cush
again so that's kind of a back cross of
sorts and then you know even katsu Baba
could kind of be considered the same
when I cross katsu to the original Bubba
I think that's kind of a back cross or
something of sorts and so what is the go
with I've heard of like Obama cush being
like a totally different genetic makeup
to what you listed eyes is there someone
else who tries to like take credit for
it or something I think it was like a
dispensary and they said it was like
Super Skunk and something else and right
well to clarify there's definitely at
least three or four different Obama
pushes because everybody named their
favorite Kush
after Obama you know any person right
yeah so there's a Obama coach down in
San Diego there's an anabolic ish over
in Michigan there and then my Obama
coach which is extremely popular around
Portland and Eugene and Seattle the
Pacific Northwest you know that that
came from me and my buddy you know
Tigard so Leafly or Leafly or whatever
they they call themselves they have it
as a Afghani og or something I don't
know but they're they're based out of
Oregon so they should kind of know you
know what the the popular Obama in that
area is I don't even know yeah you know
then the notorious from having incorrect
information about strains right everyone
is cam know anyone you go look
says CEM know anyone is across of CEM
dog &amp; skunk number one is not man and
then me and my buddies have talked him a
little bit and they're like oh we'll
change them you just have to hit us up
and was like yeah sure you will
yeah you know what's funny I hit I sent
him an email one day I said why don't
you guys just pay someone to like just
do this properly and like fix all the
things and they sent me an email back
being like we just rely on information
submitted by users and so I was like
okay so that's why we're in the state
we're in right now right yeah next
question yeah how are you dealing with
making the transition to the legal
market we'll see yeah it's it's gonna be
interesting yeah no no no telling right
now I worst-case scenario I'll have a
good high-paying job for some corporate
big-money cannabis best-case scenario
I'll have my own company and you know
find a little niche that I can fit into
that'll support all the research and
development that I kind of want to do in
the future but uh yeah yeah okay so this
one's I'm not entirely sure what they're
getting at so just choose to answer it
how you will what's the best way to
pollinate something without having a
seed your whole room and this is the
pouch doesn't quite make sense take it
out of the room and spray water on it
after so I I don't think they're talking
about ammo maybe they're saying if I
want to pollinate a female and I do
pollinate it should I then like take it
out of the room and like spray it down
after it's accepted the pollen off yeah
yeah no I understand what they're saying
I mean if if you have mobile plants
where you know you have your plant your
female plants in in a pot that you can
actually bring out of your room and put
and say like a dark tent or something
you can you can definitely just pull
that plan out pollinate it and that
little private tent you know all by
itself leave it there for 24 hours
in the dark is just fine the whole time
and then spray it down with water just
like they're saying and pop it back up
in your room and you won't have stray
pollen because water kills all the
pollen and it will produce all the seeds
it needs to not pollinate in your room
yeah with some hay are you able to give
us a little more information on your
10/14 light cycle um
that's usually only a light cycle I
would use for longer flour and sativas
or in the heat of summer if you want to
reduce temperatures or if you want to
pull off a crop a little earlier than
normal I generally don't use them unless
it's a heat issue or you know I want to
ripen stuff up early it definitely
affects yields a bit just because you're
you're losing you know a good portion of
time but uh yeah it's a time in a place
to have to think yeah okay what's your
favorite place to eat in the Triangle
huh and I wish we had good food around
here
oh it's rough oh shoot
honestly uh I like some of the wool
Mexican joints as long as they have a
good margaritas nice yeah what's the
difference between granddaddy purple and
the southern humble well I'm not exactly
sure what cut goes around the southern
Humboldt purple
I mean granddaddy purple of course is
Arkell times Salmon Creek big bud
whereas southern Humboldt purple
generally refers to just purple or coal
or purple or chol types
it's it's kind of just a vague maybe
generalization a bit yeah yeah okay and
what's the difference between gray pipe
and Pecola who do you think purple
Urkel's the dad or how do you think it
offshoots from it that's a good one
I ran out you know beds full of Oracle
granddaddy purple Grape Ape
you know Pakistani purple black
Bridgeville black Afghan just a ton of
these different purples from around the
triangle years ago and the Grape Ape
supposedly has the same heritage same
exact heritage d'azyr chol um but it
seems to grow a little bit stronger and
a little bit faster than then the Oracle
I've had since you know 2001 2002
yeah intercept what is your so recipe
for indoors I know you touched on it you
know what's the you know without listing
whites and stuff you know what are the
basic amendments you're chucking in
right basically I keep it simple I just
you know for my own needs I use a buy
gold cocoa blend and then I mix in like
some Bokashi let's see what else some
insect frass and then fish meals fish
bone meals
alfalfa scalps it depends on which run
sometimes I just go you know with a
little bit of a high nitrogen stuff
other times I'm throwing in a bunch of
extra rock dust green sands you know
long-term release stuff and then I
always add a nice chunk of a
diatomaceous earth and you know Omri
natural because anytime here doing
organics and cocoa and all that yeah you
got to keep those gnats at bay alright
so why make an s-1 given there's such a
stigma around feminized seeds especially
compared to other NorCal growers I look
at main jain and loompa
I think maybe what they saying is like
you sell more because if you did dregs I
don't know oh yeah no I don't understand
the question I mean honestly in the
future a lot of people are probably
gonna lean towards well-done consistent
feminized seeds over regular seeds a lot
of people aren't gonna have the time or
the space to even grow males or even
need males you take the recreational
market in Oregon and California where
everybody is allowed to grow four to six
plants I don't think anybody any of
those people are gonna want to grow
males you know I mean if you're only
allowed such a limited number of plants
you know feminized seeds are essentially
you know a perfect option and a lot of
the stem stigma behind feminized seeds
is is kind of false you know I mean
anytime somebody starts going on and on
about how bad feminized seeds are I
asked them well hey your regular seed
breeders are they using chem dogs
Diesel's og cush is Girl Scout cookies
all those things came from feminized
seeds crossed to a male plant of some
sort you know so it's just like you know
people need eventually they'll get
educated and realize oh wait how come
you know the most notorious breeders in
the entire world like Sam skunk man and
chimera or you know huge proponents for
feminized seeds yeah like right it's out
there you know I don't know okay
Osby say sorry I'm sorry that viewer had
butchered the question but we go through
it from our buddy pee bud mark he have
in the fight last night the way how I'm
a simple man
real simple um I only like a few things
and most of us just weed so I don't even
do sports
that's just me didn't you when trying -
one whisking edge in front all right are
we are we talking box yeah yeah what
were some of the traits about the
pakistani Chitra that really drawed you
to it and what were the ones you looked
for in the Maui selected ooh
so with the [__] rolls one of the things
the things I really liked about it
for them in general was the fact that
they're extremely strong and like pining
and limonade inter paneling and they
don't have a lot of the common just
amsterdam terpenes just mirror scene and
carry awfully you know other there's so
much stuff out there that is just loaded
with nursing carry awfully that these
you know just pungent you know
over-the-top sharp astringent you know
terpenes are kind of refreshing you know
and i used more than one male you know
in in the breeding with the Pakistanis
but they they definitely were strong
plants stable plants and we're as close
to you know what I was you know looking
for out of the line is that I could
possibly get yeah okay what that take
away mm-hmm and will you use that my
father project so G you kind of retire
him after this I might use I might use
them a little bit more yeah I've still
got a couple few of those males set
aside and I definitely know what he
breeds for so there's definitely
potential for future breeding with them
yeah definitely
almost some what do you think the
genetic makeup of the black is okay wait
so are we talking about the black I use
proud
yeah okay um you know honestly I have no
solid idea I mean this plant basically
grows like a bigger Bubba cush plant it
has a fairly unique profile and at first
I thought it was nothing special as far
as you know I just figured it was like a
baa baa hybrid of sorts but um I guess
it dates back quite a ways
in the hind palm area of Trinity County
and I didn't even know this until I kind
of refreshed recently but it was even
featured and I think Jason Kings either
first or second canna Bible but as far
as you know exactly Nia JH I mean my
cousin sourced it Ruth at least 1012
years ago out of high palm and from
there I don't know aside from it just
being you know very similar to Bubba
cush but with you know different
terpenes okay and how did the pack email
in general influenced the chem dog in
the crosses you made like how did the
cross has come out basically mm-hmm
those are actually some of my favorite
ones out of the out of the f1 hybrids
they basically made the chem dogs
terpenes kind of exaggerated made a more
pungent more sharp so like with the chem
D I mean I ended up with you know just
ones that were extremely pungent and one
of them in particular it just uh it
smelled like just super sharp motor oil
like grease almost and then it tasted
exactly like that uh-huh which you'd
think is a bad thing but it was strong
so it was kind of a good thing awesome
and so an interesting question
sandalwood coffee and pine these are
terpenes which don't seem to really pop
up as much anymore
any kind of theories as to why that
might be do you think they just fell out
of favor or maybe they were like not
really dominant terpenes or I mean uh me
in a couple buddies we love pine so
there's there's a lot of pine stuff
we're working with and towards that's
one of the reasons why you know I like
the the pakistanis because there's a lot
of pine in them you know pining a pining
be you know and then Arkell Oracle has a
lot of pine in it which you know that
might even you know entertain the whole
pint Arkush you know parentage theory
right there to also another reason why
you know growing up the Xmas buds cuz
you know looking for pine terpenes but
over here we love pine sandalwood I'm
not so sure what was the other turkey
nor though Oh coffee yeah well there
there's definitely plenty of coffee this
guy just needs to get his hands on some
Bubba cush yeah yeah and there's no
shortage of coffee yeah so this one I
might cut out because it might if the
answer is what I think it is it might
reveal too much but basically someone's
messages us and they've said do you know
if Sierra skunk is the guy that skunk VA
mentions is like his friend who lived in
Tahoe and basically in skunk be a story
he's like yeah I had this friend in
Tahoe and I gave him the chem dog and
you know go there and we'd snowboard and
blah blah blah maybe that's not enough
info for you to really answer that one
but this guy seems to think it's the
same person okay so he's wondering I do
know anything about that
Sierra skunk isn't isn't the guy from
Tahoe awesome do you like to use any
specific types of growing in regards
like training you know are you like a
lollipop dirty like mainline a few
colors you just let them do their own
thing what's your kind of take on it all
I like natural so as natural as I can
but I also like to clean up the unders
and clean up the sides so I kind of
close to lollypop but somewhere between
lollipop and a natural plant structure
you know is how I like to do it look at
awesome and what method do you find is
the best for trying to yield the most
generally speaking um I mean being that
I'm not really going for yields ever you
know I I'm one of the people who firmly
uh goes with the there's a hundred and
one right ways to do something so I
think you can get high yields with a
dozen different methods you know yep so
whatever works best for you is what I
always told all righty so we'll just
jump into our last few questions just
got a little short answer ones what is
your least favorite strain ooh
least favorite huh huh damn those are
usually the ones that you just toss
right yeah yeah no no huh I've tossed
quite a few hmm I don't know if I have
any least favorites I I ran out a
landrace what was it a Pakistani Archon
recently and it was absolutely terrible
you know I was I was gonna I was gonna
do a reproduction of it and I was like
what am i reproducing here so a recent
memory that's pretty bad what do you
think is the most overhyped strain so
not necessarily like you know like blue
dream it's real hyped but like what
strain do you think gets a good rap on
the whole but it's actually pretty trash
right right um there's tons of them
these days huh yeah
yeah yeah I I mean me personally you
kind of nailed it with the damn blue
dream I mean it's been so popular up
here I mean even some of my kid brothers
have run like 99 plant gardens of
nothing but blue dream and you know the
past five to ten years and I've never
even grown the plant I'm just like no
thank you so I'm gonna give it to blue
Dre
nice so in terms of both like you know
breeding side of things but as well as
also like the general political domain
what do you think's the worst thing to
have happened to the kind of a scene
since you've became involved in it well
oh yeah
probably recreation recreational
legalization
I mean I don't I don't know any any
growers at least in California who
really voted for it and I mean just
watching what's happened in Colorado and
Washington and even organ you know
coming on now I mean it's it's pretty
much killing it's killing the way things
used to be in a anyways so what a lot of
people would have kind of like the
pitfalls that that were over sided you
know like what's happening now that's
like the problem is it the case that
people are losing like their right to
grow or like the numbers or what's up
with the legalization
it's just mass production big money
commercial grows you know one one you
know huge grow can wipe out you know a
hundred or a thousand you know small
farmers you know so I think it's just
been a way of life you know in Northern
California
you know Oregon and just around where I
grew up and it's not gonna be that way
for much longer at all
so yeah so what do you think is the
biggest mistake you see like kind of
newly emerging
his make mmm biggest mistake probably
crossing uh one male times one female
yeah small selections small selections
and the one-to-one model the one number
one model is never good you know and
then final one
oh no sorry no final one second last one
what is kind of your growing tip for
everyone listening you know what's a
little secret you think maybe not a lot
of people do and growing and it helps I
could even be like you know the use of a
particular cell phone I remember one
time someone said make sure you use
silica you know that shit's awesome
mm-hmm um let me think the simplest
thinking thing I oh I'm yeah right there
keep it simple
oh I see it all the time people try to
complicate their gross you know they
they use a dozen different you know
bottled nutrients say they try to they
kill their plants with kindness you know
and they don't even managed to you know
reap the rewards of everything that are
given so I say don't forget about
keeping it simple because you can
produce excellent quality excellent
yields and save yourself a bunch of
headache and money by just keeping it
simple yeah without a doubt
alright on to the real last question now
I like this one because it gives good
insight into all the breeders if you
could go to one place in time and
history geographically all that where
would you go to collect landrace seeds
ooh it'd probably have to be cat can I
have a a resource yeah and there were
certain years that were really good for
hash production you know back in the 60s
and 70s I just need to pick the right
year yeah I definitely go to you know
somewhere along the Hindu Kush mountains
you know Afghanistan Pakistan I'm
definitely more of an indica type myself
so
you know somewhere somewhere in the 60s
70s right read about it around them
there that would be about right for me
sounds fantastic
any comments shoutouts anything like
that you wanted to make um oh I usually
have brain farts during these things so
I think I'm good yeah no worries
hopefully we covered it all I think we
have honestly thanks so much again for
coming and you know dropping all these
knowledge bombs on us and helping us
fill in all the blanks oh yeah thanks
for having me
so there we have it guys a huge thank
you again to inspector for taking the
time to sit down and talk with us I hope
you guys enjoyed it inspectors
definitely being one of the most
requested a huge thank you as always to
420 Australia n OG s as well as all our
patreon fans you guys are really the
lifeblood of the show and it runs -
thank you for the increase in content
over the last few weeks and force to
come check out the patreon page if you
haven't already and otherwise see
[Music]
[Applause]