foreign
[Music]
for the next installment in our epic
first episode with not so dog so stoked
to have you back as always
massive shout out to our sponsors who
helped make the show happen huge shout
out to seeds here now your number one
spot to get all the hottest breeders and
all the latest drops a guarantee on
satisfaction not just germination that
means if you finish a harvest and you
are not stoked with the results hit them
up they'll make it right who else offers
such a quality guarantee CT now thank
you so much for your ongoing support
huge shout out to our newest sponsors
Organics alive no matter what level of
expertise you have they have a range of
products that are going to improve your
next growth
truly incredible organic powdered
fertilizer if you're looking for an easy
solution while growing in soil they have
it with veg formulas Bloom formulas
they've got a range of different
products at different mpks to help no
matter what situation you're in I highly
recommend it for all the organic Growers
out there
massive shout out to organic survive we
love your products thank you so much for
the support
likewise huge shout out to cope at
biological systems your number one Pest
and Predator company if you have aphids
get the Apple RM if you have spider
mites get the spidex vital I promise you
guys they're the best in the industry
despite it's vital it's got proof of
predation technology meaning you see the
Predators turn orange in front of your
eyes what more proof do you want that
they're working hard for your garden get
some beneficials in there before you're
up against a battle I love releasing
them regularly shout out cope at
biological systems we appreciate you so
so much
likewise a huge shout out to our buddies
at Pulse sensors whether you're running
a single tent a single room or a
multi-state operation Whole sensors are
here to help you get the best Harvest to
date helping you to monitor all the
variables you may not be consciously
considering like VPD ppfd humidity
temperature so much more check them out
they've just released the pulse Hub an
integrated unit to help you track all
parameters and inputs of our one Central
Hub it's been super popular you should
check it out guys before it's sold out a
huge shout out again pulse sensors you
want to get serious get a pulse
and last but not least a massive thank
you to the patreon gang you are truly
the LIE slot of the show if you would
like to get early access to upcoming
episodes unheard exclusive patreon
episodes featuring the likes of 707 seed
banks Bodie Mr Bob Hemphill Mean Gene
trichome jungle the list keeps going on
and on we've also been giving away
genetics on our Discord how good does
that sound shout out patreon
www.patreon.com forward slash the
podcast
in this episode we're here to learn more
about NorCal history
not so dog's breeding
[Music]
Mendo perks and so much more
without further delay
[Music]
alert to get into it
there you go look that's interesting
because you're giving me a nice little
segue when you mentioned the lemon tree
because I was going to say you know
Caleb at CSI has done some really cool
crosses using you know the not so dog
headband and some of the notable ones
that I've seen Garner a lot of fanfare
from the community the chemd cross
headband and the lemon tree cross
headband and I can sort of understand
why both of them have a lot of
popularity I'll be honest I've actually
got a pack of both of those and I've
stashed them away for myself my question
is did you expect some of these headband
hybrids to get the popular reception
that they have and are there any
particular crosses you're hoping to see
happen with some of the cuts you're
associated with
yeah I mean so that's like uh I gave
I've given various Cuts uh to CSI
um some of which like the headband he's
he's already used and released some of
which are still uh private or in the
works or whatever and it was mostly just
because I'm mostly a private breeder uh
and you know once you start chatting
about a bunch of this stuff and you have
interest out there and you want to you
you want to figure out a way to spread
it out to the community to some degree
right and since he's so prolific and
he's also popular and does a good job he
was a good vessel for that right
um and you know yeah there are some
things that I think that are unexpected
I didn't grow any of the La by Lemon
Tree but I did grow
um at a project I did an outdoor a few
years ago I did grow a ton of his work
outside and I did grow quite a few uh
lemon tree and other hybrids uh Calio
hybrids and stuff like that and much
like train wreck uh that terp that we
were talking about earlier
the the Citrus is a dominant terp in the
sense that it really pops up in a lot of
the progeny it's definitely something
that combines and gets passed on really
strongly
um so a lot of this a lot of the lemon
stuff uh would be uh you're gonna smell
a lot of lemon and my hope if if you
grew some La by Lemon Tree is that the
LA would lend some some gassiness and
some skunk and some potency
to the the lemon tree side of it that
would that would be the hope that I
would have is that it would give it
would give it some legs if you would
uh the chemd by La seems to be the most
popular one so far uh people have been
getting a lot of wild stuff out of that
which is cool because those two strains
are I don't know I'm not really big on
rating strains but they would definitely
go into like my all-time favorites
category
uh so it and I think they cross it seems
like they crossed really well and I
still have people sending me pics all
the time of those hybrids and people
really happy with what they're finding
in there so
um that's a positive yeah nice one
that's some great feedback and
um some people might be a bit curious
about what do you mean the LA maybe not
entirely sure on the back story on that
I'd love to get your version of events
the you know the headband cut the not so
headband cut also originally known as
the LA Kush how did that come to be how
did you get your hands on it did you
ever interact directly with uh
mandelbrot or was that just sort of
coincidental
oh no
um mandelbrot and I were friends right
and there's a buddy of mine who
introduced us uh my homie uh Josh and uh
he
um you know mandelbrot was more into
let's I don't know how to put it uh
let's put it this way mandelbrot was was
deep into the Grateful Dead hippie side
of things right and in the early 2000s
he was getting it more interested in
switching over and trying to mess around
with some weed right
and it so happened that my buddy and I
uh Stat or I called Staten Island on the
show before had been doing some projects
together and some breeding work over the
last number of years uh together and so
I had a whole big collection of
um you know seeds and hybrids and stuff
that I had made right and
he wanted to get started on a seed
company and he wanted to start messing
around with stuff but he didn't really
have very much stock so he ended up
um
he ended up getting a bunch of seed from
me uh mostly super dog hybrids super dog
Maui Super Dog by super dog various
things a handful of cuts
um I gave him a couple of my super dog
selections I gave them my Sour Diesel a
couple things like that and he had gone
down to LA and he had gotten this
headband that they were calling the LA
Kush right now you got to realize this
was in the very early 2000s so it was
before most people had heard of or the
really the cush wave of La had happened
because obviously as we're both well
aware what became known as Kush was very
different than this cut
right this was very much more of a
diesel cut very much more of a of a sort
of a sour looking type of thing
so he brings it back up and he's like
hey I want to give you this thing I have
this other Sour Diesel and I have this
headband that I want to give you and so
he drives he drives down from Humboldt
and he gives me two headbands and two
sours but they're unlabeled but he's
like just grow them save all the moms
and grow them side by side
so I grow these things up
and I'm showing it to friends and
everyone's like oh it's all the same
weed there's no difference like none of
these moms are different none of the
rooms are different none of the
greenhouse is different it's all the
same weed and they're like he gave he
must have given you his version of Sour
Diesel this looks like sour to me just
different it's different but it's
definitely sour so for four or five
months I thought he had messed up and
just given me Sour Diesel
and then he came down to my house one
day and he walks into a room that was
about 10 days away from being done he's
like oh this is all L.A I must have not
given I must have not given you the sour
this is the LA this is the headband for
sure
you know and actually and so I asked him
for his sour and he's like you know what
the one you gave me is way nicer than
the one that I had so there's not even
any point just keep this one
so I got that cut
I don't know I think he got it in O2 or
03 or something like that right in that
range a long time ago now and um I got
it as you know he got it as the LA Kush
um but it was called a headband
right and that's all I know about it to
be honest and he ended up uh starting
Emerald Mountain seed Emerald Mountain
Seed Company
um with a lot of stuff that I had given
him and some of the stuff that he had
and he Blended that La he made you
probably heard of it the 707 Headband
that is the that La cut cross to an
Afghani he had that he released as a
seed line and that still exists
um and he passed it out pretty freely
and I passed it out pretty freely and
somehow I'm not going to say I'm the
only person that uh that has it because
that would be presumptuous but it does
seem like
it's not one of the more reliable sours
uh in the sense that it's a little bit
more environmentally sensitive and
people didn't hold on to it
so somehow it seems like I ended up
being one of the only people
that had it and then when I started
chatting about it
it's got a terrible name dude
in the sense that like it's the least
circulated headband right so if you
start talking about headband people want
to know is it the one that Bob Hemphill
has that Matt Elite has is it the one is
it the Loompa is it this is it that it's
none of those right and then if you call
it the LA Kush obviously people think of
kush they think of TK or ghost or you
know or Larry or Irene or whatever right
so its name isn't very descriptive in
that regard and
um it was never called not so's anything
up until I started doing the podcast
with Matt
and then for lack of a better way of
describing it people started trying to
identify it as like oh it's this
headband well which one it is oh it's
the one not so has
yep right so it's kind of one of those
ways where like my name got organically
added to it
and you know fairly recently really but
um it is I got it as La Kush Headband
yeah okay look that makes a lot of sense
and look I I think that from what I've
heard that's actually a similar story
with Lumpy's headband right like
apparently he never called it lumper's
headband it was just people he traded it
on the forums and people were like oh
this is the headband I got from Lumpa I
think
and I go back and forth and stuff and
like he doesn't like me very much but
um I think he intentionally added his
name to it
uh and I also think that then he got
what's weird about it is when you start
adding names to things for people a lot
of times people get protective of their
association with things
right and it there's a weird Pride
element that comes in so I mean
I uh
you know and it's it's also weird for me
to talk about mandelbrot because he's
passed and so I typically like you know
uh and his you know his brother is has a
seed company now and stuff and Emerald
Mountain Legacy and um you know like his
life and how he was is you know it's a
little dicey to talk about in some
regards but because it's a shame because
he passed away early yeah and
unexpectedly and suddenly right
uh and um you know they he
people want you know when I talk about
when I tell that story sometimes people
like oh you're trying to take credit
from them you're trying to take this
you're trying to take that and I don't
think people get how cannabis really was
back then you know how you were talking
about when it came to the land race
stuff like you're standing on the
shoulders of others yeah right so Mandel
was standing on my shoulders to get his
seed company started but I'm not
standing on the ground I'm starting I'm
standing on the shoulders of Staten
Island and various other friends who
gave me the strains that I ended up
working with that we made those seeds
with and they're standing on the
shoulders of the P you know what I mean
and it just keeps going back to where
it's like well who gets credit
you know it's like well Wendy how did
you hold the Baton so you know uh did I
give Mandel most of what he used to
start a seed company yeah
does that mean I'm responsible for all
the choices that he made and all the
effort that he put in and everything he
did after that of course not no
I didn't even charge him back then
because back then
like
just you know there was like I was
saying in 2001 2002 2003 there was no
outlets for American private breeders to
really sell their seats
yeah
right there wasn't so most of us we you
know I would I I mentioned it before on
the show too like we you know we go to
these Harvest festivals you be given 50
or 100 seeds away to friends all the
time
try this I made this I got way more than
I need take some
right it was also pre-reversals for most
people so they were all regular seeds
and
um you know so yeah I mean I gave I gave
Mandel probably over a thousand seats
right
but I had
so so many dude
like what was I gonna do with like what
you know honestly like I I mean I gave
away seeds to all kinds of friends
because
um what what would I do with all of them
yeah it gets a bit like that doesn't it
yeah I mean it's like okay I got I've
got 50 000 seeds of Superdog hybrids and
so every home of mine that wanted them
that wanted to pop them that wanted to
run them in their Greenhouse that wanted
to do something with them sure
because it was long before
you there was really any weird ego in
the American scene about like oh I'm
gonna make a seed company this is my
[ __ ] you're gonna have to pay me you're
gonna have to it was more like weed
nerds trading yeah more organic right it
was very much more so organic and so now
it's like people are like you try to
honestly talk about it and people are
like oh you're trying to steal thunder
right
but has nothing to do with that really
it was just a different era that's
really all I can say about it was just a
different era it was like my homie
wanted to start a seed company I had way
more seeds than I knew what to do with
he had a couple of clones he wanted some
more clones he wanted some more stuff to
start with
here you go
you know
here's 1200 seeds here's 1400 seeds
they're like nine different crosses of
different things see what you find
go for it look I uh we're definitely
gonna jump into that but I want to
quickly ask one of the thing and then
we'll we'll loop back to it which is in
terms of the the headband with lumpers
versus your one how would you describe
the differences because I think they're
both two very good ones that go around
as the term headband what do you think
are the differences the similarities and
why do you think there are so many
different headbands out there it feels
to me like it's it's got to be up there
with sour in terms of like the number of
different cuttings that go around with
the same name
well
um so there's different stories to it
you know
um I'll start with the headband name it
seems like headband ended up becoming a
popular name right
and then it seemed like headband was
also tied into the the sour diesel
origin story
and there was a lot of mystery around it
right and so
when there's mystery around it and
there's money and there's rep to be made
sometimes names get tagged onto things
okay so I have no idea why my why the
the headband the LA that I have is
called headband it's just that's what it
was that's what it that's what it was
right lumpas
I think and he might get real mad at me
for this but I think it's an ogs one
yeah I agree my my cut is very much in
the sour or the diesel type of family
look it's it's stretchy it's got that
it's got those similar Terps to it it's
got similar growth pattern it's very
much in that family right uh Lumpa is
very much an OG Kush type you know in in
my opinion uh it's really good smoke uh
it's very potent it's enjoyable smoke
um but to me it's just a really nice
Kush you know like if you had that and
you had ghosts and you had triangle and
you had a few different things it would
fit right in that same movie yeah and
then you've probably tried I call it you
know I mean people call it different
names but you've probably tried that
other one I call it the 56.
um you know uh
um mad Elite has it
um uh I see Collective has it Bob hemp
Hill has it right yeah um it's I think I
think it's the the one that's skunk VA
uses too uh and that one's a Cush
and apparently uh you know there was you
know you probably heard the story but
there was there was some drama and there
was maybe some violence or there was
some issues going on in Southern
California over this cut and this guy
took it to to San Francisco
and they didn't really want any of that
drama following them
so they intentionally renamed it
headband ah okay right that's the very
simple version
so you have a couple of what I consider
to basically be OG Kush types
as headband
and don't get me I and then there's so
much confusion where people are like oh
this is the day record this is the
original diesel this is that headband
and they all have these very murky
stories so I don't necessarily know I'll
be able to like explain every single one
of them to you but I would just say that
headband
was a famous strain that people wanted
to tie strains that they had to that
lineage and to that Legend and the
legend was murky enough it allowed for a
lot of that to happen yeah okay that
certainly makes sense actually
so let's go back to our first question
we normally start with take me back to
the beginning what was your very first
experience with cannabis
oh my God
that is normally how how you start but
we really went off field on this one um
it's not very exciting
uh my first experience with cannabis was
basically Mexican
right and in the early 90s when I
started smoking weed uh I knew of two
kinds of cannabis that you could get you
could get brown seeded cannabis that was
compressed and you could get hopefully
lesser compressed green cannabis that
was you know and you know the good stuff
had less seeds and was less compressed
and the worse stuff had a lot more seeds
and a lot more stems and was heavily
compressed
um and so my in high school that's kind
of really what we had access to that was
what was you know it was twenty dollars
an eighth for brown weed and it was
thirty dollars an eighth for greenweed
uh and you know kind bud which is what
we you know um we all smoke now
uh I first experienced that going to a
dead show when I was 15.
I'd never I'd never seen weed that nice
before
um and it
I like Mexican weed
right so the effect that I got I had
plenty of fun getting stoned on Brown
Mexican
you know I came up in an era in America
where all the various Imports that
people talk about like Colombian and
Thai and this and that and everything
else that was all previous to me it was
basically just different grades of
Mexican that's all I saw
um and that was true in Florida uh I
guess in Florida we'd see a little bit
of of Jamaican but the Jamaican was
terrible a lot of times the Jamaican
would get sprayed with raid
uh which was a cockroach killer
um it was adulterated
um and you know who knows I was also a
teenager so it's not like
um I had very good access I don't come
from a family of pot smokers none of my
like I didn't I don't have one of those
origin stories that my dad or my uncles
or anyone like that got me into it all
early
um my experience with weed was basically
uh friend groups
you know and so what is that what is
your 15 or 16 or 17 year old friend
group have access to
that was sort of the start of it so some
people get on here and they're like oh
you know my uncle was doing this amazing
stuff and he was smuggling and he had
all these rare seeds that was not my
start in fact
I would say that maybe like my curiosity
about weed and my drive to learn more is
started from the fact that it was so
hard to get for us
right and figuring out information about
it was hard and you got to realize that
like when I started smoking there was no
internet
so it was like maybe you get some High
Times you know and read some read some
stories in High Times there's a few
books out about it I I started growing
weed in when I was 18 when I moved out
of my parents house mostly because
I wanted to be able to get good weed
like I could get on dead tour and I
couldn't find it reliably around me at
all uh look you preempted my next
question because I was gonna say I find
with most younger people the thing that
stimulates them to start growing is
getting exposed to some like super
phenomenal weed and you're like wow I've
got to do this for myself would you say
that it was on dead tour that happened
and if so do you remember the specific
Bud that gave you that light bulb moment
I mean you know you have to realize too
that like names were fairly uncommon
like there was a lot of weed on dead
tour that was like Humboldt County
organic outdoor that's what it was sold
as you know cotton Bud yeah kind bud
nuggets you know I got them nuggets you
know instead of being compressed it was
like nicely shaped nugs you know flower
um so yeah I don't really remember what
it was I just remembered that it was
green and stinky and not compressed and
seedless and it worked way better
yeah
um and even to jump forward a second you
know when I was 22 or something like
that when I first moved to Mendocino
County
most weed around here was named where it
was from
instead of getting like a specific
strain you would be like oh this is some
Panther gapweed this is some weed from
whitethorn this is some Alder point lead
this is some weed that I got up on
spyrock road it was more like location
based than even the name
right and most of it was grown from seed
and most of it was mixed phinos in
pounds or in ounces
right it was it wasn't like it was mono
cropped like it is today with like most
people weren't growing cuttings
uh most people uh maybe indoor they were
growing cuttings but most outdoor and
Greenhouse stuff was from seed and so it
would be you might have five or six
different kinds of weed in the bag now
maybe they were sisters to each other so
it wasn't like you had like
wildly different strains mixed together
right but like somebody would grow a
batch of seeds and they would trim it up
and they would weigh it up and then they
would move it all along and then there
you go and so my early experience was
like
um you know kind bud was seedless kind
bud wasn't compressed kinda tasted
really nice and I didn't know what uh I
didn't know anything dude so I got out
of high school and I bought uh Mel Frank
and Ed rosenthal's book
um marijuana horticulture
and I bought uh marijuana botany from
Rob Clark and I bought uh what was the
third one uh Jorge cervanes's book that
he still puts out
um the indoor marijuana holder
Horticulture and other than that and a
little bit of advice from some older
hippies that I saw occasionally at shows
or whatever that was kind of how I
started
um I had one light on a mover a four by
eight tray
um I had a buddy of mine he's passed
away now I can say his name Johnny
Winters
um and he was probably about eight or
nine years older than me
and he was way into the Grateful Dead
um Widespread Panic uh various uh things
of that nature he was definitely a tour
rat
and he uh had a house in Carbondale
Illinois and he gave me these cuttings
called the crystal chunk
and that was the very first
um you know I grew 1 000 watt light on a
six foot mover over a four by eight tray
of Crystal chunk when I was probably the
summer of 1994.
yeah
um and that was the first that was the
first time I ever actually the first
time I ever grew weed to be honest uh is
I used to sit in my parents house and
dc'd you know I had to deseed and
de-stem the Mexican weed that I was
buying right so I would deseed it and
then I would flick the seeds and stems
out my window into the bushes
okay
and that was that and it was my job to
mow the family lawn so one time in
Spring I'm out there in Chicago and I'm
mowing the lawn and I come upon these
bushes and there's like three foot tall
pot plants really because I've been I've
been throwing hundreds of seeds out my
window for however many months you know
and then it got warm and some of them
sprouted and I remember like running
them over with my lawnmower because I
was so panicked I was gonna get busted
so the first time I ever grew I it was
on accident and then as soon as I saw
him I intentionally killed him because
it was not gonna go over well at my
house
um and that's another point maybe I
should make too is that like some people
grew up in a friendly wheat environment
my parents didn't smoke at all
so if I needed to get away with smoking
it had to be completely hidden I had to
take the dog on a walk you know maybe I
had to bring some like you know some gum
or something to like take it off my
breath I had to take a bunch of steps in
order to get away with it
um because my parents are cool you know
but they just weren't they weren't weed
people they weren't you know we lived in
a police state at the time
um and so as a teenager it all had to be
totally clandestine
girl you taking me back now and you say
that I love it you know and uh it makes
me think maybe um you know the dog
walker should have been named after you
uh I mean yeah it's just you just needed
to get out like that's you know I got
real religious my parents were all
stoked on me because when I was 16 17
whatever in high school I'd walk the dog
religiously big long walks you know he's
a little overweight he needed to walk my
parents thought I was like really doing
a a big good deed and I get a couple
blocks away from the family and I'd
spark up my bowl and off we went right
so
um yeah growing weed was uh was just a
way like I needed I could get weed if I
went to Dead shows
but if I didn't go to a dead show there
was some people I knew in Chicago that I
could get weed from but only
occasionally and this this is going to
make you laugh right but let's say you
knew somebody that had a three lighter
okay
the person that bought that off that
person they would go through and
whatever they wanted to keep they would
pick out of like say the three or four
pounds they got they would pick out the
nicest pound out of the three nug by nug
and then they would sell the rest and
then your buddy would get it and he
would do the exact same thing so I might
only be like two people away from the
grower but everything I got was a small
yeah okay because it was so in demand
right that like didn't matter what it
was like it was 50 to 50 bucks an eighth
hundred bucks a quarter for anything
better than Mexican what an age and it
was hard to get
and it was it was hard to get and so par
I think that's actually if if it would
have been prevalent around me and it
would have been easy to get and I would
have been had multiple plugs or I would
have had someone to teach me
I learned how to grow weed by reading
books over and over and over again
I didn't know anything about electricity
I didn't know anything about wiring I
didn't know anything about air movement
I was growing in apartments in Chicago I
had to figure out a way to get her to
get away with it
um you know my Amsterdam trips were to
begin in 90 we went in 94 we went most
years between 94 and 04. is when I
stopped but for a good 10-year period
most years we went once or twice a year
on a seed buying trip
um and to party basically and uh that
was where I knew you know Dead shows and
Holland were where I knew to get good
weed that's brilliant and just
specifically when you went on those seed
hunting trips are there any real
memorable standout seeds like something
that really impressed you or maybe
something that even lived on until today
uh sure you know
um the I don't know if you've heard me
talk about or you've seen on my page
what I post the what we call the Maui oh
yeah
uh the Maui we got it uh I think I think
it was 1990 it was probably 1994
1994-ish so it's probably 29 years old
now
um that was gotten on a trip over there
uh probably the best thing that I ever
personally popped of what I bought over
there was uh black domino
um and it sadly did not live I got I got
an I got in trouble a couple times and
it got lost once and I've not been able
to find it again but as far as like my
personal seed pops of going over there
probably my favorite thing I ever found
from Holland genetics that I personally
purchased was black black domino
and I got it the first year it came out
I think I got it in like December of 96
or something like that it had just been
released that fall
uh and I found a killer one it was
really really potent tasted like black
pepper uh it was really enjoyable smoke
I miss it quite a bit actually
um and I was dumb too dude I should have
probably bought
two or three things and bought like 50
to 80 seeds of each right
but instead I'd bring home like
15 packs of one or two of each of each
of it
right so you have like 10 or 12 seats
you know or 15 seeds or eight seeds or
whatever and then you get like five
girls and then you don't find what I
need what you wanted if I was smarter
and I was older if I was doing it today
and that [ __ ] still existed I'd be
buying 50 to 80 seeds of each and
probably only buying two or three things
and like coming home and giving myself
20 or 30 or 35 females to look through
yeah right hindsight's 2020 for sure I
didn't know what I was doing I mean some
of that stuff like back in the day when
we were first getting it you know we
killed all the males we didn't make seed
that didn't occur to us at the time it
was like the way that you did it is you
got seed and you picked out the best
females and you killed everything else
look that's almost the perfect segue to
talk about the Mendo perps but I'm going
to resist the urge to jump there and try
to keep us in chronological order so do
you remember what it was you were first
growing when you started growing
yeah I mean the very first weed I ever
got it was uh I actually it's really
weird how the internet works but I
reconnected with someone
um who was friends with Johnny Winter
back then
um and in that same group of people and
um he told me that the crystal chunk is
some kind of he doesn't remember which
one but he said it's some kind of NL or
NL hybrid that they bought from the seed
bank uh back then oh wow and I don't
have it anymore I have some see some old
seeds of it that a friend gave me I
don't have this the Clone anymore
um but that was the very first
um kind bud strain I ever grew was I
grew a couple I grew a light of Crystal
chunk and then shortly after that we did
an Amsterdam trip and uh we got some
various different strains we started
seed popping and we got the Maui ended
up popping up in our group and that that
obviously still exists
um so uh
yeah that that was that was kind of like
that was what we were going as far as
like trading with other people dude like
two other people besides myself knew I
was even growing in Chicago yeah
I would like to keep it that crazy like
to make sure that I didn't get in
trouble I would literally be at parties
and I would buy an eighth off my friend
who I sold a pound to wow so that way I
did it in public right and that way a
bunch of friends would see oh this is
why Francis that this is why not so has
this week yeah okay I love that right
because this is this is this is why I
saw him he bought a quarter he bought an
eight of course he's got the same stuff
it's from dude right but then if you do
that in public I can't be the grower but
a social engineering at its finest why
why would I be buying it so the world
that you came into where like there's
connectivity and there's people trading
cuts and there's access to cuts and all
that type of stuff
that was Zero my world
like we had our small little group of
friends that had that that like were all
the same age that had a few cuts and we
went to Amsterdam we got some seed and
then my buddy ended up moving to
Colorado and that sort of expanded
things a little bit
um that's where I got introduced to the
caller the to what people call the cough
um the wheelchair the question mark
um the Hong Kong
um that kind of thing and then
I moved out to Mendocino County which is
a whole kind of crazy story in itself
but I moved out to Mendocino County in
the late 90s
and then eventually stuff really started
shifting for me I met uh Staten Island I
ended up getting the super skunk and the
and the chem dog I started trading with
various people in Mendo and getting some
different stuff and that's kind of like
the the journey that began
wow you definitely preempted my next
question which I was going to ask which
came first meeting started an island or
moving to Mendocino oh I guess you sort
of answered it but my question Still
Remains what was it like when you first
moved to Mendo was it like were things
big and popping off or was it still like
that old world vibe that like Mean Gene
talks about where you know like there
was just these old Afghans and NLS and
like not too much more was discussed
beyond that because it was just good
weed
um I would say that's true so I I kind
of came into like uh me and Jean and I
have chatted about it a bit you know
um and I came out to Mendo in a really
weird way uh I don't know I don't think
I've told this story publicly I'll I'll
give kind of an Abridged version of it
but
I had
um
my partner
and by partner I mean like my uh my ex
she
got cancer when we were in our early 20s
okay
and in back in Illinois there is no like
uh I don't know what it's like in
Australia but there is no like Universal
Health Coverage here
okay
uh there's zero it's pretty much Darwin
um like if you were to get into like an
accident and break your leg or you were
to have some kind of crazy emergency
they'll take care of you but if you need
like dialysis or you need chemo or
something like that
um you're pretty much out of luck
um so
I was in this situation where I was
totally in love with her and she was
sick and I needed to figure out a way to
help her
and so I started hustling and doing all
these various things trying to earn
enough money
that I could afford the surgery she
needed and the chemo that she needed
right and the chemo I was like a
Grateful Dead hippie dude so I was like
a million percent against
doing any kind of radiation or any kind
of chemo I was absolutely convinced it
was poison
and then the doctor pulled me aside and
he was like look man
he goes if you do this right now
she has probably like a probably a 90
chance of complete remission
and I went home and I was like man you
know 90 is pretty good
right if someone tells you you have a 90
chance of getting what you want you if
you do this thing you'd probably do the
thing right
so I
um we did the we did the chemo and it
worked it was she went into remission
but
I don't know if you know much about
women's sizes she was about a size seven
when she started she was throwing up a
whole bunch
and she couldn't keep food down and she
was dropping weight like crazy and she
ended up being like a double zero in
size like she was just wasting she was
wasting away
and they went through every every
anti-nausea medicine known to man all
this different [ __ ] none of it was
working
and so this guy this doctor this
oncologist that we had he was like an
old Roman Catholic Italian guy and we
were obviously Grateful Dead hippies
okay
and he looks at me and he goes do you
guys smoke weed
and I was like
I smoke weed and he goes you know we've
tried everything else maybe before she
comes in and she does her chemotherapy
you guys could smoke a bunch of weed
because we've tried everything else and
nothing's really worked so I'm not
really supposed to say this but you know
I've heard a little bit that maybe it
can control nausea and it it's so why
don't you give it a shot
so we would wake up and we would watch
the prices Bob Barker and the price is
right and we would smoke joints and and
pole bongs and I would get her
hellaciously baked before these chemo
treatments right
and she stopped vomiting
and she started gaining weight
okay that's incredible and it was
literally like it was literally like a
[ __ ] miracle like she went from a
size seven down to a double zero back up
to a size five all from weed so this is
probably I don't know this is probably
1996 and I had some at this point Jerry
Garcia had died and there was no more
dead tour and I had friends that had
ended up in Mendocino County growing
weed that I knew from a couple friends
that I knew from dead tour
and in November of 96
um
my buddy called me up and he said dude
it's time for you to move and I was like
what do you mean and he was like we just
passed the first medical marijuana
law in the entire United States we voted
and it went through it passed and he
goes there's only five things that it
covers and one of them is cancer and
chemotherapy
he's like so you can come out here with
your lady and you can grow weed and you
are safe
they won't put you in jail for it
so it took a little time but you know in
97 or whatever we pretty much
started shifting our life and figuring
stuff out and we moved out the following
year
um into Mendocino County and um that's
how I got out here uh in a in a totally
random way and she went into remission
and uh got completely healthy and I
loved it out here and she absolutely
hated it and she wanted to move back to
Chicago
and our relationship did not last and so
she moved back to Illinois and I stayed
in California in Mendocino County and
I've been here since
and what's weird about that is that at
one point Mendocino County had the most
liberal and forward-thinking
um cannabis laws in the country
I was actually part of the Sheriff's
Department's medical marijuana program
we were vetted her and I through the
Department of Health
I had a I had a Mendocino County
Sheriff's department and and Mendocino
County Department of Health laminated
membership card
that said I was allowed to carry up to
two pounds on my person and I was
allowed to legally smoke cannabis and
consume cannabis and grow it for our
personal use
and we were part of the part we were
part of the pilot program that they
started
and fast forward a number of years I was
part of that program I think it was
until 04 the federal government
threatened to come in and take
um all of the records that Mendocino
County had on who was in their medical
marijuana program and at the time our uh
our Sheriff was so hardcore he canceled
the program and burned the records so
that the feds couldn't have access to
them so
that was how I ended up in Mendocino
County and if you wanted to segue into
the Mendo perp story it's got a pretty
good tie to that actually lead the way
my friend I just want to quickly say
what a what a beautiful story of the uh
the benefits cannabis can have for
people battling cancer but please please
lead on so
um I had a I had a friend of mine who
was blowing glass at a time when blowing
glass was pretty lucrative and mostly
only hippies knew how to do it right and
he was trying to set up an actual real
Glass studio in his in his shop that he
had on his property
which because you got to realize at the
time a lot of the early glass blowers
like actually ended up damaging their
lungs fuming gold and silver and not
realizing that they needed to have
proper ventilation okay
and they ended up breathing in heavy
metals and doing some damage to
themselves and so he wanted to build
this
um basically this HVAC system that would
pull you know a certain amount of air
away from the station that he was
working and uh
and not toxify him right
so he hires this guy
uh who is a retired HVAC guy and he
ended up being sick and he had cancer
and so
he was kind of going through the same
thing my ex was going through and so I
felt really bad for him and I ended up
um I ended up giving him a chunk of
water hash and I don't know
two three ounces of weed or something
like that
and he had and I was like I just hope
this helps you the way it helped my lady
right
and he was like man I can't afford this
and I'm like I don't honestly I don't
care you can just have it
right you're helping us do this HVAC
thing you're struggling for your health
and your life I'm doing fine you know
take a little hash take a few take some
weed you're good and he felt embarrassed
and I was like just just just do it like
if it helps you it helps you I I need
Zero from you okay
so fast forward a week and he goes man
you know I used to grow back in the day
but I haven't done it in a while and I
was digging in my closet and I found
this little thing of seed
and I thought maybe this is a way maybe
you'd accept this as payment if you
won't take any money or any work or
anything like that and so he gave me two
seats
and uh I Sprout these things up
and they both pop
and I'm growing them up
and one ends up being a girl and one
ends up being a boy okay
and I was having a friend of mine back
then mostly we grew in bedrooms
right it was pretty clandestine so we're
growing in this bedroom and I'm having a
friend of mine help me set up a bedroom
because I had a three bedroom house I
lived in one room
one room was veg and one room was was
flour right
and uh
I had him help me hang up all these
these lights in this room and set up
this veg so we get this veg set up I
move all my plants in there I go in
there the next morning and one of the
lights you know the old school metal
sharp uh Hood one of the lights he had
put one of the one of the wood hooks
into the ceiling but it had only gone in
the drywall he'd missed the stud
and as the night went on it fell out of
the thing and it swung down and it
chopped the mail off at the base oh my
God and it was just laying there on the
ground wilted
so I'm like oh man well at least I'm
like in my mind I'm like at least they
killed the boy okay so I had this one
girl so I bloomed this girl out
and you got to realize this is the late
90s so this is way before Urkel or
anything like that and so all of a
sudden I get this like crazy smelling
Royal Purple looking cannabis and I am
tripping out I've never seen anything
quite like it
and so I take it to dude and I'm like is
this what you what is this and he looks
at it and he goes man I didn't think
that even existed still
and I was like what is it he goes I
don't know he's like but the only time I
grew purple weed was like the summer of
77 in kovalo
which kovalo is a little uh remote uh
town in Mendocino County uh tucked away
in the middle of nowhere
right so
the seeds were basically 20 21 year old
seeds
that he had just tossed in a cold Closet
in Laytonville and ignored
and
um he died that following year so I
never really got more information off it
besides that but that is literally how
the way I got the Mendo perps is I gave
a cancer patient
um some hash and some weed to help him
out and he gifted me back a couple of
seeds and that's how I got the perps
what an incredible sort of real organic
story I love that you know just someone
helping another person out and the
universe rewards you for that indirectly
that's that's beautiful did you have any
idea it would go on to become what it is
now and I think I have to preface this
by acknowledging I think Mendo perps is
still kind of coming into its prime
especially with all the work Caleb's
been doing I think it's even still like
it's not like it was big and it fell off
I think it's still gaining momentum but
what's your perspective
I would say that as a part of the reason
why when you talk to people dude that
the stories are so funny and they don't
always line up is a lot of times it was
young kids that had no idea that
anything that they were doing was ever
going to be talked about or be important
again
sure
right I mean think about think about for
a second think about uh chemdog popping
the chem 91 when he was 17.
right yeah yeah hugely unmemorable in
the moment just you know and that's part
of why some of the stories with sour
diesel or with kush or with chemdog or
with whatever gets so convoluted is
because nobody knew that they needed to
be that they were going to be asked on a
granular level what happened
right so no I didn't I didn't know I
mean we
um I knew it was special because at the
time I had never seen purple weed before
like that it's not like there was no
purple weed that's silly there's plenty
of Afghans and Mendo and stuff like that
that
um will turn purple in the cold
especially you know you get some a cold
snap and fall as they're ripening or
something like that and they'll purple
right up
but for me at least in my experience in
my realm
um that was the first thing I ever grew
that like in a 75 degree indoor room
would just turn dark purple and it just
smelled wild right and
so
um we loved it and I passed it around to
good friends it's kind of a crazy story
how CSI got it uh because you know but
I'd let him tell that aspect of it but
it was it it's
I think it was sort of it was
pre-purpled it was pre-pre
um the purp the first purple wave that
really got popular
um and it only spread out so far but we
did make some hybrids with it and those
hybrids that we made
um one of them was intentional we
crossed
um this Durban Poison line we had to uh
the Mendo p and called it anise because
it smelled very much like licorice
uh and that has gone on to make a number
of different things and then
um I had this strain called
the effects
okay
ef-e-x and I got it actually you know
I'm sure you know who Tim Blake is right
yeah
um Tim Blake is actually the first
person that ever showed me a 90 lighter
uh way back when and I became friends
with him I used to go to his house and
he'd throw like he'd throw events at his
at his spa and he'd have music and food
and you know they'd pound music all
night and have a good time and such and
his worker gave me this cut that that
some people called garlic Bud and some
people called effects and I was growing
a room at my friend's house
um that had effects right next to
semendo perps it was summertime the uh
air conditioner went out it took me a
couple of days to fix it and that amount
of time the Mendo perps hermed it harmed
all over the effects and I got a bunch
of purple effect seats
um and that was that was my first
feminized breeding totally on accident
not not intentional
um and that strain actually you can see
it I think it's in the second Canna
Bible uh purple effects and it's gone on
it's in a number of modern strains today
like it's in the Sprite it's in the Rose
um it's in a few different things that
people have used over the years
um I don't have it anymore I lost it and
the seeds in a bust but it percolates
around
yeah wow that's a that's a really cool
story and and could you ever have
imagined that like you know the Mendo
perp was what led the way for these
things plus a plethora of other strains
like you know I know that on breed of
Syndicate I mentioned that um you know
the Mendo breath was one that I feel
like I see a lot of the Mendo purpose
within that strain even though there's a
few Generations removed could you
imagine that like not only might it be
used in things but even multiple
Generations later you can still really
sort of see it shining through
I can uh and the reason is is that the
one thing that um makes me think that my
that the guy was telling me the truth
okay is think about 1977 that would have
been
um like I was saying earlier in the show
that was sort of like the first couple
of years that Afghans were started to
make their way into Humboldt and
Mendocino County and spreading out a bit
amongst the grower community
and the only reason why I think it could
possibly be true is that it's pretty low
THC but it's very it's very much within
the range of what most things THC wise
were in that era
um and it's got a very when you S1 it
when CSI is S1 did
um it's got an extremely wide gene pool
in there it's definitely not narrow it's
very broad lots and lots of different
things pop out in those s1s much more
broad than most strains and it's got I
don't want to say it's got unique Terps
because I don't think there is unique
things in cannabis but I do think that
it might be unique to what we know today
in the sense that almost anything I've
ever smelled that smells like Mendo
perps I find that it
ties back to Mendo in some way
right and I would say that Mendo is
probably a better breeder than it is as
an actual plant itself
um I think it's children
um or even some of its s1s can be nicer
than the mother plan I love the mother
plant but it's got some things I really
adore but it's also missing a couple of
things that I wish it had
so
um you know it it uh and there's a weird
thing where people don't like to give
credit you know they like you were
saying before everyone wants to walk out
with their strain and have it be like it
CR and it it I created this out of
nothing
so I can understand how a bunch of
people don't want to give up their
secret sauce but what I do think is cool
is that uh Way Beyond anything that I
had to do with it the biggest
contribution you can make in cannabis is
to get some hybrids out there or to get
some crosses out there to get some seed
Pops that you happen to be a part of out
there and that those things are valuable
enough that other people most of which
don't even know you or might not even
know that you exist find valuable enough
in that weed to keep breeding and
growing and smoking it
yeah certainly certainly and that's why
I always try to mention to people you
know I think there's nothing more you
know there's nothing more to be grateful
for as a breeder than when someone
dedicates some space and time in their
grow to Growing your workout especially
if it's multiple times you know it's
it's a real Testament yeah I mean think
about like you know when people when
you're talking about how people get mad
that people steal their work right well
you know what's worse is uh everyone's
saying man that sucks I would never work
with
it's actually a compliment to have
someone to have someone use your stuff
and maybe it's even a bigger compliment
if they like it so much they want to
obscure where it comes from and say and
make up their own story about it because
it's so good they wanna they they want
that like rep or whatever that comes
with it to like come to them instead of
you right because everyone's going to be
forgotten dude you know like we're all
just passing through a bit and you know
20 30 years from now like you were
talking about like you know what do you
think strains will be remembered
hopefully some of the Breeders now are
making good enough work that some of
their stuff still exists or at least is
Blended into the modern stuff that
exists then
that's really the goal of breeding right
is like to leave a genetic imprint and
to maybe improve what you found in
certain ways and pass it on to the next
group
for sure for sure maybe in uh 20 years
we'll still have rainbow belts there you
go Fletcher I gave you a good one yeah I
mean I mean it's it's entirely possible
man I don't even you know I don't even
like cookies very much but it's
certainly
um it's certainly a big part of an on a
permanent part of the community and I'll
say this too like you were talking about
Caleb and his and you know
most of the time Caleb told me when when
he meets people that are actually the
originator of whatever strain that
they're using he's using they get upset
at him and they want some kind of
compensation or they want some kind of
shout out or they want rep because he's
using their thing right he said I was
like the only guy that was like just
super stoked that
um he was doing all these really cool
things with the Mendo p
because I do think that no one is more
is going to be more responsible for
making sure that those genetics don't
get lost than him
he's made more hybrids with it and he's
popular enough that so many of those
hybrids have sold and he's made a bunch
of s1s and he's made it so that even if
him and I or somebody else lost the
mother cut
that it's probably a permanent addition
to the gene pool because it's been mixed
it's been mixed into enough things
that's going to survive in some form
yeah definitely that's that's a great
way to view it and um I I wanted to just
quickly loop back to the other thing we
mentioned a few questions ago which was
you know you said you moved to Mendo and
then shortly after you met Staten Island
and you got exposed to the dog and the
super skunk how was it exactly that you
met Staten Island and when you did meet
him was he already in the thick of like
the chem 91 and the super skunk fandom
or was it still like he'd only just sort
of got them like where was it when you
sort of stepped in
um well I would so you know memories
vary on this one a little bit but it
seems like
um
it seems like he got both let's say
sometime in 1994.
okay
um and then he brought them back to
California
uh it seems like
um skunk VA was still traveling with the
Grateful Dead then and so he didn't
start growing I don't think until after
Jerry died in August of 95
and it seems like
um you could ask him I suppose but it
seems like after Jerry died he I believe
he quit touring right away because there
was no more tour and he came out
um and get and uh Statin gave him
um some super skunk and he started
growing that and I believe those
Polaroids that he posts on his page are
from those very first few grows that he
ever did okay and so I think
um I want to say that maybe he got it
from Staten Island and maybe 95 late 95
maybe early 96
um and then I see Collective
uh graduated high school in 97 and he
ended up moving in with skunk VA and so
that's I think he got access to it
um by that aspect and then I got it the
following year from Staten Island
um in 1998 and uh we just met randomly
and um
smoked each other's weed and really
enjoyed it
and then I ended up going down and
having some dinners at his house he
lived in Sonoma County at the time
um with his with his lady that became
his wife
uh and we just ended up we just ended up
becoming really good close friends and
so he he was a stickler and he
um really was very intent upon none of
these things ever leaking
uh but for whatever reason he decided to
give them to me
um and so I got the skunk and the uh and
the chem dog from him
and uh I've had the chem dogs since I
had the skunk for a number of years I
lost it I don't know maybe nine years
eight eight nine years after that
something along those lines and uh I got
I got in trouble and uh they got cut
down and I was the last person I knew
that had it so that was that
but I will say that there was Zero Fame
around those cuts
um there was nothing of the legend that
you guys know of there was nothing of
the like I think that uh I don't think
that they even started getting
popularized very much until skunk VA
went on the forums in 06 maybe or maybe
it was o5
but for the first I don't know half a
decade I had it
uh
it was just like some super fire weed
that we had
and uh Staten Island wouldn't let me get
wouldn't let me give it to anyone so
nobody else could have it
Ah that's that's so interesting and so
most of the stories that I believe are
the ones that I heard earliest
right yeah
um because obviously there's you know
you know Fame gets into it different
people get into it and people start
arguing about time and stuff and so
you know I I came you know do I know
it's origin stories 100 you know there's
obviously some debate back and forth on
that but I got it pretty early from
Staten Island
um just by being good friends with them
and the whole super dog project was
um also just something that happened
because I was good friends with him and
him and I were doing some stuff together
and um
you know that whole the whole like
beginning of that really was that I
don't think this is particularly well
known maybe it is maybe it's not but
after Statin had given the skunk to
um to chemdog on the east coast and then
brought the skunk and the chem and the
dog out west
um chemdog called them later and said
dude the first time I grew this stuff it
harmed
the skunk hermed all over the chem dog
and I got seeds and I'm growing those
seeds and they're better than both of
them
so the whole start of his idea to like
create the super dog was basically
trying to combine those strains into one
line
but you got to remember back then that
was so long before there was reversals
or we even knew that reversals existed
so in order to like even make the line
happen it was like you had to BX you
know it's almost like you had you had to
get a pollen Source somewhere because
the two clones that we wanted to cross
were both girls
we just had a single clone of each
right
and I knew nothing we knew nothing about
reversals we knew in fact back then we
thought that hermaphrodit exceed was
cheating and it would [ __ ] up your seed
line by making more hermaphrodites
so uh we didn't know anything about
reversals or feminized breeding or any
of any of in that kind of stuff so
he ended up taking the super skunk and
he ended up Crossing it
um to a male and then I think we took
that I think he took that to F3
something like that selecting for uh
skunk traits and then I believe if I
remember correctly
um we might it might there might have
been a a back Cross of that back onto
the the skunk cut itself
and then pollen from that got thrown on
the dog and that became super dog
that's interesting I didn't know there
was that outcrossing step but I'd love
to ask you whatever happened to the
super dog because you know like we we
spoke to skunk VA recently and he also
sort of had fond memories of the strain
and so it got me wondering like was
there any specific reason no one held on
to a cut or anything
well there's a bunch of reasons so
like I said before 99 of people won't
hold a cut unless it's currently popular
right so people plenty of people held it
and plenty of people grew it most people
just didn't hold it for a long time okay
and
uh you know there was as far as
gosh
this gets kind of tricky but I'll just
say it so
I gave all that stuff I gave to
mandelbrot which was basically a pure
super dog and then a bunch of Superdog
hybrids that uh Staten Island and I had
made Staten Island and I the final stage
of Superdog that we did was we took
seven or eight males combined with our
favorite
females of Superdog so I think there was
seven and seven seven and seven of each
we put those in a room and then we put
it in there with like every single cut
of quality cannabis that we had at the
time which was Mendo perps Super Skunk
the dog
um black black domino the Warlock
um the Maui all kinds of different
things we put them we put everything
every good cutting we had we threw it in
there on eight lighter and we just let
the pollen fly and we just pollinated
eight lights which is
using making regular seed with copious
amounts of pollen is a ginormous amount
of seed right
so after that we had a ton we had a ton
of seed I gave a bunch to mandelbrot and
the only thing that I asked was that if
you found anything cool give it back to
me or if anything ever happened and I
needed it give it back to me
um and neither one of those two things
happened
so
um the mandelbrot story I don't really
want to get into detail too much about
all that because it's a little I just
you know he was my buddy and we had we
had some issues over it I will say that
you know he had a little ego that went
to his head and he didn't want to share
and he didn't want to admit where some
of it came from
um we had kind of a falling out over it
and then we met randomly in Ukiah we
bumped into each other
and we kind of had a heart to heart
about it and he told me he was gonna
give me back
um some some selections he had made and
he'd give me back some seed and we were
going to be all good and then with
before that actually happened within a
couple of months
um he unexpectedly passed away
and uh when he passed away
um I don't know exactly what happened
but it seems like people went into his
grow room and people went into his seed
stock and a lot of that stuff
disappeared put it that way
so then that left me in Staten Island we
each had a bunch of seed
um
and uh
I had jars and jars and jars like mason
jars full of hybrids of it dude and I
had it stashed in a couple different
places in my house and
[Music]
um
I got busted I think it was in early 09
I got raided and uh they took all my
seed
and they actually flushed it down the
toilet
I don't usually tell that story very
much but I got handcuffed to a uh to a
computer chair and they wheeled me in
front of the bathroom and then they took
all these seeds and they opened up each
mason jar and they poured it into the
toilet while they were waiting for the
Paddy Wagon and they flushed all the
seed down the toilet
Jesus what's that death by torture
and so then shittily right in that same
time period
um Staten Island went on vacation and he
had all of his seeds stored in a fridge
in his garage
and someone had plugged something else
into into an outlet and it popped the
outlet while he was on vacation and so
the fridge stopped working and they
ended up the whole time he was on
vacation which I think was two or three
weeks they ended up in a 115 degree
garage unrefrigerated uh R.I.P and so we
had he had jars and jars of seed
we tried all these different ways to
make them pop they wouldn't pop we
passed them to friends we did all this
stuff about scuffing them and soaking
them and peroxiding them seed cracking
them and every once in a while we'd get
like a tail that would pop out
um and then it would just not continue
and die
and uh he actually had all that seed
um thousands and thousands of seeds but
we just couldn't make anything happen
with them and then in 2017
we had those massive California fires
and his house burned down so we lost
them so
um there's a Emerald Mountain Legacy Ben
who is uh Emmanuel brought's younger
brother he has some stuff that has like
some of that stuff worked in it I don't
know if out there you know supposedly
there's a cut called the truth
um that is Superdog by Maui
um that exists that I haven't grown
um but it's a selection that Mandel
brought made out of uh Super Dog by Maui
seeds that I gave him that exists
um and if you look in the in the second
cannabiable the red one
um there's a bunch of pictures of the
super dog super dog seven super dog
three some of the phenos I selected but
uh yeah four or five years of work
through uh busts uh cops fire and uh uh
popping circuits we lost the line
man that's that's heartbreaking to hear
but you know sort of speaking to your
point earlier
um you know nothing more of a honor than
to have someone want to use your work I
guess and hopefully you know you get
something that reminds you of it I'd
love to ask while I got you here what do
you think is the lineage on the chem dog
you know the much speculated and guessed
at do you have any ideas yourself
so I think it's I might get in trouble
for saying this but this is kind of how
I see it right so
um Joe B and Peabody
or older cats and they were on dead tour
and they were buying and selling weed
right it was very common for people to
buy weed say a half pound a quarter
pound a couple pounds take it on dead
tour and sell it in chunks and that's
what paid for their tickets and their
life and their partying and having a
good time right so these guys are buying
and selling weed all the time on dead
tour they buy weed they give it to they
they sell a bunch of it some of it goes
to a 17 year old kid
okay
and then that's in 1991.
Peabody and Joe B don't figure out that
anything came of those seeds until the
Forum era 0.506.
so literally 15 years goes by
without them having anything to do with
the chem story
okay
and then they're asked hey do you
remember 15 or 16 years ago
that one week when you were in Indiana
do you remember what the weed was like
that you had and that you were buying
and selling then
you see what I'm saying yeah it's a big
ask for a non-memorable event right
right it just it was like it was one it
was like Not only was a non-memorable
event but like they didn't even realize
that anything came of it for a decade
and a half
and so I've I definitely I've heard
people talk I don't even want to say
some of the rumors I think that
um I think that we just won't ever know
uh I have a bunch of theories about it
um some people get mad at me for talking
about the theories because you know the
the chemd and the chem dog and the the
one through the four and all these
different things they're all supposed to
be from the same exact seeds which
everyone assumes that they're sisters
right
but
what if in that ounce there like I was
talking about before what if there was
multiple phenos in that ounce
yeah that's what I've always thought
what if some of them were hybrids and
some of them were s1s
what if there was even more than one
source of pollen I mean we just don't
know and the people that we know that
gave dude the weed they weren't even The
Growers they were middlemen
buying weed from someone and then taking
an Undead tour and parceling it out to
make money
what I will say is that I do think that
um just by growing it for a long time
and Crossing it to a bunch of stuff and
seeing it I do think that the Mendo or I
do think that the the the chem 91 I
think it's already an S1 hmm ah okay
interesting and so that way like when
Caleb or somebody like that when you
when you s want it I think part of the
reason why it looks so uniform and
there's like not very much variation
going on there at all is it's already an
S2
yeah okay just because like the results
the progeny give mm-hmm
just because of how narrow like
if you were like remember how I was
talking about how I thought like the the
Mendo P might be land race because when
you S1 it it's so wide
like and you see so many different
expressions and and size and and colors
and nose and all these different things
the chem 91 is the opposite of that
almost all of it looks extremely similar
to the chem 91.
there's very little physical there's
some potency differences there's
actually some s1s that are even more
potent than the mob
um that strain
uh CSI has told me he thinks that
nothing in his entire collection passes
on potency as consistently as that cut
yeah but it but it just kind of is what
it is like when you try to go through a
bunch of s1s you're not going to find a
bunch of wildly different things
yeah that's interesting and I've
certainly heard you guys mention that
before and I've used that in some of the
seed selections I'm making you know
because I thought to myself all right if
the 91 really consistently passes on
potency maybe I should try to get
crosses where the other parent is like
really terpy or something because like
if it's gonna pretty consistently bring
potency maybe like a a forbidden fruit
cross chem 91 is sort of like the go-to
you know in terms of getting like a nice
well-rounded sort of plant
now that is real breeding
so what I think happens in breeding
today is people try to take two things
that are already popular
but you probably don't have access to
and combine them
and then you get hybrids of them right
in my opinion real breeding is like
there's these qualities in this one
plant and there's these qualities in
this other plant and I wonder if I can
get them in the same plant by making
making seeds with them
can I get these can I get these
qualities from over here and these
qualities from over here and can they
combine
and that to me is breeding
right so yeah anything you wanted to add
potency to
um you know the 91 will do that
you know it also you know add its look
too
um you know which is uh kind of that old
dark olive dinosaur looking weed
um it's one of my favorite strains still
it's well stood up to the test of time
it has probably my favorite Indica High
um I adore it
um not everyone thinks it's a favorite
but I personally love it a whole bunch
yeah beautiful stuff beautiful stuff I
wanted to quickly ask you before I
forget because it's like a fleeting
moment but uh when we spoke to skunk VA
recently he mentioned that there was
this cutting that went around sort of in
the 2000s it was a super silver haze and
he was like oh man it went around the
bay it was it was actually pretty
memorable I wish we still had that one
did you ever get exposed to that one
slash what's your thoughts on the super
silver haze in general
I like super silver haze
um you know super silver haze and
Neville's opinion was kind of an
improved Jack Herer it's basically a
blend of haze skunk and Northern Lights
right
uh and so you know in that regard
um there's a lot of variation in there
depending on which ones I had one I lost
it in the fire I had one that was
um you can still see some pictures of it
on my page that I loved a whole bunch I
don't think it was like elite elite
elite but it was really nice weed it
smelled really good it was really Frosty
it threw chunks all over itself
I like that line I like the mango Haze
line a little better
um but it's one of those ones that you
might have to look through a lot to find
what you really adore but it's in there
somewhere
and sometimes
you know you can look as much as you
want and you won't find what you're
looking for
uh and sometimes it's easy to find it
and sometimes it takes work and I think
the super silver haze that are really
good takes work but they exist
um and I so yeah there's there's various
phenos of it that float around that I
think are quite nice and I'm a fan
that's awesome to hear that you uh you
know got a soft spot for the um the
mango Haze that's one that you know it's
actually very popular in Australia a lot
of the older dudes really Vibe on it and
haven't really seen it represented as
much in the states outside of um
what's his name you know mango the the
guy from Florida but um yeah really
stoked stoked stoked to hear that yeah
mango I mean mango Hayes and um super
silver haze are sisters
um they're very closely related so
um super silver haze is C5 cross to
um a skunk Haze
okay and mango Haze is a sister of that
C5 Neville called it the 122 crossed to
the same dad
uh yeah yeah yeah yep yep yep does that
make sense
so they share so mango Haze and soup
Super Silver Haze share the same father
and the mothers are full sisters
wow so yeah they're very closely related
they're very closely related indeed it's
just that they actually called the 122
the mango
in Holland that was one of its nicknames
um because it had that mercy and it had
some of those Terps that were that were
like that and so I actually if I had to
pick
um super silver haze tends to be much
more of a commercial Planet It's like
got that those skunk colas all over it
it yields really well it's like
bulletproof mango Haze is a little
hazier to me it's a little more sativa
it's a little more finicky but I tend to
like the weed better
um then Super Silver Haze on average I
think it's a great strain
um I you know and I think it might be
one of the ones from
um from shanti's uh shanti's company Mr
Nice it might be one of the ones that he
actually still has the real parents of
which is always a big debate
but uh I I like mango Haze
it's a good one look while we're on the
topic of uh seeds and what parents might
be in them I want to ask you you know
sort of a two-parter but we'll keep it
simple to begin with I've there's been
speculation in you know the community
for a while but more recently you know
Matt chucked up the post which
um sort of openly said that the chemd
may be a chem 91 cross skunk and I would
love to hear your thoughts on this do
you think there might be any Merit to
that
uh yes I do
um I I'm one of the proponents of it I
know it caused some battles uh with
various various people that did not like
said speculation
um but
that's what it is it's speculation right
um what's the harm in speculating uh the
reason
why I think so is that
you know
um the uh
I just see like having grown the chem 91
for a really long time now and having a
a pretty long experience with the skunk
before I lost it I just I personally
just see both parents in that plant
right and you know like we were
mentioning about how narrow banded the
chem 91 s1s are
um you know it's also possible I mean uh
JJ and I got into a battle about it not
that long ago Top Dog
and he was like well could it be you
know he's like let's say that everything
you say is true why couldn't it be sis
by S by super skunk
and I had to admit that that could be
true too I just don't see that
the chem 91 the chemd the chem4
um the chem one that still exists some
of these different things I just don't
see them as being able to have the same
exact mom and dad
now whether that means that like dude
it's all true and it's the same original
13 seeds and there was like mixed phenos
of actual females in that ounce that he
had or there was multiple pollen sources
or
some of the other chems are later
hybrids you know it's like I'm not there
I don't have any super Insight I can't
say
um but it is I I think that
um I think that the chemd is a chem
skunk I just do I I the way how green it
is the way it grows the way it smells
the way it harms
um I've just grown it a whole bunch and
that would be my guess and I hoped that
philos or some of these other genetic
you know offerings that people have done
would have started to unlock some of
these oral histories and some of these
Legends and tales that we have and like
been definitive right
where they can be like this is
absolutely a full sister or this isn't
but we're not there yet
right so we don't have verifiable proof
one way or the other
we just have you know a story about a
teenager starting some seeds and
you know that's all we have
I totally can understand your point of
view and that there's so much ambiguity
it's hard to really say for sure and
something that I was thinking about
myself is that a comment that sort of
lasted with me was when skunk VA said
none of the super dogs came out like
chemd you know so like why would I
necessarily believe that that's the
lineage but then what I thought was if
you look at the GMO we know what the
lineage is chemd cross cookies mamiko
has put out a bunch of those seeds
people have popped them and no one has
found anything like the GMO yeah and so
I thought what if it's the same with the
chemd and the the skunk you know it's
just like a one in a million Fino I mean
it's kind of like the same thing with
cap right when he got famous on the Mac
one
and he sold a ton of Mach 1 seeds and
hybrids and nothing came out looking
like it right sometimes that happens and
you know Caleb and I have this thing
where like plants don't lie people do
um most of my stuff that I just told you
is just
my guess is based on breeding with the
plant growing the plants no it's in the
other thing too is that you got to
remember when skunk VA was talking about
the Superdog when I kind of gave that
quick
um rundown of what happened with it it's
not like the super dog was a pure Super
Skunk by chem dog
there were steps involved
right so we never actually like you know
maybe if we were doing it 10 years later
we would have just you know used some
STS or something and reversed one on to
the other
but that's not how it happened
right so we don't know what but here's
the thing right is that I have a theory
and I'll I'll just say this okay and and
like this and this is where like talking
about history gets really delicate
because
you know you you try to tell history and
there's history and there's known and
there's unknown and there's people that
get attached to certain stories and so I
start talking about this and then people
are going to be like oh people are
people are saying you know Francis not
so dog is saying that like uh
um that Greg is a liar
that it's that that I don't believe his
story and that's not what I'm saying
um you know chem dog two of my all-time
favorite plants uh the chem 91 and the
chemd came out of either you know his
room or his efforts right so I'm
amazingly grateful for that right
but you also got to remember and think
back to your own experiences say he pops
this stuff when he's 17.
how on it were you between 17 and 22 23.
you know what I'm saying yeah like not
very own it at all not very honored at
all and so could he honestly believe
that it's all the same 13 seeds
absolutely could they be they could but
I have a hard time believing it unless
there's multiple moms and dads involved
right
um but you know there's also like
there's some chemd fakes out there which
has caused its own a whole set of series
and I've battled with people on it so I
don't know if we really want to get into
that on this thing but
the problem with the chemd fakes is that
they all seem to originate from Greg and
so I've had this thought that it's
possible that some of those seeds were
either
um you remember how I told you when we
the for the whole first idea of the
super dog was the Super Skunk
accidentally hermed on the chems and he
was all excited about it
what if some of that stuff was just seed
from that accident
what if what if it just ended up he had
a box of different seeds and some of it
got into a different labeling and he
thought it was this and it was this I
don't know it's all supposition right I
just know that the 91 and the one and
the 4 and the D are vastly different
than one another
yeah look I have to admit I've always
been a bit uncomfortable about the one
especially it's just so left of field
yeah and it just it it it the the way
you know and it's like the the D is like
a short stocky Afghan thing you know
that takes nine weeks the one and the
four take 12 or 13 weeks and are big
stretchy long running colas that throw
bats the 91 is like this mutant
um old Afghan leafy looking thing you
know
um they just have very very different
looks and their kids look very different
and you know I don't know that I'm not
sitting here saying anyone's wrong
because I don't know that I'm right
I'm just saying observationally I see
things that make me question
yeah of course and look I I there's so
much more I want to ask you about this
but I think we'll we'll have to save it
for a part two otherwise we'll end up
going down this uh Rabbit Hole forever
but while we're talking about the actual
lineage of things I'm sure you've
noticed uh Caleb's put up a post that
he's done this F1 Durban reversal my
question is do you suspect he's gonna
find anything similar to cookies in the
dirt cross OG hybrids he's done
so there's there's some interesting
stuff in all that
um that probably if we want to wrap this
up in the next few minutes I'll keep it
pretty short and sweet
um but there you know he is uh he has
very different thoughts after after
doing it than he did in the beginning
um I gave him the FlowRider
to use in that in that cross
um I got the flow right the only the
flow writer is an OG I don't know it
could be you know
um I don't know if that's its first name
or you know it's it's it's it's got name
changed or whatever but what I do know
is that the person that the cookie
accident happened
um that's the Kush that he had he gave
it to me directly in o4
um so I am absolutely convinced that
that's the cushion cookie
um so I gave him
um that cut so that he could add it into
the F1 derb room and we could see what
what happened
um I think that cookie was a multi-stage
accident
and uh I um
we could talk about that but that
probably would have to be a part two
uh yeah that would might have to be a
part two look we're we're definitely
gonna have to do it and I do want to be
conscious of your time because I've
already taken up the best part of four
hours so how about uh we do one more
question before we get on to the quick
fire and then we'll we'll definitely
have to do a part two but questions
specifically I I was thinking about you
and I was like oh I'm this is actually a
perfect one for not so dog
um I you know when we think about modern
breeding we have this sort of more
analytical more scientific approach
these days compared to in the past when
it was arguably a bit more intuitive you
know people were still using science but
you know generally speaking education
was less widespread and when I think of
that sort of breeding I think of people
like DJ Short
and I wonder
if DJ Short existed in today's climate
as a fledgling breeder and expressed
some of the zany some of the more wacky
ideas at least by modern standards that
he has in the past do you think there
would he would get a reception or do you
think he would be sort of laughed out
you know like because it feels like
we've come so far with our understanding
of genetics that maybe we might be at
risk of losing some of the more left of
field ideas what's your thought you
gotta realize that most people breeding
or breeding for money
so we haven't really Advanced all that
far in the sense that and I I know and
I'm painting a broad brush so there's
plenty there's people out there with
passion there's people out there doing
you know microbreedings of their own
stuff and all that so I'm not trying to
lump it in I'm just trying to talk about
like the commercial aspect of breeding
right at this particular moment
I don't think we're actually doing very
much in the way of breeding right now
there are some people like Fletcher or
CSI or different people doing some like
multi-stage breeding I think most of the
game is take this reverse it onto a
bunch of well-known Cuts sell
and it's just a one-off and that's it
right
so DJ is interesting in that if you
believe his story
he basically created everything out of
four plants
right he had like an Afghan he had like
a uh he had a couple different kinds he
had a wahawkin that he crossed to uh to
a tie that he called juicy fruit and he
had an organ purple tie and that's
basically it
and so to me I don't think DJ has like a
bunch of different lines I think he has
like one line that he's pulled different
Expressions out of and then bred with
those expressions if that makes sense
so
um and you know I I think he probably
bottlenecks stuff accidentally early on
too
and um
you know I think that the the there's a
lot of cool breeding that's going on
right now it's just not for sale dude
right like people that are making things
for SK sale are like okay so I'm gonna
take this Lemon Cherry gelato and I'm
gonna cross it to Skittles and then I'm
gonna cross it back to thin mint and
then here you go
right when you're trying to breed and
even if you're somebody doing
experiments like let's let's talk about
uh CSI for a second again right he does
you know reproductions of you know pine
tar kush or or deep chunk or Burmese or
these different things or Sterling skunk
right he does open pollinations he does
that he did the ml project he does all
that kind of stuff but that stuff's not
as bread and butter
like his bread and butter is like you
know Mendo P hybrids and Skittles
hybrids and Crossing this by this he has
to make enough popular stuff right to
fund the weird [ __ ]
that might not have too much commercial
value but still important to make seed
of and half
does that make sense certainly I
remember Bodhi expressing a similar
Point saying a lot of the stuff he
offers is not his true passion it's to
pay the bills and then on the side he
can do the passion projects you know
this might be a little good segue but
are you familiar with the actor Michael
Kane oh yeah brilliant so I watched you
could probably watch it on YouTube
there's this there's this thing that he
gave where he he got this award and he
gave this speech and it very much made
me feel like it was about breeding even
though it was about acting and he
basically said look when you're young
and you're an actor and you're poor you
take any work you can get
right doesn't matter how crappy it is
you just take it because you need a job
and then if you do a good job in those
things maybe you get some bigger roles
and you're still just taking whatever's
on offer and he goes and then
you get to a point in life where maybe
if you've been successful enough you've
got some Blockbusters you've got some
big hits you've got some stuff going on
maybe you can take a risk on a passion
project or something that really makes
you feel good
but he's like then you have to balance
that with some big screen production
because you're still trying to have a
career
right so he goes when you're in the
movies maybe every once in a long while
you get to really follow your passion
when mostly you're just trying to do
good work along the way and stay afloat
yeah huge parallels
right and so that's kind of what I was
just talking about is like like you were
saying with me talking to Bodhi or what
I was just mentioning about CSI is like
in order for him to do these open
pollinations in order for Bodhi to mess
around with some like weird-ass sativas
he has to release some popular stuff
that's going to pay the bills
yeah
you have to blend it right going out on
a limb and making a that that's what's
so cool about being a private breeder
dude is you can literally do whatever
the [ __ ] you want
when you don't have to worry about
making money off it
it can have Herms it cannot yield well
it can have all these problems it
doesn't matter you're still you're still
doing it for you or your friends and
you're going to look through it and if
you find good weed you're happy
but if you're gonna breed and you're
gonna sell
right then you have to take some
commercial aspects of that into
consideration
and and so when you look at when you
look at people right like
um and I'm not gonna like I'm not trying
to call anybody out here by any means
but you remember how I was speaking
about how a lot of famous people get
into breeding and they kind of breed
with what made them famous
right like NorCal icmag breeds a lot
with OG KB because it made him famous
um you know swamp boys did a ton with TK
because that was kind of their bread and
butter
skunk VA stays pretty close to the chem
family of things
right and these aren't disses on them
but imagine if skunk VA was like hey I
got this weird loation sativa from Bodhi
and I got this other African thing and
I'm gonna start doing these weird
sativas that I'm not associated with
and he puts in all this time and he puts
in all this money and he puts in all
this effort and then it sells like [ __ ]
and he's stuck with like 10 000 seats
there's a commercial aspect to it right
where you're trying to figure out what
and and I can tie that back in so like
even if I'm not talking about breeding
even if I'm just talking about like like
uh preserving a large collection of moms
or something like that you still need to
do enough stuff that's commercially
viable
that you can fund your passion
yeah it's interesting it's like it's
almost like um you know to be
commercially successful it almost forces
you to stay in your own lane
yeah it does it limits you and then you
get known it's like um you know like
take going back into acting right I'll
use another example
I remember watching Jackie Chan give an
interview on one of the stupid late
night talk shows or something and they
were talking about did he ever want to
Branch out and he looks right at the
camera and he goes I would love to
Branch out he goes
they want to see me do martial arts and
be funny they don't want to see me in a
tender romantic comedy with Jennifer
Aniston would I do it sure it'd be kind
of fun do they want to cast me in it no
they want Hugh Grant
they want you know
um they want bread pit
they want Leonardo DiCaprio
they don't want me I can be in a buddy
movie I can be in a martial arts movie I
can be in a comedy maybe but I can't be
in a romance or a drama that's not where
they want to cast me
and I think breeding has parallels to
that like you you get known for what
you're known for and it's hard to Branch
out
and if you are going to Branch out what
happens if it's a total flop
yeah I agree and look this perfect segue
this is why we need to all give credit
to Berner for casting Bodhi as the head
of genetics you know he's given Jackie
Chan the role in the the dramatic
Thriller man I will say you know uh
Bodhi was at the party we just had you
know and uh he's my buddy
uh I will say that um him and Berner
trying to collab I don't know if it went
well for either one of them in my
opinion
a very different fan bases
I just I hope it transpires through you
know he said he's
um you know trying to get some cool
stuff on their menus and there's nothing
more I'd love to see than for that to
work out
I understand why he did it and I don't
even disagree with his reasoning
right I'm just saying that like for a
lot of Bodhi fans they look at burner
and cookies as sort of the evil empire
yeah true true but yeah I guess I think
of it as like I think his intentions are
coming for what he hopes is best for the
plant
oh he's a sweet man he absolutely he's
not he's not thinking of it in some kind
of like selfish or negative light I just
mean that like
you know it's a good example of stepping
out of your lane and he had a certain
Lane with people and he you know he
stepped out of it it was probably
stepping out with Bodhi but with with
Berner but you know those guys they
desperately need people that are
different breeders than
um than they've been currently working
with
they have cookie themselves has stayed
way way too much in their own little
stream
and it's way too inbred in there and so
they definitely need to bring people in
that can widen that pool
because that you've kind of gone
anywhere you could have possibly gone in
that tiny little shallow in that shallow
end yeah yeah I definitely can say we
are coming from and I think this is
another one where we could we could
probably spend a whole hour talking
about this so we'll we'll definitely
touch back on this one in part two but
we could my phone is gonna die too so
like uh this four hours or whatever is
like no I'm at like eight percent so
we're probably gonna have to cut it off
regardless because uh it's gonna die and
I'm not gonna be able to chat
yeah no worries all right we'll we'll
shorten the final five to the the quick
three then quickly so I'd love to know
what's the most memorable experience
with cannabis you've ever had
the most memorable experience with
cannabis I've ever had
um
when I first realized how powerful Hayes
was
uh I kept going out to Amsterdam and I
kind of thought their weed was bunk
compared to ours to some degree
and then I met one of Neville's friends
who grew for him and then they sold the
weed to the coffee shops he's still
around his name's Steve and um I smoked
some Neville's Haze
just a little Pinner uh and a by Pinner
for people that don't know it's just a
skinny joint
between me and my buddy who I went out
there with and Steve
we smoked that joint and I felt
soaring high
psychedelic high like I was tripping
High to the point where when I walked
out of his flat as a you know I was
probably 24 then or 26 then or something
I like held on to the railing so I could
walk down the steps
and that was the first time that I
realized that maybe some of those
Old-Timers talking about how like some
of those sativas had this like soaring
psychedelic disassociative Speedy High
which I kind of thought they were lying
about I realized it could be true
and I I think that that Neville's Haze
cut that still exists is very very
different than most weed that's out
there and I would put it up as one of my
probably my most memorable wheat
experience
wow you got me jealous I'm gonna have to
go hunt for it but on to the next
question which is I'm going to drop you
off on a desert island and you can take
three strains with you there could be
packs of seeds if you want to do some
breeding or they could just be clones
and you know somehow on this island
you've got the resources to grow them
forever what are you taking with you
oh my gosh uh I'm gonna take the LA
I'm gonna take the chem 91
and I'm going to take an nl5 Haze
that's a nice balance I can get behind
that that's that's good you're not
spreading yourself too thin in one area
I dig that so final question we'd love
to ask everyone at least on their first
appearance
I've got a time machine for you you can
go back anywhere Anytime Anyplace
presumably to collect some cannabis
either cuttings or seeds where are you
going to go back to what are you going
to get
oh absolutely I would go probably to
and I would buy everything from Super
sativa seed club and Neville seed bank
that is a brilliant answer
absolutely what that's absolutely what I
would do and in line with the earlier
answer I guess we'll try to grab like 50
of each seed
yeah it would be it would be a lot do
you know that that in like 89 90 that
Neville literally sold 50 packs of maple
leaf Indica the same exact
um seed batch that he found all of the
Finos that he used to make super skunk
and all that other stuff with oh yeah
yeah he called you can look it up it's
in his book it's called Original Afghan
mix
and it was just extra seed that he had
that uh that uh Jim Ortega had given him
so I would absolutely go back to 89 or
90 and I would buy both of those
companies a lot of their stuff
and I would have real nl1 real nl2 real
nl5 Haze
um just all that and just grow it out
and see it for myself
that is beautiful I love that that's uh
one I'm definitely gonna have to
consider for my own pick should I ever
find said time machine so I think that
just about brings us to the Ender are
there any general comments or shout outs
you wanted to make
uh the only the only General comments or
shout outs that I would make is that
um
you know to P if anyone out there is
thinking about breeding
um you know or or saving clones or you
know
don't do it based on anything more than
like pick things that you love
right that you that personally Vibe well
with you try to save a couple you don't
have to save everything try to save a
couple of things if you can find some
old and unpopular stuff that maybe you
care about a bunch everybody can pitch
in a little bit and this person can hold
two or three here and this person can
hold five and this person can hold one
but every little bit that you hold of
that 80s or 90s or early 2000s era is a
gem
and then if you're going to get into
breeding
um try to like I said try to find two
plants or two lines that you have an
idea that you could get both traits into
the same line and breed for what you
like because there's not enough of
breeding for what you like there's
breeding for what other people might
like so you know breed for what you like
and then if nobody else likes it at
least you do
brilliant answers definitely some
sentiments I can Echo myself you know
coming from that passion side of things
it'll be much more likely for you to be
successful than if you just you know
trying to slap two things together that
you think will sell so once again a huge
shout out to the weed historian weed
librarian originator of the Mendo perps
one half of the breeder Syndicate so
much more I don't want to sell him short
huge thank you for coming on the show
not so dog
yeah man I I appreciate your time as
well and uh I hope everybody enjoyed it
so there you have it friends what do you
think the end of the second installment
for our Mammoth episode with not so dogs
huge shout out to the man himself we are
incredibly grateful to have you bye
I think we might have to get him back
very soon for a follow-up
we had such a good time chatting with
him it just makes sense
as usual we want to give a massive shout
out to all those who support the show
huge shout out to the patreon gang we
love you so much they've heard this one
a few weeks before you have at least if
you want to get early access to episodes
check out the patreon at
www.patreon.com forward slash the
podcast
likewise a huge shout out to our amazing
sponsors if you want to help support the
show please go check out our sponsors it
helps them it helps us massive massive
shout out to the crude Organics alive we
love their dry powdered organic
fertilizers making growing in soil easy
from Veg to transition to bloom any sort
of deficiency any funny situation you
find yourself in there got organic
nutrients that will help you get out of
it help your plant power ahead to be the
best you've ever had to date if you
would like to step into the world of
Organics but take out all the guessworks
check out Organics alive
seats here now best seed bank in the
industry guarantee on satisfaction not
just germination why would you go
anywhere else pulse sensors best sensors
in the game they've just launched their
new unit the pulse Hub and all in one
integrated unit for you to keep your
Gardens parameters in check and pumping
on all cylinders thank you so much Paul
sensors
and last but not least copper biological
systems all the best pest and Predator
technology if you want to keep your
garden happy healthy Pest and pathogen
free check them out guys after param
spydex of Idols two Staples in any
Garden that's looking to be optimized
and putting out the highest quality crop
to date huge thank you again Copa
biological systems
That Just About Does it for this episode
my friends
we'll see you for the next one
thanks so much for joining us
we'll see you
[Music]