foreign
[Applause]
[Music]
welcome to the next episode of the
podcast a cannabis podcast for budding
enthusiasts as always you're joined by
your host hippie days here from the
upside down libraries and as always we
couldn't make these episodes happen
without the help from our sponsors seeds
here now number one seed bank in the
industry all the hottest breeders the
latest drops and a guarantee on
satisfaction not just germination why
would you go anywhere else they
guarantee you'll be happy with the end
results to grow what more could you want
well you need to make sure that your
Harvest is on point and to do that you
want to make sure that your garden is
happy healthy test and pathogen free and
in order to do that you need to check
out our buddies at coppet biological
systems these guys have all the best
predators in the game from the afip RM
if you've got aphids to the spider if
you've got spider mites get it now guys
keep your garden pumping on all Pistons
Pest and pathogen free trust me guys
nothing better have known you God McLean
[Music]
as always shout out to our friends down
under holding down the fort organic
gardening solutions for all your organic
gardening needs best soil in the game is
what I use check them out or if you're
looking for some of my genetics go to
Top Shelf sea Bank they've got a great
range of both domestic and international
breeders go check them out if you're
after some of my work
[Music]
and last but not least huge shout out to
the patreon gang you guys are truly the
lifeblood of the show Without You
episodes could not happen if you're
interested in helping support the show
all while getting early access to
episodes unheard additional content
prizes and giveaways check out the
patreon
we just gave away 30 packs of hash plant
13 across to the puck back cross one
from crickets and cicada they were
generous enough to donate it to us and
our fans got those for free
[Music]
go check out patreon today guys
on this episode we're lucky to be joined
by gas the Swami Organics system
here to talk breeding history
plans for the future
and so much more
without further ado
[Music]
let's get into it
alrighty friends we're back for another
one and on this one we are joined by The
Man Behind Swami organic seeds the old
school genetic Guru himself gas thanks
so much for joining us today hey how are
you doing man
I'm doing well my friend the the first
question we love to ask our guests what
have you been smoking on lately well you
know I just had some nl5as
along with the Fosters bro
God that's so funny that you bring up
The Fosters it's like uh I don't know if
you know this but like it's it's not
really sold in Australia but it's sold
everywhere outside of Australia
yeah I'm not I'm not a real big fan of
it but you know I just there it was you
know I appreciate it you know putting in
the uh the effort for the Australian
chat I love it okay and it's it's so
interesting that you mentioned that
you're smoking the nl5 haze you know
it's uh such a sort of trending strain
at the moment how would you describe the
effect of that
well it just depends on who you are
really because it's quite introspective
you know
um I wouldn't recommend it for anybody
with anxiety issues I wouldn't recommend
it for anybody
who has any kind of bipolar or mental
disorders or anything like that because
it can take a normal human being and
turn them into a freaking nut in a in
seconds they'll they'll be walking
through glass they'll be dry they'll be
crashing the ditch you know they'll
forget to water the dog they'll it's
just one of those things and that's why
that the warning is still there you know
and it's I don't find it extremely
comfortable to smoke it but I'll take a
poll here and there you know just it's
it's a it's a good tasking thing if you
don't get too far into it you know
laughs
okay interesting yeah I know that for a
number of years I certainly really
couldn't go near some of the strongest
sativas I enjoy nowadays
um and I I think that in part that was
probably because I had a lot of sort of
general anxiety at that time
but interesting nowadays it's sort of
one of those things I gravitate to more
so it's it's funny I imagine having a
conversation with myself you know five
ten years ago and like you couldn't pay
me to smoke
right and and you you really hit the
nail on the head right there it's it's a
state of mind
it you know I can smoke anything
you know around the globe oh no I'm
there's nothing to be afraid of
ever
it's all what Society put there oh it's
illegal oh no it's illegal so
automatically your brain's set up for
failure you know
so if you avoid those those thought
processes of of
oppressing nature then you're gonna do
well you're gonna do way better and then
you can do anything in the world you
know smoke anything smoke smoke all the
Highland ties smoke all the Africans
yeah it's going to give you some anxiety
but you know if you're skilled at what
you do you're gonna find a way to deal
with it and you're going to go out and
put that to use you know
yeah that's interesting like yeah
finding a way to make it work for you I
certainly can jive with that I would be
interested to know because I was I was
pondering this last night as I was
writing some questions for our chat I've
spoken to a few people who have sort of
touched on this idea but never fully
gone there so I wanted to ask you
specifically do you think nl5 Haze is
one of if not the ultimate expression of
cannabis no
it's just one of those things that made
its way into history at a time when uh
the DEA was really harsh on on everybody
in the United States you know and how
Neville introduced the nlives there and
all that to us over here in the United
States that really changed the game over
here I grew up in the Pacific Northwest
I know what roadkill skunk was I know we
were buying bags in Northern Lights
where you know it was all here but what
dominated everything here was killer
green butt it sidelined in all five Haze
and anything that came around you know
because all the local Growers are
growing this Puget North you know this
this Puget weed whatever the hell that
was
but it's it's it's just different it's
totally different
I've been wondering this myself for the
past week or so is killer green but the
same as Kentucky Bluegrass you know I
just don't know because it's possible
that somebody actually did take
something out of the Pacific Northwest
back then but when we were growing up as
kids it was everywhere that's all you
had that was all you bought everybody
was growing it it was everywhere and it
had a really pungent Indica kind of it
was it reminded me of California Orange
quite a bit
you know but it had more of a garlic
thing going on and it's very well could
be uh in our lines and in that killer
green Bud too my parents knew Steve
Murphy too oh okay you think maybe it
comes from Steve Murphy I don't know you
know he what he gave people it spread
around and the Imports had a lot to do
with it too because the Brotherhood
Imports were coming up there you know my
parents had Panama Colombian Thai stick
I remember being in fifth grade and
unraveling
the the twine off the Thai stick man you
know we smoked that [ __ ] and
oh boy I thought I was in trouble for
the next Universe you know oh man I
think everyone listening to this right
now is a little bit collectively jealous
of your childhood after hearing that
well it was my parents that had a lot to
do with it I was born into the culture
you know my dad unloaded tankers of a
Mexican weed in North Hollywood in 1966
at 18 years old and got paid by my
grandpa to do it so it's just been
something that was in the family for a
long time just working with the biker
side of the the gig the Brotherhood of
Euro love what people don't realize is
they were bikers and Surfers and they'd
made a pact
to work with each other not work against
each other
so that's what they call the Brotherhood
of eternal love
yeah often we hear Hell's Angels thrown
around do you think that it was like
sort of them and then a group of hippies
and they combined together and then that
made the Brotherhood
it was up in the Pacific Northwest it
was specifically the bandito's faction
of the Hell's Angels yes
you know many nights I'd wake up when I
was a kid and they just all roll out
there you know 300 strongest and fire
off all their oozies and just just leave
you know but that's who brought us the
Roadkill
that's who brought the roadkill out to
us and I remember seeing it growing when
you know in 1981 82 I remember watering
the plants I remember picking buds off
the plants and taking them to school and
smoking them with my friends you know
that's how I got busted with this stuff
oh wow wow so many Avenues we're gonna
have to loot back on I guess before we
get into the roadkill skunk too much
because I would love to pick your brain
on it I just wanted to quickly ask the
KGB the killer green Bud any speculation
as to what the genetics might have been
it was in Afghani probably a Mexican
because you know they're or Colombian I
would say too
you know
because there was a lot of Colombian
Imports most of the herb that was coming
in back then in the late 70s was
Colombian
Brown dark black Colombian
cheap plentiful
fat sacks
good weed
yeah wow and just because I'm a little
out of touch with the timeline was this
before like the commercial release of
skunk one
oh yeah absolutely you know I I hadn't I
never heard a skunk one until probably
1987 or 88. and by then I was already
incarcer had already gone through the
ringer with roadkill you know and when
skunk one came out and I smelled it and
I grew it and I looked at it man
I thought it was a joke you know because
it wasn't skunk at all it was just a
plant that seemed to melt under every
condition that we put it in it would
melt in the frost it would melt in the
heat it would melt and just melt you
know these these weren't
these were at the Pacific Northwest
genetics that we knew
yeah I've never been a fan and still not
it's just not a real story so what what
is the rks to you is it like a pure
Afghani how would you describe it
it was probably yeah
the HC says it was a pure Afghani and I
believe him because everything he told
me corresponds to timeline that my
parents were associated with this gig
so I trust what he's saying and I would
say he's probably right that it's a pure
Afghani but it could have an import in
it
we don't know when I was growing those
plants in 81
they were thin okay they were thin Leaf
they weren't wide fat leaves and they
would get black and green when the cold
hit them lots of purple in the buds you
know uh more of a Christmas tree Indica
profile like if you look at the old
catalogs the old indicators they looked
a lot like that it was probably a Hindu
one of the things we've heard from other
people who have come on the show is
obviously they're not stating it with
certainty but they've said you know
there might have been a few things that
had that Aroma and you know not just one
specific clone where do you sit on that
one
absolutely you know if I've I've grown
just about everything from around the
world you know
um and not just one or two at a time I
grow a bunch and um I've seen a lot of
the that skunk pop up in a lot of
different things but what I see it pop
up in most is uh unmolested Hindu type
stuff you know the higher altitude
Afghani Pakistan Hindu stuff just that's
where I see it yeah okay and you know
people often say that the reason why
roadkill disappeared was because people
were getting busted is is that your
thoughts on why we sort of saw it vanish
um it's probably at least 70 to 80
percent of the reason yeah
because it was so loud it was so stinky
man you were just done you're done
you're not getting away you know they're
gonna track you down
percent
yeah it was impossible it really was it
was quite difficult
yeah look I can only imagine pre-carbon
filters the anxiety level must have been
through the roof well it I got cracked I
did two weeks in juvie for it
so you know and we did know Growers that
were getting cracked and and you'd be
driving down the street and smell it you
know
you just knew that house right there you
so we we've seen like a huge over the
past probably three four years now this
huge Resurgence in people looking for
the roadkill skunk do you think it's the
type of thing where we will ever find it
again and if we do would you think we
should try to breed it from scratch
again or go back on Old seeds and try to
hunt it through that
well I've done both I've I've I have a
five-year rks project going now and
we're all just about done with it
actually
and um we looked at a lot of stuff man
we went through a lot of things a lot of
Old Land races a lot of old types uh
and it just boiled back down to the
original lines
it really did you know so
but of course I had to outcross to get
it back you know I'm using
and 85 humble roadkill that was taken to
Mexico in 1985 dude stopped by Humboldt
bought a bag went straight to Mexico
gave it to his sister
smoked the weed took the seeds out of it
gave it to her local farmer who's you
know doing exports
and he crossed it to that type which was
a European type Uruapan
it's outside of uh
oh man I forget but anyway
um it's a good reason for growing good
herb and it's noted for that
the seeds were sent back in 2017 and I
only got two males they were pretty big
yeah so you know so I figured I'd just
cross up outcross them to my oldest
types in the hopes that I could grab
that genotype in there somehow by waking
it up with these old types
you know with Mr Green jeans cherry bomb
with Coots blue Orca and and with this
purple Zeb which had blue mystic in it
and the purple roadkill skunk in there
you know and that one was pretty good
but that was more of a poly from Nirvana
than just an old unmolested type
you know and it did it worked but it
wasn't
I I had to go through a lot of seeds so
I did F2 of the blue Orca by the 85
roadkill Uruapan
and just search through massively of
those and we found what we were looking
for was going Yep this is it this what
it looks like this is what it smells
like let's hope that if we cross it back
to one of these 63 breeder packs that HC
gave me
that we can wake up that genotype and
that's all we got man
honestly
unless you're gonna go out there in the
world and go search for unmolested types
for that skunk phenotype and then bring
those types back to the United States
and sit there and work and work them and
work them and work them together
it's just nobody's ever going to find
that you know
unless they don't unless they don't have
it
you know
yeah it it's interesting because that
that sounds like it could well be a nice
recipe for success and we've heard other
people sort of use alternative routes
and looking through what they consider
to maybe be like really Early Skunk
releases I guess I'd be interested in
hearing do you know a lot of people say
that at a certain point pretty early on
in the grand scheme of things Sam Reddit
from stinky to Sweet skunk do you think
there ever was a stinky that's what they
say but I just don't I think sounds
[ __ ] man I think that guy's just
[ __ ] dude everything he said he tried to
sell out the industry you know he's a
known liar I mean he all his stories
don't match anybody else's stories
there's people that were here there's
people that were there and everything he
says he can just contradict everything
man you know what I mean David Watson is
a douche man and that's that's I said
that okay it's all right anyway I don't
believe him I think it's [ __ ] you
know because I've seen a lot of types
man you know I I know what Colombian
does I know what ties do you know I've
worked almost every damn tie yeah so
like to confirm do you think like it
always was sweet like there was never
this rks prior to the Sweet skunk it
don't have nothing to do with it nothing
to do with it at all none of that it was
it's just [ __ ]
if he got a hold of it and bred that out
of it he had nothing to do with it
yeah I guess I still see where you're
coming from yeah even if he did make the
sweet from the rotten he it's sort of by
itself saying he didn't make the rotten
it was just another claim to fame you
know people want to just
jump on top and jump on a bandwagon and
be the one and the only to have the one
and the only whatever it is
you know
either you have it or you don't
and it
it's a pig with lipstick or it's the
real thing man you know okay
um so I'd be interested to to hear your
thoughts on I mean you sort of just
touched on Sam and mentioned you're
you're not a fan I'd love to hear your
thoughts on Neville because he's someone
who more recently we've been hearing
thoughts about well I respect Neville
yeah I respect Neville hell yeah because
he was actually a breeder he bred dogs
before he bred cannabis so that gives
him authenticity
okay he's not some dude that just woke
up dude I'm gonna be a breeder and open
the same company you know cat had an
idea and Cat did it
you know he he's not the father of
modern breeding for no reason at all
yeah he really was great you know so he
knew what he was looking for they say
Neville had the eye you know what I mean
when you when they say yeah he's got the
eye
if you got the eye you got the eye you
know what you're looking for you see it
you know it's they're they're smiling
compared to the ones over here that are
frowning you know you know when you see
it so Neville had the eye
you know so he was really good at making
selections like like I am or like a lot
of other breeders are too
you know they see it they see the hybrid
potential they see the the Vigor they
know what they're looking for
you know and he knew what he was looking
for
and yeah he he he took it to the top
didn't he
yeah definitely definitely I mean I
certainly regard him like yourself as
the the father of modern braiding I
guess I'd be interested to ask some
guests in the past have mentioned that
through having known him more closely on
a personal level or maybe friends of
that he might be one of those people
where you need to do a little bit of
separating of the uh the art and the
artist so to speak have you ever heard
anything like that like you know he's a
great breeder but maybe there was some
character flaws any thoughts on that at
all
well I talked to his best friend every
day you know and he's online now because
he just resurfaced out of the woodwork
from being you know these guys were
persecuted internationally
they'd had they were sought after for a
long time
by you know
and um so people just get tired of it
they get tired of hiding they get tired
of seeing all this [ __ ] and they
want to pop out of the woodwork and say
hey no that didn't happen so before
Neville died
he said he told Dwight find me
because I'm doing what he was doing I'm
doing what Neville was doing I'm
focusing on on breeding not magazine
culture
you know I'm not I'm not my head isn't
in magazine culture and capitalism and
trying to be the next big thing my
head's in breeding and the fascination
that lies in that
you know so anyway when I posted my back
Cross of the Neville uh nlfi by the 88
5 Hayes Neville saw it and he's like oh
that's it right there in the end before
he died he pointed Dwight in my
direction and we got in contact with
each other and so we've been
communicating each other and sharing
projects and doing things with Neville's
last works
you know like the Outback Haze and
Neville's Kush and a couple other things
you know
um wow would I be able to pull you up
for a quick second and ask you about
some of those varieties because I had
seen the Outback Hayes mention never
heard of Neville's Kush I'd love to hear
a little more
well here's the thing about the
Neville's Kush is we don't know what the
lineage is is because Neville was really
sick at the time
and he didn't want to bug him you know
hey man what's this
you know so we don't know but never
wanted a Kush because that's what
everybody was doing in the game so he
said hey I want to make one too so he
did
and yeah Dwight has those
and yeah he's he's in with the family
the the Neville family is is uh is is
I I can't talk about it too much okay I
could just say that things are happening
that's all just just for clarification
say are we talking about like his
extended friends or like his literal
family are sort of doing stuff with his
literal family family and friends ah
that that's exciting he had a son you
know
and he's interested
wow that would be cool I know that just
out of like you know being Australian I
tried to sort of track him down many
many years ago and it was very hard but
I had always hoped that some news like
this would sort of come out of the
Woodworks
oh there's a lot going on man but I
can't talk about it you know it's not my
position but if you interviewed Dwight
you should he might he might talk about
some of that you know what I mean I
can't I can't overstep my boundaries and
and
just you know give that information out
sure yeah but yeah you know it's it's
it's alive wow that's that's really
exciting and and just to loop back
before we move on the Outback Hayes I
think it's one that people are still
sort of learning about it's not super
well known are you able to tell us
anything at all about that in terms of
maybe the genetics or what it's similar
to at least
well you know it says it's 21 33 and and
hampi's tie
you know whatever tie that was we don't
know
but
you look at Thailand and you look at the
types in Thailand and for thousands of
years it was the squirrel tail type you
know
that it was held by Kings and
distributed throughout the regions by
the people that held that type and
that's that's the esan province type the
Thai stick
those types
but there were other types of course
that were you know like the red tie the
blue tie the blah blah blah blah tie the
chocolate tie you know these were
developed for export
yeah not not the red but the chocolate
and the in the Thai stick that was all
that was all export those were export
crops
but they were based off of the squirrel
tail variety
and there's like three or four or five
different phenotypes of this squirrel
tail tie and I think that's probably
what it is it's it's a squirrel tail
variety
and Neville liked it
you know so I used it so he put it in
there and there's probably a tie in the
haze so it it matches up great
you know wow and I'm I'm feeling a bit
out of my depth right now you you said I
think you said 21 cross 33 sorry what
were those cultivars that was his Haze
ah yeah like the numbered cutting
there's photographs of if you look I can
find photographs of them and they look
nice you know they're like wow that's a
nice looking Haze man yeah wow nice and
for some reason I thought when you said
the 21 I was like is he talking about
Mueller Madness because I think there's
a famous 21 cutting of malam or
something yeah I grew those that
flowering time was too long man what
Neville said sent Dwight his branch of
the Outback he also gave it to other
people connoisseur
you know uh and a couple other guys
but they they have different lines or
different branches of the word so each
one of these guys that have a different
branch of his Outback work have
different you know they've put their own
selections on it in their own IBL Elling
of it and have made it what it is in
their own selections so Dwight's is
different than connoisseurs and and it's
different than whatever whoever else has
it in San Francisco and you know
so the phenotypic
variations are going to vary depending
on what breeder gets it you know what
I'm saying
yeah okay so I've already you know like
like how I got a hold of the nl2 the R2
you know
my selections were different than than
Dwight's selections so right there our
line goes in two directions
you know so if I keep going down my my
path my mind is going to be totally
different than his in three or four
generations even though it's a 30-year
ideal and how would you describe your
nl2 I've been lucky enough to try uh
bodhi's thin Leaf nl2 but I've never
tried the more Indica leaning phenotypes
what's your thoughts on the line in
general
this is the uh I got this line from from
Dwight it's the uh the R2 it's it's
popular up in Northern Ontario it's a
30-year IBL of the nl2 that they did
Outdoors they had privacy and they had a
lot of space and they had a lot of room
to do a lot of selections so they really
did a good job on selecting for
phenotypes that finished early with a
nice cush profile you know
um
they're fast and they're resonance
and they withstand the cold pretty great
um R2 means Ron had two seats whoever
honest that's a great name and it was
rumor that there's skunk one in it but
we don't know
you know
it looks like nl2 it behaves like an nl2
you know cushy because that's what nl2
is it's nl1 by Neville's Kush ah and and
do you see any real sativa in there at
all or no
very very little just enough to make it
interesting you know how most Afghan
dominant types are with that one sativa
in it you know yeah I I think that was
largely the sentiment body echoed when I
was talking to him he was like oh you
know this was just one plan out of God
knows how many that had a little bit of
a thinner leaf and uh just melted your
face the highest lovely stuff oh I like
it it's great I smoked the hell out of
it it reminds me of a good Williams
Wonder you know nice rounded nice warm
Huggy kind of thing you know
man I love that you just said that
Williams Wonder is one of my super
nostalgic strains I love and not enough
people have had experience with it I
feel like
yeah it's a it's a good one huh nice and
Huggy yeah I think I think it was like
the first weed I ever tried where I was
like oh this is kind of like mangoey
passion fruit like getting towards that
passion fruit side of things at least
the sample I tried was
it's the Rooter Alice in it that gives
it that Unique Kind of uh astringent
bitter thing that it has you know what I
mean on top of the suite that The
Afghani has and do you know anything
about it like I think there's some
rumors that it was created in Oregon
somewhere between Williams and wonder
but I've always wondered is do you think
there's any truth to that
I used to think that too and that's what
that was the rumor right but it was
spread by some guy in Indiana and his
name wasn't even William
do you think like that was the case for
a lot of the SSC crosses
I don't know you know when those guys
source that stuff back then they were
getting what they could get you know oh
this is good let's get it you know
Oregon Afghani what the hell was that
you know a Kandahar probably
you know who knows
but back then it was mostly Imports or
what heads had gone and collected from
their travels abroad you know
what I want to know is who sent Mel
Frank the nine seeds of Afghani number
one from Kabul Afghanistan in 1979.
was that was that was that Watson
who did that
yeah that's that's actually a really
good question because I always ask
people who are a bit older like do you
remember distinctly the first time you
saw Afghans rolling into California for
example oh man man they brought him in
in 69. they were going to Afghanistan
and getting the hash they were the
Hawaii was loaded with hash that the
Brotherhood brought there man it was all
Kandahar you know
it was the candors yeah wow and I mean
you you may not have a definitive answer
to this but do you have any guesses as
to what uh Steve Murphy's purest Indica
might have been
Mazar
or or just one of those region you know
it's rumored to be a Mazar it looks like
a Mazar
but it could be a Kabul it could be
anything within that region a bulk
anything Bishop Bergen and who knows you
know we had little knowledge of these
things back then we just knew
Afghanistan
you know
it was only the Brotherhood and people
that kept record of this stuff that came
back and said yeah we got this from
gandhar
you know I think a lot of people looking
at the purest Indica would be quite
impressed it's a very pretty looking
plant and in a lot of ways it sort of
reminds me of deep chunk do you feel
like it's one of the better expressions
of Afghani or like there's actually a
lot that's better it's just less known
no it's the Western world's used to One
Thing Man and it's the combination of a
Mazar and a Hindu in one package it's
simply because of the introduction of
the Northern Lights combination of the
Hindu and the in the Mazar
so people this this Americanized thought
process they love that outboard
exhaust smell on Labor Day you know what
I mean that that greasy sweet
tiny you know they're just used to it so
that's what all through the 80s is what
Americans
the palette was used to
so as we bred with these types into the
early 90s that's what everybody got
that's what everything is now it's all
all Nazar Hindu effect
so unless you really go to
the the specific regions and get those
specific afghanis you're not going to
know what this is all about each one of
these hash plants you know these
families kept these things for hundreds
of years in their family or their tribe
or whatever so they have a unique
special product that's like unique and
special and like food grade super
valuable you know what I mean and it was
only war and stuff like that that
started disrupting that that
you know that heritage
so like I said I've grown a lot of
afghanistans I've probably grown maybe
10 different land race afghanis and
we're talking you know up to 40 plants
every run Outdoors
so I'm looking at the trains of all
these these afghanis and none of them
have that
that modern indoor perfect Cola thing
going on
but all of them have a higher
kind of resin quality a higher terpene
value a higher you know you really your
eyes really light up when you when you
put your senses on
you know like the ball cash for example
that's like one of the best caches in
the world man
Smiley giddy happy just boom yes
you know
like if if all herb could smoke like
that everybody'd be happy you know wow
you've uh you got me thinking I think I
might have some bulk seeds stashed away
maybe I need to get on to them
it's interesting man you know it would
be really cool to do an indoor run of
something like that and you know maybe
hybridize it to a modern type and see
what you can what you can do that's a
popular thing now you know and I don't
know if I'm the cause of that because
that was that's what I started doing so
long ago and then other guys started
doing it another guy started doing it
you know back then it was me snow High
but I just a couple guys doing it
now now we got 500 C 999 seed banks and
they're all like ah trying to be the
next big thing you know it's just funny
yeah certainly and you know what you
just touched on a question I wanted to
bring up which was sort of ties into
both when you were talking about Neville
and he had the eye as well as what you
just mentioned about the types of
crosses you do I noticed both in
Neville's work and with your own that
possibly from my perspective one of the
sort of key components that seems to
have a good chance of success is doing
those raw f1s you know you mentioned
earlier that hybrid Vigor you know you
really can't replicate it do you think
that's one of the keys
there's a method to my madness and it's
not magazine breeding culture okay
I have an agricultural background I went
to college for this stuff
you know before
I was listening to the advice of ask Ed
you know what I'm talking about but
so when I popped out of college I had an
edu I had an agricultural background
when I first started growing cannabis
you know on my own as an adult out of
school and
so I approached it at on that level the
way I cloned the way I did everything
was different than this magazine
Paradigm which seemed to be geared
towards product sales and selling mark
gimmicky this and that
and the way they taught us to do this in
Agri and in the agriculture sense it was
so much more simpler and basic and and
right
you know
it was really that the magazine the
myths
that turned turned me off about all that
because it's just [ __ ] you know you
don't need none of that [ __ ] yeah look
it's interesting that you you bring that
up because I did want to talk about that
and I thought I've been having more
recently I think it's pretty edgy a bit
controversial is that I'm starting to
think maybe High Times was like equally
as damaging for the scene as it was
beneficial
it's it's true but you know
it's like don't shoot the messenger
they gave us a lot during the 70s they
gave us a lot during the 80s but
somewhere in the like 90s it started to
fall off into into glossy marketing
gimmicky [ __ ]
you know
in the 70s they were they were thick fat
informative magazines you know I
remember sitting around reading these
things as a kid when my parents got
would buy them you know so they're
always around I've read every damn High
Times there ever was
you know I've watched the magazine
deteriorate into what it is today is is
what you might say but yeah you're right
it did
in a way lead to a lot of misinformation
and targeting a lot of 18 to 25 year old
males to buy Just Junk
you know yeah that that junk comment you
make really hammers home because I think
at a certain point you see that you know
pay for play advertising and awards and
articles start to creep into the
magazine and for a long time I thought
you know whoever was the editor-in-chief
sort of dropped the ball a bit by you
know we're gonna do a big strain
write-up about this company's blueberry
and it's like what like that's just some
random paid advertisement more or less
and you start seeing it what it is man
you know you start seeing it for what it
is you see right through it yeah I
thought it's interesting and I thought
even more funny was that you know a few
years ago High Times sold and like Danny
Danko and all those people working for
it moved on and now they've started a
new magazine and everyone was like sort
of keen to support it and I was like but
hang on wasn't Danny Danko the
editor-in-chief who allowed all this
sort of faux advertising to occur that's
funny you say that Donnie Danko did a
living next soil article and basically
plagiarized all of her information and
didn't gives any credit you know because
we're the ones where I'm the proprietor
of living organic soil we just dropped
the soil thing in favor of the seed
thing because that really wasn't going
anywhere you know you could teach a man
to fish guess what he fishes for the
rest of his life
so that's what we're doing we weren't
making any money off that and we
couldn't sustain that
so we taught a man to fish a thousand
times
for free
you know the information's out there you
could go and get it you don't need
nothing man your which the secret to all
of this is increasing your negative
ionic surface area in your soil That's
it man
well yeah okay and you think that's why
without people understanding exactly
what you're saying they sort of have
this propensity to want to increase your
cationic exchange capacity
well as Americans and capitalists and
marketing victims they're they're you
know they want instant gratification
because they're Americans they they want
to spray the bug and the bug needs to
die now shh you know so when they apply
these fertilizers they want to see magic
they want to see oh just like in the
picture
if I put more on it'll get bigger more
more you know
it craves electrolytes yeah exactly bro
okay so that's what's going on and it's
it's a big scale and there's a lot of
money to be made millions of dollars you
know and now Monsanto has their hands in
this they own General Hydroponics blah
blah blah blah Miracle Grow blah blah
blah they're not gonna take their dirty
[ __ ] hands out of that scene
they're gonna They're Gonna Keep
marketing they're gonna keep pushing
their [ __ ] poison on us you know
so
you know like I said my information's
free get online and go find it you know
the soil recipes all of that everything
tell you how to do everything for free
what's trippy about it all is is that
the seed company idea because anybody
can do this so that's that's what's
happening anybody is doing this
so it creates a lot of confusion it
creates a lot of you know I don't even
know what this stuff is anymore nowadays
I I totally disregard it and excuse it
as [ __ ] let me pay attention wedding
cake whatever cookies what huh no not
doing it never I haven't even bought
weed out of a dispensary man you know I
smoke black Colombians and Panama's and
just
come on you know
it's it's so I guess I don't need to ask
you what your favorite girl scout
cutting is
no I just don't know
no well I mean it Suddenly It's tap into
that then because I'd love to ask you
you know out of those cool funky you
know black Colombian cool stuff like
that what's a variety that you think
isn't particularly well known but
everyone would like love the [ __ ] out of
it well you know anybody that smokes a
black Colombian would just love it
or it's a Jamaican or a nice African or
a good Thai you know one or two pulls
off this [ __ ] it's all you need man and
you're so
see ya go go do a task bro you know
that's that's awesome and I'd love to
touch on the Colombian a little more
because I think as time's gone by I've
started to realize that when I first got
into genetics so to speak I maybe put a
bit of over emphasis on Thai and
especially with the re-emergence of like
the the black Colombian Haze things like
that I think I'm starting to learn more
from people that like Colombian might be
the unsung hero in a lot of different
things what's your thoughts
I think you're right man I think it's
it's it's
um overlooked a lot
it's quite potent it's quite has a nice
effect it's it's your eyes man they just
boom you know you're baked you're stoned
you know there's there's CBD in there
you know you're you're on the couch you
think oh I'm gonna smoke this Colombian
sativa and I'm gonna just get all this
energy it don't really work that way man
you know I had a cold I smoked some
black Colombian with a friend of mine
who grows a bunch of Pollies wedding
cake this cookies that and all this one
hit dude was on the floor one hit of
some ropey ass looking black Colombian
okay
and that's that says it all you know
and do you feel like you know a lot of
the consumers out there for example who
might say oh you know cookies is all
that really does it for me do you think
like they just don't have the exposure
to really make that claim
yeah they don't they're just they're
just lost in that world of capitalism
and you know they don't
maybe they're not thinking enough maybe
they're just complacent in their lives
with their device and their programming
and everything that they do in their
life and they just don't care you know
but I mean look at somebody like me
who's passionate about cannabis and
everything and has done it his whole
life compared to somebody who just wants
to smoke a smoke or whatever and get
stoned what does he care about cookies
or whatever you know what I mean and
there's a lot of that a lot of kids
younger younger people
yeah look I think it's actually probably
one of the more pertinent questions
that's been in my mind for a while now
which sort of if I gist it out it's like
is the onus on us as The Growers and
breeders to try to educate the general
consumer or like like how do we let
people know that like cookies is not the
ultimate expression of cannabis
well I kind of do that you know I kind
of that's my there's a method to my
madness and that's introducing different
types of cannabis to people
from around the world man in different
combinations and in going back to what
you were saying about uh hetero hybrid
Vigor now there's a method to my madness
with this
and I I don't I guess I'm gonna say it
I I'm I'm working with heterosis
breeding okay I'm following the
heterosis pattern
that when I take parents of unrelated
genetic origin and I cross them together
I'm going most likely going to have a
heterosis hybrid child
there's going to be parents there's
going to be kids that look like their
mom there's going to be kids that look
like they're dead and there's going to
be kids that have hybrid Vigor because
these are unrelated genetic parents that
push everybody out of the way
their flowers are bigger if there's more
resin they're faster they're they're
everything
so that's kind of what I focus on is
because I want people to experience the
heterosis value of the F1 and they get
it
finally they see it finally they're
getting it finally dude buys a pack of
seeds cracks them open finds this plant
goes oh my God
you know over and over again
it doesn't matter what what happens
online because that's all [ __ ] that
dude's life just changed you know he
told me in an email and it's it's year
after year man you know yeah you know
what you just made me think back myself
when was the last time I grew a true F
on Harvard and I thought it's probably a
while ago and so then I thought you're
right there's probably a lot of people
out there who have never grown a true F1
and they they do have that sort of you
uh yeah like Revelation moment
yep and that's what it is man
um and the Chance exists that you're not
gonna find that heterosis Vigor and some
of these these owl Crossings but the
reality is is it works 95 of the time
man
so out of a pack of 15 seeds cat's gonna
get five individuals exhibit heterosis
trades
you know sit like with a bulk I did a
bulk by a cyanide
they're monsters man those are just just
colas of hash
you know are branches of hash
you know and that's what those plants
were traditionally bred for they were
hash plants they were bred to produce
resin not take centerfold pictures in
High Times
Sinai it's not not a strain you hear
about often I have heard about it before
and I thought oh Egyptian that sounds
sort of cool anything unique about that
one from your perspective that maybe
differentiates it a little bit
well just the fact that it's an ancient
type and it was developed as a hash
plant for thousands of years you know
it's drought tolerant
um it's potent you know it has flavor
it's it's you could tell it was selected
you know it was something that was kept
by these people for a long time it's
pretty neat actually but you got to be
you got to be a gland race guy to
appreciate this stuff you got to be like
wow man yeah I'm gonna I'm gonna grow a
bunch of cyanines and like fill a jar
over that you know
you gotta be one of those guys
yeah certainly certainly okay so if
anyone was listening and they're like
look I'm Keen to give it a go I want to
try a cool F1 maybe find some of this
hybrid Vigor you're talking about what's
something you offer that you think you'd
be happy to sort of say look start with
this you probably find something good
you know one of the things I always
point to People Too is a Mazar Sharif by
the 76 Peace Corps Guerrero and I've
worked that line into the into an IBL
over the last 10 years using siblings
and back crosses and blah blah blah blah
to get what I want out of it as as a
line it's got a good medicative quality
to it okay it's better than an OG it's
better than cookies it's better than
that you're gonna eat you're gonna sleep
you're gonna be well
and and you're you know this is weed you
don't smoke for like two three days in a
row because you're gonna have a hangover
effect for two three days in a row
you know wow that's not
well you can look at the numbers on my
page and you can see the CBG in there
and you know it's very odd that these
these these terp profiles are so
different from all these modern polies
you know because they are different
period these these all these modern
polies have the same genetics unless
these guys are outcrossing them to these
land races
you know out of curiosity because it
does it is like a bit of a focal point
in discussions more recently have you
ever tried Mach 1 and if so do you think
the Colombian in that is a real
Colombian there's been some question
marks around that from people
no I haven't but I have had smoke the uh
Cuban black Haze and I can tell you that
is definitely in all five Haze and
probably skunk one ah interesting okay
because I think some people think it's
just pure nl5 Haze do you suspect some
skunk
here's my theory here's my theory here's
what happened dude bought a pack of
seeds from the catalog he moved to
Florida
skunk got mold if you got a male so he
used it on his NL Haze and are there any
specific skunk traits you see in the
Cuban black eyes yeah the orange hairs
you know the nose bite
that sk1 has you know those trades that
sk1 has that are identifiable in most of
its out crosses you know but it's
definitely in all five Haze no doubt
about it and um you mentioned before the
the Peace Corps Guerrero we had a
listener who was a fan of yours asked if
you could maybe talk a little bit about
the Peace Corps Panama
okay here's what happened
I knew a guy one time who knew a lady
who during the 70s all throughout the
70s worked in South America and Mexico
as a Peace Corps worker
she was heady she was from California
and she was a stoner so she collected
seeds from the weeds she bought and
every freaking region she went to when I
got the package there were over 30 types
and stuff I couldn't even pronounce
you know they were all stored they're
all stored improperly
it's rolled up in little bindles and put
in a film container you know
kept in a box somewhere so the only
thing that we got up was the Panama
the Guerrero and the Acuna okay
now the Acuna was given to another
grower and he got robbed and we lost it
so the Panama
we reproduced it we reproduced the Guero
and we distributed it snow High got some
of my Panama and he calls it the 76.
okay
we don't know what the years were on the
Panama so I say 74 through 76. he says
76 I say 74.
but they all they all came through my
hands first
yeah wow and and do you feel like
they're quite unique compared to maybe
some of the other Panama's we see like
from maybe ice seeds or Coastal genetics
oh yeah they're beer man they're just
pure Panama
there's there's no molestation about it
it's just the pure Panama Red Line you
know everything that it ever was uh it
starts stardom Under 12 12 in seed you
know
big long red Spears lots of lots of
hairs you know one or two hits and
you're blah blah you know
so I guess I'd be interested in asking
you some people think that the reason
why Haze is so good was because
collectively it was better than the
individual Parts but it sounds like
you're really fond of each of the
individual parts do you think that Hayes
was much of an improvement on each of
the components
well the thing is is nobody really knows
what Hayes is
okay we can only guess and we we what
what we what the top guys think me
Dwight and these other guys we're
tracing lineage and we're tracing
history and we're we're tracing roots of
import and all this other [ __ ] so it was
most likely Brotherhood Imports
okay whatever those guys brought in
what you know here's a here's a hint
in 1966 there was a movie called uh
oh what was that it was a surfer movie
um
Mike Henson and the other dude that go
around the world it was called Endless
Summer Okay that was a Brotherhood of
eternal love sponsored movie
it was actually a hash and Seed scouting
Mission okay they used the movie as
cover to go and do this in 1966 so they
set up all these relations
seed hash and everything in 66.
so they could come back and this is
where it held Mike Henson got all these
seeds and hashback he started making the
old surfboards because you could carry a
surfboard on the plane and you could
carry epoxy
so they could build these compartments
with massive seed massive hash and just
get right on the plane man
yeah so now by 1971 they told me okay by
1971 all the genetics in the world that
they knew of were in Laguna Beach
and do you think like there's this
Treasure Trove of genetics sitting
somewhere waiting to be cracked open or
it all got dispersed there's Brotherhood
guys I know that won't come off their
[ __ ]
you know and like I could have had a
chance but not anymore you know it's
just that way these guys are never gonna
come off their [ __ ] they're gonna die
with it or they're gonna give it away
when they're dead when they're dying
you know that's how I got the one in the
blue Orca off cue you know what I mean
and we were on good terms the whole
freaking time man
just one day I'd show up at his house
and you don't even know who the [ __ ] I
am
dude had a heart attack okay
forgot everybody and everything got
addicted to [ __ ] opiates forgot who
the [ __ ] I was forgot even gave me the
one
and just you know just forgot us forgot
that we had kid you know we'd come there
with our kids and sit on his couch and
eat dinner and all this other [ __ ]
[ __ ] you know yeah it was It was kind of
disheartening you know but I've seen
that before where a guy has a heart
attack and he forgets his own [ __ ]
kid
you know
so whatever whatever all the [ __ ] that
coot said it's just crap
you know we never really said anything
about it he said he only said one thing
to me he said well you got the genetics
now so you're set
and I said yeah I know man it says but
we got to do something for you we gotta
you know he says just just make a
donation in my kid's name
his kid got run over by a drunk driver
in the early 70s and he went out and
beat the [ __ ] out of the guy and went to
prison for it
so we did that we made a donation in his
kid's name and we still got all that
[ __ ]
you know
food bank or whatever that we're doing
for for for what he gave us you know
because I've always been fair and I
don't steal [ __ ] from people or none of
that
this game's pretty uh Cutthroat and
dirty man
some Scallywags out here
I mean it's good you brought that up
because we did have a viewer submit a
question about that and I guess you sort
of answered some of it but they were
sort of wondering is there an
alternative cutting of like the one like
a sort of a fake one or is it just the
one real one and that's the one you have
yes people that coot didn't trust and
people that I didn't trust who we
thought that were going to [ __ ] us that
we're going to go out and just
automatically start a seed company
we didn't give them the cut we gave them
the one by blue moon rocks that cross
too or back cross one
and they looked almost the same
you know and sure [ __ ] man those guys
take off and boom that's what they did
so guess what
now we can illegitimize you
you know if you if you think that you're
gonna like just blow smoke up somebody's
ass to come steal a cut and you're not
going to get found out in the process
come on man
and yeah there's been people that I've
worked with that have stolen the blue
orca from me house stolen the one from
me there is the one and there is the
blue work out there I can't tell you who
or where or whatever but it's floating
around
and but they're hard to keep the cuts
are hard to keep so good luck
and the reason I like them so much is
because they're authentic old
Brotherhood Thai in an Afghani
combination I love afghanis and ties man
that's my favorite
you know that sounds amazing I would
love to ask you because it's actually
really hard to find this sort of
information what on in terms of the one
what are like the Terps like what's the
flavor what's the effect
oh man it's just it's just really strong
you know all these these kick cookie
Growers man once they get a hold of that
they're like [ __ ] that man that's all I
want to smoke this is all I want to grow
and that's what they tell me it's the
truth because that's all you have in
your jar that [ __ ] works
you know after you smoked everything in
the universe there's the one sitting
there in the jar
you know it's one of those ones where
you're like uh
it'll wreck your day
so you know you don't just jump into
that now Blue Earth on the other hand
that's that's like a Williams Wonder or
uh something like that that's something
women can smoke it's gonna make you feel
good it's gonna you know it's gonna make
you feel warm and Huggy and smiling and
have a good appetite and sleep well you
know because blue Orca finishes at 56
days and the wand finishes at 80. so if
anybody out there thinks that they have
the one better check that at 80 days bro
you know what I mean okay that's
interesting to hear and and one of our
listeners specifically was interested in
picking up across from you of the one to
something they said which cross would
you recommend and which of the crosses
do you think like you're best gonna get
like a dominant the one sort of
expression
well I'll tell you what I'm doing now is
I'm trying to put
a package into seed form
so I've done all these various I did an
outcrossing to the black candahar
to get the one in the blue Orca together
in one package so I've been working
those lines and working for the trades
to get into a seed line that's that
represents everything that I expect out
of it and if it's not gonna work I'm not
gonna do it
so I'm pretty far into it right now and
you know that might be done pretty soon
maybe this year
but as far as like what somebody can buy
it's the one by blue moon rocks the back
cross two three four if it's cubed
you know yeah I had seen that one online
and I wanted to ask you was there
anything specific about the blue moon
rocks that you thought made it like a
well-suited partner to the one
well when I was uh
growing herb in the 90s
I went to Canada and I bought
bubbleberry
um Bubble Gum and shishka Berry off Mark
Emery in like 1993 or some [ __ ]
and they were 200 a pack dude for 10
seeds
and I grew them all you know and I I
found a nice bubble gum and I found a
nice bubbleberry and it wasn't really
the chiscuit berry didn't do it you know
but I kept that one kind of that that
bubbleberry and you know made a million
dollars you know
because it was the best thing anybody
had ever seen it was the original DJ
blueberry by the Indiana bubble gum you
know sag your mouth is bubble gum it was
a DJ Sagar math of collaboration and
they made the bubbleberry and won the
cups or whatever with it so we're like
yeah this is it boom you know and I got
cracked thrown to prison all that other
[ __ ] and I got out of prison the first
thing I want to do is go find
bubbleberry again
well that's gone but now we have OG kush
I'm like what so I go to Humboldt
buddies down there and they hook me up
with these these cuts and I bring them
back up to the back up to Olympian I
grow them and I'm like what the [ __ ]
what is this this is what people want
big spindly tall falling all over
themselves mold and tiny little popcorn
buds but they smell good you know get
you stoned
and
then I started looking for bubble Berry
started looking and looking and I found
out that bogg had crossed an old DJ
blueberry to Blue Moon and then to his
Boggle bubble gum which is a good bubble
gum
you know so I thought oh
this is gonna be good you know and I got
them and bought the pack and yeah there
was some good phenotypes in there but
there's also some [ __ ] hay man you
know
saying the same thing with everything
though people think oh man yeah I got
this and you did through a nanner
you know
and my from my experience all this
intersex [ __ ] comes from poor breeding
okay from my predecessors not me it's
their [ __ ] lines they [ __ ] up on
you know
because I won't I won't use that [ __ ]
man
I guess an interesting sort of uh
Counterpoint maybe just to be Devil's
Advocate slightly is I can't remember
who it was but someone who deals with a
lot of land race work it might have even
been Lewis from AC said that
um if you do truly want to work with the
land race line there is a bunch of
Hermes stuff you've got to weed through
would you agree that there is some land
races that do have sort of Hermes and
it's not all horrible breeding per se
absolutely you know uh allows for
example
um absolutely riddled with it in a
cashmere absolutely riddled with it
um
things like that you know that are often
these really weird regions of the globe
that they don't really give a [ __ ] about
intersex you know they use it as hash
Planet you know so when you go up you
get you start pulling the stuff out of
the woodwork and think that you're gonna
breed with it you better think again man
you better you better look at it real
good you know
yeah definitely but then again there's a
lot of land races and a lot of the
narrow Leaf drug cultivars and we're
talking as far north into Kazakhstan 50
degrees north that have no intersects
that that are just nice plants you know
yeah that's true I guess it also is a
reflection of the the thousands of years
of caretaking and whatnot but uh just to
jump to another question that a listener
had submitted that I think you'll be
able to answer for them is they said oh
you know unfortunately I'm sort of
limited to growing in a tent do you have
any offerings that you think would do
well in a tent or just a small space in
general yeah I I would do like uh you
know if somebody came to me and said hey
this is what I need I would I would give
them what they need you know like a blue
Orca Cross or or something that I know
stays Squat and Compact and that that
they can manage the short flowering time
you know what they want
yeah nice nice you know where myself is
like I'll grow anything you know
no no roof limit yeah pretty much you
know
and I just don't grow inside I don't I
don't grow inside anymore man it's all
it's all in greenhouses
light up you know
because I can control the flowering and
in height and everything and I can see
the full range of expressions and and do
whatever what I need to
do you think that commercially produced
cannabis like you know for the masses so
to speak will eventually transition to
being sort of all Greenhouse slash
outdoor I don't know you know I just
don't know the industry is really a
mystery to me right now it just seems
that there that marketing's over the top
man CBD toothpicks CBD socks you know
CBD cars for your tire I mean cars tires
for your car you know it's just a joke
man so it's gonna spill over into the
legitimate legitimacy of it you know all
this gimmicky [ __ ] so it's it's gonna
climax it's gonna boil over and then
it's gonna settle
so whenever this in the settling is when
it goes federally legal that's gonna be
that's it and that's kind of what I'm
waiting for too because that puts
legitimate that puts legitimacy to what
I'm doing I can now go and patent my
types
nobody can patent a type you can't do
that don't believe anybody it's [ __ ]
only Monsanto can
okay the wild west not until it's
Federal and and we're talking you're
gonna be shelling out you know a
thousand two thousand bucks for this
patent and and you're gonna be waiting
six months seven months 12 months for an
answer and it's gonna come back as a uh
oh what's the word I'm looking for uh
not a patent but uh
in the process of being a patent for the
next five years you know so you got Five
Guys Pat trying to patent the same type
and you're hoping that oh am I gonna be
the one to do it so that's what it's
gonna be and if I don't patent my times
guess what it's up for grabs man you
know everybody's type is up for grabs
until the patent is on
you know I could go steal cookies if I
wanted to
you know there's no patent on it
yeah wow that'll that'll be an
interesting day for sure yeah it's gonna
it's gonna level the playing field man
and it's gonna really get rid of the
noise
I'd be curious to to know what strain
like in your opinion most emulates a
coffee
hmm good question man it's going to be
South Americans you know here's a here's
a something that
well I guess the Western World doesn't
know much about is that the indigenous
people tend to select for their culinary
traits
so a lot of South American types
Echo their Colonnade their culinary you
know
spicy cilantro chocolate coffee all that
stuff
you know peppers
you go to Africa what happens there they
start it starts imitating they're called
they're what they eat
you know
that's one thing I've noticed
yeah that's cool I'm gonna have to give
that a go a nice nice Mexican or
something
um I would say yeah man a Mexican or
um uh Colombian or uh or even a oaxacan
would give you a nice probably a good
coffee
you know
I'm just I might say that Oaxaca is
probably my favorite
it's just it's just man wow
you know pretty neat
yeah that's that's really neat is it one
of those ones where like it's a nice
balance of different sort of things or
it's just it's a it's a feel well type
you know it's a well-being type
where you smoke it and you just
shit's okay man
you know it's just something you can
work on something you can play on
something something you can do anything
on and not be too out of your mind
you know like say a Vietnam would do to
you certainly
and So speaking of Hayes Origins we
suspect it's Vietnam making the noise in
there
because I'll say it there's nothing
stronger than a good Vietnam man
they're just
I'm really glad to hear you say that
because I uh I think that one of the
most memorable equatorial land races
I've ever had I've had some really nice
ties through Bodhi but um he he let me
try one of his Vietnamese one time and
that's forever held the the spot in my
mind is like most memorable sort of weed
I ever smoked
it's it's very haze-like you know and
these properties that Hayes has they're
they're reminiscent if you're if you're
a smoker of all these land races so what
the things that I identify and these
other guys identify Vietnam uh Colombian
uh walking
uh Thai these are these are there's
notes in there you know it's like when
you're when you're playing in a band you
you know what that note is you know
they're playing a G man you know
it's like that it's like you can you can
you can you can tear it apart with your
mind you know
but anyway get a hold of these via Just
Watch What Happens Next okay
Dwight and me we're we're working on
this Vietnam Haze trip thing okay
that's that's awesome I'd love to see
that happen
oh I got some good Vietnam crosses I did
cross um
uh
that
um Vietnamese Provincial Park land race
to the black Columbian and that's
probably pretty Haze like man you know
if you're Haze guy that'd probably be
one to get and check out and go through
a pack of those you know
wow I might need to do that what sort of
flower times do you think might sort of
be in the ballpark they're long man now
the black Columbian isn't as long as
people would think we're talking you
know 70 days but it will go over 100 if
you have that phenotype it does now my
selecting when I do this stuff I'm doing
it in a in a light depth hoop and I'm
looking for stuff that finishes early
because I know what you guys want you
don't want that oh two million day
whatever when we could have the same
package in 80 Days
you know
and yeah I'm not overlooking that we may
lose something in later flower times
either
you know I'm still paying attention to
that
yeah sure sure I I wanted to ask you
because for the longest time I had
always seen this most beautiful picture
I think it's of your chocolate tie how
how did you get it like like with those
really swollen bracks and the purple
look I think it's an outdoor photo from
memory it might even be I think it might
be Darwin's chocolate Thai I don't know
yeah it's it's that line but one of
them's from snow high and one of them's
from uh Kirby okay
Kirby did a back cross and he wasn't he
wasn't supposed to but he did it anyway
and I gotta hold the pack of seeds so I
I put that to the to the snow high and
worked it out into what I remember
buying chocolate tie
you know the traits I remember the
smells the look The you know what the
flower looked like and everything so
that's what I was doing so after a
couple you know a couple runs of that
that was pretty easy because that Line's
pretty much an IBL anyway
you know I just put my hand on it you
know yeah wow I mean I think one of the
things which always caught me about it
was that it looked so modern for a
strain that obviously was old world
well you got snow High working it you
got Howard which is Daryl spelled
backwards working it
okay
and you got
Herbie working it you got me working it
you got three four breeders on the thing
and we're not just dumb asses we're
breeders you know
you know we we we're looking for stuff
we're looking for trades and everything
so if it's gonna happen after that yeah
it's gonna have a modern
you know Cola nice looking flower kind
of trip
there's still radial ties you know
it reminds me of um what do they say it
takes a village to raise a child
that's one of those things man really
and that's the result you know you're
looking at it right there in that in
that photograph
you know
that's awesome look we touched on it a
bit earlier but I'd love to come back I
am a passionate organic grower myself I
would love to hear a little bit about
your grow style obviously you mentioned
it's organic what are some of the
general things you think are important
to focus on in your organic grow
well it's just soil food web gardening
you know we work with the soil food web
not against it microbes
um funguses uh there's so many things
that we utilize that enhance this
experience on a natural level man that
just takes this to a different place you
know and we've educated people on all of
this you know I'm the first guy to use
aloe okay and post it um you know all of
this stuff
we hammered it out an icy mag 10 years
ago it's all hammered out there and the
mess is still there but they've you know
they've gone in there we got band and
all this other [ __ ] and
you know what happened was
we had a big group on icy mag and we
were you know my thread was leading the
[ __ ] charge and I see mag every day
biggest threat ever you know
biggest flat ever biggest [ __ ] listen
that ever whatever
you know but it was just good fun for us
and we were teaching people and learning
and doing all this other [ __ ] and um we
just busted everything open and
everybody came together at once and
really took it to the next level you
know everything
enzymes
microbes fungus fertilizers ionic
reactions everything
you know and so we put all that
information in one package and yeah and
I'm not gonna just tell everybody it
anymore you're gonna have to pay for it
because I don't want to do that anymore
you know
but
you're working with the soil food web
and one of the main things that makes
this all work is the fact that you have
to increase negative ionic surface area
in your soil there you have to there's
only one in all this hydroponic [ __ ]
they're cheating they're cheating the
system by tricking the system with a
with with ions and anions okay it's a
trick
so that's why the weed [ __ ] but
if we can increase negative ionic
surface area and how we do this is we
add those things into the soil compost
the humic material okay
earthworm castings humic material
um anything that has that that that
value like basalt rock dust for example
has a paramagnetic uh negative charge on
it and it's igneous rock it's every
freaking mineral known to man it's
immediately uptakeable and
you'll burn your plants with it if you
don't follow the directions
okay now there we go again we've just
increased in our negative ionic
you know everything so you're getting
more calcium you're getting more
magnesium and all this system works
better if you have those negative
attraction sites and it
I could go into this in more detail in
in another time but
what I can tell you right now is the way
you can get this is through compost
earthworm castings and using those inert
materials like like Char for example
you know Char isn't humic material it
does it unfold to accept more ions it's
just a carbon 14 frame which will hold
ions okay
the humic molecule this is what's weird
about it actually unfolds
to accept more
so it's just this weird mechanism that
like the whole Earth runs on it and you
can look it up and read about it
um some of the better studies come out
of Germany on it
um
yeah check it out you know
check it out
that's that's cool to hear I mean I I
guess I would be interested to ask you
are there any things which over the
years you've realized uh probably more
important I mean I guess the obvious one
is like inorganics watering when you do
it how much that's pretty important
um are there any other things which you
think are like should really have
attention paid to them or not so much
it's really just that you know once you
change the negative ionic surface area
in your soil your whole game Changes
Everything Changes
so whatever food you use is gonna
have an effect if I go to and buy
whatever at the grow store it's gonna
it's gonna work if I go and I get some
horseshit it's gonna work too
you know as long as that mechanism is
there as long as that attraction as long
as those attraction sites are functional
you know as long as you have them in
there so when you see people with
growing in Cocoa cord oh how come my
blood
it's in air material it doesn't even
have a negative charge on it man what
are you doing
you know
it's that simple man
I noticed when I was reading through
some of the old posts I had seen that
there was at one point at least there
was some talk of you leaving icy mag
starting your own forum is that
something you ever want to pursue or not
so much no we did that's what happened
they banned us because they thought they
were they were spying on us in a private
group and I see mad we had an advanced
living soil uh private page you know and
there were mods in there and everything
and one of the mods knocked us out to
like skip or somebody you know these
guys are they're talking about going to
the Sea Depot because they they say we
suck here
you know this is when the sea Depot
opened up and whoever that what was that
guy's name I don't know but he ran off
with everybody's money or something but
anyway he opened up the sea Depot and
and or whatever that that Forum was or
whatever the hell that thing was called
and he made me a mod and made to other
people mod and we had a big section
there and that's that's where we took
over the Forum again
but then that collapsed he got busted
doing something or ripping people off or
some [ __ ] and then we created our own
website which got really big
super big massive members everybody knew
about it
but it was Private because we get sick
of dealing with [ __ ] dumbasses and
trolls you know if you're gonna come in
here and start [ __ ] you're out man
you know and and people did get banned
because they would do that they would
argue and fight and and just go against
the progression of it so of course
you're getting [ __ ] banned so a lot
of those problems reflect on me now
because of the people we banned back
then you know
like dank Frank and all those other
disgruntled employee Vibe people
you know they their butt hurt because
they didn't get what they wanted out of
it they didn't get they didn't get my
seeds they didn't get this they didn't
get that they didn't get to be a mod or
they you know
it's some kind of uh entitlement issue
you know and they were never even hired
this is all volunteer [ __ ]
um
yeah sure I can see people often get
very passionate and uh involved in these
sorts of things I've got a bit of a
longer question here to ask you but it
was one that sort of I was hoping to get
around to and this seems like a good
point to jump into it basically as I was
sort of doing some research for our chat
um I I came across some posts of people
who sort of said that their experiences
with you were a little bit questionable
but then many of those same people would
go on to put a post up and say oh you
know hey guys gas contacted me he's made
everything all good
um and it made me sort of Wonder you
know was there maybe a specific time or
incident where maybe orders weren't sort
of going out as we might want or
something which might explain why there
was this hiccup I'm I'm confident that
you're not a fraud and many of the the
posts go on to say that but it appears
some people did have blips yeah
posts are made by those very same people
I was just talking about and they're the
repeat offenders okay they're the repeat
guys they got mad because I didn't let
them release this or got mad because I
didn't get them that they're those guys
and they actively follow me around and
troll Mass just do it you know
that's what they do but yeah it's
[ __ ] it's all [ __ ] okay we've
we've worked with a lot of Distributors
and we're trying to find a distributor
that we could rely on and get our [ __ ]
out there when we need to you know it's
been a hard game man because 10 years of
mailing [ __ ] seeds dude at every
[ __ ] post office and every [ __ ]
place up here and getting busted and all
these stupid asses filling out the wrong
thing getting us crack busting our [ __ ]
in that post office oh God they [ __ ]
up that one gotta go this one
year after year after year all you got
to do is read my instructions and you
can figure it out
that we're just done with the [ __ ]
man you got to do the [ __ ] right or
don't do it at all I'm not to the point
right now I don't want I'm just ready to
give their money back if they're going
to give me any [ __ ]
you know if you don't follow the
instructions and you're gonna start
flipping me and [ __ ] and expecting that
that I'm gonna just jump out of bed at
three o'clock in the morning to answer
your question no here's your money go
away
you know it's getting old man yeah look
I can certainly appreciate that when you
hear stories from some of the older
members in the community who are like
man back in the day you know I'm sending
off money to Amsterdam's not tracked
like you know you just got to put your
faith in it and it all worked out oh man
not only that but all these guys they
rip you off man you know oh I didn't get
my seeds they'll the classic oh I didn't
get my seeds trip you know so every
order man guess what tracking now we
don't have oh I don't get get my seeds
you know we've seen every trick in the
book man you know yeah I would say
50 percent of the time it's a positive
experience fifty percent of the time
it's a pain in the [ __ ] ass
because these guys are really [ __ ]
entitled man
you know
um
look yeah as someone who has sold seeds
themselves uh I certainly feel like
there are some very high expectations at
times like I remember one guy he like
made payment on the seeds and like
within an hour he's like where's the
tracking number it's like that's what
I'm talking about just give me a minute
bro who are these guys man what do you
think man like a [ __ ] drone is just
gonna come drop them at your [ __ ]
feet in five minutes
so what we do is we take orders we have
a thing now where we take orders for two
weeks and then we pack seeds and we send
them to our distributor who then sends
them to you because we're done man we're
done going to post offices it doesn't
work anymore for us we Guardian family
tree is our distributor now and we're
happy to work with them and they're
doing a good job and they're getting our
[ __ ] out there and there's a lot less
Mix-Ups now
yeah that's awesome to hear and there
you go for anyone who's keen on getting
some of your gear that sounds like a
good spot to stop by do they have an
Instagram or their primarily website
sort of thing I believe they have a
website and they have an Instagram page
and they distribute other people's seeds
as well
yeah fantastic I found myself working
with seed banks who prioritize like
customer service and quick shipping has
always worked really well
yeah if you have a good relationship
with people and everything's flowing
good and right everybody's happy man
you know these guys get their seeds in a
decent amount of time and
but you know sometimes weird [ __ ]
happens you know
as a a more personal question I was
lucky enough to be gifted uh some of
your nl5 Haze I believe it's the F4 it
could be the F5 I think it's the F4 I
wanted to know you got any tips for me
any certain phenos you think I should
keep an eye out for what's your
recommendations
the F4 is pro will probably probably be
pretty good but it's not as refined as
the F6 you know because every time I I
go through them I go through a lot of
numbers and I always get rid of the [ __ ]
you know there was that there was
intersex in that line from the beginning
and now F6 I don't see I don't see
intersex anymore
so that's good
so it's possible and therefore you might
see some nanner maybe but unlikely I
would say 99 no
you know but you're gonna see more
sativa Expressions back at F4
uh that's got me excited
yeah and it's no joke man you know this
is Herb that you like
it's gonna sit in your jar for maybe a
year because you're you know you're not
gonna smoke it that much
you know oh you gotta be excited now
that's that's amazing
so oh and I was also gonna say I uh I
feel like as Growers people need to
accept that every now and again you're
gonna get a plan with a nano and that's
okay you know the world keeps turning
it's all good
well here's a here's something that
people don't realize is that you can
take these stable lines and and give
them a little bit of stress and guess
what happens oh man yeah
stress anything and and stuff man that
I've I've worked so hard on and I give
it a little stress and boom you know
it's just the nature of the Beast man
you know you can't you can't you can't
get rid of something that's part of it
yeah
you know and if you bring any condition
that's gonna wake that up it's gonna
wake up you know certainly
look Let's uh let's go back to the
question we used to start off the
interviews with tell me about your very
first experience with cannabis
oh you know
probably as a kid you know I start
smoking herb in the 70s you know
back then parents smoked her but they're
kids it was like you know it wasn't so
frowned upon you know people think oh
what was the 70s like well everybody
smoked pot man
everywhere you went everybody smoke pot
you know
so but I didn't tell my mom I was
smoking pot in fourth grade man you know
like go out with my friends after
pinching some Thai stick off them or
something and and and and go smoke it
after school with them and Chase ducks
at the park or something you know play
football or frisbee or something
you know until we had to go home and eat
and then I guess somewhere around sixth
grade I went and lived with my dad my
dad was way more heady you know biker he
was teaching he didn't give a [ __ ] he
was like
whatever just don't make a habit out of
it
so you know we get big but when I was 13
14 I was getting bong hits for allowance
man every day dude would leave a bong
hit on the counter for me and my brother
after we got on the bus because he
didn't want us he didn't put the weed
out before you know he got on the bus
but after school man we raised each
other home
you know to get the bong first
I sure [ __ ] man and he wanted us to do
our chores first you know do the dishes
clean up the house vacuum and all this
other [ __ ] before we smoked our herb
because he knew you know if we smoked I
heard we just sit there and go
so we we obliged in we did our chores
first before we smoked our herb and
everything but that's how our lives were
we scored weed for our parents all
throughout our teenage years you know
yeah wow it does really make you realize
it's been quite a shift in the dynamic
hasn't it it's a different it was a
different world growing up in the
Pacific Northwest you know
it was it really was it was like we were
just isolated from the rest of the world
as far as like the Cannabis culture
thing went
you know that you had your cannabis
culture in California which was kind of
like the culture up here
but I don't know we just had our own
little bubble up here you know
yeah it's very lucky indeed so if we
move forward a little bit what
stimulated you to do your first grow
well I'd grown an herb you know like I
said as a as a kid with my parents we
just that's what we did
so I took care of the plants as they did
we watered them
but I didn't grow myself you know
because I I'd left home and wanted to
just go be a person you know put on did
all that [ __ ] went to college Grateful
Dead and all that [ __ ] and and just my
Fascination still lied in cannabis
you know I wanted to be one of these
guys I didn't realize it back then but I
wanted to be one of these guys the white
lab coat and working in in a lab and
taking tissue cultures and doing all
this crazy [ __ ]
but I didn't realize back then that I
was working for the wrong team if I was
going to continue down that path
you know what I mean
so I made a decision you know after all
several Grateful Dead shows
to to to freelance this and do it myself
you know what I mean
so I started you know I started breeding
probably oh 93 just throwing pollen
around making my own seeds just for
environmental purposes because most of
the stuff that we were getting out of
the seed banks or a cut from your buddy
or whatever your half gooey cut you got
it didn't make it man
you know we're up here we're getting
frosts in September we want to crop the
finishes
so that's what I started doing I started
breeding four crops that finished so by
2000 I had types that
you know that would could withstand
cellular damage of you know minus
whatever degrees and they would finish
in you know early October and
you'd get a harvest
and what's one of the first Creations
you made where you were like really
proud of it and you're like [ __ ] I could
like sell this basically
oh I think it was uh I got uh what used
to be called Eugene green
and I crossed it to an old Oregon
blueberry and then I crossed it to the
Alaskan [ __ ] to an old Alaskan
Thunder [ __ ] from up here that was it
had been around a long time probably 30
years
a guy grew at 7 000 feet in just a month
you know some of the phenotypes finished
in July some of them finished in October
some of them are two feet high some of
them are 14 feet high
you know but it was the real Alaskan
Thunder [ __ ] a nice red you know dark
plants that that Alaskan smell and
everything said I knew that that's what
I gotta work with if I want to bring
this modern
flower into this bag
you know and I did
out of curiosity I think I'm just
probably a bit uneducated in this aspect
what do you think are the genetics
behind the uh ATF
oh it's like it's got a rush in it for
sure a rooter Alice but I don't think it
was a tribal you know like nowadays it
wasn't a a tribal drug type
it was just a [ __ ] Rooter Alice
nowadays you have Tribal drug drug types
that are autoflowers from as far north
as 50 50 degrees
and I got a bunch of them man you know
but Auto flowers don't fascinate me I
think that's just dumb you know it's
boring breeding it's boring
do you think to a certain extent that
orders are sort of always going to be
somewhat inferior to photo period or do
you think they will come a day where
they're a bit more equal playing field
I got a friend right now who last year
did nothing but breed autos
and the results were pretty neat man he
used a bunch of my stuff
and I was like wow
that looks just like the original
you know
so there's potential in it and there's
use in it absolutely
you know but I wouldn't say I'm like
Jeff lowenfellas and I'm gonna predict
that's gonna be the wave of the future
yeah I remember when he uh said that on
the show I'm sure he said it other
places as well but when he said it on
the show there was a few listeners who
were like not sure that'll be the case
no I I gave him some other one by a
Kazakhstan too to take up to Alaska
I don't know whatever happened to it but
I'm pretty sure you know it did throw
off those Auto flower trades up there
yeah
yeah nice nice nice nice nice
so I don't think I've asked you but I'd
be interested to know do you consider
yourself more of a concentrate or flower
guy
I like flowers man I don't smoke that
[ __ ] oh yeah you rip it you're a bong
guy or a joints or yeah
since I was like you know 14 years old
or some [ __ ] bong it up you know some
some period in my life somewhere in my
20s I thought joints was cool while I
was while I was driving concrete mixer
or something you know
but I can't even smoke a joint without
hacking now man you know
It's Paper I can't stand that paper man
you know
in the dabs dude I'm just I'm just I'm
not into it man I get so much more out
of the flower
so much more so much more pleasure so
much more effect than this just big glob
of [ __ ]
you know
I think it's silly humans you know
always wanting more
yeah I think you just perfectly
expressed my feelings on that as well
like yeah I just get so much more out of
flowers and I never really Vibe with the
dabs but I think it's probably related
to tolerance and whatnot and I think
there's value to keeping your tolerance
to dabs low
yeah I wouldn't I just why you know like
I said I can take one hit of black
Columbian and be
keyed up right you know
function talk be
you know
so we sort of touched on this a little
bit earlier but I'd love to just flesh
it out slightly more what was the last
thing you smoked that left a really
lasting impactful memory fee where you
were like wow that was neat
we'll Hawking by chocolate dye
yeah good good stuff man like right
there that's that's what I'm after
that's that's it man that's it you know
and I don't want to say it too loud but
I guess I just did you know because I
don't got many seeds left but you know
once you say that these people want them
it's the truth it's really nice herb
dude you know it's like one hit and
you're like wow this is cool
like you feel like a little kid again
you know yeah it sounds like it could be
like very haze-esque
it's it's nice
um some of the phenotypes are maybe too
potent you know for functionality
but most of them were pretty good and if
you find the right one so so what I'm
going to do is I'm just gonna I'm just
gonna do it I'm gonna make a blueberry
just because just because I can and
because I have velvet Rush
you know you know what that is
I was gonna ask I got a question tell me
about velvet rash okay
blue tie and it's the Brotherhood of
Eternal loves Highland blue tie and it
was imported from 76 to 77 for 15 months
in military cargo shipments via plane
that landed in 29 Palms okay
yeah
now when they distributed it it was the
best thing going around but it only
lasted for 15 months because when the
man got wind of it they shut it down
so that's why that
little amount of Highland bow tie was
around so collectors you know Mel Frank
DJ whoever
obviously found out about it and got a
hold of it
you know
well anyway it was DJ who who crossed
the Highland blue tie to The Afghani
number one the Kabul
it was mailed from Kabul in 79 to Mel
Frank you know
[Music]
that's what it is
okay so what happened was
DJ worked the line
and somewhere back there in his workings
gave some seed to Mel okay
now when the Brotherhood had a barbecue
in Eugene Oregon in 1986 Mel Frank was
there and so was coop
and so were other Brotherhood guys
so cute and Mel hit it off Mel gave
back to Brotherhood The Velvet Rush the
other half you know it was molested but
the Highland blue tie got back to the
Brotherhood
so coot gave it to the Brotherhood down
in San Clemente and they took it in the
hills and they grew up for six or seven
years
and they said
it was amazing they said every color in
the rainbow was in the plants they were
nothing but Bud they looked like
Christmas trees they're probably 20 feet
tall
um just monsters and they did that for
however many years five six years and
then put the seed
you know the seat away
for however long that was from 91 until
2010 when I got it
and opened them up and repopulated them
and yeah I did give it back to DJ okay
like pretty quickly too like here man
you know no thanks no nothing
you know what I mean just whatever and I
went I went on his page and I see mag
and posted oh velvet rush and blah blah
blah look look it's cool
not a word
you know they're just scared that I was
gonna do what I did with it
well after being just dissed I did I
released it hell yeah it's the
Brotherhood line it's not yours anymore
you know
so
that's what I did I just I just I just
IBL it and keep it as original
so we have Afghani who won by Island
blue tie and I have the oaxacan by the
chocolate tie so I'm just gonna [ __ ] it
up put them together man make a
blueberry there's no [ __ ] patent on
that [ __ ]
you know
can we expect to see that offering yeah
we'll do that this year
because I'm halfway through it
that'll be neat for sure because I know
a lot of people really want that like F1
blueberry not like the F5 or whatever
DJ's got it at well it's not that I'm
trying to copy the guy I just have a
Fascination and how that happened and I
want to see it for myself I just want to
experience that for myself and through
my own hands not that I'm gonna oh I'm
an American bunch of money yeah [ __ ] you
no it's not my trip man you know
I just I'm more I'm more into just
seeing the fascination of the line you
know how these things work together the
way that oaxacan works with the
chocolate and the way the the the tie
works with the Afghani in there and that
Afghan [ __ ] dude that's one of the
shittiest afghans
you know oh really
yeah
see that that's really interesting for
me because I think the thing that you
consistently read about blueberry is
that people are like I want the early
version which had like you know the
blueberry muffin sort of smell the new
one it doesn't even smell blueberry and
I always wondered like why did he like
he says oh you know I've read for the
effect not the flavor and it's like yeah
but if you had blueberry muffin like why
would you expect on the old blueberry
this morning I smoked some old blueberry
by velvet Rush okay a back cross two
velvet Rush this [ __ ] Dynamite one
hit boom whoa I'm going to the hotel
you know whoa I'm here
yeah wow potent [ __ ] but there's not a
lot of berry flavor in it
it's it's kind of just Highland blue tie
you know
yeah
now the old Oregon blueberry which I
have had and have and worked with
I didn't never get any males out of the
old pack I got so that's why I didn't do
the line
but I did outcross two appropriate tides
and like I said I did the back cross to
Velvet rush just because
and are they available at the moment
yeah but there's intersex in the line
I'll tell you
but the good ones are good you know
they're good it's like one hit pow this
is this is what blueberry is supposed to
be
now somewhere in
I don't know when DJ did it but he put
another Indica in the blueberry and
that's that's what the world knew as
blueberry when it was released that nice
glossy leather leaf and I'm saying it
was an NL I think it was an NL
no one or nl5 or something
as in like just to confirm like as in he
had like a sort of blueberry clone and
then he hit something to that and then
those were sort of the seeds that you
think went out the whole profile changed
from sativa to Indica like overnight
and the people were like huh
you know what happened that's not the
Oregon blueberry sativa we know
yeah okay that was awesome to hear about
that everyone I recommend you go grab
those seeds um I did want to just jump
to a different Cross of yours for a
moment
um because I had noticed that you
released the the Nigerian Sunshine a
while ago and that also used the the
blue moon rocks was that the same male
that you crossed to the one yep
it was the same male I used
on all the blue blue moon rocks
Crossings so that's why all those look
the same that big giant bog bubble gum
flower top you know
yeah yeah
nice and I mean would you be able to
give us any of the backstory on the
Nigerian I think Nigerians are
Australian they're always well received
but hard to find info on
okay this Nigerian
is a Brotherhood Nigerian
um it was brought back from Nigeria in
1976 by a be a Brotherhood couple who
were fleeing persecution from the feds
you know and went to Africa to look for
exotic textiles
and that's what they brought back now
they grew it from seed and found that
particular cut that I had
and a couple and another one so there
were two cuts that they'd had since like
1978 or 79 kept as cuts
and I was like what
and there was nothing on earth like this
okay nothing on earth like this there's
a Nigerian out in California it's a Big
Sur somewhere that's the same one but
it's not the same one it's busted up
it's outcrossed
no I I know I know the cat who has this
who he also had the Brotherhood Cruella
and he also had the sister the only
other living sister of the one in blue
Orca which they call Mary Poppins
and at the time man I was like God I
don't just want to take it all these
guys a [ __ ] like I'm just greedy
so I didn't oh no it's cool man it's
cool
you know
and now I'm just kicking myself in the
ass about it because I could have had
that Cruella and Mary Poppins and
but the Nigerian was lost okay it was a
76 Nigerian it was beautiful one hit man
you're on a Rocket Ride like you've
never been on your life
and when I outcrossed it to um
and a former employee lost the cut so I
don't have it it killed it lost it gone
so anything I had is the blue moon rocks
and and everything every time I get into
that line I'm always looking for that
Nigerian
you know
um there's a guy uh boy forget his name
uh Synergy genetics on Instagram
he is a nice expression of a Nigerian
sunshine with that Nigerian expression
popping out nice and big if you wanna if
you want to see what you're looking at
there we go we'll have to go suss that
out I mean if we quickly jump to another
strand that I think uh is quite notable
I'd be really grateful to hear your
thoughts on Cherry Bomb you know like
the the infamous Maui Wowie sort of
variety it's it's not when you find a
lot of info on but you hear it whispered
about it by the heads
yeah Mr Green jeans gave me the line he
you know he gave me the permission to
breed and sell it and I don't know why
what happened to the guy he seemed
dropped off the Earth man for a number
of years and people thought he was dead
or something well he wasn't dead
we don't know what happened
but anyway he said here the line's yours
so I'm like okay
now there's always been intersex in
Cherry Bomb okay it's a real Maui Wowie
it's a it's a it's it's a oaxacan by a
Brotherhood Afghani
it's Brotherhood wahawkin by Brotherhood
Afghan that's what it is there's no tie
in it
um
what can I tell you about it it's mostly
sativa
and the reason that they think all these
Maui's you know most Maui's in fact all
Maui's have intersex problems
now they say it's because of the city
lights when they were breeding it back
in the 70s now I just don't know you
know it could be
but anyway the lion carries in her sex
and since I got a hold of it I've read
it for 10 years
and every time I get in there I try to
get rid of that [ __ ] man
you know so now we're sitting pretty
good we're sitting pretty good with our
Cherry Bomb it's it's pretty clean I
like it but it's but it's just Cherry
it's just cherry pie it's just a it's
just a Maui it's not there's no tie in
it there's no
it's it's what I call medium duty herb
you know stuff you'd give your mom or
your dad and you know and not not wig
them out
novelty stuff here Mom have smelly wowie
that's that's so interesting because I
think like I I'd be interested to ask
you earlier you mentioned that you know
the Brotherhood was sort of like a combo
of like bikers and Surfers and so do you
feel like the genetics like the breeding
itself was mostly done by sort of the
more Surfer side of bowl or it was
literally by a mixture
yeah it was it was straight up hippies
and these weren't just hippies man these
were freaks you know they're
they had some far out philosophies
they're chowing on LSD and DMT and they
were you know but they were the biggest
Distributors of the hash and herb and
LSD on the coast they had a pretty big
organization and they were
they're doing it
but by 1971 they were all busted up CIA
got in there and got him
that's why they all fled
you know and the only reason that this
stuff keeps popping up oh 76.77 blah
blah blah it's because they would meet
up later and say hey let's do it again
let's take one more run around the track
that's that's nice I mean we're gonna
loop back but before we do you mentioned
7677 and it just sprung a thought to
mind what's your thoughts on the whole
Uncle Fester skunk story
I don't know man the plant kinda looks
like an rks
but I don't believe that the lineage
goes back to 68. I don't [ __ ] believe
it because
none of it adds up okay the only thing
that adds up is the leaf morphology and
the fact that it may be from bikers
but it doesn't match with the rest of
the stories and the skunk isn't the
skunk that that fits the skunk
you know
some people say oh yeah man it's it's
good you know but it's it's not and I'm
not trying to diss it or anything but I
don't think it's real that's just my
opinion
okay yeah sure
um I do oh I I remember now I wanted to
add in that uh kudos to you with the
Cherry Bomb because I I did find some
posts from Mr Green jeans last night
when I was reading over to it and he
quite emphatically says in all his posts
that he feels you improve the line from
when he gave it to you and he sort of
talked he didn't he didn't mention
stability which is interesting but he
just sort of generally says it's better
so I guess that's what he was talking
about well when I got it there was a lot
of sativa expressions and like I said
when I when I breed I try to breed man
I'm not growing in a [ __ ] shoe box in
an apartment somewhere I'm gonna go and
we're gonna bust open a bunch of seed
and we're gonna do a proper selection
so when I saw that there was all these
sativa Expressions I was like oh what
happened to the Indica expressions
I want to put that back in there
I want to balance that out a little bit
more you know what I mean so luckily I
found a nice looking male [ __ ] Cherry
Bomb man you know that had a nice fat
Indica profile and I said okay here we
go boom
so that you know it brought the Indica
back into the line and now and now we're
now we're a little more resin you know
hell yeah look while we're on the topic
I'd love to ask you are there any
specific characteristics that you look
for as a sign of a good male
uh males are really deceptive you know
because they're all they all look good
they all have a tendency to look good
you can't really tell until you really
put it through the paces until you get
it up and you beat it up a little bit
you know what I mean damage it run into
it smack it around you know damage it is
what I do to see how how well that Vigor
continues if it's gonna lie to me I'm
gonna know right away
they're tricky man they're tricky
they'll do things you would not believe
you'll be looking down here for all for
six months pulling males
and then
six months later look up there's a male
that somehow snuck around your your site
and climbed up a [ __ ] tree and put a
big flower head above everybody and went
boom
that's pretty neat
it's it's quite deceptive it's like
these things have minds of their own I'm
telling you okay but a good male is
they're they're usually easy to find
you know because they like to express
thems they're like yeah they're usually
they usually look pretty good so I
usually have like 10 20 good males I'm
like oh no you know which one do I use
so I'll tell you what I I often use two
males on one female
yeah I think that can be an interesting
breeding technique and I think there's a
lot of reasons for doing that for sure
um I I guess to ask specifically a lot
of breeders commonly will say oh you
know I feel like the most vigorous
fastest growing males
um that can be a a more hemp trait than
a drug trait do you sort of disagree
with that is there a standard process
you go through of putting them through
the gauntlet so to speak yeah it's it's
that's just rumor man because just you
know you could have a male that'll just
boom boom boom and just blow big fat
Leafs all over the place and he'd just
be a monster
you know and everything he does and
every female he touches no matter what
it is is always good
that's like 805 Hayes you know you take
any any nl5 Hayes good male and touch
anything with it and it's [ __ ] bomb
so it's about 50 50 on that you know yes
and no
sure
and uh just as a sort of one I probably
should have asked back when we were
talking about grow mediums but I think
you'd have a great answer for this do
you use the same general sort of soil
mix slash approach to Growing when you
say grow like a land race variety versus
say something more a little more modern
or do you find you have to factor in
that sensitivity
it's all the same
it's I I use the same soil on everything
the traits that I recognize that that
are different are like drought tolerance
you know like okay that one is from
cyanide that doesn't get water today
because it's not gonna like it don't
give it water
you know those are the the growing the
things that I see it's just
environmental conditions
not more trait driven stuff because they
all pro they all behave the same as
cannabis you know
they flower they they grow the flower
they die
yeah sure
sure so
I uh I I took a look at the website and
I noticed that the 2022 menu
um looked like it was a lot more tighter
sort of more focused a little scaled
back than say the 2021 menu which was a
bit more comprehensive was there any
particular reason you decided you want
to sort of focus on a smaller number of
varieties I mean it was still quite a
few I think it was like 10 or something
you know not not a small number by any
means but was there a reason you wanted
to scale things back and just focus on
these specific lines a little more no
just getting tired man you know
I I figured well
everybody's you know a couple years ago
I figured Well everybody's doing this I
better get out there and bust some ass
I better get out there and just kick ass
so I did you know two three years in a
row just kicked ass
you know woke up micro dosed every day
ate a good breakfast you know drinking
spring water running around half [ __ ]
naked and just yeah
moving pots around soil just throwing
around like there's no tomorrow you know
breeding this breeding that I mean
there's a there's a point where
every day I'm going out in Braden and
it's becoming a monotonous task where
you're like okay I gotta go do this and
you're out there and you're you're
rubbing stems your chicken Leaf
morphology you're doing all this [ __ ] in
the Sun and it's just like it's a job
man
you know yeah and and after a couple
years of going on it on that scale like
I did you know that's epic that's like a
world [ __ ] record two years in a row
after two years after two years of that
dude I was like oh my God
this year you know I have all these
projects I just need to to calm down
you know
so I did I just I just scaled back for
my own health really
you know because I'm just running too
hard man you know
totally understandable and I I think a
lot of people may not be aware I I
certainly wasn't
um that you you sort of do a lot of your
work off grid is that correct yeah all
of my work is off-grid now yeah okay
that's really interesting just because
yeah yeah I got out probably five years
ago
just just said no I'm not doing this
anymore
got out on the land and you know
now we're doing domes [ __ ]
how do you find that lifestyle you feel
like it's really conducive to sort of
what you're doing and how you want to
live
that's the only lifestyle for me yeah
it's it's the only way for me man
I drink spring water every day you know
I get my water from the spring you know
it's not beautiful
breathe clean air at least 25 2500 feet
up on top of a mountain you know I mean
I had no neighbors there's nobody around
me
I get neighbors you know but you can't
see them yeah
just Forest a nice first Forest that I'm
in you know
the dream yeah it's pretty nice a lot
you know it's harder to come by nowadays
that's for sure
you know it's a lot of people wanting it
it's a lot of work though man I wake up
and I bust ass every day and that's
another thing people don't understand
man I'm off grid you know I gotta work
to live I'm not sitting around online
okay I gotta answer this guy's question
because he needs to know
you know
priorities yeah
that's it yeah you know what you made me
just feel so lazy because it's like I
could just sit here all day and like
water's still gonna be there when I want
it we're like you gotta go get it
well yeah you know and I'm pretty fit
too you know because of this
you know I get out there and throw [ __ ]
around and [ __ ] you know
pretty fit so it keeps me fit keeps me
healthy it keeps me active it's
everything you know
it's a lifestyle
truly truly
and I know you know the biggest thing is
I never see a stoplight okay I could
drive miles and miles and miles and
never see a stoplight yeah you know
that's interesting I uh
I was I was gonna say I I normally ask
breeders whether they feel it's
necessary to be active on the Instagram
scene in order to sort of be a breeder
in the current market so I'd really like
to hear your your opinions not just
because you're obviously not as invested
as others but more importantly because
you're off the grid like I'm sure that's
an additional hurdle it's the internet's
[ __ ] you know you you don't get good
bandwidth you can't load pictures
sometimes your messages don't come
through or sometimes you don't get your
emails until two days later you know I
have an antenna booster and everything
it's just how it is out in the middle of
nowhere they don't have the signal
strength you know
so
yeah
that's real
do you feel like it detrimentally
affects your ability to interact with
the market or you think like no I can
still interact with the market it's just
you know once a week no because because
the way these apps are set up they have
advertising priority of bandwidth
okay
Instagram priority man they got ads to
run you're gonna get through
now I may not be able to post pictures
when I want but I can eventually do it I
just gotta wait for the bandwidth to
come rolling around again and then we'll
do it so but like you said do these guys
have to be on here and at this point in
the game yes and no if you don't make a
present you're not gonna be seen
you're gonna get buried in the in in the
marketing you're gonna get buried people
aren't gonna know you're there you go
you could be out here for 10 15 20 years
man and get buried under all this stuff
nobody even know you're there if you
don't make a presence
so yeah you gotta you gotta have a
presence you know you have to have some
kind of presence
yeah certainly I guess the the follow-up
to that I wanted to ask is do you feel
any level of how shall I say like
disillusion with sort of the way the
market trends are going you know at the
moment we're very much in the thick of
the the mylar bag hype culture is there
any part of the way that the trajectory
of the scenes going that sort of has you
a bit bummed or do you think like no
it's fine it's just doing its thing
well you know
a lot of the times I can predict what's
going to happen next but lately it's
been really kind of chaotic with the
marketing thing it's really
which way is anything gonna go
you know it's it's a it's pretty loud
out there with noise
with products and people pumping this
and people pumping that it's like I feel
sorry for the consumer man
because they're getting hit with so much
misinformation they don't know what to
do I have more people now asking me what
they want from me and I have to tell
them what they want from me then what
they come to me and want
I gotta tell them all you want you want
the Mazar guillero oh you want the haze
oh you want you know it's kind of weird
yeah you know what that's actually like
a really unique perspective that I I
think I'm gonna have to pay more thought
to because yeah I think I think it is
hard as a newbie
um or someone who's just entering the
market to know yeah like what like
what's true what's false uh where do I
what what's correct they don't know
they don't know because there's so much
noise there's so much misinformation
there's so much marketing they can see
that people are just trying to sell a
product and that they don't give a [ __ ]
about you
you know
yeah you know it's it's interesting that
you you mentioned that because I one of
the criticisms I had heard of this show
in fact is that
um you know people might listen to
certain things and yeah take it for
gospel when really it's just one
person's account of things and it's not
necessarily true and I I guess that's
actually sort of one of the reasons why
I started the show is that I I never
Proclaim anything as 100 truth I'm just
trying to share everyone's stories and
then you can pick and choose what you
think is sort of the real deal
um but but it's interesting because yeah
a lot of people do
take what they read online is like 100
the truth and yeah maybe there's other
aspects of the story which you know like
like what we were talking about earlier
when people maybe read a bad review
online and they don't understand exactly
yep they have no idea they're missed
they're all the information that they're
putting out there is false they have no
clue nothing and and the the reality is
it there was a you know if you if you're
gonna get trolled by somebody that wants
you not to succeed they're gonna do it
if they don't have nothing better to do
that's what they're gonna do and I got
it I got these guys all over me you know
because I didn't give them ten thousand
seed when they wanted it or whatever the
[ __ ] you know some some crazy demand or
some crazy [ __ ] where I'm like okay well
I'm just done with you bro you know and
they get so butt hurt they gotta go out
there and talk mad [ __ ]
you know it's mad [ __ ] too and I get I I
get on the [ __ ] for it get on them
foreign forums and I get on those
platforms man I go in there and I chew
their ass out I give all the facts I
give all the information and they
[ __ ] ban me and [ __ ] I'm out of
there and nobody hears the [ __ ] truth
oh that's you know [ __ ] roll it up [ __ ]
icy mag [ __ ] all those douchebags
there's douchebags dude you know they
this the way they slander people and and
and let people treat people the way they
do
horrible
yeah look I've been thinking as a as a
bit of a joke we need a we need to breed
some anti-grudge weed and just hand it
around I got tons of it
I don't want to keep these Grudges on
people man I just want to progress and
move forward and do all this dumb
you know climbing up your coattails and
you know trying to empty your pockets or
something you know while you're while
you're giving water to your kid
I feel you I feel you okay
um
I had I had one question that uh it
might be a little bit of a funny one but
I I found an old Forum post and I'm not
sure if it was tongue-in-cheek or what
but I was hoping you could give us the
backstory where you had said that uh you
were selling some seeds the blue Walker
Hayes crossed the Velvet rush it was
listed as fifty thousand dollars cash
only I was like oh that's got to be a
funny story what's the backstory behind
that oh it just did that's what my
competitors do they'll get my [ __ ] cross
it to what I have what I'm doing and
then go sneak around on Instagram it's
just some auction and try to sell it for
some ridiculous the high price you know
so I'm like oh
[Music]
10 million dollars
and honestly bro I don't think any cut
is worth more than 500 nothing
never
because I have so met so much genetic
potential in my library
I can do anything
yeah you've got you've definitely got
the base palette to to mix the colors
and and in effect Terps everything
it's just you know
every if you ever what every breeder
wants they just want to be turned loose
and
and to breed you know it's it's always
the fantasy of every
serious breeders just let me add them
let me let me out there put me to work
you know I want to I want to move
through a selection I want to select out
of ten thousand parents man
yeah nice
look I'll uh I'll I'll bring it up
because I think this was actually one of
the things which I saw recently and it
stimulated me in a message it was um I
think you put a post up relating to some
of the comments uh Todd McCormick had
made about skunk and uh for the
listeners of the show they would know we
had Todd on recently
um I just want to put it out there I
like Todd I felt like I learned a lot
during that chat I would love to know
you know what was sort of some of the
issues you took with some of the
statements he made about the roadkill
skunk
oh I don't know I don't I'm not I'm not
recalling anything on roadkill skunk I
think most of the Flack I'm getting from
the Todd Camp is the nl1 stuff every
time I post at Neville's n01 man I get
an army of [ __ ] trolls from Todd's
camp
and I'm like no okay
Greg knew that nl1 was sent to Amsterdam
and Neville put a napkin or a Hindu on
it and send it back everybody knows that
for years we knew that Howard marks
knows that everybody knows it you just
can't come along and change the
narrative oh that never happened
every time I post no one man I get that
[ __ ] you know
so I'm just over it so Dwight all these
people that know the truth just keep
saying the truth
over and over
and Greg even says so himself man
he says it says it himself listen to the
interview people
no I'm not making it I'm not making any
claims about anything I'm just I'm just
experiencing
everything else everybody is you know so
and just for clarification
um when you say Greg's interview that is
that the one he did with Matt riot
oh yeah I'm not sure which which one it
was
but um yeah he says it he says it
himself okay yeah sure well for anyone
who's Keen to to listen I think that
might have been um the the Breeders
Syndicate podcast with Greg so check it
out
interesting okay so I I guess it sounds
like it's it's not so much that there's
any sort of real beef there's just a
discrepancy and and you feel like
there's more people from his Camp coming
to yours every time Dwight posts this
information he gets trolled too
you know he's on LinkedIn right now he
posts this information he gets trolled
anytime we post this information about
what Neville did we get troll
and would you just for anyone to save
them sort of clicking around from
different things could you quickly recap
that story for us about how it all went
down
which one is that huh the no one or
would I remember yeah I'm not on point
because this isn't my [ __ ] man but okay
this is what I know okay
Greg sent Neville in cassette tapes the
Pacific Northwest hash plant Northern
Lights
l-i-t-e-s okay Neville got it Neville
bread it to us Afghan or Hindu
Afghan Hindu or Afghan hash plant one of
the two
and set it back okay
that's when Greg or whoever and they
crossed it out to a bunch of [ __ ] and
then sent it back uh yeah okay so it was
like a back and forth sort of thing for
a while just like we do
totally totally totally okay cool cool
so you know Neville did the work because
Neville handled the genetics that's why
Greg was working with it
yeah sure
we actually had a fan submitted question
about
um one of your nl5bx is so I uh yeah
enough I pays so it might be a good time
to bring it up but um our listener
basically wanted to know if you had any
information on what they or you called
the pine box release of the nl5 back
cross
oh that's just one of the parents that
had a really nice Pony smell
you know how the nl5s had that Pine lime
kind of thing
it just really really notable on that
one
nice okay cool I mean they they also had
a follow-up question where they were
wondering how potent is the nl5 cross
Haze F5 oh I don't know if we've talked
about the F5 only the F4 and F6 um yeah
I didn't release a lot of F5s it's kind
of crazy
um
yeah only a few packs of those went out
of the F5 I don't know why I just didn't
do a big breeding of it
but um is it his thing it's an IBL so
you're gonna see the same traits of the
nl5 haze line every time you're gonna
have Indica Expressions that finish
earlier and you're going to have Haze
Expressions to finish later
and we all know that the haze expression
expressions are the ones that we tend to
favor
because the Indica ones are more dull
boring
you know
ugly plants small buds they get mold but
Daniel 5 Hayes line itself doesn't
really get mold
in in any of the nl5 hazes say across
the different Generations were there any
of the generations where you felt like
you were getting the the incense or like
the church sort of smell from it
yeah absolutely man all through it all
through all of the lines you know F1 F2
all the way through it the back crosses
everything
you know I've done I've pretty much
chopped it up into little pieces and and
took those expressions and isolated them
and bred them out
this purple expression I brought out
this liquor licorice expression I
brought out this expression not
expression
you know
so you can individually you can access
those expressions if that's what your
favor in those lines
you know
yeah sure sure as a as a follow-up how
does the the blue Orca Haze compared to
say the nl5 haze just because they are
sort of similar in some respects
Lyrica Hayes man it's like the best weed
on Earth
it's like it's like ml5 Haze went to
heaven and
came back and said hey we're all going
to heaven now
um it cleans it up quite a bit it takes
the teeth chattering out of it it takes
that the the harsh vibe off of it it
takes but one thing it does it really
creates a pretty powerful introspective
behavior and this is really
unique man because most people that that
it get those phenotypes will say the
same thing and I said the same thing
forever you know you think Kelly I
missed was good you think this was good
you think that was good
smoke this get on this and you're not
going to come off it for two years
because nothing's better
nothing
it's like there's nothing better
no matter what
you know yeah it's the truth
there's other types out there that are
that are that will give it a run for the
money I'll be like yeah I want to smoke
that too
but you know I know what it does and the
people that the people that grow and
have those those cuts know what it does
too and they're out there
you can access these cuts that people
have that they've kept
you know if you do the research on Blue
ARCA Hayes you will you will find the
information
they put this [ __ ] out for over 10 years
nice I you know that brings us to the
next question really nicely in that I
noticed a lot of people sort of talking
about their experiences of growing at
the pure blue Orca Haze and I think a
lot of them sort of got the impression
that it was going to be like a mostly
Haze sort of line is that how you would
describe it like what should people
expect if they're gonna grow that one
out
no I just named it trans we
traditionally name lineages
you know
this and that
there's a predominantly a large amount
of haze in that in that breeding yeah so
we got blue Orga hey every time anybody
puts nl5 on anything it's always a haze
you know what I mean this Haze that Haze
butt run pays whatever you know
tobacco Haze
okay so people can sort of expect like a
mixture of like some sativa some Indica
sort of stuff yep same thing as in all
five Haze man really because blue Orca
is a kandahara and a tie
so you're putting the same ingredients
in but
it kind of really enhances it
like next level enhancement you know
yeah nice we've got a few more questions
from our listeners before we sort of get
on the tail end of things as we are
getting there but uh they wanted to know
what's your experience with the Lamb's
breath and do you think it's still
around
yeah man well
the lounge bread that I have was given
Vibes Collective gave it to me they had
it for whatever time long they said they
had they got it from Bushman
the reggae artist
because it was in their family since mid
60s or something like that
anyway Vibes Collective they got a hold
of it they got it in Spain they lost it
somehow
no
um
somebody had a pack from them and they
gave it to me and I grew them out and I
repopulated them they're like wow cool
thanks man blah blah blah and so I gave
him that gave it back to him
and they said just keep it just it's
yours man
so apparently it's a real land spread
and the 77 Jamaican I had have is is far
superior
if you've seen pictures of that
which was taken out of the field in 77.
by a friend
that's interesting and I guess one of
the reasons I was curious about this was
because I had seen you a photo it looks
glorious and uh what I thought was
interesting was whenever I talked to
people about Lamb's breath Lamb's bread
they all say oh you know no the one
you're looking at it's actually Lamb's
bread sour d however that goes around
but people call it lamb spread are you
confident like yeah that's that's
probably not the case
absolutely man I'm pretty confident that
I have a hundred percent Jamaican
pre-1980 hybrid man
so I crossed those two together and I
called it the hinkster bread and I I
gave a 20 portion out of every pack to
the hingster movement of Rastafari
which is Earl China Smith who was reggae
he's one of the greatest reggae
guitarists ever he's Bob Marley's
guitarist blah blah blah blah yeah wow
that's that's a beautiful sentiment to
give back to the community and the and
the land and it's back on the island and
they've told me they've wild fired it
across the island [ __ ] yeah that's
awesome to hear
it's funny because yeah
Dwight told me that hit they they went
to Jamaica years ago to go check out the
Maroons back in the 80s or 90s or
something and they say they didn't have
nothing then
and that's that's the story too because
I asked the rosters man hey go to the
Maroons go check out what people have
there's nothing out there
you know it's gone that's a real shame
isn't it seeing our seeing Greenhouse go
there and like some kind of super Safari
Mission I'm sorry man but there's
nothing there
I just put it back on the island
he's gonna go and find my stuff and pull
it out of the bushes somewhere look what
we found it
it could trade him a bunch of Easter
eggs for it you know
well it does make me wonder why because
like I try to get over to like the
states sort of once a year maybe go to
the emerald cup just to keep my finger
on the pulse and I I always see Ari in
there and he's always welcome with
smiles and handshakes and I'm like why
it's just the name man like I said it's
marketing if you have a name or anything
you know what I mean who was it what was
it uh oh
what happened to Howard marks man didn't
he pay like sixty thousand dollars just
south whoever it was uses likeness until
he died or some [ __ ] oh Shanty Baba with
Mr Nice you know it's just
it's everything's for sale it seems
sure I put like a very sort of specific
type of question do you think that for
example you know we already brought it
up the greenhouse seed crew do you think
that there is some onus on them for like
the way they have arguably [ __ ]
various land races
I think it's [ __ ] up
going into these
reasons and leaving [ __ ] behind
that's [ __ ] up dude
you know that's that's culturally that's
like colonialism man that's like
Christopher Columbus [ __ ] man
totally
get over it get out get out you know get
the [ __ ] out of here it's not proper
it's immoral
I was yeah I was trying to explain it to
a friend who's not really involved in
cannabis so they sort of didn't
understand it and I was like look it's
almost like the the trademarking in a
way like they go there they get the pure
then they pollute it and then they're
the only ones with the pure it's like
they've got a copyright on it or
something like they're the only ones who
have got it and then on top of that
they're not it's not like they're
releasing the lines like if they
released pure stuff from Greenhouse you
could be like oh well you know there's
some Merit but they're not even doing
that
though the truth is man is when they
left with when they when those guys all
split off and got you know
with what they got from Neville
it wasn't as good as what it was
and we all know that
I know it
because my haze is better my haze is
better than their their theirs
yeah yeah interesting stuff I I we could
probably Riff on it forever
um one of the the other questions we got
from one of our listeners was uh are you
able to give us any information in
regards to like the Terps or the yields
on the Congo cut used in the Congo cross
BP Congo
that was really an interesting plan
and I got it from
through a trade from some guy in Africa
who was there and collected it himself
um
greasy
super
um it has a lot of haze features like
it's the grease and the stem and the
that that Carillon Indian scent
that there's there's only one plant on
the earth that smells like Hayes and
it's a corellan Indian
now some Africans have that scent too
and this was one of them
you know
so when you come across that and any
types out here on Earth you're on to
something
you know
yeah
that's Nate that's Nate
um I mean we sort of touched on it
earlier but I'd love to just get a
definitive answer
um what what's your thoughts on how
Greg's Northern Lights compares to your
one do you think they're more similar
than different
okay I'm just gonna say it man I think
it's fake I think it's it's a marketing
play I think it's not real okay
here we go are you ready
long time ago I had a conversation with
kit with chem dog okay and he told me
that it's not a tie it's not a Hawaiian
it was a Java Indonesian and they called
it and I've heard of this before too and
other guys have come at me Yep they're
saying yep that's what it is it's a job
it was it's supposed to be extinct now
it was called they called it the Java
lime green and they described it as
clayon sticks and when I saw this stuff
out of that back cross I was like holy
[ __ ] I had never seen nothing like this
in my entire [ __ ] life it was like
Clay on sticks like clay you could
smoosh it like clay
you know wow
so
with that armed with that information I
began to dissect it you know what I mean
once I figured that out that oh it's not
a tie it doesn't behave like a tie and
Neville doubted that too because it
didn't behave like a tie okay
so now we know that Herbie did nl5 and
it was a Java lime green whether he
admits it or not other people have okay
that's what separates that
now what was back to the other part of
your question
oh Greg's in L5 so what I think they did
was that whatever the story was about
the seeds being the sister's freezer or
whatever
[Music]
these are the original blah blah blah I
think they did have that but they pulled
it out and they just crossed it to any
tide to try in the hopes of having nl5
again didn't work okay I got several
pictures of these plants I got a hold of
Greg's five before other people did
okay
through some Trading
and they're pretty hey they're pretty
it's either no one or it's hey okay
because that's what they did they used
No One by a mysterious tie
you can't fool me okay
yeah wow interesting stuff that's that's
really cool to hear that thanks thanks
for the inside scoop that's my opinion I
could be wrong
but I'm probably not yeah sure no I get
that so I mean while we're on the topic
of nl5 haze we had a viewer submit a
question
um I'm hoping it won't ruffle anyone's
feathers it's not going to ruffle yours
but um without so he says without
throwing the guy under the bus I'd like
to hear his experience on dealing with
uh Mob seeds I understand that mob
advertisers as that he has a pure
Acapulco Gold but it might actually be
some nl5 hybrid I don't care you ready
for this
you ready for this
okay this was a guy we met online okay
and we said come on up here and it will
all go I don't know if you know the
story about can have you heard that name
no I haven't anyway he was he was part
of our group right and we told blue jay
hey come on up and invest you will all
grow a big Garden together you'll be
just happy
well he got up here
he showed up with a U-Haul some lights
and a box full of uh
weed
in baby jars that was so old
it was like you know it looked yellow
all of it
and even he'd open up and say I don't
smoke it but here
and I'm like what
what are you doing carrying all this
[ __ ] around and you don't even smoke
weed
it was like it was it was really
puzzling to us because this guy kind of
sold himself as somebody and then when
he shows up he's somebody else okay
now he's like
well I don't know I don't know if we
have enough money to do this as a man
don't worry about the money I can get
the money okay
look we're just gonna do this don't
worry about it he starts copping out oh
no no it's and I think a lot of it he
starts asking questions about Sue
where's coot live cool you know you
could tell this guy's on a we start
figuring out he's just on a mission to
get genetics
because he didn't want to agree halfway
through the night he's like oh I don't
want to do this I don't think we got
enough money and he starts asking
information about how hey how can we get
these cuts
okay
and I told you I said hey man this guy's
kind of weird
anyway that night he takes off in the
middle of the night okay just splits
gone
what
just like a weirdo you know what I mean
and um
we're like wow I wonder what happened to
him what do we do what do we say was it
our hair
you know
um and that was that and what Hindi what
he'd done is in the middle of the night
he went into the grower room and stole
guts
okay but he didn't get the he didn't get
the one or a blue Orca because I I'm
just on the ball man I'll Trust [ __ ] her
anybody I know what you're up to
you know so
so he goes to coup
and I'd pre-warned him cool
and he's so cute gives him BMR backross
one
I don't know if he gave it to him in
seed or cut
okay I don't know where he got the
Acapulco from but that was my
my
F2 no5 Haze
cut he stole
oh this guy goes out after he [ __ ] us
and just
you know markets himself as whatever and
this and that starts taking my stuff
Crossing it up and selling it and all
this other [ __ ] I'm like wow this guy
and then he takes Coots information that
he said don't don't go and do this I'm
just sharing this information with you
he took enzyme tea recipe and went and
[ __ ] sold it
just a douchebag dude this guy's a
douchebag have I ever seen that guy
again man I'm gonna peel him so hard
just appealing
yeah look that that's uh that's crazy
you know you hear stories about cuttings
getting stolen and stuff and I mean yeah
it's really frustrating stuff I bet no
that didn't over the next 10 years the
guy's releasing all your [ __ ]
your [ __ ] saying that he has the one and
all this other [ __ ]
you know and anytime anybody anybody
confronts him it's just
ignore crickets and that's how a lot of
these guys behave it's like you confront
them and there's no accountability
you know
yeah I know that uh coot and him had had
a falling out so I guess that sort of
lends itself to what you're saying
yeah that's all these falling outs with
Coots is is it has a lot to do with coot
in his medical condition
okay okay
um
I remember one time rolling up there and
he'd been laying he had back surgery
okay because he broke his back and he
could barely walk
and he's laid there in this [ __ ] back
rotten out for however long on [ __ ]
opiates before if any you did anything
about it I mean sometimes he'd be on the
ball sometimes a guy would be just like
half dead
and like I said the last time I talked
to him he had a heart attack and didn't
know who the hell we were
said we lost his lost his collection or
whatever we're like what what are you
talking about you know
no clue
I would like to to get to his wife one
day and tell her hey you know we've
we don't know what's going on here but
we don't have really have any hard
feelings here you know
yeah yeah look I mean it sounds like a
medically complicated situation and you
know obviously we wish Kudo the best but
um yeah it sounds like it would be hard
for you with things sort of changing
depending on his mood if that was how it
was we we actually had a really good
question that I'm I'm a bit bummed I
didn't come up with it myself to be
honest
um from one of our listeners and they
said do you have any secret inputs or
advice for producing nice healthy seeds
and grow organic
use the soil food web
you know that's that's it
yeah sure and you reckon just you know
your standard Organics repertoire is
going to give you some nice seeds well
here let me give you a soil recipe
Pete one part perlite one part compost
and earthworm castings in three equal
portions this is the Cornell University
potting mix that's always been around
that they buried because of
petrochemical Industry back in the 30s
this is the secret behind all your
potting mixes hell yeah I uh I
definitely use that General combo Okay
add any food you want add any calcium
you want add any whatever you want
that's the base mix that's the mechanism
that's the battery you're building a
battery okay
yeah I like that that's a good analogy
charging the seed
well it's it's the soil is like a
battery it has those those ionic charges
in it and when we when we when we were
when the plant gets in there it works
with it through its Exodus
they're they're ionic It Wants What It
Wants it's like okay I need calcium boom
it sends the signal and it happens yeah
nice it releases it from the it releases
it from the negative attraction site and
tail takes it you know molecularly get
into that
once you learn about that all this gross
[ __ ] just Falls away man and you're like
you're just growing herb yeah
that's some great food for thought I
like that I hadn't heard that uh battery
analogy but it certainly actually makes
sense so that's really neat another
question we got from the listeners was
uh someone's sitting on a pack of your
uh Cascadian Frost cross UW hash plant
um any tips on that one what they might
be able to expect
oh those are pretty good man
you know highly Medical
you know good stoner stoner weed ain't
nobody gonna complain about that
I love it I love it well there you go
whoever sent that one in I'm sorry I
don't have your name on hand right now
but crack those bad boys they're
sounding good so nice you know me and me
and a buddy work these and we both did a
good job
lovely so second last question uh sorry
last question before we get into our
quick fire questions which is sort of
the final five or so but one of our
listeners wanted to know if you had any
sort of info about the Thunder [ __ ]
Hayes
um what that is it's
um AK beans brains Matt nuska and
pharmacies
um sheberg and Afghani which is from
Land race uh
you know I forget the damn name land
race collections or whatever it was egg
now oh yeah
yeah land race exchange yes
um
it's crossed together I think AK did it
send it back to Mike Mike
send them to me
um I said yeah I just Bob just put them
on top of my Alaskan by you know Hayes
you know get get all those alaskans in
there together and see what they do
that's awesome get them all together and
playing together and uh so with a haze
and it's just a novelty it wasn't a
serious breed it was a novelty just to
put the alaskans together
you know I didn't really work it much
it's just a novelty but yeah it's
probably good
that's awesome to hear I think novelty
strains can be cool to be honest but um
that's good so we're on to our sort of
final rundown of questions so first one
being out of all the plants you've ever
grown I know there's probably countless
is there one specific one that you
really miss that you think back on at
night and think man if only I still had
that one
at 76 Nigerian man
yeah
yeah what a kick in the ass that was you
know and what a kicking it ass was lose
it too
like I always think about that I always
think about that plant man because it
was so unique you know it was just
absolutely unique nothing like it
beautiful
and that's a great answer and the next
question is sort of a bit similar but a
little bit different at the same time do
you have one specific memory of cannabis
that to you is the most memorable it
might not necessarily be the strongest
weed or anything but it's just for
whatever reason it's memorable
yeah doing five-year mandatory minimum
for growing weed
that's a pretty good answer that's
memorable [ __ ] right there five years in
[ __ ] prison man
out of curiosity when you got really and
by the way thank you for your time um
when you got released what was the first
thing you smoked you must have been
thinking about it like man I'm gonna
puff on this one as soon as I get out
um actually I was really serious when I
got out because I didn't want to go back
in so I didn't smoke you know because I
had to do drug testing I was on I got
five or five okay buried a bus and
[ __ ] grew a bunch of weed in it and
they got cracked you know somebody
knocked on me because they got popped
anyway that's how it goes but when I got
out I was like oh I don't want to smoke
weed or grow weed I'm gonna be a good
boy
because I was getting drug tested right
yeah but then I moved I got a parole
officer who was real cool it's like hey
man I'm not gonna drug test you just
[ __ ] smoke I'm like okay
so it was game on you know started
growing again right away went and got a
loan from a friend
you know while on parole
so I started the seed company and it was
growing on parole
wow bless that parole officer
so five five [ __ ] years of dealing
with these [ __ ] trolls and being on
parole man I there's some people I just
wanted to [ __ ] murder you know
gosh I can imagine all right well let's
go to the other end of the spectrum now
what was something that you were excited
to try people had talked it up to you
and then you finally tried it and you
were like oh is that it
Cuban black Haze
are you gonna ruffle some feathers there
it's just it's not it's not what I
expected it's just it's just another
variant of nl5 haze
because I have a million of them you
know yeah look I can only imagine you
you probably do in fact it's neat it's
cool I mean I appreciated it sure
certainly I'm not dissing it in any way
I'm just saying that it wasn't what it I
expected it's not it's pretty cool but
you know like I said I got all Pockets
full of that stuff
sure sure so
let's say I'm gonna go drop you off on a
desert island and you can only take
three strains with you to grow for the
rest of time what three are you gonna
take they can be either clones or packs
of seeds if you want to do some breeding
the one nazarbate Guero and then all
five hairs hell yeah you feel like you
could probably make most things from
those
yeah it's all there that's everything
you know yeah nice everything you want
okay so on on the other end of the
spectrum you're gonna drop someone off
on this desert island and you're not a
big fan of them you know maybe one of
these people who's given you grief over
the years what are you gonna leave them
with
animal five Haze
just the one
and blue Orca Haze so they get to know
themselves a little bit better
oh that's nice I like that you know the
introspective angle that's good yeah
it'll help you you know help your
problem
so if there was one person and you could
select alive or dead who you could have
a in-depth conversation with about
cannabis who would you want to have a
sit-down chat with
probably never man
you know
I can't really think of anybody else
I talked to his best friend every day
and that's almost the same thing but
it'd be really interesting to pick his
mind and and because I kind of have the
same thought patterns he did back in
1985 as far as hybridization goes he was
a breeder and he knew what he was doing
and I know what the [ __ ] I'm doing too
with it there's a method to this madness
so we're on the same path we're doing
the same thing so in a way you could say
I'm continuing his work and so is Dwight
we're both continuing his legacy by
selecting exactly how he did
and by using his cues and what the
information that he left behind and the
information I'm getting from Dwight and
the information that I have
you know I I agree with you I think I
would definitely pick never if whenever
the emotion involved it's been that way
since the beginning
it's it's like a curse you know
that's a good angle
I haven't heard that yeah
so on to our final question for the
interview if you had a time machine and
you could go back anywhere in history
any place to collect either seeds or
clones where would you go and what would
you collect
well I'd probably show up in Laguna
Beach and see what those guys had in
their surfboards
in 1971.
yeah that's a nice mixture because you
could like get access to different
things at the same time well this was
pre-soviet war stuff too you know
yum I can only imagine the Afghans they
had
oh they're different you know that's why
I'm like the one
yes
I don't know what to tell you I smoke
that [ __ ] you know
that's incredible so look I think with
that being said we're we're just about
at the end of things were there any
general comments or shout outs you would
like to make
oh just anybody who supported me thank
you very much man you know we do this
for you guys you know what I'm doing I'm
doing for other people so that you can
experience that as yourself
so you can take that that's something
you can take to your life to your you
can take that through life with you you
know I'm just I'm just just doing the
rough work out here I'm just putting
I'm putting the pieces together it's up
to you to find the goal
and there's lots of gold in there okay
that's that's what I gotta say
and also I was here before that [ __ ]
Swami select [ __ ] too those
[ __ ] tried suing me for my own
[ __ ] logo twice and you cannot sue a
religious icon
you can't sue Jesus man
uh you know what's funny I actually that
that came up last night when I was
writing questions their page came up and
it's like we've asked him to change his
name and I was like you haven't even
provided me with proof that you were the
first ones to have the name I provided
them with proof that I was first hey it
goes ignored they're capitalists they're
fake I'm the real fake Swami man
because Swami's look listen man swamis
were fake to begin with this was
something that the Western World put
together
okay
the Swami figure you know the mystical
holding on to the crystal ball Swami
thing
you know it's fake it's not real
it never was
not only that he paid he makes people
pay to watch him talk to [ __ ] plants
to ask him if they can be harvested
laughs
I didn't know that
it's insane okay it's just nutty
California nutty stuff you know it's
it's a joke
yeah look I can imagine it's got to be
frustrating but you know thank you so
much gas canistan for taking the time to
come on the show today for sharing a
whole bunch of knowledge and a bunch of
information about your crosses we're
really grateful to have had you on
yeah man thank you for the opportunity
to let me say a few things that I kind
of needed to say too because like you
said man there's like there's a there's
a handful of people that follow me
around that are just disgruntled
employees that like to to slander people
like that you know and it comes from the
Forum days when we had to ban people
that behave poorly
from I see mag all the way up through
all the forums that we had is just
reverberations of the poor poor taste
so anyway peace
[Music]
[Applause]
there you have it my friends a huge
thank you again to gas for taking the
time to come on the show share some of
these histories thoughts and knowledge
likewise huge thank you to you the
listener for making it this far I
encourage you please go check out our
sponsors they are truly fantastic seeds
here now number one seed bank in the
industry check them out guys they got
all the hottest drops likewise keep your
garden happy and healthy get copper
biological systems these guys kill it
they'll keep your garden pets from
pathogen free
shout out to ogs organic gardening
Solutions the organic home is down under
top shelf seed banks for all your
genetic needs Down Under
please
and last but not least huge shout out to
the patreon game you guys are truly the
lifeblood of the show Without You
episodes could not happen if you're
interested in helping support the show
all while getting early access to
episodes unheard additional content
prizes and giveaways check out the
patreon
and I guess that's it for this one son
I'll see you for the next one
[Music]
I'll see you
foreign
[Music]