hello and welcome to the next episode of
the podcast cannabis podcast for budding
enthusiasts
this episode as always is brought to you
by
seeds here now your premier store for
seeds guaranteed not only on germination
but also satisfaction
as well as 420 australia your number one
store for lifestyle and apparel
and finally the good folk over at
organic gardening solutions you want
that top shelf hit em up
on this episode we're joined by bushy
old grower otherwise known as bog
[Music]
here to get some old school knowledge
some predictions for the future and some
other cool tidbits
let's get into it
alright so i'd like to welcome on to the
show a true veteran of the scene a man
known as bushy old grower or simply bog
thank you so much for joining us
well thank you for having me daddy i
appreciate it and i'm happy to talk to
your folks this would be great
so a little deviation from the normal
first question what are you currently
smoking on at the moment
well my wife and i are old school you
know been smoking many years together
and
uh we're smoking my sour bubble it's an
elite breeder clone that we've had like
17 years now
and sour bubble is really a very unusual
selection out of my straight bubble gum
it was supposed to be straight bubble
gum it was
bubble gum from amsterdam
and i called it bog bubble my version of
it you know
and and we grew that for years
every once in a while and with the
originals that we noticed that there
were
an occasional different phenotype and it
wasn't always exactly the same but
compared to bubble gum
the sour bubble as i called it
was a darker green and looked a lot
lot its leaf structure and plant
structure
like 398 bubba kush
and uh it doesn't quite have that kind
of flavor
but it's kind of uh
almost as cushy as bubble gummy you know
for like above a kush it's kind of
unusually cushy
and we had it uh
tested when we originally
had that clone cut and that was
up in anna when we lived in bozeman
and it was 30.5
resin weight
uh now that's all the thcs and the cbds
and all that put together
but back at that time
which was like you know 2001 i think
that was a really really high thc clone
that we selected out of the bubble
government was normally
uh
much lower you know
more in the range of around 20 percent
thc usually just delicious and
everything you know but
this was a lot stronger and a lot
tighter
and maybe didn't yield quite as much but
we had that sour bubble clone and we all
just loved it you know
the uh
the high is really quite indica sided
it's probably my most indica strain and
it uh even has a little trait of the uh
leaf hands where like pre-98 bubba kush
one of the tiniest little leaves
sticks up like a finger like you know
the three stooges is called a teacup
with their little finger sticking out
somebody's showing me a picture of their
pre-98 bubba
wow and so when you found the sour
bubble clone
was your first thought like i want to
find the male version of this since you
had the seed stock
well yes exactly and you know what this
is the thing
uh i had or two or three of these
different versions and we decided this
clone this was this was it we were just
calling it super bog bubble at the time
and my son who's also you know all he's
a
42 year old man down he was a man at the
time
was was helping me and he he decided and
i did that this was the one we
definitely wanted to
keep
just and breed with it
well we were growing from seed
commercially up there in montana now i
may have inadvertently um
violated a few statutes but in montana
uh you may a man's home mrs castle and
you can pretty much do what you want to
do in your home
and they they can't get a search warrant
for in a private owner's home at all
even if they think they're fairly safe
growing our own way there we did it back
in michigan too
but uh we
had kept growing the bog bubble
which was supposed to be straight bubble
gum but was obviously really above a
kush
and uh
it took
two years of continuously growing from
seed
uh to come up with the mail and i
finally did and it just it just appeared
and you could smell it and you could see
it and it was obviously a sour bubble
mail and it was like you know a gift
from above i mean honestly i had been
hoping and not seeing anything like it
because it's quite different than the
bubblegum version that i have you know
isolated in the blog bubble side and so
we were able then to make that first
cross and then keep back crossing to
uh the original clone selection
and the sour bubble became a big hit
back at the same time on overgrow
which was like you know the big mega
site back then
that the guy i sent my seeds to
came out with what was called og kush
and it was the first ochi kush
that any of us that overgrow
oh i know there's all kinds of stories
about where it came from but uh i knew
that he had it and he sent me seeds and
clones of his version and i knew that we
both had
you know different versions and i didn't
you know i didn't call mine that i
i came up with the name sour bubble
right and who was that person online
well i don't remember
it's a long time ago and the guy did
acknowledge this his clone no longer
exists
um this would be something to be
investigated but you know i mean back in
the day we just you know knew each other
by names and stuff and didn't keep
anybody's names or addresses but
i had sent him
my bog bubble seeds and my boggle gum
seeds which is blog bubble cross with
nl5
and that he had had selected this clone
out of either one or the other okay i'm
not even sure which one but i had
assumed
out of the bog bubble
yep
so if we take a step back all the way to
the start now before we get too deep
into things what was your first
experience with cannabis
oh wow
well that was a long time ago
i think i was
only 13 years old
and i had moved from birmingham michigan
to algonac michigan which was on the
water on the saint clare river which is
part of the great lakes system and
beautiful
and the new friends i met and we
had boats and stuff and we could go camp
on this island called go island
and it was just paradise for like young
teenagers no parents and
you know i mean we could take beer or
anything well one of my friends from
birmingham came up to visit and go with
us to do this and he had brought some
pot
for me to try
and i don't know why but he didn't even
want to smoke it he had just gotten it
was like enough to fill up by a good
sized tobacco pipe and probably had a
few seeds in it you know
and anyhow
i was the only one
who smoked it
and we got to the island we set up our
little tent or whatever
and everybody was having a great time
and
i remember i sat down and i smoked that
whole pipe load i mean we were we were
cigarette smokers anyhow so i i didn't
have much trouble at age
token down that big tobacco pipe full of
weed and it was probably like some
mexican weed with a few seeds in it
and i got a damn good buzz off it i mean
it took me about 15 minutes to smoke it
i think
and this was a fun night let me tell you
man
this island is only about i don't know
half a mile long and it's just sand with
a few trees on it i guess and you can
run around the whole damn thing in about
half an hour probably
but
i mean it was two or three other guys
were out there after i got high and
running around on the beach and
fooling around the water and i was just
stoned and i've never been stoned before
i didn't really know all i knew was i
was happy i was having a good time
and before i knew it there i see that
they're laughing at me
and this is my one little friend who had
brought the tobacco up i mean the the
marijuana up for me to smoke
uh he was laughing the hardest and it
looked to me like he was he was putting
his his pecker away and what's going on
here and he said you didn't even notice
did you and i said what he says i peed
on your leg
you know we're like standing in the
water but no i had not i had not felt
any pee hit my leg i said it did not
you know so anyhow
that was the first uh
you know adventure i guess on pot and
you know i could tell you what happened
is we fooled around out there for a
while
we ended up i went back to the tent i
had the munchies like mad i didn't
i i actually i ate like a dozen donuts
and drank like a two liter bottle of
cola
and i probably smoked about a pack of
cigarettes i had a damn good night
that's a great story i like that a lot
so
from there did you you know decide that
weed was your thing and you began to
smoke it regularly or was there some
time before you become like a regular
smoker and got really engulfed in it
well that's interesting i did love it
and i i don't think that was actually
one of those like totally addicting
moments though because no i wasn't right
out seeking it or anything like that and
it seems to me though
that the next time i got high
uh that a buddy of mine and i
and i don't know
i can't remember that
but we got high we went to a carnival
and we rode the loophole plane
and you know the one where you hold the
break and the eggs sort of go upside
down
well it
you lose all the change in your pockets
of course and you know that's how they
get a little extra money for the carnies
but we had a ball on that ride i
remember that ride i mean the buddy yes
making that thing spin and we were so
high
and that was the second time and that
was the time that i really thought geez
i've got to have this weed more often so
i think it took a couple of happy
evenings on it to then be convinced you
know and i and i was then getting in
there
at an age of like
uh
for sure by 16 but but i think
at 15 i i had weed about half of the
time because we could get bags of weed
wasn't very good
but a lid of weed which was like you
know maybe a half an ounce even
for for as little as 10 bucks
maybe 12 bucks
and it was a guy named chief
that we had indians that lived across
the river
so in algonac it wasn't too hard to find
a guy named chief who might sell a kid
some weed
and uh being a buddy could could get a
lid from him for 12 usually
damn that's good
so
at what point did you decide you wanted
to start growing yourself and not just
be a buyer
well uh we
even teenagers in high school were
experimenting with growing pot we lived
in michigan
which is a very northerly state in the
u.s and you know you you
you get a fairly well of course we
didn't really have the right kind of
seeds it would finish early enough
but i remember that we were growing a
few plants in the woods behind a friend
of mine's house
uh back when we were only like 15.
but we weren't having much success but
we got some leads and i remember
that his name was todd and
and he was uh he had a bag of
leaves you know they chopped up and of
course we smoked some of them
and he was actually rolling joints and
selling joints in school and as i recall
they were
uh you know like
uh really cheap you know like
i can't remember how she made they might
even be as cheap as three for a dollar
and uh you know like 50 cent joints
so that's what i recall and they really
really weren't worth any more than that
because you know they couldn't have had
like more than a half of a percent of
thc
but you know
when your kids
bought anything you can get right
make it work
that's
we did actually though uh start trying
to grow in earnest shortly after i got
married
uh
my my wife and i got married when we
were 18 years old and not because we had
two we had been going steady into high
school years for two and a half three
years
she's a wonderful girl and uh pat and i
uh
got married and then we had this
apartment for a year up at the college
where i was going to school
and uh my dad bought an old farmhouse
just because he was buying the property
up in that area and i had some family up
there in
central michigan
and so you know oh there was this old
vacant house i went looked at it and
asked if i could live in there and he
said sure
so uh once we were out there which is
like when i probably was less than 19 i
was probably still 18.
we were growing weed outside and
uh
you know i was working on outdoor
growing
and it was kind of difficult but you
know i had some limited success
and we were still usually mostly
having to buy her from somebody
but you know we we always managed to
have a little bit of it around and did
eventually get better at growing
i did eventually get some plants to
flower in the summertime and realize
how good cincimelia could be
and that was before i really even knew
what it was
and that was probably in about
right
the uh
really what helped me living in michigan
was they came out with something called
a halide light
and i was already growing indoors before
the halided light was invented
and i had been doing high output
fluorescence
grow tubes that were like eight feet
long
and i also had some regular fluorescence
and four foot things and so i had a room
that could
uh it was you know equivalent to maybe a
thousand watt room now or something like
that one big row of plants
and i had some limited success with that
but then the limited genetics that i was
able to obtain back then
uh i would tend to get things that were
you know that would run under lights
like that so when the halide light came
out
all of a sudden i was able to grow top
grade since amelia
and uh i
had also
upgraded from my own seeds that i had
worked on for years you know even back
in michigan
uh but that i had then brought out to
montana when i moved out there
and in earnest started trying to you
know work on seeds and i even
well i went through a whole progression
of different stages but finally got some
genetics from
amsterdam and some from canada
uh and that sort of got my company
started without intending to
okay and the stuff you were working on
prior to that did you do you still use
any of that at all or is it kind of just
being outdated
well the the first things that i worked
was were from michigan and some of it
was just bag seed
that i had crossed to this one strain
that a friend of mine had in michigan
and uh
you know he had an indoor halide light
too but he had done some outdoor growing
there
and
his strain was called blanchard strain
which blanchard's a small town in
central michigan
very rural
but his his
plan i remember was just delicious
and i cried i had you know what i called
red was my own original first strain
and uh my strain red
tasted good and and people liked it
but uh
his strain the blanchard strain was a
lot stronger and it seemed more
indicated
and very sweet and it must have had some
skunk in it it seems to me
and and i'm not sure what else but it
was a very sweet
with the very bitter skunky leaves you
know
and it just
hard to say for sure i mean it wasn't
like anything from local
but uh stuff that had been around back
when
uh the grateful dead were passing out
is there something like a long time ago
well yeah
and if they
actually neither of those strains
ended up in any of
the world once we were selling seeds so
no i don't have those anymore they're
just be so old now they wouldn't work
i have had luck with seeds older than 10
years old and i do keep old seeds
but no i don't have those anymore
in when you look on your library with
all the genetics you've collected over
the years is there any older stock that
you've got in there that you might want
to work with but you're thinking oh it's
a bit old i might not really be able to
get it to germinate
oh i see what you're saying well
we of course are always working on
something new
and uh
with my
company and the way i do things
sometimes it's a long time between a new
strain because
we got up to like 15 strains and
uh it became difficult as a small
mom-and-pop operation to keep them all
in stock
and i don't like discontinuing strengths
too much because i you know my niche is
old school and i
try to preserve the genetics as i got
them
originally now i i have wonderful
genetics that i was gifted by friends
that people when they knew that i was a
breeder at overgrow and we were actually
selling my seeds worldwide
well i was the first american breeder to
sell seeds worldwide through gypsy
uh
nobody was doing that from here and then
i brought a couple other guys in
reservoir seeds red dog he became a big
deal
and you know
he was a friend of mine and i was the
one who talked gypsy into
bringing him in because he had so many
good genetics you know
but in my old school genetics and res
dog would say this that that bog had the
gum
and the fact is that the way we worked
and progressed in each of our strains
all my strains have bubble gum in them
they used to call me the bubble gum guru
there's a little story about the bubble
gum that i'd like to tell you
you know when i was a little kid
i was a little businessman of a little
kid
i was always uh
thinking about how to buy something
cheap and sell it high honestly i mean
when i was only
10 years old i was buying and selling
switchblade knives i got some from italy
and i also when we were traveling
managed to to gamble and use slot
machines and make money and
so i was always thinking about this well
when i was really young one of the first
times i got any money in my hand it was
like five dollars you know
and i went down to the horse stable
where they sold publica
now that's why this story is because i
got a box with 500 pieces of bubble gum
in it and that was my first stash
this was the gateway drug they talked
about pure sugar and it tasted like
bubble gum
so i took that box of bubble gum and i
took it home and i guess i had to stash
it somewhere so i hid it in the garage
and i found a spot in the garage and
luckily the mice didn't get them or
maybe they got some and i didn't know
but
i used to go and grab me 20 pieces or so
or my bubble gum and head to the movie
theater and you know i'd be chewing
bubble gum like a wacko
so
i was an abuser of bubble gum well when
i got bubble gum seeds from
amsterdam later when i was a grower the
last thing i really expected what darn
buds would actually smell like bubble
gum
but we grew the plants and we hoped for
the best and when
the plants got to be like
four weeks and before
i was fooling around and
sniffing them and i rubbed a step
smelled my fingers and my mouth
dropped open enough what the hell
it smells like bubble gum i mean how do
you how could that be possible and i
went up and i told my wife and son we
were both upstairs
i was living in montana i had a montana
basement it was only like five feet high
it was horrible you had to stoop all the
time and you couldn't use
big lights because of the height
restriction but
it smelled like bubble gum and i went up
and i told them that and they both
doubted my work they can't believe that
dad tells them and they don't think so
and i
i said look you go down there
and you just check it out for yourself
and they did and they both came back
upstairs and their mouths were hanging
open too
and i'll tell you bubble gum really
smells like bubble gum before it gets
done
and they were like how is that possible
i said well the name that's on the seats
there you know it it's actually uh
supposed to be a bubble gum
and uh
we grew that and we were amazed uh for
one thing that it was a decent yielder
and we really liked the high the indica
high was very relaxing and stuff we
thought it was plenty strong enough for
us
what i thought most about it was it was
like candy
that uh who cares if it wasn't the
strongest thing you could grow wasn't as
strong as skunk or something like that
but
i just couldn't believe how yummy it was
and i mean that's all we smoked for
years
until we got hooked on the sour bubble
and then
that ended up being no like we got
totally addicted to that
wow there's a lot of things i'm gonna
have to ask questions about the
so the first one is
do you remember who you got your bubble
gum from breeder wise and is it the same
as the one adam dunn took over there
oh well actually you know it's drunker's
bubble gum and he deserves some credit
uh my seeds were obtained through white
label seed company
before they called it double gum
they did call it
bubble gum
and
uh i had a small selection of those
seeds
and you know he was the third guy
who also had cloned the real bubblegum
clone
so uh i say yeah
you know i met and talked to adam and
the other guys and the only one i didn't
mean to talk to was was ben drunkers
no okay interesting
um and so
the next question i had which i think
everyone wants to know is
basically
a lot of people sent me in questions
asking me to ask you about this so i
thought i better bring it up your
relationship with the infamous res dog
so
the the
question which struck me the most was a
lot of people are familiar with sour dub
but they may not you know realize that
it's obviously like a collab between you
and res how did that happen and how did
you meet res
well res dog and i were friends online
back in the overgrow days in the icy mag
days uh from before he was a seed dealer
and uh
the sour dub was a cross i made
of
um
the new york city diesel from soma
to my sour bubble clone
and uh
it doesn't have anything to do with any
of rezdog's genetics
oh there you go maybe i missed it
just um i might end up having to cut
this question out because it looks like
i made a blunder there but did you guys
do it collab i think i maybe just
misspoke when i said sourdough
um the the the question isn't uh
wrong man i'll tell you there's
definitely been some rumors
around about
uh either sour dub or sour bubble
somehow be it
some kind of joint project between a
rash dog and me
and i'm sure he would confirm that
that's that's really not true
he may have sent me a few seeds at one
time or another
but uh as far as the sour bubble and the
sour double
and you know with the sour double i
didn't take that too far
i gave those first cross secrets to i
dub
out here in california
and he worked with that first cross
seats and gave me credit for the strain
and so
uh
i can tell you that my original cross
that i gave him
uh was that's what it was was so much
new york city diesel
and my sour bubble clone
and as it turned out i should have kept
that and bred that and made that a
strain for myself
uh because it turned out to be really
darn good and you know a lot of great
things have descended from sour double
uh the name sour double is a misnomer
uh because of the fact that
the uh the sour diesel in my sour double
wasn't sour diesel but was new york city
diesel
and so you got
sar bubble with one sour
and the other one actually new york city
diesel
so
uh
i didn't name it that
yeah okay i understand what you're
saying
so
one of the other questions i wanted to
ask you about res is do you still stay
in contact with him and the the profile
that popped up recently or you know a
few months back do you know if that was
the actual res and if he does plan to
return to the scene
no i haven't been in touch with him
since before he had some problems you
know and
we were both doing you know
sort of the same thing so
no we haven't been in contact with each
other at all and as far as whether
the person who you're talking about i
haven't seen that or or read that
so
i can't help you there but it's possible
it's him as far as i know he's out and
free and
it could be
okay and so i guess the final question
is you feel free to decline i can cut
this one out if you don't want to
ultimately do you think he's the snitch
that some people label him as
well i don't know i honestly wouldn't
have any way to know that i i you know a
lot of these things are
are stuff that people read on the
internet and while i do know some people
and maybe have had
some inside stories nobody ever
convinced me that he's on anybody and uh
i i guess nothing that he did but i sure
can't say that he did
yeah okay
so if we just jump back to another point
you mentioned with the bubblegum story
your relationship with gypsy gypsy is an
interesting guy and there's not that
many people around who had like a
working relationship with him who was
still active what's your take on the
gypsy situation and you know have you
had any contact with him after he got
out of
jail i think at the start of the year
yes but i'm not really in regular
contact with him now but i did uh
he did
have an exchange
online
since he got out i know that
a wonderful friend of ours a buddhist
who sort of brought me into buddhism and
his name is tom
actually went over to the philippines
and sort of paid gypsy's way out
of this horrible
like detention facility you know he was
never convicted of any crime or anything
and the fact is that that's all it took
was money to get him out of their
corrupt
system
you know to be held without being
charged with the crime and they tried to
send him back to the u.s
and uh
he actually fought
as they were trying to board him on the
plane it was going to take him to the
u.s because the u.s wanted to extradite
him
yeah and because he caused a commercial
they uh they took him back to the
holding facility
and it he didn't he ended up not being
extradited to the us lucky film because
you know guys like him uh they they
really would throw in the book at him
yeah okay
and so
i think um the interesting thing about
gypsy is it's kind of like back at that
same time frame is when overgrow was
around and i think you have kind of the
uh the cool fact of being able to say
you were the 12th member on overgrow
which is obviously
kind of confirms your ogenes
do you think though that people look
back on overgrow with the sort of
rose shaded glasses and there's a
certain sense of romanticizing going on
or do you think that it is kind of like
what people make it out to be of like
where it was this mecca of information
and it's such a shame we don't have
something like that anymore
when overgrow opened it was like a
birthday present to me i mean if you
realized what there was before that was
practically nothing and um the british
columbian seed company had a forum
thread where there was like one page
with one constant thread where people
could add something to the chat line you
know and that was it
and i remember i posted my whole um
indoor organic grow tips uh you know for
for new growers on that
like chat forum thing
and even though it wasn't really meant
for that they didn't object
and then when overgrowth came out
um i right away had this same thread
there and it evolved into a thing where
for like years people would just come in
and ask a question
and it was you know these were really
long threats i remember they had a room
called the sharks tank
and that was where anything goes you
know and uh
i had a thread called the new world
order
and it was it you know had some
conspiracy theory stuff in it and stuff
and you know bog bush kill grower
i mean there was a aspect of some
mythology
i mean we were kidding around and joking
around and you know my great great great
great great great granddaddy
wasn't really an alien who came down to
egypt with marijuana seeds because the
sun is a perfect grow light
but we came up with stuff like that you
know i didn't even did me any harm
that's great that's a crack up and so
what was your kind of reaction to when
it all got shut down
well it was it was horrifying because we
were doing business we they had uh each
seed company like like weld gypsy
nirvana and his like seeds direct at the
time or whatever was called
and we had our own
forum
and so like before overgrow actually
shut down
uh rc who ran overgrow and was connected
with bc seed bank and stuff
decided to close down all the private
seed forums
which had sort of put us off of the the
public pages and into our own forums so
that we wouldn't offend it
but that's what overgrow was all about
and teaching each other how to grow i
wanted to talk about overgrow because it
was it was better than you think it
wasn't over romanticized it was
awesomely huge for the time you know
al gore he claims he invented the
internet
but i
helped to invent social networking
because
at overgrowth we had what was called
karma and you could give somebody good
or bad karma and giving bad karma was
bad but they actually could you could do
it okay
and so
i
quickly accumulated a lot of good karma
uh because i was teaching people basic
methods of growing indoors in a time
when it was all totally illegal and
nobody knew anything you know and it was
like to be able to get this off your
computer i mean people were sitting
around high learning how to grow and as
soon as they learned something they were
teaching it to the next guy and this was
really a great thing you know i mean if
you love marijuana
this is why you know so many people in
the world
know me it's because i was a big deal at
overgirl and you know i was just posting
my pictures of my
flowers to show off
and i never had planned on having a seed
company at all
i mean i was just happy
growing my weed and selling my weed i
mean prices were good
but then
uh gypsy nirvana who was the seed dealer
he
saw how popular i was how many views i
had how much karma i had i mean i was on
there every day i wasn't working i was a
grower i was spending 20 hours a week
and i
was uploading photos every day and i was
showing all kinds of cool stuff it was a
lot of fun because it was all new the
internet was new the idea of posting a
picture
was you know awesome
and uh so i just want
to say that
my teaching threads and uh my our
picture
forum show-off threads we had contests
and things overgrow was really pretty
far out and it still suffered from the
same kind of things we have now like we
have trolls and things but you know one
year we had this big contest at overgrow
and there was like five
or ten categories of things people could
win and top one was grower of the year
and uh
yours truly did win grower of the year
the only year that over
did that content and so many people
voted for me
because of popularity not really because
i was the best grower you see
and so it was because i had my fan base
because people liked me because
you could they could see that i was
answering everybody's questions every
day
and so i was providing a service where
anybody could come into my thread i mean
i wasn't the only one but my methods
were simple and basic and it was all
written so that any idiot could figure
it out
and so what would you say is the biggest
difference in the community when
comparing things between now and back
then
well it's changed a lot
you know there are still sites like that
like um
still exists and runs and there's still
some traffic there but
social networking has evolved you know
and i mean everybody's on um
their instagram the twitters the youtube
and the big sites have sort of like
sucked up all the
all the others and and overgrow was a
huge mega site in its day i mean it had
over a million
members i guess that probably wouldn't
be that big a deal now but not that many
people were on the internet back then
and that sounded you know even people
that just came one time might have been
considered a member you know who knows
if they jacked it but we had a lot of
people there and when you put something
out you definitely got a bunch of
responses in a hurry but i like the way
instagram is now and i like the way
things have evolved the truth is that uh
it was tedious
wading through the threads in the forums
and now
it seems like it evolved in a natural
way where you decide that you want to
follow somebody like i'm on instagram
and you can just you know look for bog
or bog seeds
and you you can become a follower on our
feed
and every time i post a new picture or
say something
you get a little notice that hey your
guys up you want to have a look
so i kind of i like it it's like i get
an instant response
from the instagram it's where i do most
of my stuff now
yeah i agree with a lot of those points
and so i guess kind of maybe the last
question about overgrowth
were there any people who you saw back
in the early days of overgrow and you
had a feeling they would go on to do
bigger things and you know true to form
that prediction has come true and now
maybe they're you know some of the more
relevant people in the industry
well i'm sure that's true it's been so
long ago that i mean i got most of these
people like we all we knew each other by
was
was our online handles
and uh you know i'm not i'm not the best
with names but i've been out doing
events for a long time and we run into
each other
and uh when we do it's fun and i like
the fact that people recognize me
from
on overgrow
and that they want to meet me
because
they really thought i was you know like
a huge leader on the site and then at
the time there i was and i was a good
guy you know i mean i was always telling
people to be nice and terrible and
honestly i i
i fooled around and maybe was a little
off color sometimes about i would say
things like
that my plants you know because they
were they
were girls or cincinalia that they were
my virgins you know
and we would make jokes sometimes that i
guess you know once in a while could
have been a little too much
but we were just having fun
and it compared to some of the stuff you
see out there now the overgrowth was
pretty tame
it seemed like that was fairly well
moderated
and that
i know that i couldn't get away with
just anything
and that
neither could anybody else so honestly i
think that that sometimes there's less
responsible
uh places where they're you know there's
chats all over the place every game's
got one and things like that so
you know there's all kinds of trolls out
there being nasty we had a pretty nice
place
fantastic so
i know that you have put out some um
soil mixes of your own maybe a bit of a
redundant question but are you an
organic grower or more like a synthetic
slash bottled nutrients grow
well i've always promoted organic
methods and while some people have said
maybe i'm not always totally organic on
everything you know i had a guy dispute
that pete you know like peat moss in
your soil
that that's not organic well it seems
organic to me anyhow
it's not it's organic enough and i try
to stay away from anything synthetic
and you know like insecticides and
things like that aren't even legal in
california you can't even buy them
so they have all kinds of alternative
treatments and things that don't involve
that but you know i i've been through
all kinds of things and we've used all
kinds of stuff different stages now we
know better you know like
if you know what you're doing you don't
get too many pests
uh because you know there are good
products or if you're doing it indoors
you're not letting any of that get
inside anyhow
but uh
yeah so i guess my question then is
because you've probably had a really
wide exposure to you know over the years
you've tried a whole bunch of different
samples from a variety of different
growers
do you think at the absolute pinnacle of
both organic production and synthetic
production do you think there's still a
difference do you think like organic is
still the best when they're both at
their optimal levels or do you think
it's just still you know devils in the
detail type of thing
i think organic still best and i'll tell
you why
i know that
yields can be larger and it's really not
an issue of that
but i do think that the flavor is better
and you know
all the
growers that are are growing outdoors
and growing in greenhouses are also in
competition with
organic products that are grown in
yours too and
believe me that's the the best product
and the highest prices given for indoor
organic
now
indoor generally brings a higher price
than
than the outdoor of course and
especially
you know if you think you can get the
same quality i'd like i'd like to see it
but a controlled environment and you
know
i know
that you know
but being outdoors is rougher on plants
and finishing plants indoors allows you
to get the quality higher
and so overall are you just primarily
indoor guy or is your favorite outdoor
or where do you sit
we're mainly indoor growers and now you
know we're mainly just a pretty small
grow to produce seeds and it's like uh
not not producing a lot of we just we
need for my family
uh and a little extra
but uh we are trying to uh
downsize in a way that we've pretty much
just produced enough seeds to keep the
business going and about the level it's
going right now we really don't want to
uh
become a huge company in fact some of my
best friends you know
advised me that it is best to keep it
small
it does seem to me that it's a lot less
worrisome you know we don't have to have
employees or
a whole lot of complications because you
know i'm i'm getting older i'm getting
ready to retire i'm nearly 64.
and what i would like to do is just be
able to keep supplying
distributors and and live economically i
don't need to live large anymore i've
done that
no frugal man i like that
so i mean just kind of touching on
distributors
do you ever get requests from
distributors or maybe even fans and
customers probably the more relevant
person to
kind of
change up some of the genetics and i
guess the question i always like to ask
people is when i notice that a breeder
tends to stick to a more old-school pool
of genetics a good example is our friend
the mad farmer he like you sticks to the
old school stuff that he knows
with that in mind do you ever consider
giving in to the request to maybe bring
in a strain of the month and spice
things up a bit
yeah but i'm still like the old school
guy who does it that kind of resists
that
and that's because
if i really had the time to do the work
with something else i still think that
i'd rather continue to
work on and select from
my old school genetics and it's not very
often
i mean okay
there are great strains and they come
out you think i should jump on this one
or that one
like when sour diesel first showed up
well maybe better or get some of that
wasn't really my thing okay i really
would rather you know be related but not
the same
and and come up with my own
now a project that i'm working on right
now
is all my old genetics but
uh used in a different way and
another project that i'm considering
doing
is taking some high quality pollens from
another fine breeder
and using that probably on my sour
bubble clone
because it seems to be have the genetics
still the old clone may have declined a
bit as far as the
quality of its buds over so many years
but
its genetics are still throwing awesome
phenotypes and
so yeah there is a possibility that
within the next year or two
uh or less than a year that will at
least be working on
something crossed to my sour bubble that
is from someone else
um
currently i do have a new strain
that is across of a couple of my strains
it's been reselected and worked on
it's a high yielder and it's uh
more inclined to be a great outdoor bush
but these
also tend to yield well inside
we have
a number of strains that are good
yielders and mold resistant and
where i'm at here
the outdoor growers need mold resistant
we're kind of coastal
uh
and there's a lot of growers in
california that are
and uh the
other parts of the country
everybody in the fall
when the weather turns colder and it
gets cold at night it doesn't even have
to rain
for the mold to set in and outdoor
growers you know it's real really
disappointing you know
and so
i'm working on these types of strains
the strain is going to be called
bluetooth
and it's actually across my blue moon
rocks and my sweet cindy now sweet cindy
everybody
tended to think was like mostly going to
be like cinderella 99 and there is a
little cinderella 99 in but it's a lot
more like sweet tooth three
and the fact is that that's what the
sweet in the sweet cindy
stands for
now the blue moon rocks and the sweet
cindy
will
already have shown to ingesting
produce some mega fat colas and so we're
pretty excited about it we know that
it's good tasting
and good weed and that it is mold
resistant so we've gone ahead with this
cross and we hope to be releasing it
later this year
wow that's exciting
so
i mean just to touch on the point you
made about the mould resistance i
noticed that you do list
in some kind of
descriptions that you like to breed for
mould resistance and hardiness in
general do you feel that
in order to do this it's done mostly via
a selection process or more of like a
byproduct of the fact that you're
breeding and acclimatizing them in an
environment which would help to cater
for that
well that's a good question
you know
for one thing i'll tell you this
a lot of times things boil down to being
a little simpler than you think but
not always
the mold resistant strains
are not the most indica sided ones okay
in my experience the sativas
being you know
uh not so large heavy and tight of buds
uh just tend to resist it better
also the really dark green
leafy types
seem to me to be more likely to mold and
so
my most indica strains
and blue moon rocks is quite indica
sided but it doesn't mold and so it's
not just that
um
we
did grow in places and you asked for an
indoor grower no we grew outdoors too
and some of my seeds have been made
outdoors and we're made outdoors even if
they're
also been made indoors and so
we were thinking about
two different things in our different
kinds of plants
and
that one type of plants they either have
to be early finishing
or mold resistant and likely to finish
in most places
and the early finishers are my
sour strawberry my blue kush
the mold resistant large yielders that
finished in time
are
boggle gum
you see boggle gums got nl5 with the
bubble gum it's like antifreeze from the
great white north and nothing stops that
lifesaver which we haven't talked about
very mold resistant large yield or great
outdoors and sweet sydney also
so uh the uh
lifesaver the boggle gum and the blue
moon rocks
and the sweet cindy
uh yield well finish in reasonable time
and resist the mold now
it's been true and it continues to be
true
and all i can
say is that i do my best
not to just keep inbreeding my seeds but
to do a rotation where i go back to an
earlier
set of seeds that i've saved in my
breeders seeds and you know i keep
clones it's just that you know at times
you have to reselect clones
but i've kept the same
sour bubble clone the longest which is
essential to all my sour strains and
blue kush
yeah definitely one of the more
long-held ones
so i mean if we just touch on something
you mentioned a question or two ago
about i think you said you know like it
would have been neat to know that sour
diesel was going to be the big thing at
the time but you know there was other
reasons why you didn't get into it just
on that general line of thought what's
your opinion on the general trending
nature of strains do you kind of keep an
eye on what's on the come up and would
you ever try to be ahead of the curb so
to speak like do you ever get the
feeling that maybe some bubble gum slash
you know the kind of your flavors are on
the rise and would you try to anticipate
that if so
well i you know i i may not be quite as
up-to-date on everything as i was back
in the day but
it does seem some of the work that's
being done with the couple of africans
you know
people are raving about and that there
may be some things that you know i'm not
aware of and that i haven't even tried
but you're right about people giving me
seeds
at samples and uh
events that i have a lot of people
who
like remember me from long ago and they
see me and they know i'm gonna be there
or whatever and they bring seeds for me
and so a lot of other
guys you know startup companies
good growers
i mean you know
we definitely respect some of the newer
companies than us so don't get me wrong
on that it's just that there are so many
small companies now that you know
everybody seems
to jump bandwagon with the new popular
strain and you know i i've been a couple
of times attempt i mean to me girl scout
cookies is pretty remarkably my type of
weed okay
uh uh it definitely got choices of 398
bubba in it
that uh i love our bubble is it in there
sorry what was that last bit you think
maybe some sour bubbles in there
well i just mean that the pre-98 bubba i
believe is in the sour bowl and that's
part of the reason i love girl scout
cookies too because i think i i taste it
in there
yeah yeah i've heard that comment a few
times as well so while we're on the
topic of you know seed businesses and
just that general nature what's your
opinion on what some would describe as
the rising nature of seed prices
because some breeders have pointed out
that most people are relatively charging
about the same thing if you compare the
prices in while accounting for inflation
to say companies in the 90s however
there's obviously a lot of clear
examples where this there are people
charging you know quite large price tags
associated with their seeds and it's
obviously not proportional how do you
feel about this general idea you know do
you think there should be a limit do you
think it's just a capitalist thing where
it's like you know if someone wants to
pay where do you sit on it
well i always wanted to be competitive
and the thing is uh
i didn't want to be the lowest or the
highest
i think that it's important that you
provide a good value and
i i don't know i think if something's
brand new
and they want to auction it off and they
can get a high price for it
if something's really good enough that
that people will pay their prices for
you can't blame people
for i mean you know businesses business
and
they're probably going to charge what
they can but
i
i think that there's a little bit of
old school business morality that a lot
of people could
and that is that
you want the customer to be satisfied
you want them to return and use your
seeds again
i'm
more about return customers than trying
to
to fish up a whole bunch of new guys but
like right now in states that have
gone here in the usa
anybody
can grow four or five plants legally and
they don't need any permits or anything
like that you know unless there's some
local ordinance that might prevent them
the state law lets people grow a few
plants
so it seems to me that there could be a
lot of new growers
and my seeds are easy to grow i tell
them which ones
are the easiest people usually we
recommend the boggle gum we could call
it bulletproof you know it tastes like
bubble gum but it's got the nl5 in it
which makes it
uh resistant to almost everything every
mistake you can make and it'll it'll
produce something even if you you know
forget to feed it so
we often tell people you know it's
really good for beginners but not for
beginners only
boggle gum
was
a medical strain
and we didn't even call it matt back at
the time
but uh
it was sold as such in canada online for
350 an ounce for a number of years
and i don't know how they got away with
that but when i went up to vancouver
i found places like
the the melting point where bubble man
had his
vaporizers all in view in the open
windows on the main street
cops walking by had all my stuff out on
the table and we were all getting high
up there many years ago
sounds good
so you just mentioned the nl5 i wanted
to ask you about it where did you get
yours from and do you have any
speculations on what the genetics behind
it are
oh that's a good question you know what
there's probably somebody who does know
the answer there i can tell you where i
got them
uh
nl5
a bc company uh british columbia seed
company they sold not just northern
lights it was back before they just sold
northern lights and they did sell
northern light five seeds which another
guy obtained
and transferred them to me
and he had the name he had written on
his own tag so i didn't get the package
or anything but they were alleged to be
an l5
and
i grew them out and they were different
than just northern lights
i could say this that it was pretty
decided and the plant structure was
exactly like a christmas tree and that
had a lot of green
sort of like menthol or greenness
to its composition okay
and
it was good smoke but not quite as good
as the amsterdam bubble gum that i had
grown and gotten from drunkers
but it was rugged and hardy and
it was good so we did that cross because
those were the first two
uh sets of imported seeds i had obtained
so it was kind of a no-brainer
yeah okay
and it's also one which is still around
you still you know use it to this day do
you feel that's because it's you know
it's still solid or it's more so because
you kind of you want to still be able to
offer those strains it was used in the
creation for
well
we pretty much uh for our own use grow
indoors and we've lately just been
growing three of our strains
from three clones that we've got running
and you know one sour bubble
ones uh this our grape and one is the
blue moon rocks and we were running more
types but we're kind of downsizing on
the pot growing and and trying to just
continue to keep up on the seed growing
now
so
those are the three clones i have
selected and that we're growing right
now and i'm growing from seeds and
working on the bluetooth project and so
really we've gotten most most of the
work done on that now and we're just
doing our final
uh final room full of it to come out
with the seeds later this fall
yeah okay so something our viewers love
to always hear from the guests is what
are some of the traits you like to look
for when selecting a male
well you know males have smell
and of course with my strains it's not
too hard for me to select males because
i have a couple of tricks
now
yes you have to reselect nails and
you know the fact is that
it's best to go back to older seeds that
you have
than maybe the ones that you're also
growing but find
a male as close to back when it was
early as you can and then i am not one
to use just one male
now i suppose somebody thinks that's not
right but
i am
not always trying to get them all to be
as identical as clones
i mean i've had strains get that way
and it gets a little boring
and so i think that
it's fun when it's my sour strawberry
where you do have more than one
phenotype that you're going to get in a
pack of seeds
and it may sound backwards as far as
stability but
i'll i've got plenty of strains that are
quite stable i've been making them for a
long time and being able to know what
the right male is supposed to look like
and smell like because i've done it so
many times makes it easier for me to
reselect males
do you subscribe to the idea of
trying to find a male for example which
may be as closely as possible mirrors a
female of the same strain that you find
very desirable or do you think there's
some intrinsic differences which means
you can't just necessarily do what i
mentioned
it depends on on the breeding project
okay
like every one of my strains wasn't made
the same way and i don't like to go into
every detail
about it but let me explain
uh with the sour bubble
yeah if you've if you've got a
clone want to produce seeds like that
clone
i'm not i'm not one to feminize okay
i don't feminize seeds we've never sold
feminized seeds i have a story for you
about feminizing seeds yes i did do it
at one time
but
uh
well the reason i don't do it
is because you feminize seeds it'll be
fine possibly for the next generation
but
if they use those seeds to make more
seeds the
hermaphrodite tendencies definitely come
out and so
i expected that people would take my
seeds
and probably make some more seeds of
their own
at least
when i started this company
it's more the way it was you know then
then people are just gonna buy loads of
seeds
so
given you've had some clones for you
know 15 plus years i'd love to get your
opinion on this topic of genetic drift
do you believe that over time females
and maybe even males for that matter
can deteriorate in quality or do you
feel that for the most part you know the
same plan is the same plan
i would say that the genetics doesn't
change
but that a clone the quality of its bud
and the
numbers on its thc and stuff definitely
can decline
uh
there it's because of genetic alteration
okay that's not that easy to do and you
know i don't think the plan would be
healthy if that was going on i think the
genetics of clones are pretty solid uh
but i do think that the process of
selection is one thing
uh even with clones and that a line can
deteriorate over time
i don't think my sour bubble clone you
know being like 17 years old
i don't think i could get it to test out
as high as when it was brand new you
know
i saw it come down some and i still love
it i think
but
uh
they there are theories of
ways to take a clone that's sort of run
down
and refurbish it
and the only one i've ever really heard
is to take it outside for a summer and
let it let it live like a real tree you
know
yeah
so
do you think that there is a poster
child in regards to all the strains
you've made that represent bog seeds
like is there one strain which you think
really embodies bog seeds
oh
well
it's either the original bubble gum bog
bubble or sour bubble
the blog bubble was a flagship and
the sour bubble kind of became the new
leader and all the strains got bred to
the sour bubble
it's kind of a similar
story
to one that's so much old after years of
all his strengths being developed
he finally had this one male
that he decided was so good that he had
to cross that to all his strains and he
came out with a whole second set of
strengths
the thing i wanted to go back to for a
second what i didn't really answer was
like the type of breeding projects and
and i mentioned that with the
trying to make seeds from a clone that i
get i got off the track on to
why i don't feminize
but uh
by finding that perfect match like i did
for the sour bubble
that really was important to getting
those first
seeds
from the clone
and that that you know was
the main thing in the breeding project
that mattered the most
the different batches and the numbers of
back crosses
uh the further you get away from the
clone
uh the better they would yield
uh but you know i think at a certain
point like back cross four you wouldn't
want to go any
further away so
we we would go back and start over again
but with a lot of my strains
i don't think that
you know any breeding project when you
started you really don't know what
you're going to get and so it's kind of
a crap shoot and i always told people
to follow their
intuitions and to to know what they're
hoping for
and and to wish for that and that it
could make it happen and it's it's
a spiritual power that we have
yeah okay and so do you think that
there's something more to breeding than
just purely a say criteria of things
you're looking for is there kind of a
certain amount of intuition involved
also
yeah i i'm that type of breeder
like soma who you know is is kind of a
believer in a lot of things okay a lot
of junk spiritualism and stuff
i've mentioned to you about
my new world order thread and how you
know conspiracy theories and things like
that
well i worked in medicine for a number
of years and i then went to alternative
medicine for a while like
a naturopathic therapist
and
i kind of believe in in the power
that people have to help each other
like
in massage for example
um the human touch is
single crave
and is therapeutic
and any way you do it but there's
something called
intention and attention and so if your
intention were to
a pain go away in his lower back or neck
for example
and then
you paid attention to that
by concentrating on it and working on it
and massaging it or whatever you do
manipulating it
that
because of your intent and attention
and it's not all science now i love
science
and i wish i knew more science i mean i
that's the thing i like to read and i'm
a science fiction fan and you know i
just love
space and rockets and everything like
that
so
i don't dis science i uh
was good at science and i liked biology
and science like that but i didn't have
a degree in
genetics or even agriculture okay i mean
i was like political science english law
stuff like that
regular old
college program that eventually you know
i ended up having my first child at 21
years old
and leaving my first session in college
early
uh to go to work
and so i ended up going back to school
and stuff but that's a whole nother
story
so
you touched on science there
do you like to engage in the new
emerging technology and sciences that
are kind of touted to help breeders like
for example do you use any of
not just like you know an analytical lab
testing for for cannabinoid values but
like maybe the ones where they help you
to detect males earlier on or things
like that
no i i never use those guys and you know
i am not saying that testing isn't valid
or anything okay and we we've had plenty
of tests on plenty of our strains and
you know
my my weed
different kinds been sold in california
by dispensaries for years and a lot of
times they would they would send a
sample in and get tested you know i'm
cheap but i could pay for testing
but the kind of testing i really believe
in
being with the medical background
is more like clinical testing and that
would be the results
and i know that that's
anecdotal and harder to nail down than
the thc content or the cbna
or whatever else new
component i understand a little bit
about thc
um i understand
enough about it to know that
i like my strains high thc
with a little bit of cbd
and that
indica cited strains like that like my
sour bubble
kill
my pain at the best
they are a bit on the couchy side for
some people
but it stimulates my brain now i got i
got pretty high on it before we did this
session
and it's not like i'm sleepy or anything
and i've only had a sip of coffee
yeah there you go i mean do you consider
yourself to have a high tolerance or
more just
like you know because it's for a medical
need it helps to counteract the maybe
sedative side other people experience
some people would say we have a high
tolerance because my wife and i smoke a
lot
but the
truth is that you could get a higher
tolerance by using more edibles and we
do eat edible now and then but not that
regular
and you know um
you get a high content using
concentrates and things like that
we uh we make bubble hash and sometimes
we'll add a little that to our joint if
we want to pep it up you know
but
i wouldn't say that we could take all
that much at any one time you know i
mean we're older
um we like to get high and there are
some highs that are too busy for me that
i don't even like
that are like
um really really sativa sided strains
sometimes
that
uh you know it just it makes me a little
anxious
or so i i kind of prefer the
the uh indica high
there you go that segues perfectly into
my next question where i was gonna say
that a lot of your strains tend to have
this commonality of a relatively short
flowering time and obviously that lends
itself more towards the indica side of
genetics
was this intentional or is it just kind
of how things worked out
oh it was intentional being an indoor
grower myself
i mean i actually came up with my own
uh cell phone a plant a strain
that i called the the growers rating
scale rather than the smokers rating
scale okay
and so like growers they're the ones
that have to work with it
i i like a strain
that finishes in
like seven and a half eight and a half
weeks
and it's long enough
to get a pretty darn good yield
you know i do have uh two or three
i take longer to finish
um like indoors my lsd and my lifestyle
they both take uh at least 10 maybe 11
weeks indoors and they're a little late
finishing outside
uh but the lsd is quite mold resistant
and
the uh lifestyle probably should be too
although i'm really really not sure on
that
but
yeah i
you know being an indoor grower i want
things to move along you know and i i i
i do what's called you know continuous
production now
i called it bonanza green when i wrote
my book back in the day
it described how
we keep the plants moving you know from
a veg room to a flowering room and on
down the line in the flowering room
until they reach the end
of the room and where they get sort of
set aside from the lights for a couple
more days where they can still see the
light
but finish up and could sort of get the
most out of the room that way
it's more efficient
part of the growers scale would involve
the amount of energy required to get how
much yield back and so fewer weeks of
flowering
definitely would be a factor in that
and so we were looking at it
commercially too
that you know there's some great long
flowering strengths but unless the
yields are going to be really big you
don't want that indoors and the other
thing is if if the oils are really big
and they take a long time
then the plants still more susceptible
to problems than it will fast flowering
plant like you know mold or bugs or
anything
yeah totally
so some people may not have been aware
of what you just referenced but you have
written your own book called bonanza of
green and i was going to ask you about
it what inspired you to write it was it
kind of the case that you set out to
write the book or was it more that you
were giving out all this info and just
over time you were kind of like hey i've
got like a book's worth of stuff here
well that's exactly it i kept writing
the same [__] over and over again you
know and i really got to thinking
we ought to do this you know i mean
my my wife was working at the time but i
was off work and
it could have never got done without her
help i mean we're both literate and all
but
she's
you know more perfectionistic and she
made sure that the paragraphs made sense
to everyone
my book was meant to be simple and to
entice people into growing
and then also
to you know show them pictures of my
strains in the back of the book and
recommend that they get seats from us so
you know part of it was a promotional
thing for my seats but it never turned
out to be that big a deal and we we got
a thousand copies printed and since then
we've just been burning them on cds and
sending them to people you know
uh it was on the google play for some
time and it may still be out there
online it's bonanzo green by bushy old
grower
there you go check it out people
so
i wanted to ask you this one question i
didn't know how to slow it in so we're
just going to do it here
lifesaver your cross it's an interesting
one to me because on face value from
what i can see it's one of the only ones
where it's made using two different
breeders genetics
would you ever consider doing that again
or was that kind of a one-off special
thing
no i would consider doing that again and
and that was a time when i used sub
coolest genetics and i'll give him all
the credit in the world for his jcb
jack's cleaner blueberry
incredibly fast flowering strain and
very good bud
and you know it was good enough that i
wanted to cross it to my bubble gum
which was very fast i mean the original
bog bubble it was
probably faster finishing than it is now
maybe it was a difference in the way i
grew it but i mean we were getting it to
finish in like you know seven weeks and
so
his he had some if he knows he claimed
even finished in like 42 days 43 days or
something like that
and you know that's like too fast but
they were fast they were at least as
fast
as my
bubble
so i did cross those
and like i said i've been talking to
james at seats here now
about uh possibly using some
pollen from a very
uh
uh well-known breeder i don't want to
mention the name until we actually go
forward with the project but
at
this point i've said that you know i
might take some select pollen to work
with on my strains
ah that'd be interesting and
i think i might know who you're talking
about but we'll leave that to be seen
what i did want to ask though is
i don't know if you're aware but there's
a few people in the scene who are very
reminiscent about the strain bubble
berry that was offered by saga martha
seeds many years ago and i noticed that
you essentially offer you know a very
similar version to that strain like a
blueberry cross to a bubble gum type of
thing
have you ever noticed this similarity
and thought maybe i should try to work
this a bit more
well
i am aware of his strain by name and i
never actually tried it or worked with
it but i did have some friends in
amsterdam
that told me that his bubble berry was
excellent tasting okay
now
uh
well there's several
bubble gum blueberries you know it was
not a
intended to copy him
uh it was done probably pretty much at
the same time
and i don't think we used exactly the
same components or anything so
uh of course they're related i mean of
course they both have bubble gum and
they both have blueberry in them
but he and i didn't work together on it
i didn't uh
take his genetics and use them and he
didn't take mine and use them i don't
think either
yeah of course
so one question i love to ask the guests
because our viewers always love to hear
it is do you have any tips for fino
hunting and so what i mean by that is
do you for example maybe prefer to run a
lot of plants in small pots and just see
how they go or do you like to let them
get big to get a true test of them
what's what's your method when you're
going to pop some seeds and try to
determine what's worth keeping
well what a great question you know i'm
always doing this all right and the
thing is right now
you know like i was telling you my sour
bubble clone
great for breeding definitely the
genetics are still just popping
but we decided to again look for another
select sour bubble mother
and uh
we went through a group of them
a while back no no i don't do a big
group at a time
uh
it might only be like 15 plants and
a few of them are going to turn out to
be males
with my sour bubble the strain is about
female maybe 65
so
right now
i'm doing it again and the last time
i had a couple promising keepers
and uh another guy just showed his
keeper from sour bubble that he selected
on the instagram
and it's the bubble gum version of sour
bubble and it's not an uncommon one
and it's super delicious and sticky and
frosty and finishes real fast
but the one i had wasn't a very big
yielder
and i didn't think it was quite as
strong as you know the other phenotypes
so then there was another one
that i
also thought was a possible keeper
and it didn't have the same taste that i
was looking for
but it was really strong
and it had an interesting taste
but we just wasn't sure it was good
enough and so we're doing another look
right now
now the way i do it
is
i
this time
had a set of sour bubble seeds i wanted
to go ahead and check out some of the
ones that looked marginal actually small
and marginal that it probably wouldn't
have sold anyhow
and it was funny all germinated you know
and i thought well
let's just see how they grow you know
and if there's runts or anything and i
guess out of the bunch we might have had
a couple that died off or were weird but
i've got a group of plants now there
must be about 10 of them and we what we
do is we number them all
and we clone them all
and we keep the clone
and you know often the males
because you know
usually they just die you know
anyhow
you can clone a male but it's hard
and that
after we find out which ones are the
females we go ahead and flower out the
big plants
you see i got a limited size indoor grow
and i'm just trying to you know do
everything in sequence and so it can't
be all that many at all one time
you know when i get those
into flour which is really soon they're
getting huge
uh we'll just you know finish them out
we'll try the different kinds of blood
and will
will write up you know what i thought
about each phenotype
and uh see if there's something like at
this point
everybody wants something that's a good
yield or in sour bubble
it's just a moderate yield it's not a
great yielder i've i've grown big plants
you know to show that it's possible but
it takes a while vegging it and then
they
flower fast they tend to not be the
biggest fielders we'd like to find one
that's really good
it has similar tastes to my old clone
and that yields more
and it has higher content like the old
clone did originally
sounds like the dream combo
so
this is going to be
a bit of an interesting question because
i'm not sure on the timeline but
how do you feel about
what it appears to be to me the fact
that like barney's farm stole the lsd
name from you
well i didn't look at it that way you
know the truth is when i named lsd hey
here's something res dog had something
to do with
name instead we were talking about it
and i says what am i going to call this
[__] i said it's lifesaver it's crossed
with so much diesel he says huh let me
see
lsd
so he actually came up with the name i
went like duh
okay good idea his idea and i did name
it lsd and i do think it was after my
lsd yes probably a couple
years later lee the barney's farm came
out with their lsd
but do we know that they were even aware
that there was another lsd and did they
claim it was bog lsd no they didn't and
did it have the same components no and
did they tell what the components were
yes they did and so even these
strains are
they came from different origins i don't
think they just knocked off my lsd seats
i think they made their own and they
came up with their own name from the
same abbreviation system
of like lemon skunk diesel or whatever
is in it
yeah okay
so do you think though that there should
be some sort of standard by which if a
name already exists you you know like
there's some rules you should follow or
do you think it's fine so long as like
you know you state what it is and so if
people look into the details they'll be
able to see that it's
different i think it's fine as long as
you're not dishonest
i think it's awful to
to uh not give somebody the credit they
deserve if you use their work
i think it's off to try to steal you
know somebody's strain but when it comes
to names look there's a bunch of sour
grapes i'm not so sure that mine was the
first sour grape i sure didn't know of
another
one but the past one the thing is mine
is box our grape
and i can tell you what's in it and i
have told everybody what's in it and
it's the truth and it's the only reason
i can remember anything
is because i always tell the truth
if i did lie to make it look better or
sound cooler or something i could never
keep all the lies straight i mean i'm an
old guy and a lot of stuff you're asking
me to remember you know was you know 15
years ago or more
yeah totally sorry to
put you under the pressure like that
well
no i've enjoyed it just fine uh i'm just
saying that you know
that old stoner and in my memories the
worst things are
uh the actual names of people but i did
i did meet a lot of the big breeders you
know i i did go to amsterdam a few times
i traveled with gypsy in his jaguar in
europe i drove this jaguar man it went
156 miles an hour it was a nice big car
and man that was so cool i mean
cruising the autobahn and stuff man we
were
we were uh down in switzerland we went
to breeder steve's greenhouses and stuff
just before he got up
i i was worried that us being the
pictures that were shown could have led
to him getting in trouble and i thought
[__] me and we were all pretty careless
yeah wow that sounds very much like the
heyday
well
you know i mean it was like
when i first
got into this business with gypsy you
know i mean he was the one that asked me
to make seeds for him and he uh
had put up a picture of this bubble gum
because he knew i grew bubble gum you
know
and he had had a win to free pack about
of seeds if you can tell me what this
strain was and the picture showed how it
was all popcorned out the bud the way
bubblegum should look when it's done and
i right away said well it looks like
bubble gum to me
and he says oh yeah you win bushy you
you definitely get the the pack of
bubblegum seeds so i got another pack of
bubblegum seeds and they were uh simon's
uh and uh i grew those
and you know they were a lot different
than than my bubble gum and they tasted
and smelled like bubble gum too but a
little bit more like
cotton candy to me
than my bubble gum
and i also thought that while it was a
large plant and everything
it was awfully woody like it was more
wooden tree than it was bud you know but
of course phenotypes vary a little bit
who knows how many
i had to work with just one pack i think
of those
yeah okay i've heard people comment
about that about how i think um there's
kind of a more indicating bubblegum and
i think simons may have been the more
sativally anyone
i don't know if it was more sativa or
not it definitely had this woody and
stout structure
uh it definitely was you know a pretty
good size player but i thought it was
just as indica sided in my opinion
yeah okay i could be offered that one
so i mean while talking about you having
your little holiday in europe is the
european market something you want to
explore more or are you just already too
busy trying to keep up with domestic
well we've been limited in our ability
to stay
like distributed to to distributors in
other countries um
we uh
after
you know some problems that res dog had
we decided to go domestic for a while
and we're entertaining the notions of
certain countries
uh that allow it
that we are
you know talking to people some people
interested in having distributorships
and uh so far
right now i do have distributors who
will ship anywhere in the world or just
about anywhere
but they're based in the us
yeah cool so anyone can get them if
you're wondering all my australian
friends inevitably i get i get that
question
well i would also like people to know if
they want information
about
who my distributors are and where they
can be found and reached that they can
always check out bog or bog seeds at
instagram
or i'm willing to
email address if you would allow that
yeah of course
well we can give information on
obtaining seeds depending on where you
are at blogland bogland72
gmail.com
yeah fantastic and of course
you can get them from ct now one of our
favorite sponsors
seeds here now is our uh our largest
distributor
and uh they have done a great job for us
and you can be assured that if you deal
with them
you'll be satisfied you'll be getting
the best service around
that's the one
so sorry just to uh jump back to the
question i was gonna ask i've got a
legal question here so it's it's a bit
of an interesting one but i want to hear
your opinion on it where do you see the
future of cannabis going in california
because obviously that's what you're
probably more familiar with and do you
think that the world will follow
california's suit
i hope not
honestly
uh
and eddie lev is a good fight he's a
cannabis activist out here as am i
in california
we had the longest running medical
marijuana system
of any state
we ran it for like 15 years with no
problems
believe me a cottage industry
people could take their
half a pound or whatever to a local
dispensary
they could be paid for it
they could go home and they could afford
to have a roof over their head
legalization
well we've always all wanted
but we want sanity
this kind of legalization
is just regulating it far too much
taxing it far too much
with no exceptions for medical users
senior citizens
or people that want to grow be limited
to like four plants
no this isn't going to stand
eddie lep and i and a lot of other
people involved in the medical
industry out here furious
with the fact that they lied about the
promises that our medical rights would
not be lost well maybe not for a year or
so
yes they are threatened and we are
working on
ballot initiatives
to get
our medical rights protected and listen
i'm naturopathic i'm into health and i
believe in medicine and doctors and all
that but i believe in the personal right
of a person to grow herbs for their own
use and i mean any plan and i don't care
what plan
the fact is that if it's for your own
use and you're not even selling it it's
nobody's business but your own
and there's a lot of people that think
it's healthier
than a lot of the medicines that people
use for god's sakes
this this pharmaceuticals that got
everybody addicted on opiates if people
were growing their own
opium poppies
and bleeding them and putting that on
their weed and smoking it they wouldn't
even get addicted to it because it would
be at such a low level
but it's not in its natural form
you know that's why i like raw cannabis
much better than concentrates yeah i
know raw cannabis it's a fresh produce
and it doesn't last forever and we got a
lot of it and we need to turn a lot of
it
into concentrates but
what i like is fresh cannabis and i
honestly think that it's it's healthy
and maybe it's healthier to vape than to
smoke but i still smoke it after all
these years of my wife and i sm
smoking all kinds of marijuana it hasn't
harmed us it kept us from getting cancer
i smoked cigarettes for years and i had
a heart bypass operation 25 years ago
but cannabis has kept me alive since
then
yeah wow what an incredible testimony
so
with that being said
what legal changes do you think need to
occur to facilitate a more productive
cannabis industry and just culture
well to tell you the truth i agree with
governor brown and the governor of
colorado and a lot of people and this
may sound crazy to you but i was not for
this legalization proposition and a lot
of people in oregon and ohio you know
the horrible thing they set up in ohio
where just five farms would have a
monopoly growing all the wheat in ohio
and the voters voted down just like
california voted legalization down the
first time
and they voted it down because it was
all commercialistic it was all about
taxes there's only reason they're doing
it and you know i don't begrudge a
recreational system
there can be a recreational system of
legal
weed and there can also be the medical
marijuana system where people don't have
to
work in the same fashion and it doesn't
have to be taxed so heavily
yeah of course and so do you think that
that is a potential for california to go
back to like the former model or do you
think you've almost come too far
well tell you the truth i don't know
what the future will bring i do think
that a nationwide medical marijuana
system would make more sense
but
i understand they just think everything
commercially in the business world like
making
fewer producers to make sure you're able
to collect all your taxes you know we
could have made sure that all the all
the
was safe so there could have been a
system set up that would have preserved
the cottage industry it's going to
create and is creating a disaster
in the states where they took away the
medical marijuana and put in effect
legal marijuana the same thing's
happening in canada right now and that's
a whole country you know they just
legalized it well one of the seed
companies that i sell seeds to up in
canada just informed us that she's not
allowed to sell seeds anymore now how is
that legalization man yeah it's
one step forward three steps back
well that's exactly what i mean
everything was just fine in california
with the medical system that we had
and i didn't hear anybody complaining
you know but real commercial interests
you know it's like the politicians
didn't want to pass a bill to legalize
marijuana so what'd they do
you can't change a ballot initiative in
california in congress without having
like a two-thirds vote in both house so
they got another ballot initiative up it
made it look like this was going to be
good you know
and all people can buy now
is a lesser grade of marijuana at a
higher price or they have to go back
underground
to the black market to get good weed at
a reasonable price from one of their
friends
yeah
just as a bit of a change of pace
because that's all the legal questions
we had we've got a question here that
was submitted by one of our patreon
viewers
however i'm actually not that familiar
with it so i'm hoping you're just going
to be able to take the reins and answer
this one here
the question is
what are the common mistakes you see
people making when they're making water
hash at home or bubble hash
oh okay i love bubble bash and i still
make that all the time and
i'm just getting ready to make a whole a
whole bunch of it to put away and store
for myself right now don't even have any
plans of selling it
i'll tell you how i do it first of all
you know a bubble man is a friend of
mine from back in the days of either
overgrow or icy mag whenever he came out
with his bags inhale
i was one of the first guys that he
wanted to send a free set of three bags
to
because he knew i'd make the hash and
how many followers i had at the
overgrower or i see mine
and so i appreciated that and i read his
thread about how you do it
and i pretty much followed his
directions and
found that my different strengths
produced the different hashes and that
for a while you know we were uh mostly
making bubble hash and then switched
over to making sour bubble hatch
the sour bubble hash
it turned out
it we did get that tested and it did
turn out to be uh
pretty darn good for bubble hash and the
way i made it wasn't all that special
but it was it was nearly 60 percent
still it's nearly 60 percent
thc
and not too much cbd
but
it comes out really dark like a really
dark red to black
and i really like
the hash that comes from the sour bubble
but my process is pretty simple and you
know
i really think that it's not necessary
to use a whole large number of bags
i just used two bags
i mean three
i think one of the mistakes people make
is is taking out
and separating away from the hash
uh
resins that are
in the like 120 range okay
like i mix and strain my weed in a 220
and then that bag
goes into a 160
and i do a second strain with the 160
and then i just catch it all in a 45.
now
unless your strain is really high
quality
and your trim is just sugar leaves like
i use really
upgrade
trim this won't work for you but it
works for me in sour bubble and what it
does to improve the hash
is
the larger stuff like the 130 140 that
gets through the 160 bag
there's a lot of flavor in that and that
that's what people are realizing they're
just going ahead separating that out and
using it in their edibles or whatever
because it's lighter weight hash and
then a lot of them collect in the 73
which is good
but believe me
there's stuff going through the 73
that's also good
so
if you catch it all in the 45
from the 160 to the 45 and it's really
high quality trim that you put in there
then you can get a good amount of a more
flavorful bubble hash see the thing
about bubble hash is you don't want them
to all be the same and that's what i
find
sometimes a lot of concentrates is hash
gets to be hash you know
well
more flavor like if if you've smoked the
old conventional hashes and you know how
good they taste like these fingers like
good moroccan or good
lebanese or lebanese these ganaches
weren't as strong as bubble hashes we
make now by any means
but they were delicious and you know to
me that's a big deal
uh i don't often agree with everything
that dj short says
and you know
so one time he was talking i was
listening i know him slightly
about how people are trying to just jack
up and get these
highest potency strains like it's like
adding neutral spirits to fine wine or
something you know
well i i see his point you know but my
sour bubble's really strong and it's
really good and so i i don't think
there's a problem with them having good
power
yeah and i agree
so on to the last question before we do
our last little quickfire ones
so we've kind of already touched on this
but just to get a clarification where do
you sit on the issue of people breeding
with your work specifically
do you like it if someone comes to you
and says you know hey i've got this
thing i'm doing is that okay or do you
kind of think like there's no onus for
them to contact you and ask for
permission or anything like where do you
sit
well i like it when a person shows me
the respect to expedition but i don't
expect that and you know the truth is
when i sell you my seeds
you've bought them and you own them and
you can do what you please with them now
if you actually make see my seeds i hope
that it'll at least be across with
something else and not just a knockoff
of my strain and they wouldn't just make
a knock off of my strain and call it
exactly the same but i wouldn't mind if
you made a strain
and then you told what was truthfully in
it and gave me a little credit now
that's good enough for me
because you know i'm i'm actually more
part of the past this industry than i am
the future i mean i know what i'd like
to see and what i'd like to see is that
everybody contributing and coming up
with new stuff on their own
like back in the day having so much fun
doing it
yeah fantastic what a great sentiment
so on to our last little few questions i
call them the quickfire section
so
let's jump into them it's just five
quick little questions so what is your
favorite strain that you think has got a
bit of a bad rap
i'm thinking i'll tell you i do think
that uh sometimes bubble gum doesn't get
the wrap it deserves
now maybe you think it never got a bad
rap but
the truth is i remember
uh things like you know it's kind of
inconsistent or
or or runts or mutants or something like
that and i don't ever remember any of my
seeds being that way that they were
always
hearty and healthy
other complaints that it really wasn't
very strong you know
well i i remember i had people say to me
why do you like to grow bubble gum you
know i mean
it's really not that strong
well it seems strong to me i mean it's
got the indica high it's very relaxing
and you know i
i'm not so sure i know
many strains that have gotten such a bad
rap you know i mean
uh well i i think of
do i don't want to any negativity on any
other straights from any other breeders
you know i'm a really nice guy and i
wouldn't want to point out
you know some bad work that some other
breeder did okay
you just answered the next question
which is going to be
what is the your least favorite strain
maybe you know it doesn't have to be
something from someone else could just
be a general thing you know you might oh
well to tell you the truth uh
even though
uh i recognize how strong it is and how
good it
there are i really don't like that much
most sour diesels are too fuelly for me
and i won't smoke them i smoked one so
strong one time it practically put me
down on my knees okay
i know how strong it can be
uh
some of the canned dog stuff i really
don't like the taste
and uh no i i like train wreck and
people got sick of the taste of that and
maybe it got a bad rep but trainwreck is
a great old strain
that i would still consider working with
yeah well maybe we need that because no
one is working with it really
well the truth is that it has a great
painkilling effect
and uh
i like the taste but people get sick of
the taste and you know of my strengths
like one of the best tasting ones
that has like a lot of nose and flavor
is the blue moon rocks
but
i love this stuff but i couldn't just
smoke it all the time it's like after a
while you definitely want something else
because it's just
so strong of kind of blueberry taste
yeah well that sounds like what i need
in my life
oh it's beautiful stuff you know the
blue kush yields a little less but it's
even stronger
they're both related and it didn't talk
about it but the blue moon rocks one of
my old strains
that it was an old clone blue moon
uh
and that had a blueberry in it that
wasn't dj's it was vic's blueberry
and so it makes my blue moon rocks
considerably different blueberry that's
not as dark purple as dj's but
yields real well
yeah okay i might need to take a little
investigation into that one myself by
the sounds of it
so well the blue moon clone was gets me
either
by one or two guys okay and i'm not sure
if those seats were given to me by sub
cool
but i had a friend in florida named
tommy and i think he sent me the seeds
and he told me
that the blue moon was a cross
of this vix blueberry and i remember vic
from back in the overgrown times
and a mcgannopy moonbeam and you know
there was a blue moonshine that came out
after blue moon
which was different okay it was probably
blue moon crossed with something else
but anyhow i got the seeds of the blue
moon and i didn't want to change it that
much you know that would be my bubble
berry
but the fact is that i kept it more like
the blue moon
than bringing it to my bubble gum side
yeah okay
so the next question is desert island
situation you can only take two strains
with you to this desert island you have
unlimited amounts of it but you can only
pick two strains which two
well sour bubble would definitely be one
of them
uh
there
there's a several others that i really
like a lot and you know it's really fun
to
grow the strawberry and
the sour grape is of nearly comparable
quality those three the sour bubble the
sour grape and this
strawberry but i wanted to mention sour
boggle because
you know my boggle gum was one of my
original streets that we crossed to the
sour bubble
and the sour bottle came out
surprising results
in that it's very bubble gummy flavor
uh it's very up daytime high unlike most
of the mostly bubblegum flavored ones
and you know it's got a taste
that there's something besides the
bubble gum but uh i kind of call it a
champagne bubble gum for some reason
kind of like a gold bubble gum
yeah that sounds great so that might be
the other one no
yeah okay so you got your two
bog bubble and the uh sour bubble i i
think i think sour bubble
and the sour
boggle which is sour boggle gum
uh yeah that's the one
so this is one of my favorite questions
if you could go back to any point in
time and history as well as anywhere in
the world to presumably collect some
land race seeds where would you go and
what period
that's a good question
you know
land raised seeds working with them it's
definitely like would be very rewarding
you know to say
this is you know the congo bongo you
know this is what they grew there for
hundreds of years
and you worked with it and you
you know bred and selected until you got
it even more potent you know most of the
land race strains really start out not
being
all that great and i'm not sure but it
seems to me that
it would have been a long time ago and i
would be thinking asia you know like you
know
one of the things maybe
maybe mountainous regions where you know
the the uh
the fast flowering uh cushes
it seems like in india
where the hindu religion
do you know
that when they were
their students
in religion and spirituality
that they would drink bang
which was a mild cannabis beverage
to make them more astute more able to
learn
so
maybe an indian strain
yeah okay that's certainly one that's
not not explored much currently the
indian genetics
oh well it's just that they have an
ancient history
of cannabis use
and it's interesting to me
and i am kind of a history buff but most
kind of history that i study is like
ancient aliens and stuff man have you
seen
that there's like pyramids all over the
world
and there's pyramids on the moon and
there's pyramids on mars and out in the
asteroid belt
there's a dwarf planet called sirius
and they show pictures of one of our
probes went out through the asteroid
belt and took pictures of this planet
there is a six mile high pyramid on
sirius man
all i can say is i'm so happy you just
said all of this
yeah i think it's great
well i tell you the aliens are out there
man and they're already here too
and the fact is that i don't really
trust them but they have telepathy they
can look just like regular people
and i don't trust them but they seem
nice
wow yeah you want to
just shine the spotlight on someone name
and shame someone
well i can tell you you know like i
actually had experiences
that are real
not just made up mythical stuff about
bog living in a cave or anything like
that
but
that when i was just seven years old
and i was in a kresge store in
birmingham michigan my mom let me go
look at the toy section while she was
shopping
which was usual today
and i'm walking down the aisle
and here a man in a business suit
is facing me down the aisle like 15 feet
away from me
and has telepathy to me you know we have
an eye contact
and this is what he said i swear to god
he said
i'm from another planet
he says there's a million of us here and
we're here to help you and he walked
right
on by and mouth dropped open and i told
my family about it
and they knew
that i didn't make up stories when i was
a little kid or anything
so that happened and then when my wife
and i were first married it was 1974
we've been married a couple years we
were in central michigan it's just one
summer where we saw a bunch of ufos and
i mean
i i had other people at my house see him
too and and my family my parents my
sister her
husband her kid the darn things were
flying around and they were triangular
most of them and then one night
uh my wife and i just alone
and we had taken some shrooms so you
could say wow you were just tripping but
we didn't see [__] like this when we
took
rooms okay we saw
something come down
and land on the road in front of our
neighbor's house which is like a quarter
mile away okay
and this wasn't triangular and it landed
and
it looked kind of like a bus you know
like a short bus or something or
shuttlecraft from the starship
enterprise
and it landed on the road like
i guess facing away from us and i got
binoculars we're up in our yard and i'm
looking at it
and the thing rotated like an army tank
in the road
and a a hole opened up it had sort of a
hood on the front that stocked out and a
hatch opened up on the front of its hood
and i had to pull the binoculars away
real quick as a giant light a bright arc
light came up through the hole in the
front of that thing and after it turned
on this huge bright light
it was the craziest thing you ever saw
man i swear to god it's the whole truth
my wife and i
there was a large field a kitty corner
from our house we're out at a farm in
the country on dirt road
and this large field across from the
neighbor's house it went out in that
field and it skimmed it like an air
cushioned vehicle
or like something that could have been
making a circle zipping around the field
back and forth so fast that it looked
like a cartoon like it couldn't be real
or something you know
and then the thing actually went down to
the river a creek anyhow
and it's turned off its light and it sat
on the ground and the river there
for possibly a half an hour
and while it was on the ground
it had little remote sentry vehicles
marching back and forth
to a corner right over us basically on
its perimeter
and after it was there for about a half
an hour
it it took off
and this was the strangest part you know
the other ones
they were always pretty quiet you know
nothing but a low hum
this one when it took off the ground it
was going straight up
slowly and the lights revolving around
each other and it had a whining sound
noise building up like we'd never heard
from one of them and it reached a
certain altitude and the red lights were
spinning real fast and the whining was
real loud and all of a sudden it shot at
an angle
really high like for orbit
and it took off so fast i swear it would
have killed a human
it set three shock waves it almost broke
my front window it buckled in and out
three times and later did break in a
storm
and that thing
shot across the sky at the highest angle
like
jail it was going up and then just
disappeared it was so fast
and
you know that's
my well that was full-on
it's true
yeah no i
don't think you can make that up
believe me i wouldn't and i know how
crazy it sounds all right
i even admit that we took a couple
shrooms that night but maybe it somehow
allowed us to see something that we
normally wouldn't have seen now the next
day i went and looked around out that
field on a dirt bike like did it knock
down a fence or anything did it make any
marks in the weeds and
nothing
there was no trace of anything so
it might have been an encounter the
second kind because it did make my
window bounce in and out and the
shockwave did hit us in the chest like
uh air cannon you know it's what it felt
like it broke the sound barrier
instantly
wow
yeah okay
so i think we could probably get stuck
on this all day maybe maybe we should
jump back to the last question
yeah
so absolute last question it's a good
one
if you could recommend one bog strain to
anyone out there regardless of their
skill level their experience all that
what would it be
well i guess you would say would be
boggle gum because
i i want them to be successful if
they're novices
i want them to have a nice yielding
good product that they would probably be
happy to grow if they're not novices
and i think that it is exemplary of our
strengths
because it does very much
have the bubble gum taste that i love
and it also is easy for anybody to grow
what a great answer
so
brings us to about the end of it did you
have any comments or shout outs you
wanted to make at all
well i didn't really plan on talking
about the aliens or anything and you
know if i was crazy i'd still be seeing
them and i'm not so
i'm pretty sure they're still around
but i'm not trying to say i know what
their agenda is or anything
you know i'm kind of a buddhist
christian
and i'm just a believer in the golden
rule
and i i really don't believe in
in accumulating wealth i mean i've lived
pretty well all my life i've been a
pretty lucky kid
i appreciate that i've had the love of a
good woman for 48 years
and that until one of us dies we'll
still have that
and you know
we shared our marijuana
every day that we could i mean almost
every day all those years
and i have to say that it's been a
sacrament for us
that it's it's been
uh a right
that we do and soma says the same thing
his daily sacrament
and you know that's the way we look at
it it's not like
it's not like i really want to get
blasted all the time and it's not like i
really have to get high
but we get up in the morning and after a
while you know drinking some coffee and
watching tv
when we do smoke some
then it does open our minds and the good
thing about cannabis
is that it does stimulate creative
thinking
and the biggest miracle of cannabis is
to allow you to forget and you know it's
hard to forget the things that are
worrying you the things that are
bothering you a lot of people feel
depressed a lot of the time a number of
my strains are very antidepressant in
effects and i don't think it's a phony
thing you know honestly we use medicines
all the time
and
it's more like aromatherapy
therapy it doesn't take that i mean a
really small amount of cannabis
can be enough to completely change
someone's frame of mind because believe
me that's an internal thing whether
you're happy or not
look in the mirror
can you smile at yourself can you give
yourself a big smile do you know
that you'll feel happy
just by smiling
well you know it's just a thought from
an old guy that has a few mood swings
now than himself and uh
anxiety and worries and pressure and
that's what cannabis is for i mean it's
an anti-stress thing it's like that's
why you get the munchies because now
it's time to relax and that means that
we can stop fighting for a while and we
can we can stock up on food and we can
have some sleep
and and we can laugh it off you know the
day's troubles and if if i didn't have
it you know
i i'd definitely not be a nicer person
okay
and i'm not saying that everybody needs
it or anything but i do
no i can agree with that one so thank
you so much for taking the time to chat
with us today book
well i enjoyed talking to you i
appreciate it and uh to all your
listeners uh thank you for listening to
me
[Music]
and there we have it guys a big big big
thank you to bog for stopping by
and a big thanks for you guys for
hanging around till the end
as always huge shout out to our patreon
fans these guys are the lifeblood of the
show we've got a really cool episode
coming up make sure to check out the
patreon episode if you want to get
access to it
and a huge thank you to our sponsors as
always seeds here now best in the game
i'll say it again
420 australia
organic gardening solutions
the premier store lifestyle and
gardening
we'll see you guys next time
see you
[Music]
la la la la
[Applause]
[Music]
la la la la
you