hey there gang this is your boy heavy
days
giving you a big thank you for coming
and checking out this episode
i just wanted to let you all know that
we have a patreon over at
www.patreon.com
forward slash the podcast if you enjoy
the show and would like to continue to
help make it happen
head on over and get access to a whole
range of goodies
including early access to episodes bonus
patreon exclusive episodes
and extra goodies like shirts stickers
giveaways and a whole lot more
thank you so much to everyone who helps
support the show you are truly the
lifeblood of it and you help us to keep
the wheels turning so that we can
continue to bring you the content
you enjoy now let's get into the episode
[Music]
hello and welcome to the next episode of
the podcast
a cannabis podcast for biting
enthusiasts
this episode as always was brought to
you by 420 australia
your premier store for lifestyle and
apparel
as well as organic gardening solutions
your one stop shop for organic gardening
needs
this episode we're joined by none other
than duke diamond va
to chat all things breeding and what we
can expect from him in the future
so let's get into it all righty so big
thank you and welcome
to our second part tour duke diamond va
thanks for coming back
ah thanks for having me buddy so
first question this time what are you
currently smoking on at the moment
um it was a uh genius skunk fina
and popped out and it was like captain
crunch crunch berries and
it's real good kind of surprised me
is this a cross we can maybe expect in
the future
i don't know i have to uh i'll have to
show it to
uh mr soul there see if he likes it
but uh and i think he would like i kind
of discounted it because like
i kind of made it already knowing like
well
it's going to just turn out like genius
because like everything
kind of you know leans that way so um
i was like you know see what happens and
the whole time it was growing
i was like yeah it looks like genius and
it kind of smells like it
and same pretty much everything had a
little more resin a little more
structure
so i kind of discounted it and so uh i
was like popping the jars
and uh crunch berry smell came out and i
was like whoa
so i tried some and then kind of hooked
on it so it might be something
i have to make yeah that's interesting
because
i remember i think i mentioned before
that i had found a really genius
dominant
genius haze which is perfect because
that was exactly what i was looking for
i love genius
but it brings to mind the question for
me what's the ideal partner for genius
if she is so
dominant would you need to match that
with something equally dominant or no is
the ideal partner like something kind of
more quote submissive and just kind of
allowing her to shine what's your
theories on that
no no i guess it'd be like uh
whatever your whatever your end goal
would be if you're trying to make like
you know more like a replica of the mom
or if you're trying to make something
you know totally different maybe like
leaving certain attributes and
changing others you know um
so um yeah it kind of depends what you
would
your end goal would be like if i was
going
if i was gonna like back cross it and
try to get that phenotype kind of
isolated that probably
[Music]
like like when we did the green avenger
i would probably like use
like a male from that or something and
that crosses at least
probably two maybe three times till i
felt like it was pretty good
and then i would like probably filial
breed it
f3 f4 or something like that and i feel
like you would get a pretty good
representation of that you know that one
fino and
try to improve it along the way as well
because like any time i've ever tried to
like
really inbreed something i was trying to
you know fix certain things you know
while
maintaining the the good attributes too
it's kind of tricky sometimes
yeah okay and i mean that kind of makes
sense to me in a way because
the green avenger i think you even
mentioned this it's probably
the most replica of genius in seed form
of all the brothers grim offerings
but at the same time at least from what
i could see
seems to have that really i'm not gonna
say a lot more but
a little bit more aesthetic bud look
that kind of the space queen and the
the you know the derivatives of that had
would you try to retain that per se
or do you think that the genius has good
aesthetics as it is
i mean it it looks good as is but
you know it
like it's kind of a weird weird plant
too because like it it does like the
biomass thing
so like later you know like mid-40s and
then it starts getting interested in
like resin production
and like on a good run with it i mean it
looks pretty pretty darn good but
um the branches on it are kind of floppy
you know it's not like the most uh you
know structurally strong plant
especially for something to grow such
big bugs on it you know the yield on
it's like really nice
but um you got to keep up with all the
branches so
uh green avenger really you know
strengthened everything up and it also
reinforced a lot of the desirable traits
that like ran through the apollo lines
also like you know going back with it
it's not like
like a back cross per se but like a
generational back cross of taking those
desirable apollo jeans and then going
back
you know to the uh you know to the
grandma so um it seemed like you know it
fixed all the
the weak branching and giving it that
extra layer of resin
was really nice and the only thing
that i would say like that i would like
to see like
stronger in it or not really stronger
but
i guess more consistent um in the
progeny would be
the the the effect because
genius has a really really really nice
speedy effect to it and like some of
those green avengers
would just put you put you like
ridiculously stoned you know um
my favorite one was like real speedy for
about like 40 minutes and then you would
just crash
like i mean crash hard um
which you know like the genius wouldn't
do so like i think like you can get
a certain way and then like if you
wanted to like replicate that chemo type
you you'd really have to hunker down on
that you know to get it get it just so
but i think like a couple of back
crosses from
say like a green avenger back to that
would would
you know isolate that a little bit
better
but it's just you know each step you'd
have to make sure to not
not let any of the weak branching back
into it you know
what would you consider in with all that
being said would you consider
just say doing s-ones of it to be a bit
of a waste of time
in regards to trying to put it in seed
perform because like maybe you could put
it in seed form in the most basic of
senses but
you would still have all the issues
which you just you know listed you would
try to improve on
or would you still consider doing just a
straight s one
well like if he did like s1 and then you
know found that
particular female that matched up to it
very well and if it could also
go through like stress testing and
everything and not like freak out
um maybe reversing that one back to the
mom
um you know
you you might be able to find something
in the progeny it would have like a
stronger structure
and if it's on that x chromosome going
back like that should
you know should improve it but um
you never really know to you until you
do it so
he might actually he might be working on
doing that here in the future
but um and then like the other
i guess like the op not the opposite way
thinking about another way of thinking
of it
is like you might have a certain female
that you can get just about everything
out of it
look smell taste um structure flowering
time
with calyx ratio colors etc
but like it never never has that that
good potency
that the uh that the original mom had
and i've noticed that like certain ones
like you can only get it to pass like
i think by reversing it out to something
else and then
um you know trying to recover it recover
it from there
um it just seems like certain things it
won't breed out you know
so you might actually have to like do
the back cross and the filial route on
one end
and then also like self it you know
we're not selfish but um
out reverse it now cross it to
maybe something else closely related in
the line to like go back to it
you know to really you know get every
single
point made you know from your structure
vigors and
redesigned stuff and resistances and
yada yada you know
so it might take like using kind of like
three different tools to
to get to your end goal definitely some
meaningful breeding in those ideas so
i guess if we're going to drag things
back to one of the main projects
everyone's interested from you the skunk
project how's it all going you know like
you want to give us a bit of an update
on it all
oh yeah yeah it's going real good um
it's like at this point
like we can hit we can hit a lot of
those uh phenos but it's not like
every single one and like some of them
tend to be a little more fuely and
you get the burnt rubber smell and then
like you know you can
lean to a more just kind of a
burnt rubber rotten meat and then
sometimes you get you know like a good
blend of everything
where it's coming out pretty pretty damn
skunky
so it's more or less like
getting it to the point to where you
know i could say all right guys here's
you know much seeds and when you pop
them all it's just
it's all skunk you know it's just you
gotta
you know pick which one you like the
best i guess you know
for like maybe flower time or you know
normal normal you know so
yeah sounds almost similar to like just
a cindy 99 pheno hunt you know like
all the same you just pick the one you
like yeah pretty much
pretty much but i want to refine that
like a little bit
a little bit further than that you know
i just
i don't know i just can't i couldn't
have it out there
if like everything isn't you know firing
on all cylinders and
you know real good so i figure anything
it takes that much time you know
might as well make it super super
rad and put the extra time into it and
you know
make sure that everybody be happy with
it because if i gotta put my name on it
i don't want any bunk
you know going out there so i mean i
guess just to clarify for the die hard
fans
are we talking about a skunk project
here or a road kill skunk
project yeah yeah like because
if and like to me personally like i feel
like
if that's the same thing you know like
there really shouldn't be any
differentiation you know like if you got
a skunk it should smell like a skunk
you know like as simple as that because
you know the things that are dead on the
road that got ran over i mean you're
smelling their
their gland you know that that glam
burst and that
that skunk sprays out there so um
yeah so like i always kind of felt you
know that that
you know it was kind of messed up with
somebody you know it had that
the real sweet skunk you know and
started calling it that
so um yeah um so like yeah what i'm
working on
like if you if you did have a
differentiation of the two
i guess red kill skunk whatever the one
people would consider stinky air i guess
i think that's what the people are after
yeah
and so kind of with that being said
i have seen a few photos going around of
a few of our friends with a
plant called roadkill skunk number four
what's this is this just maybe a a
particular pheno that's
you know hitting all the right spots for
you no
no it's um so when i
when i really got to cranking down on
everything like a
you know i had like a bunch of older
stock that i had to get pollinated and
every herb
that pollinated germinated and um
there were a few things that you know
you
used to give us that funk back in the
day you know we're growing outdoors
but um you know i figured like i'd pop
them and check them out
and um i kind of just you know
was doing a pollination i had a client
and one of them in there
and it was like more of the sativa route
and um toss those in there get them made
um grew them out and like you know you
got you got some
some little skunky notes to it you know
like it's pretty good
um you get like the cheesy cheesy skunky
citrusy diesel a little bit with it um
and some of them would be more like i
don't know how to explain it other than
a sour apple green tea or something you
know
but nonetheless like you know it was
kind of just like for shits and grins so
what i did
um they were like 12 things they got hit
um early on to kind of get the project
rolling and uh that was one of them it
was like
wasn't gonna go that route but just kind
of did it
just cuz you know and um hooked up a few
friends with it and they grew them out
and you know everybody liked it a lot
they were like yeah it's funky as hell
but
it's like i know that like i mean yeah
it's skunky but like it gets a lot
better than that
you know it was just kind of like some
shits and giggles
stuff okay so if we just quickly
jump back to you mentioned earlier as
well as i've seen
photos of this one as well the uh the
skelly
cross to the skunk and i think he also
said there's the
chem dog in there as well um
what's what can we expect from that
would that be like an individual release
the chem cis
skunk skelly or just more of an r d
thing well that's kind of kind of more
of an r
d thing um you know you know how i only
and i always hook up
i've got friends and you know cool
people just to
just to be cool like that but um
um like uh
what's more to be seen out of that is
more like an isolation of the
of the mom um not
much is really going to change off of
that and
the hmm
put it um you kind of
you're kind of bringing a lot of family
jeans together
if you will and um
like the recombination that stuff it
worked out really well it was like you
know it was like spitting out
reflectives of
the mother plants you know they were
like a little bit of
little bit of variance you know which
you know i expect you know to see like
you know what
what what are the weirdos gonna come out
like and um
like one of the ones with the sister it
smells like uh
like yellow starburst candy
um like if you could have that smell
with like a patchouli
type incense you know so like alan was
like real off the wall
but like all the rest of them you know
kind of
garlicky and skunky and funky like that
sister was
um the one thing
i noticed like when doing the light leak
stress testing
um they resisted all that you know very
well there was
one that kind of you know tapped out a
little bit toward the end but
it wasn't the last you know that last
week and like i mean it's a pretty
pretty decent light leak i was giving
them too
so they did a lot a lot better than what
i'd even thought they would do
but i did notice like just like the mom
um when they were at that that that
prime time harvest window that they were
going to try to poke at least one or two
nanners out
you know somewhere in the top of the
canopy and um
they resisted the light leak and you
might could say that maybe that was like
their point of tapping out but
the mom kind of does that too you know
it wants to push that little one out
like at that that peak peak harvest time
it seems
so i kind of didn't pay that as much
mine
you know i was just kind of looking at
more of what was
what was retained and it was nice to see
that
you know they didn't they didn't really
you know freak out
but um out of the test group um
there were a few of them that had didn't
even have the the late manner you know
it was
100 are mad for date free which
you know really surprised me and then
out of those uh
one of them actually also happened to be
the best one
you know so that told me hey
you know you're on the right track you
don't have to sacrifice in
any of the other stuff you know like
like that late niner
trait you know that's wanting to push
out during the peak time
like hey the the best pheno didn't do
that it also resisted
you know a lot of stress too and turned
out to be the most potent and the most
uh representative of the mom as well so
i was like huh
cool so maybe you know in a couple of
generations we can fix that
and kind of have more like a pure pure
kim seed
that's the goal of this and how many
generations do you think it would take
to get such a thing only one way to find
out buddy
um but i mean just just based off of
what i saw on the f1 i mean
you know if i want if i wanted to be
like a real shortcut [ __ ] i'd just be
exit one time and i bet you i'd be there
but um
um i don't know i think
if if we're gonna have it more like a
seed form of the
of the mother um i think at least
you know three or four back crosses and
maybe a filial
breeding after that maybe or
i don't know it's it's really hard to
tell until you really get into it
and you know start working them and
growing them and then you kind of
kind of see what direction you're going
to have to go but
um [ __ ] just in the f1 i was i was real
happy with it though
so i mean to draw you back to a point
you made before you said you know
it's all kind of drawing on a lot of
similar genetics in this cross just to
remind everyone we're talking about
skelly original skunk as well as the
chem sis
something i notice is people frequently
reference skelly
as like a skunky strain and i always
inquire about that and there's almost
like this pause for a moment they're
like oh
no i just meant it tasted skunky
and it's almost like i don't know you
know not to sound weird it sounds like
you know like some people out there
maybe think there's skunk in it i guess
well that's like kind of the impression
i get do you think anything about that
well it's really stinky um
i wouldn't call it skunky but it's nasty
you know um
and the the the main components of it
um being is what it is it's like an old
seed bank um hash plate you know like a
neville
made hash plant and i want to say it was
like nl1
across to like a male of nl5 and then l2
or something like that so like i know
that it's like it's primarily
it's like a northern lights combination
focusing more on the shorter phenos and
more indica dominant phenos
so um you know it it definitely it's
stinky as a [ __ ] but it's
like to me it was like more more fuelly
spicy hashy you know but um
like i mean if you had like a bud in
your pocket and that here's the other
thing too is like to me
a lot of weed can smell skunky um
but like something i've noticed is like
a you know weed in a jar
as you're smelling it like all
concentrated like that
when you when you take like a bud out
and you let it breathe
you know and it's able to permeate and
especially like if it gets hot
you know if you're just walking around
with a bud in your pocket like in a bag
you know a lot of weed can smell really
skunky you know
but um sure i forgot where i was going
with that man
i mean ultimately right i think maybe
one of the other
implications we get is something a lot
of guests have referenced in that
the roadkill skunk itself or even more
so just those extremely
accurate skunky smells may actually be
something which is more of like an
afghani artifact as opposed to like a
sam the skunk man type thing oh yeah
absolutely um yeah i'm always on that
same line of thought
that a lot of the skunkier stuff from
back in the day were like afghani
hybrids
and um like skunk afghan hybrids
as well as like northern light skunk
hybrids
and those tended to be you know
everything that
ranged like from garlic to fecal you
know
and everything in between coffee beans
slash skunk burnt rubber
that whole side of the spectrum you know
interesting so another post i've seen
which i think might be in relation to
all of this is
you've referenced in a few posts
something about
the masterpiece you know what is the
masterpiece
ah that's like all my little all my
little projects i've been working on for
so long and finally have them all
done all completed and just be done
like uh then i feel good about it you
know
so because like a lot of projects you
know there's a lot of years on some
stuff too
and some stuff i don't really get to
talk about because you know i just kind
of want to keep it dl
but um it'd just be really nice to have
it all done and
you know people can enjoy it and like
the thing is like i made everything kind
of for me
my snobby uh weed standard so
i kind of figure if i really like it you
know other people would probably like it
too
so um yeah it'll just kind of be the end
of the road i'm making a few things that
i was
pretty proud of and it'll be all
all finito and so
can people expect to be able to maybe
grab a few of these finito
projects at the emerald cup um
well some of them like it's um
it's just some stuff that's um been like
steps into making
making those things but yeah like i'll
always have some
some neat you know neat things with me
and there were things that i made like
intermediary steps or
things that i made just to like kind of
study like what a male is doing across
the broad spectrum
and after running them and growing them
and testing them smoking them stressing
them and everything like
they were really super awesome you know
but it's like
it was never intended to be the project
it was just more of a study of like how
the males
you know kind of going along with
another female
and um you know stuff was really awesome
so like i'll have
some of those things and like i'll hold
on to them like
a little while because you know i'm
still you know researching them and
looking at them
and you know making sure that you know i
know
what i need to know and um
i don't particularly want to just say oh
okay here you go
everybody you know when it's like part
of a program that i'm working as well
so um a lot of it's stuff like that like
so many steps have been made
you know i consider them what's left of
the
what i made to do all the testing with
um
you know i can let some of those out but
they're real limited
limited quantities so
yeah i mean it's interesting that you're
gonna do it that way because i think
it's almost
one of the best ways because something i
noticed was a while ago someone posted a
photo of
growing out cindy 88 and it was like
everyone
in the comments was like wow you got to
grow out like one of the steps in like
you know the overall process and like
obviously you know there's a lot of kind
of excitement as to you know there'd be
more variation that'd be cool to see
you know all that type of stuff so i
think in a way
it's almost like the most rarest of the
limited edition
yeah absolutely like that headband with
the super sativa c club skunk one on it
i mean it's really it's really
phenomenal you know
it's really really awesome but um
like i said with that one i was just
more or less like looking at what the
male does
in a in a related cross you know like
being able to see like
chem 91 with the same male sister d with
the same male
and things that were outside of that
family too you know
like all types of things across the
board and really figure out
you know what was happening but like
with that one with headband i mean he
throws like huge big old fat colas
and real stinky lime candy kush
like uh a little skunkiness to it as
well you know
but um real killer but you know like i
got a handful of those and a bunch of
bunch of little jewels so i have them
with me at emerald and
like when they're gone they're gone like
i'm not you know gonna be making more of
them or anything
so that's interesting you mentioned that
as well because i was gonna ask a
question about the dead bands
um mostly i was gonna say
do you see it as a potential source for
you know like future work maybe like a
new mail but
i actually realized a better question is
have you ever
been doing a similar thing you know
where you're testing out the mail
and then you do maybe not necessarily a
dead band but you trial out one of the
crosses and
and it just catches you off guard and
you're like [ __ ] i've got to work this
out
yeah oh yeah that that happens uh quite
frequently
because like um in certain cases
you you'll do something and be like wow
that didn't work out at all
it's complete [ __ ] there's opposite into
that spectrum of like
holy mother like that is like
far far exceeded what i'd expected
and then you realize like well hey you
know
if i could work that a little bit better
that could actually like change the
whole
the whole duration of the process up and
you might yeah
you might end up wanting to work one
line a little bit longer
and more you know to go back out to
something else and it would improve it
make it that much better
so you will you will run into that
you know like both of them you know
stuff where you're like ah that sucks
and then stuff that's like wow that that
could actually
work and improving something else
because like if you're
you know really studying those males and
how the gene pairs are like transferring
with each other um
you know you can you can see like a
method to the madness
and that's typically how like the
improvements go
you know so yeah
yep you would definitely definitely want
to do that
okay so i mean if you were going to do a
cubing project
for example would you want to use a male
that was
very similar to the female in question
or something
radically different in order to have
easier differentiation i guess
i guess like because after it's all said
and done you're gonna have six percent
of some genes after after four back
crosses right
so i guess it's whatever the
the six percent that you would want left
over
as well as like how something that was
opposite
how it bred into that first f1
generation
and and you know i've
you know there's two lines of thought
with it but i
you know i can say like if you do go the
opposite way
so it's easier to tell out traits in the
males you know for
further back cross and um using
something opposite
you know can make that easier but as the
the process continues you know you're
you're up in the frequency of those
genes from the mother that you're back
crossing to
or the dad that you're using in a back
crossing so
um you you know
it really comes down to like growing out
that that f1 generation
very very very thoroughly and it can
make it tricky if you're using something
that's
you know maybe looks the same but acts
completely different
but if i was gonna go like the
similarity route
me personally i've always been a fan of
like jumping back into the same gene
pool
maybe not the exact same clones and the
exact same thing
but but it is the same gene pool
you know might not be that clone and
that exact male
or what have you but if you're already
like jumping back into that gene pool
during your
you know your your first grow out of
this f1 that you're going to try to
select a male from
after you've looked at enough of those
females you can see how everything's
kind of put together
and then that'll you know can lead you
on your on your journey to finding your
mail that you're going to back cross
um and then that's where the
improvements can come in as well
you know so say like a green avenger if
that was or
you know if we were going to do that
genius project right
you know we'd want to go with that green
avenger and like you know we're already
kind of there because when we grow out
the f1
you know version of that of course it's
like very very similar
um the backside of it is like you have
so many of those genes that are already
back into that pool that you know you
you might really water it down like
sometimes you know not everything
responds the same so like you can
inbreed something
weak you know what i mean um
there's a lot to be said for for hybrid
vigor too
so i mean there's there's a lot of
different
different routes you could go with that
man
there's also the line of thought of um
using two different males to do the
first f1 that aren't related
um if you can have them both in that
same gene pool
and back cross two separate lines um
and at the end of their cubing combine
them um
that that like that little six percent
difference on
on both sides you know um can
reintroduce like a bit of the hybrid
bigger
you know so that's interesting i got
so many questions um first one
do you think that doing a few back
crosses let's say
you know more extreme example be cindy
where you know
got four do you think that you've really
lost hybrid bigger at that point or do
you think it takes a lot longer than
that to lose it
um it depends but if you think about it
like this like
say like you know you're talking about
the princess clone
if you knew it came out of some some
jack hair right
so you got that far um if you figure
that
nl5 and skunk are part of that jack hair
you use nl5 skunk to start your cubing
process
so you take in l5 skunk and pollinate
princess with
it you know that you're kind of you're
back into the gene pool
but yet you're you're still quite
different because
it's not jack that you're starting with
right you know you're using like a
two-thirds of the combination plus you
got an unknown male on there too
perhaps or you just say unknown pollen
donor
in there and
um you um
doing it like that i don't think like
you'll run it down as hard
um but say like
if the say like the bud
that the seed came out of that you had
that clone and
some other type of pollen donor um
if you started cubing from there you
might actually
kind of be more
more pure before like you would hit say
like that point of like where you're
you're starting to water down again um
so and and different things act
differently too
like we have a skunk at a f10 you know
it doesn't lose vigor but i've had
things that you know if you brought them
from f3 to f4 it hit like a big
a big drop off you know so different
things are gonna
kind of respond differently too and so
if we just jump back to a point you made
earlier in regards to say you know
you do your cubing project with two
lines and combine them at the end
do you think a lot of the
characteristics that people would
consider unique to a cubing process like
i guess most notably people will say
that the more inbred a line is
the more dominant it will be when you
cross it to things you know so if you
cross like
you know a bx4 to just like an f1
you generally get you know more
dominance from the bx4
and so with that in mind when you said
you know you combined those two lines
together
technically it'd be an f1 right because
they've got slightly different genetics
even though
very similar um would you consider it to
still be
like have all the properties of like a
cube at that point or
more have like more f1 than the average
cube so to speak or like you know what i
mean
well what you would have you would have
extremely consistent f1
you know like when you did hit that f1
generation
you you would have a lot of a lot of
good attributes you know it wouldn't be
like a poly hybrid f1
you know um it would already kind of be
kind of be locked up but still you know
technically
uh it's still a f1 hybrid just because
you know
from both sides you had six percent and
six percent that weren't
you know um they weren't that clone
so you still have that difference and
then when you combine you make the f1
um you know you're you
you've you've gotten it you've gotten it
all back back together
and um i think from there like if you
you know if that's where you were
looking to to breed from from there like
you know
by f3 like that should be
consistent as hell you know like you
should really be
throwing like the very consistently the
same phenotype
by f3 if you you know if you cube two
separate line
you know to the same to the same mother
and then combine
make the f1 and continue to f3 by that
point you should be really really really
tight
very tight tolerances at that point yeah
wow
i guess that's what we could only hope
all f1 will become in the future right
yeah that wouldn't hold your breath
buddy
so i've seen recently not only the use
of
s1s but even s2s as breeding mothers for
a few different breeders out there how
do you feel about this and is it
something you would ever consider to do
yourself
it might be might be what you have to do
you know i mean it's like
you know reversing and filial breeding
and back crossing i mean all that
you know they're just like different
tools to get to the goal
that you're looking to get to and
whatever
whatever tool you need to use you know
by all means go for it
so like in the case of the the clone
that can only
you know really breed out that that real
stellar potency through you know a
reversal
you know that might be what you have to
do you know
and then you know you might have to to
go the other route you know with males
and
back crossing and out crossing and
taking f3
to read the rest of it you know very
consistent
and you might have to take that f3 that
you've read
and go to the one that you reversed to
say like s2
you know to make sure that you're
hitting that uh if
if you can get it to breed that way that
is to to get that potency
as well okay well the devil's in the
details with this one so i'll give you a
real example
maybe not an s1 or an s2 but would you
no not would you but let's just say you
have to you have to breed with
a feminized plant it's probably going to
be like a pretty well known one which
one would you pick out of all the femmes
good clones that have come from a
fantasy that you're aware of
which one would you pick so to speak
what none of them
uh no no i just didn't um so you're just
asking me like if i could pick like a
like a reversed uh plant like which one
would it be
like yeah yeah well like there's a bunch
there's a bunch of
clones that have come from like femme
seeds right
and like or something right
um yeah or like any of it right
yeah yeah yeah yeah power diesel or
something right
yeah um yeah so yeah what do you reckon
which one would you pick um
for and you said for stability yeah
i mean i guess maybe i figured what you
pick would have be
based on like something like stability
but i mean you could pick up for
whatever reason you want
ah [ __ ] man
um hmm
you know like uh like from like some of
the little side projects and working
like
headbands pretty damn gnarly like
doesn't really have any like what i
would call like bad tendencies to it
it's well behaved yields good it's very
potent
you know so headband's always a good one
jumping onto the next one i guess after
you've finished
the kind of skunk project is there
anything on the horizon that you're kind
of eyeing off already is maybe
next project um
no not really because like by the time
it's all said and done
like you know like i work on multiple
things
at the same time um
so like when that's coming to fruition
you know there's a bunch of other stuff
coming to fruition too
um that 187 with the screaming eagle
that was you know um that was one of
them
um so essentially trying to make my own
little
uh g13 hash plan of sorts you know
so i had to make all the all the steps
to
get to there so that was a little bit of
a
little bit of an endeavor is that
the uh 88 bx or
something a little different no that's
um so i took a kandahar afghani and i
pollinated the 88
grew out a bunch select the male um
real real nice you know very 88 dominant
and then i hit the airborne g13 with it
so that made the stream an eagle um
like the the phenotypes of it um
you know fairly consistent um here and
there you'd see that afghani
pop up like it made like a thicker bud
but the smell flavor
potency was like pretty true across the
board which i liked
but there was this one in particular
that and i didn't keep a clone of it
and like i told myself like no keeping
claims of this run because it's going to
make you complacent and then you're not
going to grow anymore because like
you're just going to have this clone
so anyways man i don't take the clone
and like i'm kicking myself in the ass
for it but anyways
it had a lot more um of the 88 dominance
because like that airborne g13 like
it's a strong breeder you know and like
it really shines through
later in the uh in the offspring so
um that one in particular had that
little bit more 88
influence and um god man
it was great it was like uh
like taste the rainbow style you know
like uh
like every type of fruit candy like
smell all wrapped into like one
it was really really exceptional and it
uh
the the flavor of it too man it really
coated your mouth
you know stayed lingering for a long
long time and i was like man that's
really nice
and uh really nice relaxing
chill effect to it as well you know very
potent
so um anyways you know i was pretty
happy with that
yeah so had to continue to keep growing
them keep growing them until
you know if i'm like the girl that i'm
really truly happy with
and you know get that part done at the
same time
um i wanted to add a little more 88
influence into it
so knowing that the the cinderella 99
male that i had picked out
um it didn't really take too much away
from the moms and if anything it donated
a little
few good things to it made it a little
faster flowering
made the the bud size pretty you know
a lot bigger than what it was but it
retained the purple color
that purpley grapey smell um
water a lot of really good things so um
very potent as well so i wanted to take
the uh
i was calling it 187 because of the 88
c99 you get it
uh male 1 and hitting the best screaming
eagle female
and that should that should combine
everything just right for me it should
be real good
and then i had stuff uh going on with
the orange project
um with that orange uh it was like cali
o
eric 77's calioclone
to sativa c club skunk one and then um
doing a few projects with that i mean
i'd have the orange thing
and then um had some other stuff going
on with um
oh the um uh smokers
so i'm making some uh strawberry stuff
as well
cheese again that's a lot of a lot of
little odds and ends plus the skunks
plus the kim's and
kimmy skunks and this and that's you
know
and everything yeah and i mean i just
kind of figured just hold back and get
it all
you know work just right and perfect and
when i'm real happy with it and then
then it'll be done um
then there was some other things that i
had thrown into the mix
that uh i had reversed the chem dog onto
a bunch of stuff too
and been hunting through that here
lately so that's uh that's pretty cool
too
which cam come dog
the only yeah 91 yeah
so the next question i guess then is
what do you think about uh the idea
of like standout phenotypes being
associated with
uh trifoliation or you know whirling
phyllo taxis
soul mentioned that with the queen of
soul and i've seen the idea also
mentioned by a few other people and i
was just always under the impression
that
you know the whole trifoliate slash
whirling file taxi was
actually like not related to like a
phenotype per se but more just something
which would have like you know like a
probability of affecting each and every
plant
where do you sit on that one um i've
seen it go both ways
like um the the foul attacks is like
i've seen that have like
some adverse effects you know um
you'll see it in certain plants like pop
up here and there but not like
consistently like where you could like
apply like the golden mean to it or any
[ __ ] like that
but um on triple eights
um i've always kind of viewed it as like
um given the rarity of it you know it's
not something you see every single day
um that it was kind of like the plant's
way of trying to evolve
you know so you know i've seen it in
certain cases
where it didn't work out too good but
that's not to say
because it was a trifle eight you know
it could just been like some [ __ ] jeans
in the pool
you know and it just came out shitty
because trifle eight or not it was just
destined to be shitty
um but i've also seen it work out very
exceptional and once again
i you know i couldn't say for sure
but it it's also turned out
um to where that did
become like a distinguishing trait that
you wanted to
look for in the males you know so
um
you know it actually make your make your
hunt a lot easier if
if that is like what you're kind of
looking forward to
so if you have noticed the correlation
like definitely the trifoliate females
you know were the ones that really
really really kicked it off like
100 notches um ideally you'd want to
look for that
that triflate male and you could
actually you know if you knew that
for fact is what you were going for you
could sprout
a pretty huge population and um
not take up much space but you know i
have seen trophies like turn into
triflates later on too
so but a lot of the times you know from
the from the get-go
they're you know going to be expressing
themselves
yeah okay so a question i've got
which i mean you could apply to that
previous question really perfectly if
you wanted is
how many generations do you think it
would take to be able to breed
one very specific trait into a strain
you know while obviously trying to not
[ __ ] up too much of the other things
going on so you know yeah like if i said
i've got a strain and it's perfect in
every way and i just want to get one new
trade in there you know
how many generations approximately do
you think you'd be looking at like if i
said to you know can you give me an eta
so
you might you know what i mean like what
would you tell me is what i'd be looking
at
um depends like because if it breeds
true or not
you know if it pops up as a recessive
then
and also like the you you're looking
like for like uh
like a clone or are you looking for a
seed line that's like consistently
spitting
that trade out yeah i guess like a
seedline
all right well i mean it i i've seen it
done
in one i've seen it done in one step
like and it just works you know but that
doesn't happen a lot
so it would depend on what trait if it
breeds true
for that trade or not and the frequency
that you see of that trait
and you know each generation and monitor
the the percentage the increase of like
the
the the more desirable trait
frequency that you're seeing until
you're you know you're happy with it
so um
so like if it's like with color right so
like they had to be purple
um you know you might notice
it could be like more like 30 percent
you know showed color
in the f1 generation um you took the f1
generation right
and you back crossed to the mom and then
you also
uh let's say you went f2 selected a
purple and went to f3
um you might grow out the f3 generation
and say
well um you know
i'm only like 50 50. you know
even after all that i'm at 50 50. um
in the one back cross you might have
noticed that you upped it to like 75
you know purple you know so
yeah you know in that case
and say well you know if the only thing
that's truly important to use that
purple color i would say
you know continue to back cross you know
um or you know it might not work that
way at all
you might just say like yeah you know
one in ten you know maybe purple and
then the rest aren't
and you know it's really hard to get
that it's telling you you know it's not
not really breeding true for that trait
and um
it'll take you know very large
populations
and probably a good good amount of time
before you could really
you know read that true so the
differences in
all this is like could be a year it'd be
ten years man
you know and anything in between and
just kind of
a lot of variables you know yeah okay
so i got a bit of a devil's advocate one
for you and i think me and gene kind of
even referenced this the underlying
principle in this question
let's say you were doing a project and
you know you obviously you know you've
referenced already your
high levels of standards let's say you
could only get
one in 10 seeds to give what you wanted
but it was exactly what you wanted but
no matter what you did you could never
get it to be more than that
would you want to release that or not
give it out so to speak given it's kind
of not really up to par with your
standards
um well it's
if if we're talking like overall
standards like it was like some straight
[ __ ]
like it's going in the trash can now if
if you say like if i was gonna breed
something and i want it to be
very um i don't know
uh high yielding and skunky um
and like i said you know out of every
pack you're gonna get that one
that that does do that and like you have
tried to further breed it and it just
does not
it just does not work but you do get
one in ten that say well we'll do that
and then the rest are like
you know maybe subtle variances of it or
um maybe different um
if you just couldn't do it and people
wanted it that bad and you were up front
about it
you know and just say look you know this
is the one that you want
it pops up one in ten like you know you
just tell them
you know right off the bat you know this
is gonna be your hunt
but you should have one out of you know
if you sprout all these seeds you
you know you'll have it um in that case
i guess it would be cool
you know long as it meets all the other
criteria and that you're
you're being upfront about it um but
like i mean if it's some straight
garbage and it's
taken a lot of seeds to find that one
like you
probably wouldn't want to wouldn't want
to let that one go
let's throw it in the trash yeah
interesting to me it it spurs this idea
of mine whereby
it's it's kind of like for me it's an
odd thing the way
a lot of strains are advertised in the
sense that most strains you're going to
get a
large variety of phenotypes and so
it it sits a bit weird with me the way
four phenotypes all have the same name
and so i don't know i almost think that
it kind of is like the way in which you
are describing things already you know
like for example if you buy a packet of
blue dream
even if it's really well made there's
maybe only one particular phenotype
that's like representative of blue dream
and the rest are kind of what we're
mentioning now like
variations maybe even a bit bunk you
know what i mean so i kind of feel like
that
almost happens yeah it happens a lot man
and like um if they were you know if
they told like if i was like a seed
buyer
and i bought them and you know they're
like yeah you know this is what you get
and if i grow 10 of them out and don't
see it and then if i grow 20 out and
i'll see it and it's all a bunch of bunk
like
i'm gonna be pissed but if the guy told
me like
typical results are this this this and
this
but one in 50 etc
may end up like this it was like that uh
cherry ak-47
you know and those guys like even put it
to the test like
how many how many seeds does it take to
get that cherry
cherry fina and serious seed dudes they
grew out a thousand
and they found one so they were like
yeah cherry finna is about one in a
thousand so
you know if everybody had smoked cherry
ak and was like wow that's
[ __ ] then they went back united by you
know pax ak-47
um you know and didn't see it they'd be
like bummed out but
the thing is like they didn't advertise
it as such
you know what i mean yeah interesting i
never knew that was the backstory behind
that one
yeah man yeah that was a real
really rare gem and you know they ended
up doing it over there just to see
you know what what it would take to to
find that one
and yeah it was out of a thousand
so one strain that we don't mention
maybe as much as we should on the show
coming from serious seas cali missed
it's an interesting one because a lot of
people are polarized by the fact
some afghani genetics were introduced
into it i think around the 2000s and for
a lot of people it just ruined it
where do you sit on all that and you
know how do you view the original cali
mist at least
i was never really into it man i never
you know maybe i just didn't get the
right um
the right expression or quality grow of
it you know what i mean
but like in my experiences through the
days like
it just never really appealed to me
too much okay cool
might do a bit of a random question what
is the best barbecue dish
you know brisket button bulk shoulder
um i'm pretty i'm pretty keen on brisket
man
like i do like that but i don't know you
can't really go wrong
as long as this cooked right that's good
oh yeah but yeah brisket is pretty good
man
i'm looking forward to the emerald cup
getting some some good brisket from
barbecue bee
oh yeah yeah that'll be keller man i'm
gonna tear it up too
alright starved the whole time
yeah yeah so i mean while we're on the
topic of the emerald cup the inside
scoop is that you and skunk va will have
a booth together is this true
yeah yeah he's going to be pressing
rosin
he's going to be hooking it up out there
so
yeah expect maybe a bit of a collab
project in the future
you never know man you never know
[Music]
i know he's not he's gonna have a lot of
he said like chem dog
kim crush silva kim and all that and
he'll be there and uh
preston rising like on the spot
so should be good man that's that's like
an experience like come get some fresh
rosin from skunk ba himself
yeah yeah that's like that's pretty
that's pretty darn good
yeah get some chem 91 rosin and that's
like your stoner story to top everyone
else
yeah that's pretty good uh i couldn't
think of a better way to get it
and i will be too sorry
let me get a little bit of that man
alrighty so um we were chatting about it
a little while ago
cindy 99 it's got crazy needs for
calcium i've had a few people message me
about this what's your tips for ta
for staying on top of essentially a
plant that's got crazy calcium demands
um what the like when when you already
know that
in advance um like the way that i mix my
soil up
like i got some pretty good pretty good
sources of calcium that are in there
that you know break down you know nice
and slow and steady
um so it just
you know it just revolves to me you know
trying to facilitate
that especially during bloom
so i know before i even go into bloom
like i'm feeding at a heavy dose
um prior to that you know where most
people would
you know wouldn't wouldn't really slam
it that early on
i do um that way you're kind of kind of
always like a week ahead of everything
but the beauty in it is like when you do
take it away
like she really fades out really quick
and really nice
you know so that's kind of like the good
point of it
yeah okay so you use it to like yeah
time you fade well
yeah yeah exactly if you're in um if
you're in hydroponics you know you're
just
you know upping up your calcium and [ __ ]
um
you know i'd say like the week prior to
bloom
you know like where normally you know
you wait to be in bloom or
you know you would go ahead and give it
give it that
that little boost prior to
okay and so just as a bit of a
change of questions here resonance males
you know this is something that's come
up before
i got a bit of a specific question about
them i've noticed
when i look at like really closely at
seedlings when they're really young
i swear i find like little almost like
trichomes
on a lot of the small ones when they're
really young do you think
that's like a commonality thing or is
that the same as like if i grew
some of those males out they would be
males with trichomes on them
um i've kind of seen it hit and miss you
know
because like the little ones you know
seem like a good majority of them do it
it's just like to what degree
and then like you know um they tend to
keep that
that type of characteristic you know
through through the growth
um with the with the males i mean i've
i've never been so lucky as to see like
the the one fellow from alaska
he uh he constantly finds them like i
mean
full-on resin rails down the leaf
down the petiole stems like pretty
pretty nuts
so like i can't imagine it would be a
very bad thing
so um but that that's telling me it's
something i guess coming off the
coming off the x chromosome wants to
breed for resin
resin production so that would tell me
it's uh
it's a good thing so would you
be so willing as to say that you would
go for resness males
if i had one yeah absolutely absolutely
all righty kind of somewhat related how
detrimental is it to
re-veg a plant some people i don't think
it happens so much anymore but some
people do struggle to
tell the sex of the plants so they'll
kind of change the light cycle up and
re-batch it you know do you think this
is damaging and i guess maybe at the
more extreme end of the spectrum
if you've forgotten to take a clone and
you know you're like re-veging like a
fully floured harvested plant
do you think that's detrimental like is
is the resulting plant going to be
similar or maybe a bit
worse um i think like both ways
like totally doable thing but they take
time so in the case of we just had like
the lower
third of a plant you know we left like a
couple of buds on it right
and we're just to re-badge it takes a
long time before you really get any
growth out of it anyway
and then that growth is going to be kind
of wacky for a little while
so i just think it takes it takes a
little longer
for it to really get back into the swing
of things
before like you can start taking planes
and blooming them again
because i think like if you take another
climb too early and throw it in bloom
it'll act a little bit wacky on you so i
think it's just more important just to
give it that
that time you know to fully fully
revenge and start throwing out you know
more than single leaves and
a little mutated stuff you know throw
out like some proper fans and
become more of a plan again and then
taking climbs from there
but like i've re-veg stuff before in the
past
and i have one that we did five times we
were just doing it just to see
you know like what you know what
happened
like if it got better or got worse or
whatever what not
and um you know stayed the same every
single time
a bit unexpected in my opinion yeah
okay so i mean we're on the topic of
unexpected
are you kind of of the mindset that some
of the more memorable strains
throughout history or just maybe ones
you've made
are ones that kind of produce really
unexpected results like i guess you know
if you've got one parent that's
chocolate and one that's strawberry you
know you kind of
expect it to be like chocolate
strawberry or whatever and
the offspring instead is like rotten
cheese i find that
the predictable strains tend not to be
ones that go down in history
would you agree with that or what do you
think yeah it seems like that's the case
a lot of times
but it's like the weird ones you know
that's that's the reason why they're so
memorable because they're really unique
so um i did uh chem dog d
and hindu kush and that
in in theory should produce like a lot
of like really nasty
funky smells and um they did
but there was one that popped up you
know strawberry man
the most strawberry strawberry i'd ever
seen in weed
and that was the one we called smuckers
man but
you know totally just blew my mind you
know
and then that turned into its own little
and little project
you know for strawberry stuff and like
found out like it
something that weird you wouldn't think
like all right now if i take this
and you know breed it to something else
like will it
will it retain any of the strawberry
fruitiness or am i going to go back to
like rank and ask
and um we hit it with c99 and it stayed
nice and strawberry and
and good so that was like a big big plus
lets me know that
it could be work so i started working on
that too
you must be a mine reader so my next
question was
i have seen a photo of smucker's c99
cross
ii bubble berry what's what's the deal
with bubble berry and what's the deal
with this cross
can we expect to see more of it yeah
just uh
messing around with it at the moment
just seeing uh seeing what all it would
all it holds
because yeah it's like an old old bubble
berry clone
so it uh it's got more of that
i don't know how to explain it really
like a pungent
very pungent skunky fruity it's kind of
like that
uh like that four-way it's kind of funky
okay and do you plan to do any future
work with the bubble berry because
that's
that's an interesting one that i don't
think too many people are familiar with
but the ones who are and the ones i've
spoken to
extremely fond of it oh yeah yeah that's
a
really killer killer plant um
a lot like i reversed the 91 on to it
as well so i think it's going to start
digging through
through those here really soon too
so if we jump back to a comment bode
made in his interview he said that he
thinks
the uh the hash plan neville used in the
creation of skelly was the pnw
hash plant i'm pretty sure you could get
that one if you wanted you know have you
ever grown it out and do you think that
there's any possible relationship
between the two
um sorta um i
think so i know that when
he may i'll tell you what i'm gonna grab
this catalog real quick
that way i'm not guessing hold on
all right so
now it was always my understanding
like he used that ash plant
to make a hash plant but he also had one
that was just a northern lights
um hybrid
so i know that uh
they're very similar you know very very
similar
yeah so i mean i guess it maybe goes
without saying that
i think bodhi kind of referenced it as
well skelly is like a big
step up in potency than what the pnw one
is right
all right so here we have
uh out of the 1989
seed bank catalog all right
so hash plant pure
says after years of inbreeding and
testing
we have decided to offer our famous hash
plant as a pure variety
the pure hash plant differs from the
hash plant northern lights
number one f1 hybrid and that is
it is in red strain possessing the
wonderful
indica taste and high of the original
cutting
okay so that that tells me like he's
he's talking about
you know that original you know pacific
northwest cutting
um the yield vigor will be less than the
hybrid
under most conditions and that's like
what we were talking about earlier
you really you start inbreeding
something you lose a little bit of that
hybrid bigger
but the quality will be better this one
this is the one to get if you're a true
indica connoisseur
or serious breeder you can expect a very
fast indoor finish copious resin and a
flat top
fudge structure now when i look at the
picture of that
that looks like you know skelly all all
day long
so now if you look at the um
the um hash plant northern lights number
one
hybrid it looks like you know you just
took that that
pacific northwest cutting and hit it
with a
nl1 what else did he do here
man if you could just order some of this
[ __ ] still it'd be awesome
the g13 hash plant
but like uh unless he was making films
you know that
you couldn't have couldn't have done
that
and i think he said he still has some of
the stock
heck yeah so
northern lights 5 across to the nl2 then
he was selling the nl2 and an f3
and let's see
what else got the garlic blood and he's
got a lot of
oh [ __ ] just basically every building
blocks train ever
yeah pretty pretty much but um
so yeah i would i would say that um
his hash plant pure was probably said
that
that pacific northwest cutting across to
one of the
one of the nl crosses that he did um
i'm thinking like the the one within l1
or two
probably uh bat crossed or inbred
somehow with that
pacific northwest cutting again and then
yeah that's where
where it is interesting and so
i guess the notable thing i find about
scaly and
uh some other plants is that the
aesthetics
isn't really the the be all end or with
these plants
yeah i guess it's a little different for
you because you're quite familiar with
this but overall
where do aesthetics sit kind of in your
little hierarchy of attributes do you
value it or just given you're familiar
with strains where it's
totally not correlated in general do you
not correlate it
um oh man like
i see i like i can see you know like
beauty and
all of it because like i know what it is
you know
like um certain things like said that
skelly it's not the most aesthetic
thing in the world but uh the smell the
taste and the quality of the stone and
everything
um makes it makes up way way up for it
you know
um and there's other things say like
purple punch you know
they're purple real frosty and kind of
worthless you know
like in the in the standing department
you know i looked real pretty
so like i'm more of a smell
taste quality type you know
more so than like the looks alone you
know what i mean
yeah for sure and so i guess kind of
with this in mind
how can breeders better cater to the
commercial market
because i think me gene kind we kind of
struck on this idea a little bit and
he said something along the lines of
like there's two major types of growers
and cali's the one who pump out
units and the ones who hold on to the
rare heirloom strains and basically
sacrifice the crop to do so
so i guess with that in mind how can we
try to cater
you know to the guys pumping out units
so that it's not just blue dream and
it's not just
you know certain strains that maybe
aren't the best like you know purple
punch as you just mentioned
yeah you really have to you have to
start breeding
for um yield and mine too and that's
whether
you can breed yield into something
without sacrificing
a lot of other things or if there is
some type of sacrifice and you can reach
some form of a compromise with it like
if it's yielding that much you know
if it is like commercial commercial
units as they put it
it's normally not very good you know
what i mean
so if you can make that better um strike
a happy medium or
get better i think you could do that
um if if i was gonna do it i'd probably
be looking more to
um cater a lot more to the greenhouse
and outdoor dudes
um they tend to you know
they grow a lot um and since like the
price of a pack in
california for their outdoor it goes so
low um
you know they're looking to get it
extracted you know so
once they extract it you know the price
went
went back up you know because the oil
that was produced from
something that was greenhouse or outdoor
um you know it's worth just as much as
anything else long as the quality is
good right so if you could
if you could offer good outdoor and
greenhouse producers that
offer the yield and very high level of
terpenes and
be a good quality product with a lot of
the
pest and mildew and mold is right into
it i think
like that's where you would have it and
then if you're marketing say toward
like commercial indoor facilities
you would be looking for very short
flower times
as well as you know the yield and trying
to
keep the happy medium but i think like
if you can
you can shorten your flower times enough
you know you can get a whole extra
run in per year you know versus the next
guy
if you're like really on it you know so
i think like that would
bring a lot of value to you know a
commercial facility
um and especially like if you can give
them that
ridiculously high yielding and also like
pretty damn potent and stinky weed
you know that that would help them out
you know
okay and so one question i personally
wanted to ask was
the genius haze the apollo haze
fantastic line at first i was wondering
are you going to work it forward but
then i was like no more importantly
are we ever going to see the grail haze
released in straight form
you know i really love all the crosses
it's been used in what were the females
of that like
um they're really really gnarly and like
the thing is
is like a body of mine is the guy who
made those
so um you know unless
that was something like he wanted to do
you know he can do it
but um you know nobody's heard from him
in a while
like it kind of he's kind of like half
worried about him i don't know what
happened to him
but um yeah he was the one that made the
the actual grill hayes so i was just
selecting a
select number out the bunch and so what
were the girls like were they just kind
of like bigger yielding cindy's
sort of yeah more or less like a
long like more like spear type buds and
um still really quick flowering time
um a lot of candied type type smells you
know
it's pretty nice so
here's his interesting one i've
mentioned before and i'd love to know
your opinion on it
i've noticed that you know often plants
can basically be telling you that
they're happy but then if you were to
give them say a t
i e externally more nutrients than they
would have otherwise had access to
you know they might have a bit of a
bloom of growth and so it kind of
signifies to me
like although they might not have been
showing deficiencies
like they likewise could have used more
than what they had access to
do you think that that's kind of the
case or have i kind of misanalyzed
something
how do you see that whole situation yeah
i mean you're totally right um and i've
seen it like the opposite too
like it's not showing up it's not
showing a toxicity
but you're like stunning the yield you
know like it's not like harming out or
like burning
or darkening up a whole lot but that
extra bit of food
caused it the yogi less and you know
i've also seen it
where it yields more so and then you got
to find out why
you know sometimes it has nothing to do
with like any npk values
a lot of times it has to do with a lot
of you know like sulfur and
magnesium and gaussian you know
sometimes it has to do more with a
certain timing
of a of a tea like you said and also
you know like a fulvic and veg or a
humic and bloom
type you know supplement to help it take
it up you know
and then some plants don't react well
some plants freak out and hurt
you know like uh it's really an
individual basis
like their eating habits and all it's
like they're generally the same
it's kind of like people i guess
breakfast lunch dinner
but what do they eat for breakfast what
do they eat for lunch and what they eat
for dinner you know you might have a
vegan versus a
you know meat eater vegetarian in the
middle
some people don't eat breakfast you know
i mean you gotta kind of
work with them and tune them every time
so sometimes you get lucky and you know
knock it out the park the first time and
then you'll try something different like
feeding it that little more
and notice your yield went down or maybe
it went up but that's what it's all
about is repeating the
same grow over you know over and over
until you've really
really tweaked it and that just takes
time and trial and error
so how do you feel about some of the
organic additives that
fall outside of kind of the norm of
products so like you know obviously
fulvic acid pretty common one
what about some of the more i guess kind
of exotic things we see nowadays like
insect frass or like chitin based
products or things like mammoth pee
where do you sit on those ones have you
dabbled with them and would you
recommend them
yeah we use insect breasts that's really
nice stuff
um yeah those kittens you know
it's a big help um keeping the immune
system rolling and everything too
um that in correlation with like alloy
water and everything
um the mammoth p i tried out
um it kind of
like it did did what it was supposed to
but it seems like it's like um
like got an enzyme in it or something
too there's like certain things that
made it like want to foxtail out
so i kind of figured i was like ah it's
probably like
you know it's like an enzyme and
you know some type of fungal fungal
microbe
so um
so do you tend to like dabble with all
the
the new and latest things or are you
more kind of like just sticking to like
the
the known and trusted things per se you
know i
i tried to be that guy and uh trying
some things out and um and it didn't
work out good
you know i mean it was all right but the
old tried and true system was better
so kind of went back to that and um
you know every now and again i'll i'll
hear when
but it's normally like through a friend
or something like it said that you know
they tried something out
and it really really you know helped and
there's only like a handful of people
i know that i'm really gonna listen to
you know what they have to say so um
so yeah every now and again you know try
something different
and so what is kind of your tried and
true staple like what's
what's the one kind of amendment or the
one
thing in your soil mix that you just
think does some serious good work
that's all of it you know all but kind
of working together
but the soil mix with the dragonfly
coconut for uh coconut water for an
enzyme
rotate that with like malted barley for
an enzyme
instead of the dragonfly and the
microbes you know like the lush roots
and then supplementing like you know
some like juices and
some sugars toward the end uh it seems
to work the best
nice nice and so question i've been
asking a few people
and you i guess you kind of brought it
up once or twice already strains that
throw
nana's in like the last week or so
i know that there are a lot that do it
and they're like they don't have pollen
they're infertile so that's really kind
of like a no-brainer obviously
it's not that you know it doesn't affect
anything per se except for maybe
aesthetics
but the ones that do produce pollen it's
in the last week
do you find that to be like a negative
trait or do you just think
oh you know i guess it's only really a
problem if you had like a plant
several weeks behind in flower you know
like do you think it's pretty
acceptable because i mean there's a lot
of strains that do it
yeah i mean like i i grow some things
that
that do it you know and like they're
they're that good so you know
i cater to it but um
if me and you was running like a big
commercial facility and like
you know we have like tables or like a
quarter of the building
or a room what have you comes down um
when we're breaking plants down
i mean the pollen could go over to the
the part that's
say week two week three flower and get
pollinated
and then you know people end up with the
seeds and they're weed
you know they don't they don't want that
so uh
um you know it would be a problem with
that but if me and you're just like you
know
running our little grey rooms doing our
thing and you know no big
no big deal but um
yeah like it just depends what you're
what you're doing it could be a big
problem but
me and you're just running like grows at
our house or
where we're running like a monocrop or
something and it all comes down at the
same time you know
that could be fine but um
ideally yeah you wouldn't have it but
that's just the way it works
some of them are some of them are that
good and they like it
you know you just gotta do your best
yeah yeah and i dig so switch it up for
a moment
when can the general public expect to be
able to experience
local h for themselves uh like smoking
some weed of it
yeah maybe growing it themselves oh
well like giving a client you mean like
if that's what you're gonna do
no hell no
um i don't know it plays like a nice
little role on like a lot of the
little breeding projects and stuff so
i don't know man i couldn't tell you
well there's your answer folks yeah
um so a question i get
asked from a lot of people because i
think they probably think i ask
people the question even though i don't
include it in the interview which is not
true i include basically everything in
the interview
basically i always get asked the
question
how do you guys source all the
old-school gems that you work with you
know is it like a
a crazy seed hunt expedition or like you
know how do you go about coming across
some of these old ss
c gems so to speak well a lot of that
um it's like family heirloom type [ __ ]
if you want to
call it that um you know something like
passed down to me
um you know and then you got some old
cats
store the seeds up in the freezer and
they're kept you know a long time that
way
and sometimes people get there get their
stuff like that or
if you travel around a lot and
meet and greet people i guess you know
like i've been to like shows before
where
dudes come out the woodwork and they're
like hey
yeah you know i was growing
a bunch of williams wonder on the hill
for like forever and
i heard you you know you're into that
and i made
a batch of seeds every few years from
the original so here you go
so sometimes it could happen like that
or somebody's just keeping a clone
around
or whatnot but a lot of it's just like
what we've what we've had in our life
leading up to this point it's not like
we just started doing it
you know a year or two ago yeah i've
been doing a long
long time yeah ain't no fresh meat
no definitely not the first
rodeo so
how can growers be properly rewarded for
finding kilafinos
if if you have a certain space and you
choose to use that space to entirely
phenoh hunt
and you sacrifice a large part of what
would have been i guess like a good crop
how can we as like a community like
compensate people i guess not
like in the literal sense but i feel
like essentially
if over the years and this kind of goes
back to that point me and jean made
about people
either pumping out units or retaining
the heirlooms it's like if you do the
math over the years
these people are foregoing a substantial
amount of money to do essentially like
you know obviously they enjoy the weed
and enjoy keeping around but it's
there's a bit of a community slasher you
know like a
a selfless aspect to it you know how how
do we properly like thank and or
you know what i mean like compensate
people who do this
um i mean it's it's kind of
it's kind of crazy on like a lot of
levels but
i would say like the number one thing
would be like
people that do put in the time to
either like do the big pinot hunts and
like actually have
like that very superior weed
or if it's like you know they're growing
an old heirloom strain
um some of these things you know they
don't
particularly yield like blue dream does
but
they sure do smoke a whole lot better
and like the mindset
with a lot of the stores and the
dispensary world
like especially like in colorado's like
they really want to lowball the hell out
of you
and they want to make out like it's kind
of all the same a pound is a pound is a
pound and
um you know they don't want to pay
pay the grower what it what it actually
is worth and then they go and mark it up
like 260 percent or something you know
it's kind of ridiculous but i think like
if you support good
um good farmers good farms um
you know don't don't be the one to
complain about i guess like the price
you know within reason
you know if you're like a um
like a distributor or a store owner or
something you know
like that that would help immensely you
know
but um you know if people would reward
quality with you know sticking to that
or
you know i don't know just
like with anything else i suppose like a
good restaurant
or what have you you know you'd
recommend it to your friends
you know yeah so the idea that jumps to
my mind when you say that is
i i know of some people who grow some
incredibly boutique
weed and it's it's more expensive than
the average stuff
and people you know there are some
people who get really angry at that
and like in my mind it's kind of a bit
like well
you know like if you want to drive a
really expensive car like that's kind of
your choice you know what i mean like
it's not like a car that costs a hundred
thousand dollars is
literally five times as good as a car
that costs twenty thousand dollars you
know like the
the scaling isn't linear it's you know
it's probably like 50
better or something like that you know
but but nevertheless there are people
who want that type of thing so in my
mind it's like if you want to pay for a
premium product like
cool you know as long as no one's
forcing you to but then the the
naysayers will say
yeah but this is different because this
is medicine and and i kind of think like
i don't really see how that works though
are you with that same mindset or like
how do you see that
well i mean if it's if it's through
somebody's medicine
um i think it should all of it should be
like of the utmost quality
you know and if it's for
like a truly sick individual then they
should be helped along with that
but i ain't talking about like you know
i mean like
us is like humanity on on earth like
we're all sick
right to some degree or another whether
you know you back aches or you know
you're tired or
you know you're too jittery or you uh
you know what i mean everybody
everybody's got something wrong with
them you know so like if you say like
medicine in that regard
you know whatever but like truly truly
ill sick people that like rely on it
need it they should be helped out
you know um and yeah if it is
for like genuinely you know for medicine
medicine like um
it should be the utmost quality and like
the the best it could possibly be
you know that's my my standpoint on it
recreationally i mean
[ __ ] i mean if i was if i had a weed
store
or you know a grower that supplied
stores of both you know like
you know maybe it's just me but like i
want it to be like the best
possible i want people to say like hey
wow you know that's awesome
because i feel like if you're giving me
money you know i'm gonna give you
quality
i'm not gonna give you dog [ __ ] and two
like i want to stand out against my
competition
he does sling dog [ __ ] you know so
um either way like me personally
i'm gonna go for the quality and the
best you know each time i don't like to
sacrifice that type of stuff
yeah it's interesting i think i guess i
think kind of the underlying
argument that some of the people make in
the
you know the australian scene at least
is like if you're producing really high
quality and maybe you want to be
compensated for that it's like
no you're like obliged to instead sell
for
like you know far less to someone who's
really sick even though you may not like
know someone who's sick and like you
know what i mean like
yes yeah so that's what i think is
interesting because
i also just think at least in my
personal experience i haven't met a ton
of like white collar growers
and i have a feeling you need those guys
as well
and so yeah my my kind of thinking is
that a lot of white collar guys just
probably do it for themselves and don't
talk to anyone
you need those people to come to the
table and so if there's pressure
that you have to be doing a certain
thing with your crop like it's not going
to be incentivizing people to come to
the table so to speak
yeah yeah exactly like i said
you know there's like varying degrees of
like
sick you know um so like when kids i
take care of like
they're reliant on it like without it
they're
most likely would die you know they need
it
it's so like and you know very very ill
but then like you know i got a couple of
buddies that like
i mean they could be like yeah my you
know my back hurts a little bit
or whatever you know they they're fine
monetarily or whatever
and that's one thing but it's yet
another thing you know
one it's kids two they're really sick
very very sick
and three like family doesn't have any
money because you know
all of it goes to doctor bills if they
do got any you know
so like with them like i don't charge a
penny
you know i just give it to them like
here it is it's on the house
but like if my buddy that like his back
was you know
whatever i don't i really don't give a
[ __ ] what did it what it's for they're
gonna they're gonna pay me
and they're gonna pay me good for it
yeah yeah that's that's kind of what i'm
thinking
yeah another kind of similar thing to
what we're referencing with you know
like compensating people for finding the
clones
is that often you'll hear stories of
people being like oh yeah this this
clone was worth
five thousand dollars ten thousand
dollars and you know and and the
underlying tone is
that's outrageous and it's like but at
the same time
the person who found that maybe had to
do such a big phenomenon that they
forego
like more than that amount of money in
you know what i mean potential crop
and so i guess what i'm thinking is do
you see a bit of a cognitive dissonance
there in the way i do where it's like
well to get these things you need to
sacrifice and you're not willing to make
that sacrifice so
you kind of do have to compensate in a
way you know what i mean or do you think
like now you shouldn't
really charge for clones or something
along those lines well
i mean people are going to pay and
people are going to do
and do what they want to do so like as
long as there are people
out there willing to pay it people are
going to be out there selling it
you know like um there there's a lot of
things out there that go for astronaut
astronomical amounts of money that
aren't really
there's no like real hard work into it
or anything it's just based off of
rarity you know there's a lot of
paintings out there that are worth
millions of dollars that
frankly i mean to me this looks like
[ __ ] this looks like somebody just
[ __ ] threw up goddamn color
on a canvas you know but to somebody
that's
priceless you know so you got that
end of it um then you have
the other end of it i guess like if it
was like uh
say like for breeding or what have you
you know like if it was that rare of a
genetic or something or whatnot i could
see like value in that
um or if like you were making um
[Music]
making a seed line right like we have to
do the same thing
we have to grow out a whole lot you know
stuff and
you know a lot of it doesn't turn out
that great you know
like i mean it's all right most people
would be stoked but
i'm not so to me it was like you know
it was filling up space where it could
have been used for something else so
like you take losses there
but when you do have like your good seed
lines and you sell it i mean that's why
we charge money for it
because you know we had to put money and
space and time
into it you know um and then there's
guys that sell like individual
clones you know flats of clones like us
to make their money back
and then there's other people like we
used to do back in the day we'd make
[ __ ] that the other guy doesn't have and
we know he don't got it because he
couldn't make it
you know it was something very unique
but in that case we would hoard the hell
out of the clone
and um we'd be the one growing the wheat
and selling the weed
and nobody else had that weed because we
had that weed you know
so we were getting reimbursed in that
way so
it seems like no matter what you know
somebody's gonna get
reimbursed for it no matter what
but to what degree you know because like
there's people who sell like thousand
dollar packs of
randomly chucked together seeds and
fancy boxes like
people people do that [ __ ] you know but
it was like real rare and maybe it's
like the dankest [ __ ] on earth like i
don't know
but there were people there like waiting
to pay it you know
just because you know beauty's in the
eye of the beholder
i guess you know yeah okay
and so if we jump over to some more
growing style questions
we've seen a rise in popularity of
defoliation lately
what's your kind of thoughts on this
whole thing are you into it or do you
feel it's maybe counterproductive
uh it depends uh like it goes back to
the feeding thing
and how caliber plants kind of different
you know some plants are into it some of
them aren't
some of them are into it but only at
certain points during the cycle
you know what i mean so i've never
gone so extreme as like
what i've what i've seen but i mean i
like on headband you know i defoliate it
you know fairly fairly heavy in the
beginning and
sometimes even like cut them back just
so that way they'll
um they'll stack a little bit harder you
know
certain things that want to stretch a
lot like that and get viney on you
they tend to respond a little bit better
to that
um you could take like that skelly hash
plants a leaf
monster you know um you can
pull off so much leaf off of that thing
but
i found that it likes it like done at a
couple different points you know
so like pre pre-flower and then a little
bit
um a little bit later
[Music]
but it grows too much leaf so you have
to pull it off
and um but it still wants some
you know i don't like it like if you
just strip them all off
and don't like that at all so it just
depends you know
and so you mentioned earlier you like to
rotate your enzymes in your feedings be
it the
aloe the cocoa or the mold how do you
kind of rotate your feedings you know
because
question i get asked a lot by people is
should you try to like stagger each
thing you know like as you
reference like malt one time something
else the next something else the
following
or a bit of everything in one do you
think there's a difference between the
two
what's your breakdown on the situation
i've messed around with a few different
ways from like
using nothing but the one thing each
grow and then going to where i was like
staggering it
and then where i was going like half
strength with both you know
to kind of combine them and then um
going with using one in the first
part of the cycle and then another one
during the latter part of the cycle
um and it does it does seem to
it does seem to kind of have their their
benefits on the timing
but i don't know if it's just me or not
so
um i would just say like you know
play around with all those things and
see what works best for you
okay and i had actually read some things
saying that
some of the specific cytokines in
coconut water
may not be all that um how should we say
advantageous in flower versus say
veg have you ever noticed anything like
that or do you find coconut water and
flour is still good
yeah it's pretty damn good and um i
think like a lot of the simple sugars
and carbohydrates that are in it
um help with the terpene production a
little bit
so like i'd be more inclined to use like
make sure that i was using like the
coconut water
like later you know like mid bloom
and stuff that's just my my opinion on
it
and so in some of your posts we've
started
to see more and more reference including
other people as well the va afghani you
know what can you tell us about this one
oh it's just a really old um
afghani like afghani one cut
um i think like we've
like i know i've talked to a couple
people that were going to um
dcu college like downtown richmond like
the very early 80s that were
smoking that same bug and same crew of
dudes that were kind of running it
around and growing it
so it's just really old um it's really
piney with eucalyptus pine um
sagey sandalwoody you know
very very funky but it's really really
potent you know
and very heavy and dense dense weed too
so it was a always a good grower um
the potency on it was like real top
notch man
it's real nice do you plan to braid with
it at all
oh yeah yeah man been doing it just uh
haven't really been talking about it yet
trying to make everything like a big
surprise for everybody man
i've probably already said too much but
when can we expect a grand unveiling
i don't even know man i reckon whenever
whenever it's done okay
okay shouldn't be too long
so in recent interviews uh we've brought
up the
the topic of the brothers of eternal
love and how
you know their stock is kind of similar
to the ssc
regarded you know extremely highly if
you had to choose between the two you
know
i know that they're not exactly apples
to apples so to speak because you know
like bowl didn't make packs of seeds but
if you had to metaphorically choose
between a pack of bowl and a pack of
sssc
and it could be either of either you
know what what would you pick
um it depends on what it does
you know but i i'd like to think i'd
i'd go with the brotherhood stuff you
know a little bit more
because a lot of like european stuff
revolved around
american stuff you know they got took
back over there
so i'd like to think like the bowl
and the sacred seeds you know and dojo
and those cats like i'd like to think
like there's a little more stout
you know a little more a little more
hardcore
but like ssc man like they won't
they didn't produce no slouch [ __ ]
either so
um that's a tough one but like certain
things
you know i would definitely be
you know looking at the seed club stuff
but
yeah if like if you you know had a gun
in my head made me pick one and i'd go
brotherhood [ __ ] nice okay
and so are there any clones out there
currently that you would love to work
with
like you know you know they're about but
you just haven't got for one reason or
another williams wonder man
really good williams wonder would be
nice
and i don't know that's probably
probably about it i've seen a few posts
of that popping up do you think it's
all legit or maybe there's a few people
who think they have it but they don't
have it
no i don't know i haven't uh
i haven't seen any or smelled or smoked
them in
long time so yeah
[ __ ] man ain't no telling i would
imagine like
you know that stuff was pretty damn good
so i would imagine like people kept
kept some clones rolling you know i'd
find it hard to believe that it
you know it's extinct extinct yeah okay
and so if you had to pick just one clone
that you felt had the most potential to
breed with what would it be
and i guess by that i mean it pairs well
with just like such a variety of
different males
you know he just consistently produces
good results you know what's your one
client
uh as far as like a male to to
to cross to or female yeah like a female
yeah just works well in
all the hybrids i don't know
man like i mean there's there's certain
ones it's like you can take it to the
bank and count on it you know
like producing a certain result and then
there's other ones that like
you could get like such a varied result
where you could
end up with 10 different other things to
work on
so if i was looking for like the old
faithful or if i was looking for
something to give me a multitude of
variety
you know yeah
um
[Music]
i don't know that's that's a really hard
question man
yeah all right well how about another
one that just came to mind
out of all the females you work with
what's your
what's your go-to female for when you
want to cross a male to
you know like we referenced it early you
know like you're going to cross a new
male to something in a project but
you've always got that one standby where
you know
how it reads you know what's predictable
so you can use it as like a calibration
reference almost
what female is that for you um
i can like local h is real good about
that
you know um there's a couple of them
that are
really good because like i know like if
it can dominate over
something from a particular cross then
you know that i'm i'm doing pretty
pretty damn good like that's my my goal
is to
you know have a male that's a little
more dominant you know
so uh but that local is pretty good
you know it can tell me a whole lot
about what what something's doing with
structure especially
um especially if i'm running down a
particular
set of genes you know it can tell me a
whole lot
yeah okay so another little personal
question i wanted to sneak in there
do you think it's detrimental at all to
have
a male in your flowering room from
flower
day one such that essentially you know
the the first pistols are that are
emerging on the females are going to be
pollinated
fairly shortly after that or as soon as
they emerge like do you think that's
detrimental at all just because the
common thing which you know i even say
to people when they ask me is
oh you know ideally you want to
pollinate the females around week three
week four
so you know probably introduce the male
into the room around about that time
which is obviously
counter to what i just mentioned earlier
what how do you feel about it all
of course you know different females are
going to have different
flowering times um
they all have their own
peak time i would say like to get
overall
saturation right now with your male
it's going to be the same thing i have
some males that are very fast
that are actually faster than the
females
so he's already dumping pollen
by the time that they're just getting
like tiny popcorn buds you know
that and me personally that would be
that would be too early
you know i mean if you're making beans
for yourself
like just [ __ ] rounds whatever but
like if you were doing it in a
production
type thing you know that wouldn't be
good you know you'd want them a little
further along
so you'd really have to know when did
your when does your mail start to
actually drop
drop pollen you know and then you can
kind of gauge that
um versus like the peak time on the
females that are going to go in
and then that wouldn't bring them in
because certain ones
um there was like a
certain sativa male in the past you
would have to put it in
almost a week ahead of all the females
you know um and then there's another one
that i can't put in the room until like
day 14 of bloom for the females
you know so there's some that go in on
the same day
you know so you got to really have it
timed out on how your boy is
um so to know like when you're going to
hit your
peak sack yeah peak saturation
okay interesting and and what do you
think is the peak saturation
from most plants in the sense that i've
heard pretty wildly varying
figures in terms of like the number of
seeds you can get off a plant
obviously it's got a lot to do with the
size of the plant but
i mean often people will talk about a
plant in a certain size
pot and that helps to give a little bit
of frame to the whole metric but
some people say you get 15 000 off a
plant where others will say for the same
size plant you'll only get 1.5 000.
what what is it um well one it's
not just how many there are it's the
quality
of the ones that are there um if you're
too
late going in you could end up with
thirty thousand but you know
twenty thousand are good you know um
if you're too early you know you might
end up with ten thousand
really really perfect ones and not the
first dud
um so there's there is like a balance
you know
but i think like if you hit if you hit
the plan at the right time i mean you
you can get a lot of them and have them
all all be good at the same time you
know if you're giving them the right
nutrition and
um trying to facilitate seed production
type type food you know
you can have some really nice seeds and
a whole whole lot of them
fifteen twenty thousands not that
you know it's not that unfathomable
to have on a plant yeah okay and what
would be your advice for helping to
supplement
the uh seeded plants nutrient demands
after it has been pollinated because it
seems as though
the nutrient requirements for a seeded
plant is probably about on par for a
flowering plant at least from what i've
seen
but at the same time you know it's it
seems as though you can certainly keep a
seeded plant very happy and i think
that's maybe a little bit of a
misconception people think that
seated plant will just look [ __ ] or
maybe like they use it to give credence
to the fact that their plant looks [ __ ]
yeah nah like um like you they should
look
look pretty good you know like on
when i when i make seeds like a lot of
the stuff it looks just
very similar to the room like when it's
unseated
you know like very very fat and
small calyxes because there's actually
seeds in it instead of
swelling um lots of resin lots of stink
you know everything's right on point
point with that
i've always been under the
thought of like i mean you're
reproducing
you know and um you know new life
is being created not only is it being
created but it's being created at like
you know 15 or 20 000 fold
that you would want to facilitate the
building the dna building blocks as much
as possible
you know so i think like the amino acids
and um heavy emphasis
not so much on the npk side but a lot of
other smaller things that go unnoticed
like
tend to tend to help facilitate the seed
seed making as well boron's a real big
one
and yeah you know and like i said you
know keeping a good steady diet or that
type of stuff you know
pretty moderate npk um seems to
seem to do the best
yeah okay awesome and so what would be
your advice to people who feel like
they've got a pretty solid grasp on
organics
that are really looking to take it to
the next level whether it be you know in
general maybe they're looking to
get a bit more out of their crop you
know like what's kind of your advice
maybe
in terms of resources to look up
products to look into things like that
you know like what's some of the more
advanced stuff that
you feel can help people take their game
to the next level
i really feel like the most simple
approach is always the best in that a
lot of it really falls into your
environment
and like you were saying earlier really
tuning
your plant knowing exactly how much it
wants to eat or not eat so
you know like you're saying like you got
a plant doesn't show any deficiencies at
all but you know had you fed it that
little more it would have
doubled in size what have you um vice
versa with the one that's not burning
but
you know it's being over fed so it
doesn't doesn't want to blow out
um so i think a lot of it has to do with
like one's tuning to a plant
and then also their environment you know
making sure the environment's real nice
temperature
humidity was um
light intensity is also a big one a lot
of people overkill their
their plants um
so you know if you can get like a little
cheap light meter
play around with that a little bit that
tends to help
um
[Music]
as far as like nutrition wise like uh
like i'm pretty sold on
the dragonfly stuff man you know
so i used to like make my own little
tees from scratch you know raw
amendments but
like the dragonfly's taking it up you
know
quite quite a substantial notch so
i'm real big on that um adding grow
stones and everything
to the soil um when you're not breaking
the root ball up and tilling it all
up you know i don't want to say like i'm
doing no-till but i mean essentially um
yeah yeah you know agree
but um i just remember i just remembered
how you were like
ain't no no-till going on here yeah yeah
yeah exactly bad
that was a really good accent too that's
funny as [ __ ]
well as it turns out we're down to like
our last few questions
so first one i've been asking everyone
over the past few months it's kind of
like died off a bit but it's i think
it's still a bit of a pertinent question
should you ask for permission so let's
give the most extreme example
um you know obviously given you've got a
good relationship with mass g
this would never actually happen but
let's just say you went to recreate a
batch of grim dog and for whatever
reason
he contacts you and says i'm really not
comfortable with you doing that
would that be enough for you to not do
it or you know like do you feel like
you need to respect someone's intentions
to the point where like it could
literally stop you from making something
like that or you know what i mean where
do you sit on that issue
well me personally like you know i have
a respect for people
and you know i was raised pretty good so
like me personally i'd be like yeah
without a doubt you got it at 86 at
that moment you know um i know a lot of
people don't
you know because like they don't their
circumstances are different than mine
you know
if the guy the guy who you know popped
the seed that found the clone is also
the same dude that gave me the clone
the whole reason i got it and you know
i'm gonna respect that
you know but a lot of these guys you
know they
they scored their clan off of a forum
from a guys guys
cousins uncles from maui and
oregon's finest [ __ ]
underground brotherhood crazy [ __ ] you
know
he doesn't know him he's never met him
you know he probably just doesn't give a
[ __ ] you know
so you know that guy you know it's
different than me
so you say with me you know i've
always got a you know a line of respect
for for people you know
good game plan alrighty so next little
question i think you'll
be able to help me resolve is after
discussing it with a few people the
consensus seems to be
that the joshie d o g
is the ghost og but it's not the tk
but people seem to be suggesting that
it's
probably an s1 of the tk
how does that all sound to you in terms
of like correctness so to speak
shut up man like i
always thought that they were all the
same but yeah
okay i mean um
yeah maybe maybe they are um
because like i've never been able to
like
uh so like if let's say like josh d
comes up and he's like hey buddy here's
this this uh
og kush you know i want you to get to
grow it
and i'm like okay and if he told me like
yeah
this like you know we had a buddy that
held onto the clone and called him ghost
and
you know blah blah they run through the
story and it
tells me like yeah it's the same clones
just a different name
it would be like skunk va chem dog right
it's really it's chem dog right
but you know there's something else
attached to it but you know
you could say it's like yeah it's the
same clan now if he gave that to me
and then say like cornbread's like hey
buddy
here's my tk con and grow it now if i
can grow them side by side
then maybe i could i could answer that
better
but i've never had that that happen
so um and like it's weird too because
like
you know people's like grow style and
stuff like you know you can smoke
something it tastes completely different
than the other
guy they're growing like the same [ __ ]
but you know they have a little bit
different
way of doing it you know sometimes
things express a little bit differently
so that's always real real hard
yeah totally i think it's actually quite
dramatic the differences from person to
person where
it's at the point where even if you're
running all the same strains as say you
may like you're gonna kind of have your
own
weed in a way like you know like it's
you got your own little fingerprint of
growing almost
yeah man yeah exactly
alrighty so one question i wanted to ask
you
was do you have like a cut of northern
lights
or like something akin to that that you
use or you're just never interested like
it's never really come up when we've
been chatting
yeah i do but you know like uh
northern lights is like one of them
things um
like if somebody like offers it to me
right like i'm always real leery of it
it's like sour diesel or something you
know
it's like ah you know i don't know man
you know yeah um but yeah
yeah and like that's that's another
little another little project that's
going on at the same time
he said all all in due time buddy
sneaky very sneaky all righty
lucky last question oh sorry going
i was fun all right
so yeah lucky last question for today at
least is
would you and should other people use
cindy 99
as a male more so than a female in any
breeding projects they're looking to do
and the reason why i think of that is
because all the females are consistently
phenomenal
and you know the males are basically
just male versions of the females
and so there's really like no guesswork
in it you know it seems like um
it seems like yeah like you're just
going to have a killer mail no matter
what
so with that in mind would you not want
to use
it as a male in the cross because taking
the guesswork out of finding a good male
um no i mean it's it's a pretty good
place to start
and like um anything that's been inbred
you know heavily that still produces
like really killer female offspring
um and like you know fairly consistent
you know that's that's gonna help you a
lot so
like skunk one you know that was like
bread to like f4
you know that was that was a great one
to use you know that's why it was like a
pretty good backbone
some of the northern lights that were
worked same way
um it gave you a pretty predictable
outcome in that f1 generation you know
and then the rest of it was kind of
working up to you
you know either philly would breed it or
back cross it or whatever you were going
to do
yeah i mean my experience with the one
that
i had selected was um it wasn't taking
anything away
from the from the mother in the
offspring you know
it was just kind of adding adding some
good some good notes to it you know
so that that was nice it wasn't like
overly dominating
which to me is like kind of important
like if you're making like
f1 because you know the mother's like
it's got so many good qualities that you
really want to retain
you could go that route and just kind of
enhance it a little bit you know it's
going to change some
of course but you you retain a lot of
those high notes from the mom
so um that was a you know pretty good
thing
okay i thought of a actually as a sneaky
last question for you hopefully this one
will make you laugh
we got we got the newest hype straight
on the scene in my opinion
and it's somewhat related to you so
you're gonna have to have an opinion on
it
gmo oh yeah it's the chem d and the
cooks
yeah is it how do you feel you feel like
betrayed in a way
no no um i have so like my buddy
he uh he stays up in oregon he's
uh got it held on to my chem d cup for
me for like
freaking ever he uh he made a forum cut
cookies
uh and pollinated it with the chem d
like a hot minute back
and um they're nowhere like they're not
the same
type um offspring because that gmo is
like
kind of kind of garlicky funky you know
um his like turned out like it was
really good it was like one of the times
where like it was a cookie hybrid and i
was like oh that was actually pretty
pretty damn good man and um
actually i liked it and like i see
collective and skunk you know they did
the
the kim scout you know that one's pretty
good too so like they go
they go pretty pretty good together man
[Music]
that's it that's it so when can we
expect the uh the gmo
cube project to be done
that's somebody else to do right there
all righty well um any comments shout
outs anything he wanted to make
oh just thanks for uh thanks for having
me on again and um
yeah i mean if i get to doing shout outs
this is too many people man
anybody i know okay
yeah let's lock it all into everybody
and
you know a little patience down south
and um
dragonfly earth medicine and
yeah and uh come by to see me at uh
emerald cup i think it's uh boost 92
and it's gonna be it so you have to come
say hey to me and
scott va and get some raws and get these
or just come by and
shoot the [ __ ] whatever's clever come on
through
there we have again part two done
hope you enjoyed it like i did
a big big thank you to 420 australia ogs
and our patreon sponsors
[Music]
stay tuned for more content soon and be
sure to check out
duke and skunk's booth the emerald cup
i'll see you there
la la la la
[Music]
lalalala
you