I just wanted to make a quick
announcement guys first of all some good
news
we're gonna have some changes coming to
the show and it's going to basically
result in more content so I hope
everyone's excited for more episodes the
bad news however is that SoundCloud is
likely closing down in four weeks or so
most people do listen to our show
through SoundCloud however I've begun
the process of uploading all of the
content onto YouTube so if you could all
remember to go over and subscribe to our
YouTube channel you can stay up to date
I'll put a link in the description and
you won't risk missing out on any of the
new content hello and welcome to the
next episode of the podcast the cannabis
podcast for budding enthusiasts this
episode as always was brought to you by
420 Australia your premiere clothing and
apparel store as well as organic
gardening solutions your one-stop shop
for organic gardening this episode we're
thankful to have mr. Bob Hemphill on the
show to talk about coastal seeds strain
preservation and model have you enjoyed
its get into it alrighty so big welcome
and thank you to a true veteran of the
breeding scene Bob Hemphill of coastal
seeds it's good to be here the question
I like to start off every interview with
is what was your first experience with
cannabis it was summer between ninth and
10th grade and a friend of mine from
neighborhood uh Ron scored some Mexican
we eat and you had this little homemade
pipe and we smoked one day after school
at a party and then we smoked like you
know two or three days later and after
that second time we smoked I know you
know I had a big love for cannabis cuz
the way it just relaxed me um where I
grew up in Northern Virginia was
high-stress area you know very
competitive and um you know just to be
able to relax and connect back to nature
type of vibe is you know how I always
wanted to live and
it was just just it was awesome and so
what with Australians kind of floating
around back then well I could only get
Mexican and Jamaican and now
occasionally Asian or African brick
weeds alone and you know they were
smashed and mostly sativa and that's
where we got our first you know seeds to
grow we just you know pulled them out of
some of the first sex we ever smoked and
um we just planted the seeds and I had
you know two really hard Hard Knocks
years of you know like the first year
just left the plants in too much shakes
I know I had to hide them and I put them
in so much shade they ended up just
falling over and dying the second year I
grill um had a plant growing and I had a
flowering and I literally brought it
inside because of a frost warning and
stuck it under 24 hours old I cuz I
didn't know as a twelve and twelve life
cycle that made it flower at the time
and you know really hard knocks yeah and
so during that time were there any
things around like you know like the
counter Bible or was just predating that
and I mean I guess it goes without
saying you didn't have kind of any
family members you could refer to
because that's something I found is a
bit of a commonality between a lot of
people we talk to a lot of people seem
to have at least one family member who's
kind of pushing them along but you sound
like he didn't know I had a lot of older
brothers and sisters but none of them
grew or really hooked me up with
cannabis um it was actually the other
way around even from a young age I was
always giving my older brothers and
sisters cannabis because after that
second time of smoking it I knew I
wanted it around me all the time and you
know us you know I was hustling it and
trying to grow it from the start you
know just so I could get a free sack and
like I said the first two years I tried
to grow it was hard knocks but that
third year I left it out and it was
Mexican sativa and
and it was amazing you know it was total
citrus amazing high and then um
at that time you know Grateful Dead
would come around um that was when I was
a senior in high school and that's when
I started going to the Grateful Dead
shows and actually people were burning
kind but out from California and that's
less the first kind but I got was you
know going to a Grateful Dead show and
then the first time actually got my
hands on some kind blood seeds was 1995
right after I harvested data first
Mexican weed that fall at my fish over
New Year show I scored some kind but
from Humboldt and I got dank seeds and
that you know kind of odd seeds and I
grow them and [ __ ] was amazing you know
and I you know I bred those
unfortunately crossbred them to a
Southern Virginia string instead of
breeding them brother to sister and
keeping that line pure because I was
really quality weed and so was that
outdoors and if if it was outdoors did
that just signal in your mind that
genetics was the key to you or what what
did what did it signal to you at that
point like you know you had kind of this
awakening with cannabis of what was
possible what was the first thing you
were thinking like [ __ ] I need to start
be doing this indoors with good genetics
or like you know like maybe something
different but what were you thinking
well you know I was always getting the
High Times magazines and hearing about
sensi seeds and in Nevel and all that
[ __ ] and you know the amazing strands
they had and you know uh you know I knew
could be bud was out there just you know
being in Northern Virginia as far a few
between especially for young kids you
know when you're in high school you're
low on the totem pole so we just pretty
much had to make the good but you know
and you know the first time I smoked
some good Northern Lights was
Philadelphia spectrum at a Grateful Dead
show and
it was in the fall of 94 right before
they came and played a the Capitol
Center and smoking that indoor good
Northern Lights it was actually from
this dude that I knew from Virginia but
seeing them at a Grateful Dead show he
kind of opened up more and it was just
amazing and you know at that same time
you know everyone was on a quest to get
the best genetics and I had a friend of
mine who went to Amsterdam and early 95
and he bought packs of everything he'd
get his hands on like the most you know
everything he could have floored he
actually got money from another friend
of ours too and those guys you know that
about the the four way pack and you know
when we popped it that far away it was
you know took stuff over and I mean
being with those guys they had mentors
unlike me they who I taught him how to
grow inside and and run [ __ ] you know
like not just in a closet like one a
whole basement or a whole crow and I was
lucky to get with those guys and you
know at the 4way pretty much changed it
was almost like we we had that and it
was like there wasn't much better at the
time the only things I remember better
was a no hash plant cross and that [ __ ]
was amazing
and then an old hash plant nlg 13 cross
and that that cross used to come around
to Northern Virginia when it was called
to kill and that was the best weed I've
ever smoked to this day I remember
telling the guys hey we'll trade this
for white clone for that kill clone they
straight laughed in my face you know
they just didn't think it was even a
fair trade at all where the far away was
a lot of people consider it the best
we'd ever smoked in our ice this kill
was that much better and to this day the
only thing I can you know reminds me I
was like you know chem dog and it was
very loud and just very crystally and
amazingly and so in God's to the full
way
do you think that that pack was a lucky
pack or like this was just at a time
where since he was so good that every
pack potentially had a clone that good
in it well since he was really good in
the early 90s because I remember anyone
that got a pack if they you know found
some good [ __ ] maybe they didn't keep
the clones cuz it was hard at that time
to keep clones but everyone that was
getting stuff stuff was pretty good but
I really think that four way was you
know very special because other crews in
Northern Virginia told me they bought
several packs and never found anything
to play thing near as close this thing
wasn't very skunky you know pretty stony
and I'm very just loves flavor and so
the 4-ways got some interesting genetics
in it you know specifically the Pocky
and the Indian you know we see Pocky a
little more common than Indian but you
know you rarely see Indian at all you
just mentioned its skunky you know do
those other genetics really influence it
too much like do you think that I know
you so you mentioned it's very skunky do
you'd notice any Indian influence or do
you think maybe that's what makes it
more skunky than the others so to speak
like some weird interplay between the
two you know it's a really complex
strain some people you know describe it
as like a buttery smell when you're
breaking it up and then like a starburst
smell and just kind of sweet but from
like ten feet away if you have a bag in
your pocket it just reeks like skunk you
know like if he brought it into a
two-story house the people in the second
storey house would say damn this show
what the [ __ ] who killed skunk type of
[ __ ] I remember one time I have long
dreadlocks and I was you know waiting in
line in a gas station and the guy kept
asking everyone in line who hid the
skunk and I literally had to bite my lip
just to not laugh and I finally you know
got to the Castro Chinese damn he's like
someone really hit a skunk out there and
I I can't believe the guy never thought
that this dread head has a [ __ ] sack
Oh Eden's sock in pocket but he really
thought someone had hit a skunk
nice nice and so just in terms of the
whole timeline of things did the
roadkill skunk exist at this time or was
this before or after it had come onto
the scene well I remember seeing skunk
number one a few times and you know 94
95 96 it was always a more citrus town
never us allowed skunk you know and you
know only skunk number one clones I know
of people that save just you know the
Las Vegas lemon skunk and then yeah UK
cheese and the other of them smell like
skunk either I'm not saying there wasn't
skunk peanuts and skunk number one I'm
just saying I personally never saw them
yeah so you have the opinion that the
red kills gun was possibly an Afghani
which is what we've heard frequently on
the show you know every time I smell
something skunky it was yeah
a strong indica cross for sure and so
one of the other cuts you hang on to and
I see regular on your feet is the black
Domino is this one that is kind of
equally as good as the four-way or do
you think maybe it's almost as good but
not quite as good but you know like if
anything's within the ballpark of the
four-way then you know it's like it's
probably gonna be elite nonetheless um
you know to be honest with you about the
four-way the only reason I'm keeping it
alive is because of a special connection
with it and what I hope it can produce
and its offspring and that's what I'm
seeing and over the years it's always
been a good producer for me but um the
black domina cuts I have our old Scentsy
stock and they're much stronger than the
for white potency wise and you know I I
prefer them and you know I'm always
looking for any block down I'm gonna cut
I can get I have one that's just 1995
sensi seeds selection I got from ethnic
the nature farmer and I got another one
up in southern Humboldt at a harvest
healing harvest farmers market held by
that guys a whole demo cup and
it was actually their vending booth and
I walked by with a friend and we'd seen
that they had black domina for sale
and you know I'm like oh I want to pluck
domina he's like well you know get to
the end of the line and I turn around
and the lines like you know fifty feet
long
you know go way down to the line and you
know it's fun you know we're talking
about weed the whole time um and you'll
get to the end of the line and he tells
me they're sold out and you know I'm
like a little you know heartbroken and
my friend he's a you know a real smooth
talker he's like you know can you can
you go look and the guy goes and looks
and he's like oh my god there's one last
one and you know we just start giving
each other high-fives and [ __ ]
because I was told the only thing I was
told about it before I got in line is it
sold ciências seed stock and you know if
it's kept around in Humboldt County and
it sold since he seed stock it's you
know it's a winner and um yeah both of
them have a very narcotic stone which
I'd prefer and above because I like
something though relax man calm me down
and it's a mix of Pacific Northwest hash
plant Northern Light Ortega and Afghani
number one which is originally known as
m10 the land race Afghani ax um from the
super sativa seed Club so what miles do
you think partner well with it like you
mentioned it's really not Kartik so do
you think that for example crossing it
to a sativa would kind of take away from
that you want to keep it kind of in that
indica dominant realm or not necessarily
well III don't have any but I've always
heard that since he seeds produced some
fire a really good blackjack like
dominant Jack here crosses and then I
personally you know got my hands on mom
Yemen I really was excited to cross him
to the Northern Lights number one male
just to keep that old-school North
narcotic indica Janecka live in the gene
pool cuz it's you know that's my most
sought-after stuff and it seems like no
one's really offering that and luckily
keg you wanna
and the open pollination in a one pure
line that I had never left the west
coast that it he had gotten from his
friend classic seeds and I was able to
select a male out of that first I popped
like 40 and then I realized how good
they were and I thought 95 and selected
the best man out of all those I really
went for the side of the gene pool and
then no one that was like a spray paint
you know kind of a chemical and that was
only a I only solved in about 20 percent
of the gene pool the other 80 percent
was your more classic fruity indica you
know very kind of smell and you know I
had some good friends up and we smoked
on my chem dogs and on my oh jeez and
naturally said they preferred the
turpentine spray paint and Alfie nosed
over everything and I you know that's
the type of nail I was going after you
know tried to match the phenotype okay
and so do you notice any of those NL
characteristics in the chem dog when
youse were smoking that or is it more of
it was just like a preference over well
you know as far as chem dog I always
thought chem dog went back to Northern
Lights um but you know recently now that
I'm really got my hands on some really
good classic cache plant cuts I think
it's maybe a combination of the two um
but that's just my guess you know just
from how I saw we progress you know all
the best [ __ ] was Northern Lights
crosses and then you know come dog
anoche came on the scene and no one know
what they were so you know I um there's
some ask Andy to the next that were
similar to that or the same exact
genetics okay
and so just out of curiosity when you
mentioned that keg you had done the open
pollination with the no.1 had he made
any comment about how the plants that
you grew out like you know was there any
little slight differences between that
generation
the previous or do you think that they
were pretty much identical you know like
I guess I'm wondering even throughout in
pollination techniques do you think you
do get a little bit of change over time
or not really so from what I've learned
from him if you use as many males as
many females don't bottleneck the
genetics that you can keep everything in
see Flom that's how he's always done and
stuff his whole life he never really
kept clones until you know about ten
years ago they always just put stuff in
the seed so they could grow it again you
know like you know I wish I had known
that in early 90s I have a bunch of
amazing lines now so in terms of the end
product of the Northern Lights you go
out have you seen yourself or being
given any NL stock or buds from you know
any modern breeders that resembled that
or was it just totally different well to
be honest with you I feel like most of
Northern Lights genetics disappeared I
was given some of sensi stock recently
to grow when I was growing those ones
from Katie one and I got some Bodhi
seeds I know and grew them at the same
time and I was very thankful to find
that kgs no.1 was exactly what I
remembered from a kid and it was so much
better than sensi seeds it was
ridiculous and what I grew from buddy
was the nl5 British Columbia sea cloth
open pollination and a few other
different crosses that my friend Kelly
death vest gave me and they were really
good but none of them had that narcotic
turpentine spray paint Venus that I was
really looking for that uh I was very
excited to find and I don't want um
because you know we were hoping to use
it and as exactly what I was looking for
so how do you think Northern Lights v
became this massive poster child for the
cannabis community if it sounds like
Northern Lights one was way better when
I grew the Northern Lights one versus
that British Columbia sea club from
Bodhi day his nl5 had way better bag
appeal we're talking way better it had a
more round nug it actually had a more
crystals on the outside of the note but
the effect of the nl1 is exactly what I
was looking for so with that being said
about the betta bag appeal on the nl5 do
you think that that kind of highlights
the issue of you know the compromise of
quality traits within the plant versus
bag appeal over the years yes when I
moved to Northern California in 97 there
was so much diversity in the wheat grown
in Humboldt Mendo and Trinity counties
it was amazing and then right about 2000
everyone that had to have purple or it
became a problem to sell your wheat and
then a few years after that it was you
had to have OG and if you didn't have OG
the buyers didn't even want to look at
it and at that point you know a lot of
people just dropped their old lines and
everyone was growing oh gee or purple
and there are amazing types of weed but
a lot of genetics were lost and it's a
shame and so do you think that people
drop stuff out of their head stash
rotation so to speak I guess because
what I'm trying to say is I thought that
there was always strains where people
always viewed them as like this isn't
something I can sell like grow for sale
to the masses because like maybe it's
hard to grow or it doesn't yield well or
bla bla bla do you think strains that
even fit into that category were drops
because I guess my initial instinct is
thinking like surely some people kept
like the really good ones even if they
just figured like I just grow it for
personal to be honest with you most
people don't keep that good of a mother
room or don't keep strains for long
that's the reason I you know I've got
the nickname the librarian mom it's
mostly because I just keep the strains
for all my homies and I've been doing
this forever because just like when I
was like
I just wanted to have a good weed around
me once I have it around me I just want
to keep it there and I just take care of
these plants and it's very dedicated to
it and you know there are other people
that's how I find these jewels and
trading you know when I got on Instagram
it really helped me gain access to a lot
of genetics you know meeting other
people that kept strains like that you
know but I kept a lot of strengths for
my friends and a lot of times even when
they were just running one strand they'd
come back and get the copy from me after
a year to just cuz I kept a healthier
copy mainly because I never compromised
them never you know there was times
where me and Hannibal literally had a
bedroom in her master bedroom not even
in the closet just in the corner just
because that's you know the kind of
commitment I have and I think she has it
just as hard as me and she's actually
encouraged me to keep some of the
strains around forever that we
necessarily don't like to smoke on like
the train wreck is a perfect example of
that
when I first you know got the strain in
99 you know it was amazing but that
terpene will get to you after a while
I'm kind of cut and chuck about it you
being train rat poison and so on the
idea of you know the whole librarian
thing what are some of the more
lesser-known cuts you keep in your stash
that you think would be well received by
the public if they were more well known
black domina you know the public is you
know different than me I'm a real
serious indica lover you know and
anything that the public really likes I
generally try to have access to but I
feel like a lot of the strong calming
and because most people have kind of
lost stuff like the Black Diamond odd
and Northern Alliance number one a lot
of people don't have the real chem dog D
which is absolutely hands-down favorite
and you know there's not many people out
there you know producing those you know
it costly people's out there and with
Incredibles and they got the real deal
that's gonna be amazing for the weed out
in Colorado yeah so this idea of the
fake chem Dodie I've heard of this
before I do you think that there's just
like a bunch of s ones floating around
or you moreso referring to the Decius
well there's a lot of people with the
sister that the think it's the D and
then there's tons of fakes out in
California if you just go to any club
and you you got you you you can get any
elite they're all on the menus that
these clubs out here but ninety nine out
of a hundred times they're gonna be fake
as can be and you know there's a million
clubs out here selling chem dough and
there's a million fake breeders out
there breeding with chem dog and people
never seen it because like I said it's
kind of limited and there's only a few
people are really grown commercial you
know and I'm mostly grown for head you
know I just covered on myself yeah okay
and so if we just jump back to that idea
of you maintaining the client's and your
friends would come back and grab them
from you because you know they couldn't
keep it as good as you that got me
thinking how what's the shortest amount
of time you've ever seen for a clone to
go bad like have you seen a clone turned
crap in say like a year because or does
it take like longer than that even if
it's really poorly maintained well you
know our selected females out of you
know seed hunting and you know hunting
and some of those are amazing from seed
or the first clone and they deteriorate
fast you know and I couldn't tell you
why and then some of these are old you
know really good clones I have you know
they're very old and they have been you
know dgeren generated as much as other
clones that are younger because like I'd
say for example far away from ninety
five has degenerated more than the chem
duck ninety-one and I have the Romulan
1969 Ron one show cut and you know that
thing hasn't degenerated too much at all
it's a you know it'll
it's a picky little girl's gonna pre
flower but considering she's going on 50
years here in a year to UM just [ __ ]
amazing you know and then you know the
train wreck is deteriorating on me
pretty hard in these last few years no
matter how healthy I keep it and I think
it's just genetic just like people you
know that's you know people age faster
than other people and just a roll of the
dice okay
and so just while we're on the topic do
you think that Romulan Joe's cutting of
Romulan is the oldest cut in existence
or do you think maybe someone's hanging
onto something colder the oldest thing I
know of I'm not saying it is the oldest
by any means but I've heard rumors that
I might be even older than 69 cuz pagan
no alarms guy was working on the farm
and Romulan Joe pretty much drop it off
with his boss kind of deal in 1969 and
he held it on to it all that time and on
his since passed away and so what do you
think is the back story behind it
because what I heard was that either Joe
or someone he knew was in the Korean War
and they brought back some land rice and
it was just like you know selectively
bred to be squat and more indica though
it was a sativa
that could be total [ __ ] but love to
you what you think you know it's a squat
little undercooked plant you know I you
know it'll dent your head man you know
it's just [ __ ] it'll [ __ ] you up
that's some strong [ __ ] and you know I
would brother scrum produce some really
excellent stuff with it you know um
space clean so yeah yeah the Killer
Queen yep I'm gonna grow that out soon
yeah I think the killer queen is on the
airborne g13 yeah yeah yeah true true
true sorry what I was thinking was um it
was it was Vic hi who made space Queen
yeah yeah yeah for sure
I love the The Killer Queen cutter I
have it's amazing and
I'm stoked I just declared the airborne
g13 so how would you describe that
that's actually probably one of the few
things I wasn't able to smoke out of
Tony's collection I just don't think he
had me around yeah how would you
describe it because he said to me he
reckons it's g13 NL 2 or something you
know that's what the old forum people
saying you know I'm gonna believe them
and I've not got a chance to flour it
out yet but I'm excited very excited I
will have it ready you know in a few
months here so ok it's just got the cut
all healthy and cleaned up and you know
it takes a few months because I don't
like the flower things right awake so
I'll get a bad impression generally oh
really it's like you want to kind of do
a little bit of revitalizing yourself
before you get in there yeah because I
have so many our clones and stuff I
don't have that many times to just run
them all new ones unless you know I just
want to have them really healthy so I
don't get a bad impression and giving
the Delta clone its fair chance you know
yeah ok and so let's get to that
revitalizing of clones because this is
something you're very known for and I
think the other kind of guy in the scene
is well known for this is Kevin Joe jury
and he often talks about putting the
plant out in the Sun to veg you know
like not letting it flower cuz obviously
you don't have a clone anymore what do
you think about this and how important
is it to have that Suns role in
revitalizing the clone it's huge it's
definitely huge but the most important
thing is to have a good mother room I'm
talking like everything most people out
here just put into a you know the flower
room you know most people kind of keep
their mom's shitty and that's what I
think deteriorates um you want a good
not a light on them you want good
ventilation you want good humidity
levels you need a lot of right light to
keep those old clones on edging you
don't I'm under some weak light you want
some serious light over top of them and
you know some you're gonna notice they
like to be off to the side a little bit
more but
a majority that all clones need a lot of
light a lot of food a lot of foliar
feeding I think helps you know
regenerate these old clones because a
lot of times they have weak root systems
you know and it's hard for those old
clothes to root and when they just
barely root and they pop out these weak
root systems that they're never gonna
regenerate without a foliar feeding and
I folio speed coconut a low on calcium
25 a lot of compost tea earthworm stuff
fresh extractions and just alternate
between all those things to get all the
nutrients in there and I think that's
crucial is the foliar feed Amin and then
I think that helps them you know get the
nutrient dense and then your next round
of cuttings will be much healthier okay
and so we often hear about specifically
aloe and kelp having a lot of really
beneficial hormones in them I mean more
specifically aloe has the salicylic acid
which stimulates the plants immune
system which in turn has a big effect on
kind of the whole rejuvenation process
how long do you feel you need to be
doing this before it's gonna work
because I remember I was talking to
skunk VI about it and I was like yeah
man you need to start using some alloy
to help rejuvenate it and he was like
awesome I'm gonna start doing that but
then the conversation was kind of like
well how long do I have to use it the
firmest not to say effects and things
like that so how long do you think it
would take through treating him I'm
really good giving her all these kind of
folio fades and all the the good things
when would you expect to start to see
some positive improvements on a
sad-looking clone so to speak every
clone is different sometimes it'll snap
right around after first few foliar
feeding sometimes it'll take a month or
two but you gotta be consistent with
putting those products and I I didn't
mentioned the kelp and the kelp is huge
and um dragonfly natural medicines
natural mystic is huge getting that
sauce in there and just uh you know
alternating it up so that you did
everything in there is I think really
important
so if we were to just jump back to how
you were talking about keeping a mother
room really healthy that brought up this
idea in my head of what should you do
should you make your mother room a
priority such that you say alright I'm
gonna have a smaller mother room or for
example less plants in there and I'll
try to cater to them better and then
it's you know like that trade-off it's
like alright well I won't be able to
keep as many clones but I'll try to keep
the ones I do keep better health do you
think that's kind of a philosophy you
would advocate or do you think yes yep
a hundred percent if you cram too many
of them in there and you know you start
making your favorite ones a special and
suffer just for a random clones you're
shooting yourself in the foot and to be
honest with you keeping mothers like
this and all these different clones is
not financially benefit at all you know
you know people making money or the
people or mono crop in the newest latest
flavor so you know you really just keep
as many as you can keep healthy and you
know that's why I'm pretty ruthless on
them I'll call them if I don't like them
I don't keep everything I just try to
keep the rare things and everything else
I want to smoke and a few close friends
around me
want to smoke but you know I do have
about 80 strains that are certified in
my MA I got a bunch of the testing -
okay and so that raises a bit of a
peripheral idea I've had on my mind for
a while now you mentioned the idea if
the people making the money the ones
montemagno cropping I've said this for a
long time I've in fact almost come up
with my own analogy saying at the end of
a harvest you've got kind of two results
you can have one somebod you can like
maybe sell it for some money or you can
have new clones because you've grown out
seeds and you've kind of seen or hunted
them and you sacrifice that mono crop
yield to kind of find your new elite
clone so to speak with that in mind how
should people be rewarded for finding
seeds you know a lot of people criticize
people who want to charge money for
clones but at the same time it's kind of
like if I spent a whole cycle running
seeds and at the end of it I find one
elite client
and in that same time period you do a
mono crop and make $30,000 is it kind of
not analogous like isn't that clone I
found kind of not you know what I mean
like I've traded the potential 30,000 or
you know whatever the money value of the
crop was to find that Klein you know
what I mean so how do people get
rewarded for that it's given that people
don't seem to like the idea of you know
people charging lots of money for clones
well you know in my book you know anyone
that's you know hunting is highly
respected and anybody that you know it's
putting in work to help progress you
know rather than just ride coattails
you know rewarded or not you know even
if they don't find that amazing you know
you know putting in a work and help them
progress it and save old stuff is you
know should be rewarded you know um you
know like you said you know some of
these clones you know are worth a lot of
money I personally never sell them no
matter how much money someone comes at
me with and I've turned down some
ridiculous amounts but you know I'll pay
money to buy him you know I think I mean
- I'll pay money to get them into my
hands you know but at that point we'll
never sell them again I'll just give
them out to friends and trade once it's
trade yeah ok so that calm is kind of
like suggests like we need to value
these community members who are you know
really doing that feeder hunting for us
and I wouldn't say you know like give
thanks because I mean they produce have
a bit more than that but yeah maybe do
you feel that's an issue do you feel the
people who are doing the hard yards in
the industry to get the credit you know
like I said they're doing my book and
you know I think we should keep it that
way you know keep it old-school and
mostly only deal with people that are
near school is you know you're trying to
get into this game now because it's
legal in America and make a bunch of
money because you see dollar signs and
you think it's fun and exciting I don't
really want to deal with you I you know
I want to deal with the people that have
been risking their lives but in work
their whole [ __ ] life and so it's
kind of a bit of a final question on the
bigger falling off over time thing in
relation to plants you mentioned the
different genetics fall off at different
rates however
do you find that there's a commonality
between clones losing vigor in that they
tend to lose certain traits first you
know I've commonly heard that flavor
falls off but I'm sorry flavor falls off
first you know do you find that's true
or do you find some strains no like
maybe the vigor falls off but the
flavors still there or something like
that no I agree with that the flavor and
the smell are the first things to
disappear and you know they'll still get
you high but they don't taste as magical
as they did you know a lot of these
strengths I have from the nineties so
with that being said do you think you
know so the the poster child the camp 91
the you know kind of not to give it a
bad name because it's still my favorite
word but like you know it's deteriorated
over the years a lot of people say that
you people say the potency is still the
same though but wouldn't logic suggests
that the potency is reduced because we
know that you know the more terpenes
there are the more synergistic that is
with the high and for me at least them
the more Turkey is the the more potent
it is to a certain extent so in that
regard has a not lost a bit of potency
well on my opinion with these old clones
um to make them knock them out of the
ballpark to get them you know to their
old-school vigor and best it's not gonna
happen every round even with a healthy
clone but I feel like you know sometimes
I can knock those old clones out where
they're better than anything new so it's
you know it just is not as easy and
that's not it you can't do it over every
round but it you know sometimes I'll
turn out just as good as ever
okay so I kind of jumped back a bit in
time now when did you first decide you
wanted to start breeding um when I first
got those kind bud seeds at that fish
New Year's Eve I was turning from 94 to
95 and I wanted to have more kind but
seeds you know I was you know I never
had a lot of money and getting a bunch
of packs from Amsterdam less you know it
just it seemed like too much and to
actually get seeds from a sack you know
that I buy I own a lot you know was a
lot easier and I I just wanted to keep
those around
and unfortunately I didn't keep on PR
across them onto a strain from southern
Virginia and you know occur that's the
next year and those work great but if I
would have you know kept that lime chair
it would have been something special it
was really good
stony purple indica you know nice
Afghani and so when did you make the
transition to indoors when I gotten
mentored by a couple friends that are
the guys that actually popped that
Fairfax four-way seat there were really
good friends of mine and they had a
house that you know and I learned how to
do it like that you know and you know
luckily always taught right from the
start you know as far as when to take it
inside because my outdoor [ __ ] was
ridiculous or obnoxiously it was suck to
do all that inside with all that risk
and power bill and stuff back east yeah
and so just as a bit of trivia one what
do you think was kind of the silliest
thing you guys were doing back there
indoors that you thought was like gonna
make the plant better but maybe in
retrospect you're like are we thinking
to be honest with you
those guys were taught by some you know
people that neither [ __ ] the only thing
I was able to bring to the game with
them was the use of back on us and Linc
help to help make the weed taste better
and that's kind of reason they brought
me in is because they tasted that mom
seeds that I'd gotten from that fish
show and they tasted the crosses those
two years in a row I've just grown that
[ __ ] outside like in Northern Virginia
like we're talking in clover dales and
you know that's the thing in the highway
where they looped you loop because no
one really goes into that inner median
or along its railroad tracks and some
some briar bushes and [ __ ] because I
didn't grow up in the country it was
more like inner city you could get to
the the capital in 20 minutes you know
Washington DC yeah okay and so as time
went by when was the first time the chem
dog came to you in person
it was Phish tour
and it was in fall tour and we went to
mass choose this
I forgot the University and you know
some of the kids that I met on tour were
really excited like hey when we get the
you know mass we're gonna bake em talk
you know man good would get kim dogyun
so i can you know it was they just kept
talking about it and [ __ ] building up
and it was [ __ ] they lived off to it
is [ __ ] good a sweet yeah that was a
96 the fall of 96 that tour I did that
now selling grilled cheese sandwiches
and I counted the money my friend made
almond Allegan buttered bread and I'm
also sold you know any way I could get
the whole time you know just to get from
show to show and we get to the next show
we just have enough money to buy grilled
cheese sandwiches you know and I'm
talking we could get the butter we could
get the cheese and we could get the
bread and we used to turn that it in to
enough money in the parking lot to good
tickets sack of weed and hotel and gas
money to the next show in just enough
money to buy curled cheese again that's
awesome
so that whole time we kind of thinking
to yourself I need to get these cans of
genetics for when I want to breed with
it
Oh to be honest with you man I never
even thought of that
but me and chem dog had a good friend
mutual friend between us and that it was
a true hustler and he was smart enough
to keep our crew separate because of
that way he could get the Kim dog from
Kim dog and you could get the for away
from us haha and he did that and he did
that successfully and it's a you know
fine cuz I'm we were at a lot of shows I
actually think Hannibal has a Chilam
from him from like 90 96 or 97 for my
first show I need to get a picture of
that to him
you see yeah why cuz but it looks like
Danica like is all work ok nice and is
this guy fit into the history anywhere
is we just kind of a personal friend
doesn't fit into any other of the story
at all
he's somebody that I never mentioned his
name but he's a huge you know respected
guy friend of chem dogs and he's the guy
that got then ninety-one and stuffed one
I um who bred the dog walker og out in
Oregon
he's another Virginia guy he actually
told me uh you know the four ways what
inspired him to start growing and you
know that's an honor no that's cool to
hear a lot of people claim that you know
that was the best weed they've ever
smoked huh
but boy yes you degenerated haha so
scrolling through some of your earlier
posts on instagrams we see things like
the ominous itís wrong is that the pune
bada cookies how do you say yes yeah
peanut butter so Hawaiian heroin strain
and keg you've got those seeds from a
friend of his and this is before I was
in coastal seats and he gave them to
Bollywood BAM Bollywood BAM he made that
cross and that peanut butters um really
stabilized the cookies and there's some
fire to be found in that and I think we
just sold out of the last packs and
that's that yeah so hopefully someone
will keep a card so how would you
describe the influence of like Hawaiian
land race / heirloom strains because
it's one of those ones where there's not
a ton of information on it you know some
people say oh she couch comes from the
creepy which is a Hawaiian strain and
then on the other hand you've got like
the Molokai Frost which is you know
another Hawaiian strain which doesn't
seem to be overly similar to the
supposed creepy how would you describe
the Hawaiian land race in general and
then what would you describe that the
Puna butter kind of brings to the
cookies it stabilizes it didn't throw
many horns you know cookies throws a lot
of homes and - peanut butter cookies in
our testing throat zero and we sold a
lot of seeds and I'm sure there was a
few in there but we didn't really hear
any complaints over so that's what the
main thing I brought to the table
cake you really respects those old
strains you know right before I became
the coastal they lost the Maui Wowi you
know and keg you was real sore about
that for a long time the old brotherhood
strain and he has high regard for the
Hawaiian heirlooms cuz he actually got
to smoke them in their heyday so you
know I was a young kid on the East Coast
so I really don't know much about that
you know it's kind of I'm seeing some
now - luckily working with coastal and
keg you nice and say how would you
describe coastal seeds because I guess
it's kind of different from a few
companies as a few people who braid
under the banner of it but it seems like
the overall project is you know land
rice / heirlooms how do you think of
coastal seeds so to speak well coastal
suits as Hannibal Kade you first he
started it it took Bollywood BAM as the
first people to do work with keg you and
then they brought me in and Hannibal and
and um kqs and og you know he's 72 years
old he's been growing since 1969
so me and bam just look at him you know
just as a you know like a mentor and you
know just door were lucky to be able to
work with teachin acts he has in the
help help him do this work you know
cousin when you're so need to you know
like becomes a lot little harder than
when you're in your pond and he's got
all these to nedick's and that's
actually the main reason I joined just
because he had all these awesome tunics
and I wanted to cross him to all these
awesome old clones I had and I wanted to
help them keep these strange pure and
soon as I dug into the vault
you know first things that you know
grabbed my interest were on the Northern
Lights number one it's kind of
disappeared it was quality you know
top-of-the-line we when I was a kid and
also the m10 that's the second thing he
got that from a friend of his in Santa
Cruz jr. and that's some [ __ ] call
it's also known as Afghani number one
and you know those strains are pretty
much not around anymore not in quality
form and I was very excited to see that
both those lines were exactly like I
remembered and you know it was very cool
and coastal seats is you know KQ is
trying to grow the old land race pure
ones because those are the the things he
remembers when he was a kid and those
are what he wants to smoke you know I'm
trying to bring back the indicas um
Bollywood BAM is on he's really in a
flavorful food and exotic flavors and
tastes and his favorite leads to Arkell
and you know he's gonna breed for what
he likes cake he was gonna breed for
what he likes and a boat's gonna select
for what she likes and you know I want
to breed indicus you know and that's
kind of what I'm gonna concentrate on
after I finish those two classic
Amsterdam strains I'm gonna work with
all the land race indicus he has and
also working with the Panama red that he
had and they keep Ruffino out of the
selection after we had had it for a year
and I grew it on other people Raven how
good it was and take you sent it to the
lab and to our surprise it was the
two-two-one seaweed he dominant and
right around that same time he was doing
it he had just done an open pollination
and when he does a kampala nation he
marks all the females and keeps them
separated and uses as many males as he
can and the last summer in August my dog
got cancer and I you know I wanted to
treat her with everything I could and
CBD it was one of them so I was inspired
by that and I went to one that gave you
and I said you know give me the give me
100 seats out of the CBD dominant FINA
and I'm gonna work it and I I took him
and I grown and everyone that wasn't see
but he diamond and I killed except for
one that was Chi hcve it had a
ridiculous amount and the ratios we
never sent it the finished product to
the lab yet we must don't do that but
the leaf sample that people
steep hill top Bollywood bam that this
is special and they also sold Bollywood
BAM when he took the leaf samples and
cozy gels with labs and stuff like that
that three or four of the CBD females
and one of the male's had really really
high ratios of CVG and those are in the
open pollination too and one was
definitely a male and really excited to
be able to bring that pure landrace CBD
um to the public and keg you actually
just sent some to file those so you know
we're pretty sure it's just gonna start
its own galaxy so they'll be now debate
you know it's its own land race CBD you
know and gonna be excited to release
that to the public this fall after it's
tested you know I did I open pollination
like like eight boys and um twelve to
sixteen females I you know the about
sixty out of the hundred were CBD
dominant and and any ones that were weak
I called off and I just opened
pollinated the rest so when you first
did the CBD so I when K GU first did the
CBD open pollination do you remember
what type of percentage of acidity
trades there because a lot of people
often reference the the older land race
strains there was like potentially a
reasonably high proportion of them the
hyde CBD in there and it was kind of
selectively bred out do you find that
that was the case or do you think that
that selective breeding took a much
longer process than just kind of recent
years so to speak well but that was
probably the case because you know back
in the day they just said hey this
didn't get me as high [ __ ] let's kill
this thing they selected that as their
keeper cut before I was in coastal seeds
and you know I was able to just grow it
when I'm joined and I found out how
special it was I told keg you this is as
good as anything I got I brought some to
the Emerald cup two years ago and spoke
to that people with the Coastal's booth
and everyone raved about it and at that
time we didn't know is CBD dominant and
most of mine see we do element in that
and that in that line but that you know
that one mother that was CBD dominant
her safety 60% of her offspring were and
we're seeing now that I took just CBD
dominant males invite him to just see be
dominant females on the next open
pollination of locking down the CBD
genetics or seeing higher ratios and on
it it's exciting you know it's a it's a
very good line because of what I've seen
in Elaine race so far as you know some
good bad and ugly and this stuff is good
weed um it like that that we found out
just because we kept that clone around
to smoke and it's gonna be cool to share
with everybody yes I think it was Bodhi
who said that he found it was kind of
like being a little bit higher and a bit
on tequila
having the CBD Panama how would you
describe the effects to people and I
guess the the extrapolation of that is
when you do get it sequenced and you
know it's it's only animation or you got
the proof do you think that'll it'll
open the doorway to a new type of high
kind of like what Bodhi referenced in
that you know you don't get but these
days it makes you feel like you know I
caught it I think tequila wait you know
that's not really common do you think
that it could open the door to a whole
new type of high in that regard
you know this all Android strands are
definitely unique on high um I need to
get some pictures up on my Instagram
account but you know it's not the
prettiest stuff it's for the sativa
lovers it's long flowering long skinny
buds
um very chirping rich slimmer similar to
haze summer cherry and lemon but cakey
one says it is the best drain to give
him two munchies right now and I Grove
Ottaway and I give him whatever he needs
for um because he just got over cancer
when he was younger he just loves to
Tevas
he loves it to us and then when he got
sick he really got to appreciate these
strong into cuz I have because he said
they just helped his pain you know like
the Black Diamond the chem dog d LG
coaches and
it was cool to be able to introduce some
to the Australians at that time in his
life when he needed them yeah without a
doubt
and so do you think that the use of CBD
treatment in conjunction with say
chemotherapy for example is more
effective than CBD on its own yes you
know what I did what the dog was
chemotherapy treatment
combined with we did four to one CBD
dominant 40-pound dog she was getting
about a hundred milligrams and at first
it was 75% CBD and then 25% THC and we
kept it like that for a long time
and at that same period I was taking
just pure CBD oil and robbing it all
over her belly and her armpits and so um
she's still on the 25% CBD 75 percent
THC right now and she had a hell of a
tolerance gosh you know she got cleared
up for a cancer and in January and we've
kept her on you know just for safety
facts because you came and noticed she's
high um she's got a very strong
tolerance you know I know I'm a grown
man that can't handle you know 75
milligrams of THC you know and she gets
25 of us gve and I give it to her and
just to keep the cancer away because she
had lymphoma and they said it was you
know very close to stage four and they
were pretty shocked by the end of her
chemotherapy first round that she'd came
in the heat and they said that was
extremely rare yeah well that's a good
outcome while we're on the topic of dogs
on your Instagram you got a fighter and
you it says headband underdog I thought
there were two different strains or are
they the same so you know weasel and
Sandow and crew out there they had a
strain that
all those same names this is not that
same string this is a very good OG Kush
cut and alum with the headbands there is
a lot of confusion like my friend not so
dog has that headband from a mutual
friend of mine all quality over quantity
of it to him years ago and we've all
known each other unknown quality for
quantity forever but I I'm no nonsense
dog since like 2006 and will its endured
she's got three headbands now on one's
loom post one is the one from us and one
is Mandelbrot's and you know DNA
released a 707 and um swerve really
really stuff I had been and you know so
there's so many headbands and that's
just so confusing but the one I have is
that I feel like the best OG Kush cut
there is so on the history of oh jeez
we commonly hear that the TK is the
original but I mean it's still not
confirmed you know there's still a lot
of people who dispute that what do you
think the origins are well I think it's
very interesting that Josh DS cut the
one also known as the ghost cuz I is the
guy that shared it on over girl with a
lot of people the ghost OG the Josh D
the one that he took down to Southern
California that got was called cushion
Florida the cathode G named og cush in
Southern California you know I think
that's the oldest one um I think it's
very you know there's something behind
it because that and the TK both came
from Florida and they're both amazing
cuts and um some of the best I have any
you of the opinion that it's most likely
heavily Afghani landrace in origin or
maybe a cross and hybridized a bit
further before the public got their
hands on it you know I think it's
Afghani I'm dominant announcer got going
very round and dense that the high is
very strong you know kind of indica but
on
you know it's a good question I think
time will tell I think it eventually
will come to light exactly what it is
you know I think it probably went back
to Northern Lights because before I G
cush the best strains were Northern
Lights okay and so I read online that
you could harvest TK at 12 weeks and so
I asked Duke about that and I was like
what's to go with that I thought it was
like 10 weeks then he goes are ya like
some strains I've got like two windows
so to speak you know like it like peaks
at 10 weeks that's a good time to take
it then 11 weeks you know not so good
then 12 weeks you know gets good again
and I was thinking I've never really
heard of that before you know I don't
doubt it
but do you have any kind of you know
personal experience with things like
that or have you heard of an idea like
that well those are oh geez and chem
dogs are some of my favorite strains to
grow and I feel like the longer you can
keep them healthy and they're green and
still growing and you know not starting
to die off and catabolize themselves the
better they're gonna be you know I like
to take home definitely seventy days you
know if not 77 so I like the long window
I've always liked the the stronger one
oncotic I have all those strings and not
too long to you let him go to more
better the buzz in my opinion a lot of
the Northern Lights are the same way
that you want Benny to go like ten weeks
a lot of those old clones like I have
like black domina and the dumpster um
they need to go and what is the dumpster
we've read a little bit about it online
I've seen it on your Instagram there's
not a whole lot of information you know
I've heard two backstories and they're
kind of similar um came from the
University of Ohio campus one story was
a guy went into a bar and he he was
having a celebration drinking he's you
know he's like I'm not by around you
know I just almost got busted the cops
were onto me and I took everything I
threw it in the dumpster
he was like I'm buying everyone around
they didn't catch me and some of the
guys in the bar were like what dumpster
and then I've also heard another story
where someone actually did get busted
and the cops it was early in the back in
the day and they just maybe through
the weed in the dumpster and someone
pulled a clone out who saw the lights
and stuff but it's rumored to be a old G
13 NL or a G 13 Shiva skunk and I see a
lot of Northern Lights in it um I think
it's Northern Lights something
and what's your you know kind of
hypothesis on the history of the real G
13 you know we I'm kind of sick of
hearing that story about the University
thing like I just don't think it's true
well you know cake you told me about he
grew up in Santa Cruz and lived their
whole life he told me about this girl
and he just said up north and he said
her name was hash cake patty and back in
the day they used to the smugglers the
Brotherhood and everyone else would
smuggle hash in surfboards and and
whatnot and um they were smashed and
that's why she was called hash cake
patty and he said that she had heard
about the government growing g13 and she
just turned some seeds she found out of
some Afghani hash and called it she 13
for marketing you know I don't not
saying that's true but it you know it
really makes a lot of sense and you know
he's very old-school and everything you
see from the government is a very sativa
plant in g13 that Neville bred with was
a very Afghani plant you know similar to
what the story keg you said about hash
cake patty finding the seats and the
Brotherhood's hash it they brought back
in his surfboard it was smashed out
yeah killer so while we're on the topic
of the Brotherhood it's kind of
something I haven't mentioned a whole
lot but as time goes by it feels like
they're becoming more and more important
in the whole history of things
what can you kind of tell us about the
Brotherhood and what you knew about
their contributions original smugglers
you know I you know heard rumors that
some of the guys that did the endless
summer were part of that you know and
you know that's when they learned his
smuggle stuff back in surfboards
and um you know later grew so big that
they were buying brand-new Mercedes Benz
and VW goes out of Germany and shipping
them over at Afghanistan and I'm filled
with hash and and and weed and taking
that to California and then driving
those cars already loaded with stuff to
the college universities and supplying
the weed that wasn't available and
they're the first guys that brought
indicas into America is what I heard and
before that they were bringing Mexican
sativas and they are also brought a lot
of the Mexican sativas to the Hawaiian
Islands and they were just you know the
original guys and you know anyone that
can get any genetics you know that
anyone say I'd offer many of their
imports you know that's what Kiki was
looking for most cuz when he thinks back
you know it was the who brought the best
weed yes you know when he smoked stuff
that's who had the best you know they
brought the Thai in there just oh jeez
you know they paid the Weathermen break
timothy leary out of jail
you know when Timothy Leary was in there
for pot charges and they had Jimi
Hendrix play private concerts for them
and their property in Hawaii you know
who long and so do you think it's safe
to say that what a lot of people
consider to be the original braid is
like Neverland the likes most likely got
their stock from them oh yeah or people
that you know got the gene X from them
and you know did the same thing I did
you know just earlier in time kept the
seeds alive and bred them so they could
have more that the next year and not
thinking of anything other than being
able to have good wheat the next year
you know interesting and so something
you may or may not be able to comment on
is the more I research to the original
skunk story the more this question
becomes more you know kind of pertinent
in my mind is in the original story that
gets talked about they speak of how the
original skunk it was actually a project
which was
to recreate a clone that was both
unstable and didn't breed true and that
was how they ended up like trying to
recreate it I believe it was Mexican
cross Colombian but then they couldn't
they couldn't recreate it even just
using raw landraces again
and so they hybridized it using the
Afghani first and then crossed it back
in and made what we knew as skunk number
one now but what I'm interested in is
what was really that clone that liking I
guess the the you know progenitor skunk
what did it what like was that Bowl
stock potentially like what was that you
know do you have any idea you know I
really don't have any idea that would be
an interesting question asked aq but I
think most of the stock was Brotherhood
back then because they were the ones
importing most of the weed and hash into
America so chances are you know what
snacks that came from them I know the
guys on from sacred seeds were out of
Santa Cruz and you know Sam you know I
guess ratted everybody out fled - and
with all those seeds yep
and so a you of the opinion that Sam
skunk man is not a good dude
I don't know I'm personally but you know
it's not a good thing to narc on your
friends and then take your everybody's
work and go profit off of it that's not
[ __ ] cool yeah cuz I mean there's a
lot of there's a lot of stories around
you know like what I've basically heard
is that everything people give him
credit for bringing to the market he
didn't actually crack he just took it
from someone else you know like notably
skunk and haze how do you feel about
that you know online stuff and I've also
heard what cake you told me and I know
nothing about his breeding but you know
I just turning on your friends like that
and clean what did you next man that's
cold-blooded
yeah without a doubt that's you know all
I know about that story
yep and so a breeder who is very near
and dear to my heart
Tom Hill he releases a lot of strains
which in many regards could have kind of
fallen into projects bicoastal seeds you
know he was very much during the open
pollination landrace type of thing how
do you view his strange to have any
personal experience with them I have
high regard for all of his strains and
he was also a pioneer in thermal
triangle on growing giant trees you know
like really monstrous plants you know
and there's no it's just amazing you
know he's somebody that I would love to
me his [ __ ] lines are amazing I hold a
deep chunk in high regard
some people don't I hold it in high
regard and um you know he put out some
amazing work you know I love it all and
so have you ever heard of any of the
other lines that are not commonly
referenced because he only ended up
having like I think it was like five or
six lines for sale but like you often
heard about other lines he worked on but
just that they weren't released like one
that most notably comes to mind is he
did a deep chunk cross x.18 and i think
he called that the boneyard or something
like that but there was these other
strains that he had made or was working
on that it started to gain notoriety and
like I think there was another line he
had it was like the blue Afghani and you
know like have you ever heard or worked
with any of those or not really well I
do not have the x.18 and I would love to
get some seed stock of that I only have
the deep chunk line and I'd also like to
get that pine tar you know Tom Hales
haze is also another line you know I'd
loved it to get you know just to help
you know keeping my personal seed stash
for Oakland pollination
you know and to keep around and share
with friends and Tre well not
necessarily stuff that I'd worked for
with coastal seeds you know just stuff
for the preservation aspect and so have
you ever had what you would consider to
be a true or accurate representation of
haze because it's one of those ones
where you know like you still get packs
that
say Hades but everyone who had the real
stuff says like you can't really find it
anymore like it's just not the same I
remember the first time I tried pure
haze it was in Trinity County at the
tribal stomp in 1997 that og guy B Smith
from Denny Canyon gave a talk that year
and [ __ ] right in front of all those
people he said he had like thousands of
plants that were like he's a tall guy he
reached over said like eight feet tall
just right in front of the whole crowd
police and everything I'm real pioneer
but that same weekend I got a smoke case
for the first time and wow it was
[ __ ] amazing
and I've seen it a few times since then
and it's definitely still there I know
people that have original A's cuts um
but you know I don't know anyone that
has seedstock of you know really good
old you know pure Santa Cruz pace you
know only Amsterdam haze and when you
make that distinction do you mean that
the Amsterdam haze was worked towards
that kind of less flavorful more kind of
chilled out buying I mean that's what I
commonly hear from people or is there a
difference a different difference in
your mind well you know unfortunately I
never got to smoke the Santa Cruz haze
cake you actually knew one of the girls
that shrimp for the haze brothers and he
contacted her and you know hoping she'd
have some seed stock you know and
unfortunately she didn't you know it's
you know local Santa Cruz weed I heard
one of the brothers is still alive he's
not in the cannabis he's in the other
substance substances and he's into them
heavily unfortunately and I guess the
other brother died yeah that's
unfortunate I guess we may never know
unless Sam decides to tell the truth the
Pacific Northwest hash plant is one that
exists me because I have a feeling it's
possibly one of those same plants which
came from the brothers blocks of hash do
you think that's a possibility and how
do you think that cut has persisted for
so long it seems like it's not widely
circulated
it also seems to pop up here and there
at the same time boy I really wish I
knew who held it so I could give him
credit I'd seen that Bodie was breeding
it with it and I'm keg you and Bodie are
good friends and you know I told keg you
hear here's the list
anything he [ __ ] wants you know I
want that cuz when I was a kid you know
and I told you I couldn't even really
afford packs of sensi seeds and to
actually be able to get one of the cuts
that you know Neville was breeding with
it
you know this [ __ ] dream come true so
you know I got it and it's it's it's the
funk it reminds me of the the skully the
super skully the that the the pot cash
plant it reminds me of the HP 13 you
know what I've heard it is pure Afghani
alayan race it's an amazing cut and how
similar is it to the Skelly I mean like
in the sense that is the hash the you
know the pnw hash plant the same is it
just kind of look pretty unsuspecting
and just kind of knock you down as well
yeah they all have the same look you
know none of them are very resinous but
it's the Terps and just that real good
indica you know I grew that HP 13 back
in in Willets with my friend quality
over quantity and 2006 and ended up
dropping that in like 2008 cuz I just
couldn't get the powdery mildew off of
it but that was an amazing stream
actually the most strain that I'm
looking for the most right now I want
that one the most
it's amazing they all have very similar
buds and when you break them open that's
when the nose really comes out of them
you know and when you break them open
and start tearing it off it's just a
very intoxicating nose and you know when
Neville got the cut he took his best
indica mail which was a Northern Lights
number one and he read it to the Pacific
North hash
and release does I know how sprint on f1
hybrids and then he did a back cross and
as the hash plants eats and you know
it's really cool to be able to put the
Northern Lights number one mail up to
these clones you know yeah and so I mean
with that in mind I guess theoretically
cuz we should maybe stay this for anyone
who's not on board with this idea is
that we I strongly believe that Skelly
is the result of a plan from nevels
original of the seed bank the hash plant
seed stock which is what we just said
was the hash playing across to the NL
one back cross to the hash plan again
so with that in mind you could
theoretically back cross Skelly either
way way no you couldn't you don't have a
male of the hash plan but you got a male
of the northern light so you could back
cross at that direction and you could
also now you have to reverse it wouldn't
you yeah yeah some people I know
actually a backyard farmer in South Fork
seeds got an old hashed plant pack and
it was really old stark and I was just
like please give me in mail I want to
make a triple back cross off this
Pacific Northwest and they didn't get a
meal unfortunately KQ has a friend in
Washington that in 1989 um did f2s off
Pacific Northwest hash plant seeds and
then a few years later he did another
breeding took him to f3 and um he's
given KQ some of those seeds extremely
excited you know possibly work with
those males if his friend would give us
permission you know if not I'm gonna do
it just for preservation sake and so I
wonder if you would ever be able to find
out who popped the initial you know the
the land race hash plant seeds that you
know never will ended up getting the
clone or his initial breeding I wonder
who popped that found that that's a good
question
um I was hoping you would ask bode that
I'm gonna have to have a conversation
with bode about that and he'll know the
backstory on who's been keeping the
clonal
because I know archived and CSI also
have it I noticed art on all three of
those breeders list and then my new gig
you and thought you were good friends so
that's who I went through to access it
and um yeah okay I'm sorry I didn't ask
but yeah you'll have the answer
oh yeah I'll get that question answered
synonyms yeah fantastic I'd love to know
but what I wanted to jump back to for
just a moment was you mentioned in a
story a few minutes ago that you lost a
plant because you couldn't get rid of
the p.m. off it I got a hypothetical for
you let's say you had only one cutting
of a strain that you really love and
it's got that same issue it's got Pam
you can't get rid of it would you rather
lose a cut then potentially have to use
some kind of you know systemic chemical
type thing or would you just lose it and
kind of be happy with the memories so at
that point around 2005 I was one of the
first people I knew that could get rid
of powdery mildew it hit California
pretty hard and before that no one had
really dealt with it I have to growing a
will it's Hannah bolt and I moved up to
Trinidad in Humboldt County and we lived
right on the coast and I took Master
Kush train wreck
sour way purple a Sour Diesel
headband Pacific Northwest [ __ ] and
the HP 13 clone up into that house and I
was getting rid of the powdery mildew by
getting the plants and a healthy grow
environment healthy humidity good amount
of light healthy organic nutrients
growing the plants fast spraying them
with potassium silicate and neem oil at
the time and that's what my only method
of attack back then was those two
products and I had everything else clean
for several runs of clones you know and
those two would just pop it out the
Pacific Northwest and the hash plant and
I just killed them and
I personally never used pesticides
strictly against it a hundred percent
organic nowadays I'm not scared of
anything I'm like bring it on because
with my organic IPM regiments I spray
every other day with a great go on x9
ping sprayer really hard when I'm
cleaning up clones and I'll spray every
other day with micronized sulfur for a
month and then I'll switch to potassium
silicon neem oil and essential oils and
I'll spray every other day for a month
of that and then I'll put them through
like a week of green clean there's
another product I'll use to just kill
the [ __ ] out of bugs and systemic and
powdery mildew diseases and I feel like
if you get enough of those products in
the plant and they're in a healthy girl
environment growing fast that you can
get rid of anything and so here's the
moon dollar question do you have to
abandon crop if you get some kind of bug
infestation you know maybe rude aphids
maybe mites if you're in flower because
that seems to be the big one I have
issues discussing with people like
people say to me you know like i'm kind
of converting to organics and they're
like what do i do if i get into in
flower and it's kind of like you just
kind of avoid that and they're like so
there's really nothing you can do and
it's like we yeah you can't really spray
the IPM stuff in flower so what's your
what do you say like you just prevention
is the best answer so you know i've been
gone since the early 90s and then i just
told you how serious my IPM methods are
to clean up clones and that's what I do
before I decide to flower something I
put them through literally two and a
half months of every other day spraying
literally a micronized sulfur will kill
micro my spider mites any fungal disease
and then soil essential oils neem oil
and potassium silicate so I feel like
you get in all those products in there
you're not gonna have problems I've been
growing forever of course I've had runs
that got [ __ ] up by spider mites or
powdery mildew but I grow number one
reason is for my personal headstand
and I want really good strong clean meds
and I'm dedicated and that's the reason
I developed that two and a half month of
cleaning up clones before I bring them
into my flour room and that also gives
some really healthy so that I'm gonna
see their true genetic potential and now
you know not contaminate the rest of the
collection you know and then I'll put
the whole collection through that
treatment once a year just in case you
know yep sure so on the issue of p.m.
I've heard that some people say once a
clones got it it's got it forever you
know and the idea of it being systemic
kind of hints to that but at the same
time never found hard evidence do you
believe that you can get rid of it or
you're just kind of beating it down to
the point where it's not likely to
manifest out I believe a hundred percent
that you can outrun it when I mentioned
Hannibal and I moved to Trinidad and
those that Pacific Northwest [ __ ] and
HP 13 kept persisting we when we called
those I didn't spray [ __ ] and we had no
PM for eight years and I believe it was
through getting the plants in a healthy
environment growing fast and then taking
cuttings off the top of the plant while
you were hitting the plant at the same
time with potassium silicon and NEMA
loss and both of those are fungicides in
their own right and you know it might be
in the stump but you know I took my
stumps at that point took the top of the
cuttings and I [ __ ] got the red of
the stumps you know and just kept the
tops and I believe a hundred percent
that you can get rid of powder powdery
mildew that way especially if you use a
micronized sulfur which I didn't know
about back then that's even a tougher
plan on the PM it's nothing I'd want to
use for something I'd want to smoke but
we're talking about cleaning up all
genetics here so they're not lost okay
and are you also of the opinion that
sulfur is one of the more overlooked
elements in when people are kind of
building their soil
hundred percent it helps to bring out
Terps on I believe yeah fantastic and so
if we look at the discussion of jeddak
genetics sorry if we look at the
discussion of genetics throughout
history people often say our genetics
used to be really good do you think that
what they're actually trying to maybe
say is that they used to be more variety
or do you think genetics in the past
were better like on average I think on
average [ __ ] necks are much better
today I just think our genetic diversity
has somewhat been lost especially with
the sativas that are very difficult to
grow you grow them for twice the amount
of time and you get these small spindly
buds that you know it's not really what
the market wants now and some people
that's their cup of tea those soaring
psychedelic eyes and there's not many
commercial growers that'll provide that
form you know and there's not very many
places that people can go and buy those
types of seeds you know unless it's you
know a czar trainer across so how do you
tackle that issue of having you know
really long flowering strains let's just
say you know an extremely sample your
flowering 16-week strain so you know
let's just say 14 you know no one's
early flowering 16 weeks rains 14 week
strain you know not that unheard of but
um you know you should you be charging
like you know close to twice as much as
like a seven or eight weeks train like
how how do you compensate that in the
business model when I guess you know a
lot of people are probably not going to
expect maybe they'll have except a bit
of a price increase but maybe if you
look at the flower time proportionately
they they won't budge in that and that
was the driving force that got us to
this spot wasn't it like you know how do
you think we tackle that issue you know
unfortunately on what I see is people
that are complaining that there's no
city bus but then when the city bizarre
available they're not willing to pay
anymore form in the city was actually
good overlooked pretty much it's fear
sativa lover I recommend you get some
good sativa genetics and growing
yourself in a greenhouse because you
know that's where sativa is really shine
in my opinion
and so if we look at the photos on your
Instagram a lot of them are from green
houses in fact you probably struggle to
kind of find one in an indoor setting do
you do indoors at all or are you all
outdoors no I love indoor growing I keep
a lot of my mom's indoors currently I am
excited actually to be moving them to my
own facility with just me and Hannibal
in Salinas going for the legal permit
down there on 10,000 square feet so that
we can keep the quality up but uh you
know I love to work outside you know and
if I had an opportunity to work in a
greenhouse versus an indoor warehouse
I'm going to take the greenhouse any day
of the week um I love being outside I
love being with nature fresh air well
not under the artificial lights being
under the sunlight and I'm really really
working hard to bring the quality of my
greenhouse up to the quality of my
indoor and you know that's a fun
challenge for me yeah that's an
interesting one in my opinion because
often I find people you know they'll say
outdoor is the best it's unbeatable and
it's like I think what they really
trying to say is like theoretically it
can do better than indoor but rarely do
I find personally outdoor that is better
than indoor at least my indoor how do
you feel about that you know you have
the same opinion that like outdoor is
the best or you like you know in the
sense of that mindset of like
theoretically or do you literally
believe that or do you believe the
opposite man I just like to be honest
with myself and you know my favorite
strains are indicus and when I turn them
out inside they're [ __ ] amazing and
I'm getting close to that quality I feel
like in the greenhouse now and I feel
like greenhouse quality's definitely
better than full Sun I really love
smoking full Sun Organic weed though
that being said you know if there's
something about Nam especially if it's
growing in the ground you know and they
can get some of the native soil and
flavors in the full season just the
whole experience this is really good but
you know if you're talking about corona
and all
clone like when my black Dominus or one
of my chem dogs or one of those although
jeez endure and a stable humidity and a
stable temperature on those old client
clones shine better what they just like
the stable environment I don't think it
has to do with the lights I think it's
more about the stable humidity stable
temperature okay
and so you know often you'll find that
plants will grow slightly different
phenotypically slightly different taste
wise and potency wise when you compare
the needles outdoors do you find that
there are some strains that you know
have one taste indoors and when it's
outdoors it's like it's quite a
pronounced difference in flavor like
what strain to you has the the biggest
just natural variation when you
transition it from indoors to say
greenhouse well you know the chem talked
is one of the flavors that you can
really hit or miss and I really enjoyed
the full season Sun grown I did last
year it was really a cool you get a lot
of strains out in the Sun and they're
just gonna have thicker stems and really
shine but the best stuff outside if you
can get it in a greenhouse is the sativa
that's you know they just shine outside
under the Sun they don't like being
close to the lamps they grow all tall
you know and then getting close to that
warm lamp that they don't seem to like
it um you can get on a greenhouse and
just get them under the natural Sun they
just that's the one of the strings like
that does turn out better outside than
it does inside for me are sativas and so
what's your favorite landrace sativa to
be honest with you I really like this
Panama red stuff it's it's good I've
been smoking that the crap out of the
THC vina THC V FINA on we haven't got
the percentage tested but I've been
smoking that a lot and to be honest with
you I haven't worked with too many
landrace sativa lines cakier that's his
specialty and like I said I'm a neuticle
still see it's and then I went for the
old Afghani lines that I knew as a kid
first
and you know it's I have some cool old
cuts you know that I like one of my
favorite says the monkey Paul's it's the
enemy's soldier brought back Vietnamese
black and he crossed it with the
Nepalese Highland sativa up in Michigan
and that's a real Oakland that for like
a twelve to fourteen link sativa really
has a lot of earthy um cush flavors in
it um and they're really kind of
grounding not so paranoid of a high for
a sativa and that's one of my favorites
the Pacific Northwest [ __ ] is another
one of my favorite old sativa cuts yeah
I mean that's a planet we've never
really spoke of on the show but I think
I've read online of there's like a few
that [ __ ] cuts the car around what do
you think about that do you have you had
anything along those lines or do you
think like no it's just um one of those
cuts with is a few there's other plants
that have similar characteristics but
like you know this fights essentially
well there's a humble [ __ ] which is
different from Oregon Pacific Northwest
[ __ ] and if you go to any of these
clubs or dispensaries in California
they're gonna have clones of everything
on the menu and ninety-nine out of a
hundred times they're gonna be fake so
it's pretty much you want your dog [ __ ]
cut to come from a certain crow in
Oregon you know because that's where you
know what's the real one and that's what
I'm big on my clones its provenance I
really try to get them through the right
people so you know it's the right clone
yeah okay and so in general when you're
looking to do a breeding project do you
approach it in more of like a calculated
method in that you kind of thinking what
is gonna pair really specifically well
with a certain strategy or are you more
so just like I like this one male let's
hit everything with it and then see if
any of them particularly work well no
I've kind of been doing kind of like in
cross work work
send these lines back into something
that I think's in them you know or
definitely confirm to end the string you
know to kind of stabilize it and bring
it back to a pure form so that other
breeders and friends can get these
strains and back cross them further or
take a little work lines with them I
really want to provide old-school
genetics and stuff this ready for people
to breed with do you foresee a time
where your breeding methods would have
to change by virtue of just you know
there's new let's just say we fast
forward 10 years from now and coastal
seeds it's got an awesome menu with most
landrace strains on it work to a point
where you're happy to have it publicly
available do you think you would then
look at say doing some f1 hybrids with
land race strands kind of similar to how
bode does or what would what would you
look to do at that point if you know you
had to kind of if you were forced to
evolve out of just doing preservation
work well I'm gonna spend 50% of my time
pretty much doing the preservation pure
lines and then I'm gonna spend the other
50% concentrating on these NL outlines
with the hash plant and m10 and working
those ok and do you have an end goal
foreseeable with those or you just kind
of see where it takes you I want to
remake that a old kill stream from North
Carolina that I used to cut that's the
best weed I've ever smelled the rapture
the kill and sorry you said that was a
g13 cross and no hash plant a no hash
plant MLG 13 yes old-school Amsterdam
stock so how you gonna fill that any OG
13 spot luckily I just got that airborne
g13 okay and you think it oh it was
maybe the airborne used originally or
you like because I guess I'm thinking is
there everyone g13 in my eyes is not
like pg-13 you know it's like it's a
cross it's the closest I can get and
it's actually uh I think it's she
thirteen Biennal - so it's actually half
the work done for me yeah okay and so do
you think the real original g13 is still
out there or are you just saying like
now we haven't heard about it for so
long it's it's most likely gone
you know I like to think that anything
could be out there you know a lot of
people that put in work
don't come online I just came online up
with my Instagram account a few years
ago you know and I had tons of strands
that people really didn't have and you
know I've really shared them a lot you
know yeah okay so you never know who's
gonna come out and burn a blast from the
past and a lot of time when these
classics come up they want cookies or
skittles or something like that for
these old classic gems and I'm happy to
balázs so what is the most type in rich
plant you've ever had or grown yourself
as a bit of a just totally different
question wow there's so many of them
unfortunately a lot of time when you get
super high amount of Europeans in this
string you don't really get potency and
that's a rare combination you know this
lemon tree out of santa cruz that's one
of the few strains that really combines
the two together it's an amazing cut
yeah do you know the history behind the
lemon tree it seems to have gotten a
popularity really quickly I mean I think
people may have seen it swamp boys breed
with an S one of it as a mother so
that's even a bit of an interesting
thing in itself yeah I have to cut
through Santa Cruz and his literally uh
since I harvested it it's like this top
ten top maybe top five in the collection
I've heard it's you know maybe an old
string called Lemon Drop or a lemon tie
cross it's a very short compact indica
growing plant with a very lemon strong
flavor and in narcotic I so very strong
and
you think this isn't a new hybrid but
just something that's been unknown for a
long time and like do you kind of know
anymore of the genetics besides that
potentially that it's the lemon drop you
know that's all I know
you know that's pretty much it the rest
would just be me taking somebody that's
something else you know yeah might not
be true and I don't want to lead anyone
in the wrong direction but I'm pretty
sure that's kind of like what the guys
are saying yeah so I mean on the other
spectrum of instead of being a
hypochondriac the most underrated car
you know the one that doesn't get enough
credit for what it is you know I think
I'm dog decent on the best weed and you
know I don't have that many people that
agree with me unless I smoke it with
them on the black dominance are really
good the super skully the podcast plant
when done proper is really really good
red Lebanese house plant
I have is an amazing cut the athe 13
hash plant those are all some of the
most kind of underrated I guess 8hd 13
hash plants been getting a lot of
respect because Bodie used it and you
know yeah okay so just while we're on
the topic I guess you kind of already
answered it overall you just said you
prefer the chem date but do you think
the 91 is more potent than the day or no
the d actually takes the potency for you
as well
potency 100% when done right I think
they're both very picky but you know I
think they're equally picky people say
that ninety once pickier but I think the
T is very picky too and it's mine and
Hannibal favored weed okay and so what's
the one cut you most wish you could get
your hands on HP 13 and are you
confident it's still around
yeah either through the island crew or
the New York career um I could probably
get it it's just you know that's obvious
a lot of work okay and so I found an
interesting photo on your Instagram feed
you know it's I'm pretty sure it's like
a compost tea from what you said in the
description but honestly it looks like
soil with these crazy mycelium hi-5
forming all through it kind of looks
like you know iconic the way Bokashi
does to your topsoil what's your recipe
for an awesome tea like that because
that was like the most photogenic
looking tea I've ever seen yeah so one
of the key ingredients for me to get
that messy Liam that's thick literally a
stop fungus gnats dead in their tracks
though it'll kill them is grow Kashi and
then you know you mix that with some
dragonfly Earth medicine brilliant black
and then some really high quality
compost and are thrown castings it's
really you know really I can't emphasize
you know how important it is to get high
quality of those two products and also
to get several sources of high quality
compost several sources of high-quality
are thrown castings for the biodiversity
the keys are the grow Kashi and the
brilliant black that just get it looking
like a carpet and so in general how
would you describe your gross style you
like you know you kind of run like a
no-till type of system or more of like a
super soil type of thing or liquid how
would you describe yourself I I would
describe my style as I do a lot of top
dressing I do a lot of fresh extractions
of earthworm castings and compost I
don't throw them all just extract them
into the water and water immediately
lots of for you live feeds as we go in
to the first beginning of flour and
through veg not to really make sure it
has everything it needs and the right
parts of the plant and top of the plant
and then you know I just kind of you
know it sounds a little hokey pokey but
I keep you know just can look at the
plants and you know I get high and I
spend time around them and I can just
read read the plants
what they're lacking and how happy they
are about how they're holding their
leaves and how their growth is and I
really feel like if you can hang out and
your grow room for a certain period of
time look at your plants kind of vibe
off of them leave for a little bit go
take a bunch of bong hits or you know
smoke a joint whatever you like to do
and then go back in and just read and
vibe you do that a couple times a day
for a long period of time you're really
going to be able to just walk into a
grown and and look at plants and be like
that's that strain on death strain is
unhappy because of the way it's holding
its leaves I could see you know
different strains by you know at their
Leafs and just how happy they are and
you know you really you know it just
comes with spending time with the plants
and so what do you think is the kind of
upper ceiling of what one person can
tend to in terms of plant numbers and
giving them adequate care because I
think a lot of people are worried about
the idea of big companies coming along
and you know like the idea of like a
grower having to tend to like 10,000
plants in a day and it's like it's like
surely you're spreading yourself too
thin at that point of the plant can't be
getting enough attention what for you is
do you think the upper limit yeah well
you know I grew nine acres for a hemp
company in Colorado and by the time we
got it back around to the other side of
the field the water um they were about
to die of water and you know that wasn't
a fun experience and since then I've
turned down a couple job offers to be
you know I had gross four large
operations and Hannibal and I decided to
you know go forward and put the whole
life savings and to go get permitted in
Monterey County in Salinas and get a ten
thousand square foot apartment and you
know that'll be cool because I'll be
able to have the collection in their
safe kind of greenhouse and yeah for
sure
and so a question I wanted to ask you
because I think you might be able to
give an interesting perspective on it
I've done some research on the history
of Northern Lights and I'm sure you are
pretty well-versed in it given the
projects you're doing
I have a feeling that the guy who first
gave Neville with the Northern Lights
you know the Indian Joe I have a feeling
that's Romulan Joe what do you think
about that so for a long time growing up
I had heard that they were the same
person recently when I started the
project we did a lot of Investigation KQ
calling up all friends me doing any
research Bollywood B I'm doing um
computer research and Bollywood vamped
on this High Times article where it said
they were the same person
kqs research led to the fact that they
are definitely different people from
what I believe in what he told me I
think some of the original Northern
Lights guys are on Facebook I'm not on
Facebook myself I'm from what he told me
some guy named Harvey is the guy that
brought him back from Afghanistan and
gave him to Seattle Greg Seattle Greg
worked with to Jos on one home was
Indian Joe that's to kick Hugh's friend
classic see it's met up in Oregon and
that's where he got the NL number-one
stock so I think Seattle Greg is in
islands and that would be one hell of an
interview if you could get him to talk
Oh interesting and so you think is with
people like this where that old stock
resides not just necessarily for
Northern Lights but for everything type
thing you know if they still have some
northern likes you know if that would be
very cool we're not supposed to release
the Northern Lights Pier ourselves so
we're only supposed to release hybrids
and why do you think they wouldn't want
to come forward and get credit for what
is easily you know the poster child of
all cannabis I think um from what I've
heard maybe he hasn't been approached by
somebody like you I think if he's
admitted on Facebook why wouldn't he
want to
on a bigger show and get further into it
mmm okay we have to follow that up so
I've been digging around on Instagram
for a bit and I found a post which says
that you have a legendary back story
behind the red Lebanese hash plant um
and you think it could be closely
related to the g13 you know what is that
story well from my understanding Howard
Marks the smuggler gave nevels two
favorite strengths the red Lebanese hash
plant and g13 from America and Howard
Marks is also known as mr. nice he's
since passed away rest in peace and he
also you know he obviously was importing
a lot of weed from all over the world to
England into Europe and um he shared
some of those red Lebanese suits was
somebody in California and Bollywood BAM
was given the cut to hold on to because
they know he held on to stuff and he
gave it to me a few years ago and I've
been holding on to it you know it's from
the same stock you know like 100 percent
believe that from smell taste grow on
stone um it's just unfortunately we just
have the cutting we don't have seed
stock that's really interesting to note
so what can people expect from the
northern line crosses you've made like
what type of plants would like whatever
plants should someone expect if they buy
this packet and more importantly what
would you advise each person to get you
know so if I'm looking for a real super
narcotic one which one is the one I
should go for well to be honest with you
if they're not up to par I'm not really
seeing though and some of my favorites
this far are the black lights and pakiya
the super skully ash plant by the
Northern Lights number one and since you
see it's a selection of black dominant
by Northern Lights number one just
because of uh I like to smoke the
mothers a lot and you know I just like
that old-school narcotic indica bus yeah
and so just last question on Northern
Lights for the moment often I've read
things online saying that the SSC in a
lot of their crosses they used a Strang
cord the basic five I've heard people
say that they think that's just like
what they called the northern my it's
five do you think they were the same or
different I think that they were the
same from my understanding the basic
five was the no.5 awesome and so when
people think of Afghan is in general
they're often thinking of things like
you know barber cush and master cush
like you know these real squat plans big
fat leaves you know really broad leaves
however as we know there's there's a lot
of Afghanistan are like that you know
they're more thin they're more taller
how do you think it got to the point
where people think of Afghans as these
you know squat indica plants and no one
really thinks of them as you know these
taller thinner leaf plants even though
they were you know definitely they're
from what I heard on a lot of the you
know original hippies that went over
here that make their own hash and they
preferred the little bush weeds that
grew in the drainage ditches were these
really fat leaved in because that you
know just really slow growing hard to
grow and what people are we're actually
growing fields of was a taller growing
for already just easier to grow and you
know easier to grow an acre of you know
cuz growing an acre of bubba kush ism
and in the ass yeah for sure so you know
bollywood BAM got a bunch of seeds from
his father um unfortunately right before
his father was killed by a suicide
bomber in Afghanistan and it's called
the he calls it the last laugh after his
name his father and you know that's a
much taller growing longer internode
Afghan I guess his father had
connections and he got it from you know
I guess the Department of Agriculture
over there in Afghanistan and mystery
250 years of provenance behind it
documented it's not what we were all
thinking we were you know gonna see
Afghani you know it was a taller berry
drought-resistant very tough plant that
had CBD and the gene pool to seeing that
gene pool purple in the gene pool green
in the gene pool on they were a denser
and to conduct but they had a taller
stretch your inner node structure and
you know something that would be better
for a large-scale agricultural and on
the only time he's released any of that
was for the auction for a Mandelbrot
song and he's kind of keeps that line
tight say would you guys ever consider
working really or you just don't see it
having that much breeding potentially
because it's just so suited for just an
entirely different I love going to a we
do you know Bama stoner a few open
pollination zon it and um that's a
question you'd have to ask him okay and
so how would you feel about ever doing a
cross way you're really kind of mixing
old and new you know like one of your
old school lines like you know maybe the
Panama with something totally new you
know like just a throw a random one out
there you in pure cush you know one of
the kind of more newer hybrids well you
know you'll see some of those for me but
mostly you'll see the older you know
classics clones have stood the test of
time
Bollywood BAM likes to breed with some
of the newer clones so you'll see that
from him you know when he did the peanut
butter cookies Noli headband those were
two examples of inbreeding in that style
mostly what you're gonna see from keg U
is open pollination bland race pure
sativas so that's the cool thing when we
come together
Hannibal like something probably would
being like something I like something in
cave you like something we all share
genetics and then I've read for on what
we like and so are you kind of the same
school of thought of what I think DJ
short is kind of quoted as saying is
that you know at the end of the day all
that really matter
is the end effect and so I guess the
underlying question I want any exam what
makes something worthwhile breeding for
you to just come down to effect or does
it have to be a compromise of things so
it's 100% effect I want you know to
breed for strong indicus you know I
remember and I won a half and does a the
favorites in my collection and they have
them fresher we you know rejuvenated not
you know 15 to 30 year old cuts is a you
know really exciting thought yeah for
sure and so what is the biggest fee you
have about the sweeping at slash you
know kind of unrolling of legalization
in California how do you think it's
gonna affect things positively and
negatively well unfortunately there's a
lot of people getting into it that see
nothing but dollar signs and they're
growing way too much weed that's why we
went for the 10,000 square foot permit
it's actually the smallest permit
available and you know that way we can
pay attention to our we in Hannah bolt
and I can't grow it and it'll be grown
by us and not by irrigation or other
people that we hire to work we can
actually handle it ourselves and with
you know but you know I had to basically
you know spend every single penny we'd
ever saved in our life just to do it and
it's been extremely stressful and the
fact that you know it is gonna be
competitive it's gonna be hard you know
for certain people to be nice like they
were sharing genetics with friends and
you know the greed you know just because
everyone's putting their whole life on
the risk that that's not a good thing
you know the people getting into it from
other industries just for money that's
not a good thing old school people being
left out and taking advantage of you
know that's the worst thing that's why I
advise anybody team up with your friends
and try to get a permit you know go ever
wherever you can you gotta get them now
are you gonna be shut out in California
when
let's you know keep the power with the
people that have been pioneering and
working with this plant their whole
lives they deserve it you know one of
the good things that's gonna come out of
it is you know you know me giving them
other collection and a place where you
know I can go over 99 plants and keep
them legally safe because in Santa Cruz
I'm only allowed 99 and then he's being
able to select over 99 without fear you
know and to be able to show stuff like
that you know to people on Instagram you
know because a lot of times I don't get
to see everything just for a safety sake
yeah without a doubt
and so just to play devil's advocate
let's say the worst case situation
happens where there is just a few large
companies mass-producing really bad
quality wheat do you think in that
situation things would revert back to
how they were before legalization where
we go back to you know people just doing
stuff underground growing you know the
better stuff and you know the black
market blooms again so you know I like
to think that you know this show will
hopefully encourage people in California
if they don't have their permits to go
out and get their permits I would like
to see the people that have been in the
game stay in the game you know but like
that you know if you know I said Hannah
Bolton high risk in our whole life
savings on it and we're gonna work our
hardest to make it work you know and we
work hard but you know if it didn't [ __ ]
I'd be in another state in a house
someone else paying all the [ __ ]
bills you know I'm never gonna stop I
won't stop I can't stop so what the [ __ ]
I do I didn't have any fear then I'm not
gonna have fear you know but I'm putting
everything I got into making it is no
legal industry and so a question that's
quite specifically relevant to Australia
do you think that people should
compromise for access to medicine if
it's you know sub quality you know is it
worth allowing like a pseudo medical
system through if all it is
you know like large companies even like
specifically people like tobacco
industries are really looking at getting
in the game if it was just a few big
providers like them would you settle for
that in terms of like as a society
should you settle for that or should we
be like no have to be able to grow alone
or at least have you know some means
have access to high-quality medicine
yeah I say over grow the government
everyone in Australia should be growing
their own medicine legal or not you know
if it's not legal just don't tell
anybody
don't tell anybody just you know do it
like we did in Virginia old school days
and make the good medicine there for the
people and grow a good and from form
your cruisers and you know form your
networks to get the buds to the the
patient's underground you know
definitely don't trust the man and grow
your medicine you know I everybody
should be able to grow on their own
medicine and if they're too sick to grow
their own medicine they should know that
someone's gonna grow up for them that's
not [ __ ] spraying pesticides on it or
you know doesn't give two shits about it
because I feel like it's a type of plant
that needs love and it needs you know a
caring person to take care of it or the
medicine ain't gonna be the same yeah
yeah I'm definitely the same belief and
so just to kind of get into our last
couple of questions who's a breeder who
you really like their work you know and
you know bonus points if it's not
someone who's just doing lad Raceway
archive CSI top dog freeborn selections
does puros bode seeds I know I'm leaving
some out because it's you know it's the
actually I feel like it's the golden age
of America American breeders right now
with you know the selections and this
the the community you know being able to
get so many different clones off of
Instagram and stuff and so many
different people are breeding and going
in different directions
it's gonna be cool to see how it
progresses because I know coastal seeds
is going to be trying to provide the
land race building blocks and you know
there's people out there trying to
progress stuff and bring new flavors so
there's just so many different people
with different goals and so many people
breeding in America that it's you know
it's it's kind of the Golden Age and say
if you were just a breed oh sorry sorry
and so if you were just a grower and you
had to go out right now and you had to
buy one pack of seeds modern hybrid
which pack would you buy chem dog from
top dog one of his pure chem dog crosses
preferably one of the Trez dog back
crosses because I feel like the the Trez
dog tripled that cross chem d he made is
one of the best breedings and the
marijuana community in history you know
he gave those treads dog seeds to high
and lonesome high lonesome bred dog
waltz and the Appalachia with Bodie bred
with and then JJ kept him and worked him
himself and made the star dog and the
original in New York City diesel and
there are so many keeper star dog cuts
and my dog Walt's cut is one of the most
amazing and all the amazing stuff that's
come from the Appalachia
so I'd say uh you know just gonna have
to go with dogs that is history stack
down and go for some inbred come from JJ
if I had to go for one half it sounds
good and so what are your kind of you
know top five top ten favorite strains
for just smoking yourself cam dog og
black domina my hash plants and then
more Kim dogged a nice tight list but I
love everything if I didn't love it I
wouldn't keep it
so my headband is one of my favorites I
love Sour Diesel
there's so many of them I love all these
new strains I loved OC
I love the real good cookie cuts I love
this one size sugar you know I just got
that papaya that's pretty impressive
stuff I'm smoking on that now you know
the strawberry banana from Crockett you
know that's some serious fire a lot of
stuff from Bodie it's a really good
hippie Slayer dread bread yeah it's
pretty deep I you know I could never
even remember all the clones I have at
once that's why you know labeling them a
list is very important yeah no worries
so if you could have one strain back
that you used to have but have lost what
one would be there's so many so one is
tough I had SEC Mathis bubble berry from
like 96 and that stuff was amazing every
Fino and there was amazing
um I never had my hands on the rapture
kill but you know that would obviously
be it but I never actually got it I did
get some seeds and I later across those
NL ak-47 and made some some really good
hybrids that I would love to have those
I was growing those in in Colorado in
like 99 2000 and I'll a K by super
Silver Haze crossed into the rapture and
I had to feena's back then and anyone I
smoked him with Tina would admit they
were one-hit [ __ ] and I'd have to say
those unfortunately I've lost all the
seeds from that line yep and so who's
some breeders you'd love to do a collab
with Bodie
si si top dog keeping a Kanda
those are guys that you know I have to
put in work for years I highly highly
recommend
yeah awesome and so if you could go back
in time to anywhere to get one landrace
strain or seeds you know from anywhere
where would you go and what would you
get I probably be buying from sensi
seeds a bunch of hash plant and black
diamond right when they were released
but if it was you know I had to go for
land race
be in Afghanistan and you know like 1977
and the Hindu Kush mountains close to
Pakistan nice and so final question what
are your top traits you look for in a
man when you're breeding um he's got to
be like the sisters that are keepers you
know if the sisters are keepers I ain't
gonna [ __ ] breed with the male you
know keep him around for a long time and
torch room you know yes if make sure he
stands yeah make sure you can stand that
test of time and yeah don't you know
that's come through the wringer awesome
so thanks so much for coming on the show
and for spending the time talking to us
I look forward to growing out some
hockey hopefully thanks for having me
you know I love talking about this plant
and it was a real pleasure to be here
and talk with you you're an amazing host
can't wait to meet up in session person
awesome
[Music]
a huge thank you again to bug sitting
down and talking to us be sure to check
out costal seeds particularly there's
the upcoming release of the Northern
Lights lines through CT now the big
shout out to 420 Australia and OGS as
always hoping to make this episode
happen and a big thank you to you guys
for listening see you
[Music]
[Applause]
you