one thing i find with the australians is
i never get any negativity and i just
think that is
i think something everyone could learn
from
seriously just
never get any negativity or any rude
anything from anybody in australia and i
love it
hello and welcome to the next episode of
the podcast a cannabis podcast for
budding enthusiasts
[Music]
on this episode we're excited to have
the other half the mad combo mrs mad
herself but as always this episode was
brought to us by our sponsors seeds here
now you know they're the best they've
got mad farming gear probably gonna want
to hit that up by the end of this check
them out 420 australia number one 420
lifestyle no questions ogs if you want
that top shelf it's that simple
[Music]
let's get into it guys
alrighty so big thank you and welcome to
other half of the deadly mad duo mrs
madd thank you for joining us
thank you for having me
so a little mix up to the normal
question what are you currently smoking
well um right now
i just finished smoking a joint of
the rainbow ssog by smell boat seeds
actually
so is that is that some like sneaky
product placement that's been popping up
everywhere is this intentional
no actually it's not i just happen to
sit down and roll a joint i i actually
haven't been smoking a whole lot of
flour lately i've been smoking mostly
concentrates um
we haven't had any of our own dry flour
for a while because we've been pretty
busy lately with everything going on
um but no i was lucky my brother-in-law
gifted me some of his concentrates and
some of his
dry flowers so
i figured i'd twist it up and sample it
no sneaky placement
no no no i i wouldn't think so anyway
it's it's great i was lucky enough to be
able to try it but the the question that
i really want to ask so are you like a
joints person primarily
depends um i just
i just like to honestly smoke um but
like i said daily lately
most of the time throughout the day i
smoke concentrates um
right now i have uh
some extreme cream from the jennison
project there are some local friends of
ours
it's actually really good um
and then a friend of ours named bang
mingo he's
gifted me some um it's like from dragon
scale emerald dragon out of humboldt
county
it's a yeti og uh live resin it's really
good
killer
and so
do you find that you would you would
smoke flour exclusively if you could or
you very much like concentrates as well
if
if i'm if i have a chance to smoke flour
it would
most likely have to be hours um
i am i'm really picky when it comes to
dry flour
i don't know it just has to be right i
don't like harshness oh i don't like my
throat throat to burn
i hate to cough i don't want to choke
from what i'm smoking so
in my personal experience dry flowers my
best
best bet is going with whatever we've
grown personally
but concentrates if we don't like i said
if we're out and we don't have access to
something
any one of
our good friends usually have some
really killer concentrates that i can
get or like i said i got like a couple
of buds that were gifted to
to me by uh smell boat seeds which is
nice
for sure okay
and so now let's go all the way back
what was your first experience with
cannabis
oh my gosh
um honestly i don't even know if i can
specifically remember my very first
experience with cannabis
as far as cannabis itself i'm smoking
wise
i was young um
i almost hate saying some of this stuff
out loud
because i was i was really young um
sixth grade probably
i couldn't tell you what it was because
back when nobody really named anything
and they all had real generic names
everybody called it green bud chronic
it was kind of
it's not like it is now
once prop 215 in california um went into
motion here
and
there was um
obviously a market for it that's when it
seemed like strain names became
something that was real prevalent until
then though
it was pretty much called um
green bud skunk
nothing really had a recognizable name
like it does today
so when you were growing up it sounds
like cannabis was rather prevalent did
you grow up in the emerald triangle
no we're
everybody always asks us like where are
you from what you know where do you live
specifically and i could tell you
specifically but nobody ever really
knows where we're from it's a very small
town i've been in california my whole
life
as we're with matt he traveled a bit as
a kid but i have i've been pretty much
in like the central valley area my
entire life
um but yeah cannabis has been uh for as
long as i could remember
i was really young i can even remember
um as matt has stories about his
his parents when they were kids
i think my
my dad hid it a little bit better um
they didn't really smoke a whole lot in
front of us when we were really small
but i do remember a couple of times
seeing some plants growing in our
backyard when i was a real small child
okay and so
at what age were you when you first
heard of like the first breeders and who
was the first breeder you'd ever heard
of
oh my gosh
you know i don't know because i would
say for me personally like as far as
breeders and the whole community i've
never been seriously fascinated
um
like the way matt is he
he has an insane brain for it he
remembers anything and everything he's
ever read or heard or any research he's
ever done he i mean he has just an
amazing brain for it um
but me i've never actually had a
specific um
interest or draw or any of that to like
hunt as far as who who all is in our
community i feel kind of like a jerk
because i was saying we were we just
went to
um the endo ex expo in san francisco and
i feel like a jerk because i really
don't know anybody i don't spend much
time online i'm pretty much a homebody
and i spend most of my time with either
my family or my plants so it's like i
don't i've never really uh i don't spend
all my time doing research on who's in
the community and who does what i focus
mainly on what we do here
um and on our own projects and in our
own house like i don't even remember
when i was a kid and like pot was on the
scene i don't even remember
uh talk about pot breeders it was really
something that i learned a lot about
um once mad started taking like a
massive interest in really learning
about cannabis that's when i started to
really
just learn anything like any real true
knowledge there was to learn i learned
from him
before that i would say was all probably
just
wives tales and probably junk really
yeah i think we've all been fed one of
two of those wives tales before
oh yeah there's there's
there are there's so many of them and
with cannabis like the entire almost the
entire industry seems to be kind of
built on that in some way shape or form
so
yeah like my knowledge anything
um
anything that i have it i'm lucky i was
blessed to learn directly from him and
he just has an amazing mind so i never
really got involved in the like i know a
lot of people do they spend a lot of
time online and they spend a lot of time
researching
strains and breeders and all of that i i
don't i don't have the time for it and i
never really had a massive interest in
it
nor have i had a massive interest in
searching um the information on lots of
different strains only what i'm
currently interested in at the time i
just don't have the space for it
so if we were to say
take a step back what was the first
strain that you and mad were maybe
growing together that kind of really got
you in wrapped in the whole saga of it
all
oh my gosh um
we actually have some pretty funny like
really interesting stories um
the very first few plants that i can
remember like specifically remember him
growing they were actually outdoors and
i don't even think they had names to be
honest
i i can't even remember how we went
about
getting them um we we pretty much
you know now that we've been growing for
i don't know 20 some odd years longer
i'm not sure but around there um you you
get to where you have to keep notebooks
uh so i would have to like go dig and
try to figure out when and what but back
then i think those three plants he had
i don't even think they had names but he
was growing those outdoors at the time
but as far as like when he really took
um
like i knew we would be growing for the
rest of our lives when he first locked
down that lavender plant
um it was pretty crazy he i remember the
day he brought him home
um it was a weird day because i at the
time i had a full-time job i was working
a full-time job and that day when i was
at work i got a phone call
and they tell me that my identity had
been stolen somebody was using my social
security number and my full name
and they were basically using my
information to obtain employment so
um this particular day when i got home
from work i did what most people would
do in the situation i had to call the
police department and file a report and
we had a police officer standing in our
living room taking this police report
from me and he comes walking in the door
with um his lavender cuts
they were in a brown paper bag he had
gotten from like um our you know our our
small circle of friends that we had back
back when
and yeah he walks in the door with those
and it was um it was actually
valentine's day
and he walks in the door with them it
was kind of awkward but of course the
police officer in our house he has no
idea what what he has because they're in
a brown paper bag but it's just one of
those things that you remember forever
because that really was the strain um
that started his major interest and his
complete love and passion for cannabis
and learning about
um the benefits that it's given to not
just him and me but a lot of people that
we know as far as like a medicinal use
yeah of course and so
how did the urkel then get in your
possession
oh that came super short after um
see this is one of those things um like
as far as like the a lot of research
being done
um like i said he took matt took such an
interest in really learning about just
cannabis and
proper ways to grow it and the you know
the ways to go about getting like the
best flavors most resins and just all
the stuff that he had such a fascination
for
and um
he was reading a lot about
i don't know you can call him rumors
whatever the stories that were going
around at the time about urkel and
lavender and how
they were um said at the time to be the
same
and he was dead set and proving that
they weren't uh and again we had this
small circle of friends and
um our friend at the time was super
interested in scoring the lavender that
we had and of course matt wanted the
urkel that he had
so we um tight circle keeping keeping
things amongst ourselves
uh we had agreed we were we were
actually gonna give him a cut of our
lavender which never turned out to
happen
um but we got the urkel and we've had
her ever since and i want to say that
was just like maybe a couple months
possibly after we scored that lavender
but we've had them ever since
and he was just dead set on proving they
were different and
that they were not only different but
different enough and worth hanging on to
both of them as different cuts for
you know for as long as we've had him
and how come the other guy didn't get
the lavender
oh yeah he shortly after went to prison
it just
yeah so he's we
yeah he's gone we haven't seen him or
heard from him in years i believe he's
still in prison but
yeah just one of those unfortunate
events you know how things go
in this business especially if you're
someone who may not necessarily be
careful um yeah he was a good friend of
mads and
known them for a long time and
they made that little deal and
um we hadn't it was one of those things
we hadn't taken cuts yet and he had his
so we got the urkel and we hadn't taken
the lavender cuts yet and
before we had gotten to take it he had
gone gone to prison so he
yeah that's how it turned out and lucky
for us we had we preserved both of them
because
matt and i were just talking about this
the other day
if it were
if it would have turned out any other
way this person that were you know this
person that we're talking about who
ended up in prison he likely wouldn't
have even hung on to
um the oracle cut because he was much
his interest
kind of funny was much like people today
you know they move on to the next strain
and no one really hangs on to anything
it's really funny and we did we we hung
on to him this whole time
so i guess the question i'd love to know
then is what project or what strain was
it that really got you involved in it
because it sounds like mad kind of had
the the reigns of the
the chariot up until this point like at
what point did you really kind of become
like a 50 50 in the partnership which we
know now
oh my gosh oh that's a crazy story
actually um
well
because i don't i don't have a full-time
job anymore but at the time i was
working a full-time job one that was
extremely stressful oh i don't even know
how i did it
um but i was a manager in retail and um
i was on a just a short vacation just i
took a couple of day vacation i want to
say maybe
two days backed with uh two more days to
get like a total of a week long
and uh we had gone out to dinner
and come home and mad was out back with
our dog playing with him
and just one of those things he pulled
something we think not sure but you know
he has a long uh history with health
problems with his lupus and whatnot
and he started to not feel good
instantly after this
and i knew he was sick but i wasn't
exactly sure what was going on long
story short short he ended up having to
go to the emergency room he was in
really bad shape
and they admitted him pretty quickly
they had a lot of specialists come in
and they ended up having to do like an
emergency surgery on him
they opened him up and had to figure out
what was going on with him and they even
at the time had told us that he was
likely to die
they had had us call in all of the
family and do that whole bit
and he was in extremely bad shape
and we had um an entire set of plants
full-blown flower
needing care
and i didn't have a choice but to do it
and it wasn't really my thing like i
said i was stressed i worked a full-time
job and we have a daughter of course and
i i would help him you know on anything
that he needed
but at this particular time um i just
didn't have a choice he was in the
hospital and he couldn't do anything
about it and he ended up being in there
for like almost a month
so i had no choice but to care for
everything we had um running at the time
and
i kind of uh with my personality just
adopted um
i don't know i i kind of like to have
control so
once he got home i had a hard time
giving back giving him back his space i
just i wanted to be in there i i felt
like i needed to have input on
everything which i'm sure just annoyed
him to no end because he's thinking
you're telling me what to do and this is
my space you've
cared for for a month but yeah it's like
i just really enjoyed it i found that i
liked it more than i thought and
eventually like work started to stress
me out to the point where um i just
between that and with mad's health it
was so bad
it was just easier if i were home to
help him with what he needed help with
and
i it made me just a better all-around
mom to be home instead of giving my time
to a full-time position that i wasn't
able to really keep up and
so helping him with the plants that's
how i ended up getting thrown into it is
how it happened i got thrown into it and
didn't have a choice and
lucky for me he's um
he's a wicked record keeper and he has
stacks and stacks of books with dates
and
every day he does something he writes
notes and he gives a solid explanation
for why he does what he does and that's
how i learned and um
once he got out of the hospital he
obviously needed my help for
a while afterwards just his recovery
alone was like a solid year
um but yeah he
just over the time taught me and i've
taken over small things here and there
like
i am insisting i do all of our cuts i
just have a
preference and i am i'm a con i'm a
control freak so
i like
to have control of things
that's how i ended up doing what i do
yeah no i can i can see where you're
coming from so what was the first strain
that you were involved in the creation
of because i guess i'm kind of wondering
was this all happening before the
creation of say the tripoli wicked or
was it after that just as a general
timeline
uh you know i've always had some kind of
some type of influence um
uh what i you know when we when we when
we decided like when we started breeding
um initially it wasn't even about like
breeding for anybody we were doing it
really for ourselves and
like i said mad had like this interest
in the comparison of
you know what are the true differences
between urkel and lavender can you see
it in their offspring and so yeah like
this was his
project that he took on and
that's where it started but you have to
remember like i was his
the person that gets to sit there while
he bounces all these crazy ideas off of
so i'm always present listening to you
know what he thinks we should do
and then of course he always asks my
input
um
i had i i think that the tdub and the pj
lines particularly are his babies but
for me
my one of my most hands-on i would say
is probably our clementine selection the
clementine male
that one for me was definitely my baby
because originally he had no interest in
it and he wanted to kill it
and i just insisted no that he was
definitely a keeper and i just
there was just something about him he
was amazing and he ended up becoming a
really solid project
and so that's one that i would say is
pretty much
more mine i'd say than his
that's a really good point for us to
jump off on because
one of the questions we had submitted by
our patreon fans was
why is
uh the urkel cross clementine called mrs
mads bubba is it like for example
because you think it it's like a good
representation of barbara in seed form
or is it like what's the back story
well
i okay so first off never was really a
fan of naming strains just to kind of
put that out there
never thought i'd do it honestly swore i
never would but the time came and we had
to obviously start naming things so we
did
that's actually not as easy as you think
um i i don't i don't really particularly
like it but with that strain um
like i was saying california
for us particularly we started with the
prop 215 and when back when we had a
bunch of dispensaries you know open up
and down the coastline
um and
one of a really one of the common cuts
that was always floating around was
the bubba kush and
when we started searching through when
we were doing our own um searching and
testing of the
these particular beans we had noticed
that in this particular
this particular strain the
urkel by clementine
it was showing
tendencies and a
physical appearance that did it looked a
lot like the bubba kush and i honestly
thought that it was even had a little
bit more of a better flavor
um
i would say probably because of our
urkel
um but that's actually where it came
from plus the need obviously
to name strains but that's just how it
does it comes about in that way we
when you're when you're growing them
you're looking at all of um the traits
that they express and that that
particular strain
showed a lot of um just it looked like a
bubba kush and um
i don't know i kind of thought it it was
a bit better myself but you know i'm
good that's a biased opinion of course
and so how do you feel about the
original bubba are you just not like the
biggest fan or
no no i liked it um
you know we obviously don't don't have
it but um no i i obviously i did i liked
it or i wouldn't have
looked to try and make something that
you know resembled in some way shape or
form or was like my spin-off version of
that
that's like basically you know what
we're we're always trying to do we're
always trying to
put something out we're always looking
to do something better hopefully
yeah of course and so
do you like to approach a project with
a very kind of pre-conceptualized idea
of what you're trying to do or are you
more so happy to just kind of you know
trial things out and if something hits a
winner you're like great let's pursue
that
well i i don't know i think there's a
kind of a fair amount of both really um
we could sit and talk you know plans all
night long um
and we actually do we will sit i tell
them this is another reason why we're
like the house of notebooks because we
will sit and try to write things down
and you jot your ideas down because as
fast as they come you also lose them if
you don't you know write them down
somewhere but
we do we talk about what we think would
match up well
we think about what we would like to
maybe hunt for say male
and in the future or maybe like what
what we're looking for both male and
female and what do we want to like hunt
and we're always hunting we're always um
testing something uh that we're not
growing something without you know we're
always looking through something but
yeah we're always keeping in mind um
we're always looking to make
you know what what's the next strain
that we can possibly make what would be
good pairing up and always looking to
make something better there's no point
in doing it if you're not otherwise
so
a question i love to ask people you
mentioned you know you're always looking
to pop new things find new things what's
the next thing you're most excited or
going to pop to look through
well
um
gosh she i don't i'm not really sure um
i know
i don't see i'm not i don't know how
much i can say i got to be kind of
careful here because i don't like to
give away too much um
i know we're gonna start looking through
our t-dub
uh we're gonna start
narrowing down some selection there
as i said i think i saw from maybe it
was you or maybe it was mad that yeah
there's gonna be like a filial release
of pure t-dope
he's got something he's got something in
mind um
like i said he bounces ideas off me all
the time but yeah his he he's talking
about his next angle he wants to really
dig deep in the tdub so
um that's where he's going um
i don't know like i said we talk we talk
ideas all the time and we do have a new
female well we have two
two relatively new females in our
collection
the hogs breath which we were gifted by
the hogs breath family they are amazing
people by the way
um they gifted us that female and
we are for sure going to take it to our
clementine mail i think that will make
for something amazing for sure
um so we have that project at some point
in the works there's that's nothing too
secret everybody pretty much knows about
that one
um and then we did we scored a new
female
uh the sr-71 i can't wait to see you
know what she has to offer but again yes
another known kind of purple strain so
that's purple kush isn't it uh-huh yes
it is
uh matt and i were talking about this
just last night um you know how there's
some things that him and i have grown
before and we've really held on to
things for a long time
there was um i want to say we we had a
celine for the longest time we had her
for like six years and
we just eventually
uh cut her loose but she was really nice
it's just it takes a lot to
to say you're a solid keeper and can
stay in our garden for that long you
know
so outside of lavender and urkel what
has stayed in the garden for that long
hmm
well we've got
scdc would be like a close second or
third and then we've got our clementine
um
and that's another thing too we will be
digging through our clementine lines
because we have f
we've got a knight we have f2 f3 and f4
stock of our clementines just sitting
the the threes we've dug through a bit
but the f4s are the ones that i'm the
most interested in so those are ones i'd
like to make a project of
soon but that's another one that's been
in our garden for a while um our
clementine
um but clementine sedc i don't really
know um
how long like the i'm not really even
sure how long the oracle and lavender
have been in our garden exactly i just
know
they've been in our garden since pretty
much since madd got real serious about
growing and
um he you know he knew he wasn't gonna
let him go
but the sedc was the one i want to say
he acquired
around that same same same time shortly
after and then the clementine also we've
had for quite some time
oh northern lights too i don't know why
i forget her we've had her for a long
time i want to say maybe
six or seven years possibly
somewhere around that
and do you know where she comes from at
all
like your one
um
i don't
yeah he was gifted the northern lights
was gifted to us by
a friend um of mads and i don't know
like what of that
i don't know what of that he has said i
guess i should have asked him that um
um he could tell you more on that
because that was something that he
actually had to direct
it was a cut that was gifted to us from
a gentleman he met
um on one of the
boards way back
um but like i said we've had it for
about six or seven years but
i i honestly can't even remember his
name
i would have to ask matt on that one
and so what are some tips or tricks you
might have to just kind of keep plants
healthy over the long term in the way
you guys have with these cuts we're
talking about
um cleanliness is probably the
the biggest thing that in your space
cleanliness is the biggest thing that
you could do
no matter what cleanliness is the
most important for healthy plants um
air flow is also
just
small things um common sense with the
garden seriously
you'd be surprised apply common sense to
everything you do with the plant and
you'll keep it alive it doesn't really
take that much
um
but yeah we try to keep um we try to
keep it as organic as possible
mad mixes it up quite a bit when he's um
in flower
he's like a little scientist in there
but as far as me when i'm anything in
veg
and our mothers
or
our fathers i should say
um
just i do i like to keep them as healthy
as possible
um
just
control any obviously a a clean area and
keeping your
bugs gone or out under control um
cleanliness controls all of that believe
it or not um
but it doesn't take much and like i said
we use really basic products two of
my staples would be like dirt md and um
sea crop use those religiously micro md
love those products
and so i think you just hinted do you
tend to more look after the fathers
um
well
i
look after pretty much anything that's
in anything that's in veg i
keep those going 24 7. um
but yeah i do i look after our fathers
too
do you what are like some tips for
maintaining dads because that that's a
that's a good question
yeah i know some people tend to i know
some people have issues trying to
maintain males i i don't i just um i
find if i keep them you can keep them
cut back more which is nice um
i tend to keep them cut back and smaller
than i would females you can control
them more that way
and
one of the things that's really nice
for
like i was telling mad when if we're
gonna be running um
like a pollination
one of the things that i like to do is i
will
keep my like if i have a couple i always
they're always in the same space but i
always have at least three males at the
same time um
in any given space but what i like to do
is i won't cut on them if i know we're
going to be pollinating and the reason i
won't cut on them is because they will
actually compete with each other and
they'll force each other to like throw
pollen faster and more pollen too which
is really nice
so if we're getting ready to do
something like that like we're gonna run
a pollination run i'll leave them in
there and i won't cut on them at all
during that time frame because then when
i do throw them in there
to throw pollen they seem to be a lot
they look like they're competitive
basically and they'll throw a lot more
pollen um and they'll produce faster
which is nice
and have you ever noticed any changes
over the long term to the males just
because
people sometimes say i mean so maybe
this is a bad question because i'm going
to completely contradict myself here but
people say when you um
maintain mothers in poor conditions you
know over time they deteriorate i'm
wondering if a certain similarity would
happen with males and how it would
manifest but i guess because you know
you maintain things nicely you probably
wouldn't see that anyway
yeah but you know what something like
you're saying you you wouldn't think
that but
i do i actually will i will put plans to
the paces i will stress them out like
you do
you would not believe i mean where they
look ugly and sad and completely unhappy
with me but i have to do that
it's something you have to do you've got
to know
you know what are their limitations what
do they like what are they tolerant to
how do they react when you do this um
it's something that i do i do i stress
them out i make them ugly but one of the
things too plants do they will i have
seen they will deteriorate especially if
they're not in like optimal conditions
but i've also found too that even though
they will do that i can turn that around
also so
you kind of have to stress them
you have to stress them to see
you know what they do when they're
stressed how they handle a stressful
situation so you have to do that you
have to introduce that kind of
environment to them
um but yeah the males do they
i don't know they
they have obviously differences because
it's a male plant versus female but
i don't know it's kind of common sense
you you can kind of just watch them and
you can learn from them as you watch
them grow
it's a pretty common sense basic thing
yeah
so i remember last time i spoke to mad
he said that you guys were running hydro
and organic and then like does that mean
you've got two different setups or like
you do like a hybrid type of thing
no from my understanding on that um yeah
i was wondering i was wondering about
that and my recollection of that was
he was referring to
um
because we're always in soil but he my
understanding was he was actually
referring to organics and synthetics
because he does he he does use some
synthetic nutrient lines um and i
believe that's what he was actually
referring to yes no weird synthetics not
hydrating
yeah
no yeah he does um
he does he does try um
he does try to keep it as organic as
possible and now um from when we first
really started heavily growing
it wasn't as easy organics weren't
as big of a thing there was a lot less
nutrients and there were a lot less
lines on the market back then
but now he has a lot more options
available and
we both we're always willing to try you
know something new you always have
somebody approaching you asking you if
you're interested in trying a product um
i'm always willing to try something new
i just don't like to
personally take taking a bunch of stuff
i know i won't be able to use or
i'm not going to have time to get to
but i am i i am always interested in
something new
i in our veg space
i always try to keep it um
organic
for me
i find as long as i'm doing my
transplanting like i should
um i i rarely have to give them much of
anything and like i said my staples are
like pretty much uh dirt md micromd
and um c crop and if i'm transplanting
my plants appropriately and i'm
maintaining everything the way i should
that's pretty much all i have to do and
then i throw it over and it's it's in
mad's hands at that point
i give him big healthy plants and then
he gets to go from there
nice and so do you ever like to do
flower runs of your own or you're just
happy with the end product you get
already
everything that we do we do as a team
i'm super lucky i would say he is too
um but everything we do we do as a team
we do always have something going
always there's never a time
when there aren't plants growing in our
space and um it's kind of funny because
our daughter was
in here the other day and she's like you
know
most people grow up on house plants
me
pot plants
it's just kind of funny yeah
you know she's she's been around them
her whole life since the day she was
born she's known the pot plant
so it's kind of funny because like we
too we grew up with house plants not pot
plants but she's grown up with pot
plants so
i've had that that proper upbringing
yeah proper upbringing but hey must be
right because she's like uh she walks
around carrying a 4.5 grade point
average
must be
must be doing something pretty alright
so something i was meant to ask you
earlier but we'll just loop back on
quickly
i wanted to know so you you mentioned
which stock you guys were interested to
pop from yourself but this one could be
real could be hypothetical
if you had to or maybe you already are
planning on it popping stock from
another breeder who would it be
oh my gosh dude that's a hard question
and two i don't want to offend anybody
but that is like such a massive list to
choose from
off the top of my head because this
isn't off the top of my head sort of
question here no one's going to hold you
accountable don't worry no i know i'm
i'm sure they'll all hate me in silence
um no
just
with you asking that question in the
moment i have a serious interest
in obviously playing around with some of
duke diamond's gear
i just do can't help it but i do um
uh one of our friends like i was saying
earlier bang mingo he's one of my he's
my go-to concentrates guy right now when
i'm desperate he always hooks me up
he's been growing some of duke diamond's
gear and he's actually growing our gear
in there too
and his plants i mean everything coming
out of uh
duke stable is gorgeous so
off the top of my head that's what comes
to mind but um
like i said i've been listening to a lot
of your podcasts too and uh
mr bob hemphill too he's
got some very beautiful plants that he's
working with there so i imagine he would
have something of interest to
um
got to remember though we're always
going to be limited to space
um
so
anything that we pop it has to be worth
our time you know it just has to be
yeah well i mean those are two solid
choices i'm sure they but i also
i also have some of yours i have some of
your genetics too so
i have a
i want to know what
out of everything you have if you could
if you could out of everything you have
if you could share one of your strains
with everybody which strain would it be
probably the licorice mama i think i
sent you that one as well
nice yeah i think and why this one in
particular
well it's like it's two strains i made
so i'm super down with that um like
crossed together to make that one so i
can definitely get behind that one is
like my own work more so than a lot of
other ones but more importantly i was
like super super disappointed with like
the colorado durban and people because i
love licorice and people always said
that was like the licorice thing you
know like the anisee type of thing and
it just it just wasn't it was like it
was just the most generic sweet smell
i've ever had like i've literally
bought um like shitty feminized seeds
back when i was a noob and i didn't know
what i was doing like not because i was
buying feminized seeds but i was
literally just on like you know the very
beginning of my whole grow journey and
you were learning yeah and some of those
shitty feminized seeds i had had the
exact same smell as the durban just this
generic sweet smell and i just don't get
how people can get licorice from that
but i've created something that i feel
is you know very liquoricy admittedly um
you know it's it's got some gojiog in it
which is australian that's also known to
have a bit of licorice in there so i
think it's obviously probably tapping
back into that to a certain extent but
yeah it's it's very much a licorice
whereas the derby and i was like man
anyone who says this is licorice has
got quite an imagination
are we talking like a black licorice
though because i mean that's very
difficult yeah black licorice yeah and
that's what i wanted and that's and so
that was why i was a bit let down with
the durbin
ah so that one would i would be
interested to definitely look in that
yeah i think it would be a good one to
check out but um any of the raspberry
mama ones are good and all the tests
have come back like it seems to be quite
dominant so you get a lot of raspberry
in most things so
in that regard i'd say look at the mum
you like and go from there
nice nice now i am curious about this
because
i know i've heard this question it when
you're selecting for like a male your
male selection is there something that
you specifically look for
yeah like traits well i'm like you i
stress the hell out of it so it needs to
survive the gauntlet for one but um i
can't stand like auto flowering males um
because i for a while i thought that was
like the norm and then i realized i was
just stressing everything too hard
and so then i took a step back and i was
like oh okay um
but yeah there's a few little inside
tricks like duke's sharing okay i'll
share one here um which dude share with
me i hope he doesn't mind when you when
you get real serious you can start to do
some crazy stuff you know you can
get your mail you take clones of it so
you've got you know backups and whatnot
and you grow all your mails out to a
certain size and then you um like you
know get all tease the soil or whatever
the medium is out and you can actually
make judgments on it based on the size
of the root ball and stuff like that
which is not immediately apparent
otherwise
and that can be you know pretty
indicative because on females like a lot
of people think that yield is
proportional to the number of nodes on
the plant and that's not true at all
it's totally proportional to the root
mass
in most cases and so
yeah like having having a really solid
root system is something i value on a
male which i think people don't look at
at all
right
yes that too
that could be with
i think too something people don't look
at either is um
you you know starting with or using just
a more mature plant in general
is in like the males more mature
well female or male um just maturing it
you know letting it grow letting it
fill in its container just letting it
really grow and express
a lot of times people with females too
they'll
uh sex them and just straight throw them
into flower we actually do we like to
mature and we like our plants mature
before we
you know flower anything
yeah
you just get a better result much better
yeah like when they're they're naturally
kind of already transitioning to flower
because they're that mature
yeah it's just like um like him and matt
and i were talking about this the other
day
who do you think is going to make a
better mother a 15 year old girl
or a 30 year old woman
wait
yeah i mean it's it's interesting to see
i i cause a lot of people talk about
like bob hempel will loop back to that
for a second he talks about the the
four-way and it kind of brings this
point in mind like does a mother that's
really old make worse offspring than the
same cut when it was younger like does
it affect the seeds
you know i honestly i i don't know see i
there's so many um
there are so many aspects to which you
have to consider
you know
from
with each plant you know the growing
conditions
um was it stress did you use you know
new things with it like there's so many
different factors that can play into a
plant doing different things it's so
hard to pinpoint like you know to a
scientific level what caused what so
that's like tricky that's a really
tricky question i don't
i don't know but i do find that
with us here we have lavender and urkel
they're very old plants they're
extremely old we've had them
like i said i want to say around 2000 or
so
maybe longer maybe less i don't know
like i said
back then you didn't really keep
dates on stuff you just kind of hung on
to something but when those plants are
really healthy they produce beautiful
seeds so maybe it's just the factor of
whether or not you're you have a healthy
plant versus the age of the plant i
don't
know i think the the far better way to
uh to phrase that question would be like
deteriorate cuts because if if a cut has
known to deteriorated and like it the
bud you get it off at now is just
nowhere near what it used to be when you
make seeds with it at the offspring
going to be similar to like you know
they're going to have flavor profiles
similar to the deteriorated version now
or to when it was fresh and much more
fuller and you know like its original
self
yeah i think that's a really good
question and i wonder about that too i i
don't i don't know for sure like i said
there's so many factors
that go into
um
well
when you're making seeds for example
there's so many things you'd have to
look at um
you know with that particular grow
that is a really good question have you
noticed anything in particular with your
testing
no i mean i the uh the i lost the oldest
cut i had not too long ago sadly but um
oh it's i mean but even then it was only
like three and a half almost four years
i think no i think it was about three
and a half but um so i don't know if
that's really
old enough for stuff to really
deteriorate maybe it just means i've
taken care of it well so to speak but
yeah not not in that period of time
unfortunately i haven't noticed anything
yeah i mean there are times where um i
even mad and i have talked uh
well we're we'll complete a grow and
we'll be like we'll we'll ask each other
do you think maybe this is showing signs
like it has degraded at all
as far as like the flower the finished
product and there are times where we
will think yep it is it's just old and
then you'll have your next run and
you'll be like nope she's every bit as
impressive so
sometimes i i wonder if it's a per
strain thing it could be um based off of
that particular run you had
like i said there's so many factors um
but i haven't us here have we haven't
had any
particular experience where i would say
you know we've ran we've we've created
seeds with like our older cuts which we
have both the oracle and lavender even
the scdc she's older now too
most of our stuff is older at this point
um
but
as far as like
how the seeds are created um are certain
things that i have picked up on that are
different from plant to plant
but i haven't actually noticed anything
as far as like a degradation handed down
in like the offspring to the seeds
nothing like that
but i did notice uh as far as breeding
goes with our our clementine the
clementine line
um whenever we make seeds the clementine
seeds they come out every time almost
without any stripes they're just almost
like little blondies is what i would
call them little blondie seeds and
they're even kind of have a good shape
to them but they're
always super viable they pop instantly
they're fast and they're just really
strange looking seeds but they
uh you never worry about them because
they always pop and they're really fast
to pop but they just look so different
so different than the rest
so what are your tips for picking a mail
oh
um i it depends on um
it depends on the the strain to start
with um
for me i like to see a good
i like to see consistently what the
females look like um so we'll start
there first um i want to know what the
females
of that line come out looking like
before i would even consider whether i
want to even look at a male
um if matt and i are um going through
say a particular strain and we're
testing and we find um really worthy
keepers uh within those beans then we
would consider
maybe a male and that would be worth
looking for um so at that point maybe we
would and um structurally like with our
clementine male when i chose that male i
chose him
because he
came out and he actually looked like
what you would
attribute to a female plant his
structure was just super squatty
he didn't have hardly any node spacing
and i just loved him he was pretty and
he had just such a deep dark green to
his leaves he's just a beautiful
plant and i just really liked him
so for him i liked his structure
um
but with our pj mail he's a little bit
different he also has um he resembles
the appearance of a female plant
but of like the pj female so
um there's more a lot more node spacing
than say with the clementine male way
more nodes spacing on the pj mail
um but really with this one he's got a
instant smell
develop
developing resins to them already
just unique colors running all up and
down the stems and the pedials of the
plant
so him it was just about that he had a
smell and structurally he he resembled
pretty identically a female that was a
keeper for us so that was kind of why we
chose him
and those seeds themselves were they
quite old when you pop them
oh my gosh
um if so
what are germination tips you have
oh my gosh um well on the the clementine
male that one was hunted a while ago
and i'm not really sure how old those
beans were
i'd i would i would have to ask mad but
on the pj beans i'd say they were
probably about eight years old i want to
say maybe older that's getting on
eight but um
yeah they were a pain in the ass they
didn't the pj beans didn't even want to
pop for us we had a real hard time with
them and i'm not a fan i honestly i
struggle with the beans if they don't
want to pop they just irritate me
usually mad deals with the beans i do
cuts
they tend to agree with me more
um but on the beans there's a couple of
different things you know some people
like to just so like soak them in a dark
space in a cup see if they
a tap root will show um
some people like the whole paper towel
method
you know moisture and paper towel
um we usually will use uh if we think
they're gonna be a tough crack we'll
usually soak them um it depends what
your issue is um
you can scuff them sometimes that helps
them pop there's so many different
things that you can try um
there's the the
brelic acid i haven't used it yet but um
that's only because i haven't dealt with
a bean yet that we couldn't eventually
get open
but i do have some
um yeah usually you can
usually you can help them along in some
way shape or form so we haven't really
encountered a problem to where we
couldn't get at least um some beans from
a strain to pop but
the pjs were a little bit trickier but
we obviously were still able to select
from those which was good
so
i just wanted to loop back to one of
your previous breeding projects i was
interested in whatever happened to the
space queen male you guys were using in
the evil queen project
um we killed him
he just didn't make that oh he just
didn't
no we didn't um
everybody really did people still ask us
about that to this day we still even
have some of the beans like if people
ask i'll totally give them
um we do have some and there is some
really interesting things to be seen in
there but
mad mad and i both we hate anything that
has any tendency to show instability we
just
it's you know nobody you just that's
like the most dreaded thing when you're
hunting through seeds and you're you
know you have that feeling or you're
concerned about finding something that's
not stable
so when it came to those it just we
didn't trust them and it just left us
uneasy and for that reason we knew we
could find a much better male so we
killed him
yeah okay good answer
and so
i feel bad saying it but it's true yeah
well i mean
do you think it came from maybe more of
the the chem side of the genetics or was
it more the space queen side of things
i i would say space queen side it had a
oh it was a that was a stinky plant um
and it also too it had that that that
pineapple expression that was really
like known to be on the space space
queen side of things
but like i said that one wasn't even one
that really interested me uh that was
that was one that was really more of
mad's thing um
back then
when he had acquired the urkel and the
lavender the reason why he even got into
the whole space queen side of things is
because
he was really interested in proving that
there is a difference between the urkel
and lavender and he thought that that
space queen
uh male might be the way to go about
doing that by showing the different
expressions in the um
you know in the
in the seeds that we created from both
parents
uh so that was his main reason for that
and then once he pretty much
got the answer he was looking for
and he was pretty much done with that
mail we just decided to move on to
something else and
that's when we stepped into the tdub and
the um the pj project originally
so yeah we had just decided to move on
to something so we wanted something
obviously more stable is what we were
looking for
so
in the past madd has hinted that he
thinks tdub might have somehow found its
way into the creation of tangi i've
spoken to a few other people about these
quite credible sources and they say
they're not so sure that's the case what
do you think on that one
well
um of course i have an opinion um i
don't think i'll share
um
yeah i look i
i gotta be honest um
on this particular topic i kind of hate
this topic
um this was a topic that was actually
brought to i'll say matt it was his
brought to his attention by
a few different people um very credible
sources some breeders too in the
industry um
this wasn't something that was a thought
of his this was something that was
brought to him uh by outside sources
originally so that's where this whole
entire thing started up
um up with to begin with um
i think basically
uh i like i have my opinion he has his
other people have theirs
basically
him and i
all that we ever ask of anybody is if
anybody uses ours or anybody else's
genetics for that matter or their
strains
i just ask that people are honest and
say they say what they use and we try to
live by that the best that we can too
which is another reason why we don't
work any we try not to really work
anything outside because if you're only
working
what you have then you know you can
trust it and you're not being dishonest
about what you have um
but as far as him
you know kind of creating that topic
that didn't come from him that was
brought to him by other people
um as far as his opinion on that i would
i would i would much prefer you ask him
about that
um but we just don't like to start we're
not looking to start any trouble in the
industry for sure and um
just basically i just think everybody
could benefit from honesty and uh it
would it would it's in the best interest
too of the genetics too
and everybody just being honest about
what they're working and
you know saying
what it is is actually what it is
that's all i really have to say on that
okay and so just on a topic you
mentioned then about like not really
bringing in new stuff do you ever feel
like it's self-limiting
limiting maybe if um
i guess if if our entire game plan was
based off of just looking to pump out as
many strains as we possibly could
um if we were on the whole you know
strain of the month
what's everybody interested in in the
moment
yeah then i would say maybe so maybe we
were limiting ourselves but i'd like to
see more that we just have um
some guidelines that we've set for
ourselves it's kind of like a set of
standards
it kind of keeps us
i don't know it keeps us kind of working
staying away from what everybody else is
doing
um
and you know at least we're working
things that we have true confidence in
is how we both look at it and we're not
opposed to bringing
bringing things in um it just has to be
really worth bringing in to even
bother i guess i would say so
again like you you have to give up all
your time and energy to keep these
plants alive so it's really got to be
worth giving your time and energy to to
keep it alive in your stable so
you know i would say we don't limit
ourselves we just have really high
standards
and so like with that being said about
the willingness to bring in something if
it was worthy is there anything that's
caught your eye and you're like oh that
might be one of the things
well i can't say a particular strain um
like not not as a particular strain but
i have told mad one of the things that i
would like to really start looking for
is a really good cbd strain
um because for me
i've actually been getting into some
really awesome cbd concentrates lately
and they work really good um i have
fibromyalgia and it just really does it
helps
with all my aches and pains and just
that overall
shitty feeling that you can have
throughout the day and it just works
really good so as far as bringing in
something new
that's my personal interest i'm i want
to find some like a really good cbd
strain that i like
so again if it's something that we're
going to bring in it's got to be
something that either he has an interest
in or i have an interest in or it's
going to benefit him and i in some way
because that's like everything we work
is based off of that to start with you
know everything else is just like a a
bonus i guess
and so what would be one of the current
males you'd love to cross to a cbd
strain because that was one of the
questions i had like what would be the
first cbd offering you guys would want
to do
oh gosh um
well i think for i think if you were to
ask i'm just saying based off of my own
personal experience but i think if you
were to ask mad
i think if him and i were to to have a
discussion on we were to throw a mail in
there that we have a lot of both have a
lot of confidence in i would say we both
have a lot of confidence in our
clementine mail
so i would say definitely can't go wrong
there
plus he's he seems to be doing pretty
all right in um
in all the other projects that we've
used him in so far
and so how do you like to test your new
lines do you just like to you know pop
10 seeds pop how many seeds you give
some to your friends like what's your
general kind of way of doing that
well
well we of course we like to grow
everything we like to always test our
own stuff
it's really hard to try to form an
opinion about a strain based off of just
what you're seeing coming from other
people
we also though
keep in mind we love to see
other growers growing our genetics too
because that gives you
um some solid insight as to what the
everyday person who grows your beans are
going to get it you know what i mean it
gives and it also gives that kind of
perspective to the to the public to see
what you know a random person who buys
your beans gets and this is what they
were able to get when they popped your
beans and they grow them so we also like
that so
we do put our beans out there
um
oh there's a lot of people who grow our
genetics and we don't really know them
um
there's uh a lot of people who actually
appear to rep us
quite aggressively online and i do like
to put out there like believe it or not
we met them online we that's the only
way we know them is because they've
acquired our genetics which is really
cool
because all the representation of us is
basically just what they have come
across on their own
so we do
we both have tried to spend a little bit
of time
uh we asked that our growers you know
tag us in
like our own genetics that they've grown
so we can repost them and show people
like this is what the general public is
also getting with our genetics so we
find that to be helpful but
we um
we have uh some personal friends too we
share with but we like to test all of
our own stuff first first and foremost
that's how we do it
so just referencing social media i've
noticed that since we first chatted to
matt over a year ago your guys social
media presence definitely ramped up was
that intentional and do you think it's
possible to survive without a strong
social media presence as a breeder
you know i do um i do think it's
possible to survive without social media
it's harder because a lot of people like
to have that contact with you
i think that's one of the things that
matt offers that a lot of people don't
um it's really cool he's will he'll
he'll talk to anybody he and he tries to
answer everybody uh in fact i personally
i feel like people get more time from
him than i do believe it or not
he does i mean i honestly i have such
respect for it because
a lot of um a lot of growers something
that you know if you ever ask them
they'll tell you
they will message breeders over and over
and over again and nobody will get back
to him most of time they get blocked
so i do i love the fact that mad will he
will
sit down and he will
give lengthy responses he will answer
anybody's questions um
so i do i think that's awesome that he
does that and i think that's one of the
things that he does very different from
a lot of other breeders out there um
[Music]
just the fact that he allows access to
himself i think is big
but i do think you can survive without
social media but it would be a whole lot
harder i really do
how do you feel about the way female
growers and breeders are perceived
within the industry in general
um you know you don't actually see a lot
of representation of women in the
industry uh
i think there's probably a whole lot
more women growing
women growers and breeding than than we
know about
and i
don't wanna i don't wanna say something
that's gonna be offensive but i think it
has something to do with
i think that there's a lot of obviously
it's like a male dominated industry
um
but there's there's something uh about
the way it's changed a little bit
because of social media
you have um
i don't know it
kind of like ordinary people feel more
like um kind of like somebody famous i'd
say and i think they really enjoy that
attention
and i think that um with the female
growers you're not really going to see
that as much i think they just kind of
do their thing and
i don't know i i i i you just don't see
them out
like that but when you do the only women
you really see heavily in the industry
are usually
dressed up and you know
meant to be handing out dabs in a tight
tank top so
and i don't think that's like a fair
representation of women in the industry
but that's basically what i've seen from
my perspective
one of the criticisms put forward that
i've heard at least is that there's
seemingly like a dichotomy within the
mind of the average male smoker within
the cannabis community in that
uh you know
a lot of guys
within this criticism will supposedly be
like yeah we want more female breeders
that would be awesome you know i'd love
female britain whatever like that whole
type of thing
but um but then as soon as a girl puts
herself forward as maybe something like
that the immediate assumption is oh
you're just [__] around in your
boyfriend's grow
yes yes yes
do you feel like that's quite an
accurate representation of the way women
are met in the industry
yeah i think um there's a lot of i think
there's probably a lot of
men in the industry that probably have
that perspective that they don't want to
share this does that make sense i don't
want to share this i don't want to share
this with
when i'm with women i don't know what it
is
men and women
we think very different um it's not a
knock i think that
we work the way we work because this is
how it this is the balance of things i
really think that um
but i think too
when you've got something that they've
started out with and they were used to
it like being theirs i don't know that
they're so confident or comfortable
sharing that per se and let's face it
you do not have to be a dude to grow
good weed you just don't any think of it
like this when like i was when i was a
kid
um all the men in my family were all
either in the military or something most
of them were away most of the time
women they ran [__] they ran the entire
house they cooked dinners men went to
work they came home at the end of the
day they had dinner they went to bed and
they did the work process all over the
only time you saw them was on the
weekends when they were doing a couple
of things around the house but let's
face it women ran stuff they cooked
dinners my grandma she had two vegetable
gardens in the backyard and my grandpa
did tend to him on the weekend but my
grandma ran stuff
all the time you know it's like that's
kind of i think we forget how much um
hands-on women really do have just in
everyday stuff all the time
so i think they forget that
yeah without a doubt and so
this is maybe like a harder one to
answer because it's just so blunt to the
point but do you feel it's harder for
women to gain recognition or respect
within the general industry as it is
yes i can tell you for a fact i know it
is um
uh prove a point
um
if you just to prove a point open up my
instagram page and then open up mad's
instagram page and look at our followers
i'm just saying if something happened to
mad all you guys would be [__] because
if you don't have contact with me how
are you going to get our beans you know
what i mean like seriously if something
happens to him you guys need to be able
to talk to me
so yeah i i do see that i noticed that
some some people have no problems but
there's a lot there's like a a vast
difference between um
the people that view me and him as
equals despite how many people he tells
he's like i'm right by his side i
every bit i need him as much as he needs
me this is how we work together we're
100 a team
but you can see it like clearly um just
in the respect that we're given not by
everybody i'm not singling out everybody
but you can clearly see it there is a
difference
yeah
and so
what i was just going to say was one of
the the counter acting views that i had
seen to this discussion was that
as we mentioned earlier it could
fundamentally also just be a little bit
of a under representation problem
um and what i think is meant by that is
the fact like if you were to say for
example look at
how many male breeders there are and of
those male breeders how many have gone
on to become super successful not just
in the fact that maybe they're known but
they've actually got something which is
really well regarded and it kind of
stands the test of time or whatever
right if you set the bar that high it's
only actually you know like a you know
maybe 20 30 people who really meet that
criteria
and so you kind of get what i mean when
i say there's an under representation
like maybe
we just need more females contributing
stuff and then we would easily see stuff
rise to the top because it is the cream
of the crop type of thing
yeah i do think um
i think that is
that's actually probably um again that's
one of those factors like i was just
saying there's lots of factors that
contribute to why things are the way
they are and
again you have to remember too the seed
industry the way it kind of started up
was
mainly because you had legalization
popping up in the states you know here
and there and you had people who were
ordering seeds overseas and whatnot but
that's kind of what started the market
and
um
you don't it was guys it was it was the
men in the industry that were doing it
and a lot of it was again social media
has really kind of uh kicked that into
like a much higher gear
and it was men that um it's the guys
that were doing a lot of these little
internet deals and trading and sharing
and
swapping genetics and that is what built
this industry so at the same time i can
understand that and that is why you
probably don't see
a lot of female faces
you know behind genetics and breeding
but i do think you will see more yeah
like what i was just going to say with
that being said you just recently
partook in your first breeding panel
over the weekend i believe
yeah that was interesting that was
really interesting so how did that go
for you what was the experience like
cold
it was actually
it was actually cold that day no it was
nice um
i got to meet two other ladies in the
industry both very nice and smart ladies
elena she's with the green fire genetics
she's
she's young
um but she's really sweet she's really
nice and she's coming up in the industry
i
i spent a little bit of time hanging out
with her she's a really cool chick um
people should check her out
and then the other lady on the panel her
name is
gingerdewer now that lady right there is
an amazing example for
just growers honestly
um
have you have you looked into her at all
did you happen to see anything i was
about to say you sent me the name just
earlier and i was gonna look into it but
i haven't got a chance to just yet
yeah
um both of them
um elena is
more familiar with
her yeah she's more into like our side
of things you know like the
you know
breeding and whatnot and
um ginger is has like this massive
commercial
background and she just has some of the
coolest stories and
seriously the knowledge in that girl's
mind
puts most of the people to shame um
she's just
she's an amazing example
of a grower
on so many levels like if you can track
down an interview with a female
she would be i'm mind blowing i i think
it would be a killer interview to listen
to and she has so much knowledge
it honestly like i have a little bit of
a crush on her i gotta be honest she's
so just she's amazing she's a mother of
five for starters
um she's also like into painting and
stuff i've done a little bit of like
research on both of the ladies i thought
they were both very nice and interesting
but
she's um got an agricultural background
and she's been into like growing pot
since a youngster so her story is really
cool
and she just the knowledge in her mind
is just
it's insane i think if you could track
down an interview with somebody
she would be a cool one to get
i'll uh send her information
yeah
so i'm gonna stretch your mind back now
to the emerald cup i asked madden smelly
this question but i wasn't able to ask
you in the interview did anyone bring
you anything at the cup that you were
really surprised by
yeah actually um i do remember this
question um
i i got i'm gonna be honest here so
first i'm going to say
to have that much cannabis in that small
of a space i would have honestly thought
i would see a much higher grade and
a wider range of really killer weed i
really am surprised that i didn't
however
there were people that brought us some
really killer examples um there were a
lot of people who
i don't want to sound i don't want to
sound like that but i'm going to just
say it a lot of people brought us um
samples of
our genetics so basically they had got
our beans popped them grew them and
brought us finished product and that was
some of the most impressive that we did
see um
one other really kick-ass example of
some solid smoke i not only saw but i
was lucky enough to smoke um was from
duke diamond and it was his um his
lavender
that was on point just saying that was
really killer weed but there was there
was um
there was a a good five or six people
that brought me in mad personal samples
of their own grows and
there was some really well-grown
cannabis in there some outdoor indoor i
mean just really nicely grown
nice
well done product but i was a little bit
underwhelmed at how much cannabis was
there
considering there i i would have thought
there would have been a much wider
selection
and a higher basically a better grade of
cannabis
just to be honest
and so i i know that you're quite uh
selective with what you smoke however if
someone like you know whether it's
they've grown it or whatever if you've
got some stuff not grown by you but it's
some stuff from your
stable so to speak you know it's one of
your guys creations does that kind of
make you more open to trying it or it's
still just like it just has to be
growing well
um no i'll if look if we're in a
situation and somebody passes me a joint
and it's lit i'm gonna smoke it
i will hit it
i'm gonna hit it dude i'm i'm a stoner
i'm just i'm being honest i'm gonna at
least give it a shot you know um if it
makes my throat burn and it makes me
choke i'm less likely to take it back
and hit it again so
yeah i'm that diva like i will i'll i
will bypass it but i'm always gonna at
least give it a try
um i mean unless i'm sick of course if
i'm sick i'd probably just altogether
pass but
no i'm not like that i'm gonna if
somebody tells me it's good i'm always
going to give it a shot people
people send us stuff and give us stuff
all the time
when we first really got into this one
of the reasons why we ended up breeding
cannabis seeds in the first place was
i can't tell you we had what we felt
like we had a few really solid keepers
you know at the time i think we had
urkel lavender and scdc were our main
keepers and
um every time somebody would come to us
and tell us oh i got the best strain you
got to try it it's so good so we would
start there they'd give us some samples
of some dry product and we'd smoke it
always disappointed so then we're like
maybe it's just needs to be grown proper
so then we would go about it that way
you acquire a cut or whatever seeds
however grow it out finish it no it just
wasn't uh no just wasn't wasn't good
enough to be considered a keeper like in
our stable and that is
another reason as to why
we do keep um i mean we have we have a
lot of plants don't get me wrong but
that's why you do see us work with a
very limited selection because we have
like a set standard that we go by
and if it can't stay i mean if we can't
hang on to it
if it doesn't stay in there for at least
four years we're probably not even gonna
bother with it
yeah okay
you know
and so
what do you
think is kind of your favorite aspect of
breeding
um
i honestly enjoy just the selection
process uh
cannabis it's it's crazy because you
never real you'd ever really know what
you're gonna get you kind of just have
to pop the beans and start looking
and that's what's really cool um you put
these two parents together and you might
find like less variety
amongst these beans while you put these
other two parents together and you might
have a lot of variety but the only way
to know what you're going to get is to
just grow them out and look and that's
like one of my favorite parts is
pop in the beans and then
they're really not that fun until they
get to a certain size for me but once
they hit a certain age and then they
start to mature and sexy and whatnot
that's when they really become fun
because they start to at least show you
something
i personally too
as far as like selection and keepers and
deciding
i don't like to decide on necessarily a
seedling i would prefer to make my
decision on
a taken cut that we've grown multiple
times to give it a fair representation
because they always grow different as a
cut always grows different
than a seedling
so that's kind of one of those things i
like to do too
it's interesting you mentioned that
because i remember
again looping back to the bob hempfield
chat he he referenced that because we
were talking about how you know like
over long periods of time cuts degrades
and he was saying yeah like how many
times have you seen like a plant perform
well on the first time and then it's
just [__] after and i actually thought
about it over you know the period
afterwards and i was like yeah actually
i have seen that once or twice like you
know
and i i guess i i didn't really
understand why it was happening at the
time but i just figured like maybe i
grew up well the first time and then
just whatever afterwards but
it's also interesting how there's the
opposite to be said as well you know
like how there's i've got more examples
that come to mind of stuff that gets
better you know like the older the clone
is like i think it's a pretty widely
held consensus that um the flowering
time drops a bit you know once the clone
gets like you know maybe a year or so
old like it you know over the course of
that time it drops a little bit like do
you feel that's the case
yeah i do
yeah i mean it does it change it change
by taking the cut and flowering out cuts
you do have a more true example of what
you're gonna get especially you have to
look at it from the perspective of
if you're flowering out your seedling
and you're trying to make all your
decisions based on what that seedling
does you're not going to have a very
good representation because the cut
always it always behaves different it's
more true to what you're going to get if
you continue to continue to grow that
cut you see what i'm saying because
you're going to grow a cut so
i just think you get a better
representation by flowering your cuts
than you do making a judgment call based
off of your seedling
and the cuts do i do find that they what
they call it a little bit of a loss in
hybrid vigor is what they that they
would attribute it to
um not all of them are that way but i do
find um the cuts grow much more
consistently so as far as structure i i
much more prefer
a cut because seedlings tend to grow
kind of crazy in my opinion
but i do think there's a bit of weight i
do think you do suffer a bit of weight
loss but you can make that up like i was
saying earlier by just um like i said i
like to have a more mature plant i
prefer to flower a more mature plant an
older plant one that's been
kind of shaped and
you know one that's basically been
influenced by me for a set amount of
time
yeah totally
so
how does the growing trend within the
california seed to the sorry the
californian scene
to grow from seed affect your breeding
does that make you guys want to try to
you know get something that's really
vigorous out the gate or do you still
think it's it's rather a small
trend so to speak at the moment
you know
i i don't i don't know i don't want to
sound like an [__] but we don't
we don't we're not aiming and everything
that we do we're not we're not basing it
on what you would say the market is
asking for or what the general public is
asking for and we're not we don't do
that because there's plenty of people
out there doing that
um
what we're trying to do was more um
we got started for ourselves really just
looking to make a real solid different
forms of medications that can target
different things about your illnesses
some that are better for daytime some
that are better for nighttime but
something that you always have to go to
that's always going to work so i i mean
the basis behind why we do it is very
different from why most people are
breeding
um cannabis seeds in the first place so
yeah we're not really looking to just
please like the marketplace um
so i think that's different our
priorities i guess are a little bit
different so maybe that's what it is
but our main goal is always just
basically
really good solid medicine
something that you can go back to
hopefully year after year but will still
offer you
that solid medicinal value you hope it
has but also stability because you can
breed all the flavor you want but you
got to have some kind of stability and
that's what we're hoping for we're
hoping to kind of just have an
across-the-board
awesome strains for people to have
access to and hopefully not too
expensive because you want everyone to
have access to them too
so we're aiming for stability
good solid meds and something that you
can turn to year after year so
you know
that's our goal
so that brings up a good question
submitted by another one of our patreon
fans
they say i'd love to know
what uh
what strains these breeders consider to
be the most medicinal like what is a
medicinal quality to you because
obviously it's very subjective so yeah
what to you is medicinal well i think it
really depends on what your
obviously would be symptoms that you're
trying to target um
for me
i would say like if i'm gonna if i'm
gonna grab any strain that we have in
our in our arsenal to basically smoke
to just overall take care of any issue i
may have
for what we have i would aim i would go
for the lavender every single time
um and the reason i say that is because
that particular strain just gives you uh
just an overall calming effect
throughout your entire body head to toe
and it just does something to like your
stomach it just soothes it makes
everything calm it has the ability to
target migraine headaches so it's just
overall
a solid strain for your entire body so
if you're not really like sure what
you're aiming for if you're just trying
to touch on different
um symptoms that you may have for a
range of ailments i would say lavender
but you know your reasons might be
different you might want something just
to help um like you might want to take a
couple hits and lay down and be able to
go to sleep easy
um i would you know every and everyone
is different too so it's like a
tolerance thing um our clementine
it
um
if i haven't been smoking a whole lot
and i smoked that that one can actually
make me quite paranoid
i mean like i'm not like really paranoid
uh and makes me stupid just really
i can't think i can't focus it's just
makes me a mess so that's not a good one
for me if i'm like feeling a little
paranoid
but everybody's different um i'd like to
say that every strain we have offers
some kind of medicinal value to it
otherwise we wouldn't even have it
so
it kind of brings me to i mean not not
the best segue but i'm just gonna run
with it anyway in terms of your guys
offerings
are you gonna have a really wild sativa
offering ever
hopefully
where would you even start like what
type of genetics would you think about
like you know do you have anything in
the in the you know the treasure chest
which might be able to fill that
category or you'd have to find that
first
oh my god no we actually we do we have
so many beans it's ridiculous like we
have so much stuff
it'll probably sit there forever and
never get touched would be my guess um
we have a lot of things we have a lot of
stuff that we've even created that have
never even
seen the light of day um
we've got stuff like that but we also
have a lot um a pretty wide collection
of beans that you know we back in the
day we're collecting
um you know kind of to touch on
something that you brought up about
limiting yourself or bringing things in
from the outside um that kind of
actually plays a role in why we do stay
within a lot of our own lines because
we did there was a point in time early
on where we were we were searching beans
all the time and that was the worst
feeling ever is when you're going in
there to check your plants that you need
to be able to rely on and they are you
know if they're freaking out because you
popped
genes that are just not stable and
um that's what that's kind of where we
came to the conclusion we were going to
start creating our own
genetics because it was becoming costly
you're popping beans
you're thinking you're getting one thing
and you end up getting something i don't
even know and usually it
just the risk of pollinating other stuff
in your room because you have a herme or
a freak
it just totally was off-putting and we
decided that's when we would just start
playing within our own lines and we've
slowly expanded on top of that and like
i said we do we bring things in and
there's things that we do we don't
openly talk about uh we learn that the
hard way
um
but now we've got stuff to play with
like i said we even our clementine
that one in particular we have we've got
f2s f3s and f4s just sitting
um we've dug through the f2s and f3s a
little bit but the f4s have been
completely untouched so we have some of
those to play around with if we wanted
to but we also have some some blueberry
lines um there's other things we just
it's just all a matter of time and what
project you actually want to work on at
the time and what you have the time and
space for
yeah so i mean if we just touch back on
that evil queen i mentioned before it
had some chem genetics in it kim's
obviously a pretty focal point of this
show pops up a lot
would you guys ever want to try to get
it and use it like have you tried what
you think was real chem and did you find
it medicinal for example
um
well you know we actually
that that the one that you're talking
about it was uh i want to say it was the
canton
kim by kim by cindy 99 i want to say and
we actually had that particular
that female that keeper female we had we
kept it for i want to say five or six
years at the time
um and don't get me wrong it visually
speaking it was a keeper in so many
people's gardens
um and it like it was really uh it was
really good for taking pictures of is
beautiful and it had so many resins but
the one thing that we both felt like it
just kind of lacked for us was the
flavor side of things um
and we also too we just couldn't we we
found we weren't able to incorporate it
with anything that would
um bring out that flavor but also offer
that stability that we were looking for
which is why we discontinued that
particular
um that keeper female that we were
working with at the time
but
from that particular line
we were gifted
beans so we still have beans from that
particular strain the
the kim dog by cindy 99 so if we ever
wanted to revisit we have we do have
some things to work through
um but like i said it's just really if
it's not something i want to work or if
it's not something mad wants to work
it's just gonna sit there for a while
and it's not going to get touched
so
the deep crippler is you know a line i
don't think many people have heard about
how come you guys haven't you know put
it out there as much as the other stuff
and do you plan to work it further
forward
you know um we actually have talked
about that um
everybody does everybody who has had
contact with that particular strain
really did like it
um it never
i don't know i didn't i didn't really
have um
a particular love for it
um
it just wasn't one that i don't know
people love the scdc which would be the
mother that we used at the time to
create those seeds but um
other than being super like beautiful in
pictures and like uh just a mass resin
producer like i don't i don't love her
we keep her because mad loves her so
she's not really my particular passion
you know do you know who i felt one
uh the scdc yeah
oh
um i'll leave that one you can ask matt
about that one
that's like a debatable
the scdc is a debatable i do believe we
are the only ones that hold it
yeah okay like a wink wink
no i i'm not i'm pretty sure seriously
like i have you seen anybody else that
has it no i i i initially thought that
you guys made it
well i'll let mad discuss that one with
you
that plant isn't
i just don't love her
that's one of his babies not mine
yeah
so
who are some breeders out there who you
would love to collaborate with
um
oh god why would you ask me that
i don't know i guess the question okay
the question that i would ask you is
what breeders would love to collaborate
with us
well i guess firstly you'd wanna the
devil's in the details right so we're
gonna assume that they're gonna bring
one parent to the table and you'll bring
the other
i have a feeling i know what parent they
would like us to bring to the table so
yeah i will i if i were you i would i
would push to bring the mail
jazz it up there you go
so who are you suggesting for us
well i mean it depends what if you just
it's all about what you want really like
i mean if i had to think like
i want you guys to do something
different so i'd just pick someone
really different just so that no matter
what they picked it would result in
something really different
yeah completely different
yeah or like something that's really
well regarded and super sativa and just
see how it goes like you know something
like that
so i'm a sucker for sativas you know
yeah
um
i don't know i don't really know how to
answer that one
well i guess the other way i would think
about it is
who is
is there a strain out there where you
look at it and you're like man i just
love to cross the t-dub to that and you
know if it's yes then you know who was
the breeder of it
you know
gosh i wish that was one you would have
maybe sent me in advance because i know
there are some out there
off the top of my head though that's a
little tricky um
i know there's a couple of strains out
there because i've specifically talked
about them but i just can't think off
the top of my head
like i said
if we were to work with somebody
um the first and foremost important
thing we would want to work with
somebody obviously that has a good
reputation
um and we're always looking
for honesty um again i think that's
something that
it's a bit of a problem i think
i don't know i i think we have uh
there's a problem in the industry of not
calling things what they actually are
and i wish people would just call things
what they actually are
um
so
just like just serve a hot one up for us
oh yeah right
[Laughter]
like i just do i think that i think
there's probably a lot less strains out
there in existence than we think there's
just a lot of names there's like you've
got one strain and it actually has like
seven names you know everybody thinks
it's seven different strains but in
reality it's not it's really just one i
wish there was a lot less of that
basically totally
um so yeah as far as working with
anybody collaborating i don't know
specifically not anybody in particular
i think we're just so busy doing our own
thing um
plants really believe it or not are not
our first priority our first priority
always is our our child so
um
she's 17 now so hopefully soon she'll be
going off to college if that's the case
we'll have a lot more time for other
things but
as of right now plants kind of come
secondary
yeah it's a good good life decision
and so
a question submitted by another one of
our fans is
what to you is the difference between a
breeder and a pollen chucker
that's a great question huh
yeah
i probably the definition would be my
guess
um
i guess it depends who you actually to
no seriously i guess it really depends
on who you talk to
if i'm giving like my opinion based on
what i think the like the industry
standard would be
i would say a breeder is somebody who um
has a more
solid knowledgeable understanding for
the strains that they're working
um and have some of maybe their own
stuff
um aren't just crossing other people's
works and you know this
going and getting this female from this
breeder and this male from this breeder
and throwing them together i would think
that's more of a pollen chucker
i don't know i think it depends who you
talk to
no matter what breeding's breeding it's
pollinating a plant and creating seeds
anyone technically can do it it's common
sense it's pretty
it's a pretty basic thing anyone can do
it but doesn't mean anyone can do it
well
um
but i do i think it's just um
i think it's more of a
probably the
the the standards behind the person
doing the work because i think that an
actual a true breeder
i think they probably really do care
more about what they're doing and have a
a solid love for what they're doing is
where a pawn chucker in my opinion is
probably doing it for the cash and just
to pump out strains to make money that
would be
how i would view the difference
does that make sense
yeah of course
and so
what do you think of the various land
races because i mean obviously
clementine comes from afghani origin so
maybe that's something that's got a soft
spot for you but if you you know had to
pick a land race that you know you were
more fond of which would be the more
favorites for you
oh you know
i
i don't know i would say obviously i
love our i love our clementine it's
just an awesome afghani plant i love it
the high from her is just amazing um
again for me
i
put it in front of me i'll smoke it i'm
either i either love it or i don't you
know um
i think
for me to actually say that i like a
particular strain or i have like a
really solid love for something i do i i
would have to sample it and i'd have to
i'd have to be able to um at least try
it i that's the only way i can really
give an opinion but um
as far as ours i just love
that the clementine that we have that's
why we you know we continue to work it
and
like i said why we even talk about maybe
digging even deeper into those f-4s that
we have might be something interesting
to look at
yeah well i mean would you ever consider
trying it maybe not necessarily a pure
clementine line but just trying to maybe
create a more indica type of tangy thing
because that's the thing which i found
unique is that a lot of the more orangey
strains are not afghani by nature and so
um i think it would be really
interesting to have like you know like
an offering that's basically like you
know a very indica very medicinal you
know trying to gun to be a very orangey
type of thing is that something that
interests you or you think the fad's
over
you know
i honestly think that pot strains as far
as like the fads of flavors and coming
and going i think it's going to be just
like
probably just like music and clothing
you know from the 80s to the 90s we're
gonna recycle through all the ugly [__]
all over again
that's my guess
you know like we'll like something now
and then give it about 10 years and
we'll bring it back and everybody walk
like it's new again um that's just the
nature of it i think that's what will
happen
um i don't know like i do don't get me
wrong i like good flavors in my cannabis
but there has to be a balance to it
you know it can't just be good flavor
it's got to it's got to do more than
that it's got to do more than offer a
good flavor it's got a gotta get i'm
sorry it's got to get me high
so
this one's a little left of field but i
really want to know the answer to this
would you guys ever consider doing urcle
or lavender s ones
no
everybody asks that and everybody says
why not
the question is is why
well he i to i want to really play
devil's advocate here if someone else
came out and they started doing it and
their cuts were real so you knew it was
happening would that affect your
decision at all
nope um actually doesn't i believe csi
doesn't he as in he asked one is urkel
rats no you're one step ahead of me
oh i'm sorry that's all good
yeah no okay he definitely yeah he
definitely does do that and the mendo
perps as well which is cool because i
mean i think there's some people out
there who are looking for that but to me
it raises the next question is
do you think it's possible to find
something as good or better than the
mother in an s1 and if so is that an
influencing factor in your decision not
to do it
well um first i would say there's a
reason why we don't we don't do the
whole s1 thing we don't believe in it
you know it's your
i know on some levels you say part of
like the advancement in society is
technology and whatnot and we're always
manipulating things you know so people
die later on in life and all this stuff
but as far as messing with genetics um
matt and i aren't fans of it um
just not um and i would say as far as s
wanting the lavender or the urkel if it
was that simple as just s won it you'll
find something so much better than why
hasn't it been done and why isn't it
talked about all the time
and if it were that simple why do
breeders that have also supposedly the
oracle cut
ask mad for it regularly i so those are
the kinds of questions that i ask myself
um
so no s ones won't i don't ever see them
happening not with us um
and i don't think it's as simple as just
s1 and you'll find something better
because if that were the case it would
have been done already
yeah so i'm actually of the opposite
mindset of it i i've yet to see a single
s1 which is as good as the parent
yeah see and i but you know some people
ask too um
do you do you ever find where uh the
strains that you created come out better
than like the keeper mother and i'm like
yes otherwise we wouldn't bother uh
create you know otherwise we wouldn't
bother
you know it's a different obviously it's
better but it's a different better it's
different than the mother um but i do
think there's if it did come out if it
was something as good or better then
people would do it all the time and they
would do it with everything and then
there would be no need for regular seeds
i would think
so yeah i gotta i gotta say no to the s1
thing if it were that simple to find
something so much better and it were
that that much easier i would think it
would have already been done by now
and does that extend to just feminize in
general like would you do femme crosses
or just now
no we we we um you know like i said i've
learned from mad so
based off of his um
like i said he's he's got a really he's
got a mad brain
he um the amount of knowledge he has
taken in when it comes to cannabis is
insane
it's just like nothing i've ever seen
before and um he has a solid belief on
why he doesn't believe in it why he does
like regular seeds and
he's made his argument with me and i can
i can i can agree with that and i you
know i i can look at it too even with
like people and genetics i mean i really
wouldn't want to do that with my kids so
you know kind of the same thing
yeah
so
i wanted to ask you a question that i
asked matt in the initial interview i
did with him
how do you feel about granddaddy purple
seeing as it's kind of like the watered
down urcle
um
you know i
i guess i don't really have much of an
opinion either way um i was actually
smoking some some concentrates of the
granddaddy purple um
we went to that endo x bow and mad
packed my vape pen but he didn't pack
the
the top of it so i only had the bottom
half the battery portion oh no cartridge
yeah so i'm like how am i supposed to
smoke when you only packed half of my
[__] but when we got there the one of
the seeds here now guys um ben was nice
enough to gift me
one of the little concentrate tips and
it was granddaddy purple so i got to
smoke that it was pretty all right so i
mean
no to me wasn't as wasn't nothing like
urkel
do you see any similarity or you're
skeptical on the link
it's like a like a very watered-down
mild
version maybe but it's definitely not
it's not the same as urkel it's uh
actually has
to me it had more of um
i don't know maybe more of like a
perfumey type kind of spin to it
that made it more different than the
than the urkel was for me but it
definitely it didn't the one thing i can
say is for being concentrates it didn't
even get me high
it just gave me like a really like mild
buzz
so that was kind of a disappointment but
it was just nice to have
is that a concern you have in general
because what i've heard is is that
there's just like an exponential growth
in both the demand and the supply of
these cartridge types of products and
i've heard that that's where a lot of
the shady back
back counter stuff can happen in terms
of like material getting processed that
like probably wouldn't pass or stuff
like are you concerned about that or do
you think it's all a bit of like rumor
wife's tale type stuff
well i think any time that you have
rumors you gotta take into consideration
things come from somewhere so there's
likely some truth to it
um but i think anytime you're doing
business with people you just need to do
your research
um
you know you should know what you're
getting into at least if
as far as that goes
um
like you mean as far as uh
concentrates like as far as testing and
being clean like for your bugs and yeah
what i've heard is that like
there's
a lot of bud which you know maybe does
have an issue but it just gets turned
into concentrates and then by the time
it gets down to like the type of thing
which would end up in a cartridge it's
so highly processed that you just have
no idea
like that it's been like there's like
pesticides and all that yeah yeah like
peter and stuff yeah no yeah no i'm sure
there's definite truth to that because
it had
that has to have come from somewhere i
would assume there's truth to it but um
like like i was saying i would just
assume you know um whoever you do
business with if you have somebody
you know creating those for you or
making putting your
uh making it into concentrates you
should you should probably know where
you're getting your your medicine from
at least have an idea
uh once which is also one of the reasons
why mad and i like to um
smoke our own
you don't have to worry about it
do you think there's a certain negative
element in the way that there's this
separation from the plant in that you
can just get this cartridge and it's so
removed from the flower
that it leads to the situation where you
get these crazy you know possibly
adulterants in there whereas if everyone
was just still sticking with flour
arguably it's more medicinal and you're
more likely to spot any you know visual
issues things like that
yeah and i actually do i have even
noticed um
you know concentrates they say
concentrates are stronger but i've even
noticed sometimes
um
a difference from say
if you were to take this
urkel
flower smoke it and then compare it to
the same concentrates made from it i
noticed there is like a difference in
the way my body like
reacts to that even if it's the same
strain
um
i don't know i do feel like um
i feel like i do have a more true
feeling fro of a stone when i smoke a
actual flower versus concentrate i get i
feel like it gives me a better um
i don't know like i have a better feel
of that particular strain if i smoke it
in flour versus concentrates
okay
i definitely agree with that one myself
and so
i found a forum post many years ago i
think it was 2011 or something and it
said that like it reckons it had the
genetics listed for the tripoli wicked
and the purple jackie have you guys
tried to keep that under wraps
no no
any any
anything that you can find like any any
records of when we are online it should
be fully accessible to anybody that
wants to see i um
we've always been honest about what we
worked from when we originally first got
um the mail that we worked in those
lines um that was it was a male that was
gifted to us i know mads told this story
before um
it was uh like all the names were always
left out so it just made me wonder like
do you intentionally not want to reveal
the lineage of certain things or
no like on on which one in particular
which which form is this that we're
speaking of is it was it who's post
there's one on roll it up by a guy
called elite nuggs um he says he's a
friend of yours but you know oh yeah
yeah i remember him okay i know who
you're talking about yeah yeah and what
it what is it that he listed
specifically because i was never on roll
it up he says purple jackie is mendo
cross a purple local male
and
uh tripoli wicket is lavender across a
purple local mail
okay now there is actually like a bit of
a story to this it goes back a bit
further and i i do prefer mad tell this
story i think he's even actually covered
this when when you and him did one of
your interviews before um okay oh my god
it's like such an extensive story the
gentleman that we got our mail cut from
back then when we first worked it
there's like he contacted us and he says
i've got this cut the these are he has a
cut and
um
these beans that he had and it was uh
this the particular he got them they
were
what
labeled as urkel purple oracle beans now
this is many many years ago so
madden him formed a relationship and
there's like a whole story from there
and i believe he's told it but as far as
like dates and all that stuff that's
something that you'd have to touch on
with him because like i said this goes
back to like the beginning
when i really didn't have so much
involvement um and this was a deal
between him and this particular guy
but the reason it's listed that way is
because uh
they believed it was from the urkel the
lineage was from the purple urkel the
male that that we were gifted back when
we used it which we did we ended up
killing that male which was the one that
was used um to make the original purple
jackie beans and the original t-dub
beans
yeah okay
so if you dig back a bit further maybe
2006 or so somewhere around that area
um it's another forum that we were
actually on
there's a particular story in there and
it'll explain all of that it explains um
just in in full detail
um
where the cut itself came from that this
mail we we used in the project
the truth is is it's just basically we
had to label it as we were told it was
and all we know is what
people believe they were labeled as at
the time and it was supposed to be from
the same lineage as purple urkel itself
so
there's no secret behind the lineage
it's just nobody really knew what to
call it and at the time it was actually
labeled
the triple e male like as in e
e
and e
because back then too i don't know if
you know or how familiar you are but
there were times when they were spelling
erkel with an e does that
ring a bell to you yeah yeah i remember
that photo right okay so
uh and
um some of the research done back on
this this cup that we also were gifted
back when this project was originally
created
that's how they were labeled was as
urkel so that's where the e came from
because the original spelling on those
were spelled with an e
so if you look back further you can find
some more research it's all there to be
seen but as far as like
the full details and the story and the
names that would all be best to come
from mad because
my brain just doesn't remember all of
that stuff quite as well plus i like i
said i didn't jump in until i had to
and that was much much later when he got
so sick and um
he ended up in the hospital and he just
couldn't do all this work by himself
anymore so
yeah um
i believe he told you this story too
when you guys did your one of your
interviews like i almost positive he had
yeah yeah he did it was just um the
those details about the the urkel and
the lavender and where it all status the
parents i think we didn't get those bits
yeah and see that's too where his why
he's always had such a fascination too
for
understanding the urkel and the lavender
lineage because
he's and he he's he's positive like
he's he's sure he knows what it what it
was that created like he knows if you
ask him he knows in his mind what
created that lavender and what created
that urkel and
i just he he has an amazing mind for it
and
um
back then that's what sparked his
interest because everybody was so
insistent that all the purple strains
back then were identical and they just
weren't and he knew it and that's
that's where all of that that interest
came from was because of those projects
he had started up
yeah and so
the thing that i've noticed about the
purple strains is to me they've got some
of the most kind of most enjoyable
terpene profiles you know you referenced
earlier there's like a perfuminess to
them almost
how do you feel about that and what's
your favorite terpene profile
um
well i don't know sometimes i feel like
a brat um
with the lavender side of things you
tend to have um
i would say it is more floral
sometimes
my daughter will even say it has like a
like it's reminds her of walking into
starbucks the smell
um so lavender has that smell which is
really nice and it does um it does roll
over into the flavor sometimes and then
as to where urkel
urkel will tend to have more of like a
grape soda
every once in a while too you'll even
pick up like a pink bubble gum flavor in
there
um but that's like you those are the bit
of a different uh flavor profiles in
those purples and then in our uh wicked
clementine and like some of the tita
tubs that we've grown
they are heavily citrus i mean it's so
it's so it's so
dominant and some people will say it's
orange like some will say it's uh lemon
like pine uh like pink lemonade like
some will say it's more like grapefruit
um but those those types of terps
actually start to bother me after a
while
i do lean more towards um
that the flavor that the oracle and the
lavender tend tend to carry
but i do also like um
the more old school flavor that that
clementine kicks out because it's just
it just reminds you of like a real old
school bud um
just kind of
maybe like uh
i don't know just really
really soft easy on the lungs like a
real mild maybe mild kind of like a hint
of pine to it but almost sour at the
same time it's really nice
it sounds good
mouthwatering it is good and it's
actually super stoney that clementine um
it does if you like if i haven't been
smoking much of her it just [__] me up
like makes me stupid
so final question that was submitted
from one of our patreon fans
they say i would love you to ask mrs
madd
what does she look for in a keeper and
how does she approach a grow room in
general and so i think what they mean by
that is is it just purely about like
effect like you just smoke it and that's
all or is there other considerations
like yield you know ease of growing all
those types of things like how do you
decide keepers
oh god everything everything i take
everything into effect um
like starting in veg there's a couple of
things that i'm going to pay attention
to first off in there um
one you got to take into account what
your growth space is like you know if
you have um height restrictions space
restrictions of any type you need to
focus the strains that you grow around
that
which is one of the things that i love i
like to say you know our streams are
really nice about that
because we are limited with height and
space and whatnot we do try to focus a
plant that
can produce you
something super stoney with the flavor
but also in a manageable space and
doesn't like top out at crazy heights so
we do try to touch on that so i'm
looking at stuff that grows similar to a
structure that i like and i do i like a
shorter squatty plant um
i like a growth structure that i can
control rather easy
um i don't like a super finicky plant so
if if um
if she gets like if a female especially
gets root bound and if it starts getting
temperamental with me i don't like that
i don't want it to be rebound and start
showing problems instantly i like them
to be super tough
i don't like them to be um
i don't like when they're temperamental
because then if you have to like be away
or there's going to be any type of
stressor you know that they're going to
be easily set off i don't like to
necessarily keep plants like that
um so structure's big
pest resistance is nice i do not like
strains that have like a tendency to
have powdery mildew that's the worst
especially if you're
limited on the space that you're working
you don't want to have to deal with
powdery mildew and stuff like that so we
stay away from strains that
have tendencies to pick up powdery
mildew or draw in certain bugs but at
the same time we also uh
plants that are really expressive in
their terps tend to draw
bugs nuisance bugs so you know you kind
of have to balance that out
um
now as far as in
flower like oh two stem rubs are always
nice i know people talk about that a lot
but just any kind of smells that you can
pick up from them
might give you some um signs on what
what a plant will give you
um
just the colors that they express
how thick the stalks get i pay attention
to everything um
again like i said i stress them i make
them ugly
i like to see how
how reactive they are can they crowd out
um
are they strong enough to crowd out
other plants when situations get tough
you know when when things get really
overgrown
can they dominate as to where another
plant may get pushed out so i look at
stuff like that
um
just stuff like that
uh
but keepers again like we're always
looking for we do i like to stay within
a certain type of structure it was
really super hard for me to take in that
um the the lemon larry that we took in
because i hate its growth patterns
they're really like crazy and it's not
really within the
what i'm used to but um
so yeah that's something out of what i
typically would like but i'm working
with it
that's still very comprehensive answer
so
something i would love to quickly ask
where do terpenes and aesthetics rate
for you so for example if you bread
something again it's absolutely amazing
smoke but there's no terpenes is that
like a no-go for you like where do all
these things sit
all right that's actually really an easy
that's really one of the easier
questions um
seriously looking for balance all we're
always looking for balance
it's got to offer you up some you know
very specific things um
like i said one
you want stability first and foremost
stability is important two if i can't
stand the taste of it that's going to be
a bit of a problem
if i don't like it if it's going to make
my throat hurt if it burns my lungs
those are all problems
so i know like if it's
i know if it's doing that on a
consistent basis i can tell you without
a doubt it's not what my husband is
doing
in flower because he babies his plants
and they always come out with the best
available flavors so if it's something
that's not
just
giving it up in the flavor department it
likely won't even be touched by us but
it could have all the flavor in the
world if it doesn't
uh doesn't give you the desired effect
of you know getting you stoned taking
care of your stomach issues um taking
care of your aches and pains and your
sore back or helping you sleep at night
it there has to be balance but stability
first and foremost um
and like again it
it should be giving you something
every bit as good as
those keeper mamas and if it's not
giving you every bit as good as those
keeper mamas or better then it's just
not worth your time
so
on the tail end of it all now
this is a question i love to ask people
um but i think in my head it always
seems like it'll be a harder question
than what it is
if you could only do one for the rest of
your life indoor or outdoor which one
would it be okay yeah see this is funny
mad would tell you all day long he would
say outdoor i would not i would say
indoor i
maybe because i'm i'm i'm not big on
change um
i don't like change whenever i make
changes nine times out of ten i find
myself very disappointed
i'm talking across the board in life so
maybe that's why i say that um no i'm
just being honest
every time i make a change
it rarely
turns out better so i'm not a fan of
change because of this i'm i'm the kind
of person that if i find something and
it works for me
i'm not i will i will make a change if
you can give me evidence that shows me
if you do it like this and you can give
me an example of how there will be solid
evidence to prove it will be better i
will
but you have to be able to present me
with solid evidence because i'm not
about to abandon everything i know and
everything i do great at
unless there's a good reason to do that
that's just that's me
soon regards to indoor what is your
preferred type of light
oh my gosh see now this is where there
is no there's no uh there's no real
compromise here
this is all mad
no compromise what mad says goes
um no for my veg i we've got just basic
t5s um mad's pretty basic he's old
school he likes old school all the way
but no he's um pretty dead set on the
certain things that he uses but no
um when it comes to stuff like that i
don't i i don't um i don't pretend to
have input there
like i said are you guys running flower
um he's actually he's old school dude
he's got um
the uh what it
is so hard for her yes he has high
pressure sodiums but he's got just we
have our old-school ballasts in there
but they have never done us wrong
um hydrofarm all the way uh never had a
problem not once and i think the ones
that we even have have like
just the best warranties on them so
yeah he like i said he even is to a
certain extent like me you know you
um in anything that we do he's very much
a perfectionist like i am um
i don't mess with anything if it's
working well for me unless i find a
reason that i need to change it
in that case i will um he's the same way
but actually it's funny that you bring
that up because he was just telling me
the other day
um
because we're gonna be
needing to put some
plants into flowers soon but he is
talking about wanting to go through a
bunch of changes on um lights and
whatnot and i'm thinking oh i'm so glad
that's not my
that's not
not in this within the realm of the
things that i do because i don't want to
deal with it
i really don't but that's one of the
things really nice about what him and i
do together because
it's such a shared uh responsibility he
really does do the things that i hate or
i don't i don't like to do and trust me
there are some of those and then there's
some things that i just
i'll be honest that's another thing i
love about this industry you will never
know everything there is to know there's
always something to learn
cannabis is one of the coolest things
because you will never have all the
knowledge there is to have you can
always learn something new and i really
do enjoy that
um
but yeah uh we get to share in
everything that we do and
he has such an extensive knowledge um
and he's been studying for so long that
he's he does make a good majority of our
decisions unless like i said it's one of
those things that falls within my um
you know things that i like to control
because i am i am a control freak he
will tell you i'm almost borderline
psycho when it comes to the things i
like to control
so
what's a general grow tip you've got for
the viewers just to you know get things
you know just perky a little better that
type of thing
you know i think one of the things
people don't realize i i think they
forget it is basically a weed
um just keep in mind uh they they're
real basic they grow it's pretty simple
um they don't require a whole lot um
just really
love and care
you can really just watch them and
they'll tell you everything that they
need
reading is always good
one of the things that i actually
personally feel like i have learned
myself that has been extremely helpful
for me
is if i ever have a problem
the one thing i don't do i know
everybody runs to the computer first
thing
i do not go on
pot forums
i refuse to find information there
because most of it a lot of it is crazy
for starters but
a lot of it will send you to doing
things to your plants that's crazy
dangerous bad for them um sometimes will
kill them
um but also will straight up make you
panic um so i what i try to do is i try
to do a lot of my research
just basically apply common sense
knowledge to it and then i do a lot of
agricultural site research and we're
lucky to have some friends in like
agricultural business so you can ask
them questions and they can kind of give
you some guidance on which way to go
with certain products and or you know
pest questions
so yeah i would say don't get all your
information from pot forums that could
be really dangerous and really bad for
your plants
and just
don't overdo it keep it basic and then
read books don't just run and ask
somebody that you think can answer the
question for you
go get the knowledge yourself read as
many books as you can there are some
really good ones out there i think matt
has probably about 20 of them in his
possession
over the years he's been collecting
but yeah i think a lot of people too
with um pot plants they just overdo it
they
they think more is better and it's not
it's just a basic plant and it grows
pretty easy it really does
yeah killing it with kindness
yes
all righty so this brings us to our last
little quickfire questions first one
what is your favorite strain you only
pick one
oh that's a hard
i don't know like today my favorite
strain would be lavender
for sure
um i don't know we've been we've had it
in our collect in our collection for so
long it's like i said it's one no matter
how crappy i feel i know that i can i
can go to lavender and get some type of
relief so i've got to say her lavender
all the way
and so what is the strain that's just
least left an impact on you slash just
didn't impress you at all personally
oh
my gosh oh this feels like an awful
question to answer
there's so many of them
oh
yeah
i i i don't know i don't want to say
like left awful impressions i'd say that
there's a lot of strains out there with
a lot of hype to them just based off of
names which kind of drives me crazy well
that's and i think that's actually the
next question like so we'll just combine
them together what's the worst strain to
ever gain traction with the masses
i i
i think depending on what strain is
the current cut of the month club would
be the one that falls in that category
for me
so probably as of lately i'd say some
dumb ass
cookies or
something like that
i just hate that i don't know why but i
really do
again like you were asking earlier do
you feel like this is why i don't feel
like i'm limiting myself i feel like i'm
setting standards
by doing that because then we're not
running out doing the exact same thing
that everybody else is doing and let's
face it everybody else is doing that
same exact thing
so yeah nope
cookies all of those what else is there
you've got what was you had that nine
nine pound hammer for a while there
which that's been a lot a ways away
thank god there was um
you have like of course like the og kb
like all of these little ones that pop
up with all these crazy
followings but i do i'm not saying that
the strain itself sucks because i'm not
saying that i'm just like i think the
hype behind it is
overplayed and overblown is more how i
would look at it
totally
so if you could only smoke one land race
variety for the rest of your life what's
it gonna be
oh
my gosh
um
i don't know
that i don't know what would you pick
whatever that land race thai boat he
gave me was
[Laughter]
you don't know what it was
yeah it was like pearl tie i think he
said it was lowland thai
and why why was this your pick
god is so good
what stood out what about it stood out
to you
because it's like um it's like what you
wish super silver hayes was it's like
everyone's happy you're happy it's a
good time
is there any strains that you can think
of that um
are like really really good but just
don't get any attention
blue magoo
straight up
number one i love blooming it's my
favorite strain can you hear me okay
what what is it
it's um it's the
it's it's made by an unknown grower from
oregon and it's a cross of blueberry and
williams one to f2
um so pretty solid genetics in it and
it's kind of like it's kind of perfumey
in the same way that like urkel is but
more of like a blueberry and roses type
of thing as opposed to like
a real you know like musky perfume in
the way that hercules i think
yeah that the blueberry flavors can get
kind of overwhelming at times though
is it
you like it we actually yeah we played
with some blueberry i i think we may
that might be something we might revisit
at some point but when we did we played
around with the blueberry and the urkel
we even have some blueberry the northern
lights by blueberry somewhere um but
when we played with that urkel by
blueberry everything it just smelled
like a giant blueberry muffin and
everywhere it was like blueberry muffins
all day long and i just got really tired
of that
there's a significant demand for that
maybe we should maybe we should
definitely consider looking back into
that because i could see maybe the
northern lights by blueberry being fun
to play around with you know that might
be something worth looking into
i think it's it's a cross that's been
done by so many different breeders it's
going to be hard like you know i think a
lot of people probably like for example
me when i hear northern lights blueberry
i'm like oh yeah like one of the million
northern lights blueberries um and
that's just obviously like a knee-jerk
reaction due to how many just rip-off
companies that are offering that um
whereas i think the urkel blueberry
would be really really unique and as far
as i know no one offers that
yeah we have those too we do we've uh we
we grew actually a bunch of them out and
it was just like we were both so sick of
it
when we were done it was like
that smell
everything was just like a blueberry
muffin it was so overwhelming you just
really got sick of it but i think we
were sick of it but i don't think
anybody else was it was just one of
those things and the teeth the the tdub
lines are actually like that too because
they're very that citrus the citrus
scents and tones that they pick up are
so heavy and dominant it's like it's so
overwhelming for your palette at times
yeah okay so lucky last question
if you could go back in time to any
place collect any seeds which ones would
you get
[Laughter]
i don't know
hmm
that's actually a really good question
would you go and grab the bundle of uh
you know because who knows how many
seats there were in the original urkel
lavender batch but like you know go
sweep them up or what are you thinking
no i don't think i would
i don't think i would i think i'd go
i don't i don't know i just
i
i i think i'm ready to look look at
something a little bit different too
um i don't know it would
i'm not really sure
i think there's
so much put behind
everybody wanting certain strains and
whatnot i don't think i'm as obsessed as
others are
so these kinds of questions i think
other people think about them quite
regularly and these aren't things that
really have ever crossed my mind and
i think it's just because i've never
really been into that whole
the strain craze
uh like the research and who had what
and what stories this i've just never
really been that into it
um i don't know and it would be hard for
me to say if i haven't actually smoked
this particular strain i can't see
myself really wanting
i don't know i i guess i'd have to have
some sort of interest in it to say i
would want those beans to play around
with and off the top of my head
nothing that i could particularly think
of i think
everything that we currently have that
i'd want to play around with we have
access to
but like i did say though i definitely
want to get some awesome cbd strain in
our in our collection to work through
but i don't know as far as that question
that one's tricky
yeah let's make that cbd thing happen
but i mean i know i really i really do
yeah so i think that just might bring us
about to the end of it did you have any
comments or shout outs you'd like to
make
yeah actually um i'm curious too though
what is it that you're currently working
with
like my current project i'm doing
yeah what what strains are you currently
working with i'm doing i'm finishing off
the cube of the phantom crackers so i'm
pretty sure i sent you the bx ones so
i'm currently finishing the bx2s and
then i'll probably do the bx3s as well
depending on how the bx2s turn out like
if they if they're good enough i'll just
leave it at that but you know i i like
the idea of finishing the project off
where it should be so
um it's just you know in the sense that
you know statistic i like how you know
at a certain point you can statistically
calculate it should have a certain
amount of the parent within it and so
yeah the cube seems like the the good
end point but who knows but then i got
some other stuff off in the the back
that i'm toying with but
not 100 sure yet i'm gonna maybe see
where it goes
there's so many possibilities when you
start putting strains together you never
really know when you're going to be done
looking through them there's just so
many possibilities it's fun
yeah for sure and i mean i need to take
a page out of your book in regards to
the um
the organization and the notes because i
got a lot of good seats but some of
those little baggies the uh the the
riding on them starting to fade
oh yeah no i actually i i sit down about
once a year i pull our stock of seeds
like that that all have different types
of packaging and whatnot and i sit down
and i will re-label and make sure
because you notice after handling and
whatnot some of them will rub off or
yeah you know you just don't want to
lose what your seeds are but two like
like i was saying we are uh you know i
hear these interviews and people can
quote you know months and years and i
can't i would have to tell you right now
if you wanted to know these things i
would have to go into the other room and
dig out we have stacks and notebooks
i actually i started out buying mad
calendars
with the big you know the desk calendar
so you have the big squares and he
started out using those but then he
would fill up the entire note section
and he needed more space so i started
buying notebooks and what we do is each
day that you do something you write in
the you write your month your day and
the year and you even write the day like
if it's saturday you write down saturday
so you know bet you know you can go back
in reference each time
and we list uh like if you're if you're
feeding or you're giving them something
you write down what you're giving them
how much
we get real specific if you're doing any
type of treatments of any kind you write
it down we write everything down and
then we keep these stacks and stacks and
notebooks and it gives you
believe it or not you don't use the
majority of it but it's really neat to
look back through because you can find
that you have a lot of knowledge there
you you completely forgot you had
and it tells you a lot about the strange
you're growing so we do we're note
keepers all the way
yeah killer
and so it's nice
yeah you wanna any shout outs or you
wanna wrap it up
well i would definitely like to thank
you for um for interviewing me today
it's been fun talking to you and thank
you to my husband and my daughter
they're amazing i don't i wouldn't i
wouldn't i'm nothing without those two
and seriously i give all my credit to my
husband because i've learned everything
from him he's just
amazing and i love him
um
and you know to all of our our amazing
growers and supporters
all of the people that have grown our
genetics are always so nice and kind to
us
and
of course we're nothing without them so
we appreciate all the support that
they've given to us
super special shout out to everybody in
australia like i was telling you
everyone in australia is always so
positive and they're such amazing people
great growers too i might add
but one of the things i think everybody
could learn from uh just like online
presence of the people in australia
everybody is so kind i have never
ever been trolled by somebody out of
australia and i just think that i just
want to make that known
i absolutely love that
and again
i just would like to thank dirt md nc
crop both of those guys are amazing
um their products are amazing and
everybody should check them out and two
like i said
our homie bangmingo
um he keeps me in my concentrates when
i'm out of anything else and he's too is
likely to be a future business partner
of
me and mad so there's nice things coming
to in our future hopefully too and like
i said we've got some local friends the
jenna's in project they're out of
modesto
they operate both the medicinal and an
adult use store
they're called the jennison project and
i go to them too for
concentrates when i need
and they also actually do quite a nice
selection process through our genetics
and they also
sell
cell flowers of um mad pharma genetics
out of their shop too so that's nice um
but yeah like i said i appreciate my
husband he's taught me a lot and
he's just awesome and wouldn't be in
this industry without him and i really
do appreciate you taking the time to
talk to me today
killer yeah so thanks so much for coming
on
oh thank you thanks for having me hey
don't forget to tell us how beautiful i
think he is oh yeah and mad said to tell
you um
how beautiful you are
so a huge huge thank you to mrs mad for
taking the time to talk to us
huge thank you to all you guys for
listening
[Music]
our sponsors seeds here now 420
australia organic gardening solutions
you know you love them they're the best
big ups guys we love you
and finally our patreon fans lifeblood
of the show
go check it out if you haven't already
does diner seem to be up there you've
probably never heard about
[Music]
la la la la
[Applause]
[Music]
you