all righty gang we're back at it thanks
for joining us on this episode we're
joined by our good friend direwolf to
talk all things Canadian history
genetics Trends the future so much more
very excited to have him on the show
thank you for joining us again direwolf
oh thanks for having me man
always a pleasure always a pleasure
first question I want to know what have
you been smoking on today or have you
even been smoking today what are you
smoking on yesterday
I I have not been smoking today I've
been working all day but I've I'm
actually traveling at the moment all
week so I do I'm trying to think what
I've got in my travel jar I think I have
ghost of Leroy from rare dankness which
is kind of like a ghost OG triangle
cross and some purple kush which is like
a Canadian classic and
I've got some GMO and I actually just
got a couple of days ago from visiting
some big commercial living soil friends
of mine that gave me
some of the they've always got the
newest stuff I think they gave me gas
Truffles and greasy runs and something
else I can't remember
got a good selection that does sound
really nice I want to jump into a few of
those and hear your thoughts but just
out of curiosity you mentioned quite a
nice range of genetics you know from the
old school Purple Kush through to the
newest you know greasy runs what stands
out the most to you out of the four or
five you just sort of mentioned
uh probably the oh honestly that one to
me uh that's kind of a lovely
relationship with it because it's so
nasty sometimes you crave it and
sometimes you cringe when you open the
jar but I still think that's a
um strain all the way around
oh sorry I think I I lost you for a
second there what was the name of that
one we heard everything just not the
name of it oh GMO
I'm saying the rankness of GMO yeah okay
that's what I thought
yeah beautiful beautiful and out of
curiosity have you ever had many strains
from rare dankness because I've actually
grown out ghost of Leroy myself and I
thought it was a pretty good strain but
I feel like um you don't hear a lot
about rare dankness have you ever had
much experience with their genetics or
not particularly not particularly I
actually that's I only ever bought one
pack from him quite a long time ago but
it was a standout pack where that was I
would consider it one of the best packs
I've ever bought in my life it was just
like a counter a 12 pack and there is
two like super super nice
oh geez it came out of it and that one
is actually I think that's the longest
I've of any of the Clones that I've held
personally that I popped that's
that's the one I was super impressed
with it oh wow that was the Ghost of
Leroy was it
yeah I was a ghost of Leroy
the reason why I picked that one myself
as well is because it's so heavy on the
OG isn't it it's like TK into ghost into
TK it's uh it's a cool one for if you're
looking for OG and Seed form
yeah I actually just picked it randomly
I was just at a trade show for something
else and uh I just randomly bought it
and I just wanted to try an OG pack and
uh you know it turned out super nice
it's a funny strain because I that
cologne when I first ran it is still the
tastiest clone I've ever grown
personally and I was probably like I
don't know seven or eight years ago and
I've been chasing that flare ever since
and never got it to to uh pop the Terps
like that one or two times it's still
super nice but I know it has the
potential but uh I guess I don't have
the skills to bring it up I'm so glad
you said that because I've had a similar
experience where I'm like chasing that
first cycle with like a different plant
and um it's good to hear I'm not alone
because I sort of I'm like no it was
definitely a worse grower back then how
did I make it pop so hard like it's an
interesting one but I guess while we're
on the topic of uh maybe not being quite
as good grower and making things shine
well I'd love to talk some of the early
days of uh the BC growing life with you
and I guess the the point I'd like to
start it off with is I'd love to hear
your experience because we have we have
lots of chats in the in the DMS and I I
value
um how should I say I feel like your
perspectives are very honest and
um unbiased and so I want to start off
by asking you hear a lot of people
talking about the olden days of cannabis
and like how it was so much better
certain strains were just insane you
don't see that anymore do you think it
really was like that or do you think we
have a bit of Rose shade glasses and you
know like good quality wasn't around as
much all that sort of stuff I think a
hundred percent it's a million times
better today I think it was a lot more
varied back then um like these days it's
I do find it's like super limited and
like everything's kind of an OG or
cookies or and back then you really
there's definitely some stuff when I
look back and I'm like oh that was way
different and there's nothing around
like it now
I also don't lose sight of the fact that
most of it was garbage
um there was a both the stuff that
people were growing I mean you could
like I kind of got started back in the
have been around like since the late 80s
but I started in the growing scene in
the early 90s and I mean back then
nobody even tried hardly anyone even
saved good stuff they just popped a pack
and whatever was the biggest yielder
that was your keeper and because you
could sell anything
um so but I did see some there was
definitely some nice stuff but it was uh
I would say there was a whole lot of
mids around
um the only ones that really there's a
couple that stand out from back then but
honestly like if I had to go back in
time
I I can honestly think of like there was
an old NL clone that we used to have
that I would love to give back I've
never seen anything like that since and
there's some other good stuff but
they're mostly still similar stuff today
there's like you know some of the hazes
were nice I could still get similar
stuff today
some of the northern light stuff was
nice but to me I just kind of think like
Bubba and stuff like that are basically
just modern day Northern Lights of the
type that I liked but there's a lot of
there's a lot of garbage back there
honestly man it was people remember the
good stuff but it was pretty dismal
okay well good to hear that I haven't
missed the Golden Age of cannabis in a
sense I'd be curious to hear you
mentioned Northern Lights and one of the
questions I wanted to ask you was back
in like the 90s say in uh the Pacific
Northwest of the USA when Northern
Lights and those sort of colors were
really starting to take off did they
just come up and cross the border around
that time or did was there a bit of a
delay before they made their way up to
you so to speak
yeah I don't know I'm guessing they
probably did but I think most of it was
I mean if you I don't really I'm not I
don't remember the exact dates but it
was around like what when I kind of got
into the growing scene it was like night
probably around 91 like I was around it
but I really it was like 91 or so anyway
I just remember when I started most of
the stuff was second hand from seed bank
so it was like Neville stuff was what I
can tell is like a lot of people ordered
stuff in around 88 or so that time for
the late 80s and then they got shut down
by the DEA and you couldn't get seeds
anywhere so what all you got was
basically whatever f2s or clones getting
passed around from people that had
bought from the seed bag I think there's
probably some stuff around BC and that
that might come up from Seattle but who
knows I think the reality if you look
back in Canadian history a huge portion
of it was old seed bank
um genetics and also you got to remember
where I kind of been back and forth and
I'm originally from like the Toronto
area of Canada which is yeah it's kind
of always our kind of crew was kind of
half based in BC and half based in
Ontario and I've always
bumped back and forth between those two
places but I was mostly in Ontario
around Toronto area and it was super
like they're two different regions of
Canada and where I lived it was super
hardcore for like policing and stuff for
cannabis so people were pretty tight
like there wasn't a whole lot of sharing
of anything like that it was like
whatever was in your own crew and then
BCU was a complete opposite like nobody
had been put in jail in like a decade or
something for for growing it was a bit
of a free-for-all but even I got the
feeling like in DC I don't think there
was a ton of sharing outside of like
pretty tight networks like even there
like you kept your your head down pretty
good it was gonna get lobbed off yeah
look certainly it makes sense
um I'd be interested to to ask like at
what point do you think that the laws
really started to relax on the East
Coast or do you think they still haven't
really caught up with the West Coast
uh there is pretty relaxed now it has
been pretty recent like it was pretty
crazy like I remember even after
legalization which I'm not like full
legalization which I'm not sure I don't
remember what exactly when that was
probably about seven or eight years ago
I live in a area that's like The Big
Greenhouse area and there was some
massive like legal cannabis places and I
don't own like a big property and the
property was still getting flown by the
police looking for people growing plants
in the backyard while there was like 20
acres of legal weed like a kilometer
away so it was those habits died died
hard with the uh Ontario police force
these days it's a free-for-all but back
but it took it took a long time it used
to literally be like like most of the
time that I was growing if you got
caught with a single plant you were
going to jail period
wow that that sounds really brutal
yeah I know it was it was a war zone man
it's interesting because you hear about
how the USA historically had really
harsh penalties but I guess it's
interesting to hear that they weren't
really too much different just over the
Border I'd love to ask you if we roll
back a little bit what was I've always
been interested what did Gorilla growing
look like in Canada back in like you
know the 80s and 90s when people were
just starting to really grow flower
because I guess you hear about Gorilla
growing in the state some stuff but in
Canada the the conditions are just harsh
I imagined for a good chunk of the year
how did that work was it really limited
or like what was the limiting factor in
your Gorilla Grow just the stealth or
the environment so most of Canada
um basically like where I most of
Canada's it's really situated along the
U.S border the population but there's a
giant vast Wilderness Area like pretty
much wherever you live only a couple
hours North
so it was basically impossible to grow
along the southern areas because it was
you just get either busted or somebody
would rip it off so everyone kind of
grew up in like the Wilderness areas and
there you were really limited especially
back then the main thing I remember
about cannabis or cannabis in Canada in
that period this genetics were really
locked down he couldn't get any so like
when I went like just for roughly when I
started growing you could not it was
illegal to buy anything telling you how
to grow cannabis it was illegal to buy
seeds anywhere like there's basically no
place in the world other than you
literally had to fly to Amsterdam to get
seeds and snuggle them back and so
basically what you got is the people
that were in the game you just I mean
that's how our crew kind of got started
is we were the had good genetics and you
just kept it on lockdown and nobody
nobody else could get in but especially
the case with outdoor genetics because
uh basically nothing finished out here
um you had to be out in a lot of areas
but kind of third week of September was
kind of the magic number and basically
nothing finished there was a couple of
really crappy Dutch strains so it was
really uh it was all about that's kind
of how I got into the genetics what end
of things was if you're in the game you
had to like basically breed your own
genetics because you couldn't get it
from anywhere else so that was a
limiting factor and kind of
you know our crew kind of got into some
of the earlier stuff was which was
mostly of Canada the early stuff is
based around a strain called Mighty
might and that was kind of like a
depending on the phenotes kind of an
auto to semi-auto on it would finish
anywhere and you could also get it in
before like it used to be back in the
old days like a drought so in this end
of the summer through the summer there'd
be no weed and you could if you had weed
you could sell it for really high prices
just uh really really easily so these
strains kind of um
I allowed you to hit that you know get
it in and also get it in before uh on
all the mainstream stuff started coming
in then the prices dropped when you get
in early so it was definitely genetics
and willingness to do like hardcore
stuff to pull it off like some of the
I've seen some crazy stuff to where we
used to grow one of the places we
literally used to like drive a couple of
hours then canoe about two hours Into
the Wilderness and we had like a grow
out it grows out in the swamps so you
could kind of water them I'd say swamp
growing is one of the big Canadian
Canadian things because we've got plenty
of swamps and no one in the right mind
is going to go in a Canadian swamp in
the summer because the bugs were just
you know Fierce uh that's cool that's
like a nice little bit of uh what would
you say like human IPM
yeah yeah yeah it was different I mean
it said it was that's like a real
Community I think the Canadian gorilla
was quite a bit different than the
us stuff because it was I don't know it
just seemed a lot different because uh
hey you're growing really small plants
because in order something to finish by
September 3rd you weren't throwing like
you know two Pounders they were more
like quarter pound was a good plant and
it's mostly Rock so you can't dig
anywhere
um so you couldn't get that was one of
the big problems is there's you couldn't
dig a hole you had to basically either
float something on top of a swamp or
um they did a lot of like whatever we
put bushel baskets on top of a swamp so
it's self-water or there's a bunch of
different methods but it was always
interesting back then you'd stumble I
stumbled across quite a few you know
Wilderness gorilla grows and that's that
was kind of before the internet so
that's how you learned you're like
how people different people do is by
stumbling on there was a lot of patches
back then and stumble onto somebody else
and oh man I never thought of you know
dropping bushel baskets on my
four-wheeler and dropping it in a on top
of a wet part of a swamp as like raised
beds or there was other ones on the I've
seen on the east coast of Canada where
we have these like kind of oh their
official name is but it's like a
floating so you could actually it's
almost like standing on a water bed so
it's kind of like uh surface layer of
soil and Moss and it's just floating
over top of the pond and uh
they would grow on top of that and it
would just the roots would just grow
right down into the swamp like the water
Roots there's a bunch of
crazy uh methods and probably a bunch of
stuff I've never heard about before
because everyone kept it tight
that's cool I would uh I'd be interested
to hear the uh the terroir and the
Fiverr the swamp weed literally sounds
fun but um I'd love to ask you we had a
white buffalo on the show recently and
they referenced an early Canadian strain
I'll be honest I I wasn't I've heard of
it but I'm not as familiar with it as I
should be but I'd love to hear if you
have any experience with it the old
spice of life cream sodaka did you have
much interaction with that one at all
yeah I actually grew it I was that was
in my opinion one of I think it kind of
became an important building block but
honestly like just to clarify in my
opinion most of the Canadian Outdoor
weeds has never been that great with the
genetics being able to finish like in in
some parts of Canada you can grow some
like kind of more indoor like regular
strains but most parts of Canada when
you're limited to that so like for
instance like if you grow like
I don't know like a Bubba or something
like that I personally there's like a
lot of decent weed I I haven't smoked a
whole lot of like really good Canadian
Outdoor short season weed
um and I would say no offense to uh
reader Steve but cream sodic would fall
into that
that realm I think that probably so that
was like an early like it's a purple one
and that was kind of some of the earlier
stuff we were working with which was
like
um I used to work with one outdoor
genetics
um we sell this purple stuff that came
out of Holland and it was pretty
horrible it looked really good but it
didn't taste that good
um and it didn't get you that high and
I'm thinking the purple the cream sodico
was one of them sort of put it in
perspective reader Steve when he
released it he immediately pulled it off
the market and kind of regretted it
because even though it was uh I think a
good like production strain it was
definitely like lacking in some of those
other areas
wow that's interesting perspective
that's that's cool to hear and I mean
while we're on the topic of purple
cannabis you mentioned the Purple Kush
earlier and you said it was a Canadian
favorite you got my brain juices sort of
pumping around I I had remembered that
it was a popular one in Canada
um but I was interested to know do you
know which cutting of the Purple Kush
that is because I know there's a few and
I think the popular one is like the the
SR whatever is it that one or a
different one as far as you know uh I've
got a couple that particular that's like
a seed line that that I run and it's
actually uh based off of uh Garberville
one
um which is just the Barberville Purple
Kush which is one that came which isn't
so it's a California one not a Canadian
one but it's been around Canada for
probably like I think I don't know when
I first saw it early 2000s or so
supposedly got snuggled up in the door
of somebody's car that was fleeing
California on charges but
um there's a couple so Purple Kush it's
kind of a weird Canadian thing first of
all a lot of the purple fish we have up
here isn't actually purple
um but it was kind of a I'm trying to
think it was early kind of weird
especially BC where
for on the commercial Scene It was
really like it would be like all one
clone so be like for like a few years I
think White Buffalo there's like these
arrows and it was like in the early
2000s it was like purple kush and
everybody was growing purple kush and
there was a few different types but it
was mostly one clone and then there was
another era it was like the hash plant
era and I think if you go back earlier
it was the there's a Northern Lights
thing and a big bud and purple kush was
a long pretty long-standing era in the
early 2000s and we talked to one guy who
I'm pretty sure is this kind of source
for her and it was actually a California
broker
that smuggled up the Clone and I think
it was kind of during that Koji Kush era
um and it was actually a Kush we call it
purple kush but when I've grown out s1's
of it and stuff it pops at OG Thanos I
think it was basically the first OG Kush
it doesn't look like an OG Kush but when
you taste it you're like that's got that
kush Funk to it and when you pop seed
lines out of it not the Garber build
that's a separate one
um but the main one that everyone I just
call it the BC Purple Kush that's the
main one that everyone was growing and
that one I'm pretty convinced was an OG
and uh
I've talked to the actually talked to
the broker
um that supposedly brought it up and I'm
pretty sure it probably came from him
and he told me it was uh
uh Hollywood Purple Kush cross with
Bubba which I've never even heard of a
Hollywood purple Crush I kind of want to
wonder if it's the Hollywood pure kush
but anyway he was a big broker and he
was back in the first early days of that
fishing in California and a lot of the
BC
um Growers that there was it was an
export market right so brought up this
cut and gave it to a bunch of you know
organized crime gangs to grow for him
and this whole story totally as like
everything like matched I have
laid-backs that's probably what it is
and it matches with the s1s and Crosses
that have grown out come from it it's
nothing special it's a nice clone but
the other thing I was Finding funny
about the Canadian Purple Kush is a lot
of them didn't really go super purple
they kind of have like a little bit of
purple and the calyx is or if you really
drop the temperature it would be like
lavender but but it sounded a lot like
the Urkel story from California
yeah wow there's so many interesting
talking points you drop there and I mean
I've certainly heard of the Garberville
purple I mean uh Mean Gene well-known
breeder he uses that in his work as well
so definitely some uh established uh
provenance behind that one and you know
what I'm I'm so stoked that you
referenced that a lot of the Purple Kush
doesn't go purple because one one of not
the very first because I've told this
story on other podcasts like the first
good weed I ever had that really got my
mind ticking about weed was some green
Granddaddy Purple like the second or
third strain I got to try that was
really good was some green purple kush
and I always look back on it and was
like [ __ ] that was good like but it I
don't know if it was actually Purple
Kush and then I just realized it
actually like my mate did tell me he got
it from like an online Canadian weed
seller or whatever back in the day so
like it could well be similar because it
was definitely nice stuff but that's
cool you've pulled a lot of those sort
of stories together for me I would love
to sort of move to a topic that's hard
to get a lot of info about you mentioned
it yourself that the hash plant era it
seems like pink cush has been popular
for quite a while and from what white
buffalo told us those hash plants and
pink cushes are sort of from the same
era what's your perspective and
recollection on the hashplan era so to
speak
um so the hash Point Eric kind of start
like right from this Iron Rock was I was
in like University in like the 90s early
90s and I can remember some of those
cuts like champagne was one of them that
came out of that same group of people
they were like biker Cuts I think is the
all the PO all the stories point back
towards a group of bikers and champagne
was probably the most elite cut back
then
um like we'd never seen anything like it
at the time
so it was going around back then but it
really kind of blew up where we had I
think it was the early medical days and
there was you could get
I can't remember if it was like there
was mandatory minimums around 10 plants
or if it was you could get a medical
card for 10 plants but for a while it
was like these crazy scenes where they
would like drop down these vertical they
were called biker buckets so it'd be
like like a hempy bucket or whatever
they call like a big five gallon tail
and some Hydro corn and uh super high
power bubbler in the bottom and with
like coolers and stuff and it was like
really high tech and then they would
drop these vertical thousand watt bulbs
and they'd have one bulb per plant and
grow these massive massive beasts like
they'd be commercial Growers that had 10
plants in them and in order to yield in
them there was only a couple of strains
that could actually do it and and one
was uh it was a hash plant and the other
one was like a BC big but I don't I
think the hash plant was decent quality
the BC big bud was horrid
um but that was their claim to think if
you wanted to grow the 10 plants you had
to grow like one of these handful of
clones anything else you'd get like you
know three quarters of a pound of light
or something like that
yeah wow so champagne's an interesting
one from a few perspectives I guess I
feel like you don't hear about it as
much as say the king but I have
certainly heard about it a lot uh how
would you describe it is it like a like
a Kush sort of plant ever tried it a
couple times it was going back quite a
ways it was just I consider most of
those more of like a kind of
differentiate hash plans and pushes I
find like cushions are kind of more the
more modern like OG type I mean that's
not traditional obviously fishes it
could be anything but I consider those
ones more like of a pure hash plant so
they didn't have they just tasted like
acts it wasn't like that nude it wasn't
like OG I'm a big hash plant guy right I
like the effects and I had kind of up
until OG kush and purple cushion stuff
kind of committed I mean that's my
preference for effect and I'm stuck
smoking stuff that doesn't taste that
great because it was just not bad it
just tasted like hash and that's what
champagne was kind of like it looked
good in a bag it yielded good but I
would consider this like a a pretty
generic I high quality but generic hash
plant
yeah okay that's interesting and did you
ever grow any of these Cuts yourself in
the early days or were they so tightly
held that like you just sort of got buds
of them here and there
no definitely not in the early days
that's kind of a
um I've grown I'd say most of what's
going around up until like the last
decade I got I got whatever Cuts were
going through my kind of extended crew
which was pretty like I said it was a
tight scene like these
I was like rolling with since like the
since my University days like since the
90s and some of those guys were pretty
connected and I'd get whatever they
happen to be which is usually some of
the good commercial Cuts but most of the
stuff was locked down pretty hard and
even if it wasn't up until pretty
recently but I did grow a lot of uh like
stuff like the grapefruit was the real
famous clone back there and I could have
actually could have gotten that a few
times but I've grown out a crapload of
grapefruit crosses
um so I have a good feeling what okay
what grapefruit is like just from
growing out you know 50 or 60 seeds of
it
um and that's the same thing with the
Ashland it's a different
write a bunch of them in like the actual
cologne and from dispensaries and stuff
but I've never uh never grown any of any
of those coveted ones I've never really
uh
grown myself
yeah not a problem that sounds like you
still have a really diverse range of
experience which is great to hear out of
curiosity did you ever try any of that
fabled breeder Steve DJ Short collab
stuff or was that more of like a seed
release they did and it wasn't
necessarily like stuff passed out to
locals
I think that was pretty tight I actually
have tried some of the stuff this is the
funny thing about Canada is there's I
don't know whether it's actually true
but people are always between you know
Ontario and BC especially most people
live in kind of three main parts of
Canada and I don't know whether that's
actually true in Canada but definitely
within the weed scene you were never
more than about three people or moved so
I kind of had I actually had like two
group separate groups of friends that
were all like one person removed from
that reader Steve crew and actually one
of my friends was actually involved in
that grow so I actually tried the it was
something crashed I can't really I think
it was Blue Crush or something came out
of that one
um I can't remember the actual name but
it was Crush for sure
um I did try that it's good I'm not a
giant uh
blueberry DJ Short fan I respect
honestly it's not my taste of weed
um so I did try some of that and it
actually grew some of the seeds
um I never they were decent
nice nice
and actually sir I did right now that I
think back I grew a bunch of
I think I grew a bunch of Time Warp
crossed with that blue uh true blue the
blueberry male they used in that that
actually came from Red at Legend seeds I
grew that outdoor for a few years too so
I definitely tried a few yeah wow
interesting and you just mentioned
Legend seeds I think a lot of people are
probably unaware that DJ did that collab
with them and a few cool lesser known
strains came out of it like you know red
eye bride and a few other ones what was
it toe jam and stuff did you ever have
much of a positive impression from those
ones and how come you think they don't
get uh recognized as much
all right the thing you remember about
that time in frame in Canada the export
Market was all about it had to look a
certain way almost no hairs really dumb
criteria if you think back it was like
it had to be super late green like that
was the main limit that exactly
um so a lot of that was to me that was
like commercial where it was decent
um it was definitely good weed I I
didn't really I grew a bunch of it and
it wasn't something that I would keep
around personally but it was definitely
good yeah nice good perspective
so I know that you've done some
different cultivation writing over the
years for cannabis Canada and cannabis
culture what was that experience like
and would you ever consider doing more
of that sort of creative writing
um I think that was a moment in time
yeah so basically go to my my history as
I was working since I was a little kid I
worked to make the commercial Greenhouse
industry and I
was kind of I went to the kind of the
top top AG or Horticulture School in
Canada and it was kind of at that time I
was doing like a lot of dead shows and I
was so I was hanging around with like
kind of dead head crowd in that
University
and one of my roommates was a big
wholesaler and I think just that was
like the whatever Holy Trinity or
whatever you call it of things where
that my friend the wholesaler kind of
knew everybody in town so our house was
kind of like a I don't know what you'd
call it anything good weed wise was
coming that was coming through town was
through our house like so all the
Growers would come there and you just
kind of knew everybody it was all
through like the Dead scene largely and
and just because I had all the all that
commercial Greenhouse experience I kind
of always got sucked in with a lot of
those guys because I kind of you know
came from commercial uh Greenhouse
flowers and veg
and out of there somehow I ended up
working on the side for uh cannabis
Canada which was called at the time it's
the same magazine Canada's cannabis
Canada had turned into cannabis culture
eventually and it was really like an
activist magazine so that was back in
like the dark days you weren't allowed
to really do anything there and love
them or hate him Mark Emery was the guy
that owned that magazine and he did I
don't particularly like the guy but uh
he there's no question he did a lot of
major bid for Canada's cannabis laws and
some other stuff so he was really
pushing the boundaries and that was his
magazine and that's where if you hear
people talking about Emery seeds and
that it was all sold out of the magazine
but it was very much like a it was an
activist magazine
um and it was really about you gotta
remember that that if you frame that I
don't think a lot of people realized but
at that point in time BC specifically
was kind it was BC in Amsterdam where
the two epicenters of cannabis in the in
the world California was still really
this is kind of like late night 90s
California was still locked down pretty
hard so everyone was not it wasn't even
though it was a major player nobody was
talking of it an international scene so
it was BC was kind of the Centric and
Mark Henry's kind of a big egomaniac so
he's kind of used that to promote his
stuff but I'm super proud of being
involved in that I think it really
pushed the boundaries and uh
so basically kind of my Niche there was
I kind of just took what I was learning
from working and going to school and
being in the commercial industry mostly
from being in the commercial Greenhouse
industry and putting it into cannabis
and just taking like I kind of brought
like diff was a new thing back there so
I kind of you know write an article at
diff and uh a bunch of stuff like that
but basically taking just general
Horticulture things that was kind of the
Forefront of the you know Flora culture
or vegetable industry and bringing it
into the Cannabis world and then at the
same time Mark Cameron had this giant
Seed Catalog which was at the time the
only place in the world that you could
buy cannabis seeds from without flying
to Amsterdam so it was like this real
hot
um commodium man who knows how much
money he made off of that definitely a
lot but uh yeah that magazine I mean
High Times was always the biggest and
then we were the next biggest what up to
like quite a few million Maybe I'm Wrong
I Don't Remember the circulation but it
was a substantial circuit relation all
through the world
um and that was kind of but I said I
think it was a moment of time where a
lot of that stuff it was kind of before
the internet was big internet was around
but I think a lot of that stuff just got
replaced but it was good information at
that time that I was putting out but it
really quickly got replaced by like
overgrow and stuff like that but uh yeah
it was a crazy it was a crazy time like
we had we kind of reached a crescendo I
think it was 2003 or 2004 that this kind
of gives you an idea of like who these
sort of running this for that they were
just total activists and Dana Larson's
the guy that I really have a huge amount
of respect for that nobody talks about
but to me he's the biggest activist in
Canada ever and he was kind of you know
kept his head down a little bit but it
kind of reached this uh Crescendo when
at the time the DEA had just opened up
an office in Canada because they were
concerned with all the exporting going
on and stuff like that so they'd opened
up a office in Vancouver which is where
cannabis culture at the time was called
was based and
Mark Emery and Dana and I can't remember
a couple other people from the magazine
um the drug czar had actually come up to
Vancouver and was going to give like a
drug czar whatever speech or something
like a private function and these guys
actually bought a table at it without
people realizing there's a bunch of
activists in the front row and heckled
the drug czar through the whole thing
that was the time when I definitely
regretted being part of that
organization because I didn't sign up
for heckling the drug czar and uh
so the drugs are was at the time I don't
think knew who any of them were even
though Mark Emery was shipping seeds all
over the U.S like crazy and he from what
I confused together went home and said
who the heck are these people that
heckled me through the whole thing and
they're like oh that's you know Mark
Emery and Dana Larson and the biggest
seed sellers in the world and they sell
Over America and they
started a big dea you know investigation
of the whole magazine organization that
ended up in uh Mark Emery going to jail
and a bunch of uh
crazy stuff that went around I don't
think anyone knows exactly what happened
but it was definitely a little
heart-raising I added I had a situation
at that time which I'm sure it's not I'm
still not positive it's what's happened
but I'm pretty sure it's what happened
so at the time like I said I was based
in
Ontario so all the articles I was
writing were coming from
we're just being transmitted digitally
and at the time we didn't I just knew
they'd done this thing with the drug
czar and I was like like the sounds of
that but nothing everything was kind of
going smoothly and we've been operating
for quite a few years with no hassles
and
all of a sudden all this wonky stuff
started coming like I was going back and
forth between Dana was the editor at the
time and I was sending him articles and
he kept coming back and I didn't get the
article and I was like what the heck
there's a bunch of wonky stuff where we
couldn't transmit emails which looking
back was clearly we know that the DEA
was on the servers like looking through
stuff I think I'm sure it was something
to do with that and uh I used to send
them all through uh like from an
internet whatever you call them Cafe so
it couldn't get traced to me and I was
usually I was pretty paranoid back then
so I'd always move around a little bit
but I guess I don't know I get
complacent and I kept every Friday
afternoon or not everybody that it was
like a specific time kind of you know
whatever four o'clock on a Friday
afternoon I'd stop by the same internet
cafe and transmit the article or
whatever we were communicating a bit and
then so one day I'm sitting there and I
was the only person in the cafe
and all of a sudden bang the door comes
open and this cop looking guy comes in
and he walks right past you know about
50 computer Terminals and goes right to
me and like looks over and I was like
that seems a little sketch and he left
and I was like okay well whatever it's
probably being paranoid and uh
two minutes later Ben and he comes again
with another guy that looks like a cop
and they come straight for my like where
I'm sitting there's nobody else there so
I kind of got up and was super paranoid
back there so I was I was uh parked with
three parking lots away in kind of a
busy area
and so I just I first started walking
and I was like holy cow like they're
actually like coming after me so it
ended up with me running through this
parking lot you know dodging cars like
it was in a movie with these two you
know undercover cop looking people
chasing me and I got away and thought
it's kind of like I don't know it sure
felt like that was like the DEA or
something but it seemed so crazy like to
be staking at an internet cafe
um and then like two weeks later they
arrested they took down Mark Emery and
arrested him and extradited him and a
bunch of other people so I think it
probably was we'll never know for sure
but like it was a something I'm totally
proud of I think it was instrumental in
changing kidney I think Canada and the
U.S laws I was always a big believer in
genetics of just that was always the
limiting factor of there wasn't enough
genetics or at the time know-how of how
to grow stuff so I really believed in
just spreading genetics spreading the
know-how of how to do stuff and I really
think that in the U.S that's under I
don't think they realize how much that
probably made a difference because you
couldn't get seeds other than from that
organization it really for I don't
remember how many years it's probably
like six or seven years it really just
flooded the world with high quality
cannabis genetics so I'm super proud of
uh super proud of that not super proud
of really being associated with Mark
Emery but whatever he did some good
things
you mentioned that like for a good chunk
of time say five six years as you said
um you know Mark was really the one
flooding the world with genetics I guess
I'd be interested to hear do you feel
like a lot of what he stocked was good
quality and was what it says it was
because I always remember back to that
breed of Steve's story where he rocks up
with the sweet skunk and Mark was like
whatever we'll just call it Scentsy big
bud or like is sweet skunk or like
whatever it was and I was just like oh
okay like maybe it was a bit more like
you know just whack a name on whatever
or like what was your take do you think
it was pretty above board or it was a
bit like just whatever works uh I think
it was a bit of both I think it was
mostly uh like so how that started from
what I remember is Mark he was
originally everything was just coming
out of Amsterdam and he had a guy
um I won't say his name but there was a
guy that was working over there was
living over there that was kind of uh
um I don't know what exactly he was
doing here but he was shipping he was
just buying seeds and
and moving them to Mark and then he was
just reselling you know like at the time
it was like Sagar maratha and Sensi and
uh Dutch all the original kind of Dutch
ones and
then that guy was actually one of the
guys that came back I believe and
started the BC Seed Company and there
was a bunch of stuff like that but there
was a whole lot of knockoffs so that was
basically Mark started off selling you
know Dutch genetics and any I think just
figured oh crap you can
um just knock off this stuff and then so
nobody really cared most people didn't
really know enough to care they just
were like oh it's Northern Lights but
um yeah I think a whole lot of it was
just like f2s from a 10 pack but there
was definitely some good work like weird
Steve definitely did some real
work but I mean to put it in context I
always not to
at the at the time I remember like this
is way back in the early days when Steve
first get it started I remember we kind
of used to laugh at home because it had
in the in the write-up it was like you
know his breeding operation under two
400 watt lights like it literally said
it in the in the breathing in the
company description like so that's how
stuff started and he definitely you know
disappeared Steve I think the guy did
submit some massive work but that was
kind of the context is like how big were
these places and also keep in mind like
the average size for grows back it was
Tiny compared to what we're used to like
where I was from like before lighter was
pretty much as much as most people ran
10 10 lights was definitely unless you
were like organized crime a 10 lighter
was a big deal and then if you were out
in BC 10 lighters were a little bit more
common and there was definitely like
some 30 or 40 and some big ones but I
would say the average grow at that time
in Canada was four lights so you know
how much breeding was actually you know
how much real breeding was actually
going on
um I think there is definitely some
interesting stuff came out of there but
there was also a ton of like just
um knockoffs that came at a pretty small
population sizes but I would say like
there's definitely some unique Canadian
genetics that got spread around the
world like Mighty might that I already
talked about came out of there text a
lot of time work which is a you know was
a super to Me instrumental outdoor
strain UBC chemo which was one of the
early I'm pretty sure it was like a
Canadian bread you know not related to
Dutch genetics there's definitely some
interesting stuff that came out of there
and got spread through that seed bank
for sure but there was also a lot of
just generic crap there's lots of great
stuff came out of that generic crap too
like I've I grew out the best Northern
Lights I've ever
um grown just came out of one of those
packs and I'm sure it was just a F2 from
Level stuff or something
yeah nice and out of curiosity have you
been following any of the Northern
Lights re-releases from say Todd
McCormick or inspector Matt ride and
have they picked your interest at all or
not particularly uh yeah I followed it
I'm interested but I also remember
I think people that's one of those ones
that people view through rose-colored
glasses that most northern lights at the
time it was it was totally like the
whatever they call it the
state-of-the-art modern indoor indica
and it was but if you compare it if I
had to take most of the most of the
Northern Lights was pretty generic
um so I'm really interested to see what
comes out of that because I definitely
tried some a couple of really good
Northern Lights but I also I grew a lot
of different Northern Lights during that
early 90s period and most of them were
just we'd call them mids these days like
they weren't anything special they were
just like
the hash plants
um so I'm interested to see what comes
out of that
but I I'm not buying any packs of seeds
anytime soon
yeah okay I mean hey you've just piqued
my interest if I
this is a weird situation right but if I
put a gun to your head and I said you
have to buy a pack of seeds right now
like what ones are you gonna get like in
terms of like what what would you get if
you were gonna get one
what what interests you right now uh
I really I'm actually a fan of like some
of the stuff CSI Humboldt's got going I
really like those I'm really a I love
that Elite kindly Elite or Elite clone
S1 stuff I'd probably try like
um
probably maybe some of the I'm kind of
like not so dog headband I like the
sound of some of the headbands I've
tried some really good headbands and you
gotta remember in Canada
it's gotten a lot better but we
generally don't get most of the
Elite clones are are BS right it's like
it's a cookies clone and you get it
you're like this is anything even remote
recurves it's just it's gotten better
now it's gotten legal that some of the
real cuts are going over but generally
we didn't get any of that stuff so I've
tried a lot of Cam I've never tried the
actual clones I've tried a lot of Girl
Scout cookies I've never tried the
actual girl scout cookies clone I don't
think I think it might have made of
there's a lot of stuff like that so if I
was gonna buy seeds it'd probably be
something like uh
probably a headband
um
maybe one of the
A5 type things it's going on A5 Haze but
it would probably be like a headband or
something like that
or also the also one of the oracles the
one I've never tried that I've always
wanted to is a is some of the oracles
because I'd really like to see how that
relates to a lot of the Canada purple
cushions because I would leave that's
it's probably related
yeah definitely I have to agree CSI has
been doing some cool stuff with his uh
Femme stuff and I myself have a pack of
the uh the headband cross lemon tree no
sorry headband cross chemd it's gonna be
fire
that's exactly the same we're on the
same page man that was just typically
the one that I would probably uh go for
if I had to but I don't buy a lot of
seeds I'll never go through all the
seeds I have in a lifetime anyways I
just basically go through clones and
stuff that gets gifted to me
yeah nice that's that's cool to hear
that you got a nice little stash there
if I could just loop back to a point you
made a bit earlier
um just to clarify for myself and anyone
listening
um it sounds like you're sort of of the
thought that uh that that heckling with
that drugs are that talk may have been
like you know the sort of catalyst that
started the whole demise of Mark Emery
is that sort of what you're getting at
it was 100 there was no question if you
look at the time frame it was literally
a hundred percent what what uh happened
there is no doubt at all and there are
some other stuff which I don't want to
get into because it's kind of here say
but I wouldn't be surprised if there was
actually like an undercover age and
dropped into that organization at that
time too it was like I don't think most
people realize like how much of a threat
that group was really perceived by the
DEA at the time I think
um but no there was Zero doubt that
hacking the drugs are absolutely was the
start of Mark every's divine
there you go yeah a bit Brazen isn't it
but nevertheless interesting stuff to
hear for sure so something which we hear
a lot about in the American history is
how uh beneficial that the forums were
to the scene how it promoted a lot of
sharing of genetics things like that
I've never really heard a perspective on
how it affected the Canadian scene would
you say that largely speaking it was the
same as the US in that it was like
groundbreaking you know you could get
all this info people sharing genetics or
would you say like less so of an effect
than what the US saw
um
the information was definitely
groundbreaking like that was I can
totally remember like I was kind of
around since I was never a giant Forum
dude but I was I was on there and I was
right from the start like I literally
remember I can remember the first when
overgrow
launched I remember being there used to
be another Forum called I think it was
called weed base and it was on a server
I think that it was I think it was on
something called Laughing Moon which was
I believe owned by Advanced Nutrients at
the time before they were advanced
nutrients and it was a real low-key
forum and that was the Cannabis sport
that was the biggest cannabis Forum in
the world and I remember
going on there one day and there was a
post that said you are all going to jail
um read this and get out or something
like something crazy where you're in it
was things were paranoid back there I'm
like oh my God like and I remember
clicking on it and it was shebang that
basically was the guy that started
overgrow was who posted it oh don't hold
me this one I'm pretty sure it was
shebang and it was directing you to this
new site to overgrow.com and saying this
was the safe place to go and I remember
going on it then and you could literally
go and that was the time that I was kind
of writing for cannabis culture so you
wanted to like keep up on all the latest
what was going on and I remember
overgrow was so small at that time that
I could click through in like you know
45 minutes and check every post that had
gone on like that week or something in
all the different subheadings and then
within like from what I'm remembering it
was literally like a couple of months it
just like exploded so you couldn't even
like follow the posts in like one sub
for you know evening but there was a ton
of information because it was just that
was the first everyone's just locked in
their own little bubble like my whole
cannabis world back then was about 10
people maybe 20 like you didn't even
tell like you didn't even tell like your
best friends that you grew like it was
really tight and then the internet was
kind of this weird thing where you could
tell
it just gave some and not anonymity and
you'd be like holy cow all these other
people are doing this stuff
um and I would say for me I was already
because I was always kind of on and off
dead tour during that time period or
just or in the 90s and that was kind of
the original so I already had
connections with way more people than
the average Growers had because I'd meet
all these Americans on you know on dead
tour that were were into weed but the
average person like you knew like
whatever a couple of your local crew and
and that was it but no that was
absolutely game changing I I said I
basically that's that and the DEA
involvement that's the reason I stopped
writing because I was like this is
irrelevant once overgrow blew up I was
like this writing is totally irrelevant
it basically made magazines like that
they come like you know Readers Digest
or something
um
but no I think they were absolutely
and I personally when I look back on
that time period I think two things
affected cannabis laws more than
anything
one was the internet specific like
overgrow cannabis world that type of
stuff just spreading the information and
two was people like Mark Emery seeds
just dosing the world with high quality
uh cannabis genetics I honestly think
those were the two pivotal things that
pushed legalization forward
yeah fantastic to hear that and out of
curiosity do you believe that the forums
would ever be able to make a comeback
we've seen a lot of people pushing for
it and a lot of people criticize the the
sort of uh constant feed of Instagram
but at the same time it doesn't seem
like any of the forums have really got a
lot of traction taking off do you think
we'll ever go back or do you think
Instagram's sort of here to stay
I don't think we'll ever go back to the
forums I do definitely miss parts of it
where it definitely
um
I don't like this stuff with Instagram
where stuff goes through so quickly
where you used to be like for instance I
know there's a thread on purple push
there that I always remember and it's
just like that was a classic there was a
bunch of them like that but they were
just classic threads where it's like it
was like a thing on BC Purple Kush and
there's a bunch of people you know
posting and they're like it was sitting
there you know active for probably a few
years and you got some good information
on it where now if you said something
like that just like it's a 24-hour
discussion and then it's it's just gone
into the IG ABY this
um so I have I kind of feel like it was
a moment in time I don't think it's
probably a
coming back they're still I'd go on
there every once in a while and there's
still some discussions which seems like
it's kind of some of the older dudes
that never moved on to sell things
yeah yeah yeah it's uh it's an
interesting one I'm I'm like yourself it
would be cool to see him come back but
I'm not entirely sold myself uh but
given we are in the sort of modern legal
uh climate it'd be good to talk a little
bit about that I know that you've
transitioned your work over to the legal
Market working in uh the Canadian
cannabis industry shall we call it
um what's that transition been like for
you as someone who historically was you
know doing their own thing
um and now suddenly to be working around
people it's all legal out in the open
how's that been for you because I know
that a lot of the American guys
especially some of the big players even
to this day they still really struggle
to sort of act in a way that reflects
how legal it is you know they're always
still like sort of looking over their
shoulder because of just the experiences
would you say you've had a similar
experience or is it a bit more casual
for you
similar so just to be clear like I kind
of haven't been in the commercial scene
for a long time I'm kind of one of those
people that I've been around I think
most people know me just because I've
been around for a long time
um I and I rolled with a lot of some of
my friends were pretty
um hardcore I've always kind of kept my
head down so it's been a long time since
I was like
actively involved in the in the
commercial scene so my kind of thing is
I've kind of always been around it on
different levels
um but I've never been like it's been a
long time since I've been like uh you
know a baller
um and
I've kind of I've worked in the
greenhouse industry so on both sides so
I've kind of seen watch this I'm kind of
I think a what's an arm's length
Observer so I wasn't I didn't really
have anything invested they weren't
taking I wasn't making a living from the
Cannabis industry so I
whatever wasn't hurting me seeing the
legal stuff I I like I really like
seeing people not going to jail like I
think you can't lose sight of that I've
seen so many people's lives over the
time just completely destroyed I had one
of my second my second closest friend
committed suicide and it was
um as far as I'm concerned as a Fallout
from being arrested and just having for
growing at the time it was a 600 water
and he was on the front page of the like
basically a personal group front page of
the newspaper for a week or two the you
know tax people coming out fight
haunting them for years and they
destroyed his life over a 600 watt
garden and he ended up killing himself
and I saw so many stories like that that
I just think it's important that
everyone keeps
that in the front there's a lot of lives
ruined there's still people sitting in
jail for stuff like that
um
and I do find it
it doesn't really there's a lot of stuff
that I don't like about it so I kind of
said I work
um I don't work for one of the
facilities like we're kind of work in
like supplying and Consulting some of
the silly so I've seen pretty much most
of them across Canada and the thing I
think that stands out the most to me is
what saddens me about it is especially
in BC there's a lot of cool places to
live in British Columbia
um like that don't have any jobs so but
traditionally like basically since back
in you know back in the 70s but
especially since like the late 80s when
they endure stuff took off that's what
paid for people to live in these
beautiful spots like the Kootenays which
is like the interior BC or up on the
Sunshine Coast which is like north of
Vancouver or Vancouver Island there was
no jobs there but you could make a
living running a 10 lighter or something
like that and that's pretty much done
there's still people doing it but it's
getting really hard and that I find is
that saddens me for sure and I think
that was a really great part of like
Canadian culture and you've seen I've
seen firsthand in some of those areas
that were kind of black market-centric
spots and also the big licensed producer
opens up there and these guys went from
making you know a lot of people weren't
getting rich in canvas they were making
like you know 80 or 100 000 a year or
something like that tax free and then
all of a sudden they're making you know
fifty thousand dollars and paying tax so
their wages just kind of got cut in a
quarter and then you know this is the
money's not going into the local economy
anymore the money's going somewhere else
so that that I really find
um saddening but
um
overall like I'm pretty positive about
it I think it kind of went through a bit
of a dead zone off the start where it
just went really corporate and then
there's kind of a second wave coming
where I've got like I've got a bunch of
good buddies that run licensed places
that are doing okay and they're like
legit dudes like they I think they
really love what they're doing and
they're not super corporate
um but it is what it is at least
nobody's going to jail anymore
yeah hugely that's uh actually a really
relevant Point I've been trying to talk
to people about because you see a lot of
sentiment these days about
people feeling really frustrated that as
you said you know they can no longer
pull 100k from their Garden it's now 50.
and a lot of them get really frustrated
um about that and complain about the
laws and or we should have never gone
legal blah blah blah but as you said at
the end of the day keeping people out of
jail or sadly in the case of your friend
you know committing suicide I mean I
know that that's not entirely related
but keeping people out of jail should be
the number one metric of success and it
is unfortunate that people's livelihoods
are affected but
um yeah it is good that we can hopefully
keep people from being put in prison for
just growing a plant really
yeah and I think you got to keep it in
perspective I mean why were people able
to go make you know make a whole bunch
of money you know living in some cool
spot where there's no jobs just because
that's what you were paying for
you know the risk and the risk is gone I
mean it wasn't because they were
mastered Growers or anything a lot of
the time it was because they were you
know risking going to jail and I think a
lot of them lost
um you know lost sight of that and you
saw a lot of people that also you know I
have a couple of friends that you know
they're kind of genetics Geeks and
they've always got all the most elite
clones and and I think they really
thought everybody and they do have some
of the nicest weed around and I think
they really thought
everybody was buying from them because
they had you know these super Elite cuts
and they were a great grower and then
when they found it real quick was 90 of
the people were buying from them because
they had wheat and there were a lot of
people just don't care about weed as
much as you or I do and they're just
like whatever's cheapest and those guys
went down pretty uh pretty quick sad but
whatever that's that's
kind of what you know the world's like
yeah exactly and it's you know it's
about evolving with the times and I
still see a lot of people who are able
to you know um diversify their income
streams and still stay in the Cannabis
industry I'd be interested in hearing
though you referenced how some of the
big uh companies that initially invested
in the Canadian scene uh sort of went
defunct and now there's like the second
wave what's it like now do you think
that a lot of the big AG has realized
look we can't just come in here and make
a bajillion dollars like we were hoping
to it's actually a sort of a technically
challenging operation do you think that
we're gonna see like a scaled back
corporate version of it or do you think
that people will come in buy out these
defunct facilities that are now for sale
like you know Pennies on the dollar and
they'll try to do it right how do you
foresee the Canadian scene going forward
uh I think I'll probably be driving
around showing my grandkids one day he's
rusted out all the greenhouses and
warehouses and telling them the story
about office you know the crazy cannabis
boom that never really materialized
um I think just to be clear if you can
look at what actually happened in Canada
a lot of it wasn't big AG money or
anything like that it was investment
money so for instance
um like the you know some of those big
ones like
um they came on and it was a
it was his investment thing and like for
instance the town that I grew up in
um or didn't grow but I've lived in for
a long time
um there was a big facility opened up
there and
people started and I knew a bunch of
people that literally became like
millionaires you know invested you know
a hundred thousand dollars and all of a
sudden they're sitting on 1.2 million
um they just blew up and then all their
friends were like holy cow like yield
this made a million dollars on the 30
million dollar investment with this LP
so then they all invested their money so
it was really driven by just the average
person all trying to cash in on this
jackpot and you know I was one of them I
made a bunch of money off the start and
I lost it off the long term
um but that's kind of what drove it it
wasn't a lot of like big money it was a
whole bunch of Average Joe's dumping
their money and not knowing what they
were investing in and then I think what
happened is these people just had you
know it was I don't remember I never
followed it that closely but it was like
you know hundreds I mean the one place
you know just one of the facilities was
worth 150 million dollars and they had
like you know three of that size and all
of them are shuttered but there was just
it didn't make any sense like I remember
um myself and one of the other guys had
kind of been around nothing the Cannabis
world but just in that you know the
Horticulture Greenhouse world for a long
time and we we're doing the math and I
was like I don't know I'm thinking maybe
40 acres could supply all of Canada and
then it was I think at one point we were
like over a thousand or something it was
just crazy it didn't make any sense but
nobody was really thinking about it they
were just like well we've got you know a
billion dollars to spend that all these
investors gave us so we better spend it
and they were trying to I think there
was a lot of fight for whoever had the
biggest production space was going to
win and what's really proved out is
those people all failed and now the
second wave is kind of it's still
investors but it's a lot of stuff like
uh oil and gas decided to you know put
you know put some money into these much
smaller facilities or some of the
um First Nations
um like the native Indian bands you know
Hudson cash have put it in more stuff
like that and they're much more
realistic like they're smaller
um they're not so ridiculous with all
the regulations and it it makes much
more sense the second wave but I think
for sure a lot of that first wave is
just gonna like rust or I don't know
maybe it's going to grow cucumbers or
something I don't even know what they're
gonna do with some of those facilities
but it was Jeff it was definitely like
it was kind of like the gold boom it's
that type of thing happened
yeah yeah certainly I was thinking.com
boom but you're right I guess the Gold
Rush exactly or.com or.com same thing
yeah yeah a lot of parallels there
that's really interesting so I guess
from your sort of professional
experience when you go to large
facilities what are some of the big
issues you see that are stopping them
well maybe not the ones you visit but
just in general like what are some of
the hurdles that a large producer is
going to come across that are going to
get in the way of them producing top
quality product because I'm assuming
they're all coming in going yeah you
know we're going to run these
greenhouses it's all going to be like
the AAA plus the best on the market and
then maybe it doesn't pan out that way
what are some of the issues they have to
overcome uh the issue is now are a bit
different like before when they first
started you'd go in and be like oh my
goodness they literally didn't have a
clue what they were doing some of them
um like it was horrible
um now I would say most of them are
pretty good the issue that I see the
most is it's just each it's just the the
pro it's the difference between all the
black market guys not to dismay my black
market Brothers
but they're all you know those legal
guys don't know what they're doing and
and I'm like I've been in the black
market guys places more than most and
I've been in the legal ones and honestly
a lot of those legal stuff looks better
than the black market when it comes down
um and the facility like so they've just
got great facilities it looks great and
I haven't I just had literally a place
that I was at this week that I have seen
I would consider the top grower in
Canada for the legal place like just
absolutely gorgeous product I've seen it
come down I've seen it on the dry table
I'm like this looks amazing this is
unbelievably high quality weed and then
I go to the legal store and buy the
exact batch that I bought and it's not
that great and I think the difference is
mostly age where it's just by the time
you know they cure it and send it out
for Quality tests and THC tasks to get
the results back and then get it up into
the you know the pipeline the
distribution Pipeline and then somebody
you know the middleman buys it and then
the end store buys it and then it sits
in inventory in the store before the end
user buys it I don't know how long that
cycle is but it's definitely way longer
than the black market and when I see it
I'm like this this looks like old weed
it looks like no different than good
weed that I grew and stuck in a jar for
you know a year or a good weed that my
friend was a black market grower did the
same thing it just looks like old weed
so for sure I think that's the number
one thing and maybe there's stuff like
you know flashing it with you know
nitrogen gas and stuff like that it's
just oxidized weed
um I think there's a lot of other stuff
in there but uh that's for sure in my
opinion the top one and then the other
one I'm just like for God's sake
somebody grows something other than like
wedding cake Crashers or nothing not to
diss it I think those are great strange
but it's just like everything's the same
like there's not a whole lot of unique
stuff out there and I'm
yeah it could definitely they could
widen the pallet but I guess they just
do what the the market sells but growing
wise a lot of them are really on point
they get I get I think they get unfairly
uh uh smashed these days I think they're
doing a good job
yeah nice and out of curiosity what are
some of the really popular strains in
the facilities at the moment
oh man I honestly don't even bother
keeping track I just I just call them
like glitter cookies it's just all
different versions of cookies which I
you know I like cookies they're not
dissing it but to me it all almost 100
of it just likes like different versions
of cookies
um
like I said buy cookies I mean also all
the I don't keep track of all the
gelatos and wedding cake I just consider
all that coming out of that you know
cookie family
um type stuff but all that you know
purple
dense glitter weed
um
there's a yeah I don't know it
definitely just seems to Center on there
but I honestly I'm not the best person
to ask about the legal Market because
I've literally bought from the legal
Market about like two times in my entire
life I've Just Seen I've seen a lot of
it grown and I've seen the occasional
thing that one of my friends will buy
but my whole most of my like crowd is
highly insulated even though I see it
all the time all my all the stuff I
generally smoke or my friend smoke is
all black market or just home grower
stuff
yeah nice love to hear it love to hear
it keeping the uh the Homegrown strong
now I would love to ask you because I've
been following this myself so I'm sure
others are Keen as well you've done some
killer looking GMO sweet skunk hybrids I
think you created them yourself would
you be able to give us a bit of info on
um how those turned out it sounds like a
great Cross of like new school meets old
school how did it go yeah that was kind
of my plan so it was just I said
um
I really like some of those well like
sort of for one of your listeners like
sweet skunkers
debatable whether it's a nl5 so it for
sure sweet's fun comes back to about
1994 so which is kind of like back in
the
um Naval days and we know for sure it
had Northern Lights it's for sure
Northern Lights hazy
um
maybe it has grapefruit in it maybe
doesn't depends who you ask that's
official story it came from breeder
Steve's Camp but it's regardless of
what's in it it's for sure a Northern
Lights KC
um Haze dominant hybrid and it's been
around I I personally consider like one
of the most elite poems in Canada
because if you look at like the cruise
that it came from it came from you know
breeders to use crew and and uh you look
at the people that still hold that
cutting around and they had access to
Romulan and all these crazy genetics and
sweet tooth and all that and the only
you don't see any Sweet Tooth clones
still going around you don't see any
Romulan clones still going around for
the most part you see a whole lot of
people that held on to uh sweet skunk
um
so I kind of just to me I just kind of
to me as a classic like Canadian
heirloom and I like sativas but I don't
I'm like kind of like some bottom end to
go with them I don't really like the I
kind of like some mercy and stuff and
I'd like some uh flavor I like kind of
some of the modern flavors so I just
threw I just reversed um
sweets got gone to just all the Clones
that I had and happened to have a GMO in
there and it wasn't actually my plan I
just kind of threw out the progeny of a
bunch of different stuff that I had in
the GMO one is the one that really
clicked some of the
um I was just basically looking for uh
to pull a really nice Haze dominant you
know personal cut
um out of it and honestly the I think
which is kind of in line with what you
hear with a lot of haze stuff it sweet
skunk puts out a lot of junk and I think
that's kind of the story of Hayes is I
don't know that anyone's ever going to
release like a really great Haze seed
line they could pop like it pays
dominance seed line if you pop like a 10
pack and you're like this is it this is
the keeper it's more like you pop like a
hundred and find one that's really nice
and a whole bunch that are pretty
mediocre and that was kind of the story
of uh
definitely there's some nice stuff in
there and there's also a bunch of uh
really midsy stuff in there but I got
the ones I I kept three out of what I
think about 150 that I popped that are
all uh
um super nice but a lot of them went
right in the in the hash pile for sure
I love it uh no room for the week in the
stable that's that's really cool and out
of curiosity what sort of project would
you want to work on next given you know
you've done a lot of the sort of haze
type stuff with this sweet skunk project
do you want something different or are
you like more keen to get down the
rabbit hole
uh I kind of I'm kind of I've been
around like I said I've been around a
long time I kind of
between I've traveled a lot so I've kind
of got to experience a lot of what's
going around in the U.S a lot of what's
going around in Canada and I've gone to
the Netherlands quite a few times so
I've tried everything and I kind of know
what I like and so I've kind of Taken
and said I'm not a commercial breeder I
have no interest in doing I kind of just
breed for my own head
um and it kind of just comes into a few
camps like I like purple kush stuff I
like
um stuff like the you know Haze stuff
um
you know like some of like the Bubba
stuff and I've kind of got a pretty good
stable
um trying to think the only thing I
actually plan on doing is that that Haze
project isn't really done so both most
of the stuff I probably don't have a lot
of plans for that sweet spin project was
kind of the first stage so one of the
things I always really liked that stood
out in history to me is Neville taste so
I bought a quite a few packs back in
like the I think it was around 2000 or
so back when Neville and Shanty released
their original level says I have no idea
maybe it's the same now I personally
doubt it but he was for sure the
original Neville caves which was the
haze a male
um I can't remember the exact mix but it
was a the two male hazes Haze ahc and
Northern Lights and that was like jungle
weed but they had some crazy Finos that
I would consider in that class the best
that I've ever smoked and I've never
seen anything similar to it
um so that was kind and the thing with
Haze is if you want to find a really
good one that you want it's pretty
expensive to be buying all those packs
of seeds because I really think you need
to buy like 100 to find something really
good and uh so I kind of went at it from
another point of like okay that's the
haze C side was the sweets Gunk and I
found something that I really liked kind
of modernized a little bit with the GMO
like just above the turp and the potency
up and now I want to try what I really
want out of is kind of one of those
incensey Neville's Haze type of types
um so I right now I just reversed uh
that Band-Aid number seven on the really
late flowering like 17 week flowering uh
Haze phenos with that sweet skunk and
it'll probably try to find some other
stuff that's got that Haze a side in it
to bring it in and then just sift
through those but I don't really I guess
they're technically breeding projects to
me they're just sifting projects I'm not
a I kind of look at cannabis to next a
little bit different than a lot of
people I kind of look at I used to be
down the same line with everyone with
all the ibls and all that and I kind of
look at it it's more like when they
breed like trees or strawberries or
these other like really outcrossing
species where it's just like you kind of
whack an elite clone an elite clone and
grow it a whole crapload seeds and take
the one that makes the combination we
want so that's kind of more what I'm I
don't really consider much of a breeding
project as just like a genetic sifting
product that's about the only thing I'd
probably plan on
on
working like to make some more
productive use of my space just growing
some of the Clones that have sifted over
the years
yeah nice beautiful stuff well I'm
incredibly jealous I think that some of
those uh Neville's Hayes on to the uh
the 16 17 week sweet skunk Finos would
be some beautiful stuff for all of our
sativa lovers out there I would be
interested to hear you just you just
referenced it yourself you know flaring
out some of the Clones you've sort of
acquired over the years what is the one
clone that you used to have that you
really wish you could get back
um not many of them to be honest uh I
guess it's the one that stands out I
really liked
um
there was uh when Legends used to have
uh that Legends ultimate Indica which
that was this Ortega clone that actually
came from uh Ed Rosenthal crossed with
the sweet tooth and I said I'm not a
sweet tooth fan at all but uh that
popped out these crazy like Jurassic
looking
indicofinos and I used to run like back
in the early 2000s or whenever whenever
that was reader Steve was really pumping
all that stuff out from Switzerland I
ran quite a few packs of that and most
of them I didn't like their really sweet
tooth dominant but they popped at these
crazy or tagofinos and uh those I really
like they don't stand up like today the
flavor definitely wasn't the same but
they just had
super insane uh Mercy name they were
just so heavy
um I don't think I think it was a fairly
flat profile compared to like an OG or
cookies or something like that but they
were just really heavy indicas and
that's what I really prefer
um that one I missed I used to have a
really good Ortega clone
um or whatever the terrigofino Clone and
probably the biggest one it was a couple
of indicators like I used to have an old
Northern Lights Number One clone that
was really good
and I also used to have a Northern
Lights we think it was in Northern
Lights Number two but that's the one
that really stands out and that was
we got it like whatever one of those
stories it was like from my friend's
Uncle who had it since like the 80s and
I think it was if you it was one you
could actually Trace back and I'm like
okay like that literally came from like
1988 1987 kind of period and it was like
this super
um it's actually I got the very first
picture I ever posted on Instagram is
from that clone and uh it was like this
super squat indica and it looked a lot
like the a lot of the Northern Lights
you'll see and the terp profile was just
off the hook like and I've never tried
anything similar to that there's lots of
stuff today that I think is like
comparable but way different
um I really like to get that one and
that was one of those ones that to me
always stood the test of time that
you know people didn't keep clones a lot
back then for a long because it was just
whatever someone would grow for a year
and there would be like police pressure
on them so they shut down and not keep
their clones and it was hard to get
stuff back in that one I remember like
losing a bunch of times and every time I
went to look for it you know over like a
10-year period I could always find a
friend of a friend of a friend who still
had that old NL clone that came out it
came out of Squamish in DC which is a
little small place north of Vancouver
and uh yeah I mean I think that thing
was like I don't remember like we had it
up I think I lost it maybe 10 years ago
and it was from like 1986 or 87 or 88
something in that definitely late 80s
um
and I've never seen anything similar to
that so definitely like that I'd
probably like and then some of the
incense the Novelties used to have
that's about it most of the stuff like I
kind of
that's kind of what I find interesting
with genetics is the stuff just kind of
repeats like that old famous Northern
lure that Northern Lights Number One
clone that that I really like from back
there it's pretty darn similar to Bubba
and Bubba's got basically everything it
had plus like some better flavor to it
so I don't think we lose a ton of the
stuff I kind of think a lot of it just
gets a little bit improved and the name
gets changed over time
yeah certainly as I get more experience
with the NLS I see a lot of bubber in it
for sure so that's that's cool to hear
that um you see that as well
at this point I think it'd be good to to
run through some of our quick fire
questions I've got a little alternative
list of questions for you in case you
had prepared some answers I wanted to
keep you on your toes so I wanted to ask
you in your opinion what do you think is
the most underrated Canadian clone or
genetic
to honestly it's the king it's not a lot
the Canadian gene pool is actually
pretty shallow when you digging into it
it's mostly American genetics
um underrated one
two
I don't know if I could go with an under
under uh sorry I think that like this is
my personal opinion I really like the
death Bubba which is like a modern one
that's pretty commercialized I
personally think that's like that's one
of the Clones that I would if I had to
pick a couple I'd pick death bubble I
think that's the
um
I think sometimes just because it's
super popular doesn't mean it's not also
super good I think that's a good one
nice that's good I I would be interested
in hearing how does that differ from
Bubba because I haven't heard and seen a
lot of it but never really read too much
specifics about it
it's a it's a baba I said I've never
i've smoked a lot of like Bubba from
seed I haven't smoked any of the like
pre-98 or like the ones you're like okay
this is the legit cut I haven't smoked
that I'm like for sure that's to compare
it with what I can tell is just a it's a
really nice Bubba but it's got some fuel
to it like a little bit more if you I
think it was like uh
think if I had to guess it probably
originally came from uh pip Swede from
souvenir seeds or something like that
and the story was it was because he's
the only guy ever seen it it was as a
death star or one of those death things
that came out of Ohio
um and it was like that I think it's the
choco Sour Diesel cut crossed with that
Scentsy star there's a Scentsy star that
was around that Ohio area that's really
good
um crossed into one of the Bubbas and
maybe it wasn't from from the hips but I
know he's made a lot of that stuff
around that time period and it actually
came into it was one of the dispensaries
in kind of that gray Market scene before
it got legal and it was like for a while
it was like the top clone going around
to
BC and it was locked down hard and I'm
not even sure what I have the most
common one that's going around whether
it's the actual original I don't know
um but I I really like it from my
personal
um thing I like those narcotic narcotic
indicas but I just consider a bubble
with some uh with a bit more fuel to it
yeah nice okay well hey I'm gonna have
to keep an eye out that sounds like it's
uh pretty nice actually if it's got a
bit of sour d and Scentsy star in there
but like I said that's it's actually in
America it's actually American genetics
it just goes around in Canada like most
of the stuff yeah okay out of curiosity
I like I know people say that you know
pink cushes had its day in the sun I I
haven't had it that much but I I think
it's the best where do you rate it do
you think it's like we're done with it
or what's your thoughts
no so I'm kind of the opposite to most
people how I do is I don't pay attention
to the hype at all usually and I kind of
go like I think I think I told them
before like ogs were going around for
like at least a decade before I even
bothered trying them because I'm just so
just been around so long it's it's
usually the hype isn't that isn't
actually worth the hype and I've just
wasted a ton of time chasing that crap
when I was younger so now I kind of just
don't even pay attention and when
something like deathclub is a great
example where that BC usually the really
good stuff floats to the top and it
stays around for a long time and when I
see stuff staying around I'm like oh
maybe I'll try that and
pink Kush definitely was passed that
test I personally think it's super nice
I like it I don't consider it as good to
me I consider it very similar to like an
OG and I consider OG better
um so I think it's like the same type I
personally think that OG is a higher
quality I think being coach probably
yields better and it's a nicer Growers
part I think it's super nice like I
don't think it's probably going anywhere
but I personally like to choose between
an OG and a pink pressure choose OG nice
nice maybe a reflection of uh how little
I've tried pincush is why I still like
it who knows
um one of our normal quickfire questions
we ask people what is your most favorite
cannabis experience you've ever had so
be it like you know just trying a
certain strain a certain hit of hash
like what really stands out to you as
one of the most memorable
[Music]
most memorable and again some of these
ones it's like I don't know was it
really that great or was it just because
you were an experienced smoker but like
I grew up it was all hash right it was
you got it was all I grew up when it was
just Imports around you got you couldn't
even smoke you couldn't even sell
homegrown like if you wanted to sell
whatever skunk number one you had to
like press it into a brick and make it
go all prouder and sell it as Mexican or
something so I kind of grew up around
the import and the part of Canada was
from it was all hash and most of it was
Afghan hash
um or you know that border actually it's
produced on like the you know Afghan
Pakistan area and every once in a while
we get something different and this
actually when I look back it seemed like
really low quality hash and it was like
a blonde Lebanese and I think in
hindsight that was probably not that I
would consider Lebanese like a super
it's a sativa but it's not like a
whatever it's not like a haze or
something like that
um
but I totally remember being at like a
whatever like a bush party which is
um on the side of this cliff and smoking
this Lebanese hash for the first time
and that's one of the few experiences
that I would say so this is way back
when I was like 18 or something like
that and back in the 80s and that's one
of the few cannabis experience that I
would like compare to like taking acid
or mushrooms like it was very
um
psychedelic and again maybe it was just
the fried grown-up smoke in these like
super heavy Afghan hashes and maybe that
was just one of my first real sativa
experiences but that one really stands
up and my mind it had a crazy flavor and
this really intense cerebral eye whereas
I just remember sitting off by myself on
the side of this Cliff going into like
deep deep introspective thoughts that so
that probably is the one to stand there
the most still it was a long time ago
sounds like a beautiful experience I'm
very jealous I'm not sure I've ever had
proper Lebanese uh hash maybe years ago
in Amsterdam but like who even knows
what that was really
most of it sucks most of it is not very
good
there you go okay so uh we're gonna drop
you off on an island what three genetics
you're gonna take is it going to be
clones or seeds you want to do some seed
sifting yourself what are we going to
leave you with
no I'd probably take clones I've popped
a lot of seeds in my time I think I'm
getting older in my retirements When I
Grow clones really well I would
definitely I said I'm not a big sativa
guy but I really the one I actually I
like kind of those heavy
heavy Neville's Haze types but other
than for like what I would consider like
a classic sativa the only one I really
smoke regularly is that uh Roberts Creek
Congo I would definitely take that even
though I don't really smoke it a ton I
really like having it around for uh if
you ever want to smoke in the daytime or
anything
uh
probably the death Bubba
and something purple I don't know it's
like a purple kush or uh I like those
almost like a almost like cookies type
but when it's like I don't even know
what the terp profile is that kind of
funky purple cushy lavender like a
lavender Turf I find I've tried a lot of
stuff that's pretty similar I like that
lavender eater stuff but uh those are
probably the three some one of those
purpley lavender types
the Congo and uh some death Bubba for
night time
beautiful stuff beautiful stuff so for a
final question I'd love to ask you if
you go back in time anywhere any place
to get one genetic or cut or whatever it
may be where are you going when and what
are you grabbing
um
so I'm not a mushroom I know everyone
talks about like their Landry they're
gonna go back to Afghanistan and stuff
and I do actually travel a lot but I
don't really have a lot of interest in
traveling to other countries I really
like travel around North America
um I would probably and I also like
people doing other like a lot of the
sifting before me I would probably go on
dead tour somewhere
um
both to catch some good Dead shows and
to catch some of some that was all dead
tour back in the day like that was
really to me I look at it as like a
funnel point where all the best genetics
are all the best weed going around in
the U.S
ended up on dead tour so I would
probably take like
dead tour maybe back in like the 80s
sometime maybe before just before the
seed bank or something so like
definitely something in the 80s and then
I think you could catch the combo of
like what was going around there before
you know Neville just blew up the scene
but you know I think that's really one
of the nuclear events that happened in
cannabis is Neville like just not
necessarily that he was like the be-all
and I know he just spread so much of
very similar genetics everywhere I kind
of like to maybe go in there whatever
mid 80s or early 80s before that was
around but I think there was a lot of
domestic cultivation
on dead tour and uh catch some bread
Brent uh Midland shows while I was there
because he was an awesome guitar or
awesome keyboardist
hell yeah sounds like a good one to pick
I like that a lot
so
before I I definitely want to give you
an opportunity to give some comments and
shout outs but make sure you also let
people know where they can find you on
social media
uh on social media just I'm just on IG
which is direwolf dot uh OG I don't
really do much stuff
outside of that these days uh in the
Cannabis Realm
and shout outs just all my uh all my
black market people uh they're still
rocking on trying to survive or moving
on into the new market best of luck to
them exactly that so again thank you so
much for coming on the show giving us a
rundown on Canadian history on the legal
markets the Futures and a bit of your
own plans uh again direwolf thank you
for coming on the show really appreciate
it oh thanks for thanks for having me
man it's always good uh giving
conversations with you