hello welcome to the next episode of the
podcast the cannabis podcast for budding
enthusiasts it's great to be back after
a short break and we hope we didn't
leave you all with too much withdraws
his show as always was brought to you by
420 Australia n OG s organic garden
solutions in this episode we're joined
by one of the most controversial figures
in the industry the man himself man
right here we go thanks for having me so
the first question I like to ask people
is let's go back to the start you know
what was your first experience with
cannabis my first experience with
cannabis my dad was a grower and a
smuggler and a dealer of all kinds of
different wonderful drugs when I was
young so I mean one of the first smells
I remember smelling was cannabis and
that that's how far I went back you know
I was able to water for him when I was
little and really at during those years
I had no interest in it it was a
terrible chore in there as they got
older of course the interest grew a lot
more when I started smoking and so what
was the first strain you remember
smoking Oh God you know we didn't really
have names for strains back then so it's
just like skunk bud you know that's
pretty much what they called it all of
it sometimes they call it like red hair
or orange hair which really didn't mean
anything yeah it just happened to have
more orange or more red hair
maybe that's pretty much the only names
that they ever called any of it yeah
okay and do you think that any of that
stuff you would like consider working
now some of that glorious Oh God
you know I mean a lot of its gonna be
the Mexican stuff baby's very little
Colombian at that time because I was I
was too young to really hit the
Colombian era so a lot of it was gonna
be a lot of the really shitty shittily
grown very moldy Mexican stuff they were
pushing through Arizona in California so
probably not
not a whole lot of wonderful things
coming through there and so before you
got into breeding yourself
were there ever any breeders you were
kind of looking up toward was it more of
just like a natural progression to do it
yourself
mm-hmm see Ingemar who created my
Twitter of course that was a big strain
when I was young you know that was one
of the first name strains that we heard
about other than Alaskan Thunder [ __ ]
Matanuska Valley Thunder from up of
course blueberry with DJ short the name
was well-known and a lot of the stuff
Neville shown maker did the you know was
it like the in all five Big Bud a lot of
that stuff was very big around that time
as well so those were some of the bigger
names around the time yeah and so how do
you fill those genetics stand up to some
of the ones today you know it's like a
contested topic whether you know older
stuff was better than now um you know
like you could still go back to a lot of
those old Norton like lipase lines and
there's people like tera ho they'll work
those now and it's still the same same
lines that are available back then and
they're still just as dank as anything
we're putting out now it's just you know
as with anything there's a large
phenotypic selection they need to go on
and it takes a little art election to go
through all that stuff and there's a lot
of phenotypes and I mean back then
people weren't doing these massive
selections like they can do now you know
the space was so much more limited but
ya understand the test of time there's
so many that still do it's just a matter
of what people prefer a lot of what
people prefer now is the visual look of
like the hard you know dense nugs and
that that wasn't what it looked like as
much back then you still had a lot of
the sativa Airy buds yeah yeah I've
noticed that that real swollen Brack to
kind of look from like that cookies
house is very popular yeah especially
out here yeah do you find that um
essentially do kind of subscribe to that
idea that some people have that those
older genetics were you know some of the
best and we've watered them down in a
sense or more just taken in a different
but equal direction
I'd say you know I mean even if you look
at the THC values they've actually
increased over all the years so I mean
in that sense that if you just look at
the THC percentage and a lot of people
subscribe to that being the most
important factor with with cannabis if
you if you believe that way which I
don't personally then yeah we've
increased and made everything better but
I mean just through selection alone I
mean even if people aren't breeders
they're gonna keep picking the best just
as a whole the ratio is gonna keep going
up as far as what the best is and I
think today we have a wider selection a
more diverse selection of really amazing
stuff you know it's not just the one or
two skunk types you know yeah okay so I
mean if we go back a bit now like some
of the earliest information I could find
on you as a breeder was you being a part
of that small crew the modern militia
with lumper and the blazers and haze man
how did have come about and like I was a
bit of a follow up what led to the
breakdown of that well I wasn't really
in the militia crew it's just friends
with all of them like live but it was a
good friend he still is
Mona's a good friend he was Hays man
made a lot of the gear for Mona the
breakdown I mean I would stay probably
stepping on toes saying it but I mean
motive retires three times a year so I
think that's kind of what happened
people were just like oh man like he's
gonna retire no you know and like some
people start going away and then you
know he's back a few months later he
then comes back and retires so you know
I mean more power power to him
and so I guess in that hidden retired
yeah I mean you still he's still around
so he's still who's still do this thing
still making cool [ __ ] so but yeah that
a lot of those guys are still around
yeah so I guess you know d-did you kind
of start out on your own from the
beginning or were you kind of teamed up
with someone to begin with what when I
first started like getting into serious
breeding my mentor was a guy named James
Hogg Gonzalez who made the original hogs
breath out of San Diego and he taught me
a lot of what was going
with breeding in and all the work he had
done with the hast breath and I got to
work on lines with him we released a few
seed lines and then he passed away so
that was my first real experience
working with real treat her hands-on and
releasing lines we also had the san
diego river growers society which was
basically a collective there was 32 of
us at one point and we would basically
grow we could arm our own money into it
we grow only for giving weed away to
cancer internally ill patients
there was no it wasn't like a collective
where we give them to a cheap or
whatever you know the cost came out of
our pockets and we did it just because
there was no other collective in San
Diego doing it and it was it was just it
was a curried crab for a lot of people
and we wanted to push against that yeah
okay
and so was that kind of what drawed you
to breeding initially were you trying to
develop better strains that collective
or was that like gonna track the first
thing that initially tried to get me to
breed or let me down that path was my
best friend's mom had pancreatic cancer
and she kind of raised me and during
that time I saw the only thing that was
giving her her dignity back to be able
to get out of bed even like come have
dinner with us was being able to smoke
and only some huge strains would work
and it was hit or miss all the time so
during that time was when I really
really got heavily into it when she was
still alive and she she only lived about
eight months with that and I just kept
going from then on out and and then came
the the San Diego Society came out of
that you volved out of that kinda okay
yeah that makes sense
and so were you initially just
interested in regular seeds or was
feminized seeds always something on your
mind seeing is that something you are
fairly well known for um you know back
then it didn't matter to me because I
had already learned really early on how
to reverse plant so it didn't matter to
me whether I had a male or a female
I can always refer a female and make a
line so it's either/or
um there's a lot of stigma between our
back then about breeding with feminized
seeds but looking at the science even
back then it was just like I realized oh
this is like old wives tale like these
people don't understand the science
behind it and they're just gonna keep
repeating the same ol [ __ ] until they
understand it so
yeah I've always been pretty open to
breeding with both yeah so I mean if we
want to get into the kind of biology of
all that do you believe [ __ ] you know
pollen produced from a feminized plant
is different on the genetic level from
pollen from just a straight
hermaphrodite plant yes yeah maybe not
so much on a genetic level because all
cannabis is is a dual sex plant I mean
all of it is it's just how much it
expresses it how much of the how much of
the hormones are activated in the plant
now we need a reversal plant using like
silver thiosulfate which is what most of
us use you're tricking the plant
not necessarily into thinking it's
stressed but but to releasing more
healthy
it's halting Jabril and I remember
correctly no it's bringing in jibrell
and halting uh ethylene production which
is the gas ethylene and by doing that
it's it's making the plant or more male
characteristics less female and it's not
causing us any stress to the plant but
when you're when you're hermaphrodite in
a plant you're actually bringing that
stress into it and you're pushing the
stress on into its progeny to the seeds
so that I mean that's the difference and
you know people say that you know all
feminized seeds are more bound to her
and that's not necessarily correct
there's a lot of plants that you cannot
stress and pushed to her mistress but
you can do it using the silver
thiosulfate method because it's not a
stress method yeah so that sounds really
similar to what I have always kind of
theorized has happened but just kind of
clarify a week ago saying that you know
you know in a stressed hermaphroditic
plant there the stress causes say maybe
some epigenetic changes or something
which are then put into the pollen and
passed on whereas the thiosulfate
doesn't do that and therefore it yes
yeah yeah okay great yeah so what was
the first feminized crossed you ever
made or tried to make oh god that's a
good question um you see I think one of
the first ones was either green crack or
blue tree making an s-1 line of one of
the two it was really early on when I
did the green crack and it was still I
think was right around the same time I
did the blue tree I just don't remember
which came first
yes I mean this will be another good
question blue dream very very hot line
to be asked wond do you think that the
the variation in quality because I've
seen some really good blue dreams and
some horrible blue gems from different
breeders do you think the surance is the
cutting they're used or is a good fabric
taking several stages well you know a
good feminized product project is always
going to take several stages but I mean
most people don't ever get that to do
more than one stage because people want
it now they want it now and if you try
to work on it for too long then they
lose interest and maybe maybe the line
isn't as popular you know in next season
and it becomes worthless you know as far
as making seeds and spending your time
doing that so a lot of them don't ever
get worked more than one generation but
with blue dream there's a specific cut
from santa cruz but it's called the SC
cut the santa cruz cut and that one to
me who's been like the supreme blue
dream that's the one that for a long
time everybody in San Diego was growing
everyone up north and santa cruz you're
growing and that's where its reputation
came from as being like this amazing
almost connoisseur level a massive
yielder with tons of resin production
and a really like very light light light
blueberry smell with a nice like hmm had
like a Thai uplifting happy high as
opposed to a speedy haze high but a lot
of the other and pretty much any blue
haze out there now like a blueberry haze
cross people are calm blue dream and
there's a lot of shitty blue haze
crosses this haze it's not like the most
amazing line to breed with yeah okay
interesting opinion there we'll get into
that in a moment but yeah a follow up
question is do you think that a lot of
the you know shittier cuts of blue dream
I'm abs ones from the Santa Cruz or do
you think just they're just various
people have made it because it's an
interesting point you brought up where I
don't think blue dream was made by one
person I think many people have made
that cross and you know that yeah who
said what do you mean there's there's
Johnny Blaze that was another line
released by legend seed line that was
also another blueberry haze but
blueberry haze has been being made by
hundreds of people over decades now so I
mean I think it's just a popular name
with anything that has blueberry in it
or a blueberry smell that yields well
and I think that like in California the
name change game is so stupid it's been
going on for so long
people just don't give a [ __ ] what they
pass out or what they call it flung sand
cells you know yeah and I think that was
the major the major impetus behind all
these [ __ ] up blue dream crosses when
we did the blue dream reversal almost
they weren't I wouldn't say they were a
perfectly uniform or IBL or anything but
they were they were really good I mean
all the phenotypes were fairly
predictable and they definitely
resembled the mom quite a bit you could
only see a good resemblance to the mall
so yeah yeah okay and so I mean the
thing which stands out to me above most
every other person I've been to do these
music seems to be such an influential
part of your life you know are they
almost mutually exclusive creating a
music or it is one kind of inspire the
other or I you know for me you know
musically flips my life a lot I was in
band since I was 12 and like playing
shows punk rock shows and being the punk
rock scene and it is just a wild time in
California to be alive and in that it
was crazy it wasn't like you know the
era of Green Day where everything was
safe you know kids could get dropped off
downtown and it was fun and no like you
if you went to punk shows you knew we
gonna get a fight it was gonna be
[ __ ] terrifying
you know so growing up in that kind of
the scene is it's hard not to let it
influence your life you know yeah musics
always been a big part of my life and
it's just somehow ran straight head into
this this the whole attitude that I had
in the music scene into this because
there's a lot of nasty people in our
scene and our cannabis scene and I just
I've met them all
I've met all of them headfirst and it
sucks I'm like a magnet to him so you
just have to take that bull I don't give
a [ __ ] [ __ ] you you don't like it you
know they just work hand in hand yeah so
how did right suit start then it was
after the project with James hog and you
know we had started talking about doing
right seed stuff I had already started
working on the clock work order strain
and he had sold a bunch of those he's
like dude these are selling really well
the work we did you know why don't you
start doing some of that and we had
already worked on the clock record
straight a bit and we were passing it
out in San Diego to the Cancer
internally ill patients that actually
wanted to grow for themselves and that's
just kind of working
to be you know I just started like okay
well I need a name well my bad my my
name had ban since I was little was
always Matt riot so right seats make
sense and just started from there
but the Clockwork Orange and then spread
on out so like a lot of people including
myself are interested to hear what's the
real history behind the Clockwork Orange
you know it seems to be really it's a
here and there online but there's never
the full story yeah it kind of sucks cuz
I've told the story a bunch but every
time I go look it up or I see it
somewhere it looks like all jumbled you
know so there was a dude named it just
calm crazy dog like that nobody called
him that but me just cuz he was [ __ ]
crazy
his name was Doug he was this weird dude
that lived out in the hills of San Diego
Houston he had this big massive house
left to him by his parents and the whole
thing was a girl I'm talking his
bathrooms every [ __ ] room his
basements out so outdoors and he trained
drug dogs for the cops which was even
more weird like these germ evil German
Shepherd dogs he'd speak to him in
German and trained to be drug dogs for
cops well this dude was also a Tweaker
and like I mean he had syringes
everywhere like he was out of his
[ __ ] mind anyway I met this guy
through I think Craigslist or something
at the time that was going on and he
wanted to trade clones with me I was
like okay cool yeah I'll come visit you
I had no idea what I was getting
headfirst into so I went out there I met
him and he was just an interesting dude
very weird and he showed me this really
really weird plant that had all these
krinkle mutations he's like yeah man I
got this from Amsterdam this came it
came from a bag of Alaskan ice now
Alaskan ice at the time was not a
greenhouse strain it was something they
were selling at the coffee shop as bud
but there wasn't anything that they had
named a strain yet and the genetics
obviously looked the haahoos really
sativa the leaves were more narrow early
in veg and then later in veg that got
really wide blade drug type like almost
looking Afghani but I had this weird
crinkle to it and he's like yeah man
this is this is this is as strong as the
hash from the parents and I was like ok
cool I'll take that cut so I took it
around with it and we started working
the line and I was trying to take take
the crinkle out of it
because it just
look so weird I was like how people are
not gonna be into this if we can get the
high and the and the smell and the taste
that would be great but we need to get
rid of this crinkle because people think
it's ugly every time we took a step a
step away breeding the crinkle out the
the the potency was gone and just kept
creeping away from it but every time we
do have the phenotype with a crinkle pop
up it was back so I ended up taking that
and just having to go basically work
backwards from there and trying to
remake that original clone that I had
for him and then when we found that that
original clone or the closest
resemblance to that original clone
that's what became Clockwork Orange but
nobody knows what it really is I mean
since Alaskan ice wasn't a real strain
at the time there wasn't a white widow
haze there's it's not it's not a white
widow it's it's got Afghani some sort of
skunk definitely has some A's in it but
to what degree of each and what actual
strains are in it no I have no clue okay
that confirm do you breed with the
original Cotto with the backcross I
think you said you may the original
mother cut that was the the crinkle cut
that was used to make the lines that we
use to pick the clockwork orange' mom
out of okay fantastic yeah and so or any
other of those lines being used to breed
with currently or just the the other one
every once in a while will bust out we
made the very first line of s ones of
the Clockwork Orange cut we made a line
called smart alecks and basically that
was like this really super coffee it
just smelled like when you open a fresh
thing of Folgers coffee and smell it it
smells just like that it was crazy and
uh it was more dense than clockwork it
was less resinous but more dense and it
still had a really good potency to it
then that wouldn't be came down as the
smart alecks and sometimes we use that
cut or s ones of it you know it's been
hard to keep these alive for a long long
time they're really really hard plants
to grow and anybody that asked me for
the cut when they finally get out of
like dude just just remember this is a
really hard plant to grow it's not gonna
respond to you well and usually
everybody gets so mad at if they'll
throw it out eventually
so it's kept its rarity because of that
it's just really hard to grow it took me
a long time to master
okay and so is there any reason why you
choose not to have the S ones
continually and stuff like is it
something you want to keep kind of a bit
more elusive or you know it's just hard
to do it's it's a it when it whenever
verse it it doesn't produce much pollen
I need to reverse a whole room of it to
do it and people complain about the
prices of it and I get that it's
expensive so it's like I look at the
price that I have to to charge to make
it worth doing a whole room of that and
getting you know only four hundred seeds
something like that whereas if I do a
whole room of something like a regular
line with a regular mail thousands and
thousands of seeds so it's just I try to
only do it every once in a while to
where people still have that interest
willing to pay that because if I flooded
the market with it and try charging the
same price if it just it'd be pointless
yes I mean you kind of brought up an
interesting topic people have kind of
long criticized your pricing however
nowadays we see the rise of several
breeders who routinely charge as much or
more than yours most notably aficionado
that feel pricing plays into the market
you know do you think it's simply supply
and demand or is it just haters looking
for any excuse well I mean the way we
priced everything it's way we've always
done it is on it really it was on supply
and demand and and popularity if it's
something like a lot of people wanted
and we had a hundred seeds of it then
you know I usually said make you make an
offer because that's all that's there
and that's what that's what we have you
know and that kind of determined a lot
of the prices I caught a lot of [ __ ] for
it but there's a few reasons for doing
it one
I don't mmm it's the same reason I don't
use these test triggers I I don't like
necessarily want a bunch of new growers
trying to run really hard to grow beer
all that causes is problems always
causes problems new growers want you
know tend to not all of them but a good
amount of them they want to make up for
their skill by getting a strain they
think will just be super dank and of
course everything is going to grow
itself and by having the prices I did it
kept them away and and and it kept the
rarity up and for the most part most of
the people that buy I for me are
breeders they aren't new growers so
you know I see a lot of insults online
but I also sell seats for fifty bucks a
pack on down to thirty bucks a pack it's
just the ones they tend to want are the
ones that are the cheapest yeah
interesting and so do you feel that seed
gonna continually increase in price
because I mean there's seeds that are
currently going in like instagram
auctions for thousands of dollars
routinely do you think this is a trend
that will just continue or do you think
it'll cap out somewhere it depends how
stupid the market is if they're I mean a
lot of this [ __ ] selling for a lot of
money is [ __ ] [ __ ] like oh yeah
the efficient audio stuff like I mean
jeans made some cool [ __ ] but 99% of
that like I'm looking at the genetics it
was talking about their og cush line
bean of Pakistani lemon Thai whatever
like just the typical line of what
people think oh gee cush is and that's
not correct so obviously guys haven't
done their [ __ ] homework and they're
charging an assload for it but but as
long as the market remains stupid and
ignorant to what is what then sure I
mean if there's sky's the limit on how
much they'll pay and so what do you
think is the real origins of OG pushed
not that I mean it's it's an Afghani
sort of plant it's stretchy but that
doesn't necessarily mean it couldn't be
all indica I you know it has a lot of
the tied traits so that have the
happiness of the hive but it's obviously
got the density of a Afghani so it could
be something around there but who knows
really who knows I've never heard so
many [ __ ] stories that well that
could make sense and then it all ends up
being [ __ ] so I quit trying to
figure it out a long time ago okay
digging through your Instagram I noticed
that you received a cutting of Skelly
which is a strain that's popped up on
this show before because it was around
during the time or a little bit before
if the dog bud what's your I know I'm
Skelly god it's a great plant yeah and
uh I had heard of it first before from
JJ in New York several years ago and it
was called the puck I guess the guy who
used to sell it used to put it in like a
like almost like a bubble tape I don't
know it's an American thing it's like a
bubble gum case there was round like a
disc like almost like a hockey puck and
here like a Copenhagen PAC puck looking
thing and he would sell it in those so
that that that nickname stuck with it as
well
that the Skelly hash bun is just like a
really dank stinky Afghani plant it's
really really good though it's very
that's what that's one of those ones
that definitely stood the test of time
for daintiness yeah sure and so another
thing I found in Instagram is whenever
bubblegum comes out you're always sure
to make sure that people know you're not
referring to the Indiana bubblegum what
stood behind all of this you know we
made it
I usually didn't point it out too much
we made the original bubblegum cookies
line and ever since I've made that I've
had [ __ ] cookie fam knock it off say
it was this and that you know I haven't
there's another guy in Instagram I think
he calls himself like bubblegum cookie
man or something yeah and he's taking
credit for it saying yeah this is the
Indiana and it's not it's it's been like
the Indiana bubblegum doesn't pass on a
lot of pink bubblegum traits they're
slight they're in the in the cut but it
is not by any means you know something
you could smell and go hmm pink
bubblegum
that's [ __ ] sweet you know well the
cutting we had was from the original
1995 since he Starline we had the seed
line that was originally released as a
regular line by 1996 it was cut back to
a feminized line and the regular seeds
were very hard to find but we've had we
have had a bunch of them we have to them
and we kept a large stock of them so we
could go through them in there there's
one phenotype that is like a menthol
pink bubblegum line and it's an amazing
breeder and it passes on that really
super pink bubblegum smell and taste and
that's what we used in the line so like
I mean people what they just assume like
you know if they want to say this is
their line they're assuming that the
idiot above gum was in it and it's just
kind of frustrating there's none of one
of those things or it's like what the
indiana bubble gum line is and how it
breeds you you've never say that in a
million years that's what it was but
it's just yeah again people making just
stupid claims getting used to it so in
that same kind of vein most of your
releases like you just mentioned with
the bubble gum cookies they they don't
seem to be like they're gonna be
restocked for sure and you know like a
lot of your strains into you need to
treat them as though they're possibly
one offs is that how you view them all
yeah do you make a lot of lines with the
intention of restocking them
ever make any line with intention
restocking meliss are special you know
we do a lot of our testing in-house I
don't use testers because 99% of the
time they don't know what they're doing
to even begin to test anything and they
really don't even growth traitor but so
we stopped using testers we do all our
testing in the house we watch everything
ourselves you know it runs through all
the fee knows we're getting we see what
we have and we know we're offering a lot
of the lines unless they're really
really good
I usually don't bring them back bubble
gum cookies we did a version two of I'm
just a second generation of it a cookie
berry which is probably one of our most
knocked off lines it's going around
Californian clonise blue cookies and all
kinds of [ __ ] and that's another one
cookie fans taking credit for we've
released another version of that using
ogk B instead of the form cut but I
actually do prefer the forum cut cross
which is the original one to the version
ii version so when we do it again we'll
probably go back to the original cross
and so do you like to specifically list
what generations are being used for your
projects like oh yeah yeah so like in a
parent I've noticed I mean maybe I'm
wrong here but do you always list you
know that like this is and you know
let's just say with the I forget the
name of the strain you mentioned earlier
what was it there that particular s one
of the clockwork orange' the lazy Ben
was the smart alecks smart aleck smart
aleck I was so the smart alecks you know
you would you like to write like smart
alecks brackets clockwork orange' s1 or
is it just smart alecks cuz sometimes I
guess there's more work it's a new list
yeah it's usually like with smart alecks
in that case it'll smart alecks in
parentheses clockwork orange' s1 yeah
okay awesome so people can like kind of
trust what yeah pretty specific when I
excited cuz if I would be the same way
like I want to know exactly what I'm
getting and you know what's in there
I would hope everybody else would too so
I try to be pretty pretty damn specific
is it and so when you're braiding
regular projects like regular sex
projects not feminized
the numbers you'd ideally like to use
for such a project in terms of finding
parents or testing progeny for a wrote
the line we went through eight years of
different Afghani lines and and Super
Skunk lines looking I mean I can't even
count the number of seeds it
astronomical but eight years of
constantly every run cracking more and
more Afghani seeds and super-stoked
lines to try to find the roadkill line
and that that was an ideal you know run
on something that was one of our best
ones and it's been one of the most
successful and so then regular regular
seed lines I mean like it just depends
on what you have to work with but the
one thing that I always I would make a
habit of before I go do any runs for any
lines if I only have a pack of something
I'm gonna f2 it and run through those
lines so I have you know a multitude of
seeds to look through yeah okay
and so like um in the case of the
roadkill skunk which is something gets
brought up in almost every episode
you've got several lines which feature
you know roadkill skunk traits or from
the roadkill afghani
yeah how would you describe this line
you know to you is it a replica or just
a homage something similar like where do
you rate it in comparison to the
original roadkill style well the
original Roca skunk was not a sunk one
line it was just an Afghani that
happened to smell like a skunk and
people called it skunk but that often
gets confused and confabulate with skunk
number one that was released by saying
I'm the skunk man yeah you know and then
after taken to Amsterdam and it which is
like there's a lot of phenotypes that
are sweet
there's citrus there's all kinds of [ __ ]
but you don't get is straight-up skunk
spray like like an American skunk spray
you know being run over in the road and
like our roadkill is like that but it
also has another trait that's really
strong old Afghan ease which is burn
rubber like a burnt rubber tennis ball
yeah and then there's some slight
ammonia to it too which is often
described as like an acrid and taste
okay and so which of those crosses you
feel is the most representative of the
roadkill skunk then I
think the Custis our dub which in itself
considering what's out there what's been
out there is already a pretty skunk line
which is why we chose that we did a
reversed cross with the the Afghan Imam
that had the most roadkill traits and we
released that as road kill Afghani
feminized and then we used a male health
from the pure Afghani line that we found
the roadkill mom in they had the same
exact type traits and terms when we
reversed him so we had to test him out
first by reversing him using etheral and
florell so we got to see what kind of
terpenes he put out well ahead of time
before we used any of the males okay and
that was our regular seed line of it and
is that that's the process way you you
reverse the male and get like female sex
plants like you know pods and stuff is
that right yeah it's I mean you don't
get like full-on like you're not gonna
get like a female with thick ass buds
and stuff but you will see a lot more
resin production you're gonna see some
flowers and you'll get a better idea of
what terpenes he produces and I mean
even if he produces those terpenes it
doesn't necessarily mean he's gonna pass
them on so you at least get the first
idea of what's going on and then you
have to use him to see if the traits get
passed on reliably yeah okay and so is
that a process you like to do for all
regular mouths or just the you know the
long processes it's something I've been
doing more and more often it's a really
valuable tool that was really overlooked
for a long time and now it's becoming
more and more popular I think I've been
talking about it for a few years and I'm
slowly noticing more and more people
doing it and I think that's a good thing
because all I can do is advance breeding
for everyone making a trip selection
easier okay and so what are some of the
traits you look for in a male when
you're just flowering it out leap
serration structure things like that you
know back in the day I used to look for
I mean really it is a a shot in the dark
the first the first round with a male
and early on I used to look for a male
that was the most like a female
something that I had that like I was
sure was gonna be a female when I was
looking at it you know and right before
it showed any sex and it's like okay I
don't have to you know keep an eye too
bad on this one this is obviously a
female you know that's what I would look
for but as time
I realized you know that was still 50/50
that was still here miss like you didn't
always work and I'd have to throw out
whole lines that I made so really we
just keep all of our males and we just
try to find something that has a
structure that we like one that produces
resin naturally on its own without
having to be reversed we cross them and
then we see how he does and that's just
it's a long-ass process but that's the
only reliable way to do it yeah okay
and so I mean you touched on it oh yeah
in terms of the Clockwork Orange only
producing a small number of seeds for
the whole room to be done when you're
producing a female pollen is that
something which just comes down to the
individual cut as to how well it
responds to that or is it really like a
methodology based process where like the
better you are at it the more pollen
you'll get and things like that
pollen collection is hard with reversals
in the first place but man it goes down
to the exact plant it goes down to the
environment the plants and every every
last little variable matters with it
some plants reverse better than others
some really suck in it a lot but really
dense indicas are really hard to reverse
just because the the male the male
clusters the the male parts they cluster
up and get really hard and they're hard
to pick out I mean they don't just burst
like a regular mouth the nuts don't hang
so to speak so that's that's something
that happens a lot with really dense
indicas so a lot of people like
reversing more less-dense sativas yeah
okay and so do you think being out there
a lot of pollen from such strains would
just come down to training the plant to
maybe have very few bud sites and so
that you could do it or it's just still
still more like intricate than that
there's actually certain chemicals you
can use to make the the clusters be less
dense so we've I've had someone else
help me with that and kind of figure out
that aspect of it and it was it's been
so helpful in that part because that was
always the main problem with reversing a
lot of like the og pushes and stuff like
that and never getting enough seeds it
was just that dense formation of
clustered balls and me trying to pull
the pollen how you literally have to go
in with tweezers and do it by hand and
shake it into a bag each little cluster
and
now we have another chemical that'll
stretch it out make them hang a little
bit more and it's much easier to collect
so I mean even over time it's getting
easier for us to do more developing
better methods every every year yeah and
so what what strain has been the best
one to reverse in your opinion your
favorite like to work with Bubba just
the old bubble Kirsch like for some
reason even though it has dense but
formations it's always been really
reliable it's always kicked out a lot of
pollen it's just always been really
reliable and really easy to use and and
and it tends to have amazing progeny
I've never really had a bad bubble
reversal or bad Bubba crosses yeah
that's interesting because bob is a
strain I personally love a lot what do
you think the history on it is you know
a lot of people say max Abba made it
what do you think what do you you know I
like matte bubble a lot he's got some
valid stuff he said with oceans with
sorry some just felt he's got a valid
point with the with og cush I mean he's
got a lot of documentation with his
friend Josh being one of the original
guys that were passing it around however
Bubba he was seeing I think came around
96 but you can go to a High Times
Magazine in 94 and see Bubba in it
so it's hard to say I mean I know that
the the Oregon Afghani tends to look a
lot probably closest above as a mom for
Bubba some people say West Coast dog I
don't know it's obviously an Afghani of
some sort yeah that's interesting
because I am I spoke to Professor P of
dynasty and he he thinks that the Oregon
Afghani is maybe an S one of Bubba
yeah and that could be that could be
he's worked with it a lot more than I
have that's for sure
you would know yeah okay so I mean the
West Coast dog is another thing you
brought up that's interesting seed find
it has quite a long-winded story about
you know contrary to the Matt Barber
story explaining how they think that's
the Bob wood you had put any credit to
that oh do you think it's all just kind
of Chinese whispers yeah you know the
West Coast dog gained a lot of
popularity with the guy a group of guys
called the brothel brothers and they
were some conman [ __ ] and they've
had like a few different names that
they've used over the years they've used
trichome kings and screwed over a bunch
of people on that CRS seeds yes those
guys ciara seeds brothel brothers
they've used all those names and it
seems to be that the West Coast dog
originates with those guys the story the
strain everything comes from those guys
and so what's it like to you though do
you see any traits of the buffer in it
um yeah you know I would say I would
probably guess if anything it's like a
Bubba hybrid with some sort of narrow
leaf sativa type plant okay interesting
something something fruity keeping on
the topic of history I saw in a I think
it was either an Instagram post on a
forum some way you were dropping some
knowledge about dr. Grinspoon and the
origin oh yeah
it's a very hotly contested strain you
know what do you know about it um the
first time I heard about that strain it
was called quays it from delta nine sent
it to me and it was just a clone only
strain I don't think much was known
about its its history other than it
probably was a Southeast Asian of some
sort so whether it was Thai philippi
know there's something from Southeast
Asia and that that clone that like a lot
of the pictures will see on the sensi
seeds site if you look in the quays
clone only that's what the pictures were
of and Barney's farm got a cut of it
reversed it sold it his doctor Grinspoon
that was it yeah interesting because
online on that same seed find a website
they say that it's a reef immense strain
I forget the name of oh good lord
yeah guess it's know that it was the
Oregon Utah across to something but
anyway permits a [ __ ] idiot I know me
and yeah sorry me and devil we're
working together for a little bit Nevel
show and maker and reefer man somehow
got in the middle of it and started
getting Neville to try to send me or me
to try to send cuts to him through
Neville and you know like I daren't he'd
already [ __ ] over so many of my
friends in America and I was like you
know you probably don't want to talk to
this guy and I really want to send him
anything he's kind of a piece of [ __ ]
and Neville insisted Nick no man I say
he's good so you
you're my friend you'll send in this
[ __ ] so what's he do he [ __ ] me over
there too but you know he's notorious
for that he's just a scumbag ex white
power Nazi guy that just kind of hides
out being a piece of [ __ ] it makes his
resurgence every now and then he makes a
lot of claims himself I don't know if
she'd find her made that claim he made
that claim but either way it's incorrect
definitely incorrect okay and so I mean
you've been working with the what you
say is the original Girl Scout cookie
claim for a while what is the original
Girl Scout cookie client cuz even cookie
fam can't really tell you yeah before
the forum cut was called the forum cut
it was just Girl Scout cookies and that
was it that's it everybody must argue
over it that just did that's that was
the first one that's being passed around
as Girl Scout cookies and as more people
got their hands on it they started
calling the forum cut to try to say oh
well that one's not as cool as this one
we have over here you know yeah okay and
so do you think that like most of the
other cuts are s ones from the forum cut
or other seeds that the form cut
originally came from like that same
batch or well I mean you can get like a
forum cut type plant from reversing
cherry pie Kush so I mean if they could
be more s1 to cherry pie cush they could
be s1 to the forum they could also be
Oracle og hybrids because that kicks out
the same exact type of phenotypes so god
only knows I see the most common being
the og KB type coming out of Oracle and
og hybrids so I mean yeah okay and I
mean one of the reasons why we're on
this topic is because one of your new
strains coming out is the f1 Durban
cross dosey doe yes what inspired this
and how did you get access to the
elusive f1 durbin now that strains been
going around for [ __ ] ever it's just
always been known as Mendo Durban it
looks a lot like cherry pie the original
you know it was never that rare it's
just only been rare since they've called
it f1 dirt or whatever but it's been
around forever it's it's not even a pure
Durban in any sense of the word this is
very indica Dom which a real pure Durban
is very sativa Dom it has a little bit
of that a nice like
it's called a black licorice to it not
much just ant yeah that clones been
around forever okay and so what do you
think God the the real origins of the
ghost gets you hinted before the cherry
pie this one maybe yeah I mean you can
make like it we can make Girl Scout
cookies out of okie any a really old
over to you like Lucas headband or San
Fernando Valley the real San Fernando
Valley cut or face off any of those you
can use and cross to the old Orkut and
you'll get all that say you I mean
there's a lot of phenotypes that come
out of that cross but you will see
cookies type phenotypes I mean not just
those two strings now F one herb might
be in it as they call it know them ended
urban because Cherry Pie does look a lot
like them in a turban and it could just
be the Cherry Pie as the you know the
like a granddaddy purple which is also
an Urkel phenotype or Oracle out cross
it could be GDP EOG and that and that
would make sense I mean you could
potentially pull that out of that that's
that's the best if I got on that okay
and so I mean your work kind of in
contrast to a lot of other breeders is
you clearly don't seem to have a problem
breeding with cookies what do you feel
on this never happened you know do you
do you dislike kind of the hate that
cookies gets or you don't mind you know
covered by how do you feel about it or
given you know you do bring with it a
lot you know I I was the first one to
release it to any seeds of it any of any
strains of it and see and that was a
long time ago a long time ago that's
like what five six years ago now I saw
I'd give a [ __ ] anymore I mean what I
was doing it no one else was using it
nobody really wanted to buy it because
nobody knew what it was and by the time
I sold out of it that's when people
started getting popular so I missed that
whole cookies way for the most part I
mean I'll use it every now and then now
but it's definitely not like a main
staple of anything I do I mean it's good
it has its place it's not that potent I
mean the og KB types are and they're out
crosses are but that particular one
wasn't yeah okay and so I don't know if
you're aware but there's currently like
a bit of an ongoing discussion maybe
slightly aggressive
between gauge green and cookie fam kind
of over the origins of the cookies you
gage Green is saying that they believe
that the Cherry Pie cush is the parent
of the ODE of the cookies and it's
probably s ones of that have you seen
any of this at all / you know how how do
you think about that have you ever seen
the bush uh you know I don't
as far as gage spring goes that's pretty
that's a pretty everybody knows that I
hate that [ __ ] it's not
specifically the all the guys in it but
the original guy he goes by key play he
was the first one to use the name gage
bringing he lied and cheated his way
through all of our business he did it to
me limp a guy named old man a bunch of
people and he's made his whole his whole
campaign on just stabbing everyone in
the back that helped him out along the
way
even Jojo Rizzo who is supposed to be
one of his friends that he's named
strain zapped after he traded him heroin
for his seat stock I mean that's what
killed him
so yeah I have nothing that anytime that
guy talks I just oh my [ __ ] eyes and
hope I don't see him in person well I
mean interestingly enough there seems to
be a lot of info online which you know
indicates that you guys argue over the
origins of the purple elephant slash you
know the grapes Tompa how do you feel
about that all you know where where do
you see it it was just them who made the
grape stomp or was it Jojo Jojo made it
was originally called sour grapes he
passed it out to a bunch of people but
he never sold it he had a specific clone
that he liked and that was the sour
grapes mom that has passed out to all of
us that was also given to gage who was
supposed to be his friend and gage went
and sold it to blue sky cafe as sour
grapes and then he started getting mad
said I kind of like the name grape stomp
for better and that's what he made this
heat light ass okay but gage has nothing
to do with the actual genesis of the
string just hijacked someone else's same
with his blackberry pie and that was
JoJo's there's countless other [ __ ] he's
done that with so it's nothing new and
so do you feel like it's a interesting
situation that you guys you know like
both breed with the same cup but there's
this kind of animosity between the two
is because the reason I bring it up is
there's kind of like a reincarnation of
that right now between gromer and seed
junkie where
less you know grown is probably gonna
breed with some of seed junkie seeds
even those seed junkies made it somewhat
obvious he would not like that you know
do you feel like there's almost some
parallels between that and you engage
with the Stompa who are they I don't
think I've ever heard of them I'm just
kidding I um I don't know they're
nobodies to me they're they're new
welcome yeah okay so I guess maybe the
way I should rephrase the question is do
you do you think that your rights over a
seed line kind of whatever you want to
do with it as soon as you acquire them
or do you believe like you know you
should respect the creator's wishes or
something like that or is it like not
yours you've got it what the problem is
the creators been passed for a long time
you know so in general like with any
save save on I mean you know like if the
people aren't if a breeder isn't
currently making the seed line he's not
making the money off and he's not done
how many plans to come back then I would
say as long as you credit him properly
and you've done your research then
that's fine and dandy but if you're
going in like eff doing people seed
lines like and just changing the name
that's really just the big slap in the
face you can't do that any other
industry
well you shouldn't yeah okay interesting
and yeah similarly we've seen a bit of
an argument between I don't have a site
now you have food between Melo from the
nature farm and yourself between these
the discrepancies in the roadkill lines
what you are taking this his line is
phenotypically seems different to yours
I don't I don't know who he is
I don't think do I have I said something
to him I might have said so I don't know
the [ __ ] Club yeah when every post
photos of he's uh he's roadkill on he's
working on you he who says like skunk
IBL 69 that guy yeah yeah man oh yeah I
mean that he has a skunk from 1969 that
is like that is the most [ __ ] asinine
[ __ ] I've ever heard it takes all it
takes us like ten minutes of research to
realize oh wait there weren't really
many Afghan EES come into the US in 1969
normally they being harvested for their
own [ __ ] in Afghanistan they were still
importing Indian sativa plants for hash
so
that claims [ __ ] just stupid it just
did yeah no no and it's not an IPL if
there's more than one phenotype it's not
a [ __ ] IPL I'd be able to notes
uniformity and I see people use that and
it makes me roll my [ __ ] eyes so you
just had a bunch of I [ __ ] balls
that's it yeah okay and so I mean if we
get back to say maybe riot seeds one of
many strains one for example called
blood rose nuclear is being created by a
colleague skunk Oh as yes having you
know other colleagues like flip
do you consider Riot seeds to be you as
an individual like a one-man operation
or more of like an umbrella for kind of
you know you and your friends it's do
you know there's been so many people
that had a far as my company there were
times when I like I just lost a lot of I
want to do anything in this business
just from just being jaded by all the
[ __ ] heads and there are a lot of times
other people picked up and ran with my
company and kept it going there's a guy
named 46 and two like he took a lot of
the work that I had and he kept it going
out there or kept passing it out kept
making sure everything was going while I
was gone there's a guy named Racer X he
did the same thing and he's helped out
probably more than anyone else
a skunk oh he made two lines for us and
he's an amazing guy he just you know
he's a wonderful guide to there's been
so many people that are part of our
organization and most of them are the
same kind of guys or just just people
who don't give a [ __ ] about what people
have to say and so the this has actually
been a question we got asked a lot from
people the PFS one seeds what's the guy
when are they coming
oh the piss I made those years ago but I
wasn't allowed to do the S ones the guy
got it from was a bouncer for the
Dominicans in New York
a guy named doggystyle D 79 and he's
been around the forums forever he passed
me the fifth lines there was one line
called h-11 like all h2 the h1 was like
the frankincense type line h2 was more
like a mango haze type line something
similar to that you see from shanty with
his mango haze and all I was told was
you know you can make as many hybrids
with this as you want just don't s want
it don't release appear that's it
okay interesting yet and two people
holding out for it so similarly another
strain caught my eye was the p90 one
yeah that's the one San Diego strength
yeah so what's the history behind that
and how come no one else seems to breed
with it bastions been gone for a long
time we'll leave few people including
the breeder of captives it's hard to
find there's like a p90 one skunk line
that gets passed around but for the most
part that line was really hard I
searched for it for ten years before I
got a legit cut from the breeder and
that was hard it's supposed to be
according to him a silverback tie across
to Northern Lights I want to say but
there's really not a lot of titrate
something that it being very very bushy
it's a very very bushy plant but it's
called p90 one because it's peanut
buttery
so for peanut and ninety one because it
was made in 1991 okay interesting and do
you plan to make any swans with it again
you know the cut is very old
it wasn't kept very well it's one of
those things that like I'd like to
tissue culture first and then go ahead
and give it another run to s ones I just
really wasn't really happy with the
uniformity of it it was hard to find a
lot of really super peanutty phenotypes
the line could be s1 a few times to get
some uniformity to make sure that's more
reliable yeah okay what are the
characteristics about it that you like
and how come again you don't think many
other people use it it seems like you
know a hidden gem which which one from
Sonny the neon Super Skunk oh you know
that was just that mostly used it
because I was trying at the time I was
trying to find really good black russian
strains and early on Sonny was one of
few people there was really like amazing
to me and this is before he left for a
long time and kind of disappeared after
the TGA thing he was one of the few
people I could talk to about breeding
purples him and a guy named EBU I
personally think are responsible for so
many of the purple purple work out there
and pink work I mean I couldn't have
done it without them there'd be no
to have none of my purple/pink work and
a lot of people attribute you know a lot
of my work to being some some of the the
most prolific purple in paperwork but I
trip into all that to those to the neon
Super Skunk was a black Russian line and
at the time Black Russian was really
hard to find and that was me blues black
Russian
it's a cherry AKA crossed to the oregon
blackberry oregon blackberry is a purple
pakistani to trolley and at the time
that was a lot harder to find nowadays
back to tenecia trolley the purple feed
you know is everywhere at the time was
really hard to find so you know I the
only reason I worked with the neon super
skunk was just because of the Black
Russian it wasn't so much because of the
super skunk but it's it all-in-all was
an amazing line okay and how do you feel
about people kind of there's you know
certainly seems to be a rising
popularity of people wanting to go back
to those more raw land racy unworked
type of stuff you know do you feel like
this is a well spent effort or maybe a
waste of time
it just depends on who's doing the work
I mean any [ __ ] kid [ __ ] something
up that's nice you know I don't know
it's just depend on to tune to work a
lot of people I see you're trying to
play your stuff like that and that's
finally dandy but if they don't know how
it breeds or out crosses they don't
understand what they're doing with it
they don't really have a direction
they're just making crosses to make
crosses you're I'm just shooting in the
dark and it's going to be a lot of work
for everyone else so do you ever think
that we will have you know like another
strain emerge that just totally takes
over the market maybe similar to how
skunk or Northern Lights do when they
were first released or yeah I mean og
cush og cush was one that absolutely
took over the market and it's a staple
now just as much as any stunt or
anything else you know and there's gonna
be more I mean cookies cookies has made
quite a stamp on it and even though it's
not that a whole wholly different from
an Urkel or an OG it still has made its
mark and there's gonna be plenty more to
come I mean there's still a lot of lines
a lot of us are taking up and just
playing with like we have a Senegalese
line from Africa that has like a
understands the distinctive light you
smell which is not a terpene you find
mode in cannabis anywhere and it's very
specific to that and it also is a
landrace sativa or heirloom sativa or
more correctly that is really resinous
and you don't see that a lot so I mean
there's a lot of strengths out there
that
gonna be able to bring a lot more
uniqueness and to our lines okay and so
what do you think about the idea of
breeding for turbans specifically or and
then like maybe a follow up to that is
do you think it's possible for cannabis
to create literally any smell with its
terpenes that's a hard question I don't
know I think anybody knows the answer to
that truly if we can make any smell or
any taste because I know that there's a
lot missing from the palate but III I
mean eventually if you have enough
colors you you know in your arsenal you
could paint any pictures so I that
eventually will get their breeding for
terpenes I mean we did that with the
blue berry line that we were work that
we call riot berry and trying to find
that original blue berry that is just
completely blue berry no skunk that was
a really hard hard thing to do I mean we
spent thousands and thousands on ploop
different blueberry lines from BJ short
I mean all of it probably descends from
DJ short to work originally but like
going to the Canadian blueberries from
DJ's work with singer Massa DJ's worth
of Dutch fashion they're all different
levels of blueberry but none of them
were really kicking out that heavy-duty
blueberry smell and bred reliably and
you know outcross that blueberry smell
and the purple traits so I mean that's
that's a good example of terpene work
that took a long time and was and
definitely worth it in the end and so
how do you feel about the whole kind of
crazed with terpenes at the moment you
know you see people getting concentrates
and just drowning it in liquid beans and
stuff do you think it's a I don't know I
mean looks kind of crack heady to me but
whatever I mean people are gonna always
do the weirdest [ __ ] they can do with it
and try to try to create new fads with
it terpenes definitely have their place
I mean when I was watching a lot of the
BHO being made originally when it was
happening in Southern California you
were missing out on a lot of the
terpenes and the high was so different
so speedy and it was very predictably
speedy with any strain so I obviously
they play a big part in the high I think
the the newest things going to be paying
more attention to the flavonoids as well
as the terpenes and the flavonoids have
been really ignored and I think that's
just another thing that just has another
major impact on it
okay and so I mean what is your opinion
on kind of dabbing versus flowers where
do you sit on the spectrum like and just
as a follow-up I had a friend who kind
of described America is now a country of
dabbas and not flour smokers you know
did you feel that's the truth yeah yeah
hey I hate to maybe yeah I mean like I I
myself I would I don't like Debbie not
that I didn't do it for a long time but
it really [ __ ] up my lungs there's
there's too many [ __ ] doing it they
don't again like everything else and
their business alleged it's doing it
they don't know what the [ __ ] they're
doing and they can hurt a lot of people
and they can hurt the lungs they can
make them sick not everyone's getting
there she tested obviously and not all
the tests are reliable so mm-hmm
flowers didn't have the more complete hi
and more Turkey and content so to me
that would make the most sense but I
mean I guess it's all in the preference
of the person what it does for them
cannabis is an individual experience the
high is always an individual experience
no two highs are the same for each
person so it's just really what it's
that's what it boils down to me I
flowers any day and so how do you feel
about the rise in testing you know
Oregon seems to start when I say that I
mean like pesticide and residue testing
things like that because Oregon seems to
be leading the way do you think it's
just gonna keep getting more and more
stringent or what kind of bet it would
spot it's hard to say I mean the more we
let government into [ __ ] the more [ __ ]
up everything gets but at the same time
less stuff like that's necessary people
are gonna get hurt if not yeah
but no I mean as more chemicals are
being made you know it's getting easier
for people to try to sneak by stuff so
testings gonna have to get better you
know it's just it's part of it I guess
necessary evil yeah okay and so you know
it seems like the cannabis industry used
to be very much against feminized seeds
and there's still a lot of skepticism
out there but I feel like there is a
slowly changing trend as more and more
mainstream breeders seem to be
incorporating feminized into their
projects who were you know in the past
just regular only do you think this is a
changing trend within the community or
just maybe like a short-term kind of
change from the norm you know it was
what's funny is
a lot of the people that were dissenters
maybe five years ago are now buying my
spray that I make to make their
feminized lines and I you know I don't
know maybe we're getting more educated
finally on it I sigh for you years I've
been screamed my head off showing the
science behind it and why I like saying
this or that applies to feminize see
it's really isn't correct I mean even
using the term feminized it's kind of
stupid because there's no way you can
guarantee any kind of sex on any plan
because environment determines you know
at least at least thirty to forty
percent of what that plants sexual
characteristics are going to be so the
term feminized really isn't even that
good of a term l I always used reverse
lines just so it doesn't give that
connotation and people don't have
expectations that are outside of reality
but there are a lot of people that you
know we're against it for one reason or
another or just what they had heard and
like they said a lot of those people now
are buying the spray for me and using it
and create mine so I think it's probably
I mean the science is there so people
keep reading it they'll get it and so
what do you feel about the idea of doing
like and I'm not even sure if this is
the correct terminology but like s to s
and s threes you know like making s ones
of s ones do you feel like that's going
down a shaky path or it's fine as long
as selections good as long as the
selections good as long as the lines
good I mean just run the progeny and
then yeah I mean a lot of lines a lot of
lines are you know I guess I would call
it like s1 R or f1 are f1 reversals f2
reversals things like that that's
usually how we denote it but yeah it's
kind of like if you use a shitty line
and you keep crossing it out even if
it's a regular line you're gonna get
[ __ ] same thing with s ones if you keep
reversing a plant that kind of sucks and
has little some shitty traits it's just
going to get more and more obvious as
you go on and so have you ever seen a
plant come from an s1 that was better
than the parent cuz I kind of oh yeah
that I couldn't couldn't see an obvious
you know well-known clone only that was
like you know s1 that was better than
the parent ogk be probably I mean if
that is an s-1 over the forum I would
say that's a perfect example of it okay
yeah cuz the interesting thing around
that
is I think the guy who found that one
claims that it was from the same seed
stalkers like the original Girl Scout
cookie he's like you know like they did
the forum cut would be a sister so to
speak yeah then I would make it an S one
is something because it was a yeah yeah
so yeah I mean it would be yeah I mean
the same kind of thing that I have when
I reversed Bubba and we did a large
population there was one phenotype in it
there was an arrow leashed type Bubba
plant and it had big apical buds that
just one main meristem you know and as
opposed to being a short squat little
plant yeah it was tall and had big colas
and it smelled like father tastes like
lava but the high was so much more
complex lasted longer and in general
everybody seemed to prefer way over the
original Bubba and everybody that I know
loves you original Bubba that's another
example of an s-1 that's just in my
opinion just about it the parent by
leaps and bounds Oh fantastic
so I mean yeah do you think we'll ever
see any more platinum banana OGS ones
that's that's another good example um
the original platinum banana og was a
great line but there are s1 ones that
came out they're phenomenal
even better than the mother so if I do
it I may take one of the S ones as
opposed to the mother and use one of
them because they're like some of those
were just absolutely beautiful the more
black colored ones that were just had
resin caked on it and smelled and tasted
like banana Laffy Taffy so yeah I
release it again I made I may release
the original mom s ones but I'll
definitely do an s-1 reversal as well
fantastic so I mean some of your
previous work you've worked with some of
the more raw land where AC type stuff
we've spoken about earlier I think one
of them I saw was get the chem dog
Columbian gold Harvard you did do you
think these are good breeding tools so
to speak or they can just kind of make
things harder to work with you know do
you think it'll be an ongoing trend in
the future to work with you know like a
new school meets old school hybrid well
that one specifically was work Luca had
done originally and he brought it down
to about 16 weeks the hybrid and then we
ran in after you selection and brought
it down to 10 to 14 weeks we even had
ten weeks
and honestly that was one of my favorite
lines during those years that I ever
worked with and worked but it didn't
sell people had zero [ __ ] interest in
it wasn't OG Kush at the time Kim dog de
was not in that big a demand many when
Kim has always been in big demand but at
the time Kim dog D just really wasn't
that big of a deal but now you know
people know about star dog and they know
that that's you know from the d-line so
a lot of people more more people have
been wanting it over the past few years
and that shit's a long gone now so but
that tends to be the the trait I mean it
takes people a while to catch up to what
a lot of breeders are working with it
takes several years for them to start
getting hip to land race work and what's
good yeah I mean what's your opinion on
the Kim dog family is such you know it's
a very popular discussion topic on that
show my favorites gzhel cheese diesel
it's the mass Super Skunk cross to the
Kim dog de it's not one of the original
seeds from the Kim dog line that Gregg
had but it's good you know it's one of
my favorites I think it because us one
the gzhel you can actually see each one
of those phenotypes of the chem 91 you
can see the D you can see before you can
see the sister all on those Versalles of
just the diesel because it's and because
it's so strong with the mast super spell
parent it's actually very similar in
high smell and looks to the mast super
skunk yeah that's that's why it's one of
my favorites that up for the original
line I really liked for but I mean some
people prefer the te for the high I just
didn't like Kim dog because it smelled
like baby [ __ ] and whose made me really
disgusted like in mid flour it just has
this awful fecal baby [ __ ] runny smell
and that was pretty disgusting and foul
yeah okay so what's your take on naming
strands you know and the reason why I
ask is because I feel like I can kind of
spot your names sometimes of the strain
the thing is though you don't seem to go
by like you know the standard
nomenclature where it's like you know
blueberry crust og call it blue og or
whatever you know what's your approach
to naming strains and how do you feel
about that whole new mega litter I
mentioned where you know people just
kind of ramming two names together
um you know early I would do that that
was like the top popular nomenclature
and that was what people did like if his
blue haze it you call it blue haze you
know if it was a blueberry bubblegum it
was bubble berry but I don't know I
don't know how I come up with any of the
names I do a lot of rich is [ __ ]
gonna pull out my ass or it's a punk
rock Ken's name I don't know I I have
theirs I'm reppin this with naming I've
made a lot of stupid names stuff that I
don't like and I don't keep in the end
and some stuff that I just keep because
I'm too lazy and even though it sucks
but I have learned that sometimes the
name is everything when it comes to a
strain so I probably should pay more
attention to it I just don't care on
that part yeah okay and so we don't
routinely at least or ever see you
attend cannabis cups or events like that
you know do you just avoid them because
of kind of you know all the previous
interactions with people or you just
don't see the real value in going to
them no I've gone like the ones in
Denver the first few years I went to the
80s I cup when I went that year I don't
ever have trouble with anyone because
people were [ __ ] usually I'll talk
online and [ __ ] in the frame person
but I don't like high times they're
[ __ ] [ __ ] so I call them high
crimes because all they are is one big
long [ __ ] advertisement for [ __ ]
so I don't really have any purpose of
going to their cups and giving them
money there's other cups like the
Emerald cup and stuff I didn't go this
year just cuz I was dealing with a lot
of chaos same thing the year before but
Bodie always tries to get me to go to
those with them and it's just that's the
only reason I haven't it's just because
it's usually life [ __ ] going on at the
time but other cups I don't know I just
don't care guess a lot of people that go
enter those or a lot of the newbie
[ __ ] that are trying to prove
something you've already been there done
that and don't care I don't need an
award to satisfy my ego yeah okay and so
I think you know what's one of maybe the
most unexpected friendship in the
industry being yourself and Bodie really
really dig Bodie I'm sure they'd be
interested how did you meet him and you
know developed this friendship over time
ah Wow me and Bodi how do we meet I we
were just both making seeds at the same
time he was doing it before I was even I
don't know you just always kind of
gotten along really well he's obviously
like my polar opposite he's very quiet
very reserved super nice never has
anything negative to say about anyone
ever he's really sweet me and him when
we talk we don't even really talk about
cannabis that much he has pretty good
knowledge of punk rock history and final
so we get along talking about that no no
it's just one of those things where we
are polar opposites but we totally get
along this one it's a really weird
pairing and same with loompa loop is
very much like Bodhi very calm quiet
reserved just one of those things you
know they get me yeah somehow linked to
the yang yeah it is so and we and and
and when people attack them they'll just
back down because they're nice and they
don't care to get into it and I'll just
rip into people so it just kind of works
out and so would you ever see yourself
doing a collaboration with either them
or just other breeders you know well I
mean I've done collaborations with
loompa earlier last year we were gonna
do it see pink together but just a lot
of stuff happening with his company and
someone trying to screw him over really
bad and so that kind of got put on hold
for a while
me and Bodhi do do a lot of stuff
together but it's more like passing
clones back and forth and then we'll
work with each other's cuts like I work
with this purple unicorn cut and I think
I'm the only person that works with that
specific cut and it's pretty amazing
it's absolutely amazing it's some of
JoJo's work acrostic MD yeah you know
that's that's that's pretty much how
we've done and I give him a lot of my
landrace lines that I collect over the
years that because I don't have a lot of
outdoor space so I just given to him to
run and would you ever be interested in
you know going and doing the you know
machete in one hand hacking through
Amazonian jungles to get your own land
race oh you're not really interested in
that no I loved you it's just um I don't
know I I don't have that ability to just
walk away from my plants and leave them
and trust someone to take care of my
really really paranoid about that
so I don't really do that I don't leave
a whole lot to go on big adventures yeah
that would be putting my company at risk
and that's just kind of I don't know
yeah okay so welcome but it would be
nice
what plan have you had for the longest
well we had the Clockwork Orange mom the
longest I would have to say that that's
probably one that survived the longest
not the original one from Doug but the
because that wasn't called clock
performance that was just then Alaska
nice plant of some sort but the one that
became known as Clockwork Orange that
one's stayed the longest and that's
that's not through any awesomeness of my
own I've passed it to other people and
had to get it back from them and I've
been very fortunate that the people that
passed it to if God didn't gotten her
back to me okay fantasy and I mean I
guess you may be answered indirectly but
you no longer hang on to that original
Alaskan RS plant no no we lost that
early early on after we made some of the
first rounds of seats with it trying to
get rid of that crinkled phenotype
because we thought well that's pretty
ugly there's no real reason to keep the
mom now that we have the seeds we can
pick a better phenotype that doesn't
have that crinkle and that just wasn't
the case it so for some reason that
crinkle goes hand in hand with the
potency yeah okay interesting and so how
do you feel about the whole organics
both synthetics you know like where do
you see it in the growing spectrum I use
what I got I mean any to me it's it's
like you know some people are diehard
organics and people are diehard TLO like
my buddy at the Rev like he's the T I
think he's like the TLO master I really
do and he knows what he's talking about
he's taught so many people I I'm
sponsored by botanic air and a few other
people and obviously you know there's
some synthetics and the lines but I
don't even care if it's a bottle of in a
bottle of pee in a bottle okay I can
make it work and that's just what it is
I mean whether it's organic or inorganic
I can look at the plant I know what it
needs and that's why every grower should
be I think no matter what they use they
should just be able to look at the plant
know exactly what the plant needs not
overfeed and just you know feed
according to what the plant desires so I
don't know
that's about rice depend on it I'm
pretty indifferent yeah I mean so like
do you that you can get a pretty
consistent but from either or is there
one method yeah you just personally kind
of
now I mean I cross both boundaries like
just depending on what I'm using I
usually use some organic stuff and
inorganic so I mean but I mean as long
as you know your plant you know what it
wants usually you'll get the same
standard the same standard buds as long
as your environments pretty stable other
than the feeding yeah okay so what do
you think's the future of growing and
you know like we've seen some pretty
major innovations in terms of you know
like mammoth Bay was like kind of
something people might last or Eve and
say looking at lighting technology like
Gavita what do you think of some of the
new things that are gonna roll on to the
scene in the next couple years that
might be game changes well I mean I
think I think Big Pharma coming in
sweeping through California getting the
lobbyists to pass the laws here and [ __ ]
all the growers I think that's probably
the biggest game change because I think
a lot of us that are that are pioneers
in the business you're gonna get screwed
out of our companies and kind of our
careers that would probably be the
biggest game changer because that'd be a
defeat for a lot of people who have been
fighting since the 60s long before I was
involved to to get this legal correctly
you know as far as technology I mean I
mean kavita and the double-ended valve
have made huge leaps and bounds I mean I
used Solace Tech's double-ended stuff
and it's been it's phenomenal it's it's
night and day compared to just the
normal HPS or metal halide I love it
yeah okay fantastic
and so where does CBD fit into right
seeds you know like I don't think any
CBD strains from you guys
yeah we've released a few CBD lines but
the thing I've had a hard problem doing
is when I when I make CBD lines I don't
like to charge a lot for them but they
cost just as much to produce and I'm not
I'm not a big operation I'm not some
massive [ __ ] world you know multi
warehouse operation where I can just you
know afford to take big hits on one and
then charge a bunch for another CBD work
if there's it benefits so many people a
lot of them children a lot of people
with Alzheimer's a lot you know kids
with seizures so it's really really hard
for me to even charge anything let alone
a small amount for them and so I just
try to do small projects enough to where
I keep enough in stock to be able to
give it away when I want or you know if
someone doesn't necessarily have
an ailment but just want to try it they
can buy it yeah okay and so I mean how
do you feel about the whole THC to CBD
ratio then you know do you think that
there's an optimum ratio or you know
just pure CBD is best in terms of like
you know the medical properties of
cannabis so to speak I think I genuinely
think that's that's that depends on the
individual I mean the cannabis even even
in its medical aspects is an individual
experience you'll see some people saying
you know the THC helps a lot of their
cancer their cancer is any anything
through responses they're having the
medicine that are negative but again
some people say you know that's only the
CBD stuff that helps me that helps my
pain well a lot of people are only
helped by THC from pain so I mean really
like in generally speaking it's hard to
say I mean it's all an individual
experience some some people more helped
by a high THC to CBD ratio some people
are more helped by a higher CBD to THC
ratio and summer helped more by that
even one it's it's just so hard to say
it's so open and I don't think it's all
the science is ready to show what what
body chemistry works with what best then
that we'll ever know yeah okay
some only individuals neither thing yeah
okay so I mean you mentioned earlier you
good friends with the Rev you seem to
get featured in Skunk aloy is there any
particular relationship with him you
have is that just a thing where you
thinks you've got good strains and
therefore you know it gets featured or
is it more of like a business type deal
way being paid for well we've never paid
for anything with them they they skunk
is one of the few magazines that I've
been I've been really really focal about
liking because the one they've never
asked me for a dime never ever never
have asked me for a dime they don't ask
me for anything
they feature everyone that's in there is
featured on merit it's not because
they're paying for ads it's not because
they're doing this of that like high
times they're not paying for parties for
a high time [ __ ] they're not paying for
awards they're in there on merit they're
the ones making the waves in the
industry and the revs I've got along
with him so well for a long time just
because that we talk
we're not we don't talk regularly but
maybe once a month or twice a month and
usually it's just about what we're
working with at the time you know but
yeah I mean they feature my stuff
because they feel it's on merit then I'm
the one making the waves in the scene at
that particular time and then there's a
few months where I won't be in it
because I'm not you know and that's how
it goes but I love that I love the fact
that it's unbiased in that sense there's
people in there that I can't stand that
are making waves but they don't care if
I can't stand them you know I don't have
I don't have the ability to influence
their opinion on anything and I love
that yeah and so on a bit of a similar
topic there there's a lot of controversy
around that whole attitude seedbank
incident where there was other photos
yeah representing the riot strains woods
what was your take on that what happened
there all right the photos they're
referring to is for skunk pose work with
blood rose and it was a Heath Robinson's
black rose was up there as a picture
which was one of the moms from Heath
himself and that wasn't really that big
of a deal with the attitude it's just I
told him I said that this is what's
going on skunk oh just told me take it
down that's not the mom take it down
they took it down what happened with the
attitude there's there's a it was a
two-tiered thing and the first one was
when we were up there me and sub cool
TGA were the only Americans on that side
at the time not gauge not haze man I was
the one that brought them on later but
just me and sub cool and I didn't really
know some cool from anyone I didn't know
his husband mr. Jill at the time either
and they emailed the girl I believe her
name was Natalya at the time and said
you know what that guy's an [ __ ] if
he's on here we don't want to be on here
and at the time there he they were
making the most money for him I wasn't
making that much money for him so you
know the chick emailed me and said you
know sub cool is one of my good friends
and he said that you guys are not nice
so we need to talk about what we can do
to do this can you email them and kind
of be nice to them and be kissy Kissy
and I said no [ __ ] them I'm not doing
[ __ ] anyway so that kind of stuck in her
head that I wouldn't work with her that
way and just go kiss his ass for no good
reason or his wife's husband whatever it
is is ass
and the other the other problem was that
at the time gage he had just started his
company and Hays man were on my site and
I could because they were both friends
and Hays man had just left making seeds
for Moda and they had asked me to sell
their seeds for him they didn't have an
outlet and I said okay I'll do that so
selling their seeds and when the
attitude had originally picked me up I
said I will come on but only if you
bring these two guys with me because
when I go up I want my friends to go up
that's just how it goes you know and at
that time I was also trying I was put I
was pushing Bodhi so hard to go on the
attitude he didn't really want to at the
time just because he approaches
everything very cautiously he's smart
and smarter than I was that's what damn
sure and so I got gage on there in Hays
man and they picked up five packs from
each just an easily five pack order but
they agreed that that's what they would
do at the time and if they sold well
then they'd pick up more and I said
great that's great I didn't make a dime
off in their cells that wasn't the point
but the point was to get them on there
then gage sent me an email and said hey
man I would love your contact at the
attitudes email address I could thank
her and I was like okay well whatever
yeah I'm not making any money off you I
don't give a [ __ ] if people around my
back I mean it was obvious what he was
doing but I didn't care so I wasn't
making any money off of him but that's
not what he did emailed her and said
yeah I don't know what this mat guy's
told you about me but you know he's kind
of a [ __ ] and just like completely
buried me to her so not only was I
buried by sub cool then I was buried by
him my own friend it was supposed friend
at the time and that's when the attitude
were just they tell you started writing
me nasty emails and I called her a dumb
[ __ ] and that was it end of story
interesting isn't it and so yeah is that
kind of the origins of the whole gage
Greene dispute or does it trace back
more to a reserve or you know I Jojo was
a friend of mine he was a friend of my
friend NC GA North Cal Growers
Association he's a friend of a lot of
ours and not a lot of us knew the whole
true story about how he had overdosed
who who had given him the stuff to
overdose on and where all of his seed
stock went and over time we started to
learn more and more as gage would
[ __ ] let little bits out a little of
its info out and then he'd say oh yeah I
got this agenda it's like nobody else
had that you didn't pass it on [ __ ]
you get that you know
a little bit by bit the story would come
out but that was that was almost the end
of our friendship and he did that with
me in Italian I even then I gave him
another chance I was like dude that was
kind of [ __ ] up would you do that for
her that was a very nice of you I need
to be apologized and then you know a few
months later I get an email from someone
saying hey this guy's burying you to me
like you know just random customer I'm
like what you sure
and he's like yeah yes I hit up HJ what
the dude what are you doing are you okay
you know like let talk to me what's
going on are you pissed about and then
you know he'd say no no I'm not doing
that
and then eventually happened again and I
confront him he's like yeah you know
what you're a [ __ ] [ __ ] I don't
like you and that was it that was it and
he continued to bury me from then on out
so I just kind of stayed cool for a
while I just figured I'd catch him out
and about slap the [ __ ] out of him calm
them down but he's hard to catch man
he's hard to catch out of places he runs
pretty quick yeah that's that's about
where he's at old bald-headed Heisenberg
looking [ __ ] and so I guess the
same thing yeah yeah yeah yeah I didn't
really know them that well I mean I
didn't give a [ __ ] about their lines
they were working with Brothers Grimm
stuff which is great Brothers Grimm
already did it and they were just
rehashing old Brothers Grimm work I
didn't have any respect for them because
what they didn't Sonny Chiba but at the
same time I didn't really know them
personally so I didn't give a [ __ ] to
attack I were saying anything about him
I didn't know them personally but after
they did that you bet your ass I learned
about him and [ __ ] made sure and
raised hell with them everywhere I could
[ __ ] with my business you [ __ ] with my
livelihood and at the time I was helping
my grandma who had Alzheimer's [ __ ]
pay for her her nursing home bill and
that was that was like all my money was
going to that and they cut into that
hard they made it really hard for me to
do that so I took that personal and I
still take it personal to this day okay
and some an [ __ ] like that I keep
grudges and so I mean you mentioned
heath Robertson in the blood Rosie oh
yeah I think I found a post online where
he says that you know essentially you
initially came to him at some point and
asked for some of his genetics saying
you were gonna be doing a medical type
project which I think is the one you're
referencing earlier in the episode
is that yep is that really what happened
or is that no worry just to be right
when I when I first talked to him that
was what we talked about and then he
found out I had original Apollo 13 f1
lines from Brothers Grimm and he because
originally he wasn't going to do
anything with me he's like hey dude how
about you send me those seeds and I'll
send you like you know a hundred of the
black rose all right well that sounds
good to me
send him those seeds and he had an
intermediary this dude named oh so green
who works for insane seed posse and that
guy was a [ __ ] another piece of work
him and Heath were [ __ ] butt buddies
like on the real butt buddies and yeah
so those two those two just basically
[ __ ] me over really hard didn't send
me [ __ ]
but skunk Oh had already gotten more of
Black Rose seeds from pot pimp this dude
rips that is that's another accurate
name for that dude rips but he had
gotten those seats from him and that's
where I didn't even make the [ __ ]
line so I don't know what he's talking
about
you know maybe would make the light it
didn't work delight ain't nothing to do
with that I wasn't releasing it for
skunk oh but ya know I did try to get
the seats from him originally and we
were gonna try to work with him and do
stuff with them I mean shanty Baba
worked with us back then and Ernesto
from Buda seeds worked with us back then
Delta Knight labs worked with us back
then and I'm still friends with all
those guys to this day all of them and
they were all happy with what we did
with them the only people who weren't
happy for him I mean I contacted
everyone in California to be a part of
it rascal the rascal still thought [ __ ]
like he knows anything but yeah him was
rascal and he's Robinson turned to be
out turned out to be the biggest
[ __ ] out of all that [ __ ] so what
was the deal with rascal because I mean
he was also someone who claims that he
stole his photos your strains same part
of the Heath Robinson thing it's [ __ ]
brilliant you know I've never at that
point I'd never even grown anything of
Rascals we had been trying clone only
stuff for the most part that we were
working with don't know why he would
claim that no sorry I mean that you used
some of his photos of his plans for your
strains oh no that's that's pretty
[ __ ] impossible now the only the only
photo that ever got used was one if he's
Robin says and that was for skunk was
lining he passed me the [ __ ] picture
so it's like and the second I found that
out I was like okay take this [ __ ] down
that's not good
bad business you know but but rascal no
he don't the only thing you ever had to
[ __ ] do is he got an email from me you
told me just [ __ ] kiss his ass and I
said alright dude later that's it that's
my only interaction with that piece of
[ __ ] and he still runs his dick sucker
all the time now but usually that's busy
working on swears [ __ ] knob are you
gonna have to edit all this I mean if
you want me to fit into things in oh no
he's just a runt I don't know hey he's
fun he's just he just a loudmouth
[ __ ] is he's nothing special he died
i don't even dislike swerve I feel bad
for him you know it made quite an ass
out of himself over the years actually I
pity the guy but he's never done
anything bad to me other than top [ __ ]
and I mean that plant you people do that
I don't mind that yeah okay a lot of
people who seem to hold a bit of a
grudge about the comments you made about
outlaw when he was arrested you know in
the whole that whole situation you know
would you do anything differently if you
could do that one again what did I say
he's a piece of [ __ ]
how long ya know he's still a piece of
[ __ ] he's a piece of [ __ ] then he's a
piece of [ __ ] now
I mean sigh I said I specifically said
it sucks when anybody gets arrested for
this plan I don't wish that on anyone
but the guy's a [ __ ] so I mean I
don't have any sympathy for him I'm
risking the same [ __ ] everybody's
risking the same [ __ ] we all know what
we're risking especially back then you
know it wouldn't have made me any less
of a jerk I don't know why it would make
him any less of a jerk so now he'll know
I wouldn't change anything yeah okay and
so I guess maybe a question tie up this
little segment the current the current
cannabis community would largely be
described on Instagram at least is you
know full of drama and backstabbing and
things like that do you feel like this
is an accurate statement or do you feel
like there's always been ongoing dramas
and feuds there's I mean [ __ ] I mean for
me there's always been ongoing drums and
feuds but I'm one of the few people who
will snap back at people or say anything
I mean you don't see bode and a lot of
dramas or feuds you don't see I mean
there's it doesn't really happen to him
but
because he's so [ __ ] nice and he's
hard to get ahold of to people but I'm
not I try to be really accessible and
and that's that's been a hard part of it
as far as Instagram goes though like I
mean have you seen my Instagram I mostly
post pictures or records there's a
reason for that people are [ __ ] on
there yeah so yeah I mean it's just
getting worse because there's a lot more
people involved in the scene I mean back
then there were probably a hundred of us
now there's tens of thousands of people
calling themselves breeders and it's
just worse and worse every day
and they're all a little back biters
like your groomer Grover whatever his
name is
yeah yeah yeah he's I mean he's all up
in that [ __ ] you know all those guys the
only reason I know their names this cuz
all the [ __ ] caught but you know more
power to him it makes him happy through
if that's the way they want to spend
their time and so you know all the
previous questions i I've kind of
questioned in my mind how come you don't
have any gorilla glue hybrids it it
seems like a strain you'd breed with but
I couldn't seem to see any easier no
miss decision yeah that was a conscious
decision one one being that my friend
Jason from dark horse he has he went out
of his way to make sure and get the
right the right rights from the breeder
so be the one who worked with it and
Jason worked hard to do that and I
respect that and I'd not gonna step on
his toes he's one of my friends you know
announced that was pretty much it okay
I'm help I'm helping him make the S once
in a way right now so I mean I mean it's
there's work but it's not it's not my
hands-on work and it's originally going
to be but now it's just mostly
advisement on how to make the S ones and
so how do you feel about all the other
brands who are 4s ones all that you know
given that information we've just learnt
about the exclusivity rights I mean
that's up to them if they want to do
that or not if they want to make friends
or they want to make enemies that's up
to them you know I just don't stab my
friends in the back and if they're not
friends with him and they think that's
okay then that's up to them but I mean
Jason there's a lot of friends he has a
lot of friends like me then I have a lot
of friends and it just all backfires
eventually I mean that's up to them yeah
okay
and so do you ever have do you ever want
to get any of your lines and try to take
them to like a true breeding point like
maybe an extended the ex project or you
know some kind of IPO the right berries
already at that staged where it's true
breeding and that's all the crosses we
are making with it now are from the true
breeding stance that's why almost every
right berry crosses purple and blueberry
relation to that f7 the right very mated
to f7 and that's where I stopped it
because that was any anything further
than that it was just not doing anything
extra to the line mmm as far as IBL
that's that's quite a heavy undertaking
I I don't know any IPL's that are true
IPL's deep chunk maybe but even that has
a green phenotype in a purple phenotype
which means it's not a true IBL trying
to get an IPL in cannabis is is not I
can't say it's not achievable but I've
never seen it [ __ ] happen any
anywhere so in trying to do that I mean
I don't know I don't know if I want to
go down that path of frustration yeah
okay and when you grow just for personal
use are you like more of a few strains
like you get in some variety or you're
just like a 102 strains oh I know I
always have a lot of variety and I for a
lot of Southeast Asians for myself okay
so what are some of your favorites the
right bear line would be one it's mostly
tied dominant the original Santa Cruz
Blue Dream again tie dominant it's just
because that that works with my my my
chemical my chemical body type you know
it just it's happy stuff and indicas
tend to depress me and make me depressed
and anxious Hayes's don't really make me
anxious but they I don't know just it's
not my thing it's very specific to the
Southeast Asian stuff myself yeah okay
and so if you can only name one what's
your favorite strain mmm for personal
smoke it would be the right very
definitely it's not too heavy it doesn't
end day in my day cuz I you know we're
out of business
stay awake yeah that's what I tend to
like to do and so would you consider the
riot bear
all the clockwork orange' to be more
kind of you know the thing that comes to
mind when people think of riot seeds you
know I think everybody associates a
clockwork orange' with us just because
it's been around the longest it's the
rarest the clones it mean it sells for
20 grand a shot you know and that's
that's always been a big thing with us
okay for a while I had the record in
California is selling for 500 an ounce
like constantly and in never going for
under that and it was only sold by the
ounces never sold by the pound so yeah
it had a lot of really special things to
it associated with it
I wish right Barry would probably be
more popular session with us because I
did more work with it and worked harder
on it and I think a cheap or
interbreeding standpoint but I think
overall Clockwork Orange is probably
associated with this more okay and
what's what's like the an upcoming
project that you personally really
excited for um I do want to do more work
with our plant and banana I mean there's
only been released maybe a few times we
did the be it the s1 a few times and we
did the BX one project but there's a lot
more to do with that yeah there's a lot
more to do with that I've been really
stoked with the East Coast our diesel
strawberry cream cross using that and a
bunch of lines because it's just it's
like it's it's been really reliable at
all of its out processes being keepers
to someone at some point they're all
really phenomenal and that was kind of a
surprise because diesel is very picky
and usually not predictable but the
strawberry cream cross to it for some
reason gave it a lot more predictability
and it was pretty amazing
yeah okay and so what's one of the
strains that you know if you only pick
one that you'd really love to get back
in your library that's been lost either
by you personally or just everyone oh
god that's a hard one san diego purple
train wreck was really good it was a
specific cut a purple train wreck of and
this is before DNA was releasing their
purple train or whatever the [ __ ] they
called it it was just a cross from there
and it was just really good had to say
it always had like that tight tie pie
from the train wreck side but it was
just really really really happy and if
you smoke the resin from it
it would if you smoked enough of it it
would give you almost like tracers like
acid has and that was really cool okay
interesting
yeah and so I mean you mentioned earlier
before selling clones you're one of the
few readers who I've seen you know
openly kind of selling clones do you
feel that something the other breeders
should do or is it just something you're
just kind of taking advantage of because
no one else is no one should do it no
hell no nobody should do that [ __ ] no I
mean like there's been times very like
like where I was moving and I packed up
my whole room like five times over
excited want to lose anything and I had
a lot of [ __ ] leftover Canadian lose a
single plant and I was like oh my god
what the [ __ ] am I gonna do with all
this well so I was like oh well I'll
just put up some for sale and if any
breeders want to get a hold of this
stuff that they would normally wouldn't
even have a shot at getting and I got a
lot of good responses from that so now
when people see like that I'm working
with something they'll make me an offer
on what you know whatever they think
it's worth and if I think it's worth
sending it to him for that amount and
going through the hassle of hook and
shipping and all that [ __ ] then we'll do
it if not that it won't but yeah it's
cool though I mean I don't see a lot of
breeders doing that because a lot of
breeders are working with stuff you can
go buy a collective so so I mean how do
you feel about the whole concept of kind
of like you know I'm not gonna say clone
hoarding but like you know really not
giving coins out to many people at all
do you feel like that's more positive
than it is negative or it's just you
know I used to be really really
stringent about that I mean if someone
asked me like don't pass this out it
never goes out and that's just the way
it is I mean that's why I have the
connections that I do I never break that
but at the same time I you know
clockwork orange' I kept that back from
so many people and I've almost lost it
so many times that I was like okay this
is getting kind of ridiculous I'm gonna
end up losing this just out of greed so
now I stopped doing all that [ __ ] just
for my own personal [ __ ] it's it's too
easy to lose [ __ ] that way yeah okay and
so out of all the strains you've tried
over the years what's the worst oh God
probably something I made and it was a
it was a it was de shaman's purple widow
and it was it was just like I was
[ __ ] around with autoflowering [ __ ]
at the time for no reason it was just
see what would happen crossed lowrider
and it was the worst [ __ ] I've ever seen
in my life did you shave him purple
widow in the first place Auto flowered
and it shouldn't have made any seeds but
I see three leftover nuts okay I'll try
this [ __ ] it was terrible it was [ __ ]
four it was as bad as any like brick
schwag I've ever seen and I was
responsible for that madness that was
the worst strain effort so I mean like
just touching on lowrider how do you
feel about autos is it something you'd
ever look into or no I did it a long
time ago I released a few lines but it
was only because I was trying to fill a
void in the market in the American
market and really I don't I wasn't happy
with any of the I mean they're okay
people were happy with them that grew
them but I I mean real growers aren't
gonna be happy with that they grow real
strains it's just not it's never gonna
be the same or equal as long as you're
losing ruderalis but if I was like an
aspiring breeder nowadays and I really
wanted to learn how to breed and watch
selection and and and how progeny comes
out I would I would advise someone go
get some regular autoflowering seeds
because they have a very short cycle and
you can see selection and evolution in
action a lot faster than you would using
a normal line just to learn how
outcrossing works learning selecting
traits etc etc that's what it's good for
is training someone how to do that and
that's about it with that [ __ ] and of
course like Europeans that have to grow
in like little tiny apartments I mean
I'm sure they're good for that yeah
so I mean you mentioned earlier that
like s wanting a coin only can be like a
good way to retain the genetics improve
the vigor and things lost over the years
do you like there's any other ways to
improve the you know the traits that
have been lost over the years or you
just have to want it so to speak no I
mean you can also tissue culture I mean
but that's not it does not necessary
through breeding it's just tissue
culturing you can get a lot of the
vigour back I use a lot s wanting if I'm
not using it just to make seeds I use it
for a lot for parental identification to
see what other phenotypes are that the
parents would have put out in order to
guess the parental parentage of a line
that's also a good good use of it but
yeah I mean like if you're getting a
figure back to a plant the only things
you can really do are s wanting it out
crossing in selecting for a phenotype
and then stabilize in that tray
through a successful Brewers excessive
breeding or through yeah it's funny
that's it okay and so is teacher
culturing something you're doing at the
moment or looking into or you think it's
kind of just more of a dream we did it
early on very early on very very early
on before anybody was like selling kits
or anything
it was very [ __ ] hard to do because
we did it in a normal house without a
[ __ ] fume hood without any kind of
HEPA filtration system and it was not
very successful I mean it was very very
little success with it and every time
I've tried it since it's been similar
spotty stuff I have friends that have
done it successfully without all that
stuff and I don't know how they did that
they must have insanely Anil OCD
cleaning abilities and not I've wearing
masks and [ __ ] but I think it's a great
thing to do I just you really need a lab
setting to be able to do it successfully
and make it reliable yeah and so we see
like you know these kits where you can
take little cuttings of Leafs of little
seedlings and and get determine their
sex and stuff like that do you think
that this rise in kind of our use of
scientific tools and techniques is going
to continue to rise or they're just like
kind of been moving fad and will always
do things kind of the way we have I
don't know I think I really do think the
tissue culturing is going to be the the
ideal way the future I mean it could
store so many samples in such a small
area with much less light I mean it is
the ideal method as long as you have a
clean space but it's happened to
filtration and lab lab settings get
cheaper you know you'll probably see
people weren't doing that more than
cloning but that's right now I mean
cloning is just so easy to do that I
don't see that changing in the near
future yeah of course and so a lucky
last question if you could go and get
one oh sorry if you're gonna get some
land rice seeds from one period of time
from any region where would it be oh
that's a good one but I would like to go
back to to China during some of the
earliest earliest mmm like man's
earliest work with cannabis
harvesting it and growing it and the
first early selection seven see what it
really looked like I mean there's a lot
of guesses on whether it was a broadleaf
indica type plant or whether it was a
narrow leaf plant when what exact value
was from and what it was like what it's
early trade sure like that would that
would probably be be the ultimate dreams
to see what the the first cannabis plant
looked like before it went all around
the world and changed its looking form
yeah interesting and so sorry just
clarify the the kind of the cradle of
life is in China you think yeah that's
that's that's been the scientific
hypothesis since the 70s yeah fantastic
like I guess near the mountains maybe or
yeah or the Golden Triangle I think okay
I think it's you especially that or like
the the yeah I think the Chinese Union
mountains there's some some people would
say that but I think the Golden Triangle
is also another place that it could be
so yeah yeah interesting awesome we I
think that just about brings us to the
end of it was there any shot at comments
you wanted to make no I think I already
talked about everyone that's it's been
really awesome everyone else that helped
me along the way on right seeds thank
you and yeah that's it also more things
mark on the show today man all right
thank you
so what do you think
you like my Lorna I think I do hope you
had a good time and thanks again to get
a garden solutions for 20 Australia and
most importantly Matt right and right
seeds
[Music]