foreign
[Music]
welcome back my friends for another
episode of the podcast a cannabis
podcast for budding enthusiasts and as
always you're joined by your boy heavy
days here from the upside down Library
on this episode we're incredibly
grateful to be joined by the one and
only two of the seed company
[Music]
an OG within the CBD Community the man
who brought Charlotte's Web to the
greater masses the [ __ ] Stanley brothers
and a guy who's collaborating with Duke
Diamond do I need to say any more
[Music]
so excited for this one two is an
absolute Legend here to talk all themes
from past present future predictions so
much more
let's get into it
alrighty gang thanks for joining us for
another one on this episode we're joined
by The Man Behind The Seed Company a
range of killer CBD lines affiliations
with Charlotte's Web a whole bunch of
other cool strains we're going to dig
into a big thank you and shout out to
two of the seed company for joining us
today oh thanks actually uh it's R the
R4 not the Charlotte's Web that's what
they need that you know what I mean
we'll just I guess it's yeah we don't we
don't want this you know we don't want
the Stanley Brothers coming after us
look let's start it off right there give
us a bit of a rundown what's the woo for
all right so um I came out from
Cleveland and uh
like 10 years ago 2009 uh my
managed to get some samples out to
Denver and then they were like holy wow
so I went around and you know I got
strands from all my friends and
collected you know basically Ohio and
then uh
there was this one called the cream and
um
it would mess you up so I always you
know I knew that was special and my
buddy
didn't have that cut available but he
had these seeds that this guy named we
call Wu-Tang back home great guy and uh
you know he was growing his basement and
get a little mishap there and the seeds
were made and when we when I got to
Colorado we ran all my gear in this I
set up a hundred lighter you know and uh
we ran like a small project just to get
us moving with this uh
with a company called Greenworks and uh
we got the test back and sure enough
there was uh in the Woos because I had
two of them the woo one and the wu4
they you know and they came back one was
like the basically hemp almost I mean
like within a couple points and then the
other one was a little more like a
higher
THC and then I
they were like sorry man you're not
allowed in the warehouse and uh I was
like can I get my stuff back and they
wouldn't give me that back and then
um good friend Adam Dunn who I'm sure
you're familiar with uh called me one
day and was like Yo dude they came
like uh Kelly roller this dude who was
supposed to be my homie and Josh Stanley
came shooting through uh Adams like club
or place of business it's an art gallery
and we're like trying to get him in on
it like do you want to you want to run
you know and he's like nah man that's
that's my dude's [ __ ] you're not allowed
to I know I don't want anything to do
with it you know then he called me and
then uh
well and it turned you know for fun the
cream was uh an aft Jack like an Afghani
number one time to Jack Herer and then
the uh CBD end actually came from
Alex at residencies whose Soma's
son-in-law actually he passed away uh
but he had been breeding stuff that Soma
had created and this was the reclining
Buddha that actually gave all the CBD to
the web
or the R4 or the wu4 you know to that
plant uh
and then so I was uh that's when I
started drinking a lot you know that's
when I decided yeah I got really mad you
know what I mean like he's [ __ ]
stole my [ __ ] and you know what I mean
now they're now they've got a TV show
coming out with Sanjay Gupta on CNN I
was like [ __ ] that right uh and uh I was
so I was just I was kind of ruining
myself at that point because I realized
you know
like that that one plant was like the
key to
you know that that was my millions of
dollars that I thought I was gonna make
when I came to Colorado to be a weed
millionaire and uh
so I was upset for a while man and then
my buddy was like dude you gotta watch
that show and I'm like man [ __ ] those
dudes I know they got my plant and he's
like just watch it so I watched it and I
realized that
you know uh
what I brought was helping people like
helping somebody who couldn't get any
other hell man that poor girl Charlotte
feed piggy uh was having like 100
seizures a day man she was a twin and
her twin sister didn't have any kind of
problems you could see like the
difference in like the um how she was
growing and developing as a human being
you know it was uh not to use this word
in any way derogatory but she was the
she was [ __ ] literally and that she
couldn't learn and grow do you know what
I mean
yeah yeah like it's in the medical sense
and you know I realized that like you
know no matter what man I'm helping
people and that I need to get back to
work like I cried and like I wanted to
meet her before she had actually passed
away too because she kind of saved me
like I was
I was really pushing my uh
you know my bar I was doing a lot of
chemicals including alcohol and just get
you know trying to because I thought you
know I came out here with the intent on
like
doing that whole thing you know
so then uh my well this guy Adam Cooper
who uh he helped out a lot he had a
cherry
which was like a nice it was a canatonic
S1 and we took that and we put it on
this Kandahar that uh my buddy's brother
actually got in Kandahar he's a sapper
those are the guys that uh look for they
go ahead and like look for bombs and I
you know the things that blow up and
kill you and like they had brought some
back and we intended to use that
structure of the Afghan to strengthen up
the Cherry which was and and the Cherry
was amazing like the extract from it
tasted like I mean cherries like
like
uncontrollably you know like a medicine
which was really weird to me you know
like wow this is really his medicine it
really tastes like medicine
so we uh I've read a bunch of stuff in
my backyard I took that cherry I took
the oh I somebody had given me uh a cut
of the woo five or the R5 that now came
out which was those guys those dick
heads that stole it they self my what
you know what I mean they selled it and
made s1s and sold them for I don't know
man I think I'm like a hundred bucks a
piece
like what a duh [ __ ] [ __ ] uh
so I got you know and I I got some uh
sour tsunami and then I got just a bunch
of different uh heart you know some
Harley Harlequin stuff and I put it all
out with the mail
uh
the male Cherry pandahar that we had and
there was like uh I don't know like
eight other plants out there pollinate
them all and then that's when
like I I I I'd had them all and I sat on
them for a while and then James from the
seed uh from seeds here now hit me up
and was like Yo dude you wanna
sell those things and I was like yeah
that'd be cool so we started packing
them up I gave a ton of weight Joe I
probably gave away
like uh
at least a third of what I started with
like
Cana moms and who aren't nice people and
like just just like you know trying to
be the Johnny Appleseed of sorts
and then um
went ended up going to the emerald cup I
assume that's I've only been to two of
them so I assume uh that was the first
one and then does when James only had
like 12 breeders on the it was like me
and sunny and Odie and uh
Mike from exotic you know and uh
actually yeah so he ended up selling
like uh you know that was the first year
and then the next year when we went back
like people like Duke over here actually
kept people were like do you have any
CBD stuff and he just kept sending
people to me
like uh consistently so like he was
rocking the table
it's a busy weekend man we just raged
out and I sold out a people were coming
up they're like I need CBD and I'm like
yeah here are seeds and they're like
we're gonna breed with these and I was
like that's the point and then
from that and some stuff that James did
like basically almost 95 percent of the
CBD hemp genetics in America were born
like uh from stuff that I had made you
know like uh all that cherry wine and
all that stuff has got my cherry
condohar and like just it's crazy to
think the scope but I'm proud of that
um
but yeah
that's that's all that
what a great recount I mean so many
different angles we can follow up on I
guess the first one just as a sort of
nomenclature thing would you prefer that
both I and the community cause it wu4 R4
or are you comfortable with the name
Charlotte's Web well I like woo because
it gives uh honor to the guy that made
it you know you know one of the coolest
things that uh
I got to do was I got to call him after
you know all this popped off and I was
like hey dude guess what because of you
like
hundreds of people and children and
everything or finding
and now it's like Millions you know what
I mean like CBD I you know what I told
my mom before she passed away I told her
and this is you know obviously I
stretched it through a little but I told
her I invented CBD
you know
and then everywhere that she goes and
when she sees CBD that was me and she
was like she was stoked so
um but in a way like
we brought it to the thing you know so
the woo would be great because that
gives him the you know what I mean like
it it was an honor to call him and tell
him that he because of him like people
were finding relief and not having
seizures and little kids were like we
were the my buddy Todd uh the Ravens and
I uh were the first people ever allowed
us to give kids cannabis in a hospital
ever like in in Colorado at least I know
but like uh we made a roll on like I
grew it and he formulated it and these
kids would have a seizure and maybe you
saw it it was all over the Internet and
like you take this roll on and like hit
their feet and within like 20 seconds
they weren't having a seizure anymore
wow
like
yeah that was cool and fulfilling so
we'll call it the woo
I get all messed up too man because so
what happened it became the r because I
had horrible handwriting like
like I don't even type legibly you know
what I mean like it's horrible
um
so they misread it and re-labeled it
which is probably you know that's just
something [ __ ] do anyway so
are we able to loop back on that how how
was it that um the Stanley Brothers came
to sort of enter that facility like what
was the series of events that led to
them sort of getting access to it oh we
harvested
we harvested the first round they sent
it to the lab Lab says came back with
high CBD then I was kicked out of the
the uh thing I had a I wasn't
see I'm not upset that I was kicked out
I had a felony that a drug felony from
like a while ago and I hadn't quite got
after that 10-year Mark do you know what
I mean
yeah but I was pretty upset that they
wouldn't give me my gear back which is
just some [ __ ] so the guy I came out
with was supposed to be like my
like my homie you know we started yeah
the actually yeah the statue of
limitations is up man we started
hustling ecstasy and I was like 17 going
to Raves like all over the United States
like all over well the Midwest at least
you know I made that dude a ton of money
you think he'd be like a little more
you know not piece of [ __ ] but so they
kept that and then I suppose uh this one
isn't I'm not sure I assumed the
Stanley's or at least Josh went to
you know saw the test results and went
over there
and asked him for it or something you
know okay so it's sounding like it was
all sort of quite opportunistic on their
part
yeah
I mean they they asked they made claw
they made S1 my stuff like that's like a
sin in the uh breeding community so it
takes somebody's especially like that
you know it's gonna take somebody's gear
S1 and so
you know make thousands and thousands
and thousands of dollars off of it that
seems like a pretty shitty thing to do
so uh the the listeners will will give
me grief if I don't try to follow up on
it why why was it you were kicked out of
the facility a little felony that was uh
from a drug felony like uh from like
2001 and then three so I wasn't off they
have a 10-year
uh minimum like when I got here it had
just been implemented like I was allowed
in the facility and then all of a sudden
they were like well if you've had a
felony or we're still on uh paper
in the last 10 years you got to wait
till that's over to work in the industry
so do you think that it that was like
the actual truth that they just found
out more like oh sorry policies policy
or do you think it was like their way of
being able to get rid of you
yeah actually a hundred percent uh
literally the guys that rip me off the
main guy's name was Chad
oh wow okay because I'd just like to
clarify because one of the stories you
sometimes hear around the community is
that
um the the Stanley Brothers had this
plan and they grew it thinking it was
THC only to find it with CBD and then
like they sort of like quote swindled
Charlotte's parents being like yeah buy
this weed like just trying to sell it to
anyone who would buy it
um do you think that that probably
wasn't actually the case and they sort
of had more of an idea of what they were
doing the whole time they went
specifically to those guys after the
tests were published in a local uh weed
magazine I still have it around here on
the bookshelf it was the first time I've
ever seen my strains in print so I kept
it but uh yeah man they knew exactly
what they were doing and uh I know it's
mine because it was a variegated plant
and you can see that in that video where
they showed all the plants like oh
that's my [ __ ] gear but then I also
heard that like they had uh
they had a Tennessee farmer a Kentucky
farm there Rocky whatever and uh there's
like bottles of Eagle laying around and
[ __ ]
like they had sprayed it with like
horrible fungicides like and they were
gonna give this to children
you know what I mean if that's and they
probably did actually because that was
before we established a you know
thresholds for pesticides and all that
kind of like you know yeah yeah yeah
yeah okay
but yeah that was all intentional I'm
not sure about me
getting you know I know the felony had
something to do with that but yeah that
whole
that yeah that wasn't an accident on
their part
so what did you sort of do in uh the
aftermath of all this you know you sort
of mentioned that you were feeling a bit
down in the dumps
lots of drugs and alcohol that's what I
did for a while while I was really upset
yeah look I think that's pretty
understandable was there anything in
particular that sort of helped you see
the light at the end of that tunnel yeah
that video man with the weed with Sanjay
Gupta was on CNN and seeing that girl
Charlotte
um
seeing the Met something that I did like
help anybody is cool but like to see
somebody in such a horrible spot
where even the worst of uh
pharmaceutical drugs that they give to
Children won't work like I don't know if
you ever see what they give to kids with
seizures it's disgusting like it's uh
like Valium and Keppra and like
basically you're just [ __ ] your kid
all up
you know after watching that I realized
like uh
you know hey I did this already might as
well get back to work and that you know
that what I did was kind of important if
uh
even if I don't get you know like I saw
the other day that that uh Charlotte's
Web the company is now worth millions
do you have any ambition or want to try
to have some of the credit attributed to
or are you just at the point where
you've moved on and you're just doing
other stuff no man what are you
like how do you
like what do you like I can't afford a
good lawyer and I'm sure they can like
more than anything then how do you prove
all that like
yeah like
you know that seems like a I could a lot
of money to lose the battle you know
yeah if nothing else I think it should
be a goal that the uh the community
knows what you've contributed but like
thankfully in the sort of intro you gave
us there's a there's a whole range of
other avenues I'd love to follow up on
but I guess the first question is you
know given you do have such you know um
a focal tying in to the woo do you do
you still like to work with it or are
you at the point where you've done a lot
of crosses you've got stuff to give to
people and you're doing other stuff now
you know man uh there's not a lot much
left to do with CBD or
um my homie Adam jacks up in Oregon is
making like uh
taking like you know uh OG Kush wouldn't
see any he can back it up and make OG
Kush hemp that's like the only way that
I see CBD hemp being like uh
uh yeah like okay so here for instance I
make a product called heaven and it's uh
CBD tinctures and stuff and uh when we
first start when I first started
kilos of CBD just the crude were like 3
500 bucks distill it was like seven or
eight or yeah yeah seven or eight
thousand dollars in that that uh I don't
use the isolate but that [ __ ] was like
10 20 I don't know it was high and now
like kilos and CBD are like 200 bucks
so like to be able to farm all that
you know what I mean it
at this point like I think CBD is unless
you're gonna do those Boutique kind of
things with it uh you know it's just
available I mean lots of seeds out there
you know that have
you know I think that one's done I don't
I I I'm gonna try and do some
one-to-ones here with uh
with Duke here I got I got a nice one of
my projects when you take a THC plan and
a CBD plant like on ends of the
spectrums you end up with like 50
percent
uh one to one and two to ones and like
25 High CBD and 25
and like those one to ones like the I
did the Tiger Beat and that was testing
out at 16 and a half THC with 17 and a
half CBD on it
I like that kind of thing that's quite
impressive in terms of the numbers like
normally I'd feel like you rarely see
one-to-one strains go above like 10 and
10.
I know right that was like it was
beautiful and then I had some that were
like the
at a strain called the bird I set it up
to uh Alaska and that he's got a zero
THC like it's maybe
the machines don't really pick it up if
there is any
so
that's a pretty cool
like uh
you know like if you could have a so the
THC Gene is responsible for like the
plant's immune system and stuff like
that so A pure CBD plant that doesn't
have that
Gene capable like at least being there
doesn't isn't as good because it doesn't
have that
you know uh the immune response thing
yeah certainly that's interesting do you
do you find that like you know as an
extension of that they're like they're
more prone to pests and mold and
botritis or not necessarily
yeah yeah uh the woman that owns the lab
who is a good friend of mine she
actually went through some stuff and has
uh
a non-detectable but the THC Gene is
switched on it just isn't working and
that she had uh
not patented but uh you know got some
legal paperwork over because that's a
cool
uh trait you know what I mean
yeah yeah yeah certainly okay so they
sort of do need a little bit more um
mothering so to speak
I mean
there's like uh like weird stuff like
that like genetic abnormalities that
would be fun to Surf through you know
what I mean
and find like uh polyploids or like
there's some weird autoflowering genics
that kind of come and hemp too that's
nice I'm growing CBG this year outside
because
it doesn't run hot
and I just wanted to grow some plants
outside you know
okay so do you feel like maybe like the
CBG is like a the gene is like a bit
further located away so you don't you
like you rarely get THC being made in
conjunction with it
yeah like when you see a full like a 20
CBG plant there's rarely any any THC in
there well CBG is the precursor too all
the other ones so by bottlenecking it
right there it's not really able to
produce
you know other things
and why is it do you think that CBG has
only in the past few years got a
limelight sort of shined onto it whereas
CBD has you know sort of being touted
for a lot longer
you know man we didn't even know like
scientists had no idea there wasn't even
even an endocannabinoid system in your
body until like the mid 90s they
discovered it and um you know we're
still we're still
uh as a you know a community and stuff
discovering like all kinds of new
kind of you know like stuff in the
plants cannabinoids like just you know
terpenes like they're still like cbg's
been around for a little while it's just
uh you know as people
okay so we didn't have uh testing
equipment back in the day you know you
couldn't just take in Ohio especially
you just can't take your uh weed to a
lab and have them test it so that's why
you know that that wasn't really
available until everybody started to go
online with medical so now
like uh I like to have a lot of stuff
tested and that gives me a good idea of
what's going on in the plant and like
you could find those anomalies like I'm
sure through the CBD breeding uh
somebody found them G or high CBG plants
they're very prevalent in um
in Europe actually
like uh a lot of that the hemp that they
grow
is actually High cpg
and what sort of benefits do you think
CBG can bring to the table that maybe
CBD doesn't quite do as well
you know I know it's really good for
your brain and uh your bone structure
it's like a bone but at the same time
man CBG
uh has like I don't know what hair I
have growing and my fingernails grow
super fast and uh so I assume it's like
the same I like the the
I guess it's really
I haven't yet got to um really get in on
it I've just been
I just had it I've been growing it just
caused the last couple years and I kind
of Set It Off to the side after we
harvested it and I gave it to my dude to
make some suppositories for some cancer
patients so
um I guess technically I did try it but
I don't know
hey it's brilliant you bring that up
because I was gonna say you know I saw
on your Instagram you had those uh full
spectrum suppositories by the looks of
it I just wanted to ask you know do you
feel that um like suppository based
cannabinoids work pretty well I hadn't
heard much about that but I'd love to
hear more
here I can break this down this makes
perfect sense okay um
so you eat some weed right you eat let's
just say some oil it gets to your
stomach it gets subjected to a very low
PH from your stomach acid which does
things to it converts it does you know
then it gets shot over to your liver
and then that changes it into a whole
different chemical and then it gets into
your bloodstream right yep all right
ma'am so when you when you boof it
like it literally goes all the
cannabinoids without being converted
without being you know I mean go right
into your bloodstream via your
intestines you know that's like the most
absorbent thing ever
so and it doesn't get converted in any
way or like be subjected to chemical
changes or anything like uh literally
like the THD goes right into your blood
and like all that stuff just goes
straight up in there
ah fantastic you avoid first pass
metabolism
yeah right interesting interesting okay
and then what do you what's like the
onset time you know what man uh
all right
I decided
um because I gave my medicine to a
couple people I decided to try it myself
and uh I would just I would do it and go
to bed
you know what I mean I wasn't like uh
I I wasn't like doing it and like you
know running a marathon or trying to
stay up I just it would be like you know
take a shower do that go to bed wake up
now sometimes in the beginning I woke up
you know when you eat too much weed
that that hangover feeling I kind of had
that a couple times but nothing major I
don't really know what to say about my
personal
you know like I feel great in life in
general but I gave some to this um
one of my uh neighbor landlord uh his
friend who had just gotten stage one
rectal cancer and he's down to try it so
I gave some to him and he got his blood
test back and it didn't get any worse
but I think any better
so I think the next round that we make
for him there'll be a
more THC instead of a rounded Out full
spectrum you know
so so that's that's promising and I
think those will get you high like I've
heard stories about people uh you know
doing high high THC suppositories and
getting a buzz so we'll find out yeah it
makes sense I'll keep you posted cool
cool cool well look I would love to hear
from you know the horse's mouth what do
you think is the future of CBD lines
like as you mentioned in a prior answer
you can get it really quite cheap so
there may not even be much of an
argument to grow it yourself anymore
pillows and uh firewood
so you you think it's just going to
become so ubiquitously available that
like no one will really grow it anymore
and you just buy it if you need it I
mean I assume people still grow it like
but it's like big farms
um
I mean I saw they were getting down to
like uh
like two bucks a pound
and if you were buying like you know a
considerable amount
I mean if you're really pushing it out
I think you know
I mean I don't think people are gonna
stop growing it especially like as new
state you know now that okay so
this year is the first year that I have
been like federally legal to grow hemp
thanks to oddly enough Mitch McConnell
I'm not trying to give that dude a shout
out
and and even even a trump like not my
favorite people but they actually signed
the the farm bill that included the the
hemp thing and so I had to like go
through extra Hoops like register with
the USDA and go get fingerprinted for a
federal background check and all kinds
of stuff
so I assume there's like you know hemp
farms in every state now yeah
I just think we scale back from a few
years ago a few years ago it was like a
Monumental huge amount of people growing
like there was
acreage you know like
and now I think it's scaled back
considerably because of the you know a
lot of people don't want to grow
something they can't sell yeah certainly
certainly so I mean in terms of some of
the CBD lines you offer do you think
that like a reason someone might grab
one of those is because like they might
be able to find something that really
specifically works for their medical
issues or do you think that in general
like just getting any old CBD is
probably going to be about right if
you're talking about
any old CBD strain and I don't think no
I think they're all different you know
what I mean like uh
you know a lot of the stuff outside
you know there's different Terps like uh
and I think that comes along with a lot
of the same genetic makeup you get a lot
of nursing a lot of
berries cherries you know but now things
are starting to now we're getting lemon
limes and all that stuff and with those
come different effects you know what I
mean like uh
in a medicinal way like the way your
brain wants
you know like some people love smoking
this strain because it makes them feel
terrific and then some people they're
just not getting it and they like that
you know what I mean
because that's their body telling them
what medicine they like does that make
sense
yeah yeah certainly certainly so I
noticed on your Instagram page that you
mentioned cbdv and I have to admit I
really don't hear a lot about this at
all can you give us a little bit of info
about like what it might be used for and
do you plan to do anything with it in
the future
so I have a plant I call it four-way not
to be confused with the four-way THC
plant
um it's a pain in the ass
but it sits at one quarter THC one
quarter thcv one quarter CBD and one
quarter cbdv
and I the only option to do anything
with this is uh I'm gonna try and
feminize it on itself I think that would
be
yeah the best way to express you know
because I tried to put it on some THC
and it basically erased
like uh you know the majority of
everything in there and the THC
dominated it out so it's kind of Highly
unstable I'm not even sure what C uh
what cbdv would
I know the variant is like uh you know
and THC is like a appetite suppressant
and like a more Speedy or you know alert
high
I don't know what cbdb does we're uh
venturing out into the unknown I love it
it it's cool to see like uh I met this
guy was it a seed swap uh Duke and I
were up to his seed Swap and this dude
came up and he had like jars of uh
extract beautiful stuff smelled great
they didn't really get into it then I
ran into him on 420 and we were talking
and he went and learned like oil
extraction like how they do petroleum
and then they applied that to cannabis
and now they're going through
uh like fractionally and taking you know
cataloging every single substance that
comes over
and then he was like um
this one would get stuck in the top of
the distillate you know in the
or they call that the head you know
where it's hard as a rock so they took
that
and they call it uh cbdt as in trash
and he said it would harden up like a
Lego so they started selling it to the
road crews up there to mix with gravel
and fill in potholes
reflects my brain I was like so
impressed like with you know like the
sauce you're filling in potholes with
pot oh my God you know he found a peanut
butter strain
that like when he cracked the his
brother cracked the seeds it smelled
like peanut butter in the air like and
he he I was like come on man and he's
like no I'm serious I'm like really
so he's working on like if he can make
seeds you know take the hearts out or do
whatever it takes to emulsify that into
like a peanut butter for people who
can't eat peanut butter
and I'm just like
cannabis winning like new [ __ ] [ __ ] yeah
my friend Erica her dad Tom is redoing a
house and purchased Stateside grown
insulation to do his house that has
rated better with the R value than the
pink stock
so it's I'm I'm excited I like you know
I've been I've been about this plant for
a long time it's nice to see it's
starting to finally get recognized for
Stuff
you mentioned earlier the Cherry candy
heart and before we dive into all of
that stuff I just wanted to ask one of
the comments I've heard a lot about CBD
in general is that a lot of the
varieties all have this common
denominated cherry smell do you think
that all comes from that cherry candy
how you referenced
well I can't say Arlo because panatonic
uh you know have you ever heard of Ringo
he he's passed he's like so he brought
out that uh a lot of good CBD too and it
wasn't so his his uh he did the
canatonic so that was where the Cherry
came from and I'm not really sure where
he had sourced his original CBD gear
from
so Ringo he he did the sour tsunami
right
I think so yeah
I I wanted to ask you because I I can
see you've worked with probably the
majority of the lines I'm about to
mention but if you look at sort of the
common CBD strains you see around you've
got as you mentioned the cannatonic
South tsunami Harlequin AC DC the Woo
which of them do you like the most or do
you think that they're all sort of a bit
different and offer different things
while I'm proud of the woo and
everything
that has horrible Terps and it's just uh
yeah it kind of has like a metallic
terpy kind of thing going on AC DC is an
awesome plant man I'm like uh
cantonics hours the sour tsunami was
kind of floppy you know like had more of
a like a a weak sativa kind of thing but
like the AC DC is a solid solid awesome
CBD plant like it grew fat It Made
Beautiful
like washes Bud that smelled of cherries
it's so weird like almost like a fruit
bowl like not even cherries like pear
and Cherry and like uh
peaches and like oh they're like that
all those fruits sit inside those kind
of those strains
and then berries like uh
they went and they did that cherry wine
and then through that they found some
Berry flavor and now that people are
like I said working to get more
of a flavor
uh
you know like like I said the boutique
stuff where they mix it with like wheat
and then bring it back to him
but uh in that original batch I gotta
say that AC DC was uh
that was a just a great pleasure to grow
you know I mean like some stuff's a
little more tricky
but
so that was my favorite but they all
kind of were like except for the woo uh
they all kind of were that same vibe
well once I did the Cherry things they
like that helped bring that out too I
assume like the because the Cherry back
on like all the other ones that were
similar cherry
were it's crazy though it was like
legitimate like cops are up tasting
brilliant yeah really intense cherry
flavor by the sounds of it just to loop
back on that cherry candaha do you think
that it is the case that a decent amount
of um afghanis probably has some CBD in
them or do you think that the one you
used was really like a diamond in the
rough
um you know what I don't
I don't think the Kandahar had any CBD
in it we were trying to use it for
structure because the original Cherry
was like a floppy thin plant that grew
you know it just wasn't
you know like a good Afghan is super
thick and hearty
you know what I mean so we were trying
to impart that kind of shape and
structure
into the the CBD plant because it wasn't
the Cherry would not have survived like
in a field or you know
it just was a floppy like it would have
been destroyed by wind the whole deal so
to put the Afghan on it was strictly for
structure
what at the same time if you follow on
Instagram all those like uh the land
race guys and um
all those guys over there
like they go into Afghanistan they're
like doing all the
The
Strain reconnaissance kind of thing you
know what I mean like the collectors
Izzy and those guys uh
like they they're finding uh like
one-to-ones and stuff in some of the
gear that they find in different regions
you know
in afghanis so I mean it's there
I don't remember what the strain was but
it was like you were saying it was only
like at nine to ten
yeah okay that's really interesting and
I guess maybe sort of one of the final
questions to round out some of the CBD
topics we've covered is are there any
particular CBD ratios that you're fond
of for certain conditions or do you
think it's all just a matter of personal
body chemistry first off I don't I try
to get medical advice or and I'm not a
doctor but
if I'm trying to treat somebody as
cancer I would wreck well I would give
them a one-to-one
you know what I mean I don't recommend
that I can't make medical
recommendations but I think like you
know
I think ratios are important and then I
think that like once say like a kid with
epilepsy gets used to one ratio
like that a different one helps I've
seen that happen you know what I mean
but basically like I like to give I
think CBD is an important to like take I
feed it to my dogs I felt like [ __ ] when
I woke up this morning and uh like my
back hurt and I went and ate some and I
felt like a champion
um that's just my personal you know
uh
but I mean yes I think certain people
find better relief from different ratios
definitely you know I don't think just
CBD helps out anybody like the isolate
stuff I think that's garbage I think I
think even like taking a THC out like
when I make these bottles I try and
uh get my THC up as high as I can well
I'll still be legal you know uh at point
three percent
I think that's important I think you
need that whole Entourage you need all
your all your cannabinoids
like together to help you know we don't
really know a ton ton about that like
about the endocannabinoid system yet we
got it all you know we don't know how
certain things are it's hard you know
different thing to be studying like
so
well yeah I I honestly without trying to
give I'm not like a I'm not a doctor I'm
just a guy who grows plants uh
uh I do think that it that ratios are
important and like like anything else
man whatever
like your body will let you know if
you're doing good
right like it'll tell you if that's what
it wants like oh man I really and I
smoked that
OG cushers up it and it really like
calmed my ass down and made my back stop
hurting or that AC DC really like you
know increased my appetite or you know
stuff like that or like that [ __ ] Stone
me out so much man I couldn't feel my
body that was great you know all those
things come from different definitely
different ratios and you know different
amounts of cannabinoids Within
that you know it's I mean
I mean we're still discovering new stuff
but like there's so many out there that
could be in the makeup of stuff that
it's just amazing so
I guess yeah I'm yeah I'm uh I'm
dwindling here um I just don't want to
be trying to make uh medical claims on
the stuff you know like I'm trying to
help people if it works but like I don't
guarantee any of this because it's not
legal here either they don't like you
doing that yeah so true pardon my
aversion to
I think everybody needs cannabis and you
know what works for you
uh is definitely not what's going to
work for the next guy
yeah certainly I can I can appreciate
the sentiment there
um just one of the listener submitted
questions that would slow in perfectly
right here is someone said out of the
strains you've made what would you
recommend as the terpiest one to one you
offer oh man uh I've only done one one
to one like in all honesty that was but
um
I'm going to do one with my lemon G
which
um
I don't know I I took it to Amsterdam
and uh
in 2011 and we got second
uh it's one of the most Derpy lemony
things ever so here in a minute I'm
gonna do my one-to-ones that I have back
on that and that should yield something
good but technically the I don't even
know if you can find them now because it
was so long ago that I did that uh our
initial CBD breeding you know like most
of the strains have sold out and I mean
I still have a bit of seed but they're
probably getting aged you know so I
guess the answer to that question would
be uh wait and see because there's new
ones coming I suppose
brilliant something to look forward to
and and uh just as sort of the same
question but on the other end of the
spectrum we had a listener asked
um if I wanted to give something to a
child that was going to hopefully be
non-psychoactive but still high in CBD
is there anything in particular you'd
recommend
well again
um
if you don't want to like you'd have to
get an isolate
um
like if you don't want to get like
there's going to be
like do you mean by CBD like extract or
like CBD strain
uh just a strain I guess so they can
sort of do what they need to with it I
would probably want to find something
real low uh
you know if I was you know you don't
want to be uh I can't Advocate getting
children high as much as I'd like to
and calm their little asses down
um but you know uh most of the stuff
that was given to children when we
started doing that was real
like low because you couldn't like I
said you didn't want to be heat uh you
know last thing you want is a stone kid
with epilepsy I don't think that's a
good thing so nowadays you can go get
CBD oil I mean I you know I make it and
then other people make it I mean so like
I said you don't like to grow it and
then to extract it and then uh it's just
easier to find like a good source of
like I personally Source all my stuff
organically including my carrier oil and
the flavors
um
but like yeah I would want something
that would
be the hemp there you go if you want to
feed your kids some CBD make sure it's
made from hemp that's a that's a
reasonable sort of sentiment and full
spectrum though I think is important in
my opinion yeah
in anybody eating it you know what I
mean isolates and stuff or they have a
ceiling where you know they work to an
extent and then it stops working and
then when you add in all those other
cannabinoids you get the Entourage which
helps carry it past that point
yeah definitely definitely some uh some
sensors I can get behind with the full
spectrum stuff for sure so let's
actually take it back now to the
question we normally start off the
interview with what have you been
smoking on recently
man uh JJ
uh take me a pack of this
dirty uh Taxi
and then
Duke here again like I
there was I came home from uh uh read
show and I had like ten thousand dollars
worth of seeds from every breeder like
you know I traded them all CBD stuff and
they all and um I started every
basically almost all of them and I I
ended up with two plants that kicked
asses dirty taxi and uh one of Tommy's
they're uh Duke skunk band
V2s I do believe
so um I've been smoking on that Taxi and
I took and I I I crossed it with some
stuff
uh that was the last seed run that I did
uh
it's it's dank and so
yeah I just it it fit it fits for what I
like you know it's like a daytime a good
day timer
and I just now we're about to be
we'll have all those seeds flowers
coming up here by the end of summer
seeing you know for some Fino selection
but yeah basically the dirty taxi it's
uh the GMO times that chem dog
I-95 which has a couple OG's in there I
do believe
what a brilliant answer because I wanted
to ask you I was looking specifically at
some of the crosses you'd done and the
uh the
slv-o-g is a cool one and I wanted to
ask do you in general prefer the sfv OG
over the triangle and that's why I did
it that way or is it just because the
dirty taxi already had a bit of TK in it
you were like you know I'll switch it up
a bit
actually the reason that I needed that
and I worked so I live in a valley
it's dirty
and you know the next the next round
will have the triangle in it because
it's actually shaped like a triangle so
I wanted to make like something that
would uh work down here but
you know I like to I love that sfe it
it smells like weird like some cologne I
wore is like a 21 year old trying to
pick up chicks and like tennis balls and
uh
yeah it just it smokes and I I wanted to
keep it I wanted to pull a little more
OG out of that taxi because it's in
there you know and um
I find OG's like you know I want to grow
them
I would run a bunch of them if I could
but they're always they're going to
yield the greatest and they're kind of a
finicky so you know maybe find something
that's going to be a little more uh
conducive to
just being a nice plant to grow
but the version two is going to have the
uh the triangle up on there and then
I'll work it back into like a solid
you know not you know start effing it
back a little
yeah beautiful
I did want to ask you because we we
spoke about the um the the dirty taxi
hybrids you did and I wanted to ask did
you find a male in that same pack that
you got the female or did you find the
female and impressed you so much you
were like I got to get some more go back
and find a male
um smoking the taxi now the last joint I
got
uh I've been saving it and there's a
good re you know uh you know what the
mail out of there
uh I we had just my my buddy and I given
it to him and he was like dude you gave
me a mail and then he's like but I used
it to make uh and we cross on something
and it brought forth it really was you
know a good representation of what the
thing and you know what JJ
uh is one of my favorite breeders the
guy
like really hits what I like to smoke
and he's he's honest and he's good so I
asked him like basically manless
everybody I've seen that started one
pack has gotten a winner in One
Direction or the other
you know I I got two that I really liked
the female that I kept was more
conducive
like uh growth wise and I like the herb
on the it's got a little more GMO in
there uh
and it bangs out like the weight so I
kept that one as my female and then the
the other one the the males kind of got
a
like a pissier smell to him like uh but
he he came correct with the the the
dirty jeans you know what I mean
everybody that has started them is you
know I'm seeing all the nice uh
I guess a phenotypical expression you
know that I would expect and then I
wanna I made some dirty dirties but you
know that's not my gear but I want to
see if I can even work it back a little
bit just so I can have one that is very
represent representing the one that I
like a lot
you know like it's a little stretchier
with nice big and that's what I'm seeing
uh in in
like it's pretty dominant in a lot of
stuff when it see what it seems but
uh I did find I found a great plant in
two three great plants in one pack of I
think what 12.
hell yeah that's beautiful and another
strand from that line the trash eclair
it looked great because it sort of
seemed like it's aimed for the general
grower you know like it's THC dominant
there's some pretty recognizable names
in terms of the parents got like the
forearm cut in there you've also got
another cross you know the super silver
haze with the the diaper I guess I
wanted to ask what stimulated you to
move to these more THC dominant crosses
compared to the prior work you've done
well I mean so the last project that I
did before the dirty taxi was a ton of
like hand collected land races from like
uh
wow we had
some like Siri and stuff we had some
African we had like a like uh
a lot of hash producing so man I'm
trying to remember this a while ago the
last car guy which is like actually one
of my favorite
plants it's like a pre-bubba Bubba
and it's got um
like heavy coffee and like tobacco and
leather and stuff like that and then
like I knew that uh Duke and I were
gonna start working together
and I wanted to put something together
where you know I want to work the I want
to work more dirty stuff out
so I took what I you know I had and I
thought I would work with it because I I
have some stuff like that I didn't think
would pair well but uh
just and and as time goes on you'll see
a lot of those show up and a lot of
stuff that I'm like I said we're looking
for that sour lemon male it's gonna be
you know and like so some of these
and like I'm gonna work back that
slv-o-g
and I just think it's
I don't know I like that not only do I
like to really like the flower it's
beautiful and just nasty but this the I
like a big plant you know like I like a
big
like the the G13 cross should
that's a small plant you know like that
it'll be
just amazing to have a lot bigger
heavier yielding of some of you know
like and it's gross
so I was like you know what I want to
breed this together I think you know and
I had all this stuff that I really like
so I it actually was more of a
like I knew we were going to move into
more THC lines but I really
like was like like I found this plant
and it was so awesome that I basically
just
like uh I don't smoke anything else if I
don't have to like uh I I it's just you
know when you find and so I wanted to
make sure
you know put it on my favorite stuff and
then I thought you know that's kind of
why I did that
and then a lot of those are like I said
will be used in further down the line
that's brilliant and I love that you
mentioned that like you know having that
bigger yield was important because
something that has been talked about for
a while admittedly but is coming up more
and more when I talk to different guests
is that a lot of people have this
growing feeling that we're sort of
backing ourselves up against the wall
with forever decreasing yields sort of
seems like as the years go by things are
just getting smaller and smaller
yielding
what's your thoughts on this do you is
it something you're consciously trying
to battle
yeah it's like that man like the most of
it like it's always like damn if only
that one was a little bigger and it
seems you know as uh
so then you take those small plants and
they breed those small plants and you
get progressively smaller plants you
know like the biggest yielders are never
the most amazing like you know you're
not they're not the Super fro you know
and what you know it seems that the the
most bangers are just that's like the
cruel joke from
uh you know from the plant itself like
yeah man wouldn't you love a giant like
super yielding but yet like Banger and I
think that's that you know I did find
that I found that in the taxi and I
found that in uh that skunk band beat
too like uh I pulled down all these if I
had some outdoor plants that I had
pollinated just for fun and uh we were
breaking it up and like you know uh
like doing
like and there was like a bunch of hash
like I had her breaking them up with
gloves and the hatches falling through
the trim tray and uh we did like three
plants before that and ended up with
like I don't know let's call it like an
ounce of Keith she got on that plant and
it yielded like three
like one plant yield as much as the
other three plants times three on that
skunk band
and it was it was like the I don't know
and we called it the what the [ __ ] me
and my buddy because like I he kept
breaking he would break it up I gave him
uh uh some and he would
he would be breaking it up and I would
catch it out of nowhere and I'd be like
what the hell so
like I I think I found two very good
you know representations of something
that that's gonna yield a bit and have
like
uh quite a you know especially that
skunk band I think I got some seeds I
made of it around here I think I made
some dirty ones
uh
hopefully they will uh
you know that if you could find a middle
of the road down that it's going to be
great
that's some interesting news I I guess I
would love to sort of like follow that
logic through and then say would then
you sort of agree that by that logic we
would say that like cookies is better
than TK or chemdog because it yields
less and like as things get better they
yield less
nah man I wouldn't do that uh
as much as uh it's kind of custied out a
little bit it's a really easy plant to
grow you know what I mean like it yields
well this it smokes really well and it
grows phenomenally like easy like
whereas other things are a little more
finicky and
I just think uh
I mean I get good yields I grew uh some
of that form about a while ago I like
that I enjoyed smoking it and it it
wasn't like a depressing yield or you
know
yeah
definitely I feel like cookies does get
quite a bad rap and I think it was CSI
who said that um you know if I'd never
seen cookies on Instagram or heard about
it and you just gave me a bud to try I'd
probably tell you that's some of the
best weight I've ever had what's your
thoughts on that
I enjoy smoking it I don't think cookies
is like the best at anything uh
it's you know there obviously there is a
reason that um
it's been you know recently seems to be
the bottom [ __ ] in everything you know
like it and that's cool like it went
that way but like uh
I'm looking forward to smoking this
Durban tie
you know what I mean I'm looking forward
to smoking the skunk I'm looking forward
to like that's all good I don't I like
my herb dank and funky as opposed to
like
sweet and
I don't know it's weird now or there's
new strains out that I don't think they
really have much Terps going on they're
just you know people name them weird
cookie [ __ ] you know the trash eclair
that was because there was already you
know the GMO is cookies in a way so I
figured you know reinforce that it's
kind of like some
what would you call that outcross BX is
there a name for that what do you think
like so it's cookies in there it's still
back in there like but it's a few out
you could say it's it's like an increase
of sorts so but that was uh I named that
uh you ever watched Seinfeld yeah yeah
George
I named that trash eclair that's where
George was like ew that woman caught him
eating that yeah that's yeah good stuff
uh but I mean I thought that that would
be a good
like I like the structure of the cookies
and you know it it is good I don't think
it's the best weed I've ever smoked
though
yeah Fair call so
um I would be interested to hear I was
cruising on your Instagram and I saw you
put up a photo of a plant you were
calling uh Jim Leahy how did the park
supervisor cross turn out it sounds fun
with that puck bx1 in there yeah there's
a lot of puck in there it was dirty sour
Puck Puck and that came from uh Root
Cellar the sour Puck Puck that dude does
not get enough credit he's a terrific
breeder uh
but that's the one that we crossed the
dirty with that first time and uh
and and John had just passed away uh
recently you know when I made that the
Jim Leahy
I mean as a very uh
I was a very dedicated Trailer Park Boys
fan for many many years uh you know it
just kind of fit plus there's a bunch of
puck in there what are their pucks doing
that's hockey all day so
gotta have some kind of Canadian
reference right
oh dude I'm such a massive fan of
trailer park boys and I cannot for the
life of me get my lady to watch it with
me she won't have a bar but
my ex girl girlfriend might be the one
that got away her name is Corey she got
a dog and named him Trevor
like she might be the one that escaped
you know what I mean like ah
that's pretty cool that's awesome that's
awesome
um you mentioned a little earlier that
one of your projects not long ago was
that you were working with some land
races and I did notice on your Instagram
you'd posted the the Durban the swazi
and the Moroccan like the little labels
what would they like to work with and do
you think that sort of the Nostalgia
people have around land races is like
worth the hype or like it is a bit of
nostalgia
okay that's an awesome question actually
um
in all honesty like uh Duke and I agree
on this heavily like there's something
to be said about going back you know
like I I got this beautiful lash car uh
pck Outback we're gonna do some work
with that
so the Durban let's start there
um you know a lot of Durban that you get
here like the one that is in the cookies
uh that oddly enough that extract guy
that fills the potholes with the pot he
gave the Durban to Berner
uh now that's an old like that comes
from the uh Holland and that's crossed
with an unknown indica
so that's not why you get those big
dumpy Derby buds over here whereas the
seeds that I started my buddy uh
how from Israel he went and I guess he
was on uh
I guess he was on vacation but he went
all everywhere that those seats that are
from he was there like collecting seeds
and so Durbin in the wild is a much more
yeah scraggly uh but I mean the Terps
were there so
it was I mean
it was
a lot of those that you you know it's
hard to work with a lot of stuff like
that because it doesn't you know you
want to see
like amazing flower but it does have
that like Crow magnet kind of
you know uh older school but when you
smoke it it's phenomenal
the Moroccan man that was oh that was
great it was like legitimate hash like
you like it was just a big old well not
even a big old like a just a hash plant
it was beautiful and it smoked well and
this you know the
working with those was great
um
because we seeded them it I it was uh I
smoked a lot of you know the it was
awesome man actually uh but I don't
recommend unless you want to do
something like that like there's there's
good afghanis that are are wonderful you
know uh that those guys they actually
sell but like if you know
it's not commercially viable to start
like these Thai seeds that I have
because you know they have a propensity
for hermaphroditism and all that and
then they don't produce these buds but
if you're into like really weird
right good Buzz is like a lot of African
stuff you know what I mean you get that
thcv because it's on the equator
and I mean I do think that like I bet
now that you get to see those guys in in
Afghanistan and in uh all those little
places where they're collecting those
seeds and they're showing like the you
know the the selections that the farmers
have selected
in that region you know they're doing
their own breeding technically you know
as they grow like the the more the
farmers in Afghanistan that are you know
have been growing for Generations like
they're doing their own selections you
know they're not
does that make sense
yeah
I think it's it's great I think that
there's a lot of great things that you
could like
I don't think inbreeding all like the
your cookie strains is a great
you know way to get anything but you
know you're not going to get a lot of
diversity out of that
yeah had the combos in the fridge
um
yeah I mean I love land-based work uh
my lime tar that I just bred with that
dirty is like the limest thing ever it
smells like
fresh like fresh limes like just
squeezed and then
like a weird
Turkish Bazaar over the top with like
flowers and like
goofy stuff and then on the other Fino
it's got like chocolate and mint and
like
so and that all came from Land rate
stuff you know what I mean like uh
so I I gotta say like I think that it's
gonna be you know I think that we're
gonna find a lot more awesome derps and
stuff like that in that then we're going
to like in uh
you know whatever the next cookie strain
is
I think he was releasing a fish scale or
some along those lines which is not
something you should name cannabis
yeah right there's been a lot of uh
discussion around that one and I think
it might even be a rename strain but
we'll uh we'll hear more about that
later but I wanted to follow up because
those land races you just spoke about
you cross them to the lgk which I
believe is an Afghani can you tell us a
bit about that and was it a CBD Rich one
no pcq oh it was pck so pck is the
Pakistani citroli Kush that I got from
boating he at the emerald cup he was
just like
like some kind of little
like I don't know that he just kicked me
like uh 50 or 100 and we went through
them and picked out like that stuff just
turns real purple and that's where that
perfumey
top end of the chirps comes like that
turkishy weird
because that you know it smells like
incense and uh
what is the blood structure on that is
just uh not awesome you know what I mean
it was Fluffy but it brought like this
whole bunch of amazing
chirps that you just don't really get
so
and then
like that we were trying to breed stuff
that because I I'm up at 8080 feet
which is about where all those High
regions and mountains are you know
so we were trying to go you know
intentionally like the season here is
ridiculously short like uh I've been
I've grown outdoor and I got my hemp
side you know I grew up my CBG on that
side and that luckily that stuff
finishes up but like uh
trying to grow outdoor out here is such
a a pain like I grow these beautiful
plants all the way up and then
like right at the beginning of October
you get this
like horrible week a torrential hail and
like shitty wind and you know what I
mean so
unless you're covered in a greenhouse
you really not gonna be able to pull
anything off because it's all gonna get
messed up so we were trying to breed
you know for the
altitude and stuff like in the time so
the it's nice because all those
like a lot of those Afghans finish off
relatively shortly and are used to like
this kind of same altitude so
you know might as well mimic
like
you know the same kind of environment
right I mean it's that's we're kind of
like Afghanistan temperatures like cold
snow you know all that [ __ ]
so that was the thought process on using
that plus I wanted to keep it real
still land racy you know like I didn't
want to like it didn't need to be like
uh pck times cookies you know
yeah certainly that makes sense I uh
I've been LED down the wrong path by
seed finder on that that's interesting
pck and that makes sense because I saw
you had worked with that one of the
listener questions we got is are there
any other land races that you've got
your site set on working with in the
future and what uh land race in general
do you think is the most interesting
uh I got a pack so my buddy a good
friend of mine Went Down To Jamaica and
was hanging out down there for a couple
weeks
and he was trying to find seeds and then
on the last day this old head you know
what I mean like that really old head
that old dude with the dreadlocks that
just you know what I mean like rolls up
on him and it's like uh hey man I heard
you were looking for the Lamb's bread
and your hands in this bag and he's like
this is my family's genetics and it's
been worked for like three to four
generations
uh
uh so I have legitimate Jamaican lamb
bread and I don't know of anyone else
with that
um
you know so I'm gonna try and
make more obviously out of that start
them up we'll see how it is you know
what if it's just cookies
you never know he might have just
selected some you know
but hopefully hopefully it's legitimate
and then uh
you know I I like a good weird wild
sativa
but I don't like it to
you know I don't want to grow like 20
week cases
so I mean it's nice to see things like
Ty popping up now we're gonna work with
some of that I guess
Maybe
uh
yeah and like I am going to continue
we're going to work I think we're gonna
do some youth work the U is by pck lash
guard guy which like I said is the last
place they actually smoke flour in
Afghanistan maybe I didn't mention that
uh as opposed to making it a hash
you know
and that's the one that has that like
pre-bubba Bubba feel
and then the U is like the limey one and
then it's the chocolate one too so we're
gonna put some stuff into that and I
have a the Lash car just pck lash guard
that looks beautiful that will probably
work do some work with
um
yeah I'm super stoked about that
actually
I mean in a world of poly hybrid you
know
is like just some
basically not basic but like
not yeah like not bread to death
you know a little diversity you know
it's nice like different stuff like
yeah right
yeah it sounds nice man an injection of
some fresh blood is always welcome in my
opinion and you sort of touched on
um you know it ties and I think you
mentioned Haze in there and I've noticed
that in the past
maybe a year or so like more or less
since Neville's passing Hayes has sort
of become a bit more popular in the uh
the community dialogue and I wanted to
know what's your thoughts on this do you
ever want to work with some hazes and do
you do you see it taken off
well
um I love my super silver haze and we
have another Super Silver Haze here uh
I'm looking forward to doing some work
with those I really like that uh now as
far as giant hazes go like those big
um
Tony from Boneyard great guy uh he had
sent me some of his Haze on Hayes so
it's basically he like had these giant
vials of them so
and then a friend just uh went
over season grabbed all Neville's gear
and stuff so we have all those in the I
think we're calling it The Federation so
in the Federation I do believe that a
lot of Neville's work is going to start
popping back up
you know I like the you know Liz I
listened to
the piss episode or the done show I had
never smoked papaya you know what I mean
I had no idea it was just a nl5 pays
and uh they had these old school guys on
talking about growing it and
they were just like it was so easy you
just
started from flower the minute it roots
and then you know you save on like and I
was like damn that is
okay so yeah if you only have like a
week or two or a veg and you got like 16
or 18 weeks of flour
but it's on 12 and 12. you're going to
save all that money on your veg
and be able to you know
um
so I think that's pretty cool I've never
done anything like that I've never just
been like up if we started now in 20
weeks it'll be done and it'll fill up
the whole room I've never
really uh gotten down with anything like
that so it'd be fun
yeah
but it's it's like I have I have the
ceiling height for it that's nice
um it's a big commitment hold on where's
the
I'm cooking my dog's food as we speak
um
like and it's literally cooking like I I
turkey and elk and then I gotta chop up
this broccoli and then rice oh beautiful
these dogs spoiled
well so uh I moved to this little tiny
town right I didn't know what I was
gonna do man I moved this like the cops
came to my spot in Denver and we're like
uh you're only allowed six plants I'm
like but I'm a caregiver
and uh they're like sorry we passed a
city ordinance let's see your garden and
they went in and you're like holy [ __ ]
wow look at that this is nice man sorry
you're gonna have to cut it shut it down
so I was like well
so I had to move somewhere that was
respecting you know people that still
take care of people and uh
so I found this place and I didn't know
how you know I was going to acclimate
into a Spanish Town either like
everybody here is basically uh Spaniard
like not Mexican there's there's some
Mexican people in my town but basically
like these guys came up from Mexico and
they're they were Spanish and they
settled in mine you know
so that like my landlord looks like a
conquistador kind of
um and you know so it's like
so I started like giving out
CBD and everything you know because
there's a lot of old people I I we made
some dude
um some cancer meds you know and then uh
I'm at The Butcher and The Butcher his
hands hurt so I gave him CBD and His
Hands didn't hurt so he could continue
butchering and we made friends and uh
you know now uh in the fall when he
harvests you know when people bring him
the elk and the deer and all everything
he just gives me all the scraps
so I just you know uh a this is better
than dog food you know what I mean and B
it's cheaper technically to buy like
rice and broccoli and just uh you know
do it like this plus I like cooking
and it's really good for them you know
like uh my last dogs
because I do believe because they had a
good healthy diet and CBD they lived at
17. nice that's pretty good
and that's yeah that's I mean the new
guy here he's eating like lion's mane
and uh all kinds of stuff up front I got
like a mushroom blend because I'm trying
to
you know I want to see how I want to see
how long I can keep a dog alive
I don't like him dying early man it's
the worst part like losing an animal is
the worst uh so this way
you know they eat a they eat a good diet
it's awesome
I was just gonna say one of the one of
the common questions we get asked a lot
is a lot of people want to do it but
like they don't know where to start like
what would you recommend as like
starting Doses and ways to give it
um I make a pet friendly one and uh
what it is is uh just unflavored because
you know um I make I the other ones I
make have organic flavoring like mango
and all that I suppose I could put a dog
flavoring in but uh
I give them one squirt like actually I
worked them up
my dogs are 40 pounds and I give them
like what I would recommend a human is
like you know well
you know
to take like one milliliter
but basically you know everybody has
dogs in different sizes so you gotta
again I'm not trying well I'm not a
veterinarian either uh but
like I think it's great I think you know
everything alive
uh you know mammalian kind of thing like
dogs cats we all everything has this
cannabinoid system that has been
depleted because of uh the marijuana and
hemp and one cannabis being made illegal
you know
I'm sure you've seen that Meme that's
like back in the day the animals ate
hemp and then cannabinoids transferred
through the milk and you know what I
mean
and that's why we didn't
I I mean as
uh you know I don't know if that it
makes sense I'm gonna say
um
and then when we eliminated that you
know since the endocannabinoid is
directly responsible for
like your immune system kind of you know
like it's it's has a hefty Hefty weight
in that
uh now they're finding you know like uh
but it
it actually has a lot of immune
functions you know what I mean
and then you know so it's the same in
your dog and the same in your cat like
they they have CB1 receptors and CB2
receptors like I had a buddy who I went
home my mom had passed away so we did
her celebration of life and it was
awesome and I I got to see some friends
and one of my old friends came up and
he's like hey man I'm noticing that
Delta 8 is legal now I got a great idea
that no one saw it he's like dealt a dog
treats and he started asking me when I
thought the dosage would be to like get
your dog High
and uh
and like my dogs like not Bud he's new
but Dojo woke up stoned as [ __ ] this
morning uh I found this Northern Lights
Number Five
and in my I snuck into my flowering and
it was uh throwing bananas like it was a
Chiquita banana Factory so I cut it down
and I started feeding it to the dog
yesterday not the bud just the leaves
and she she'll eat she knows what's up
like when she doesn't feel good and the
other one did too but they don't feel
good they go eat the leaves I had to
train them not to eat the plant you know
um but I think it's
First a full spectrum I would think and
then uh you would have to feel
you know you have to build up a dog's
tolerance to CBD and you definitely
don't want to get it high because I
don't know if you ever dealt with a
like you ever had a
an animal eats your weed or like uh we
made we made brownies one time or
something back in the day and threw the
trim out back with the butter on and the
dogs ate that thought they were I
thought they were dying
and it just turned out they were like so
high
uh so you know be careful with anything
you give your animals you don't want to
uh
you know make them uncomfortable or
anything but I think it's I think
cannabis in all forms is good for
everything with uh
with the system you know
yeah definitely definitely
I saw it on your Instagram you've been
experimenting with micro dosing
mushrooms give me the lowdown
so I do a couple uh things for my mental
health uh
one of them is uh I do enjoy the micro
dosing of the mushrooms like uh I don't
like I haven't I actually quit drinking
man on New Year's and I'm gonna say uh
hey I really wanted to do it but like I
was drinking like uh six to eight beers
a day ipas that's like 200 calories of
beer do you know what I mean like I had
a beer belly I was like being a sloppy
uh
drunk and you know like um my mom wanted
me to quit drinking and I wanted me to
quit drinking and I felt you know with
this new
thing coming up you know like uh it
would be just better if I quit
so uh on New Year's Eve or the no the
night before I went up to
uh have you heard of the area 420 place
yeah it's like uh so we went with those
guys we rented Adam rented uh
uh the hot springs we went up there and
I had eaten one of these little tablets
with some psilocybin in it and then the
next night my uh
my buddy's kid who isn't a kid he's like
an adult but like you know uh came over
and it was shitty outside so we all
spent New Year's Eve together and I
that's the last time I drank I I we made
some mushroom tea and
I like had a real deep conversation with
him about why I wanted to quit drinking
and like reinforcing like in my mind
what I wanted and I woke up man I
haven't drank since I believe that
mushrooms magic and otherwise like have
serious and I I you know Paul stamens
has been doing a lot of research on this
like I take a lion's mane supplement
you know what I mean like uh it's an
extract they do like hot water extracts
on them and that's supposed to you know
has been shown uh to rebuild your neural
network in your brain that could have
been damaged by stress trauma drugs like
alcohol
uh
and it also is like a mild serotonin
booster so I was taking that and it's it
uh what's the word it uh potentially
it's the suicide
into your brain more you know yeah nice
supposedly it rebuilds your uh clusters
you know where your nerves all get
together tenfold what they were like at
their height of being the healthiest
like you're rebuilding your brain
so I've been on that kick
uh
and when I take when I micro dose the
mushrooms with the with the Lion's man I
have to be like really careful like my
buddy made uh he put an ace into like a
chocolate bar and each Square was
supposed to be like a quarter gram
and that was like almost tripping pretty
good like I have to break those into
quarters because the Lion's vein makes
it so much more potent
so
I haven't been doing that lately because
I I noticed like I get
somehow I assume it seems to affect me
pretty good and I get pretty high so I'm
it's not productive but like uh
something I'm really really about and
I'm willing to scream this from the top
of the mountain is uh
Academy for depression and anxiety like
I'm on the team like once every three
three months I'll I'll uh
fruit hear some and like uh have a I do
a thing where I uh
you know will Fast and then do it and
like do it
for like two or three days and then uh
come out of it it's like you know when
your router goes bad on your computer
and you got to reset it you gotta hold
the button in and then
powers back up
I swear to God that does it to my brain
like uh ketamine hits over 150 different
receptors in your brain it's been shown
like once it wears off it I don't know
the chemical but it creates a chemical
in your brain that subsides like
depression and anxiety for like a month
or two you know like
it literally in Parts like it's fun to
do because I enjoy it and then also
um when it's all over man I feel rinsed
out like I can as somebody who suffers
from those things uh like The Logical
thought that it imparts you know makes
both depression and anxiety like
illogical you know what I mean like
because it's you know what you can't fix
the past and you can't worry about the
future
and uh I have to say that's like my
like I don't know if I would be in uh
such a good mental
state that I've been in lately if it
wasn't for you know
the four times a year that I do that to
myself
like that's just like if anybody that's
listening to this like has has
depression and anxiety like that they
can't kick the [ __ ] out of that's bad
like and they have access to a clinic or
even like whatever but make sure you get
some safe [ __ ] like I highly recommend
it it saved like it saved my life a few
times and I I can actually say like some
of my most
um
uh
uh amazing moments in my life and a
couple dumbass moves uh have been uh you
know because of it but uh I seriously
like if you if you have portable
depression that you don't think is is
unbeatable man like go find one of those
clinics man they will
like there's a place out of Durango Now
by this guy named Dr Mark
uh he
he they like send you ketamine lozenges
and then they call you and you get to
have like your therapy sessions you know
after after you ate this
um
I had some [ __ ] happen to me a while ago
and I went and got a shrink this is a
couple years ago and uh
I preached to him the benefits of
ketamine so much that he went and
started recommending it to his patients
that were suffering and he said that
they were seeing like significant and
wonderful results uh
so like that's you know that's my
regimen I don't either I I micro those
mushrooms maybe like one week a month or
something but it's that it's a uh once
every three months that really makes my
brain feel like healthy and like I feel
like a real human when I get when it's
over you know oddly you know
that's beautiful man so glad to hear you
to you know finding it so helpful man
likewise encourage anyone to check it
out especially in Australia they just
rolled it out I believe it's a nasal
spray you can get it so talk to someone
if you're feeling depressed guys
oh it's beautiful it's it's what it's a
wonderful like uh maybe you know so it's
the
it's a disassociative tranquilizer slash
psychedelic I mean they were using it to
like get they were giving the kids back
in the day to like subdue them and then
some adult did it it was like holy [ __ ]
man and we should be giving that to kids
that's trippy as [ __ ] uh
it's really like it's all over the place
man you're seeing actually you're seeing
a wonderful amount of psychedelics
become more mainstream in the uses of uh
you know PTSD like Maps just they're
pushing that MDMA for uh like soldiers
and people with PTSD and that's getting
approved like uh the FDA gave them the
approval like go ahead like they
procured the amount of money they needed
to have the the chemicals synthesized
and like uh the most what do you want to
call that uh
you know it's got to be made according
to like pharmaceutical specifications
for them so they had to like get that
okayed by the FDA to get the lab that
you know what I mean
but that's going to be like a big and
then uh
if you haven't watched have you seen
Paul stammit's movie uh fantastic fun
guy yeah yeah I love post talents oh
it's beautiful like uh
like that whole
uh end of life where all those old
people are like coming to terms and
dying and cancer and like that's great I
can't imagine like you know you're gonna
die and you're worried about it and then
you eat some mushrooms and now you're
like you know what
okay cool whatever let's do this you
know
that's a gotta be like a relief
right
yeah yeah hugely hugely some interesting
work being done in that area for sure I
think definitely a long way to go with
um you know end of Life Care palliative
care those things we could do better
yeah I mean um
it's got to be scary like you know you
know you're
I don't know yeah that's uh that's
something that I've been pondering a lot
since I I lost my mom like really like
I've been taking I didn't started a
master class course on philosophy just
and it really was like super interesting
because it uh you know philosophy is
like studying what it is to be human and
it was like uh
I don't know it really hit me in a good
way so I've been thinking about like a
lot of stuff like that lately like you
know like what's your purpose here like
what like you know do we when we die
like what's going on there like
I don't know these are things I
I have a lot of internal dialogue I
guess
which is why I loved Academy and it
shuts that down
yeah definitely hey look I mean we're
sort of on the topic not to be morbid
but I had a few people submit questions
saying I heard two lives in a morgue or
used to live in a morgue what's what's
the deal with that no no yeah I live in
an old funeral home actually I'm
standing uh I'm looking at the human
skull and the nervous system and the
scalp system all laid out I'm in the old
embalming room so this is what this is
[ __ ] crazy so uh
I was working with these ladies uh the
lady like owns the lab good friend of
mine like my mom kind of uh and they you
know I was looking the cops had come and
they're like well we'll give you 90 days
so they let me shut it down and set
everything in the flower and harvest and
then
basically like a credit you know so I
was looking everywhere
to move you know that that was like cool
with uh the medical system and [ __ ] and
uh went up north in in Colorado to no
avail like in Greeley did you know the
ground has oil in it so
no you know like it's like a not organic
you know so and they were down here so
they were like hey just come down and
check this place out so I come down here
and it's out in the middle of [ __ ]
nowhere I don't know how I'm gonna you
know I shop at the Whole Foods you know
like every guys I'm used to having
things within my fingertip reach how am
I gonna you know and it was kind of like
But as time went on
like this actually became like the best
option ever so I come down to check it
out
and uh
in the kitchen
it's like literally the posters like the
musk I still have them up the muscular
system human skull uh and then in the
drawer like there's like you know in the
movies when you get kidnapped by the bad
guy like the German guy comes out and
like the the rubber trench coat and he's
like you're going to talk and unrolls
that big roll of like evil looking metal
things that he's gonna hurt you with you
know what I'm talking about yeah that
was in the drawer oh yeah that that
whole kit like holy [ __ ] that I was like
oh man then over here there was like a
sink that they would hook up to
basically like it's a it's a one-way
system they go in through your artery
and out through another one at the end
and then they pump you full of chemicals
and like uh pump all your you know your
liquids and stuff out so I had to move
that I removed that sink
that was kind of gross
um and then the one of the selling
points that he said was like oh there's
a floor drain which is
you know so they were this was the
corners station too for 10 years so
everybody in the county came through
like this place is you know no one ever
died here but then it's weird to have
local people come over like say to buy
CBD or whatever and like they're like
man I haven't been here since you buried
my grandma and it's like that wasn't me
yeah like uh but it's a big empty space
and it's really nice and it works and uh
like uh the every like no one I'm not
doing anything out of the ordinary down
here like the what I had a roommate uh
when I first moved here and he ended up
uh robbing me with this woman who I was
uh
being romantic with we'll say and uh I
had to have the cops come through they
know like the whole layout they know
what they've seen the whole shebang you
know like the one cop watched me take
clones
and uh
like I need to save these they're gonna
you know so like I'm
you know what I mean it's not like a
I'm it's cool I feel very comfortable
here
that's awesome you know what I mean
yeah yeah did they give you any cool
stories when they left to make sure
you're well and truly scared or you're
feeling pretty comfortable there
oh man I'm super comfy here I feel you
know like uh
no no like I went down to the sheriff
department and I was like Yo dude you
know me I'm that guy that just had these
problems and I do my medical thing and
this is what I do and
you know like uh what I don't want you
guys coming to [ __ ] with me so what do
you want me to do and they're like don't
go over your amount so
that is I follow that and then I I'm
like on the other side of the building
I'm licensed up by the USDA
with the hemp thing so like
you know what where I live has a weird
uh Mis balance of like people to
horrible drugs you know so like this
area has like a mess a Coke a crack a a
pill a heroin you know what I mean like
all that kind of problem alcoholic
hey so like I don't think
you know what I mean they have much more
important like stuff to do than
you know what I mean there's lots of
people around me uh grow and they are
not they don't even I don't even think
they have cards or I don't know it's a
weird place but
yeah so it's in a funeral home
no one ever died here though just my
dogs they were the first ones oh that's
not good
it's okay though the the so the landlord
said while he was building the place
uh well while the landlord was building
the place he said his brother-in-law or
something came in and was like hurry up
I'm gonna be the first guy you serve up
and then he was
right oh no no no no and then the second
guy came in and he was like Yo dude I'm
gonna be the next guy and that dude was
like uh they were calling it you know
what I mean like
it's a weird situation uh I know I've
never seen anything weird here like uh
Spirits or ghosts I don't that's not
something I believe in but uh
you know if I saw anything like that I
might change my mind I suppose
but you know how long has Ghost Hunters
been on and they've never found [ __ ] so
well look while we're on the subject of
kooky and interesting I've been told by
multiple people that yo the uh the
Nicholas Tesla of cannabis tell me a
little bit about this teslaponics
experiment you've done
actually I'd rather fire that one back
up uh
I had
like a keyhole I think they're called
rack you like lock the little things in
and then you know and I had it tubbed
out with uh what do you call it uh Pine
liner and it was off the ground and I
had a I had a what do you call that
thing yeah
heating mat in there
and it says don't immerse in water
and I had watered through all the plants
and you know there's a fin like it was
just ever so
micro amounts of water in there but it
was all submersed and then uh I was the
next day I came in like holy [ __ ] man
these are like the nicest plans I've
ever [ __ ] seen I'm talking foot and a
half
fat ass [ __ ] Sims like thick leathery
[ __ ] leaves like not us nothing out
of place no you know nothing out of
place and I went to rub my arm over them
and they [ __ ] shocked me
I was like what the [ __ ] so I got the
the multimeter and I was running like 60
watts or volt volts Watts volts 60 volts
to the top of the plant
right like uh
like and I you know I had to ground it
because it wasn't grounded so I when I I
hit the I hit it on the concrete and
tested it so I let this go you know and
I was trying to experiment with like
this more water uh make it go up or down
and eventually I think the thing was
going bad because it got up to like a
hundred
and I assume that means it was shorting
out or something so I didn't and then I
had I just decided that like
um I don't have flyer insurance and like
this seems like how you get a fire so I
I pulled that experiment specific up and
then
um I called a friend back home
um
who you know is uh also he's a very
smart human and I was like check this
out so we looked into it and uh it's
called Electro culture the technique is
called electric culture and this dates
back like talking hundreds of years
right like uh for instance
um it was like the late 1800s this uh
one of those monks you know the guys
that do like the beer or whatever
intelligent guys uh he was experimenting
on bacterial growth from static electric
charges and he found that he like one
static electric charge from say your
foot into the ground increased bacterial
growth 400 percent
um this dude in the 30s uh this is cool
this dude in the 30s uh
we took two poles and put them North and
South like big poles he buried them in
the ground and attacked him to a big
piece of metal at each end
and then he wound copper all the way up
with the rotation of the earth like so
many times and he put him on the north
and south end of this field and he grew
clovers that he won the World's Fair
with and they were eight feet tall
office off passively pulling this out of
the air you know wow so
I I called him and he worked at a
medical supply place and he sent me you
know what a TENS unit is of course you
do you know the thing you put on like oh
I sprained my arm or something and it's
got frequency and yeah say what
yeah on jackass they put it on their
gooch
oh I did not
do you remember that on the first
Jackass movie they put it on their Gooch
and were just that was my introduction
to a TENS machine
no [ __ ] uh
but it's like you know adjustable
wavelength that like potency and stuff
so I got a couple of those and instead I
put little patches on I like put on
alligator clips and I stripped down some
like uh raw mix which is you know like
wire like housewire and I use the copper
you know I clamped them on I put it in
the plants and it was getting like the
same effect but not quite as magnificent
you know because it's a lower lower
amount of voltage but it was consistent
like uh I got some bugs and then I like
uh turned them on and you could adjust
it like I think now listen I could have
been high
I didn't document this but
I swear to God I could like make the
bugs move faster or slower depending on
the current I was giving them
so uh
got a couple of these hands units hooked
up a couple lemon plants grew them
electrically and then that's when we
went to Holland and got that uh cup
second place the whole week just
tripping on acid it was [ __ ]
hilarious I think I walked over 100
miles through Amsterdam that week like
um we I smuggled weed out I guess yeah
that's we're past that so we're I'm in
Amsterdam we got like
uh three ounces left we're at the booth
and uh just rolling mad joints everybody
else in the spot was just like the
greenhouse guys had like the nastiest
like 20 foot long balloon volcano you
know and like other people were giving
out little like one-hitters and um in
retrospect after I got like everybody
every world's flew this was probably a
bad idea but smoking joints for
everybody and then the police raided the
place and uh everybody like Adam's
grinding up all the weed and I like uh
stuffed it in my I stuffed the remaining
herb
into my coach
and walked out because the Dutch police
they didn't look very tough so they are
so I put it in my arm and then as I got
closer to where they were all at I
realized that they put the monsters up
front man so as we're all waiting to be
searched and shuffled to get out of the
venue I'm like hey because I've been
riding a tram or the bus and everybody
like I need a bag
uh we're all waiting to be shuffled out
Adam's rolling these giant joints he's
got a grinder Adam's got this Grinder
like six or eight inches across I mean
it took your whole hand to like so he's
grinding up all the weed he's got and uh
I need a bag so I get the bag
and then I throw my sweatshirt on top
and then I asked for a bunch of like
swag you know like so give me all these
like not posters or like flyers and all
this [ __ ] so I got this bag of with the
weed in it and then the cops are like
come on okay he's like do you have
anything illegal on you and I put the
bag in front of him and I opened up like
nah man you can search me and he grabs
the bag he's like not in there puts the
bag down pass me down grabs the bag
hands it back to me and I walk out and
like we were the only ones with any weed
for the next couple days of the cup
it was awesome
that was a good time uh
that was yeah like uh yeah that was fun
actually holy [ __ ]
what a killer story are there any other
strains from that Amsterdam trip that
stand out in your mind is quite
memorable
we didn't smoke I mean
the
you know like I was really working that
Booth man like we didn't have like I
mean
when you like when you go to those
things and like the emerald cup people
were like oh you're so lucky like yeah
[ __ ] you dude I'm busting my ass back
here you know like
um
so like I didn't not that I really
tasted but I didn't I honestly didn't we
worked you know what I mean like I
probably rolled hundreds of joints and
[ __ ] you know like just
and then talking to everybody and then I
on the way home I end up getting like
the wook flu from like 10 different
countries I thought I was gonna die
that's how it happens right that's how
it happens oh uh you know what though
a good solid weed at the time back then
was like Adam's cushions
oh yeah
do you know what I mean like that was
something that like yeah that was
something that was like his buddies did
and it smoked real good you know
brilliant brilliant
I'm yeah I'm glad when I met him like
because I was trying to I was wondering
around Amsterdam like trying buying weed
and that shit's expensive and shitty so
then when I finally actually met him I
could knew you know just it was uh
better herb for sure that's great to
hear you've mentioned a few times you've
uh got some stuff going on with Duke can
you tell us anything about what we might
be able to expect or is it all under
lock and key okay so we're gonna we're
making some seeds we're gonna combine
our genetics and like you know he's got
some stuff he wants to do like uh he
wants to like work on a couple of his
you know like the Screaming Eagles and
the pole cat and uh you know I'm gonna
blend my lemon to some stuff and like
that you and I got this original G13
that I've been carrying around since I
was like
like
1819 and uh it's just been through hell
and I'm trying to get it worked back
into some stuff and it's one of the
strongest females I've ever seen like it
won't turn
like I've I've been trying I've tried
spraying it with silver thiosulfate like
three different occasions and it it'll
like push the the uh male flower bananas
out and they won't open like
consistently every time
right uh so we're gonna try and get that
to work uh we're we've been sponsored
actually uh bye yeah so we got sponsored
by buildus oil who are Kick-Ass I don't
know if you ever talk to Jared man like
yeah uh they have made a special blend
of soil for him personally that it's
this is awesome um
we can't hear me uh okay so he's old
school you know what I mean like he uh
he wanted to use like bone and blood and
stuff in there you know like any good
organic old school guy does so when he
called Jeremy Jeremy's not on that kind
of thing you know it's all factory farm
animal stuff so he actually convinced
them to uh replace some of it with more
organic and more uh you know sustainable
stuff so it's actually
and it smells terrific we've been
working with it uh
so they they sent us that and then the
we were we had a couple different
options with the LEDs and those fell out
and then s-tech
uh who is a let me you know this is
really interesting
uh offered it to us and when we accepted
them the other guys were like
like just add her like come on man we
got you like because they're
so Aztec is owned by this guy named Jack
Jack is a
uh he's a Chinese guy who developed uh
what do you call him uh street lights
you only have all LED street lights over
there so he developed the LED street
light which if you get if you're
thinking like a street light has to do
what like project a lot of light down
regardless of like
you know fog and stuff like that so he's
got a special
like lensing on them that even one of
the I'm not here to talk too much [ __ ]
even one of the best LED manufacturers
was trying to steal from him and they
lost it's amazing because
um these little road they're called high
Bays they're like maybe six inches wide
by three ish feet long and you know as
opposed to those ones look like spiders
I got all those like you know bars going
on these things have like uh and I'm
gonna post it up here man like a bubble
looking things
right and inside the bubble was like
nine LEDs and there's something about
the the uh that lensing that he's got
that causes the LEDs to have like
immensely good light penetration I'm
talking like it was and I'm new to the
ppfd but it was at 8 50 it was two and a
half feet
to 850 from the lens which is cool
because
I don't know if you have you know LEDs
generally you have to like have them
slammed down on there you know what I
mean
and their Wi-Fi
okay so you control them remotely
here's the okay so uh
you know uh I we get them and we're
setting them up and uh I download this
app
and at first it's like asking me for
permissions for everything
like I mean it was scary the amount of
permissions that this thing wanted and I
didn't really understand what was going
on and I looked it up and it's actually
this open source automation app you know
what I mean
and it'll control everything in your
house like from your Lance to your
your hvnc your uh your
just everything you could possibly want
to automate and stuff you didn't even
know you wanted like your curtains
closing or your windows shutting on them
you know what I mean
um and all that's programmable within
this little
app
so and if you I don't I don't want to do
Alexa but you can do what Alexa do like
it all said you know Alexa turn on my
garden kind of thing yeah but I'm not
don't do that because Jeff Bezos will
then see your garden but you got secure
home security it's all wrapped up in
this nice app and it's sends you
notifications when the lights come on
and I imagine like once we can get more
uh environmental controls you know
they'll be uh
automated like that too the lights will
dim down on their own if it gets too hot
and they cover like a nice for being a
little bar they cover like three by four
so we got them in a nice line
and uh
we just been setting it up you know
um
we got some tense from some people I
have to look
um
and they're nice and white on the inside
as opposed to that you know speckled
aluminum or mylar or whatever
um
and these are five by five which is nice
because they're bigger like I have a
four by four that I breed in and when
that fan comes on it really sucks in and
you know what I mean like kind of puts
the cramping on the plants
hydro grow those are the guys that gave
us these tents they're really nice
and then so basically we're gonna
showcase all these people's products
because we believe that these are you
know uh especially the LEDs these are
like really the
I don't know I don't like these big
stupid LEDs that have all these bars
these things are just streamlined
they look nice talk to the computer
you know
well it smells so good in there wow
that that soil really smells good he hit
it with uh dragonfly Earth medicine also
somebody who's helping out men those
those are really nice products I don't
they probably don't get to Australia
but uh unfortunately no but they're
great product yeah and it's like they're
super organic like they're flowing in
the same vibe that we're trying to do so
uh basically we're just gonna bounce out
seeds man like
they're legal they're like 100 you know
there's no THC in there you don't have
to worry about that
so I wanna
expand the reach you know it's not my
hemp plant my hemp strains are grown
okay anywhere hemp is grown you know
it's kind of cool
but like it'd be nice to
my buddy runs a wreck I think they're
wreck in Israel I think that'd be fun to
see
um
some you know some gear over there and
stuff
yeah definitely definitely it sounds
like you got a lot of options on the
plate I um
I wanted to ask you you've mentioned the
the lemon j a few times we need to get
the back story on it what can you tell
us about it because I think I heard at
one point it's like a Colombian or
something but I'd love for you to fill
me in
okay
I have that G13 plant
that I've had for
since I was 18 for 27 years right
I don't know anything about the other
side of that uh lemon G
um
I'm not sure what uh description says
but like it is definitely
that G13 because I've done a lot of work
with it and I get G13 Finos out of it
I'm not sure what the sativa side is I'm
being honest like if I knew but I know
I'm not one to
to lie I have no idea all I know is that
it is one of the terpiest things ever
like it's literally like uh my
ex-girlfriend would break out in hives
trimming it like uh my friends would
puke
um like trimming it and I've had a
couple people puke smoking it like it
irritates um I have one Buddy's throat
so bad he won't
it's it's like lemon
lemon you know what I mean with uh a
funky from the G like a turkey gravy up
underneath it and that's like a
quintessential G right there
um
it's a beautiful plant it yields like
you could have a giant bag of it and
that's like an ounce you know what I
mean you got like a
it's so fluffy it doesn't really have a
lot of weight and that was like one of
the reasons like when I got back from
the cup I decided to put a northern
lights that my buddy had been working on
on it because I wanted some density and
they flowed really well together uh
and I also
there's a
it makes the most like uh amazing like
for a Wilder it was the hottest thing in
Colorado like extract wise because it
that whole that
that D limonene just came through so
hard you know what I mean
but as far as your question goes man I
can't answer that and I apologize
I'm not sure of the lineage I just a
friend of mine when I was collecting
strains in Ohio to bring out here
like I had been growing it but I I asked
everybody that gave me strains uh when I
came like can I take this with me and so
yeah that's that is the extent of my
knowledge I'm sure there's a lot of Ohio
people coming online now I'm noticing
I'm sure somewhere in there
because somebody tried to call Adam
after the cub and they were trying to
tell him it was skunk times Misty which
um
like I said I've done a lot of work with
it you know like Crossing it with stuff
and always get G13 my classic one out of
it you know what I mean see you can see
it you can smell it
uh so I don't know I guess long answer
no that's fine that's a good answer
what are you guys up to so oh actually
man you know like uh we're not here
here's what we're planning not only are
we gonna be planning the the breeding
and stuff we're going to be doing like I
said uh the podcast and the
instructional videos like uh you know
part of him developing his own soil line
was because
um you know he wanted to be able to give
people a reproducible
uh you know like hey you want to grow
herb like this you need you know here's
the soil you use here's how we're doing
it
and uh so we're gonna do instructional
videos and that'll be like also to show
how awesome our sponsors are and then
we'll be doing uh
uh the podcast uh we were tentatively
going with two dudes one pup or one grow
so that when we win a cup we could be
two dudes one cup which is disgusting
and funny all the same time
I love it
yeah uh podcast was already taken
uh damn it yeah we'll spell it different
the premiere podcast you man you wonder
you won the name Lottery when you got
that one off
uh dude there's like a hundred podcasts
called the podcast
yeah podcast is beautiful you know what
I mean
yeah it's look it's got us to this point
right can't complain
yeah so uh we were you know so basically
yeah we're gonna do this thing and uh
you know um
he actually has been sick he like he
sequestered himself on the side of the
mountain with uh a bunch of us like uh
video editing here and he's been
learning like proper editing and the
whole deal so when when we do this uh
when we we're gonna be putting it
together uh potential like just
commercials for our guys you know what I
mean for our sponsors and uh you know
cool star wipes and stuff interviews
with uh weirdos that we know
yeah this is this one dude in Australia
he's totally [ __ ] weirdo we're
thinking about having him on you know
hopefully you don't you want to keep
your show in good repute uh you know
it's fun to have like I I wanna it'd be
fun to have like uh people with their
own show series you know what I mean
yeah man yeah do the uh people who
already have their own show show you
know
bring them all on but I want to take you
back to the question we used to start
all the interviews off with pretty late
to do this one but I love it anyway tell
me about your first experience with
cannabis paint me a picture what
happened
uh all right man
I was you know I got started a little
later I was 17 years old
um
I met new students a guy my mom like
when I was actually how did that work
out
yeah
um around 16 I met these dudes they were
like
casbians I was a skateboarder kid my mom
moved into this weird ass little town
hick is [ __ ] uh and I made friends with
these guys we started hanging out
and uh
so I never you know I was in one of the
first classes at dare you know
and I never really wanted to smoke weed
because my
both my stepfather and my mom both smoke
cigarettes I thought cigarettes are
disgusting you know
so I went on the weed I want to do LSD
like so much that when I was like
15 I took the Anarchist Cookbook into my
science teacher I was like Yo dude we
made some acid these later voted me most
likely to do drugs and I was really
pissed off and then he was like no it's
a good thing sometimes so
we skipped school uh me and three or
four of my friends and we got some you
know the bad God
which it turns out isn't mad dog MD is
this they have a bad dog but
um
and we were drinking at my buddy's
parents during school time and uh my
buddy took his mom's Bowl she had a
little
like Marvel bull you know a few inches
three inches long and uh
they tried to give me the smoking
foreign
at that point when I was a kid man like
uh
I was like the first kid ever on Ritalin
and then like I was I was honestly
Prozac when I was later you know because
I don't know they had like in third
grade I was tweaking on Ritalin what a
gross uncomfortable thing so
I was on some kind of antidepressant I'm
not really sure I can't remember
and I stole the ball I climbed up a tree
and I [ __ ] smoked this bowl and I got
high for the first time ever
and I pulled like a false damage done I
got down and I decided to like
I feel pretty good
I'm gonna quit taking
the swagging Pharmaceuticals and I'm
just gonna go smoke weed
and then shortly after that I got into
the Rave scene and you know
experiment with all the Gambit so
but I you know uh cannabis has been
since that day because I was like you
know what [ __ ] this
horror because horrible serotonin
messing with your brain chemicals like
it's saying like Okay then I went home
and uh I wanted to buy a bag of wheat
obviously that's what you do right yeah
I smoke so now where can I get it so my
buddy who I just talked to earlier
Donnie uh and I called her other buddy
dad and we're like hey man go to sleep
so it took him like hours to come rain
is this bag of weed and uh it was like
the corner of a brick
and uh you know they'd have seeds in
them so
I saved the seeds out of my weed and I
went home and I in my
in my closet I had my toy box when I was
a kid that had things like my dungeons
in the dragons books and my Taekwondo
uniforms and you know all that stuff my
I was a nerd you know what I mean uh and
I moved all that stuff out and I went to
the Home Depot and I got myself a little
grow light
I put some plants and I started some
seeds and
my mom's like so what are you doing in
there
and I'm like
I'm growing orchids mom
and she
uh laughed and she was like you know I
grew up in the 70s right because our
organs
yeah you gotta get them out of here so
then
um I was about to turn 18 and she was
like dude if you're gonna be selling
weed you can't let me be doing it here
so I moved out I got a hot girlfriend
and moved out and then we just started
growing like uh
yeah and it started off we stole uh 400
watt high pressure sodium from the
college two of those up in a little
closet and then you know as time grew so
did you know and then you got to get a
couple thousands and you know why not
get six or whatever so
and then who got here instead of like a
hundred and you know it just
growing stuff I I gotta put on probation
or parole actually I got I had to go sit
down for a couple years uh apparently
not to make drugs in your own home
you're not allowed
what was some of the strains you were
first growing did they have names or was
it before then
uh after I got a
Jail jail uh
I'd say pee tests and um
I started dating this girl was growing
some herb and I failed the first one and
uh
I got dinged for it and then
the next one I deluded and then the net
and so then Nicole in with the deluded
one and she's like
uh look this is deluded like what do you
mean it's piss and she's like no it's
not like it came out of my dick
and she's like you diluted it I'm like
what makes piss piss and she's like
creatine
and uh
so if you test hot again I gotta you're
gonna get in trouble and I gave her this
big speech like look when I'm off parole
I'm probably gonna I'm gonna go smoke
weed I don't think there's anything
wrong with it I think it's medicinal
I'll probably go grow somewhere I laid
it out and she looks right at me she
gave me this big Smurf and she's like
uh yeah whatever you want to do when
you're not my property don't fail again
so I go and got some creatine because I
was smuggling like kilos of creatine
into the joint you know what I mean uh
that's a whole different story uh and we
were working out and so I knew what it
was so I went and got some and uh mixed
it I like diluted myself but mixed it in
and like I was taking that and like I
passed and then she took me off that
if anybody out there I mean this is a
while ago but uh I assume that still
works right
it was just creatine though so she told
she like told me what it was I was like
what makes this and she's like creatine
so
I worked it out and I passed and then I
didn't have to take anymore so then
I started I got like I started dating
this other girl and I was like we should
grow weed and she's like
but what about getting caught and I'm
like don't
and so we set up a little
a little guard in our basement and then
uh it was nice actually and it was real
efficient and then that's when uh
that's when I turned 30 and I went over
to Amsterdam
and I met like Adam and oh you know he
eventually moved to my house when we
moved to Colorado it was uh
pretty funny situation
wow so he came back to the states with
you around the end of that 90s period
no I moved to uh well I want to say
Amsterdam 15 years ago
uh when I turned 30
and then when I moved to Denver I kept
up with him you know and then when I
moved to Denver I ran into him in Denver
and then we got a house and then I was
like yo I got a house come on so he he
ended up moving there
that was crazy we had like the tiniest
house
and six dudes living in it like I slept
on bunk beds on pallet racks with like
300 clones next to me
it was the it was a wild time man that
was the green Rush coming at her
it was an interesting time in Colorado
and were you just growing like uh for
flour at that point
we just got here
and I got to sing I don't like to throw
away plant matter so I'm growing like
perfectly healthy plants I kind of want
to cut them and clone them so what
started with
I brought maybe 20 different things out
here and like uh a coat with a lock and
a lid and then once we got here they
just kept getting bigger so we set up
the Clone her with the intent of moving
into a warehouse that was uh
that was like the entire intent you know
and then that's when
that whole Greenworks thing happened and
then the whole what we started talking
about when we first started the
conversation
ah interesting interesting okay
you like that like
that Richie movie man I bounced back all
the way to the beginning you know what I
mean like a neck
and that's how all that happened
there you go there you go I mean I'm
interested to hear in the early days
were there any breeders you specifically
were sort of looking up to
uh okay so when we were like 18 uh some
friends
you know they decided to drive out west
and like go to BC
and they called Mark Henry and that dude
like
Mark Emery showed up in their hotel room
with like uh
like a photo album full of seeds and
they ended up getting
uh
I don't know a few different things from
um
like Sagar and math is uh
bubbleberry
right like what else do we have back in
Cali missed
um
I got some skunk number one you know
like that was well like 1996 Maybe
so
uh I didn't really know about all that
stuff you know what I mean that was just
I didn't really realize like the whole
like uh
I didn't you know I didn't really
realize the whole scope of it until a
few you know later
until then we were just growing like
local strains like this G and this
Afghani number one that was like the
nastiest stuff ever
and uh
the cream which was Charlotte's mom
that stuff was a little later in the
stable
uh
yeah it was
it was more like what was regionally
available than you know and I assume
that a lot of that stuff was procured
from Amsterdam you know I mean like
people do go out there it's like you
know it was a stoner repair you know
that's where you went for genetics and
all that
do you know what the cream was
yeah it's uh The Afghani number one time
is a Jack Herer
that's right okay the AFT check sorry I
remember you said that okay
uh
it would make you stupid it would like
make you so stupid that like you
couldn't function that's why I thought
it had some other medical quality uh
but it's it's funky and it's it I like
the Afghan number one like we're we're
on like a you know he's got some skunk
and I've got I think I got that Afghan
one coming back I found somebody
uh the internet is a wonderful thing
sometimes like uh
there's a like the Clone trading and
like the it's you know what I mean like
the
the genetics they're moving all over you
know what I mean that's pretty cool it's
a great way to get past the disease too
but uh you know what I mean or nowadays
man like nowadays viruses are they're
all the rage you know what I mean right
like that seems to be
the zeitgeist
it seems to be relatively new now though
it seems to have something to do with
like the hemp thing that's going on and
yeah it certainly spread uh sped up
sorry the the spread of a lot of viroids
and various other sorts of things hasn't
it
some ugly pet plants that had some [ __ ]
like my buddy puts himself out they had
like a
it was some other
weird virus you never heard of that
affected like beets or something and it
looked all like cabbagey at the top and
all screwed up
um
so
when I got here and we set up this big
Warehouse the idiot that I came out here
with uh Kelly roller uh this dude would
lay under the plants cleaning the plants
smoking cigarettes like right at the
stomata you know
like I'm pretty sure like that's how you
get tobacco mosaic virus so uh you know
I'm into hops man since I quit drinking
I've been uh I went home to Ohio
to do my mom sing and I hit up the
non-alcoholic beer section because all
my friends back home are Brewers and you
know what I mean like my whole body's
like a master Brewer at a spot so I'm
gonna be able to like you know
so I end up buying like some
non-alcoholic Brews and uh these hot
Waters
that is just Hops and carbonated water
and uh those turned out to be excellent
so I still have all this brewing
equipment I'm trying to master those
uh and at one point I was like dude if
we uh
if we put some hops into the
you know tea we could probably and then
it was like nah man hot latent virus
that's you want hot plate virus that's
probably how you get that
but I did that once way long ago and it
really did make the the herb more funky
like uh
and it was stonier like the mercy was up
you know
yeah nice that's interesting that's
really interesting to hear
I um I wanted to ask you what can you
tell me about the G13 clone you've said
a few times you know you've had it for a
long time and I saw on your Instagram
you're doing the reversal with it can
you tell us a bit about what your plans
with it are and if you can give any
insight on the back story
I got my first uh
spider mites from this kid
Jason Cantrell I think he's passed away
but they came on this Afghani number one
and this G13 and we were told
like basically okay so if you find an
old
Seed Catalog from back in the day
there's like the one of those old ones
you know it's like black and white and
stuff there's actually a picture of the
geez that I have and it's like cut only
this was uh the the lore behind it is
what is it Mississippi or Mass
Mississippi they had the federal
marijuana growing program going on for
like that dude who you always see that
gets like that [ __ ] ridiculous size
tinted joints every month he's like the
only guy left on that program uh
supposedly that it came out of there and
it was an Afghani and they started like
so many seeds and that was the 13th one
that they kept supposedly
uh
and then somehow it got over to Neville
and then he showed that picture and then
it started getting crossed with stuff
and a lot of people that's what you know
there's a lot of gender thing crosses
and then Duke here was really nice
enough to back me up I showed him I had
one in the breeding tent Crossing with
the sour and I was like smell it and
he's like yeah dude that's that and then
he would uh you know then he showed me
like that his
88 G13 HP it'll have that same Vibe and
uh which other one
the Airborne uh which I you know I've
seen I don't think it had it but this is
like more concentrated version of that
and so
um
he's got a couple things that have that
in it we're gonna try and put it on
those and
but uh yeah so it's like a funky little
smells like food
like uh
I don't know
ugly little plant that yeah it's like if
you took the lemon off the lemon G
basically yeah you're left with the
cheese but it you know um it's been beat
up man like I think that that cut uh I
wanna give some props to a guy I call
Grandpa
um he's one of my best buddies I met him
back when I was like 17. he was the
first guy I renewed to grow a plant he
called it Sasha
and uh
he was the keeper of that g for many
many years but it has probably had every
single bug you can think of it's fought
off fungus it's been it's never turned
hermy ever like you can't get it to
throw a flower it's like super solid
and uh so it's just been hanging out
I I think it could use a little
Rejuvenation and I you know luckily for
a a buddy named Nick mccooms who got the
job at Greenworks after I was fired or
got like whatever you want to call it uh
he saved it he saved a couple of my
things and and got me the that's
you might have given me my our uh four
back then I'm thinking because he he
like uh disgruntled with the company
and so he stopped working there so like
uh yeah I got he you know he kept some
of the Ohio stuff you know when these
guys like I said these the Ohio guys are
coming out now you know like being a
little more
uh on the insta and stuff and I see guys
working with the lemon and all this and
uh they say they have the G but when
they when I ask him for pictures it's
definitely not my G you know what I mean
like it looks more like the Airborne you
know bigger Buds and not quite the
because my G's kind of like bluish green
and like
I don't know not the same planet
and so when Adam moved out to Colorado
he sent it uh this is awesome he said
his goons and they were awesome these
two guys came Big Mike and uh
Sam squanch I don't know what that
dude's name was you it was a beast so we
had gotten some herb and some of that G
and uh he woke up and I handed it to him
I'm like hey man this is my G and he
took a big old hit and he got this look
on his face like he was pissed and he's
like I don't know if I like that at all
what you know what I mean
it's it's got a not a normal turret
profile so I think that's important to
bring back you know what I mean like
we're just getting homogeneous Terps
kinda like now you know it's weird how
we have uh what's the new one candy gas
that's what everybody wants
yeah and I think I think that's the new
before it was fruity gas I hate fruity
gas that's like oh my weed to be just
funky and fire and gassy like keep your
yeah
if it's fruity I want a fruity like it's
just weird I don't know it sucks that
trends like there's you know there's
we're gonna have to break free of this
uh this weird mold that we're not you
know like the bowl that we're all
trapped in when it comes to I mean you
could only read something so long like
right before it becomes genetically
yeah
and no fun yeah there's yeah
I mean
I was in a our argument I was in a
conversation with some people and we
were talking about like you know f1s
versus like F5 so we're like you know
respect the work F5 and but you when you
start them all you're definitely getting
the whole it's all the same like there's
that's cool if you want that exact thing
but it kind of loses a little oomph and
like those fresh F ones or even f2s man
that all that stuff so like you get a I
like Tofino hunt that's the fun part of
uh
of growing weed right it's fun to do but
like yeah man I wanna I wanna I wanna
see different uh expressions of the same
plants that you know
I don't know yeah you see those guys
talking about like heavy apps like I
took it to F20 and you're like but why
what it's um it was homogeneous in like
five kinda I don't see what your what
was your purpose
so plus uh both you know I'm really
excited about this project coming up I
think that uh dude can I get along well
we both have the same kind of style when
it comes to like regenerative soil you
know what I mean like you get the best
herb with living soil
hands down
I we're wanting to ask you actually what
advice would you give to an aspiring
breeder someone who's just looking to
get into it all
you know uh Tommy is saying uh
breed with intention
you know like what what's your what's
your goal why are you breeding like what
do you want what's your purpose
you know like uh
like why why did you choose those like
what about
you know what about that plant gets you
going like why do you like it like
what's so special about it you know uh
what's different like
it's weird how
there's there's so many breeders out
there now and they each like you know
most of them there's a few of them just
do that hype on hype on hype you know
and then you know a few of them like JJ
do care that they all you know they try
to work it out like
don't just buy well actually I did I
bought a Tempo I was giving a 10 bag of
seeds and I bred with it well I I did
because out of literally ten thousand
dollars worth of seeds that I started
two plants like there's a lot of garbage
in there and those are like some of
those were like 200 packs from people
who were like you know
breeders and stuff but they were like
the most garbage [ __ ] I've ever seen
like
uh
start with [ __ ] bangers you know like
I chose that taxi because
it hit me like man I love this weed this
is great this is this is my what weed
should be it hits all the notches you
know what I mean it's it's funky it's
got this crazy like mouth feel that like
leaves that greasy I just like some I
farted in my mouth or something uh and
you know I I enjoy a weed that I could
smoke all day
because like that you know
I smoke weed all day yeah so
and it fits into my so my growing style
is I got these big ass beds
um
like full of soil which is
I'm still getting the hang of man you
know like there's some it's an
interesting
you know when you're working with all
one big bet it's an interesting bit I
got some blue mats water it in and uh I
use Ambassador soil that's definitely
not something you can get it down there
I think my Buddy Rich makes it it's all
like small craft Blended and it's all
super
uh I think the plants eat better than I
do like for instance
I mean
Alfalfa cattle protein soft rock
phosphate we got some Yucca yarrow
spirulina Corella comfrey wild Yammer
Metals Horse Sale Moringa Jill Moringa
is like one of the healthiest plants on
the planet
like as far as like antioxidant
properties and anti yeah look into
Moringa man it's like a it is I don't
even know how like it is one of the most
medicinal plants on the planet so
um hey start with something you like
um
something you know why you have a
purpose like why are you you know just
don't take two stupid things start you
know and pick whatever out of there
there has to be you know like if you're
breeding for excellent genetics you have
to
uh start with the parents you know like
uh
you know and a lot what the next one
isn't applicable to a lot of people
unless you know like uh when Ben
dronkers started that skunk number one
he started ten thousand seeds and
whittled it down from there you know
um a high amount what do you call that
uh
a
a large
uh population like a good seed pop you
know what I mean a Fino month you start
you know 20 20 30 seeds you're gonna see
winners come out of those for the most
part unless you're running like JJ's
here I think they come out of everyone
I'm gonna give that dude props again I
think he's a [ __ ] terrific breeder
and uh you know uh
uh you know I'm honored that he let's
see where he's he doesn't like a lot of
people working with himself but he let
me do it I said and I sent him back uh
all the seeds that I made with it you
know I mean I sent him backpacks and
like big ones and uh for him to work you
know what I mean that's another thing
like if you're gonna make seeds don't be
a dick don't ask one somebody's beer
don't like reproduce people's gear that
they're working with you know like
be your own
like you know make your own path like
find weird [ __ ] find the one that works
like
you know what I mean don't just
I don't know don't just do it because
it's cool
like actually try and get
like
reasons like why you put those two
together like what about you know what
do you like about that what do you think
that you're male which you should
run
at least to see you know what's going on
and make sure
you check everything because
like uh
if you if you cross two plants that have
a propensity to be hermaphroditic or
intersexual you're gonna breed that Gene
in there and it's just gonna
like
magnify the chances of that uh showing
itself
you don't want that
so
like okay so what you know be original I
guess that would be awesome like we need
more
uh
need more weird [ __ ] like I don't
[ __ ] care about how your cake tastes
like
you know it's like
what like try and make something new try
something new there you go
like give give props to the people that
you
that you consider great and that you
work with and that you know like if you
like if you get seeds if you buy a pack
of dirty you know one of those and you
decide you're gonna cross it with
something uh
give us a shout out make sure that the
you know you're not
and don't don't be naming your [ __ ]
weed first I hate those cats like
literally
like grow the seeds figure it out
like I see people like I need good names
and it's like well
like just do some work first you know
that's a great sentiment
what's the single most memorable
cannabis experience you've had
um
wait in that cup and like uh 2011 the
second place that was pretty cool
um
seeing there you know actually
uh my life
is the single most awesome cannabis
experience I've ever had you know like
uh it's funny now that I'm getting older
I meet people who you know they they've
jumped from job to job and when you tell
them what to do they're like oh yeah how
long are you doing that like I don't
know 27 almost 30 years now people are
like
wow man that's a really long time to be
in a job like
like cannabis is I I live for this plant
I work for this plant when the plant
isn't looking right I don't feel right
so like yeah this my existence is the
most uh
the the most memorable cannabis event
ever of my in my personal you know like
every and it's cool like every time I
think we got it like you know that when
that comfortable moving on here was cool
like meeting Adam was cool now like
like breeding all that hemp was [ __ ]
amazing man like the fact that you know
like that the CBD thing popped off even
though it did the way it did like you
know knowing that like something I did
brought
like helped bring the whole thing to the
table you know what I mean I brought
that plant and the next thing you know
it's on TV the next thing you know I'm
getting legalized like I feel like I had
a hand in that and that makes that's
fulfilling to me
um knowing that you know I dedicated my
life to this plant and it actually
did something so that's the most
significant one how's that the fact that
I know that I did something like
profound in the what I love
hell yeah what a brilliant answer
so next question what is a strain where
all of your friends were hyping it up
telling you like man you gotta try it's
the next best thing and then you finally
tried it and you were like ah is that it
that's a good question
I hate uh and no offense to Jeff from
irie I think he's a great dude I hate
Golden Goat people I know like love that
[ __ ] it's like Ah that's gross like uh
just now it's you know like I said that
my brain isn't on the Golden Goat
all right
um and recently my buddy's been trying
to convince me a runs that's how I knew
the guy that made runs is like a
millionaire now because he's like
he's just trying to convince me to like
you should try growing this once man and
I'm like you know man I think we got
more in like I don't think uh I don't
think Duke would be like yeah bring on
the runs we'll work you know what I mean
we're gonna cross some rocks with some
stuff although you know what uh to be
honest uh I have a couple things that I
like here like the cushman's and stuff
and that's kind of bubba-esque and um
I might do like a side project when we
get some of his stuff and like because I
think that that's a good strain that
that rabbit hippie cut is it's uh and
this is why it's an amazing like it's on
its own thing you know what I mean it's
got that Bubba but it's a little
like sweeter and I don't know
uh and it stands out in a crowd
and that's important
but
uh
yeah Golden Goat I don't get it you know
yeah no that's a good one I haven't
tried it myself but there you go I like
the addition so for the next one imagine
we're on a boat and I'm gonna drop you
off on a desert island and you can take
three strains with you to grow for the
rest of your life what three are you
gonna take
well
I'll probably need some for pain
so I'm gonna take a heavy indica and get
Afghani I don't know which one though
like uh
damn that's a really good question uh
I would take an OG Kush actually you
know what and I know that sounds weird
um
before I smoked OG Kush I thought people
from California were just a bunch of
pompous douchebags not that that's
changed a lot but
um
they would always be like I only smoke
OG Kush bro and it's like yeah whatever
dude there's hundreds of strains you're
just just [ __ ] up you know then I smoke
some good OG and I was like you know
all right I can see what and I think
it's a great strain now that I've uh
kind of experienced you know
um a few different ones like we were
talking about the San Fernando Valley
one of my favorites uh also there's this
one out here called uh
the the Coal Creek
not the Cold Creek the Cold Creek yeah
uh
and that one is like spectacular and
juicy uh
so yes one would be OG Kush uh
the second might be that Afghani number
ones were back in the day you know but
Nostalgia has a lot to do with your
memories you know like as far as I can
remember it was nasty skunky earthy like
Stoney like grew beautiful
um
and then
something with CBD I suppose you know
you're gonna want
I mean if I'm stuck there for the rest
of my life I'm gonna need medicine
right so something full spectrum like uh
because at that point you don't need a
one-to-one because you got your weed
there
um
so
I don't know uh this can is so hard
that was [ __ ] beautiful man my buddy
Ian and I put it together and it's
Canada
uh tonic sour tsunami uh and Harlequin
with and it's all like basically he just
we put them all in there it turns purple
has a fruit bouquet great like have you
ever smoked any CBD dominant bud or
anything
yeah yeah it's enjoyable yeah it's uh
they say it's not psychoactive but you
know I'll be dead man that uh sure puts
some kind of feeling on you
so
something like that like the AC DC or uh
the can of so hard or just something
that smokes good and grows well and does
CBD
just because I mean you know we're not
yeah we're just growing it to stay
healthy right so
yeah there you go
brilliant answers so as a follow-up
we're gonna drop someone else off on the
island this time someone you're not a
big fan of you get to choose what three
strains you're going to leave them with
what would you give them
some Dr grinspoon
um
yeah
uphill battle
like
some hemp
CBD ham you know you want to stay
healthy enough that they live a long
time but you don't want them to get as
high as they potentially could right
yeah yeah and uh
uh
uh some pure Haze
throw them
you know love it love it some they're
gonna have to work for it but like so I
get to leave or do I don't have to stay
with them
nah no no no it's just that
oh okay cool
so as the final question
I'm gonna give you a time machine you
can go any place geographically any
point in history to collect some seeds
or a clone where are you gonna go what
are you gonna get
the future
and I have no idea
gotta bring yeah the Integrity weed that
saves the future from you know what I
mean yeah
like why would you yeah I go forward in
time and grab you know once they figure
out and get it all you know the
I mean
I don't know you know like
everything now is available like it's
cool I mean if you look hard enough
you can basically get
you know anything like you want old
Mexicans you get old Mexicans you want
all your classic you know Thai all that
stuff is still available so I don't
I don't know what why
yeah man something that's not old
you know does that make sense
yeah definitely look no one's ever said
they're gonna go forward either so I
love that for the uniqueness but that's
in line
it's in line with this whole episode
given you bring a a unique perspective
which we've enjoyed very much so with
that being said I think that just about
brings us to the end of things were
there any shout outs or comments you
wanted to make
yeah like if the the people that uh
uh do get big UPS to Grandpa big upset
uh Adam Gunn my homies good guy big UPS
to Duke wonderful human being uh Big Ups
to my my cousin Ron he's always been and
my mom like most of all you know like uh
she accepted
that I chose a different lifestyle and
it was because of her like she raised me
and uh there were
you know like I don't think she knew
what she was doing but I would ask her
to tell me stories about the 70s and
Timothy Leary and Woodstock and all that
[ __ ] and my mom wasn't like a hippie or
like a you know but she she was
she grew up in that time and you know
the more she told me all about LSD and
like you know for you know people are
jumping out of buildings but that got me
curious and that's what led me to uh
you know my my alternative lifestyle
that I chose uh at a you know was uh I
think due to all those Pharmaceuticals
that they gave me as a kid but uh she
supported me you know through like okay
here quick
so I I go to her house for Christmas I'm
there on Christmas Eve I had a drug lab
right that's what I got busted for and
uh
I was like on a lot of drugs and I I was
like I was breaking down because you
know when you're at your mom's house all
[ __ ] fired up and uh on Christmas you
know looking back like I'm [ __ ] up
and she comes up and she's like what's
going on
and I'm like it's you know life's been
Savages like you didn't kill anybody or
anything right
and I was like no I actually
my dude and I have the nicest drug lab
you've ever seen and now
I have a drug problem and she looked she
sits there for a minute
and she looks at me and she's like well
if you owned a candy factory and you ate
all the candy you wouldn't be in
business very long would you
yeah man
and I mean that was you know so yes big
shout out to my mom I hope she's uh
I hope she's telling God jokes even
though I'm an atheist she wasn't so I
hope she got what she wanted she's like
making that dude laugh that's it that's
what I got huge love to all the moms out
there especially to yours and thank you
again The Man Behind The Seed Company a
range of killer CBD lines a range of
killer THC lines check them all now the
seed company two thank you so much again
for joining us
yeah man if you can call your parents
and tell them you love them go spend
more time with them like really you know
what I mean that's probably I mean
that's what a lot of them want you know
what I mean like they only last so long
so there you have it my friends a huge
shout out to two for coming by sharing
all his knowledge with us
it was a fun episode I hope you guys
enjoyed it as much as we did
[Music]
and That Just About Does it for this one
my friends I'll check you on the next
one this is Heavy D signing out from the
upside down Library
we'll see you
[Music]