[Music]
so
[Applause]
hello and welcome to the 2019 breeder
awards for the podcast
you're joined by your boy hip days as
always here to run down the 2019 awards
i have with me mr james bean himself to
discuss why certain breeders certain
strains and certain trends have taken
the scene by storm in the past year
big shout out as always to seeds here
now your number one seed bank in the
game
and a big big shout out to our friends
in the patreon gang as always helping
make the show happen lifeblood of the
show
getting early access to episodes
unreleased contents interview with 707
seed bank bodhi part 2 mean jean and mr
bob handhill part two you know how to
get that hitter
google patreon the podcast
and a big shout out to top shelf seed
bank dragonfly earth medicine and
organic gardening solutions our home is
helping to spread the love and make the
show happen
so are you ready for the awards for the
past year
i hope so
let's get into it
[Music]
alright so hello and welcome to the
inaugural 2019 podcast cannabis awards
these awards have been decided largely
based on the activities and occurrences
over the november 2018 to november 2019
period
and so what this means is that anything
gets released at say emerald cup or at
the end of the year that will go into
next year's running so we're largely
looking back seeing what's come out over
the last years
um so the awards categories for this
year are the following breeder of the
year most impactful seed drop of the
year
hall of fame strain
hottest newcomer breeder to the scene
most anticipated seed drop of 2020
most commercially popular strain
and clone of the
year so for the most part these awards
were decided by myself however i decided
to take into account the opinions of
several other notable people and i'm
lucky enough to be joined here today by
the one and only james beam thank you so
much for joining us
hello how are you i'm very good my
friend and the final component for these
awards was decided by some polls i put
up um so some fans got some input so
we're gonna try to provide some logic
and kind of some rationale behind each
of the decisions and just kind of
accompany the decision as to why we
chose them or what we think is good
about each pick
just as a personal note
a lot of these picks are not necessarily
my personal winners so you know the
clarity in the rationale will hopefully
back up why we're picking these people
and it's not just a case of oh that's my
friend so we pick them
so jumping into it
the first award we're going to discuss
is the most commercially popular strain
of the year
so without any further ado the winner
for this was
gelato and all of the extensions
what do you think mr bean
i think i think it nailed it on the head
i think i called it last year of course
i i know everything but uh no definitely
we saw the most crosses the most um most
breeders using it you know it's it's um
it's it's become unsort of i don't know
cool or uncool how it is but it's sort
of common these days for
um a new clone hit the scene and then
just everybody get it and then the
breeders work with it because it's a
clone it's they're all essentially
working with the same branch of a branch
of a branch because they just each have
a different branch
but uh then each breeder hits it and and
um
definitely gelato was the girl that got
passed around the most this year
so to say yeah
no questions there i mean at the emerald
cup we saw ridgeline win with their runs
and you know for this discussion i
consider runs white runs grunts you know
all of those derivatives it's just
gelato you know so in essence we saw it
win them or cut we saw it was an entry
in basically every high times every
competition of all varieties you saw
this year and i think most notably is we
we saw that it pretty much wiped the
hype market out for any other strain
that didn't have gelato or cookies in it
yeah that's definitely fair to say and
and there wasn't any uh
yeah there wasn't nothing else really
gained as much traction or as much as
much steam so to say as gelato and if
you didn't come with a lot of heat like
you know years past we've had tropicana
cookies and
other other uh things that have come
through but yeah this year was pretty
much the one that was common across
debris all the breeders was gelato cross
two right two right
so
on to our next award next i want to do
clone of the year 2019 i'm going to give
you a guess because i don't think it
takes much imagination to guess this one
um
this one's uh it's a long shot we'll see
the mac oh
how did you know
i don't know we're not supposed to sell
the mac i know that ah only the coolest
of the cool
yeah
it's an interesting one you know because
this one it's kind of been in the work
for like three years now hasn't it
yeah i was gonna say it's it's got it's
had enough steam behind it for last
couple of years to be definitely i you
know i'm not sure how it uh how it all
has worked out or if everybody's happy
or not happy about the mac being in
circulation and sold uh and available to
most people but um initially it was a
harder strain to get for sure
yeah i mean in 2019 we really saw it in
full force you know dispensaries were
selling it the rappers are talking about
it every cup has several mach 1 entries
in it every instagram has photos of it
it's just
clone of the year without question but
the question is will it continue on do
you feel like we've reached peak mach 1
status yet
um i've heard of course i hear i hear a
bit from everybody but i've heard mixed
reviews on the mac i hear it's you know
great frosty and all that wonderful
thing but uh i also hear it doesn't have
a lot of flavor
kind of smells like my arm but um but
you know i the stuff i've gotten has
been has been frosty for sure so as a
breeding component from breeder's side i
would think that that would be
uh that would make anything that it
would touch you know it would enhance it
if you could so
of course so i wanted to give some
honorable shout outs for clone of the
year 2019 and the first one that jumped
to mind for me and i'm thinking you
might agree with me is lemon peel from
our buddy archive
yeah lemon peel or as a uh
uh
what's he calling one one star one stars
as it was known and so i gotta take
credit get on this uh maybe there are
the first podcast i'm on or you check
out my facebook in 2000 uh a year and a
half ago or two years ago i was freaking
out about that strain
he had given me some on a drop and i
actually i i went out to the car like
three times i was at my hotel just so i
could get high and smoke that weed
when it was gone i like i like made a
song about it you know
about because it was like my jar was
empty and i was so sad you know
it was it was definitely something
special i hit him back up that night and
i was like dude that's amazing and then
that next week i saw that he had renamed
it one star
um so on on that and just uh just to
throw a monkey in the in the monkey
wrench into the in sorts you know that's
from trojo right
really
correct archive popped it but credit
goes to trojo as far as creator of the
stream
there you go i know that it's uh you can
only really get crosses of it you know
he i think he said he doesn't have f2s
or anything like that so that's why i
think it's a good good entry for clone
of the year because it is truly a clone
you know like it's just the female
that's all there is of it
yep it's it's the great thing about
siege is you're if you're you're female
hunting you're looking for that one and
so trojo released it which he gives
credit to but it was it was archive that
selected it and found that particular
phenotype that everybody uh is in love
with but yeah i was i was rather
surprised as well right when i hit up
archive i was like when is that gonna be
releasing yadda yadda and he's like oh
yeah i didn't do that you know which is
which is
fletcher i mean that's that's that's his
credits what he would do you know i mean
he would be like no that's not mine
that's this dude's because that's what
he does he's a president you know he
doesn't want to get called out on
anything so um but yeah it's uh it was
it's a great strain i i loved it to
death uh the the few times i've had the
rosin's been amazing i love the flower
itself
um i know obsolete in love with it as
well so
perfect
well moving on to our next category next
we have the hall of fame and this one
was an interesting one because there's
really just a few contenders and
i kind of think that the obvious choice
in people's mind might be something like
og i mean of course these strains have
been ordered in the past it's not as
like this is the first time recognizing
how good some of these strains are but
for me i thought og is a little a little
before us and i thought that it's kind
of undeniable at this point that girl
scout cookies is really the hall of fame
pick for 2019 you know everything it's
given rise to the gelato the sherb the
dosy dough the mendo breath it's
basically countless at this point you
know it's it's the modern version of the
og and the popularity and it's got the
youth market in its grips that's
undeniable what do you think mr bean is
at hall of fame status
it definitely is from a from from a
strange
perspective from a breeder's perspective
i've you know we'll have to throw that
completely out of the ring and i just
i'm just going to take a like a breeding
point of view here i just you know i'd
like to know maybe and maybe it goes
back to the og but as far as who made it
there's a story behind it there's a myth
there's a legend behind it but whoever's
whoever actually created the strain or
meant to meant to do it or if that meant
to it all
has isn't hasn't come forward so to say
like it's you know i i know who i
believe it is but and and it's it wasn't
burner you know so
um from a breeder's standpoint no way
but from a strange standpoint al all day
like it's been just used in so many
things it's and it's
it's one definitely of this of this time
period that's taken the scene by storm
and is undeniable whether you like it or
not it you know you can't deny the
popularity of cookies that it's that and
the markets made on the industry
so 100 and i think you pointed to one of
the most important parts about it you
know like most big things it was bag
seed
yeah it wasn't it wasn't meant to be
done if whoever meant to do it they
would have extras they'd have a mother
they'd have a father they'd have pieces
to put the puzzle again but if there's
never a male
uh then that means that that was never
meant to be and and and and backseat
strains aren't bad and we want to talk
about bad seed we're talking about you
know maybe some headband we're talking
about some og kush we're talking you
know some some great strains maybe
seven out of the top ten are gonna be
bags you've never meant to bees
but uh
i just it's yeah but definitely cookies
has made it has made its mark but uh as
it was like like like i say as it came
from backseat it backseat it shall have
and so it keeps it keeps throwing seeds
to this day i'm sure
everybody out there has a female girl
scout cookie plant
a motto to live your life but
alrighty so
next category is hottest new breeder to
the scene so for this one we had quite a
lot of entries but the overwhelming uh
answer was our buddy from alaska
akbrains so
you know sporting a huge wave of just
old-school genetics you know things like
northern lights this year he's had a lot
of success with his some mac crosses
with a male mac he found and selected
uh and just the most important thing to
mention is his new tkno haze which is
taking the scene by storm you know it's
it's got the potency it's the unique
pairing of the old-school cush versus
the old-school sativa
it's it's a really beautiful hybrid and
it's a fantastic way to kind of start
off his
breeding platform and it's exciting to
see what's on the horizon
no it sounds like some great building
blocks for sure i'm not um uh admittedly
i'm not as familiar with um with him as
as as you are
i love alaska i've been there five times
and they're in their canvas scene was
just was just coming out of the and the
woodwork sort of saying it's it's a
great place um but uh yeah it definitely
has some good building blocks and uh
tknl has definitely sounds uh if you can
bring that bring the flowering time down
on it it's where it's reasonable from a
breeders standpoint definitely sounds
interesting so
hell yeah
[Music]
alrighty aka beanbrainz thanks so much
for coming on the show and
congratulations on winning the hottest
new breeder on the block award for 2019
well thanks a lot for uh getting getting
me uh another shout out here and i'm
really shocked and uh
humbled by the fact that i would get an
award like that so i appreciate that
yeah no well deserved well deserved so
give us a bit of a rundown what has 2019
been like for you how would you describe
it
well i avoid the crowds like normal and
kind of stick to my own thing so i just
enjoying
solidifying some lines and getting them
basically back out and shouting their
names out a little bit and letting some
of the
inexperienced people get
a better uh taste of what is available
in the old heirloom
lines so
i've just been working on that and
thinking about that a lot
[Music]
fantastic and are there any specific
heirloom lines you have in store for
well you struck a hawk horde with me
when we were speaking about the old
thai and chocolate ties and uh i did
kind of
i had some
seed stock from different various
sources and then went and grabbed a
bunch up and
i'm gonna run
pretty good uh searches on that plus the
chocolate i have is in the f4 and i like
chocolate a lot and
i got
colorado's uh
chocolate tie and nl two by five
he was giving that out as freebies and
if anybody slept on that they're crazy
because it was it's outstanding uh
good good chocolate time but the nl
sides real great too but a lot of little
things like that and
a
little bit of 80s chocolate thai that
was crossed to
boggs
strawberry kush and
i can't imagine the some of the flavors
and then
excited about uh
crossing the top the chocolatize
i'm gonna put it on the lemon tree and
some of the old standby
mothers that i have
fantastic so how about any collabs for
2020 on the horizon
you know i uh i've been playing around a
little bit with professor p from dynasty
he's uh me and him get along real good
and uh
we both benefit each other on anything
that we work on so there's a little bit
going on there and uh
he's been good enough to
gift me his medical cuts since i'm
really in need of some good medical
uh herb and
he passed me his grapefruit web which is
a seven and a half to seven and a half
it's
four percent perpend every time and it's
like
really good smoke so
that's one of the things i kind of think
is cool but he's he's done me some
favors there
kind of working a little bit on a nl
revival
that is coming up and that's with uh
mr bob hemphill and i and
we have quite a few sources of nl1 and
l2
i don't have much nl2 but a lot of nl5
sources a couple nl1 sources
so we're going to do big run out on that
and uh
he's got a bunch of mine and i've got a
bunch of his
so within the next year probably uh this
time next year we'll have some pretty
exciting original
old heirloom
uh nl as it used to stand in the mid 80s
wow sounds like 2020's got some really
exciting releases in store let's wind
back though one year 2019 just wrapped
up what are you most happy with what
would you recommend to people
oh i've always been big on
things that are just super durable
heirloomish but um i love the freeze
land that i've worked with i love the
durbin that i work with
the vintage blueberry
they're uh
they'll hold their own against almost
any strains but they'll uh they'll
weather the worst summers and they'll
handle heats and droughts and they're
bug resistant and
they're mold and mildew resistant so i
really like those and i push those along
but people request them and really want
them anyway they hit me up and i'm
usually
not able to keep it
made up
so that's uh that's one thing but i'm
always uh
loving the tk crosses that i've been
working with the tk g13 hash plant
f4 and f5
i'm getting some really cool phenos out
of that and
loving the old funky g13 that comes out
of that even thinking about crossing the
airborne g13
from tommy
uh onto uh
some of these
and i love that gk i mean the tk uh
no5 haze
it's about a thousand grove reports and
people are it's not me but everybody's
saying it's uh
it'll hold its own with the very best
real og and uh
um you know the top-end hitters like
d chem 91 and chem 4
i constantly get a lot of people telling
me it's about the best thing they have
had no ceiling it's just the fact they
haven't had a lot of that in circulation
for 20 years and it's first time they're
coming across it so
it's good to hear it and uh
continue with that a little bit
i got a bulldog chewing on their
christmas toys
okay well
some really good answers in there
i guess just on to the final part you
know do you have any comments or shout
outs you wanted to make just in regards
to 2019
yeah i had uh
quite a few people i really um
wanted to catch an emerald and i missed
the harvest cup and
i didn't get around i missed a lot of
people
friends flew in from all over the place
i feel bad i never did hook up with
about 20 guys
i did on the other hand get a hookup
with a lot of friends and it's great to
see them every single year it's great to
see you it's great to see you
all my west coast buddies
uh i really uh enjoy getting around and
i just would like to thank everybody
that's
given me a hand over the year and a ton
of support
love the uh
people shouting me out and meeting
meeting with me and uh
thanking me for what i've done and it's
just something i've really enjoyed the
whole time so it's uh
really cool to see it come to
fruition that
you know people are putting the work out
and then showing me back the
results
and shout out to my customers you know
and and general public i really do
appreciate it
yeah fantastic so again congratulations
on winning hottest new breeder on the
block award and thanks so much for
coming on the show aka bean brains
welcome and i appreciate it like i said
uh
maybe this year you'll be up here and uh
i'll show you around this place
love it can't wait to go hunting
yeah fishing fishing we can't kill all
the stuff we can just fish a little bit
okay sounds good
[Music]
[Applause]
all right so up next we're going to do
the most anticipated seed drop of 2020
so we actually had a tide first because
we had both a tie within the fan
selection as well as within my own mind
i found it very hard to discern the
clear winner so for tide first we have
the upcoming blue bonnet lines from riot
seeds which sports the blue bonnet mail
from texas resin company so this one is
essentially a blueberry offering that
was more refined by lone star to
generally
attempt to lock down more of the
blueberry flavors than say dj's previous
work had done so all the crosses are
looking really nice and exciting i'm
particularly looking forward to the
blueberry cross bubblegum which is meant
to have that really nice blueberry syrup
flavor to it
however
this was tied for equal first place with
the one and only karma whose new a5 haze
work is just looking to take people's to
the net is looking to take the haze
lovers to the next level so this is
essentially a northern lights 5 haze
cross that comes from original neville
stock from when he was releasing under
the seed bank and as such it's just the
pure old school super strong super
sativa so there's going to be crosses
with it as well as s-ones so mr beam
what do you think blue bonnet versus a5
haze which one you more excited for
uh you locked me in a corner guy pick i
gotta pick riot i love how uh how riot's
just
right right it's a great breeder and
he's he uh he's always wanted to give
credit and and like uh like we've talked
about earlier about about archive being
a you know a guy not to take undue
credit you know he gives credit to lone
star kicks back to texas present company
so um just uh it should be really good
i've already i've had a lot of guys hit
me up in the instagram and in my chats
track like hey when you're going to get
it when you're going to get it so um i
definitely think that's a hard choice
and then on the other side with karma we
also carry karma karma's great guy uh
the hazes uh
i don't think that this current
smoking generation has really had much
interaction with the hazes and may you
know or as much because they've been you
know like we've heard like we discussed
with the hype strains there's not a hype
strain that's a haze like not currently
you know there wasn't at least there
hasn't been in the sort of hype term
that we that we go to mention um and so
hazes could really come and knock people
out and it could be very interesting um
it's just for me it's just getting that
flower time down i don't know that
you know some of those strains that are
12 14 13 15 weeks
really are gonna make it
yeah it's it's a really valid point and
i think it's interesting because a lot
of the die hard fans who populate places
like instagram create this environment
where it seems like there's huge demand
and everyone will buy it when it comes
out and then you hear these breeders
talk about how when they invest the time
and the energy sometimes it doesn't
translate in sales
yeah no it's true and a catchy name and
a great picture sell you know a thousand
packs of seeds it's um but some guys do
put a lot of you know all the guys put a
lot of work into it there's a lot of
failure before there is success you know
there's a lot of stuff that you don't
want to release her that you know once
once you build up your rap you if you
release something that's shady well all
you're gonna do is just kill your rep
and like i've told my guys it takes you
know five years to build your wrap five
minutes to lose it and so they're
they're extra careful as far as testing
and putting putting stuff out and there
are some home runs about the same time
very home run there's there's a couple
you know strikeouts for sure
yeah of course so i wanted to give some
honorable mentions because in this
section we had a large number of people
who started giving um some suggestions
basically not for say a sea drop of 2020
but kind of a whole line from a breeder
and essentially we got an overwhelming
number of mentions for
the launch of crickets and cicadas which
is the new seat company from mr bob
hemphill and hannah bolt and yeah i
definitely want to give them a shout out
there's a huge number of people who are
really excited for these lines to drop
and they're working with a range of
really old-school exotic genetics like
skunk tangerine and i'm not talking
about tangerine skunk from barney's farm
which is [__] i'm talking about
skunk tangerine which comes from oregon
kids and as well as things like northern
lights and the the nice land races from
when they were working at coastal so all
of these cool old school stuff getting
crossed in new ways to the more modern
stuff like thin mints and euro g kushes
and
yeah i think these guys are going to
make some really good waves next year so
keep an eye out for them
i i think that's a really excellent
selection our uh
shout out for sure because um i know
that they were with coastal i knew that
they had moved up uh up west and they
had split um they had split with from
coastal you know cool everything was was
good with them so it's nice to hear that
they are back out and ready to release
them with some really good stuff um and
shout out again to oregon kid you know
once again it's nice seeing breeders
give respect to where it comes from and
not just trying to rename things and say
you know i made this well no everybody
worked with something and so to hear him
give shout out to oregon kid ken um like
that really good dude uh did a lot for
the scene and that's something a lot of
people don't see as you know we'll say
shout out to organ kid if you think oh
that's cool guy well these were guys who
did things and they didn't need to do
things like who would meet people off
the internet when you know like i have a
hard time meeting people off the
internet to
date you know what i mean but you would
meet we block people off the internet to
do illegal felonies with like i'm gonna
meet you and give you a clone and if
you're a cop you're gonna arrest me
and so these guys were out doing doing
the doing the dirty when nobody else
would and so it's kind of
you know they were they were rebels are
looked at poorly in their in their time
period but now you know shout outs and
weren't really counting i think i think
uh oregon kids got some some stuff
working in washington but um that's nice
to see that they're working with this
stock
yeah that'll be cool to see some stuff
from oregon kid as well
yeah oregon kids great like i said
really nice guy we'd met up with him
we've had him on a couple shows uh
he's he's good dude he does has done a
lot for the scene you know that goes on
unmentioned and isn't making he's you
know a lot
this green rush a lot of people get will
get you know oh everybody's making
thousands and millions of dollars well
these guys didn't you know they they
didn't they're lucky they didn't get
five to ten years you know so um it's
it's nice to see if he would be able to
capitalize somehow on that and may come
out with some seeds or some come out
with something but
yeah of course he definitely put the
pacific northwest on the map for sure
oh yeah so on to the next category we
have
the most impactful sea drop of 2019
so this one might have a bit of a
surprising answer for some people but
i'm really confident in it
i think that the most impactful seed
drop 2019 was the australian bastard
cannabis from csi what do you think
wow i think i think caleb caleb's a
great breeder um i i definitely have
enjoyed listening to your podcast with
him uh there's the caleb the library for
csi um i know he has this prior to the
triangle line as well but uh that uh
australian bastard campus of course it
was it was a shoo-in i mean you're
you're an australian bastard
i set you up for that didn't i yeah well
kind of it kind of did but yeah but yeah
i think uh you know caleb has been in
the scene and and a vital part of the
scene for for a great many years and he
has a he has a great great library and
so um so that's a that's a big award and
that's uh it's pretty cool yeah yeah
what did you find familiar with the
australian bastard so to say well that i
think that's part of what plays into why
he won it is that it's so rare you know
even people in australia as well versed
with things as like myself or others
even more well-versed they've never seen
it so the fact that he got it
successfully you know did a
repopulation has got the seeds out to
mark i think that's one of the aspects
of why it's so impressive but i think
the biggest thing for me is that it's
not really the seeds themselves the abc
it's it's the potential that it has to
affect future morphology and you know
imagine like a cookies bx3 that is
everything you want in cookies but looks
like the abc and you can grow it in your
front yard no one would ever know i
think that's where the real value in it
lies down the track and i think he's
working towards that type of thing
already cool so just the whole fact that
it was something that could have just
have gone off into and uh and there it
wouldn't have been lost forever but
instead it was taken by a quality
breeder uh re repopulated as you say
remixed fixed uh reebok brought back to
life and then and then redistributed to
the masses so that's uh
that's a that's a that's a big circle of
life to say that's really cool we'll
have to definitely see some things in it
because i i'm not familiar with the
australian bastard myself i know a few
but i'm not familiar with the strain
so uh that'll be very interesting i'll
have to go definitely have to go pick
that one up and when we leave here that
sounds uh interesting for sure yeah well
i mean it to me it kind of tied into the
work you guys are doing with humboldt
seedco and nate with uh the the freak
show project
the freak show just went on pre-sale
today uh the freak show
it's it's a different plant isn't it
very but it's similar to the abc and
that you know it's got that same
potential to really disguise things
and and i think that that's you know um
that may be the the cool new thing that
we're going for is how do we how do i
put it in plain sight without getting
nailed because everybody's doing it
these time of days you know what i mean
everybody's growing
um but yeah the freak show the freak
show is definitely something it looks
like it looks like it could be very
interesting um eric nugget nug shots did
a video of that and that guy's amazing
um i love that video so
uh we'll see what the freak show entails
and i'll definitely go go pick up the
abc for sure
yeah lovely so i just want to give a few
quick honorable mentions for strainer
these are probably the more conventional
ones on a technical side a congrats to
again caleb from csi for doing the tk
s1s a feat that's never really
commercially been done due to how hard
the triangle is to actually reverse so
congrats and we've also got the sauer
bx2 from karma a lot of people were
really hyped on that however the biggest
talking point and the one i want you to
talk a little bit about for me is we had
an overwhelming response from people who
said that the most impactful sea drop of
this year was candy rain
and i think that really it just
indicated how fresh this is still in
people's mind for all the wrong reasons
uh
800 bucks for breeders that you don't
know
who didn't do the thing that they told
you they did first of all
that's like that's like buying a bag
like here smell this bag of weed and buy
these seeds for that
well this bag of wheat has nothing to do
with that that box of seeds like are you
selling with the seeds that weed because
you know as
it's the honestly classic bacon switch
but on a luxury edition if you will
um
so what i know about the candy radio and
and
i guess one of the sad things is
last year we did uh we did like a little
cup kind of me and dunn did it in
massachusetts people gave us stop by the
booth they gave us give us a allegedly
gave us a gram we gave them 10 off um we
sampled them all um one of those samples
we got was candy rain
and it was like
of all the things it was probably the
definitely the smallest and maybe
not maybe not the worst but it was
definitely down there it was just so
bad and what i got notoriously from it
was like i heard 5 out of 30 like 2 out
of 30. like those were the numbers
coming back as far as germination rates
and so when anything is that bad and
then i was talking to jay beezy and
about the whole thing and these like i
had to go and fix it i'd go do these
things and you know he tried to
go contact all the people that had
bought it and just you know send him
free free gear because you felt bad
for uh the cookies fam but but um
you know i uh that's hilarious it's good
that the public got it that they
understand that you know just because
it's 800 bucks doesn't make it good you
know what i mean um
don't get taken by the hype and uh i
don't know
i'm glad i dodged one with a bullet um
you know cookies moving forward uh you
know they have a little bit different of
a game plan and we'll see how that works
out for them um
but yeah that's
that's kind of breeders just proving
that they didn't do what they did like
how how'd that london pound cake go
yeah
right
i i think the interesting
the interesting thing about this one is
that it technically actually happened in
2018 but it's still so fresh in the mind
and i think the other thing which leaves
it fresh in the mind is the fact that
people were waiting for something to be
done about the situation in 2019 and
that failed to happen so i think that's
where it's really kind of rubbed a bit
of salt in the wounds and of course this
poll was done before the current drama
cookies are facing which was at the
recent emerald cup the prevalence of bud
rot or botrytis in the outdoor flower
they were selling so it seems like they
go from drama to drama
i didn't hear about this one uh oh the
tea i tell you what uh that's very
interesting that's that's horrible like
as a
as a breeder or as a solid grower you
would know that and you would see it by
trimming and you'd never let that touch
your table
and so that just goes back to the point
that they didn't make the cookies
because if they did that or they were
responsible for that they never would
have let that hit their table they would
have
spotted it way before that and pulled it
and seen it before anybody saw it and
blasted into some high priced oil that
they sold you but because nobody had
mold or bought rice anymore we just have
a lot of oil these days
so
that's horrible of being on the west
coast i'm very familiar with that and uh
that's is
horrible that whatever they were selling
had had that on it not only did they
have it tested but to have let that go
and let them sell that especially at
their prices oh my gosh
yeah
so they've got great marketing people
i'll give it a give them that
that's one thing they've got down pat
but uh on that same topic you know you
fit that category in my opinion so from
your point of view from c t now's point
of view what was the most impactful seed
drop for you guys
i i can't i can't pick my favorite child
you know what i mean i have i have a lot
of good children they all do different
work and unique work and i'm just happy
to get the gear that i get from them and
be able to make it make it uh make it
make it to the public um any honorable
shout outs i know that you mentioned
earlier in the year to me that you were
thinking about maybe the story and cream
drop from exotic as one contender
so that's comparing apples to oranges so
to say okay um exotic isn't a is in a
different category so to say i don't
know he he's crushing it he just he just
crushes it for now for people who are
looking for for that
for what so if each breeder did this if
it was if this stuff that was that we're
talking about if this was just done out
of a book that you could read um i
wouldn't need 50 different breeders i'd
have one because you would be doing it
by the numbers and it would be you know
science it's each breeder is unique and
different they all look for different
things exotic what he goes for and his
clientele that they go for what they're
excited about are rock hard frosty nugs
and and he's you know he hits down the
park every single time it seems um that
as far as his releases go he doesn't hit
it out of the park every single time
some of these trains never make it to
market he'll dispose of them um before
they even get see the light of day but
the stuff he's been releasing just just
crushes it um he's doing a thin line
right now we'll have that drop on
new year's eve uh he's got six different
strains the grease monkey femmes those
should you know there's crescent emerald
cup we stole the city sold out of most
of his most of his regular stock 80
percent as regular stock than the first
hour at emerald cup
so
um his yeah i told him i said what are
you doing they said you left gear at
home he's like i didn't expect it
but uh but no exotic is he's he's a
different world but um some of some of
the newer guys we had we released this
year the irie irie genetics
jeff uh we started working with him his
his drops uh it was really good uh we
added him to the bank he's had a really
good uh uptake this year um we added a
muerta at the end of the year he's got a
really good following and really good
gear and he's been you know definitely
work these lines and
has had some had some good strains uh
done loud uh they've released their
recent collab uh micro tech had a good
release dj short released his breeder
series so there's just
there's a lot i can't pick you know one
over the other but there was definitely
some um because each breeder is
releasing just about you know two or
three times a year now they've gotten it
so up to a point so when a breeder
really holds back and and does something
out of the ordinary i think that's when
it'll get
you know truly that unique that unique
area but right now everybody's doing two
or three times a year and and depending
on the customer or what you're looking
for you're going to have a different
breeder that did it for you this year if
you're a guy that likes sativas or mine
races then so and so did it for you this
year and you wouldn't be going for
exotic because that'd be the opposite of
what you want it's like when you put
exotic and dj short on the same panel
they
it's just so night and day like dj short
wants big
leafy larfey buds because that's what
makes the best hash which does
exotic wants frosty hard nugs because
that's what flower's the best he likes
to smoke because he does and so
depending on their viewpoint you're
gonna have a different guy that that's
your breeder so
nice try but i'm not picking one
brilliant brilliant diplomatic answer so
that brings us to the big
final category for this year the breeder
of the year award so
for 2019 the breeder of the year not too
surprising goes to caleb of csi he's had
an absolutely huge year with i'm about
to just start rattling off a list that's
going to sound endless but the skittles
s1s the tks ones trainwreck s1s and
cheese s1s in the works all the hybrids
with all of those to things like girl
scouts to og kush he does huge 80 to 100
plant pheno hunts of his own work finds
the keepers and then breeds with those
keepers he's done durban poisonous ones
cali oranges ones bubble gum s ones old
family purple s2s as well as his pirates
of the emerald triangle which is a lot
more regular based work so he's done an
extremely large amount of preservation
work he's done some technical feats
which was the tk the triangle kush swans
as well as taking out the uh most
impactful strain with the abc it's
fairly undeniable he's been on fire this
year
uh
well i'll say you kind of copy my pants
down to be honest buddy uh
but i i've we we have caleb on the bank
um like i said earlier i think he's a is
an awesome breeder and uh i think i've
been sleeping on him unfortunately i've
been doing my customers maybe a little
disservice um i don't know that we had
or we got most of those drops
unfortunately um and so i think i'll be
giving a a call to caleb as soon as we
get our csi help since we're done with
his chat and restocking all those items
um uh that's yeah that's a that's a list
i mean you just you name them all them
all off and i was just like i don't
think i got that one i don't think i got
that one so uh it was right underneath
my nose i didn't even see it you know
sometimes when you when you're looking
uh it goes the same with seeds sometimes
when you're looking for for the babe
ruth you had the one you wanted right
underneath your nose the whole time
yeah so
uh that's it that's really awesome um
but and that's because yeah that's uh
you know the technical fee that the tk
uh uh s1 is is a pain i've heard if not
impossible so
um yeah i will definitely uh have to go
check out all his work and that's pretty
awesome to hear yeah it's a big a big
shout out to caleb and props for all the
work this year but you know obviously
there's a lot of honorable mentions for
some other breeders we should give shout
outs to and so
the kind of the other two who i think
have had really big years i wanted to
give a shout out to was obviously
capulet he's come out with his caps
frozen lemons the freezer burn crosses
and the new miracle crosses in the works
so he's had a pretty big year both in
terms of what he's been doing and
commercially he's been crushing it as
well as the mac one doing very well for
itself the other big shout out we want
to give to is to duke you know we've
seen a lot of the granny skunk lines
really come to fruition within public
gardens and we're seeing some incredible
keepers come out of the work most
notably i've seen some extremely fine
examples of the six million and the
stash plant
so yeah two really big notable shout
outs and in terms of the fan polls we
got a lot of
people chiming in saying that they
really thought trichome jungles had a
good year so shout out to him he had
some nice work with his lilt as well as
his cherry spice lines and finally an
honorable mention to karma for his sour
bx2s as well as some collabs and some
future work which people are excited for
uh that's that's really awesome it
sounds like a very very diverse list of
uh some some definitely some some big
hitters um to our buddy duke dominion
our duke diamond uh dominion maybe
you know uh maybe not breeding anymore
so if you can pick up his packs you know
definitely lock those packs down i don't
know that he said in his in his uh in
his instas what not and he told me that
he might be
he might be putting some stuff in
retirement after the first of the year
so
that being said uh great pick and and
definitely uh caleb winning on on and
and being in that field of breeders that
you just mentioned um you wanna you know
you thanked caleb for everything that
he's done this past year i think
unfortunately we go back and thank caleb
for everything he's done
over the past years because that's you
you know you don't just coming out of
the closet unfortunately or don't just
come out of the grow room so to say and
become you know breeder of the year have
released the year that that's a lot of
work there which people don't realize
you know we say a lot of stuff's bag
seed a lot of it is there's also a lot
of good work being done and i think that
you know caleb uh over the years has
preserved these items has kept these
these things work these things had a
passion for it and you know a little
weird curiosity that he's as he's put
is obviously made um very very uh very
top very popular and very good and so um
i'm definitely excited to pick up those
new lines and i'll have to go check
those out but uh that says a lot for uh
for for csi humboldt though
yeah yeah he's had a killer year
yeah and you know and and
uh was he inspector what was his online
handle yeah inspector
yeah so he's inspired me that guy's been
on the forums for years and years and
years and you know you don't just you
don't just do that stuff overnight so um
that's awesome obviously a great 2018
for him
perfect yeah so big congratulations to
everyone who won an award or got a shout
out this year
for sure
yeah yeah yeah
so let's uh script so how was your
speaking of uh mr bob pimpel and moving
up north uh how was your trip to emerald
cup yeah it was it was an interesting
one i um yeah i think it's on the way
out there was far less big like marquee
tents holding stalls there was
a really
small number of familiar faces you know
i felt like i didn't recognize any of
the people running the booths there were
like big corporate companies i actually
saw
one of the girls who was working one of
the booths on like a greyhound bus like
a week earlier like i was catching a
greyhound down
and um and so it just all clicked for me
it's like wow they're like shipping
trimmers in from northern humboldt to
run these corporate booth stands
and it's just trash it's just [__]
trash um there was a few companies who
are trying to do good stuff like
i don't want to name names because i you
know but basically
yeah it was it was weird you know there
was the cookies tent there was probably
about 10 breeders in total at the whole
venue it was crazy and some of them
weren't even selling seeds you know the
big names were selling seeds like
capulet uh swamp boys exotic mike those
guys are always going to draw a big
crowd and do well but a lot of smaller
guys just weren't represented at all and
it just didn't feel like the normal
emerald cup have you heard anything
about it
well that's that's uh that's that's uh
that's hard to hear from you you know i
mean because definitely you've been
there a couple times but to hear that
it's it's gotten so corporate
from uh from a guy who's been i don't
know how many times you've been three
four times i mean that's
it's gotta it's gotta break your heart
seeing it go downhill so quick because
you know i'm sure like i can feel it you
know when i first met you i believe you
know you turned around there was bodhi
you turned around there was homegrown
natural wonders or there was you know um
or or mojave you know somebody a bubba
or josh d and and now it's um
i had a feeling last year was getting
there and this year they were not
uh they were not they were not wonderful
to me either you know i should always
watch what i say but
they kind of left us hanging last year
and this year we didn't give them the
chance we decided we're going to sit it
out and um we didn't want the corporate
feeling so instead we did what was
called the digital cup and so we did we
all the breeders that couldn't go to the
emerald cup they did their release with
us on the digital cup
and so we had aficionados do release uh
seattle chronic seeds do release
um
a couple other
diamond data release
and then we did panels as well so we had
a we had a
panels on our form where they called in
dun was the moderator had uh kaya from
pacific northwest route spog
um duke called in jd short
chris from shadow chronic so
those are all in the forums on c2 now
but it was kind of cool you could just
sit from your head like the comfort of
your couch and order order the gear get
the drop um watch a panel not have to
wait in line not pay 150 bucks not get
rained on
so
yeah
do you think the digital cups are going
to be something going forward or do you
just think people will just find other
events that have got more applicable
kind of rules and regulations that are
you know a good environment
i on that honestly i don't know our
digital cup we had three categories we
had uh you know the best picture you
know grow out our gear send us the best
picture and we'll choose and you you
know get a nice pack of it you win very
nice very nice prize second thing we had
uh you know pimp the merchandise karen
that cat uh
category where you know pick your uh you
send us images or logos or so you know i
think it seats you now what comes to
mind if we pick your design and use it
on t-shirts and give you a nice prize
um
then we had another category as well so
uh you have to edit that some stone i
forgot what the last category was
um
so you had three categories uh which
which you could enter in that people
would win uh different prizes and
whatnot yeah but i definitely think it
will have uh we're gonna keep doing it
we had a great success with it we did
great in sales and so um you know not
every breeder can afford five to ten
thousand or is licensed and can't get a
booth of their milk cup but yet they all
have their strains that they've been
working on all summer and so we're just
giving them an outlet to sell it on on
the website so
yeah okay that's exciting
yeah i was pretty thriving we had over
5000 photos submitted in three days
so it's pretty awesome
yeah yeah i'm excited to see that and
especially because that's one of the
incentives about getting down to these
events is that there's good sales
there's a lot of good information to
pick up and i think that that's really
what draws people to the events more
than
maybe the the music or the other things
which the emerald cup seems to think is
the draw card
and that's that's an excellent
observation because i thought that as
well i mean you guys are putting way too
much
too much emphasis on your on your music
draw when you should be putting it on
your your your information your
education and your in your people draw
um but they do what they do and they'll
they'll they'll come with it and as far
as your last question goes as far as
what we'll see and what the what the new
thing will be i don't know
what i do know is that it seems that
wreck
kills
shows
period that's it washington washington
used to have shows had high times cup
said this had that wrecked past no
public consumption killed washington for
shows
portland passed wreck how do you stop
shows there high times there same thing
right past killed shows once rec passes
if you consume in public or you sell
things without paying your taxes on it
the state is right there to watch you
and they'll shut you down
and so i'll bet there's probably at
least 50 to 100 regulators there at
emerald cup probably watching that's why
you didn't see a lot of seed companies
selling because they didn't have their
correct permits or
or her licenses needed
um and so i don't know that california
will california in whole not just any
cup but the californian whole will come
back and have what we saw as as
festivals back in the day
but i don't know moving forward that the
rest of the country that
um unfortunately the west coast hasn't
killed it for you because it seems like
these states as they pass they go
quicker like they they're quicker with
the regulations right i think right out
of the gate they're doing this they're
doing this they're regulating how much
electricity you can use and how much
square footage and and it's like wait a
minute it took it took working like
three years to figure that out you guys
are coming out the gate with it
and so they're so i think that just to
the bigger the bigger thing i think you
know what festivals are left and and and
uh cannabis events that there are that
are consumption public that have public
consumption are definitely numbered and
i think they're their ways their days
are their way their days are numbered
and they're all the way out but um you
know we still don't see a public
consumption bill in the states where
people can go and consume in public like
uh even the states have been passed the
longest five and seven years still do
not have public consumption yeah you can
drink alcohol and do it at a bar but you
can't smoke in public
so
yeah it's interesting the kind of
inequity of it all
yep wreck kills parties it's always true
they say wrecked won't kill medical if
they're lying
yeah they say
parties they're lying
yeah
definitely a clear observation from
california's experiment
yeah and then i hear you know there i
know their taxes were insane when i was
there last year i paid like almost 30
tax on everything
and so i'm sure it wasn't much less
but yeah
but uh so what else did you do while you
were at the emerald cup
i
did some
did some recordings got some some cool
content recorded which we'll we'll
hopefully be able to air soon we've got
a little
i got a cool one-hour video recording of
uh mean gene myself and mr bob hemphill
just talking about some old school
strains at me and gene's place and it's
uh it's a pretty wild pretty wild video
i think the the real strain heads will
really get a kick out of it so that one
will be a ct now exclusive
wow
you didn't tell me about that you got me
super excited i mean those guys are
hemphills has some knowledge i mean gene
is you know like i said i think that guy
pops more seats than anybody i know um
uh so that would be definitely very very
interesting and yourself being um you've
got to be one of the most uh educated
guys i know in cannabis as far as
histories and stories and know what
comes from where and access to things
and so
um that would be very very interesting
and wanting to hear that
uh
so what can we expect out of the podcast
in 2020
yeah good question um i think i'm going
to focus on trying to do a bit more
video content where possible obviously
geography can make that hard at times
but for a long time we've been trying to
line up some big names together you and
i and i think that we're we're at that
point of being able to clinch a lot of
them so i'm hoping for
2020 to be the year where we kind of
take things overboard and i think we've
been making some good progress on that
so hopefully the fans can have something
to look forward to and get a bit more of
a behind-the-scene look at some of the
really big name breeders who have really
put a lot of effort and contributed a
lot to the scene
definitely i think that that with that
just comes you know with time i think
that i know that um
a lot of a lot of these breeders have
maybe mentioned to me you know uh
uh how long that laos can stand for and
they don't want to you know i'm gonna be
public you know you know i've been doing
this thing for the last seven years i
was doing this for five years ago it's
like so the fire statute limitations as
far as i know that statute limitations
is running out and i know that some
people have expressed concerns about i
am not going to go up there to admit who
i am when they saw the statute of
limitations on me they can still convict
me for [__] i did five years ago so i
think that now we're we're so far in the
in the legalization that these guys can
start to come out and they believe it
that we're legal a little bit more
they're not just you know they're not so
quick to jump on the train of of belief
that everybody else is and so they might
be coming to light more and say yeah i
did this and i was the guy responsible
for this and that so
hopefully we can definitely see more of
that next year
yeah god if some of these people want to
come out of the shadows and
kind of let us know what they're
responsible for that would be amazing
yeah and i think that goes to you know a
lot of the guys are still in the shadows
because they're still in the shadows you
know they they had to be like if you
were if you were the guy who's making
the most noise in the block and driving
a shiny car and wearing too much gold
you're the guy going down you know
they're the guy the cops are going to
look at and so they made it to where
they are believing that that's how they
had to operate
and so now they're not they're not
they're going to be the quickest ones to
switch over and say okay sure it's legal
i'm going to come out and say i did that
just so i get busted jerks idiots you
know so
um they're they're smart they're not
quick to quick to jump on things and you
know i think i see more and more of them
believing that hey it's a real thing and
you know it's it's people other people
are making money on it i might as well
come out and get some too
yeah and so they should
yeah definitely uh definitely some of
these guys deserve it
but yeah it should be definitely
interesting for 2020 and how are the
laws in australia coming along uh what
how are we this year compared to last
year speaking of awards anybody out in
australia doing good things for for good
people
um
you know what i i heard a good analogy
when i was in the states which is that
australia is about 40 years behind the
state so if you think about what things
were like in the late 80s in the states
that's about where it's like so we don't
have a real medical scene it's it's
medical by name but it's essentially a
system designed to keep you from
actually getting any medical cannabis
it's it was it was it was introduced by
the conservative government so of course
there was going to be something up about
it like why are they legalizing cannabis
that's not their card and so
angle yeah so what they did was they
figured it out like they thought we'll
legalize cannabis we'll win over all the
young voters who aren't conservative but
in reality we're not actually going to
legalize cannabis it's just going to be
legal in name so then so they didn't
actually piss off yeah so they didn't
actually piss the older conservatives
off but they won over the young vote
until the next election when people
realized it what it was so
um to be honest i'm not holding my
breath for anything legally
groundbreaking to change but hopefully
if the uh
the the labor government which is you
know a lot more progressive if they get
in power hopefully something will happen
but in terms of who's doing good things
like the states you know like we were
talking about with oregon kid you know
there's there are some people who are
just doing things at their own risk and
just trying to help progress the scene
in little ways and you know shout out to
all the homies around australia who are
doing their best to final hunt and to
keep cuts and to share cuts around with
their mates and whatnot because to me
that's what is driving the scene at the
moment because it feels like we're at a
bit of a political stand still so
well politically things are a little
slow we can still progress the scene
ourselves and do what you guys did find
good strains grow good weed get it out
to the people
i i think a lot of what what what
unfortunate you know um pushed the
states over as far as that goes and i
hate to say it but we passed cannabis on
the backs of children essentially by i
think that's that cbd and
the the
well say the discovery of it but the the
science of it all and um you know the
the medical
uh the medical benefits clearly from cbd
that although it's still a schedule one
narcotic you know i mean uh cannabis it
has this weird component called cbd
that uh that has made it you know
medically viable and i think the belief
of that and and just the science behind
it and how it's used and just about like
i can't go into a store these days
without seeing you know hand confused
cbd infused
and so i think that really helped push
the whole cannabis as a plant over the
top
and that there was a medical viability
behind it and maybe the government did
lie to you for a long time
yeah but
so hopefully that you know i'm not
saying hopefully but you know maybe that
may may come to australia and help them
pass it quicker because there's some
serious you know cbg we know works is as
a great component cbn we now know is
like the night night as far as hemp goes
and so hemp and hemp and cbd and whatnot
have have a big value as a whole
industry on them on their own and and
millions of dollars and so maybe that
helped us joyous see the see the light
of day or so to say yeah fingers crossed
you know we already see a little bit of
it but yeah hopefully it gets over the
line
yep yeah cool i appreciate you having me
on and i uh you know it's it's it was
interesting to to listen to your
selections of course i had nothing to do
with them you are you pick them all um
but i was uh i think they definitely hit
the nail on the head and um you know
once again i i applaud your your podcast
i i love listening to it thank you for
letting me be the sponsor of it um you
definitely go out of the way to ask the
questions that nobody asks and
um i know you just did a a a podcast
with true cannabis we're gonna be adding
him uh next year
um i love that guy um
uh so yeah but thank you for doing a
great year of great shows and all your
listeners really appreciate it yeah no
thank you for supporting us you know you
guys are number one in the game and
that's why we love having you on board
the team and really appreciate
everything you do and everything you do
for the wider community you know there's
a lot of people who take for granted how
wide your shipping service is and i know
that there's some people who wish you
ship to where they live and i think that
maybe there's some things in the back
end of that happening so soon enough we
can have everyone pleased
so as far as i know uh on that we have a
whole new website that i've uh i've
spoken about in the past that's been
designed finished and up and running um
so definitely go check out the whole new
website we've got a whole new shipping
methods we now offer a discreet shipping
method
um we offer also offer a flying monkeys
option
so
i believe we've got six total shipping
uh shipping options international next
day overnight all those good things
we also have a 100 guarantee we've also
added free shipping for all orders over
300 bucks as well as a rewards program
so everything you buy you get 10 back on
uh to use on a purchase so those all
those are all new for the show upcoming
year but here's to 2020 and thanks for
letting us be a part of it and here's a
lot of good mortgage shows
[Music]
[Applause]
there you have it my friends the breeder
awards 2019 the podcast what did you
think
do you agree do you disagree
if so tell me why i'll tell you why
you're wrong
i'm just kidding i won't tell you you'll
just have to know inside i don't agree
there's definitely some close calls but
right
however only the cream rises to the top
big shout out to everyone who got an
honorable mention and of course the
winners
likewise a big big thank you to mr james
beam for taking the time to join us to
run down the list of the best in the biz
for the past year and a big shout out to
mr akbrains for stopping by and giving
us his thoughts on his award
[Music]
as always big thank you to our sponsors
ct now radio ridge best in the business
likewise patreon gang we appreciate you
so much we couldn't do this without you
finally top shelf seed bank dragonfly
with medicine organic gardening
solutions we love you guys
hope you're all ready for some more
content i'll see you in the next one
i'll see you
[Music]
you