[Applause]
foreign
[Music]
[Applause]
podcast for budding enthusiasts
you're joined by your boy heavy days
before we get into it a huge huge thank
you to our sponsors who helped make this
show happen C's here now number one seed
bank in the business get all the hottest
breeders the latest drops the most fire
strains guarantee on satisfaction not
just germination why would you go
anywhere else go hit them up they got
everything you need
likewise if you want to ensure your next
car this is the best to date you need to
check out coppet biological systems
they've got everything you need to make
your Harvest happy and healthy got my
problems grab the spidex vital got rapid
problems grab the happy part
they got everything you need to make
your crop happy healthy and your next
Harvest a success
[Music]
likewise a huge huge thank you to our
newest sponsor for jumping on board
they've been in the industry for ages
you know them you love them
Pro mix introduced back in 1968. they've
always provided commercial growth with
Cutting Edge and value-added growing
media products but now we've got a new
one pro mixed connect a fantastic
mycorrhizal inocular you want healthy
and established root system with faster
growth increased crop yield and better
quality check out Pro mix connect for
all your mycorrhizal products and
mediums
likewise a big shout out to the patreon
gang you guys know you are the lifeblood
of the show I cannot stress how much I
appreciate you and how much you helped
to make the episodes happen if you would
like to help to continue to see episodes
happen and get early access to content
additional unheard interviews bonus
listing material and so much more go
check out
www.patreon.com forward slash the
podcast it's that easy guys
on this episode we are lucky to have
John of Green Bay genetics here talk all
things breeding Oregon strain history
Buddhism and so so much more
[Music]
I hope you guys are ready for it
let's get into it
alrighty a big warm Welcome To The Man
Behind the hazy Kush the tensin Cush
the other body this one's just a little
bit more green thank you so much to John
of green body genetics for joining me
today
oh thanks for having me really excited
um
watching you and hearing you for a long
time so really really honored and
pleasured by getting this opportunity
yeah not a problem not a problem how you
doing today
I'm doing really good um we just made it
down to Los Angeles down in Orange
County here
um we've been kind of on a little trip
um my teacher and a few other venerables
from his Holiness and dilemma's
Monastery namgal Monastery are down here
where
um they're here finalizing some things
for a project that my teachers heading
it's a library Museum project of his
Holiness The Dilemma
um and that's going to be in Ithaca New
York but um we're starting a center down
here also
um in Westminster area Orange County
area for his Holiness the Dalai Lama so
they're going to have a small Center
here as well
um and they're just finalizing some
things with that and also with the
library Museum project that's going to
break ground in May
well that must be a really sort of
exciting time for for you and the people
around you I guess the question it
brings to mind to me is that there are a
lot of people out there who are quite
into Buddhism quite into sort of Eastern
spirituality how do you feel that
interplays with cannabis do you feel
like there's overlap there
well of course um well for one there's
they're theorizing now that um the true
home of the cannabis plant is in the
Tibetan Plateau so
um they're now finding
Source Origins that was one of the first
places that it was so and in a lot of
the um you know deeper
esoteric studies of Buddhism Hinduism
um Jainism these different things
there's been talk and utilization of
cannabis and in a multitude of different
ways also in taoism and Chinese herbal
pharmacopoeia these kind of things if
we've been utilizing this plant
um medicinally and spiritually for
thousands of years you know humans on
all levels but
um in Buddhism especially there's
there's certain practices and certain
um
things that there was association with
cannabis in the form of bung which is a
basically a steeped milk drink that they
use cannabis so there were some
practices that basically you drink the
whole bottle of bong you get locked in
this rock Hut you have you do this
particular practice have this particular
experience and then you know so it's
it's been utilized in um
in Buddhism and in a multitude of other
religions for thousands of years from my
understanding
even I mean when you talk about the you
know with Jesus and the holy anointed
oil you know from all of our
understanding that was cannabis oil you
know so
um you know people say what they want
and whatever but when you start
researching and start studying what was
being used what oil was a prize
medicinal oil an anointing oil a healing
oil back then it all started pointing
towards cannabis
wow I mean we we've had past guests talk
about bungs such as irizen um who gave
us a little bit of a rundown of how that
plays into the Indian culture but a
really interesting point you just
brought up is how it the the the sort of
ceremony you just described sort of has
a lot of parallels with like sort of the
way people are really getting into
Ayahuasca these days have you ever seen
that or noticed that yourself
oh for sure
um I've you know personally I've drank
an Ayahuasca I don't know 30 40 times
um it was part of my
preliminary studies and practices you
know about 20 years ago I actually
wanted to be a shaman you know I thought
I was going to be one of those guys you
know until my first teacher
um you know kind of laughed at my face
and
you know stated clearly how um how
stupid that was and so I didn't do that
and instead went um
you know utilize the plant that I'd
already have a deep relationship with
and went full force into that but
utilizing these plants San Pedro cactus
Ayahuasca Salvia these different things
to kind of um disentangle
um the egoic
you know anchor to some degree soften up
the you know attachments from all your
self-centeredness and give you a
self-observation
format to a degree to where you can
start seeing how fake you are yourself
um or how you're not one of the other
you know or both
um so
for us you know the Ayahuasca and
especially when I talk about this drink
it was associated with a practice called
mahakala which is a wrath lamination of
Buddha of compassion it's a protector
but it's a it's in a wrathful form of
compassion
um so which
um the the image of this this six-armed
um wrathful protectors holding a skull
cup of a reddish fluid they called
rockti
um but you know we always make jokes
with as Ayahuasca you know so for years
you know
um but that being said
when you have a full-fledged
full-blown cannabis ingestion experience
you know we all under I mean anyone
that's ate in too much cannabis
understands that that it's it's about as
strong as it gets you know
um
Ayahuasca obviously with the
dimethyltryptamine and the MAO inhibitor
from the banisteriopsis copy you know
basically a chakruna it has the DMT
alkaloid and the banisteriopsis copy of
the vine
um has the MAO inhibitor
um
so that induces a certain experience
that's unique to those things but
um from my experience when you get into
say the you know the Apex of any
experience there's a lot of similarities
there so the Apex of an Ayahuasca
experience versus the Apex of a heavy
cannabis experience and through
ingestion they're quite different
but esoterically and emotionally you can
have a similar experience of you know
death experience
um com you know heavy self-observation
analytical annihilation of your you know
or an empowerment of you know some
people they don't utilize the plant in
the appropriate way and it just empowers
their ego you know we've seen these
kooky wannabe shamans or
um also you know I mean we're really
familiar with the Cannabis industry so
we can just use that
you know there's never I've never seen
any other industry in the world and any
other continuum
of business that it can that a plant can
promote such an ego such I'm the best
such uh you know I'm better than
everyone else I'm what I have is better
than yours it's I haven't seen that in
any other
any other thing so then I look at
cannabis like oh it's maybe exacerbates
the ego in a lot of ways or annihilates
and disentangles the ego in a lot of
ways so it's a quite unique parallel
that it has
um
Ayahuasca on the other hand
you know for me personally it was more
of a
you know Holodeck of all my karmic
experience and I was able to see
the beginning point of a lot of my
issues and why they were
started why it got conditioned a certain
way with cannabis I wasn't able to see
it so clearly but more in a
undertone was there you know it happens
in a way
it just happens in a different way but a
similar result can manifest in my
perspective of
um humbleness subdued ego these kind of
things that happen from both you know
Ayahuasca happens for me having a little
more richly
um you know because I
added to the point of death experiences
shamanic death kind of style things
which that's hard to do some cannabis at
least for me I'll just go to sleep you
know
um versus Ayahuasca you have a death
experience and you pass out because you
think you're dying sometimes because you
can't breathe you're asphyxiating
through hyperventilation and and
um you know panic attack kind of things
so you can pass out through that
experience
um so when for me personally when I've
had those level of experiences because
my teacher was kind of a freak he would
take um we would get Ayahuasca from the
shipo and out of culpa in the Amazon
jungle he would take that Ayahuasca and
he would reduce it by 75 percent so if
you have a leader then you'd put it down
to a quarter liter
um and then he'd give that
um so we'd you know the times I've had
certain doses they've been high doses of
that kind of concentrated medicine to
where you're say taking 200 milliliters
but in all actuality it's near a liter
you're drinking
um so that's that induces a different
type of experience that that our our
crew is
um it's very integral to our crew
um so
you know if you can't have a shamanic
death you can't have these death
experiences then
um your perspective of who you are we
feel is kind of limited because you
don't get to see who you are when you
have a death you know so if once you do
get to see who you are when you have a
death
and see who you're not it um it opens a
lot of um information for you opens a
lot of awareness to your own mind and
how you can work with yourself so
I mean both of those things come from my
perspective from Ayahuasca and from
Cannabis just in different forms
different formats different message
different delivery but in the end a
similar result so yeah what a great
little run down on the comparisons and
differences between the two and so much
of what you said really resonates with
things I've been noticing in the
community especially how you talk about
the Cannabis Community or the plant kind
of has this uncanny ability to draw in
people who tend to be quite focused on
ego and the thing I've noticed recently
is that I feel like there's very little
consideration given to Alternative
perspectives within the scene especially
when you've got say two people who are
having a disagreement there's often very
little room for considering the other
person's point of view
what do you think it is about cannabis
that does that compared to the
psychedelics you kind of reference
dosages and you got me thinking is it is
the problem that with when smoking
cannabis generally speaking you can't
get a dose big enough to really approach
that sort of ego death which you can
with say Ayahuasca and maybe you can
approach it with the bung what's your
thoughts on that
well I mean I think a lot of people with
these like thousand milligram Edibles
have had that experience now you know
because they'll eat the whole candy bar
you know and from my perspective when
something's extracted with hexane or
extracted with a you know a hydrocarbon
and then made into an edible
um something happens something different
happens from my perspective you know so
there's all these different
um
Avenues of extraction they're going to
promote a different type of result
versus if you're doing a organic ethanol
extraction or whether you're doing a you
know water separation
ice hash and then taking that product
and putting it into MCT oil and then
eating that you know there's there's all
kinds of different ways so that's
something to be considered as well you
know
um and I think that
strain specific you know is is is is
something for me most of the strains I
like to smoke are going to induce a high
mentation capacity
um analytical thought or hyper
analytical thought or hyper critical
thought so this kind of
um
experience this induced from certain
strains it doesn't work for some people
and maybe someone that might you know be
more
CBD or indica prone they smoke a
high-end sativa or a high-end hybrid
sativa and they're having a panic attack
thinking all kinds of weird thoughts you
know like they took LSD or something
so it depends on the person you know one
of the things my first teacher always
told me is it's all you know every
person has to know their vehicle
what works best for them
what foods work best for them you know
does drinking lots of water work for you
does it not does eating lots of meat
work for you does it not does eating
lots of edge work for you does it not
you know so really analyzing your body
and analyzing the fuels you're putting
in it
you know is really important so for us
um you know Organics is a big a big
facet in our life and every aspect of
food cannabis all these type of things
um
so you know I think cultivation methods
um I think
environmental factors all these things
are gonna
lead to a certain experience or a
certain
experience with the plant you know
certain awareness awareness level or not
you know when we talk about people's um
opinions
and their inability to find balance in a
conversation when there's disagreement
um
you know it's obviously it's hard in the
Cannabis industry because I mean it's
hard in all aspects of society these
days you know people can't disagree with
each other without getting in a fight it
seems like it's like not cool to
disagree anymore it's not cool to think
different and you know that's I think
that's maybe a more of a societal thing
especially in Western societies where
they're taught everything they think is
special they're special their view is
special their perspective is special all
this kind of thing in actuality it's
just perspective it's not special
you're not special any being is not more
special than any other being you know
that's just not how it works and the
reality of this universe but ideologies
and conditioning through Western
mindsets through other aspects of
mindsets have reinforced and conditioned
this type of specialness into everyone
where I think we're experiencing that
especially in the Cannabis industry
because it's plant
will exacerbate the ego or delineate the
ego one or the other and so when two
people disagree
it's it's really hard especially in our
industry for them to find some type of
balance and common ground because you
know most people aren't skilled in doing
that most people aren't skilled in
Psychology and philosophy most people
aren't skilled in these kind of esoteric
studies that are basically based on
recognizing the self
recognizing the problems of that it
creates and recognizing the solutions to
eliminate those problems that's not
something that's taught openly in the
western culture you know in in Buddhist
culture and in Asian cultures
um it is you know and in the
philosophies it is you know it's because
we don't believe in a self like um
Western philosophies do we don't believe
in this we believe it as an illusory
thing that's created through conditions
you know so in that contest text it can
also be destroyed through conditions so
we don't because we don't believe it's
an inherent thing we believe it's based
off of
dependence through other conditions
hence it being a result so we don't
believe it's something that's there so
we believe it's something that can be
analyzed and destroyed
um versus other religions and other
mindsets they believe this self is there
the soul is special you're special and
that's
I think
personally a a big part of that why in
the Western World we can't disagree
happily we can't be like no that's what
you think well here's what I think and
everyone be like wow that's cool we have
different thoughts we have different
views that's okay you know I mean it's
another thing if we're trying to talk
about him you know
truth because a lot of Western cultures
now think that their perspective is
truth and their truth you know and
and we all know that's not true you know
we your perspective is your opinion
based off conditioning based off
awareness or ignorances that are
developed through your life pattern you
know so then you have this perspective
and until you can recognize that as such
it's hard to annihilate such a thing
it's hard to recognize such a thing as a
problem you know so
you know it's it's a there's a lot of
aspects to it cultural you know and also
plant-based you know and from our
perspective Karma base meaning the
result of our actions you know a lot of
us make a lot of actions in our younger
life eat a lot of poor Foods impute a
lot of negative information into our
brain and then later in life we say hey
we want to do something special we want
to be a good person but we realize
our actions don't align with that all of
our conditioning and all of our study
and all of our work that we put in for
the last however many decades or years
we realized was done towards the wrong
thing it was done towards money it was
done towards success instead of done
towards empathy done towards
open-heartedness done towards compassion
and helping others you know the things
that actually
you know are going to help this world
we can see like someone like Jeff Bezos
you know through this whole cobit
Endeavor he cashed out really hard is he
helping anyone not a person
you know so
all that money all that wealth all that
success
but he doesn't have a speck of empathy
so is he successful he seems like a
troll then you know he seems not even
like he's worth to be alive on Earth you
know because if you have that much money
and success and you don't help and
change this planet you're garbage you
know so I think these things
aren't
being promoted heavily in society where
I think they should you know and I think
that's one thing a lot of us are finding
with this plant is that it kind of
engages this compassionate empathetic
mind in us to where we can see this in
others where we can see people need help
where we can want to help or we can see
this plant's going to help or you know
we can buy more Rolexes a new car you
know show it all off on IG you know like
or we can do with that style you know
there's a lot of different styles you
know but I think it's based more off of
the conditions of society and where
we're headed and where we are versus you
know
and versus the plants influence towards
that I guess
yeah most certainly I think there's so
much of what you said there that I've
been noticing myself recently
particularly that you know a lot of
people yeah never really given a formal
opportunity to learn about how to be
self-reflective and consider where they
fit into the picture and how their
actions influence things and kind of on
that line of thinking I've noticed
recently that at least from my
perspective there appears to be some
medicine coming from an unlikely place
kind of traditionally the sort of
Instagram trolls like clout King and
Stan the Man these guys who historically
I just thought maybe provided a bit of a
laugh recently I feel like they've kind
of maybe inadvertently started helping
people realize this and I noticed this
when clout King came out with some
branded cannabis which he was calling
turds and then another line called kids
and I was like it kind of seems a bit
like sarcastic and ironic on face value
but I think he's actually trying to like
wake people up to like the sort of clout
chasing that we've kind of spoken about
or ready and that you know it's not
exactly the greatest thing what's your
thoughts on them doing that do you see
it kind of the way I do or do you just
think it's just a troll
no I like Cloud King what he's doing I
don't know Stan the Man I don't know um
that reference so I'm not familiar but
you know I follow Cloud King and I I do
a similar thing I like to like you know
bring awareness through me
or whatever you call it meaning
um you know like
what we call in Buddhism there's a type
of debate called reductio reductio at
absurdum where you posit the absurdity
of a scenario or a position
first
so you you basically posit the result of
an erroneous position in the Forefront
and in the in a debate standard when you
do that you basically you take someone's
position they have and you analyze the
result of that position and you put that
up in the Forefront but it's actually
erroneous and kind of absurd so they're
gonna they're gonna attack it
but you do that in a format to get them
to attack themselves you know to them to
negate their own idea so it's a type of
um
type of a debate positioning you know
but the more the reduction is just
positing the erroneous results of an
idea in the Forefront of a debate
so I think a lot of these memes are like
that you know like kind of a not to say
passive aggressive but um more a
subliminal poke you know and we're gonna
they're gonna posit this idea that's
that's stupid basically you know in a in
in the resultant format meaning like hey
it's like this isn't this cool or this
is blah blah blah and everyone's like
that's so stupid or that's all this you
know and so what I've experienced is
that people
you know I'll posit these kind of ideas
as like
you know this is this is this is dumb
it's not cool it's not beneficial for
self or Humanity and a lot of people
will get it and a lot of people get
turned on by it and be like oh yeah
we're down with that but then there'll
be those people they're like you're so
stupid you don't know what you're
talking about you're lame you know just
come into the DM start calling you names
you know it's like wow
um so so I'm totally into it you know
I'm kind of you know I have people even
be like
who is this green Bodhi guy he says he's
a Buddhist and he like does this you
know it's like
it makes me laugh you know I was just
talking with my teacher you know well we
went to the you know we went to Whole
Foods so we can get some coffee filters
you know
so and he needed some allergy medicines
up too so we went over there and we're
laughing um you know we're talking about
this you know talking about how people
think once you're a Buddhist you're
supposed to be enlightened you know he's
like oh even people think with monks you
know even where monk of his Holiness of
the Islam and they were supposed to be
enlightened you know he's all that we're
not supposed to get angry or eat meat or
anything like that he's all so stupid
you know because the reality is is we're
all human and if we were enlightened we
wouldn't be on a spiritual path to
evolve you know we wouldn't have chosen
a path to try to deal with all our
ignorances and our own
you know lame ways of being we wouldn't
have to you know so
yeah so it's it's it's it's an
interesting um dichotomy what's
happening now I think with this whole
woke mentality
spirituality you know you can go do
Ayahuasca in any City in the nation you
know with some wacko wannabe Shaman or
some you know Shaman that some other
wacko like brought here to make money
off of and make business off of it's
like it's sad you know
um but it's a societal Norm right now so
this kind of um
you know these meme Lords that are that
are um sharing their perspective and
trying to shed light on the the
ignorances of our industry and our scene
I think it's awesome I love it it's cool
so that's my perspective of it
yeah and one I can certainly understand
in certain regards
something which I wanted to loop back to
because you mentioned it a bit earlier
was you said you like smoking strains
that are kind of more mentally
stimulating stimulating Clarity and
reflection out of curiosity what are
some of the strains which for you at
least achieve that
um I mean my favorite strain that I'm
smoking on right now is this um purple
Hindu Kush that I got from Mr Bob
Hemphill uh is his uh IG handle
um his genetics company
um with his wife is crickets and cicada
and he's
one of the
um more popular respected and cool
um strain collectors of the last couple
decades so
that's that's actually what I've been
I'm really enjoying right now because it
offers this full range of
what I'm going for from you know
stimulating mindset to also
High satisfaction kind of OG subdued
kind of but it still has this very
stimulating aspect to it
um
so that's what I'm liking on right now
but other than that
um this Sour OG from Amico seeds that's
a
um it's a Hell's Angels OG by sourdes
libel
um that one I crossed the 78 Ogle affi
to making the tens and cushes
those are really I really like a lot
because it's it brings this really
high-end stimulating
aspect but then it still has this chem
OG kind of
satisfying you're there Vibe you know
um the hazy Kush
was is another one that
induces that but that'll induce a type
of euphoria after a half hour or so for
this kind of racy
edgy onset that'll you know some people
love some people don't like it all
because it you know make it give you
that lip sweat give you that kind of
you know hyper anxiety to some degrees
if that's how your chemistry is
um
so those are those are those are the
strains I've really been liking a lot
um for those for those that kind of
Avenue personally
um
yeah
um I'm not really a sativa or an Indica
I'm really focused mainly on hybrids for
what I'm what I'm liking personally you
know
um so yeah a good great answer and some
good starting points for people to go
look into if they're into that sort of
thing I know that I personally love
exactly what you're talking about you
know those mentally stimulating sativas
and for what it's worth
the one I've always really enjoyed which
admittedly haven't been able to have
that much access to was genius from uh
Brothers Grimm that was just a
phenomenal strain for sort of that
mental Clarity just to loop back to a
point you mentioned just before the
initial one I loop back to you mentioned
that
um there's some current sort of debate
around or discussion at least around
whether the origin place of cannabis is
sort of maybe around the Himalayan
region and it got me wondering do you or
have you ever been able to smoke much
sort of Nepalese or maybe even like the
Chinese strains we see and either way do
you want to work with those strains
going forward or are they a bit too sort
of land racy
um I have smoked some of them and um
they're not necessarily to land racy
more and I do have a few things from
China right now and I have quite a few
things from The Nepalese Himalayan
region and then also Laos
um
the
um Bodhi gave me some lawation land race
years back and I popped a bunch of those
and those were very similar to hazy Kush
so I was really shocked you know
um I busted these out and I was like
whoa this is weird smells just like hazy
Kush this is true man it grows just like
a dude this is so weird you know so of
course I crossed that the hazy end of
that too but so
that was um one land race from Asia that
I really did like and I have some things
up from Northern India closer to you
know more on the western side of the
Himalaya obviously but I don't have
I haven't really sourced a lot from the
Tibetan Plateau or from even Siberian
Plateau I have some stuff from up in
Siberia but it's it's you know some
different Autoflower stuff some some
other things that I'm trying to look
through crimerians chimeria and stuff
it's I'm just unfamiliar
um with the history on some of these
things so I don't I don't really know I
started some of it but it was wasn't
what I was looking for so
um I didn't go into work with any of it
too much so
I would um I would like to see a little
more information though on
you know the history of
the gene pool I do know that like what
there's what they're saying from the
Tibetan Plateau I don't even actually
know what strain that is but they're
saying the earliest cannabis Origins
they're it's pointing to there now
um if you research it's pretty easy to
find Google searches of it but um so I
thought that was quite interesting you
know
so yeah certainly I mean it's kind of
always been thought it was sort of
around that area near the Afghan sort of
border with the Himalayas so certainly
seems like there could be some
credibility in that one
just to take us back to the question we
normally ask guests when we start the
episode what are you smoking on today or
what do you plan on smoking on later
today if you haven't already
ah that purple Hindu Kush that I was
mentioning it's pretty much my right now
it's been my go-to
all day all night kind of thing
um so that's kind of yeah I've been
smoking it all day been all night if I
want to mix it up a little bit I'll
grind up some you know
bubble hash in with it and then take
long hits of that
pretty simple
I don't um even though I have access and
I have
you know 30 30 flowers to choose from I
still just put one or two in my jar
and I gave away all the rest and I smoke
those two strains three strains usually
I mean I can certainly vouch that many
of the cultivars in Bob hemphill's
Library are just simply lovely what is
it about this purple Hindu Kush that
you're a fan of because we've heard a
lot of people go to Great Lengths to try
to differentiate this particular cut
apparently it's quite old it's not the
normal Purple Kush that goes around it's
definitely not Jaeger which is kind of
sometimes confused is this purple kush
in Oregon what's your thoughts on this
one is it totally different to others or
just a sort of improved version of the
other purple cushes we see
um well it's kind of interesting because
um you know the first Purple Kush I got
was in
90 92 in in Ridgecrest you know there
were some guys bringing some purple kush
down and there from Oregon and I was
buying a lot of it and obviously selling
my three quarters getting a quarter for
free you know so
um and then just like stacking up as
many quarters as I could so we can all
you know me and me and the homies can
all just puff and rage this Purple Kush
right
um
so from then to now I've had quite a few
different
iterations of it
um and this is by far
you know the best makes um
I mean in my own opinion it makes the
high from Jaeger kind of subpar
um it's very interesting this this train
because it has like a orangey Tangy terp
in it also which is
you know kind of reminds me of tangyland
a little bit but um
it's just more funky more kind of OG
Fury more kind of even like
oh no it just has all these exotic notes
that are just on another level
and the high is just Untouchable I
haven't you know I haven't found
something I enjoyed more to this point
yet right now
um it's one of my favorites and everyone
that I've smoked out with it is in the
same boat they're just like whoa what
was that you know
so it's it's something special
um and then like every time I keep
giving um
uh Mr Rob hampel props on it he's always
like
she's a special one that's all he
replies she's a special one she's a
special one you said that a bunch of
times now she's a special one and it's
like that you know
um so
that's kind of where I'm at with that
and right now
yeah awesome and a good little rundown
In the comparison so take me back what
was your first ever experience with
cannabis
oh that was a long time ago
um I'm 46 now so I was six years old and
I was in Nebraska I was six five or six
years old and me and my neighbor friend
um you know we he lived across the alley
from me in the back and so the alley
away was our kind of like Play Zone and
we were we you know you know back then
in the 80s it and it didn't really
matter you know you didn't have to have
someone watching you you know you walked
home from school you walked to the
babysitter you play it all day until
night you know that kind of vibe you
know
um you know nobody kidnapping kids is
like they are now you know but well it
wasn't I don't know probably just
happening then too but anyway that being
said we're me and my friend were playing
and we see these plants in this guy's
backyard and they were just like calling
us you know I just remember them like in
the breeze moving like I'm always like I
wanted them you know so me and my friend
jumped this guy's fence
um and rip these plants out of the
ground and took them back to my house
you know and then I took them to the
house and I had them you know had one of
those little blue swimming pools that's
in Lincoln Nebraska you know one of
those um and I a little just little
plastic pools that I mix oil in or
whatever you know a little kiddie pool
so if we put all those plants in there
and then filled it with water and then
we were just like tromping around like
kind of like a wine Crush you know just
like my dad goes I was like what the
[__] you know like what's going we're
like what we didn't know what was going
on so that was my first experience with
cannabis you know
um my first experience ingesting it I
think I was I was in Eugene and I was 10
years old and two different times I
remember
um one kid middle schooler kids like hey
John come here try this you know and I
tried a little hit of what he had in a
little pipe and um
and nothing really happened and then the
next time was right around that time
near this place called wiztec or
Cuthbert
um Cuthbert Amphitheater in Eugene near
the UVO Stadium there's there's like
some canoe shoots and there's this kid
there and you know you know a few years
older than me too he's like hey come
here you want to try this I said yeah I
walked over so what is it he busted out
this little foil had some hash in it
with some gold like look like Asian
lettering on it like stamp like tie
probably and he rolled up a little ball
popped in this pipe and me and him
smoked this little bowl and I just went
about my way you know I don't know if I
even felt it then either you know
um so those are my like around that same
time another friend of mine in Eugene's
dad was growing a big field of wheat in
his backyard hemp or something and we
ripped a bunch of those plants out of
the ground and dried them on my roof and
smoked it one
you know I found a found some bamboo
down the way so I cut the you know
segment of bamboo made my own little
pipe this whole thing you know none of
this is that you know I'm just you know
free free-flowing you know I haven't
learned this anywhere my parents you
know my dad was the military all this
but
so maybe it was like past life stuff you
know or something so a lot of it came
very natural you know so what's funny
when in the the my friend's dad that had
the field in Eugene and we just took the
plants out and ripped them right out
fresh but he had the shed that he was
drying all the stuff in and we looked in
there and I remember looking it was all
brown and weird looking so we're like
let's take this fresh green stuff you
know and so those are my those are my
first experiences with cannabis and then
you know it was until I was in high
school
um really before I started um
experimenting you know
there you go and I mean you brought up a
great little segue there in that I had
read online that you grew up as sort of
a military child and um then as a
teenager you kind of started
experimenting with psychedelics how did
all of that play into being a military
child I can only imagine it was kind of
a bit frowned on how did you get around
that sort of obstacle of the family
well
um you know like so basically
you know I wanted to what's crazy I
wanted to be a youth pastor when I was
younger you know so I was like
you know kind of I was going to
Christian Schools training to do that
and then had some really cool
experiences happen and the church I was
going to didn't really um you know they
didn't Vibe with my experience very well
you know so whatever
um that being said my dad was like very
strict military my mom's Asian
um so you know we had quite a strict
household but when I was 18 I was kind
of allowed to do what I wanted
um so you know started experimenting
with everything but even if at that time
you know we're experimenting with
everything because we were out in
Ridgecrest it's out in the Mojave Desert
you know all the kids are boiling PODS
of chips and weed you know like eating
eating like gypsum you know Loco weed
like um you know deter you know
moonflower you know the one the local
weed that grows on the desert yeah yeah
they're they're they're all poisoning
themselves with this these like gypsum
weed pods you know so they're all having
their stomachs pumped having these like
three days psychedelic experiences you
know where you know and the the gypsum
wheat experience isn't a fun psychedelic
experience it's like one where you go
blind and you like could have all these
crazy scary scary trips you know
um that being said so we're you know
we're kind of a weird little town so you
know we do things like drink Robitussin
you know I'd drink like you know
everyone drink one bottle I drink two
you know we'd take boxes of marazine
which is like this motion sickness pill
you eat the whole box you get
psychedelic you know you actually have
true hallucinations you know so this is
like kind of what I grew up around so
we're just continually experimenting
with everything then mushrooms and LSD
and all that stuff and
you know just being a just being like
that kind of kid I think from the time I
was 18 to 23 I wasn't um I didn't have
much agenda I was still wanting to you
know at that point I was wanting to go
into the Special Forces wanting to go on
the Green Berets and try to go Delta and
try to be like a mercenary killer you
know that was kind of my mindset
um but I was out in Georgia and you know
ended up getting a 30 strip of L but I
thought it was a 10 strip because it was
given to me as a 10 strip
um so I cut it in 10 rectangles instead
of 30 pieces and I ate a few of those
and
you know
um had quite the experience obviously
and when I was coming down I was
watching this cartoon called spawn you
know by Tim McFarlane and I kind of saw
my future if I was going to go into the
Green Berets and what was you know I
just it was a very trippy it was very
trippy to see that tripped out and then
so that kind of changed my changed my
trajectory and that's when I moved to
Eugene and
you know just bartending started growing
herb
you know and
stopped bartending only growing her and
that's kind of the all that luckily I
was in contact with quite a few good um
Elders of the Eugene community that
saw something in me and started sharing
literature and information with me that
you know set me on a different path
basically kind of opened my eyes to a
different um
different type of warriorship I guess
you know instead of being like a warrior
that kills people you know a warrior
that like is set out and steadfast for
helping others you know so just
different different I mean even then I
wanted to be the best killer on Earth to
help people you know so the intention
was right it's just the everything else
wasn't you know so
yeah certainly and so I mean growing up
with those Elders influence on you it
must have been a bit of a leg up to have
to not go through exactly all the trials
and tribulations people do when they're
kind of learning the ropes themselves
what were some of the strains that they
were growing or that you were gifted at
the time and what sort of like
um setup were you using was it like just
basic lights indoor give us a bit of a
rundown on how you first started growing
well how I first started growing um
right when I moved to Eugene in this was
a 97 97 I think 90 and a 97.
um I instantly started growing peppers
Habaneros Scotch Scotch bonnet all these
different dad teal all these different
spicy peppers because I had allergies
really bad in the Willamette Valley area
and I was using these peppers I was
eating them just to like deal with my
allergies
and then I put a couple seeds in a
spider plant in my bedroom and I
sprouted and I was like oh I'm gonna
grow these things you know so then I
made this little makeshift closet set up
with like Styrofoam walls and all that
the little light that you know 150 watt
or 250 watt light that's like a you know
a parking lot light you know that you
use for like it was off of a dentist a
dentist office parking parking the
parking lot light you know I used that
and then I had another little
um light that I was using you know and
so and then I built a little makeshift
closet box after this you know my first
run actually with these you know seeds
out of this spider plant and I grew it
all Herm they had seeds it was garbage
you know like stray garbage you know and
I was like I'm gonna do it right so I
built a little box put this light and
then put a 400 watt in there so I had
the 400 plus the 250. and built a little
box in my closet and then I had the
strains that I had there obviously
Eugene was kind of a you know a hub for
good weed so I first started growing
with this train called Trinity
um another strain called Big Sur holy
and then blueberry and blueberry Trend
and another's train called IDK which
stood for I don't know but it was you
know Eugene chronic strain so obviously
Trinity has the lore and the it's like
Legends trained from Eugene for like you
know forever still
um and then the other strains are pretty
apparent
um but uh yeah so that's kind of how it
started and then the second grow after
that little closet I made my whole
closet to grow and just had a trap door
and then you know went from the 650
watts to the thousand watt and then we
went to 2001 then 4000 watts and 8 000
you know and then it's just like that
you know you just keep
leapfrogging up doubling up
that's kind of how it started
yeah fantastic
Trinity is an interesting one because
it's kind of I feel like it's it's one
of those strains where it's like
everyone has super fond memories of it
but no one really kept it on lockdown
and it brings up this idea of like why
do you think it is there are these
strains which people Revere so much but
at the same time seemingly no one was
able to really hang on to a cut or if
there is a cut around now there's some
people who are a bit like oh I'm not
really sure if it's the real one still
how do you think we got to this point
I was the last one in Eugene that I knew
that I had the cut and I let it go
because I thought it was lame after a
certain point you know
um it was having these uh little seed
pods in it you know
um and it was just having some
degradation I think but that could have
just been my ignorance at the time and
me not knowing
how to deal with the plant in the same
way so I let it go because I thought it
was it was boring to me after
you know that many years you know
and the new the new train that's around
definitely isn't that you know the
future Trend definitely wasn't that
um and we got a bunch of Trinity strains
since then that were almost identical
but they weren't that so
um you know a lot of these strains it's
like usually
you know there's a person that's holding
a lot of these once that person decides
to let it go a lot of times it goes away
because
you know people aren't that good at
holding on to genetics
people aren't that committed at holding
on to 100 mothers you know
or just going to have a space just to
keep their staple of genetics you know
that's just
especially now it's kind of rare
I mean I wish I still had that first
Trend but
you know
at a certain point
you get over it and it's not worth
keeping anymore
yeah that's kind of how it is for me you
know like the golden pineapple
um it was it was a great one for a long
time I smoked it a lot now I don't even
want to smoke it you know it's not
something I put in my jar even though
it's
everyone loves it every you know new
smoker loves it every you know just but
it's just not my uh not in the not my
cup of tea anymore
yeah understandably after having enjoyed
something for a long period of time you
kind of look for the sort of new and
better things
I love that you mentioned the golden
pineapple because it's I'm one of those
people you just referenced I love it I
I'm not burnt out on it it's um it's
some lovely stuff is this what you would
consider one of the sort of high quality
genetics which has been around Eugene
for a while I remember I read something
I think it might have been online it
kind of said you moved back to Eugene
and found that there was all these sort
of high quality genetics and clones that
were held by the community around there
was this one of them and what were some
of the other ones that you really
enjoyed from that scene
well I mean like I was saying
[Music]
um
you know I held a lot of these things
and and I was the one that actually
passed the golden pineapple around
Eugene
um I got it from a friend
um there's this person that brought the
brought the golden pineapple to Eugene
on Instagram his um handle his Shad
glass and he's the one that actually
brought that cut to Eugene
and brought it out of Hood River
um
so yeah that that was one of them
um for sure but I you know when I got
that
uh you know
at that time we had a huge amount of
genetics in the town you know
um so like I had you know when you it
was very interesting when you have
certain strains
um and you hold certain strains and
everyone knows you to hold them without
giving them out you can get lots of
strains and people will give you lots of
strains I mean even look at the I had a
strain called the Eugene Lemon Diesel I
brought it down to
um Santa Cruz next thing you know lemon
tree pops out imagine that you know you
bring this strain that's the Eugene
Lemon Diesel to a town
and next thing you know all these
strains start popping out of it you know
and then I found out from my um you know
Santa Cruz cannabis companies all oh
dude
you're the one that brought that that to
Santa Cruz because that's where the the
lemon tree came out of I said oh I know
and you know but a lot of people don't
want to say that you know because it
doesn't sound good for them anymore you
know what I mean that I started selling
the Lemon Diesel out of a dispensary
called creme de Cana out of Santa Cruz
and I brought the golden pineapple down
there too and the Silver Surfer
um and we started selling them out of
their dispensary next thing you know all
these Brands start popping up you know
so it's funny you know
normal very normal
yeah it's interesting to hear that I I
just want to quickly ask we've often
heard that the lemon tree is some sort
of Lemon Skunk hybrid do you think it's
maybe just a relabeled Lemon Diesel that
came from you or do you think there's
maybe some sort of pollination and it
was like a seed from that
oh yeah I don't honestly I don't really
know you know because anytime I've been
around those guys they're super weird to
me so I just assume there's some truth
to something you know so I don't I don't
really know you know what I mean I can't
say but I do know that the lemon tree
definitely isn't the Lemon Diesel
because it's not as good
um it's not even close it is good but
and it grows different too
um grows a little faster a little
bushier you know the the true Lemon
Diesel was was straight Lemon Pledge
lemon rind and
I mean it I couldn't I never smelled a
strain more lemony than that but the way
it grew was this very
slow Stout kind of Afghani style but
like it had the very tight you know kind
of like the Master Kush but a little you
know it's just very interesting but it
grew more missally and
um but very tight very slow growing
very tight to the stock yeah okay so
I don't really know really when um he
told me that I was like oh that makes a
lot of sense you know yeah sure maybe
one day we'll find out the answer
another sort of genetic that I was
hoping you might be able to give me a
bit of a rundown is I've seen you work
with the uh best [__] ever and the sour
best [__] ever this is these are sort of
old school Cuts where the origins are a
bit cloudy you know you've got some
people in the scene who kind of try to
claim ownership over them and other
people just say look it's not really
known and I think we know who we're
talking about yeah I think there's only
one person claiming ownership of this
our best [__] ever and he's a complete
Kook you know so
other than that because you can tell
because this guy will steal like you
know he would he would steal our photos
you know and he would use them on
Neptune's seed bank you know as his own
photos trying to sell the sour best [__]
ever but it was tens and Kush number two
you know and so like anyway yeah so if
someone's willing to steal and use
someone else's photos as their own I'm
sure they did that with that strain too
you know what I'm saying and for my for
my understanding with um you know with
that person and where that who I got the
cut from and how they you know there's a
lot of there's a lot of uh
a lot of a lot of a lot of sinister
stuff around that kind of reality
yeah definitely the thing about it which
hopefully I'd like to get some
perspective from you on is what do you
think are the genetics within it we've
heard some people say that it's a whole
range of different things we've heard
more recently people express it it's
probably just some sort of ogs one where
do you sit on that
well that's what I've been saying
um honestly um you know the person that
uh you know um said is the Lemon Thai by
this that and the other well when I
tested it with philos some years back
you know
um there it wasn't related to any of
those genetics and they said it was an
identical clone of OG Kush it's a OG
Kush clone is what they said but they
also said that with Fire OG ghost OG OG
Kush all that so
um we just we just say it's an S1
because you know I don't think philos
could see if it was an S1 or not if
they're saying it's an identical clone
and I talked to
um you know people about this and
they've agreed so
you know I don't know what to say it
seems like it seems like OG Kush to me
seems like an S1 of OG
that's just kind of how it seems like to
me
yeah sure I think there's definitely a
gathering pool of white to sort of
support that kind of similarly I've seen
that you work with a male that you call
the 78 lafiog and this is interesting
because it popped that name sort of pops
up in other places like there's the DNA
release of La con which sort of alludes
to a similar sort of parent but it might
be different what's this male and what
does it bring to the table for you and
is it the similar sort of one that we
saw with the Bombay kush or it's just a
similar sort of name
um I'm not really sure to be honest I
got the pollen from um
um my friend he goes by Andrew Puffin on
Instagram and he got the seeds from Leo
from Aficionado and they were you know
what they were labeled so
um there's a big story and uh you know a
history of how those seeds were Acquired
and how you know what happened and all
that which I don't really want to get
into it's none of my business and I
don't really know what's true or not so
I don't even want to start to project
you know
um
so that's kind of what's up with that
the genetic pool of it I don't really
know you know we can say it's one thing
and say it's another but anyone that's
talking about it I just it's hard for me
to believe
um because nobody really knows and when
I do genetic tests on it it doesn't hit
the marks that they're saying it is so
you know that's kind of where I've been
at with it
I do like the genetic profile of what
it's offered
um that's for sure so that's why I'm
continually I'm working with it and
that's why I got you know my buddy got
he basically did a seed increase on it
and so we got I got more of that from
him
yeah nice and so how does this play into
or maybe more better put can you give us
a bit of a run down on the back story of
the tens and Kush and how the Genesis of
that sort of came about
Yeah so basically um
so basically
the sauro G from amiko is um I really
liked a lot and so when I got that
pollen I got that pollen
um from someone from Drew and I it was
handed to me in a little pill bottle you
know like a little um just a pill you
know there's a little bit like if you
were to you know as a double lot pill
and it had maybe like a half of a pea
half of a p size worth of pollen in
there
so I basically put that by the golden
pineapple and the sour G and the sour
brush it ever
um and then just pop some seeds out of
it and then every one out of the Sour OG
cross was good every single one
um and so that's why I kind of
grabbing an affinity towards it and
started working with it it's just
because of the I like the high so much
and there's CBD potential in it
um but other than that
you know that was that was the reason I
started working with it to be honest and
then
the reason I started running with it is
because what was being produced on the
female end was so
so awesome I just couldn't um
you know I just wanted to keep going
with it so
started working with some males finding
some good males throwing them buy some
things and getting some good results so
I was pretty happy
nice and I've noticed online that
there's a few different phenotypes you
like I think I remember seeing the
number two and the number four how would
they differ in terms of if people were
going to get one of those crosses and
they're wondering you know what's this
one bringing to the table versus the
other how would you kind of give them
the comparison
well the the tens and Kush number two is
more like a souped up Sour Diesel you
know has a lot of these cab notes a lot
of a lot of diesel fuel notes um but
it's going to be more stimulating even
more than this hour even
um the the richness of it and the
complexity the terpene profile is a lot
more complex you know a lot more lime
nodes a lot more I mean it almost smells
like super glue or kind of um you know
those kind of those kind of um
those kind of uh
those kind of um
notes to it but the tens and floor has
this Sandalwood incense
cush perfume kind of and and it's they
look totally different the tension
cushion number fours purple silver very
beautiful and the tens and two is very
lime green very like um soury looking
you know
um so that's that's that's that's the
difference of them um on that context of
the high on on um the other hand is is
quite different
the um the high on the
tens and four is going to be more OG
more you know Kush Kush La Kush K kind
of vibe High versus the high on the tens
and
two it's going to be more stimulating
more you know cam diesel kind of you
know maybe give someone anxiety kind of
high
oh interesting interesting
on the other end of the spectrum we've
got the more sort of sativa offerings
from you being like the hazy Kush and
the Mystery cush which is kind of built
off that what was the backstory on those
ones and was it intentional that you
wanted to have these two sort of
opposite sort of Flagship strains or it
just kind of came about that way
yeah no it's um it just came about that
way so basically the golden pineapple I
crossed the OG cush Sage from th seeds
into the um this strain called the dawn
or Kid Next Door
um is a classic Eugene's train which was
a um train wreck by purple Affy so I
crossed the OG cush Sage by that grabbed
some males out of that put it to the
golden made the hazy Kush
um and pretty much every single pheno
that came out of that cross was epic and
so then I back crossed it
um and then we popped the seed and we
didn't know what it was hence it was
called the mystery but then if it was
the daughter of the hazy you know so
um the mystery Kush was just or mystery
Hayes was just that it was just
basically the daughter of the hazy Kush
um and that's and that's what's up with
that
so it's just a back Cross of hazy
basically that we didn't know in the
beginning and then we figured it out
through testing and everything
yeah sure
so I mean talking about the back cross
what sort of a male do you want to pick
when you're looking to do a back cross
if you make an F1 hybrid with hazy Kush
and you think all right I'll use this
email from this back cross it to the
hazy cushion we'll get our bx1 do you
look for like the most hazy Kush leaning
mail so to speak or how do you go about
that process of creating that line bread
strain
well a lot of times when I'm doing um
you know so like when I did the the
tensin cross I used four males I pick my
four best males and I use those four
because I wanted to get a a a a a larger
genetic swath swath of the of the gene
pool what was crazy doing that
it felt like I didn't get that I felt
like I got
more
you know
of the same all the progeny that I've
popped they're all very similar you know
so I always I think that's quite
interesting that when I do these kind of
multi-male pollinations
how similar all the strains that come
out of it how all the the phenos that
come out of it are I thought they'd be a
lot different
um
but they're actually usually more close
to the line you know so that's kind of
how I do it personally I pick my best
males and I give more options I don't
really like to pick just one male that's
just not how I do it personally
um
you know I have but that's just not
generally how I do it
okay and do you like to keep males and
when you re-release seeds you're kind of
remaking it in the same way or do you
like to have like a pool of seeds pop
some new ones pick a new mail and sort
of like each offerings its own sort of
unique thing it just depends on what I'm
going for honestly
um you know right now like I I did a
femme line I reverse the hazy and I made
some stuff with that so I'm testing that
right now as one of my first reversal
lines so I'm seeing if they're all good
before I release any
um
other than that you know really I'm just
trying to see and find what I am in tune
with most you know right now
um Bodhi gave me um Larry OG by purple
and unicorn F3 that I'm gonna try to
make some purple OG's with
um so I have that I have an indigo child
male that's from
um mass medicinals that I might throw
into some things and then I have some
other stuff at home that I'm going to
start sourcing some things to find some
males with personally you know
yeah wow it looks like you've got some
interesting options on the horizon give
me a little bit of a rundown about uh
how you first came to befriend with
Bodhi I find everyone's always really
interested in the origins of Bodhi
friendships and I guess what's kind of
interesting is you know with the very
similar names people might have
mistakenly thought there was some
tension there or something like that but
uh I get the impression it's the
opposite
yeah yeah yeah
um
oh I'm wrong I don't remember actually
when I met Bodhi
actually 2000
when we personally met I think it was
2000 what is it 2021 2014 Maybe 13. the
emerald cup
um yeah no and and I the first I'd heard
about Bodhi which is very funny is um I
was in Santa Cruz and I was doing a lot
of work there and I was selling herb to
this spot um Santa Cruz Mountain
Naturals and Aptos you know and and I
went in there and the guy's like hey do
you know Bodhi seeds and I was like are
you [__] kidding someone's like
ripping off my [__] name but
literally I said are you kidding he said
no man his boat he sees he's a [__] G
I was like really I said okay cool you
know and I just like you know I didn't
really do much research I was at that
time I was like oh that's interesting
you know
um but then I did a little more research
and saw like because I was never in the
forums that just wasn't a part of my
thing you know I didn't know any of that
I didn't know that world even existed to
be honest so
um when I found out
um what was funny is I I find out from
all these old heads they tell me about
the forums you know what I mean
um you know my friend Mike he's kagyu or
Coastal seeds and another friend of mine
um you know katsu seeds is uh Bob you
know he's so they're telling me all this
stuff about the forums and I'm like oh
sick and I didn't really know that that
was going on so I was like it was
interesting so then when I was talking
to Steve a lot of sorry um about all
this and he's telling me everything
we're just getting familiar with it all
I was like it was very interesting you
know because it was just it was out of
my league you know it was out of my
realm I didn't know that because I was
in Eugene so I didn't have to go get it
I didn't have to go seek it it was there
I was there you know it was like the
Mecca
of Hattie herb you know so I didn't
there was you know it just wasn't a part
of our wheelhouse but even my friend
katsu sees he was telling me he's all
dude he's all back in the day bro I
would send clones to people all over the
nation through forums I was like what
he's like yeah bro like if she lived in
Kansas City and you want a chem dog
Bubba Kush OG Kush I'll send you all the
cuts I was like 100 [__] Legend you
know so sick but that's what I was doing
in Eugene kind of I was offering people
a lot of cuts you know but that being
said so
you know I mean I mean me and Bodhi
befriended and just we found a lot of
similarities just in Vibe you know we
what was funny is we actually most of
the time when we hang out and we
've these years we don't talk about herb
we talk about travel spiritual practice
different you know philosophic studies
different things you know it's like very
very little little little about weed you
know and um what's so crazy is the one
of the last times I was hanging out with
him um we started talking and you know
as we were talking about Peru and you
know first time I went down there and
blah blah blah you know I was telling I
was like oh I went down to the first
Amazonian Shimano conference and aquitos
you know he's all what so good llama I
was there I said what he's like yeah I
was there I was like oh that's so funny
because that's where I actually had um
come up with my name you know
um he's all yeah man I didn't have the
money to go into the the conference so I
went down to call but I think he said or
went on a different Journey you know I
said that's [__] crazy man because
that's where I come in contact with my
first teacher where I actually spawned
the name greenbody because you know he
was
basically a Crazy Wisdom you know kind
of like the real Don Juan you know his
last Incan Royal descendant of the royal
family basically left everything in
um Peru to go to India took his two sons
to India learned buddhistarma there for
three years under the karma cardio
lineage come back to Peru right so I met
him there and so he was basically
teaching you know the path of wisdom and
Enlightenment through the through the
wisdom plants and the power plants in
association with quantum physics and
buddhistarma you know so I was like ah
you know like green body meaning the
enlightenment that that derived from the
wisdom plants the green you know so
that's the where the name spawned from
that moment so it's like very
interesting all these very interesting
parallels you know and so like
you know we were talking some years few
years for three or four years ago three
years back and I was like oh we should
do a we should do a collab to show that
like that we're different you know and
that but they were like homies and [__]
he's all we should do that you know and
I was like oh we should donate all the
money to it's only this Library Museum
project you know and he's all that
sounds awesome so yeah he gave me uh
four ancient OG males that he had that
he had uh final hunted or someone might
have you know hunted for him I can't
remember those are the best ones he
picked though and he gave me those and
that's what we did that project with you
know
so
um yeah no it's it's it's very
interesting
um because the you know the admiration
you know I have for him and you know we
share it's very uh
it's very cool you know I have a lot of
respect for him and a lot of respect for
what he's done his travels and really
just more who he is as a person you know
that had nothing to do with weed you
know just
you know he's just such a [__] cool
guy that you know he's very likable you
know very sweet guy you know so then
when you start to research like or even
like you know if you just researched one
of his trips you know or one of his
travels you're like whoa It's like
pretty impressive you know
um so yeah you know um
it's kind of the
kind of the the brief rundown of it to
be honest so no brilliant backstory and
I can I can certainly attest he's a very
cool cat he's definitely one of a kind
interesting you brought up the ancient
OG because I wanted to ask you about
that what sort of attributes do you
think that male brings to certain
hybrids and I've always had this
suspicion that like the ancient OG was
such a crowd favorite because of that
mythical Iranian in it have you ever
seen that sort of thing come through in
the crosses
yeah so I mean for me personally that
that's the reason I like it you know the
um
and I'm not sure if it's from the
Iranian that's like that's bringing all
these qualities but
um you know from shape
um you know bud shape to
trichome size to
um you know these kind of
very interesting because you know the
snow Lotus has such a you know prominent
smell that this ancient OG doesn't bring
that to such a degree right
so I think that's what it is right snow
Lotus Iranian land race or something
like that
um and then uh you know so that snow
Lotus you know usually is pretty strong
um it comes in pretty heavy and it
doesn't with this one it's more of the
rainy in it that I'm assuming is coming
in because it's it's something different
than the snow Lotus you know so it's
like
um you know the first first nug I had of
it I enjoyed it so much that I was just
like I was kind of on a hunt for it
after that you know
um
in motherload Gardens did a cedar
increase of it you know so I was gonna
link up with him and get some seeds from
him and try to do a project that and
then I just hit up you know Bodhi and
he's all nah man I got a bunch of males
let's do it with these I was like oh
yeah all right let's do this then so
yeah the it's very it's it's a it's a
cool it's a cool um it's kind of like
honestly what it reminds me of it
reminds me of land race Terps with a
with a new age style structure you know
yeah wow interesting I noticed that some
other strains you were offering were
utilizing the RADS which I believe is a
cut of go geog is that correct
yeah so I have the pine saw on the Goji
Ras that um Bodie gave me some years
back and
that Pine saw I really like a lot the
gojiraz I like it's just a little not my
headspace you know it brings me it's a
little more Indigo head
and that's um that's a little heavy for
me personally just it's a little
tiresome for me so
yeah sure sure
so I noticed in your work that there's
often really interesting sort of crosses
that often utilize sort of plants that
aren't really used in the same way like
I think you mentioned earlier the Tangy
land I've noticed that you've used that
one before and for me personally that
was a strain which I don't feel like you
see it pop up all that often what was it
about the tangyland for example that
made you want to use it was it just a
killer strain and do you in general look
to utilize plants which maybe aren't
being used in other people's breeding
work or it's more just about what the
plant has to offer
oh yeah with the Tangy land the reason I
used it because it had this straight
like burnt rubber
lemon tan G Vibe you know so it you know
it's purple it had this look it had the
smell but um personally you know
whenever I do a lineup or whenever I'm
gonna pollinate I just kind of usually
pick five or ten of my most favorite
strains at that moment and I just
pollinate them you know so it's not
there's not a whole lot of them head
signs to it it's more just like
intuition and what I feel like doing
more than anything
sure and when you make strains in
general do you tend to sort of pollinate
all the females you've got maybe test
them out and see which ones are really
working or do you tend to conceptualize
it a bit more and think oh you know this
female with this male is going to work
really well and make them a bit more
like that on say on paper more so than
just haphazardly
um I think everything I do is kind of
haphazard but um yeah no I mean like
most the stuff I'm trying to line up
together to to make it pencil out in the
end you know so if I'm doing a bunch of
OG's I'm gonna you know do some OG
oriented towards those
um you know I'm not going to try to mix
the turd profiles up too much because I
don't want you know I've experienced
that with the hazy that anything I cross
hazy with would turn into hazy you know
so I was like that wasn't the best with
some things but some things worked out
really good awesome awesome
so when you do make a new strain do you
like to test it in-house do test it with
testers and how many seeds do you like
to see popped if so to get an idea of
what's inside that gene pool
um usually everything I give I give to
two different people my one friend and
um in Peru and he tests a lot of things
down there and then another friend in
southern Oregon that tests um them down
there in the outside environments
outside greenhouse and all that so I'd
like to do a pretty pretty rigorous test
and I
you know like to give it to my friends
and have them run it and tell me what
they think and all that kind of thing so
I'm not just trying to release stuff I
have but that's not that's not what I'm
trying to do I mean the stuff that I
have released without testing I test and
then uh you know just to make sure to
you know I've I have sent some strands
out that I haven't tested but then I've
later tested them and feel good about it
so it's not that big a deal but yeah for
the most part I'm trying to test
everything
um and but me personally you know all
I'm gonna do in my own personal testing
realities is pop ten seeds and if I
can't get a superstar out of those 10
seeds it's not not something I'm really
wanting to release to be honest
yeah sure it raises an interesting sort
of question because for the longest time
there's been sort of this underlying
idea in the community that you have to
test your seeds before you release them
and then more recently we've seen the
Advent of breeders who are open about
the fact they say you know I'm selling
these seeds they're not tested so
they're quite open about it but then
they're still and and like in a certain
regard people are like oh well that's
okay you know you're being upfront about
it
um but then you know when maybe they've
got a bone to pick with that same
breeder they'll then be like well you
don't test your seeds you know and it's
sort of like do you feel there is an
expectation to test seeds or do you feel
like just being honest is more important
and it actually doesn't really matter
what you do where do you sit
well I think being honest is the number
one
thing that should be happening if people
want to risk um you know because I've
just recently sold stuff that's untested
because people wanted it so bad and I
said dude I haven't tested it but if you
want to rock it I'll sell them to you
but I'm just telling you man I haven't
tested them so I don't know and they're
like I don't care dude they just buy
them you know so it's cool you know
honesty is the key you know
um I mean me personally I think
ethically I want to test my gear because
I don't want to send stuff out to people
that's not going to do good
um maybe not going to germinate good I'm
not going to perform good I don't I
don't want that for people
um even if I but if it doesn't perform
good
um because of their conditions then it's
okay too
um you know I have a 100 money back
guarantee not money back but I'll just
replace your seeds I'll give you packs
of seeds if you don't even like anything
you don't like the way it smells you
don't like the way it grew it didn't pop
for you it wasn't as strong as you
wanted whatever you just let me know
I'll just give you new season I don't
care you know it's not a big deal you
know so
um that's just kind of where my ethos is
on that on that
yeah I saw your post on Instagram and I
was really impressed with your return
policy in case people aren't aware it's
just basically saying that no matter who
you got the seeds from no matter how you
came about acquiring them like if you've
got the packaging and you can show me
you know that they were my seeds and
you're unhappy with the results I'll
sort of sort you out with something
going forward do you think that that's a
policy that other breeders should adopt
more so going forward or what's your
thoughts on the way other breeders offer
return policies I know that notably some
breeders are you know quite reluctant to
offer replacement seeds do you feel like
there's a happy medium or do you feel
like your policy is sort of the best
option going forward
oh I don't I don't think I you know
people can do whatever they want it's
not my business what other breeders do
or what other people are doing you know
I just do what I do because that's what
I like to do it that's the way I like to
do it that's what makes me feel good in
the end you know
um
I don't you know yeah what other people
do is not my business I don't know I
don't want to try to make a standard for
everyone how they should think and be
you know that's already happened enough
this last year I think it's stupid
so I don't want to get involved in that
yeah understandable and I mean recently
there's been a lot of discussion over
the past year or so about this idea of
if you buy a packet of seeds are you
entitled to sort of do with them what
you want meaning if you find a male from
those seeds should you breed with it do
you feel like it's okay for someone if
they've bought a packet of seeds to go
ahead and breed with it and because I
think you know we've kind of seen some
breeders who get a little bit upset at
that and it does raise this question of
you know well if you've bought the seeds
like do you truly own them in the sense
that you can do what you want with the
progeny
well don't you I mean you bought them
you owned them it's like that's kind of
how I look at it and I've already given
everyone the pass to do whatever they
want with my genetics and they don't
have to credit me they don't even have
to give me a name they don't have to
give me anything I don't care
they bought it you know do whatever they
want this it's a plan the plant's free
you know
Freedom's free too you know so do what
you wish I'm not the I'm not the boss
and I'm not the GateKeeper you know so
I think people should be able to do
whatever they want with whatever they
own I think they should be able to do
whatever they want in their own mind and
their own actions
um I don't want to be the one that
controls it so when people do ask me hey
man is it cool yeah do whatever you want
rename it whatever you want do whatever
you want
that's called freedom
and I'm into that kind of thing
yeah strong point there I like that
so on a kind of different note I've seen
on your Instagram that there were some
photos I saw of these really impressive
looking plants that were grown in
greenhouses and as far as I was
concerned they look as good as some of
the top sort of indoor you see do you
think that Greenhouse grown product will
become a mainstave the industry going
forward and do you think there ever
might come a time when it gains the sort
of top shelf status over indoor or do
you think indoors just always probably
going to hold that title
well I think um I mean me personally I
think um mixed light greenhouse is
probably gonna be a way of the future
and every level
um because you're going to be able to
advance and get higher trichome
cannabinoid counts when you do a sun
plus mixed lighting because you have the
sun plus you have these other spectrums
that are artificial and that does
something I think even just light
deprivation Greenhouse with proper
climate controlled uh
greenhouses is going to be the is going
to be the future
um personally just because of the
overhead and the P L's and Roi of what
that product is
so
um you know me personally even with all
that Greenhouse herb that was grown so
good it was so tasty it's just and I
smoked a lot of it
I mean
I still prefer indoor that's just me you
know
um but if I were to you know
if I were to have grown the greenhouse
in the same
um boundary of protocol as I would of
the indoor I mean it's just the way the
future really
to have a climate controlled
um non-artificially lit
with artificial supplementation I think
that's just a way of the future honestly
I'm not a fan of outdoor herb meaning
like full season grown outside like with
all the dust and all the dirt and all
the wind and all the conditions beating
on the plant the whole time that's not
really I'm not a fan of smoking that
um personally
um but I'm a huge fan of smoking
controlled climate controlled Greenhouse
yeah certainly and on that topic of
greenhouses what's your thoughts about
big AGS move into the can of space there
seems to be a lot of concern about it
but we've also seen on the other end of
the spectrum that a lot of the Canadian
LPS and some of the American ones have
been kind of going bankrupt like
dominoes in a sense over the past few
years do you think this is a growing
Trend and do you think we do need to be
concerned about big AG moving into the
counter space
well I don't think we need to be
concerned it's going to happen you know
I'm most my products that I buy are from
Big AG suppliers you know so why why
would you buy beneficial bugs from like
your grow store we could get them from a
big AG supplier that's going to be like
a tenth of the cost you know
um why would you buy gallons when you
can buy 55 gallon or you know totes or
whatever it just doesn't make sense you
know and the only way you can get those
is usually from you know big AG you know
um because they're the the housing
housing formats for these you know
so I mean I'm not worried about it I
like I like the I like the big AG influx
to be honest because they have a lot of
knowledge and information of scaling
that just isn't in the Cannabis industry
certainly that's something I try to keep
in mind because I I forget who we're
having a discussion with but we were
talking to someone one time about how a
lot of the sort of
um processes and technology that are
kind of being toted as the the newest
and most improved in the Cannabis
industry we're often pioneered by big AG
in like the 30s or the 40s even
what's exactly what's your thoughts on
the idea that they have a good place to
play in the sense that they're probably
going to end up producing sort of more
of like the Bud Light equivalent for the
Casual enthusiasts and then the older
heads are sort of The Craft Brewers do
you subscribe to that sort of idea
well what I what I see happening is
basically there are some collaborations
happening with with a lot of this
because when when we start working with
um big Ag and we start working with
these bigger bigger companies they're
going to want to work with people like
us because we're going to be the ones
holding the relationship to the plant
information we're going to be the ones
holding all the genetics we're going to
be the ones that can
you know with with their with their
input and with their information and
with their help and our help really
reach new heights of this industry you
know that's just my perspective Mel
certainly and do you think there are any
specific lessons that the big producers
could learn from the small time Growers
and I guess specifically what I'm
interested in is there seems to be this
critical point where at a certain point
in scaling up the quality just
inherently goes down do you think that
there's something the big producers
could learn from the more craft Growers
to get over that or do you think it's
just a problem of scale
um no I don't think it's a problem with
scale personally but the I think the
cultivation aspect is is is
um not something that could that's going
to be hindered so much by scale I think
it's more of the um
more of the processing aspects that are
limited by scale
yeah okay interesting so do you think
that there will always kind of be a spot
in the market for the mom and pop
connoisseur producer or do you think
with the changing laws it's going to
become harder and harder
well it's for sure going to become
harder and harder for the mom and pop
Because unless that Mom and Pop is
working with someone that can take it to
the next level it's going to be really
difficult for them to survive
um that's just how it goes you know and
that's how we've seen in every other
industry if you even look at the whiskey
industry
um with like you know Bourbons or like
you know craft beer it's the same you
know
most mostly's Mom and Pops aren't you
know or even the small craft breweries
they're not Mom and Pops they're
you know a a diva style artist that's
backed by someone with money
you know that so you got this craft
Brewer that's a high-end Brewer and then
they're backed with um by you know a
hedge funder or a friend that's got
money or something like that to take
them to this next level so most these
craft breweries are like that you know
so if we look at that industry
um you know doesn't look good for
the mom-and-pop little grower and Mendo
you know
yeah sure
so do you think that maybe a necessary
step in progressing forward is that
people kind of look to reach out and
make these Partnerships or you know
Foster a sort of more friendly
relationship with other people because
at the moment we see a lot of people
trying to create their own little brand
with a small team do you think maybe
it's more advantageous to try to do
something on a bigger scale in
partnership with other people
um I mean
even like myself if I wouldn't have
um
made the Partnerships that I have
whether they be friends or whether they
be colleagues whether they be whatever
they are if I wouldn't have made these
partnership friendships connections
relations I wouldn't be able to succeed
like I'm about to
um it just wouldn't be possible
it is with the right relations it is
with the right connections
um so that's just how I see it if if
anyone thinks they're going to do it on
their own I mean good luck because how
are you going to fund that we even see
how the California industry pretty much
shut down anyone with under a million
dollars you know
so
meaning a liquid million dollars that
you're able to just throw away you know
yeah that's been a focal point of
discussion on the past few episodes and
most notably we've seen there's a bit of
an exodus of people from California
going to other states notably places
like Oklahoma and a few other places
that have got sort of a more LAX uh set
of rules at the moment do you think
these states will basically continue to
flourish or do you think legalities and
the things which have turned a
California into what it is right now
will eventually catch up with these
other states
no I think some of these states saw that
saw what California did and didn't want
to do that
they saw what happened and they didn't
want to do that they wanted to actually
create business for their for their
state
versus California basically creating so
many hurdles where business isn't going
to happen in the state unless you're
you know unless you got a huge backbone
of cash so
um
yeah it's been really difficult for
people I think that way
are there any states that have kind of
particularly stood out to you as seeming
more kind of welcoming to people who are
looking to get a get their business up
and running or would you say look if
you're doing it now just do it where
you're at now and just do a good job
I mean Oregon Oregon it's been pretty
easy Most states that are happening now
are pretty easy Oklahoma's really easy
um you know obviously in Michigan you
know New York's gonna pop off soon
Florida these places are you know but a
lot of them are they're hurtled through
licensing hurdles you know
um
so I mean for me personally
I mean I don't I don't I'm not telling
anyone to get into the industry to be
honest because
you know I don't think it's a good play
unless you've already figured it out
you know or unless you're coming with
something new or something hot to the
market
I mean a new brand really now it's a
little late I think you know
yeah for sure
so something I wanted to chat to you
about is that you are a passionate fan
like myself of Organics so I'd love to
know what is your recommendation for
someone who's looking to get into
Organics maybe they're transitioning
maybe they've never grown before what
sort of a base setup you might recommend
to them and do you um you know follow a
particular style of Organics or are you
just kind of a mix and match and use
what you like
well I um I mainly use dries but I'm
coming out with my own line and my own
soil line so that's what I use right now
is I'm using all my own products that
I'm in collaboration with another
company that I won't mention here right
now
um I guess until we release you know but
we're all in licensing process right now
of offering uh you know a start to
finish soil and uh you know three-part
pelletized nutrients some um you know
liquid
um cold extract
Forest hummus
liquid product you know these kind of
things that are
basically that's my that's what I use
now I use that with a couple other
products you know I use a you know a
liquid food compost and then um that's a
liquid I use and then I use um em
also so you know just basically pretty
simple Organics but
um you know a lot of dry amendments
very little products I mean I don't
think you can buy any of the products I
use from the grow store so everything's
either on bulk bulk AG or you know these
type of these type of genre
all organic though dry pelletized or
like I said um you know em is a
basically like a super lab you know with
a bunch of other probiotic reality to it
um you know and then the liquid food
compost this hydraulic hydrolyzed food
compost they add enzyme too and break
down the food compost and make a liquid
nutrient with it so
so that's the basics
yeah brilliant and do you think that
Organics can be utilized or even
automated such that it can be used by
bigger facilities because this is a sort
of idea we've oh for sure heard yeah
we've heard a lot of people say that you
just don't see it happening do you see a
day where there will be you know a big
producer who utilizes no-till or
something like that
well I mean like even our ours is a
somewhat no-till but yeah like
honestly it's you're gonna have to love
the plant you know because this Organics
thing isn't for the money it's for the
love of it and the the P L and Roi of it
works and it can scale heavily
um if you know what you're doing if you
don't for sure you're gonna fail
um and you're not going to produce what
you need if you know what you're doing
then you're going to succeed
um I think it can uh
you know the thing is just the yield of
convention is is better you know so
you're going to get more you're going to
get more more herb with uh chemicals you
know and I haven't been able to get more
weight out of Organics yet
um I've been able to match it and I've
been with through LED and all this kind
of stuff but
um I haven't been able to surpass
um conventional
uh weights conventional cultivation
weights with Organic [__]
um but I won't you know personally I
don't ingest anything that's grown with
conventional salts and all that so I
mean even if I grew with that I wouldn't
be able to smoke it so
um you know that's just what's up I only
I personally only smoke organic herb um
I usually 95 of the time eat only
organic food so obviously unless I'm
going to a restaurant things like this
you know so that's just how I this is
how my makeup is
yeah certainly I I subscribe to the same
sort of ideas and trying to eat organic
where possible and you raise this sort
of interesting idea in my mind that a
lot of people who grow organic tend to
become more conscious of these sort of
things about the types of food they're
ingesting and trying to get more
nutrient dense food or inputs wherever
possible and I think it was even Bodhi
who said that you know Organics can be
like a gateway to just gardening in
general do you agree with that do you
find that you also tend to just grow
potatoes and you know just whatever it
may be because you've learned about how
to grow organically with cannabis or was
it the other way around for you or how
did that work
um it was kind of the other way around
for me I learned to grow I mean Eugene
if you had you know camweed like Hydro
grown weed in Eugene you're like looked
down upon you know if you didn't have
like the dankest organic herb you
weren't like anyone in Eugene you know
that's kind of just how the vibe was
there you know it wasn't like you're
busting out you're like oh man I got
this Hydro dude check out this hydro
weed it's so dank that just not what's
not happening you would be at last at
there you know
um that's just how the culture was there
you know so this is different you know I
don't know it's interesting you
mentioned that because in places in
other spots in California and around the
world you know for the longest time you
know I got that Hydro was touted as
being the bee's knees but I feel like in
the last few years at least in the sort
of educated consumer's mind the indoor
no-till organic cannabis has become
synonymous with the highest quality have
you found this to be true in your
experience
um I mean I'm still waiting for people
to give me a jar of weed that's danker
than my jar of weed I don't know I'm not
saying that I got the best weed by any
means but I sure would love someone to
give me a jar that's better so I can
smoke it okay interesting and then I
want to and I want to be friends with
that person
yeah definitely I mean have you ever
been given any Jaws that were
particularly impressive maybe not better
but just still quite impressive
people don't usually give me weed for
some reason I don't understand why
ah there you go all right people we're
putting the call out I mean I have one
friend that um is from Eugene that I I
always enjoy deserve and his herb was
always dank um he's a good buddy of mine
Brent his uh IG handles fanario Farms
um and
I gotta say that in Eugene I feel like
we're the
two of the better you know organic
Growers over the last couple decades
there and I think you know we're still
two Brands kicking out of that town
still so they must have meant something
for all those years
certainly and you raise another good
little segue here and that I noticed in
some of your crosses you utilize the dog
walker OG which was made by a friend of
the show one eye who's also based out of
Oregon and it got me wondering do you
find there's like networking and
friendships within the Oregon Community
are you friends with one eye for example
or
yeah I love it she's cool if he's he's
cool as [__] yeah for sure rich is a
good guy um I mean it's a it's a tight
scene everyone knows each other I'm not
to say everyone gets along with each
other because there's a lot of um weird
jealousies and envies and you know
obtuse perspectives based out of
ignorance and all that kind of stuff
just like normal Humanity you know
and then you know how Oregon is
everyone thinks they're the best at it
and everyone thinks they're the you know
what I mean got the best or do the best
or whatever you know it's a weird weird
area and they wanted to you know they
want the best for the cheapest that's
Oregon you know
that's like that's old old people buying
packs right
well I mean it's even in the like you
know any any anywhere it's like that you
know yeah most people don't even most
people don't even know what good is
National you know that's just how it is
I've seen I've seen all the I've seen
work herb you know I've seen boxes on
boxes on boxes of the most exotic hype
herbs it's like whatever and it's
[__] garbage so it's like
you know I don't know what's happening
you know so you raised an interesting
point which I was discussing with a
friend a few years back in that we're at
a Grower's Market in Downtown Oakland
and he had a jar of headband from Bob
Hemphill and he also had a jar of some
wedding cake from someone else and the
the wedding cake it had the look it had
the Aesthetics it was Frosty but there
was no Terps to it it didn't leave a
lasting impression it was really kind of
quite lackluster in a certain regard and
yet the headband it hit you in the face
with these loud Terps it was the real
cut it just had everything you wanted
from a headband and yet my friend was
saying to me you know these jars will
sell for the same amount and I thought
to myself how can that be like the
headband is clearly Head and Shoulders
above this wedding cake and he was
saying yeah but you know the average
consumer they're used to that headband
smell they've smelted over the past 10
years a bunch of times and the wedding
cake it's all the bee's knees and the
rage online at the moment so my question
is how do we go about educating the
community or the Casual Enthusiast if
this is the sort of dynamic we're
dealing with at the moment
well that's the thing is people are
uneducated and they're not going to get
educated because there's only honestly a
few places in the world that have
cannabis education on um you know
high-level Organics or culture or
cannabis culture all that kind of thing
it's pretty slim you know NorCal from
Santa Cruz to NorCal to Eugene not even
Portland I would say but Eugene
um
I mean there was a culture that was
happening there for a long time
especially before weed was legal
everywhere you know so that culture is
something that's not going to happen
anymore and only few people have that
perspective and understanding so of
course it makes sense why
all this everyone doesn't know you know
how could you think uh you know a gelato
cross that's grown with salts that has
no Terps is better than a good headband
you know
or whatever you know or a good OG or a
good you know it's just
it's just there's just it's lack of
Education you know lack of understanding
and lack of perspective
that's just my perspective you know
yeah sure
so I mean on a different note what would
be some advice for an aspiring breeder
this is a question we commonly get asked
by the fans how would you recommend
someone go about getting their foot into
the scene and maybe getting some crosses
out there to the masses
oh I don't know I mean I would
I wouldn't I wouldn't suggest people to
start breeding to be honest you know
not to make money if they want to breed
just for their self and getting getting
seeds out there I think they should just
pick whatever intuitively they like the
best
whatever they strive for the most
and do that again on the male side blend
them and like start just making stuff
and giving seeds out and you know doing
whatever they can to get seeds out but
not to make money you know I wouldn't I
wouldn't suggest anyone to get into
breeding right now
it's pointless
yeah okay so it's a bit saturated in
your opinion well I mean you can imagine
some new
strained person or new breeder that's
going to be new and doesn't have any
track record history you know street
cred or any of that trying to make a
business out of that I don't know you
know
good luck
I don't know and I would I would I I
just don't suggest it personally I
suggest if you want to breed right now
just breed for the love of it and
you know and if you want to do it for
the money then don't you kind of raise
an interesting point which we've
discussed a little bit in the past in
that is it possible for someone to get
in the industry now coming to the game
so late specifically I often hear this
referenced in regards to like Vape cards
and maybe products which in the past
there have been a little bit of shady
practices you know is it possible for
someone to start a company trying to
make a product like that or trying to
sell cannabis or breed seeds with good
intentions or is it just simply like the
boats left
foreign
I mean I personally think the boat's
left but that's just that's just me you
know I mean if you're if you got a huge
hedge fund and you have unlimited money
and you want to throw you know quarter
million half a million at branding and
you want to like do it like that I'm
sure you can make it you know
because we all understand it's all
Optics right now right
um so if you're if you got the money to
Brand hard and get into those Optics I'm
sure you can happen no problem but
um no one that's from the street or no
one that's from the industry that's
known anything is going to care
and give you respect that's just how I
see it but
yeah certainly and I mean it's a tough
crowd out there you know
[Laughter]
certainly and on that topic of a sort of
changing landscape I've noticed that the
breeding landscape itself is starting to
change a bit and we're beginning to see
breeders like for example jbezi a step
away from seed selling is the Main
Avenue and more so looking into
licensing their Cuts or their sort of
cultivations to different facilities do
you see this as something which will
continue to happen going forward and do
you think we risk maybe getting to a
point where home Growers are kind of
finding it hard to get good quality
seeds if that continues
well I think it's hard already to get
quality seeds I mean I've I've tested a
lot of stuff and the reason I'm I'm
doing what I'm doing is because when I
test a lot of gear and try to find good
stuff it's hard for me to find you know
so
um you know that's just my perspective
so I started doing it myself and doing
what I wanted myself and trying to you
know make things out of my own intuition
and all that
um you know so I think it's pretty hard
right now for people to you know find
good seed honestly you know I think it's
hard to find good genetics I think it's
hard to find the truth you know it's
easy to find
whatever but it's hard to find the good
stuff I think you know
unless you're unless you're working with
some some good old trusted people you
know
and
you know those are those are those are
and the industry very obvious they're
very easy to find it seems like
there's a there's a couple handfuls of
really
quality good people that are breeding
and and and they got the they got the
credentials to back them most of them
while we're talking about that sort of
you know bigger facilities and working
with things like that have you ever been
to facilities and found certain
cultivars that you think really work
well in a sort of bigger monocropped
environment and if so which ones would
you recommend
well I mean really any any columnar
style you know
plant is going to do good in a you know
giant sea of green or scaled outgrow you
know it's pretty much like uh
low uh low low BRAC the leaf ratio I
mean low low uh Leaf to Brack ratio and
high testing and you know
medium medium speed growing and it's
it's just a you know
most of my breeding I'm trying to select
for certain things like trimming and
these kind of things so not trying to
grow breed a bunch of leafy stuff that
doesn't have a high cannabinoids you
know
so
um on the scale level though I think
that you know a lot of the designers
trains right now I mean there's a reason
they're being grown the way they're
being grown you know they do well in
those conditions for sure
I mean all that you know gelato cookie
cross kind of stuff it's uh
you know grows good in that style
yeah I mean you just mentioned that some
of the traits that you're breeding for
being like you know ease of trimming and
things like that if you had to list in
general some of the traits that you
think are advantageous and you look to
have within your projects what would
they be
um terp profile cannabinoid um
cannabinoid production then structure
trimmability you know
Brack the leaf ratio all that kind of
stuff for my
really specifics you know almost in that
order
you know deter profile and cannabinoid
content those are equal for me and then
um they both have to be awesome and then
structure
of the plant
trimmability
that's kind of in that order
really the trimmability and structure
are equal and you know uh cannabinoid
inter reality are equal to me they
should be taken in account equally
that's just my perspective
yeah nice nice list of traits there that
you look to work into your lines I
noticed that you did some Femmes where
you reversed the hazy Kush onto some
other females what sort of results did
you find from these crosses and did you
find that the hazy Kush was kind of
dominating or a bit more passive and let
the other strain shine through
they're right in the middle of testing
right now I think I'm about five five
five five six weeks in flowering right
now so
it's all starting to show
are there any that have sort of caught
your eye early on or still yet to be
seen
there's quite a few what was sad as I
reversed the Luke Skywalker OG
um and I crossed it by the purple Hindu
Kush thinking I was gonna make this you
know make the infamous epic Purple OG
instead I got a bunch of Herms
like everyone almost herbed out of it I
was like whoa
[Laughter]
so anyway life yeah right I guess
there's something within those two that
just don't compute but on that topic do
you think that breeding with mothers
that come from Femme seeds or even s1s
are more likely to make The Offspring
unstable I mean I think it has that
potential for sure everything everything
where the potentials there is going to
give that um give that expression in
some way or another
sure in a sort of hypothetical question
I've been asking guests lately is this
let's just say you made a strain and
it's producing the most amazing progeny
you've ever seen like without fail the
best you've ever seen But the catch is
there's like 40 Hermes in the line would
you at that point think you know I just
go to 86 this project or do you think
you know I'd release it I'd just warn
people what to you is an acceptable
limit of Hermes if it was a really fire
strain
um I don't know I wouldn't release it if
it was herming that's just me
yeah sure
I just that's just I'm I'm just don't
want people to experience that I don't I
don't think people are up to par in
their cultivation skills enough to catch
it so I don't want to put that on them
um I wouldn't want to be responsible for
that
sure sure I mean if I were to have
something and 40 of them would be harmed
just like this lsog where 80 of them
were harmed with the purple Hindu Kush I
think two of them weren't so I'm growing
those two out still you know I'm hoping
they're going to be really sick clones
you know like clone only Elites or
something you know so they're not going
to get released but they're going to be
in the in-house yeah okay sure so maybe
like the middle ground is if you find a
stable clone release the Clone
yeah if you were to you know cool okay
so something which caught my eye on your
website was that you have a nice
write-up about the Platinum Girl Scout
cookies and you kind of talk about how
that's the Girl Scout cookies you
commonly use and it got me wondering
what is it about the Platinum that
really draws you towards it as opposed
to the Myriad of other cookie cuts
well I mean the reason I just I'm I'm
using that cookies cut is because it was
the first cookies cut you know so
and you know I just got it as Girl Scout
cookie I just I just called it Platinum
you know
um because it was there's a bunch of
different cookie Cuts going around but
my friend gave me that cut right when
cookies came out and um his name's Alec
Dixon and he owns SC labs and you know
he got that cut from the boys right when
it right when it started going around he
gave it to me so that's that cut so I
just called it the Platinum but it's I
think it's just the original Girl Scout
to be honest
okay and the are there any traits about
that one which you think make it sort of
stand a little bit ahead of the others
yeah the tricome production the Vigor
the
um the the smell the funkiness of it
it's just like just rank it was like
rank skunk Fuel and cookies you know so
it was like
it was like that smell plus it was just
stronger than the other ones that I've
seen you know so and I noticed that you
had done a crossover with the illusion
OG which I believe is a strain from
compound genetics what was the story on
that cross and what drawed you towards
the illusion OG to use that as a male
well just this genetic profile and from
my understanding it's um why use
genetics um Jeff you know Jeff was the
main breeder for compound before that
debacle happened and um you know from my
understanding Jeff from why East was the
one doing all the breeding and doing all
the Fino hunting and doing all the
selecting and throwing all the pollen
and collecting all the genetics and all
that so
um so anyway
um
so that was actually from um from from
from why East from Jeff from y East you
know
so yeah even though you know there's you
know there's always lots of controversy
with this kind of thing but
for me it's the person that collected
the genetics through the pollen and grew
in their house is the owner
so
all that points to why yeast
so credit credit to waste I wouldn't
want to not give you credit where
credit's due well I mean it's just it's
a it's just you know how it is and this
this this game where people break up and
you know
leave people off of trademark apps and
do different things and try to steal
different things do different things
it's an interesting industry you know
yeah yeah I think it was James Bean who
mentioned to me the other week that uh
as far as he can recall swamp boys are
the only sort of breeding Duo that have
managed to stand the test of time and I
think he might be right
yeah I don't really know but I think
they're still friends right
you know that's it that's it that's what
they're still they're still together so
I don't think uh
it's pretty rare
yeah certainly so yeah I mean shout out
to Jeff for making that one was there
anything about the illusion OG that Drew
to it I think did you just say it was
the traits of it like what were they
I mean
the the the ogs and cams all up in it is
kind of what what uh why why I use it to
be honest you know that's just those are
my those are my those are my faves some
of those things you know so I just
wanted to use it you know
um
and there were some um the reasons I did
it too you know what I mean I was pretty
unhappy with what happened on um with
that whole breakup just not that it's
none of my business but you know I've
just been treated like that from other
people so you know
the ghost OG Skywalker gsfv chem dog
sour it's like those are all my
favorites so I was just like yeah I'll
use this and so when I talked to Jeff I
talked to him I said hey Jeff man what's
up I said I said I got this
um from Chris uh but who who did this
you know who grew who grew this who grew
this he said I did I said where who
selected the strains who selected the
cuts who who grounded up the genetics he
said I did I said where was it grown
he's all grown in my house my garage I
said who threw the pollen he said I did
so you know those were enough I did to
me you know
yeah and I know yeah so that just you
know what I mean
yeah it's just I just gave credit to
where credit was due in my opinion but
that's just my opinion it could be wrong
too so I'm not saying I'm right
I'm just saying that's the reason I did
it
yeah
so I mean on a similar sort of note I've
noticed that you know you're a sort of
friendship and collaborative network is
very expansive and it got me thinking
you would definitely have access to a
just a you know plethora of strains
which you know many people could only
dream of getting and it got me wondering
can we ever expect to see any sort of
old school meets new school strains from
your work maybe the likes of like a land
race crossed to one of your males like a
Malawi or an Acapulco Gold I think for
some reason in my head it just I just
sort of expected to see something like
that and it got me wondering well maybe
maybe it's in the works where it's yet
to happen what's your thoughts yeah my
my friend um Bob he gave me some
genetics he's going to give them to me
again because some of them didn't make
the make the make the journey but um you
know there was some land race stuff that
I was going to collab with him in and
you know and vice versa
so yeah there's that's that's in the
works too for sure and I got some stuff
from um
you know
yeah it's in the works for sure I'm just
kind of um honestly a lot of I'm not a
lot of my stuff I'm making I'm trying to
make stuff that I'm gonna be like oh I'm
so psyched on I'm actually not that's
kind of selfish but I'm not really
breeding for
you know I'm reading for everyone else
meaning I'm going to be the one to
select it through my own intuition but
then I'm just assuming other people will
like it because I'm the hard-headed in
the in the um tolerance level you know
so yeah no I think that's a common sense
what we've heard from guests on the show
is that they tend to breed for
themselves and you know the the crowd's
favor tends to follow that that's sick
something I wanted to ask you about
because I thought it was kind of cool in
a way was the mystery Kush I liked that
in the sense that I felt like it was
sort of a misnomer of a name because you
you obviously know what it's made of you
made it
um what was the story around that one
and why did you decided to give it the
name you know the mystery when you know
it's it's made from hazy Kush
well like I was saying I didn't know
actually which one which what the mail
was
I had the seed but I didn't I didn't
actually it wasn't positive you know
until I tested it all so that's why it
was mystery but I'm like man this smells
just like this hazy Kush now I was
calling mystery Haze you know and then
when I found out it wasn't a mystery
anymore it was obviously it was it was
obvious you know
sure and how would that one differ if
someone was kind of toying between
getting those two how would you describe
the differences
um I mean the hazy Kush is much more
complex
um to me much more desirable
um but the look and the appearance of
the mystery is just so
you know desirable on that end
I don't actually don't like the high of
the mystery that much personally
um comparatively to the hazy Kush is one
of my favorites
sure
so I noticed on your website that it's
kind of geared a little bit more towards
what I felt was sort of like a
management or sort of Consulting role
for potential clientele is that
something you hope to get into in the
future in terms of like helping
facilities with their cultivar selection
and whatnot and where do you see
yourself in the future in the industry
oh well that's a big part of our future
to be honest because because you know
we've created the conditions we're
working on this new light that's
basically um you know I've tested a lot
of LEDs in the industry now and this one
pretty much crushes all of them to
Pieces there's not even a comparison and
it's got a pathogen preventative
um
on it too so it's
I mean it's on another level so I'm
really excited to release that
um and then we're going to release that
with a full spectrum of you know
Consulting
genetics the whole bit and we're we're
positioned pretty heavily to do that
with our partners and with our group so
we're just being patient hitting it at
the right time hitting at the right
moment and in the right way do you see a
day where maybe greenbody genetics are a
little more rare and harder to find
because you're sort of more wrapped up
in that side of things or do you hope to
sort of be able to offer both well I'm
hoping to offer both because I think
they go hand in hand and as the markets
come on and international markets come
on you know there's going to be a lot of
things happening we got a lot of stuff
working in Jamaica right now with some
partners and we got a lot of stuff
getting ready to start happening that
we're going to start potentially doing
some International seed distribution
either out of there or out of Canada or
you know it's like there's a lot of
stuff getting ready to start happening
so we're really excited about all of it
that's that's awesome to hear and sort
of exciting stuff
something which I've been talking to a
lot of guests about recently is there
seems to be a bit of like a cognitive
dissonance that like if it's in a fancy
package you know sort of reflective
mylar bag that it's got to be the
highest quality do you think that people
will ever maybe learn to dissociate the
packaging from the actual contents or do
you think that's just marketing and
you've got to roll with it
well I think it's both you know we
understand how marketing is right now
you know you look at alcohol how things
are packaged it's you know it makes a
difference you know you look at even
these CBD lines in CVS or any like these
you know these stores you know it's the
one the packaging is what's selling it
it's not the product you know they're
all the same product so if something
says Charlotte's Web on it versus
something says something it's going to
sell more you know
yeah sure I mean we see that cookies is
continuing to expand and release more
and more product onto the market notably
they've been Outsourcing some of their
crops to other producers and we've seen
the odd issue with quality control do
you think that these companies might
risk sort of shooting themselves in the
foot by trying to sell an inferior
quality product or do you think that
their fans are sort of loyal to the
brand and not necessarily the product
well I think cookies is a unique brand
in that context because there's a lot of
brand loyalty and you know it doesn't
matter what they put in the bag it's
gonna you know the people are gonna buy
it because of The Branding they've
pretty much crushed The Branding reality
you know they did really well
um and you know and they're good guys
you know so like a lot of people have a
lot of stuff to say about them but they
don't know these people you know
um you know they're good guys so that's
I've met them they're good people you
know they're cool you know so
um they might have had some hurdles with
some different genetics or different
seed sales or different this that and
the other but you know from what I'm
seeing their branding level and what
they're trying to do in the industry is
pretty professional and every which way
so you know I don't know it seems like a
bunch of Envy more than anything if
people are crushing it you're gonna have
haters and that's the big sign you're
crushing it too you know
um so
you know I mean we we have some we have
some stuff in in future with cookies and
stuff too so
um I think people should be excited
about that more than anything that's
happening now you know
once we start throwing you know golden
pineapple to Georgia pie and stuff like
that and you know
putting putting our Twist on these
things I think that's when people start
getting really excited but you know
maybe I'm just self-centered in that
perspective
wow that that's really exciting to hear
that you've got that sort of
collaboration down the pipeline I know
that you've done collaborations in the
past are they the sort of thing that you
want to pursue more going forward
yeah collaborations are fun a lot of
stuff happens and it's good branding you
know
it's um so all those all those
conditions are kind of the
the conditions you know I like it
sure and I know that I've heard a bit
recently about a collaboration you have
with Mass medical strains where can
people find those seeds or when can they
expect to be able to get them if they're
after them and what sort of plants do
you feel those crosses offer
well well-grown seeds is going to be one
of the big the big hubs for that those
collabs well-grown seeds cool beans um
you know so um
yeah I mean you know masses mass is a
cool kid you know and a lot of people
have um you know well not a lot of
people there's been specific few people
that have tried to bully the kid and
that's one of the reasons I um I jumped
on you know because I don't like bullies
you know and when I was younger I used
to like beat up bullies you know so now
I'll just make fun of them on Instagram
instead you know for being bullies you
know for bullying a kid that's you know
trying to do good things and he's a good
guy you know and doesn't and he didn't
do the things that these people are
saying he did so I wanted to make uh you
know
make it known and that's the reason I'm
collabing with him is because I don't
like people bullying kids you know it's
not it's not cool so
um you know I think the collaboration
between us and what we're doing and the
the the the the strains coming out are
going to be quite unique you know um
very colorful
um obviously rich and Terps on a
multitude of levels and they're just
gonna be good vibe seeds you know where
people are just trying to do good things
and you know help people and do good
stuff and so that's kind of um you know
and a lot of those things are going to
be really neat coming out of those
crosses I think you know just the color
the color really is
he's good at bringing in that color and
I think the combo with the with with our
strength and high octane profiles with
his um you know color and terp realities
are gonna are gonna are gonna make some
cool combos you know
yeah that's that's exciting to hear that
the uh the crosses are offering such you
know desirable characteristics something
which I heard interestingly sort of
mentioned and I specifically wanted to
ask you about this was that someone said
to me oh you know the the reason why he
decided to not retire and come back was
because greenbody convinced him not to
that's true
anyway
another bit of speculation that I've
seen from numerous sources was that he
came back for more or less financial
reasons you know regardless of whether
that's true or not is not really what
I'm interested in more so what I'm
interested in is this idea of the ethics
behind breeders releasing seeds for
profit intentionally every breeder is
selling their seeds to pay the bills
like why why is that like a point of
contention do you feel like at times
people just pick points to criticize
because they've just got a bone to pick
like you know people will sell seeds for
500 a pack and people don't really get
as up in arms as about you and Mass
medical selling some seeds for what's
arguably probably a much more reasonable
price do you think that there is this
sort of vitriol in the community
oh for sure for sure you know it's like
mass will sell out a drop in like one
day you know so of course that makes
these old breeders that can't sell their
seeds mad and jealous and envious right
I mean just uh I could I can go on for
days about this kind of topic but um
so yeah I know um Mass was just um
you know he was getting sick of it you
know he was getting sick of people just
hating on him and for no reason really
you know like because even the the
reasons that were given to me by the
person stirring up the pot the most
you know he told me he screwed over
Bodhi this person told me that mass
screwed over Bodhi seeds you know so I
asked him I said hey bro what's up is
this true he's all no that's not true I
would never put myself in a position to
be screwed over that's what Bodhi told
me and I said thank you
and then so then I said ah these guys
are full of it and you know what they
kept trying to they kept trying to
because this guy you know mass is um you
know he he was um doing this
fingerboarding thing when he was younger
and he started a company he was selling
like fingerboards and stuff and they
kept trying to like pick on him for that
you know oh he's this person he's that
person he's he's like so what you know
really you guys care that much about
this kid you know like what's your
problem you know and then it seemed like
everyone was bullying him so I just was
like oh yeah well you try and Bully me
then you know so then I jumped on jumped
on board with him you know so if
everyone wants to bully then they can
bully him they can bully me you know
that's kind of why I did this you know
and if anyone wants to bully him or
anyone wants to be that kind of guy well
I'm down to go to my jits gym and we can
have a you know live IG like jits battle
in the gym and you know we'll see then
you know who's a bully you know I don't
I don't know I'm not a fan of people
picking on kids you know I'm not a fan
of people picking on each other you know
that's that's BS you know so if you want
to pick on people then you can pick on
people that are that are that will
welcome it you know in front of
everybody you know and so I made those
you know I made that very clear in the
industry that I'm you know willing to do
whatever you know and then seemed like
everyone just got kind of quiet then for
some reason
so it worked yeah I definitely have seen
a lot of what you mentioned there which
is really interesting and it kind of
raised this broader idea which I really
disagreed with which was that with that
fingerboarding comment in mind people
were like you know he's had this
successful company in the past and he's
just come into the Cannabis scene to
make money and it made me think like is
it not possible to have been successful
in another business Endeavor and then
come to the Cannabis scene because as
far as I could tell that was what was
going on but people tried to make it out
as though like well because you have
this successful business in another
industry you're definitely here just to
sell out
I mean who cares what people think for
one
I know for sure that mass is in it for
the right reasons you know and of course
he's gonna do it and make money too
because that's just normal you know it's
not bad
um your intention is what makes it bad
you know if you're doing it just to make
money then that's not the best you know
but that's not what he's doing it for
I've talked to him for hours and hours
and hours and you know we go back to
that thing where someone said oh green
body got him to you know get back into
the industry well I did I told him that
he shouldn't have jumped out it makes
him look bad and he's innocent he didn't
do anything wrong you know there's not
one thing he did wrong not one you know
no one's been able to prove anything
they just try to pick on him for this
fingerboarding thing and it's like dude
you guys sound like those bullies that
I'd like to like knock out you know for
picking on my friends you know like stop
you know and I mean that's that's where
how this whole sale hating thing came in
you know it's because it's basically
that's a strain that's a collab strain
the hazy Kush with the putang is sale
Hayden and the reason it came about was
because I got tagged into
um because someone was like
well this green boat he's working with
mass and you know this this dude hates
Mass you know and so they tagged me into
his page and I said ah I said I don't
know all this bickering and all this um
this uh
gossipings above my pay grade I said you
know and I said by the way
I said who cares anyway about what I
think you know I said my seeds suck my
genetics suck my weed sucks don't buy it
you know I said I'm the [__] devil
actually
and then um that's all the only time I
commented towards all this and then
someone commented a few a few a few uh
comments down and said sail Hayden and I
was like what are they like making fun
of me I didn't even understand what the
[__] it meant you know I'm like sale
Hayden sale hating oh I I took me a
while to get it you know I was like is
sale something I thought it was some
type of New Millennium term you know
that's how slow I am sometimes it's
these kind of things you know some
things I'm not slow at this type of
thing I was kind of slow at this moment
you know and then I was finally looking
it up and I was like ah it took me and
then I laughed so [__] hard
so then that's what we started the sale
Hayden strain because of that one thing
you know and then so basically I did
this sale Hayden strain did a shirt of
this like Buddha image and then this
raffle daily image like a half and half
and they released you know release
shirts and then you know we all have our
techniques of trolling people you know
so
um that was my technique you know we'll
just create a strain we'll create shirts
you know we'll do our own way if you
want to pick on people then we'll just
make fun of you for being a bully
instead in our own way you know
but for me I don't like bullies so if
someone wants to bully someone then you
know I'm probably gonna
you know
try to make them feel like they
shouldn't do that anymore
it's like people are so uptight right
now it's like come on lighten up a
little bit you know just just like help
someone you know that's why I'm doing
this well thing you know
um I'm doing this uh these uh these
wells in India around the city of bad
guy you know because it's like man
everyone's so like uptight and I'm so
pent up and about something like hey why
don't you guys just help someone
you know instead of like putting your
energy on focusing on your illusory
aspects of your mind that creates
suffering why don't you just put that
energy out and help someone you know
it feels good you help somebody you know
it's like so here's an opportunity you
can help somebody you know it's really
cheap and so it's like anyway I'm kind
of like that kind of guy that likes to
play these kind of games you know
um you know by entangling lots of people
up putting Wells into you know
poor villages in India that they don't
have water you know
what a perfect segue because I did
wanted to ask you about the uh the well
project I had a written down as the the
pump project how did this all get
started
well um you know first time I went to
India was in 2011
um to receive a color chakra initiation
in buddhaia from his Holiness of dilemma
um but first I went to dharamasala
um and you know went to his Monastery
there received chocolate bar empowerment
there then went to buddhaia so I met
these two boys in the blue guy you know
and they're the classic they just wanted
to take you around and you know you know
how I would make money off a Westerner
and I told him I said hey man I'm not
that kind of Westerner I don't need help
I don't need anything but if you want to
hang out and you want to hang with me
and go to all these cool places I'll
take you we can have we can be friends
I'll you know it'll be cool you know we
can develop a friendship
so then every year after that I you know
whenever I come to India and go to
bugaya we hang out and we stayed in
contact you know now 10 years later you
know
um and I'd always told him I said man
try to find something to do there you
know like let's do something you know
and then they come with this idea of hey
maybe we should do this well you know
there's one hand pump well you know I
said well you tell me how much it cost
show me all the you know labor costs all
the pipe costs the hand pump cost show
me the village where you're gonna do it
and you show me say hey John this is
where we're gonna put the village hey
John here's this hey John do that so I
just you know made them do step by step
and then we did a well you know and we
did it and put a well in there and then
I posted on Instagram you know and I
said hey maybe you guys instead of um
blowing your uh you know covid uh check
on something you'd blow it on this you
know that helps some people you know
and it kind of went viral you know now
we put in I think eight or nine of them
eight of them I'm not really sure um and
I have um funds for like 15 20. I think
waiting now in line to do it you know
and these you can understand how India
is India is caste system so these are
the lowest cast in the world you know
poorest poorest state in India tourists
country in the world poorest state in
that country or you know in that area
poorest the bahara region is the poorest
region of India and these are the
poorest people of this region you know
they call them Untouchables lowest cast
you know in this caste system there so
they don't even have it's all surface
level water they don't have underground
water they don't have water you know
so
um to be able to offer you know these
people water like this it's just
something very simple but you know you
can see by the images on these people's
faces and everything how happy they are
to have water from underground river you
know
and it's very simple you know seven
hundred dollars to do a hand pump well
from start to finish you know
concrete pad everything little you know
so they have a little hand pump well
there you know so they have a fresh
water now so people just don't
understand you know what kind of um
impact that can put on a community you
know imagine you know now all these
Villages that were so poor don't have
fresh water probably using bottled
plastic water whatever probably just
whatever now they have fresh water from
underground river you know
um you know maybe 50 hundred persons in
each Village you know so it's like
yeah I don't know
I like to do this kind of thing feels
cool I like to involve lots of people do
this kind of thing because
you know from a Buddhist perspective
um since we're doing this project then
anyone that's growing our strains buying
our seeds buying our herb growing our
herb anyone that's offering any type of
money is towards our projects in any way
from buying whatever selling anything
from a Buddhist perspective they're
generating good karma because we're
doing these projects and we're helping
us holding as a dilemma's monastery
we're helping all these things with our
you know with our philanthropic work and
finances and things like that so then
anyone that's a part of our
momentum is also from a Buddhist
perspective generating those good karmas
they say you know
um so yeah
it's just fun fun kind of stuff to do
yeah what a fantastic sort of Charity or
camera or paying it forward however you
want to put it very Noble indeed how can
people get in contact with you and or
sort of donate some money themselves if
they were hoping to help out with that
oh they just hit up my DM on Instagram
and then I just send them to the venmo
and we do the whole thing you know it's
like very simple you know each well too
will do step by step you can see the
wells that we've done you know the first
one is usually them saying hi so and so
here's where the well is going when the
guys you know and so we're trying to
show that like hey this is happening
each time it's fresh it's not some fake
thing it's like here's all the proof you
know here and Everyone likes that you
know so it's very simple you know they
just hit up the DM on Instagram
greenbody
Say Hey I want to get involved in one of
these Wells and I'll say okay this is
what's up and here's how you do it and
they say Okay boom boom boom and then
they get in line you know like I said I
have I think 18 people in line right now
already paid for Wells and they're just
you know they're waiting their turn to
get them get done you know
yeah that's really awesome are you
planning to do any other sort of
projects maybe not Wells but similar
sorts of thing or do you think there's
just still a lot of work to be done with
getting the pumps in
well I mean I had um his Holiness
dilemma had um given 34 color chakra
initiations and the last one was in both
Gaia so I wanted to do 34 Wells first I
want to do 21 Wells because in Buddhist
practices there's a Tara practice called
21 taras there's actually 21 of these um
Tara deities that are you know represent
Long Live for
um you know wealthy you know healthy all
these different aspects of well-being
and fortune in the sense of Health
Fortune wealth Fortune all these things
they call them Tara you know it's Atara
and there's 21 of these taras so I was
going to do 21 but then I'm like no
we're gonna do that really easy we'll do
34. you know so maybe we do 100 who
knows you know with as many villages as
we can we'll put them in there maybe do
something else I'm sure there'll be some
other type of project that comes up
right after this I'm sure but you know
um it's only as the Dalai Lama's Library
museum projects getting breaking around
on May so and I potentially will do
something for that also or you know
again
sure and do you hope that this sort of
arms giving will continue in the
community long term like after the 34
Wells are done do you have any projects
in mind for going forward or do you
think like at that point hopefully
there's enough momentum that people
continued on themselves
well I don't know I mean I'll keep this
going as long as I can you know
um I won't I won't stop as long as
people keep giving me money to do these
Wells I'll find a place to put it in in
India
and that's just how it goes um for sure
there'll be other projects and to to do
right after this because that's just how
it goes you know there's always
something to do to help people you know
there's never there's never an end to
that in this world right now
yeah sure so kind of on that idea of
paying a forward a bit I noticed that
recently you've done some CBD work which
is kind of not as popular with the
mainstream it's often viewed as sort of
a more medicinal Endeavor what are your
thoughts on the CBD Market
um well it's pretty open right now so
you know we're going to get involved in
it just because it's we should but um
you know I'm
I like it for what it is it created a
good Avenue to help everyone be more
familiar and make it more acceptable but
you know I'm not I'm not so much of a
fan of the CBD scene I like CBD and THC
together personally
so
yeah okay sure and I see a lot of people
discussing how it's really important to
know where you're getting your CBD from
these days and I guess it's sort of
especially pertinent given we're seeing
a lot of CBD come in from various
markets around the world international
places like China often get referenced
do you think that most CBD is of good
quality or it really does matter where
you're getting it from
I think it matters where you're getting
it from
me personally I like cannabis derived
CBD better personally because it has you
know I I I have a strain AC DC that's my
favorite CBD to be honest and that's got
THC in it um
so I mean
I'm a fan
um but I'm more of a fan of THC
personally it gives me more medicinal
value
so and I guess an extension of when you
referenced cannabis derived CBD we've
heard a lot of discussion recently
around cannabis derived terpins
particularly in reference to The Vape
Market where a lot of sort of terpenes
extracted from various fruits and other
natural sort of products can come into
play or even synthetic terpenes you take
the tank the same do you take the same
stance with that in the Cannabis derived
terpenes are superior
yes if it's used for cannabis
um but I'm not really a fan of putting
other terpenes into cannabis because we
don't know you know like we do know that
cannabis
um you know medicinally
if you get limonene from Cannabis it's
going to be at a certain range you're
not gonna you know but if you're getting
limonene from lemons and then you
introduce that into cannabis is that
safe I don't really know
so I would want to say you know
sure and I guess a more focal point of
discussion more recently has been CRC
which seems to have really sort of I
don't even know what that is but it
sounds like garbage you know I mean from
what it sounds like people explain to me
I'm like whoa gnarly yeah I guess it's
sort of like the uh the the black resin
you'd get out of the stem of a bong but
it's the equivalent of what you'd get
out of like a dab rake sort of thing and
there's been a lot of uh sort of I don't
want to say Evolutions because I don't
want to promote it as a good term but
people have basically learned how to
process this in such a way that it makes
it appear sort of more clean
do you think that it's highlighting the
idea that you know people are going to
any length to make a market like I can't
help but feel like this idea of people
often push this idea of how you know
you've got to just trap hard to make a
living do you think this is like the
next logical step of that where people
are literally polishing a turd
well I don't think there's a logical
format in this but I do think it's a you
know an Avenue to make money and that
they're taking advantage of logic yeah
you know
um I'm not a fan of turning [__] into
gold you know that's not something that
I've ever been a proponent of you know
I'm like you get really high-end
herb and then you can make really
high-end water hash with it that's kind
of where I'm at you know
yeah so I mean on that let's call these
other avenues all these other avenues
are out of my league you know
so you you brought it up yourself water
hash is this your favorite sort of
concentrate
for sure 100 percent
and why do you think it is that we just
have really seen a sharp falling off of
it even amongst the connoisseurs we it's
just so hard to find
well people can't make it because they
don't have a quality product to start
with so it's like if you don't have a
quality product to start with you're not
going to make a quality product and it
takes work and effort and love you know
and that's something that's lacking in
our industry these days you know why not
just like cut your weed down freeze it
fresh
put a hydrocarbon to it and make it make
make a wax or make up diamonds or make a
whatever that's what people think's cool
right
um there's not people that know you know
I just I haven't found anyone yet that's
like oh man I'd much rather have that
BHO than this like really high-end low
temp slow pressed rosin or you know some
really good hash you know I just haven't
found that yet so something we haven't
mentioned which I wanted to ask you
about was you reference file loss
earlier and I'm wondering do you think
that sort of the scientific and genetic
testing is going to lead the way in
terms of male selection going forward or
do you think that the Breeders hunch is
still going to rain Supreme
well I think intuition and plant
relation always runs Supreme personally
that's just my opinion you know I don't
think these squares that are like
jumping into the labs and kind of going
to play Overlord are going to do Jack
you know I mean look at how look at how
well I did for him now you know I think
they let go of my ugly right and
whatever and like you know that's just a
joke you know everyone it's it is what
it is you know
so I've seen on your Instagram that
you've worked with some tissue culturing
facilities and I'm just sort of
wondering what sort of improvements can
we as a community hope to achieve from
the utilization of this technology long
term
I think it's going to
um
um it's going to change the industry
heavily you know because
to offer that consistency across the
board you just can't do that in seed you
just can't you know you can do that in
tissue culture you can get acres and
Acres all to be the same height you can
get acres and acres to be pathogen pest
free you can do all this stuff it's the
future in my opinion but you know
because often we hear about hop late and
virus and things like that have you seen
strains that have been able to be
successfully cleaned with this process
not personally but I when I had hop late
in the years back when um dark heart
Nursery was giving it out to everybody
before anyone knew what it was you know
um I got it from them and then I it took
me two or three years to call out of my
garden you know and I just did it
through sight and through you know
knowing what to look for and I didn't
even we didn't even know it was called
hop late and you know it wasn't called
hop late and then it was not even called
dudding then we didn't even know what
the [__] it was you know thought it was
some like tobacco Mosaic or something
you know
um so anyway yeah
I don't know I mean I called it out of
all my Gardens we don't have it in there
anymore so yeah wow I did that just just
personally you know
and how did how did you achieve that I
think I heard Bob hemple in the past say
that you can outgrow it is that kind of
what you did like where you would yeah
please explain so basically you take the
best cuts and you keep taking the best
cuts growing them in the best conditions
and you you basically outgrow the hot
plate and you basically take new good
Cuts you propagate those you grow them
out you take new good cuts and then you
just basically call it out you know
eliminating anything you know any any
sign that I saw of that I would throw
the soil pot and plant away completely
yeah wow that's cool to hear that you
were able to get rid of it
yeah didn't even know what it was then
[Laughter]
I just know I didn't like it
and neither did the plan so on to one of
our final questions before we jump into
the Fast Fire ones at the end I've been
asking a lot of guests recently if they
have any concern about the possibility
of there being genetically modified
cannabis specifically in the sense that
maybe it's modified such that it grows
at a very uniform height or the the
levels are very consistent in terms of
cannabinoids so that it you know it
doesn't test hot or there's at least
consistency do you think that's
something to fear not really
honestly
I mean
I don't know like in the industry I'm
not fearing much in these kind of
contexts because everything's going to
play itself out
um I just I guess that's that's
something not something that can really
uh
you know speak on too much to be honest
I don't think it's uh something to worry
about
yeah sure so
on to our final quick fire questions
which we love to ask gold readers to
kind of get their perspective on a few
different things the first question is
what is the most memorable cannabis
you've ever consumed I mean I had some
Maui Wowie when I was uh a kid and man I
was high for like seven hours or some
hydro weed you know like grown from
Oregon I think and
I don't know that put a high on me like
nothing else really that was it was
interesting
um
other than that I don't have a lot of
memorable moments you know it was like
the first time I smoked chronic you know
I was like it made it it made an impact
that was that Maui Wowie is growing
Hydra you know
yeah that's interesting so on the other
end of the spectrum were there ever a
specific strain that comes to mind when
maybe a lot of your friends or
colleagues were just really hyped about
it loving it and then you finally got a
chance to try it and you were left a bit
unimpressed
oh yeah that's happened a lot honestly
multiple times I can't even fix I can't
even explain
definitely happened quite a few times
just sort of the more new stuff or the
older stuff
um both you know I've had some land race
stuff from people that are like oh man
it's so good you're like okay whatever
um and then some of this newer things
you're like oh man this is the best and
you're like nah but then you do you know
like
then I had smelly Kush cake that was
really good you know when I had some of
this other strain that wasn't that good
you know so it's I think it's like
each person you know each person each
grower all that it's all it all comes
into play there
yeah certainly so let's give a desert
island situation I'm going to drop you
off on a desert island and you can
cultivate three strains for the rest of
time which three are you going to take
with you
wow
um there was this big sir holy strain
that was out of Eugene that I first
started growing that I would take that
one I would take the um purple Hindu
Kush that I just got from Sir Bob
Hemphill and I would also
a good OG or sour basket ever I think
I don't think those those three I'd
probably be good
honestly
no it's a solid selection there so on
the other end of the spectrum let's just
say you were going to drop someone off
to the island too you're not
particularly fond of and you get to
choose which three strains they're left
with which ones are you going to give
well I think I'd even if I wasn't fond
of them I'd probably want them to have
the strains that I just picked because
I'd want them to evolve their mind you
know because maybe if I didn't I wasn't
fond on them because they were like you
know the way they thought or something I
don't know
um if I wanted to stick someone with
some bunk strains basically
is that what you meant yeah yeah
whatever you want to do I'm happy to
accept the Diplomatic give them a blue
dream man
um blueberry
poo dream and uh
I don't know what would be another one
imitator pretend to constraint purple
punch no I don't know
Blackberry sorry I like purple punch
better blackberry kush
blackberry kush was a good strain to
stick someone you don't like with
there you go there you go okay so uh the
final question for our interview today
if you could go back in time to any
place anywhere in history and collect
some seeds where would you go and what
would you collect
wow
well I'd have to go back in time to you
know the Tibetan plateau and try to like
find some of those um you know root
starter strains from way back thousands
and thousands and thousands of years ago
you know that'd be one you know wouldn't
mind um you know going to Nepal try to
find something there I don't know you
know literally trying to find some of
that Source stuff give that Source
feeling you know
go to Africa maybe go down to Southern
Africa somewhere
find some Durban or something I don't
know really
so that was what came to my top of my
head I guess you know those three
through three regions South Africa Nepal
Tibetan plateau
yeah fantastic what what nice old world
soda selections so I think that pretty
much brings us to the end of things were
there any shout outs or comments you
wanted to make
no I really appreciate the opportunity
and like this was fun I was um kind of
yeah
really really stoked on this and really
I'm excited about this and
hope it offers people a little bit of
perspective and really just want to say
thank you to even offering me the
opportunity really grateful you know I
do know that um
you know Bodie said he wanted to do a uh
a
um kind of add-on to this at one point
so I think everyone can look forward to
me and him doing a
little Duo
um collab podcast here so that's going
to come in the future I do know that
because
he's wanting to do that so
I think this was the pilot to that and I
think we're going to come on together
and you know have a bunch of laughs one
day too so that might be pretty soon
yeah awesome I mean sounds like we're
gonna have an epic time with the uh the
Bodhi Thunderdome situation
but yeah I mean outside of that thank
you so so much for coming on and giving
us the low down on you like your
genetics some some history some culture
some Buddhism and your plans for the
future it's been fantastic I really
appreciate it and I'm really grateful
and thank you so much it's been an honor
foreign
[Applause]
[Music]
genetics for coming on the show sharing
all his knowledge and thought
likewise a huge thank you to our amazing
sponsors you guys helped make the show
happen and we're so extremely grateful
to see you too now number one sea tank
in the game all the hottest breeders all
the precious drops all the most biased
trains you know you love them why would
you go with somewhere else and I want to
know at the end of a harvest if I'm not
happy they're gonna look after me
but how do you know you've done the crop
Justice well simple go check out our
other two sponsors coppet biological
systems the number one spot to grab all
the best beneficial Predators beneficial
feeds and micro powders to make your
crop happy healthy and huge success
check out the sparkle ultimate if you've
got mites and finally check out the
apopar M for Apple you know you want
your [__] to be as happy and healthy as
possible why not get the beneficial
troops on standby instead of waiting
before there's a war at hand already
likewise Pro mix you know they've been
in the industry forever but did you know
they've got an awesome mycorrhizal
product called promix connect go check
it out it helps facilitate better
nutrient uptake water uptake stress
resistance sort of vegetative time okay
we've had Jeff lowenfell on the show
before you've heard it you know how good
mycorrhiza is why don't you get the best
mycorrhizer product on the market from
this connect better density better resin
density stronger Aroma more consistent
results what mods we want guys
[Music]
and last but not least a huge huge thank
you to the one and only Patron phone
truly a family and the last spot of the
show ensuring episodes continue to
happen if you like the show and want to
get access to early content unheard
interviews little extra episodes as well
as giveaways bonuses and so much more
please go check out
www.patreon.com forward slash the
podcast
[Music]
I think that just about brings us to the
end of it gang
thanks for sticking around I appreciate
you so much as always
I'll catch you on the flippity flop
[Music]
check that hitter
foreign foreign
[Music]