[Applause]
[Music]
hello and welcome to another episode of
the podcast the Cannabis podcast for
Buddy
enthusiasts as always you're joined by
your boy heavy days here from the upside
down library and as usual we want to
give a massive shout out to all of our
incredible sponsors who help ensure the
show continues to happen seed's here now
number one seed bank in the industry all
the hottest breeders the latest drops
everything you can look for and more
whether you're after indoor outdoor
feminized regular autoflow they've got
everything under the sun to keep you
loaded on all the hottest genetics
producing the most fire Bud you've ever
had I hear they've got some incredible
lines from heavy days still in stock if
you want to go check that out make sure
to do it before it's too late
big shout out to CT now we appreciate
you so much likewise if you want to
produce the best bud to date you've got
to make sure your garden is pumping on
all cylinders and for that we recommend
our good friends at Organics alive they
produce the number one powdered organic
products that will ensure your next crop
is the absolute best to date people are
picking up cups all around the globe
using their products which is the
highest Accolade you can get hom Growers
just like you producing not only their
best Harvest today but awardwinning
Harvest what more could you ask for
they've got Solutions whether you're in
veg transition flower they've got micro
nutrients macronutrients absolutely
every product you could want ferment and
more check them out guys Organics alive
your number one stop for all of the
highest quality organic input to make
sure your Harvest is
killing likewise you got to make sure
your garden is pest and pathogen free to
ensure that your plants are happy and
producing the highest quality Harvest
for that we recommend you check out our
good buddies at copit they've partnered
with us for a long time and we have no
doubt that if you use their products you
will find they are the absolute best in
the game you've got to check out the
spidex vital plus breeda sachet these
are an absolute game Cher it's the usual
spidex vital you know and love that's
going to take out any spidermite
problems you have but the breeder sachet
allow a continuous sustained release of
these beneficial Predators into your
garden ensuring that you don't just have
one big burst and surge but instead a
consistent rate of release truly a game
changer I expect nothing less from the
experts at copit biological you know
these guys are world leaders they're not
just in America they're all around the
world and for good reason they are the
Pinnacle of the game if you're after
biological Pest Control check out copit
number one thank you so much for the
support the final piece of the puzzle to
ensure that your room is killing it is
our good friends at Pulse their sensors
are second To None industry leading and
just recently they announced the pulse
Hub what more could you want an
integrated unit for all of your sensors
to ensure that your garden is automated
and tracking all of the variables you
may not be consciously aware of from VPD
to ppf Doo temperature humidity so much
more you've got to get yourself a pulse
sensor guys it has revolutionized the
way I grow flow and increased the Turing
content the cannaboid content the yield
so so so much more shout out as always
to our friends at Pulse senses likewise
if any of you guys have been listening
to the show you know that I am
passionate about helping people
transition to vaporized options if
they're considerate about their
respiratory health and for me dap are
the world leaders in this dnap helped me
to transition from bongs to vaping and I
tell you what I've never looked back
their unit is the most potent the most
highly replicating of a bong hit I've
ever come across and through their
incredible munit I was able to
successfully get off bongs a few years
ago now truly one of the most Innovative
and interesting Vapes on the market
using a totally different design to
others you have found please check out
dnap I promise you guys if you've tried
vaping before and felt like it didn't
quite cut it check these guys out you
will not be disappointed massive shout
out to dinat thank you so
much and last but not least we want to
give a massive shout out to the
incredible patreon gang without you guys
we could not continue to make episodes
if you you want to get early access to
upcoming episodes exclusive content just
on the patreon including the likes of
meme Jean Bob hemp Bodie triome jungle
so much more be sure to go check out our
patreon we give away genetics every
month to our supporters along with
artwork Vapes sensors so much more
please check out the patreon guys I
promise you you won't regret it you'll
get your money back in swag to helping
supporter show you love thank you so
much to everyone from the patreon we
appreciate you so
greatly and on
today we have part two with one of the
last remaining Titans in the Cannabis
scene the creator of Mr Nice Seed Bank
the upcoming Shanti Baba seeds about to
hit the worldwide web near you as well
as an absolute kickass Aussie breeder a
massive Welcome To None other Shanty
Baba here to chat all things
genetics
history medical cannabis and predictions
for the
future
preservation and so so so much more so
without further
[Music]
delay all righty gang we're back for
another one and on this one today we're
welcoming back an absolute Titan of the
Cannabis scene one of the last remaining
Godfathers of modern genetics you know
him you love him a big shout out and
thank you to Shanty Barber of Mr Nice
Seed Bank for taking the time to join us
again today thank you didn't realize
you'd be back so quickly but it's lovely
to be back uh much appreciated that you
took the time to come join us again
today same question we started off with
last time what have you been smoking on
recently oh well today um it's bit early
because it's only morning time my time
but uh I did get up in the middle of the
night and had a puff on
um I think it was pink lemonade it was
uh a variety that we've that uh we've
been growing for some years now and um
it's just uh yeah it's good good good
feeling thing it's not too strong not
too weak lovely Flav just a good effect
back to bed and had a few hours extra
sleep that's beautiful to hear I can
envision myself doing a similar thing
that little night cap to help get you
back there i' I'd love to just follow
that up and ask are there any particular
things that are like daily drivers for
you that like you know you're sort of
regularly Reaching For What are the
things in your toolkit you
know um I was thinking about that the
other day um I I don't really have a
kind of I mean I I wake up and I feel
different every day and so I I like to
have a big variety from different hashes
that I've made even Moroccan and and JIS
sometimes and and then three or four
different marijuanas always available so
I can choose because some morning I wake
up and and I just want to numb myself
and other morning I wake up and I'm
bubbly and I um I just take one or two
Puffs of uh you know a mango Haze joint
and I'm I'm fine for hours so it's
really I suppose it's to do with the
chemistry going on in your body and how
you slept and things like what's on your
mind but yeah I like to keep you know
solids and and and Greenery uh available
two or three of each thing so uh and mix
it up I mean I mix up stuff all the time
I'm not one of these purists when it
comes to you know sort of I I suppose
I'm purist in the fact of um I try
everything a lot but when I choose to
just do a myself just recreational smoke
or um then it changes you know but I
lately I suppose I I've been towards the
the solids the hashes that we make you
know ourselves out of single strains and
and they're always very interesting when
you try a single strain of hash like
rather than the grass I think we talked
about this last time a little bit about
making some different blends and stuff
but yeah it's really different when you
you try um the hash version of that
particular grass get a few more
different
effects yeah certainly we had a lot of
listeners who were really thrilled with
the sort of discussion you gave last
episode as a little followup I'd be
curious to ask do you find that there
are any particular sativa strains that
translate in effect nicely into the
concentrates cuz I think you often hear
people saying oh a lot of the times it
it just feels sort of like hybrid SL
indre you lose that uplifting euphoric
sort of effect are there any strains
that come to mind for you where like you
think it does translate over
nicely well I've made um um hashes from
obviously I think Afghan Hayes is a
really good uh an incredible strain
first of all as a as a marijuana one of
the building blocks of the industry from
from our breeding Point both Neville and
I um um over the years and uh it's a
actually if you grow it well and um you
you grow enough of it you can make some
really good hash from it maybe you you
don't make 10 to 12% like on a on a dry
you know of un yield from whether you do
it ice or dry or or whichever way but
you could definitely get you know sort
of seven 8% out of some of these Haze
hybrids and they're very different
they're really um yeah I always try to
describe them a little bit more like the
the the effervescent part of like the
Champagnes in the industry it's kind of
you don't always feel stoned but you're
cerebrally High you know and and so um I
kind of like that when you go out to a
party uplifted and you're a bit euphoric
and kind of can hear music really well
and you you know rather than your body's
tired and you want to sort of slap on
the couch and what to film and they
they're very different effects and so I
I suppose um Neville's Haze we made um
we were lucky enough to grow quite a lot
of at one stage
outside and like I said to you I mean I
like outdoor plants for making hasch I
think they actually the resins much more
rounded and and bit like wine or or or
olives you know um something to do with
the environment in that year and the Sun
and aspect and the water and all of the
chemicals in the soil you know it's just
something different and um and so and
the turpens I always find the turpens
are much stronger and they last longer
from outdoor variety rather than indoor
because in door you open it you get a
flush of of of tppon and then it sort of
dies down very quickly whereas a good gr
outdoor you open up the the jar and the
room remains fragrant you know and it it
stays that like that so we'll probably
find out a few years that outdoor um has
a better Integrity of uh um on the turp
and and the flavonoids and different
compounds on the plant rather than
indoor and Greenhouse sort of you know
controlling the climate and then giving
you the potentially the best yields of
cannaboids and stuff like that so I
think combination of both is always good
that's why I blend you know it's like
what I explained last time blending a
bit of the dry with the ice and uh kind
of making the flavors the full Integrity
of the so and and you know many times
I've I've the hat like what I was
explaining before when you do a single
strain and you make a Sie from it a dry
C from it for example
there's something different about the
hash version than the plant version
because you probably got some very small
amounts of a certain cannaboid that you
have a minute amount in a plant but you
never really get the effect of it but in
a hash you've got a higher concentration
of that and it it it fits into the
recipe of that plant so that's why I
would say the hash version of a single
strain uh field is very it allows you to
understand exactly the medicine of that
plant properly whereas the plant maybe
has a completely different feeling
sometimes and and the chlori changes
that affect as well so you know I do
think they're really important to to
study them as two different kind of um
medicines in a way you know yeah wow
that that's really interesting and and I
guess with what you've just said as a
follow-up do you specifically breed with
the intention of plants performing well
outdoors and is that where you sort of
see the global production of cannabis
heading in the
future well I mean Outdoors is is
obviously the cheapest and and um if you
have a good season it's it's the most
abundant uh cheapest uh um yielding kind
of prop you can have um in indoor
everything has to be climate control and
there's an expense and there's staff and
a lot of electricity and and a lot of
expenses related to uh an established uh
Greenhouse or or an indoor facility you
know um outdoor uh you don't always hit
it on the head with the the environment
for that year and the climate maybe
affects it in a negative way but when
it's hits it in a positive way I I do
believe you've got um a huge amount of
yield compared to what you could produce
um in inside or in a greenhouse you know
and uh so there's a lot more scope with
the cheaper production lines I mean
making hash outdoor for me would be a
very sensible um way sensible kind of
decision um and and using aspects of
indoor Greenhouse to blend with it that
that maybe that would come into it you
know but
um like Australia doesn't really have
havn't had a hash culture for example I
mean only pockets of it where people
making their own extracts now in the
last sort of 10 15 years but some of the
extreme boys have been making a little
bit of Civ but you'd have to know them
to to to actually experience that in
Australia uh whereas Europe had had 80%
of their Market had always been
solids you know for up until 20 30 years
ago when marijuana started to to kind of
come in and become interesting and and
different and they see them as different
things rather than just marijuana or
weed you know what I mean so yeah it's
been an evolution and and it still is
it's still evolving because not
everybody knows everything about you
know um strains or or or what they do to
people or how the effect is and you know
sometimes year to year they they vary
outdoor and they don't have the same
effect
they smell the same they look the same
and there's something missing you know
so I
suppose excuse me I suppose it's the
same with wine and and you know like
this year unfortunately a lot of people
in Loria in Italy they didn't pick the
olives it wasn't worth it there was uh
they got hit during the season with some
hails and got a lot of damage and it was
just not economic and uh and you know
um there's a few areas that that that it
wasn't practical and it wasn't there was
no value in picking the olives so this
year will be a
particularly average year you know for
production and um that that happens
outside because you can't control
obviously temp the
weather so I mean with that point in
mind I guess do you think that the base
sort of commodity of medical cannabis in
the future might be some sort of Highly
processed product as opposed to flour
because of inherent variation from
season to season you reference like you
know will there eventually be like a
Jack Daniels number seven equivalent of
concentrate
um you know I've tossed we we talked
about this many times when we were
riding High suppose um Howard and
Neville and myself and a few other guys
we always talked about having the uh K
connoisseurs Club you know where we've
we've kept
different years of hash and we've vacuum
sealed them and kept them in a Cellar
like we do wine you know and we we had a
bud but the buds fade because they they
yellow out and they the chlorophyll
deteriorates so when you make an
extraction they don't fade so quickly
you know maybe some of the cannaboids
change to more sleepier cannaboids over
time and stuff but if you hold them well
um and I've got a friend who's who's
made he's got a sample of every single
piece of has he came across or made from
the early 90s onwards and it's like a
coffee it could be a coffee table I mean
it was really this is really impressive
wow um and you really see the difference
and the evolution you see um and we've
become very good at making hashes and
stuff but for me early days when I
didn't when we were really tossing
around we made a lot of plants in the
1998 99 in in Switzerland when I first
came here um I used to gather the uh the
what fell off the plants they they used
to just cut the um the flowers off the
wood over the silk screens and in the
end of the day I would just go there
myself and and get it all because they
were different plants done different day
so I was able to gather say skunk one
only hash or super silver hash or early
Queen hash or you know and we kept it
and and um we're able to press it up and
and clean it up over time and I used
that as the
original um I used to melt it with um
olive oil and give that as as drops to
patients right at the beginning of
everything and and for me that was the
be I've always used that and then ice
then we started with the water hash and
that was actually real base of medicine
so yes I believe that uh at the moment
unfortunately the pharmaceutical
industry is so over regulated ated and
and corrupt that that I think that the
um the only way that the people will
take it back eventually the the hash
makers or the um like the wine makers um
they will be growing little small areas
of particular sort of strains that only
grow in those areas for example really
well and uh they'll be making their kind
of 200 kilos of cottage industry style
stuff and that maybe is by a particular
pharmaceutical who uses it to make their
base product is one of the base products
that they blend you know and th those
specific uh sort of um kind of unique
recipes will will start with like
companies that that will only demand
high quality and have found a plant
that's actually working for a particular
ailman you know and and they see that
it's useful and we'll start to
specialize down those lines even more
you'll start getting pockets of of of
people who have worked on particular
plants for certain ailments you know and
or maybe the the tppon and the cannaboid
blend of uh you know a particular mastic
Bush for example does something really
well for depressive people and and when
you make the extraction that particular
stuff works every time you know and so
obviously then we can start to say this
is much better for that problem you know
at the moment it's um a bit of stab in
the dark I'm afraid even the best
doctors and and the best Growers they
can't really predict you know what what
is happening or they can't prove it with
science why that plant is better for you
if you're suffering from Parkinson's or
or food disorder or you know what I mean
it's very difficult we're at that that
level at the moment of trying to work it
out and so a lot of scientific research
is going into very small incremental
facets of this industry at the moment
you
know wow and and do you think like
longterm I'm talking many years
eventually we'll get to the point where
you'll have a certain cannabis you know
product extract whatever form it is
that's for XY Z and it slots in with all
your other farmer tablets and as a quick
followup how do you think we can help
get the acceptance we need from
healthcare workers cuz I know that
around the world there's still a lot of
people in healthcare who are still very
dismissive and not particularly
interested in medical
cannabis you know um that's a difficult
one because changing the mentality you
saw how slowly the world changed from
marijuana being a drug because of all
the negative propaganda for many many
many decades uh to it becoming a
medicine and being treated with a lot
more respect still has a stigma attached
in certain areas and there's still old
people who don't you know would put a
pill in their mouth any day of fentanyl
but they they would question you know
someone smoking a vaporizer uh as using
drugs and uh so mindset is really
important education is super important
and uh and actually um allowing people
to decide with u a better conf
consultation from maybe an agency or or
independent agency that is not profiting
from giving out any particular advice
but helping the patient before they see
the doctor so they have a kind of
understanding of what they're looking
for when they describe their symptoms
doctors aren't always the people who
prescribe um the best drugs for people
because sometimes they're
earning um they have sponsorship from
certain C compes and I think that that
kind of you know sort of um tins the
water um so I I would prefer to see um a
much more neutral um um committee set up
to it help people get knowledge about
what things do to them and you know um
and and how they could be uh looking for
the best particular things that that
some people need to a pill they don't
smoke because they've got you know
particular sickness and and smoking is
revolting uh I I personally believe no
sick person wants to smoke inhale
anything I think they would prefer to
take a pill a capsule or slug of oil and
so for me um I believe that's the real
medical um um that's the real medical
fraternity that I look at when I'm
looking at those and not the so that the
people who have um have sort of jumped
on the bandwagon is Medical but they're
using it as
recreational I don't think there should
be a discre a difference to tell you the
truth between medical and recreational
thing I think people should be allowed
to use most everything as long as they
don't abuse these things and that means
that you you've got to put it in a
independent sort of committee that that
sets some rules that are not tainted by
by big companies and and by individual
producers you know you don't want them
to to to sort of push certain things but
you need
education difficult question look I'm
sorry to put it to you my friend but I
knew you were up to the challenge so
yeah I mean I'm looking at it all the
time at the moment um and and because
what I I mean I'm working in the medical
now where I work in the medical because
we have the licenses and and it makes uh
the legal side of it much better now we
have have Farms that we can go to and
and hold our head up high and we we can
work with certain strains now and and so
I I believe a lot of the people uh who
I'm working with in Switzerland don't
come from my industry whatsoever they
come from a very um educated uh um sort
of protocol of a pharmaceutical industry
where they they realize that uh um some
things have been pushed on the public
not really helping and they've actually
changed their way and they want to get a
natural something natural that they see
the next uh level of understanding for a
lot of people and the least harmful and
least uh you know symptomatic uh post
symptomatic problems that you have with
taking certain drugs so you know that's
half the time I mean I I don't like to
take a pill I really have to be
desperate to take a pill of anything but
when I know that I've made disc capsure
with just 6% CBD and and 40 T I'm I'm
I'm on or an extra better Carol U Turan
to enhance the CBD I know those things
work for me at the moment but it's just
trolling out I mean this is going to
take a while to be very confident to
know right this is my opinion or this is
science you know what I mean at the
moment it's my opinion based on a little
bit of Home
Science you
know certainly look I mean we had our
intuitions about the medical values
early on I'm I'm sure as time goes by
and we discover more we'll learn more
that probably backs lots of the things
we suspected but uh I wanted to quickly
change the topic cuz that that was the
reason why I asked you some of the hard
medical questions I knew you were into
it but I wanted to ask the day after we
did our last chat you put a post up
talking about how you have a new skunk
Kine coming out and appropriately it's
called new skung can you tell us a
little bit about the backstory on this
one and what inspired you to do this
project now well I I've been busting
open a lot of old seed uh from my my um
my fridges and a lot of old stuff from
Nils and some of it has been germinating
it's too a bit too old and some of it
we're we're doing different techniques
to get some old sea germinating and and
I actually was uh the new skunk was
actually uh um a very old skunk seed it
was a a skunk
one um by uh skunk 187 it was one of
Neville's very old thing and I read the
thing and I got a male out of it and um
I hit it back to my skunk one which is
the female and I produced a very small
batch of seed and I I then I put it out
there I got it tested by quite a a lot
of people on the website and stuff and
uh um I was trying to develop a good
hash making skunk you know actually that
was that was the kind of project in mind
and uh it just and and it was different
smells there was there was definitely
that old stink um you know that really
it was not
pleasant sometimes it was a little bit
you know it's a little bit
off-putting um wafted over and and I
remember a lot of people used to love
that uh the effect of those flowers so I
I must have mentioned at one time that I
was doing this on the website and then I
got a line of people and they all
started hustling me so I sent out a
batch of these old I don't have many I
only had a few and I gave them to my
daughter to put through the
options um so we we kind
of excuse me we we kind of um made test
batches and we we we've made a small
batch but it's still I'm still playing
with it I mean selecting um there's a
really wide variety in that selection of
the brogy seed that I call new skunk at
the moment I would prefer to inbreed
some of it back to the male and just
keep selecting a female and putting it
back to the male and until I really see
a particular thing coming out and I I a
few people asked me for the stink you
know they wanted to go back and they're
trying to find that and create that old
old world skunk and I believe you can
find it but you're going to have to bust
open a few seeds and so I'm I'm I'm
making some more seed at the moment just
for a few guys who who are want to do
like a thousand and they they want to
look for that and so uh yeah I don't say
that you know you'll find it every time
but I'm trying to give the tools back to
some people who are looking for
specifically for certain things again
and I've definitely got the the original
and all of Neville and all of my old
stuff and all of the old stuff that we
started all the strains from in the FR
upstairs in in the office I have you
know six or seven fridges just
full I mean I think I could oh wow I
could float a few countries with uh with
crops but uh you know they're all at
different levels and I you know when if
I don't have enough time I I kind of put
the notes inside vacuum seal it and put
it in the freezer I know I'm going to
come to it in a few years because you
know there's only so many so many seats
you can bust open and so many projects
you can do properly and and give your
attention to it at one time but um I
have a a a can of Bible I call it it's
all my my notes and and sometimes I have
to really go back to that to realize
what that particular batch of seed was
and I knew that it was a had an orange
corner on it for a reason and then I
would find the orange corner and then
I'd go oh yeah that was really
interesting batch we need to look
through that again with you know so so I
mean you know um I help a lot of guys at
the moment I've sent a few batches of
garlic Bud to one guy in England and
some old hash plant and if you find
something you'd share it with me but you
know these are old seed from 30 40 years
now um I'm never going to have enough
time in my life to bust open everything
that I've got treasured away and uh so
it's it's that sort of time for certain
people to uh trust them to to to kind of
help with some projects you know and and
I I have a really good batch of um
people on The Forum and my moderator
Musashi he's a he's excellent guy and
he's a very good grower excellent
photographer and so what happens is that
he's educated now for for these new
upand cominging guys who are really
playing with their own varieties and
adding some hazes in and then you know
he's already done all these things and
he comes from the pharmaceutical World
which disgruntled pharmaceutical world
and and he's retired now so he's the
perfect guy to to he's educated smart
wonderful diplomatic person to have
better than me in fact I I'm I'm a bit
short sometimes when I think people have
asked the question 7,000 times and they
should have read some of the literature
but but uh he's not like that so um yeah
I really thank some of the crew around
me that they have been exceptionally
helpful my daughter my son my sons
everyone actually they work really
well wow that's that's incredible you
know many hands make light work and and
so many cool little tivs there we could
chase down I guess one of the things
that stuck out to me I'd love to hear
you said your female skunk cutting
what's that one like well it's not
actually mine that was from Neville I
mean it's the original skunk one that
Neville had Dave Watson and Rob Clark
they had it um they were all playing at
the same time Neville found his
particular and he called it this his
skunk one and Dave Watson called his
version skunk one so you got to remember
skunk one was skunk is a very confused
term
because there's arguments if there
was certain things in it and and of
course you know Dave Dave Watson has his
version and that's everything is
probably correct according to him there
um whereas uh um you know Neville
probably selected they Pro they were
working similarly at one stage when
everyone was friendly
until this green Merchants uh you know
sort of problem that came in and exposed
a few of the Americans and then you know
things changed and that was all in
Holland at that St and and they all
started to then separate their plants
you know and Neville was I think he was
um he was the real um um go-getter and
innovator um of of um specific
genetics um at that time whereas the
other guys
were were were there for reasons I don't
know and they had licenses for reasons
I'm not sure and but I I was friends
with all of them and I was using both
sides and and there were slight
differences in their skunks um I did
like Rob Clark there was a version that
Rob Clark gave me once and I made uh
some incredible hash from it so you know
they're all that it it's like
um um if I pick a haze or Neville picked
a haze we'd pick different hazes there
were differences that we liked and um
you know it would be the same with you
you could put 100 haes in the room and
and there might be 100 different
versions and they're all called Haze you
know
so um I I think keeping the original in
in in um as as mother and living
genetics um has been probably the
hardest job of of my life and um and
always having four or five backups in
different countries because you lose so
many things I mean uh you know um and
now thank God for tissue culture which
is is is going to save us uh get rid of
some of the viruses that are now you
know the late Lon hop virus and and the
mosaic virus and there's other viruses
coming and you know we we really need to
be aware of um of a lot more things you
know and old seed busting it open there
weren't many viruses so I'm not really
worried about the old seed coming in but
lot of this new stuff I'm just I don't
take it in my rooms I don't take any
plants from from anything that hasn't
come from tissue culture regrowing and
plenty you know um because I I this this
this virus goes around pretty quickly
now and it it used to be just talked
about in America and a little bit in
Canada but I think it's around the world
now I mean it's it's one of these things
that maybe doesn't Express itself uh
until the conditions go down but uh it's
definitely um it's spread now you know
it's one of those things you just got
sorry yeah hugely look I'm going to have
to loop back to several of the points
there especially the hoplon virus and
you know the just maintaining mothers
over years it's definitely some
interesting topics but I wanted to
quickly ask you before we move on you
mentioned Dave Watson and I think in in
the grand scheme of things he's
considered one of the grandfathers of
the whole industry in a sense um but for
a long time he copped a lot of flak like
a lot of people would accuse him of
collaborating with that green merch and
operation and I think for the most part
people have realized that that wasn't
the case and he's a good guy I'd be
interested to hear what's your sort of
thoughts on the overall roles Dave
Watson sand the skunkman has played in
the scene any notable stories or
encounters you know I don't make an
opinion about things that I weren't
around for and and I I'm only hearing
from particular people um I was working
with Arian and Neville at that stage
Neville was very much against Dave
Watson and Rob and and the other crew at
that stage I was friendly with them both
uh I had different dealings with all
everyone I I was not a guy to make my
opinion unless I was asked and I was
definitely um more Pur purist about
breeding at that time and I was a little
bit more focused on that and they were
both excellent sources from different
things and as well as other guys in in
Holland um so um while I was meant to be
probably um um on Neville and and and
the greenhouse side at that stage uh I
kept an open mind and I did business
with both sides and um I did prefer the
diversity of seed breeding from Neville
because um say Dave he he wasn't he he
was
uh he's a wealth of knowledge he's I met
him many times and we we have a a
healthy um respect for each other like
Rob Clark's probably a better friend
I've seen him all over the
world uh and we were good mates and
still are and I just haven't been in
Holland and seen them for many years and
uh um I don't have any negative feelings
about all of that what I wasn't around
for the that Merchant thing I heard
about it was exposed on the radio one
day I was working with Neville and Aran
in a in a Big Greenhouse where where we
did our thing and they had on Dutch
radio they had a big uh explanation
about that period and and there was some
Merit to certain things I don't know
what was provable or not my Dutch wasn't
so good then and um it didn't get better
and as I moved to Italy and and so um I
I tried to not give my opinion about
things that really I'm I don't know um
and I always say proof is in the seed
that's why I took the seed from what
they said and where it came from and I
busted it open and I went through it and
so I didn't have to believe anyone I
believed me from what I was given and
sometimes it was a little bit of a goose
chase and other times it was some gems
in it and um and the guys that I
respected I worked with and um and the
other guys well you know um there was a
there's there's there's been a lot of
negative uh press uh about me I read
stories that never that never even
happened and and you know there so I
mean I don't know what's to believe
anymore you know I know what I did and
and I know what I have and I know who I
did it with
um you can ask me questions about those
things all all day long um and I would
have a beer with all of them still to
this day so I I I'm not really that uh
I'm not really that opinionated about
those things because it really doesn't
have anything to do with the subject
that I'm working on and uh usually
that's to do with breeding or selecting
or finding cannaboid uh specific plants
and you know and and for me I still uh
use Clark's book he used a lot of my
black hashers and Indian hashers for his
hashish book photographed many times in
in there and uh uh We've we've
collaborated in things that most people
would never know
um one day I suppose I'll I'll exp some
other things but you know
yeah o la la I guess we'll all have to
wait for that day and you know what you
read my mind I was going to say you know
I was hooked on on the story about the
hash you made that uh Rob gave you the
seeds from last time we were chatting
and you mentioned him a few times I
guess it's a good time to ask like I
think as as well as Rob's known for his
like seminal literature the book I also
feel like he's kind of a little bit of
an unsung hero of the scene you know he
sort of flies a bit under the radar
what's your friendship with Rob been
like over the years and do you agree
he's a bit of an unsung hero yeah yeah
no for me Rob I still recommend his
original book marijuana botany as uh the
first book that most people should go I
think he's the only um one of the I I
believe he is a
scientific uh author he he he runs
around the world to all the places not
the Cannabis cups but to the places
where genetics orig originate from where
thread and fiber is originated from he's
gone deep into that kind of side of
things he's gone to the Russian uh areas
and and Ukraine and found strains and
helped keep preserve a lot of hemp
varieties you know in seed form up in in
the cold storage and uh he's done a lot
of uh unsung uh hero kind of work and
and for me he's still a very reliable um
um source of um incredible um
intelligence when it comes to a
practical uh education and a and a theor
theoretical education of cannabis so for
me um I don't really
read a lot of the other guys books I
mean I'm friendly with them all but you
know I don't think that they I think
they're writing it from a different
perspective uh whereas Rob has always
written it from a scientific point of
view with provable referenced um
articles and and I like his books and I
think he's to the point and so as far as
that goes yes I think he's probably the
best cannabis
writer um around you know in in in a um
when it comes to not having your ego or
opinion um involved in what you're
writing
so you know yeah brilliant what a what a
testament highly regarded by all but
awesome to hear that you you have him in
such high esteems a little earlier you
mentioned that there's issues of over
the years like parents changing and
stuff of of strains that are offered by
certain companies and I guess I'm
interested in this from the point
interview that I know like one of the
notable cases was like Simon of serious
seeds mentioned that at a certain point
the parents of C Miss changed because
one of the parents got lost I guess it
started getting me thinking like what
are some of the challenges in general of
maintaining a library of stock over such
a long period of time there's got to be
things that the average person isn't
even thinking about when you're
comparing it and have you ever had any
issues with like mixed up stock or
parents accidentally being lost things
like that every single issue in the book
I've had I can tell you the thing is um
in the old days when you found something
like medicine man like Widow white r
whatever it was that we when you found
that genetic and you actually had that
genetic you would have to cut you didn't
want to share it because that was your
new baby you've been working on it for a
while it was your new baby but you put
it in rooms of people who were growing
stuff for you so you had a backup right
in two or three different places because
many time you got busted and you lost
the mother room or someone followed you
home and they ripped you off or every
story in the book has happened uh
unfortunately and I've lost I've told
you last time I had in four five
countries and I lost in four countries
all my backups only had one left and I
was in jail at that time when I came out
I I mean it was a
incredible relief but um I know the same
thing happened to Neville I know the
same things happened to every Simon he
recently had to redo all of his mothers
because he got the viroid uh I speak to
him quite frequently um he buys pills
for his father from my my company in
Czech Republic you know the CBD stuff so
um we're we're all I'm I'm pretty
friendly with most of them and and we're
all um we talk openly and and uh yes we
do all have problems and yes the the
hardest part of the job has been like I
said keeping Mothers Healthy Mothers
safe and the original genetic labeled
properly in all different countries when
you're not there um there's no doubt
that uh we've lost plants during our
lifetimes um he male how never lost died
a G13 original died uh
uh he he lost various plants you know um
um I I also went through uh uh Hawaii 5
I lost at one stage heavy duty fruity n
uh I lost I have it in seed I have a lot
of this in seed form I have can go back
but the original genetic that I selected
which I made certain things from we lost
but we have the same gene Geno uh um
generation so I can always find the
genotype
but to find the Turin and the all the
other small differences that made that
plant
special uh you know um luckily you know
genetics is based on genes so so you can
recreate things similarly but maybe not
exactly you know and um so I know
Simon's got different like me he's got
different Generations in in in in cold
storage and and you know if you have to
go back and and you got to bust open
something and find find another father
or mother or or nowadays is just mainly
selections um you know and you can spray
them and self them and do all that sort
of stuff but um I I still don't like to
use humanized or autof flowering in in
the the breeding world because I I still
think true male and female expresses
something different but that's just my
personal thing you know there's a lot of
guys proving me wrong um but I don't
know I'm still when it comes to going
back to finding the original parents of
a particular St like Afghan and hay for
example I the Afghan te that made that
up originally from Nev he selected that
and then crossed it with the haze C you
know and the haze a and then you got two
different versions and then we have to
start with selection and that took quite
some time it's not like the first one
that pops out is the right one you know
so and then you keep that live and you
know and it's a established building
block over 30 30 well older than my kids
so still the same so you know wow that's
impressive just the longevity of its
lifespan is incredible and you mentioned
the the haze dropping off you you picked
my ears because I had heard rumors and
I'll be honest I kind of doubted it but
I figured I'll ask you why not have you
heard anything about the haze sea male
still being alive I have it yeah of
course oh look at that I think I'm the
only guy with HC male I mean Neville
gave it to me uh along with pure Haze
and a few other things many years ago
plus all of the seed stuff um how have I
been making the seeds for the last 30
years in in the midst of night I mean
it's still if you have a look um I have
now selected a Hayes AC mail which is
something from old feed that I took two
years to to bring to the table but um
yeah most everything we don't have the
haze any I I don't have it in living
form I only have it in in um seed form
mixed up um that's why like in the mango
Haze the difference between mango Haze
and Super Silver Haze is that is the
haze eight I think it was skunk Haze a
with Northern Light Haze C
um those two were the parents went
eventually they selection and they were
the parents that made the mango a
whereas the haze sea skunk the skunk hay
sea
and not not not like H see that made the
super silver haze line so that went they
were parallel we call the parallel cross
though they're all coming into
eventually pedigree if you put it on a
map you'd finally come to a pedigree
line um when everything had won the
Cuffs Neville used to started like that
when he won something he used that as a
pedigree plant and then we only did
pedigree breeding at one stage and with
the widows and all of that we kept that
going in certain charts so yeah I mean
there's a lot of um and there's a lot of
things that people don't really
understand as such like you know you
sometimes when you select um an old sea
say a northern light one of and Northern
Light 2 and Northern Light five I've got
old seed of that you will select a
female and a male from that thing that
have been working properly so when you
cross it back you you you can use a male
version or a female version that might
be very slightly different giving
different things but they're from the
same genotype and and that way you're
keeping the the
genes consistent and um the expression
maybe is different in the phenotype so
yeah we
no that's that's awesome to hear stok to
hear you've still got it and you know
you mentioned the super silver haze and
the mango Haze and I'd been thinking
about that in the last episode you you
made a comment that Neville had gone
through like thousands of seeds to find
the super silver haze and you'd managed
to do it with just 250 and I guess I was
wondering do you attribute that sort of
more to luck or do you think just the
way you had bred the line differently to
the way he had bred his allowed you to
be like a bit more focused and you
didn't need to pop as many because bit
more of the selection was done in the
breeding you
know it's a daisy it's a really hard
thing it it I mean maybe I I I should
have done a thousand like Neville but
you know I think I found something that
I I could really work with and it was U
when I crossed it to see basically what
we do is we we we put out a bunch of
seed and say 100 seed at a time and you
pick the best three females best three
males you do the combinations you test
those
seeds when you can easily test throw
away a male that is not performing you
see that very quickly in the progeny
test of
seed um if you don't do that you've got
no idea what you selling which a lot of
companies don't do and they have no idea
what they're selling they just say
that's the combination now um your
punters eventually the guys who are uh
buying the seat um they they will expose
you if you're not doing a good job and
if you're if what you said is not coming
up trumps and I mean um to this day it's
like never left what 20 OD 23 years ago
from Europe I mean I can't keep I can't
have old seed batches in the fridges
from from old AC it just I couldn't sell
20y old seed you know what I mean I can
sell 2y old seed because it's still
maturing at that stage in inside but uh
everything's kept in fridges everything
uh is vacuum sealed it all has dates on
it um old seed I offer to uh certain
Growers who who ready to put out a big
lump and maybe they get 80% germination
rather than 100 and they still buy it at
at a reduced rate so we we kind of clear
our stocks a lot of the
time um you know it I don't know how
other people run their companies but you
know you you've got to have backups in
genetics in seed form as well as having
selected um real form mothers I mean
there's no doubt that that's the hardest
part of the job a mother room and a
clone room for me are the Mother
Ship God yeah look kudos to you it just
seems like an overwhelming task the more
I think about it after our last episode
we got a bunch of listeners who messaged
and they said I've never heard of this
Dr gavor and this sounds so interesting
and you know everyone's really curious I
guess the the the the summary of the
overall questions I got from people was
how come you think it didn't catch on
quite as well as the sister lines of
mango hay and Super Silver
Hayes um quite easily can answer that we
lost the
plan we um it it it was a project you
know you don't know that all these
things are going to work and so no one
kept backup we just made uh uh some
mothers we did a whole room of it we
used even the old mothers in the room we
had got compromised we had to go down I
told you the story last time with my
father we had to go and chop it all up
and load it in there was not a living
genetic left of Dr kavan there was some
seed that we'd made with that strain and
maybe one day um I know I've got
it um
um it's not the easiest plan I remember
it if I smell will just come straight
back in my head
but um there's a lot of work to do and
there's a lot of weeks of flowering of
waiting and you know like I don't know I
mean they're big projects to to try to
refine I prefer to go into it um and and
bust open old seed and see what I
find rather than try to try to control
what I'm wanting to find you know I want
to be more open about about it and
sometimes there's some really unusual
like early Queen for example is a very
different smelling unique
genetic um originating from some early
Pearl Early Girl sort of stuff that was
around and that that was it's still has
a different flavor different smell and a
different effect and I think a lot of
the people the seed is incredibly small
and dark and um it's uh it's a real
interesting kind of line and I kept it
going because you know we we've made
some Early Skunk vers we've made a lot
of um plants that have been practical
for Growers with projects in limited
seasons and and I've busted a load of
seeds for those sort of guys or made
seeds specifically for certain guys that
had a six week uh demand you know sort
of flowering season and and and you know
they had to still bust open uh some sees
but they found the six week or the 5 and
1/ half week flowering one and they were
done and and they were in and out of
their operation and uh they're probably
living happily ever after on some little
island now got nothing to do with
marijuana but we had a lot of unusual
people in those days coming to Holland
to buy you know huge volumes of seed and
uh they describe what they were looking
to do and and I think I never heard of
them I never heard they got busted and I
think that that's the successful ones
when you don't hear about
anybody obviously I love that sucessful
you
know yeah look hopefully they're off on
a Caribbean Island somewhere living it
up as a quick followup I guess I'd love
to ask firstly what's the most unique
Turpin profile like weirdest thing
you've ever smelled and as a quick
followup those plants you just
referenced are they the quickest
flowering you've ever heard of or have
you heard of something
quicker oh no they were they were in
some of I mean I've heard people say
that they've um they found even quicker
stuff whether it's finished or whether
it's mature I don't know I wasn't there
but uh I I don't I think a natural cycle
is around you know sort of you pretty
much five six six weeks I mean you know
you can cut things earlier but they're
not I don't think they're ready and and
I I honestly
think when you think it's ready one week
extra you know that's kind of always
been a R the thumb because uh a lot of
um um a lot of the things that you
you're not sure about um happen in these
last two or three weeks of flowering and
and there's some there's some stuff that
still hasn't been exposed with science
that that we need to understand about
that thing like whereas you can find out
the alcohol levels and and all of the
different things when it comes to grapes
and the sugar content and those sort of
things we we need a lot more of that in
in sort of um um in people who have
knowledge about uh what they're breeding
it for what they're growing it for what
the production for what the based
products for what you know there's
there's a multitude of things you can do
now with this plant and so I think
having sometimes a
pure sativa and a pure indic
extract and blending them in different
concentrations you come up with some
really interesting ideas and um
different flavors and what one of the
questions that you ask me was what's the
most unique one well I
mean that's an exceptionally difficult
um question to answer
because um like I said early Queen was
very unusual compared to the fress of
skunks and the and the heavy buiness of
the kushers and the and the the the body
odors or the onion kind of flavors of
the widows and and then maybe some
Menthol alpines of the the hazes you can
have rough
generalizations but specific
plants don't fit into those rough
generalizations when you start to single
them out you single them out for some
reason to do with the old factory system
or or the effect or the one of the
sensors that it it hit you with and uh
and uh up until
um like the CBD crew where with science
was helping us select um these were just
all personal um reasoning behind it and
personal likes and dislikes and that's
why some structures uh I can identify as
Neville's plants from other people and
others I can identify as mine because he
went for kind of a different flowering
cluster that looked more like balls that
fit on top of each other where I I had
more individual flowers that were not
like that structure and so many time I
see it you know that they've leaned
towards those sort of thing I mean you
got to face it Neville was uh out there
he was selling seed before most
everybody commercially to many corners
of the world and I think a lot of that
um you know it's the Adam and Eve of of
the seed companies it was a lot of
things evolved out of that original
stuff you know went
to um different Corners like I said in
and you know um there's some excellent
grows out there that took it on and and
ran with it and um we see a lot of those
strains that now pop up every so often
some people say they created but usually
I think they've been created by
excellent grower and hobby breeders who
have been staying very quiet and don't
commercialize their strain someone did
it for them and and and some ego took it
on and you know and then I call it the
seed circuit nowadays because there's
just there's not a lot of specific
knowledge where certain things
originated from they they're all more
poly hybrid kind of things that you
started at that level and then you went
on with it there so I
mean I mean it's very difficult to to do
that you know um to to to start with
something that you got no idea where the
original parents what they were you
might know theoretically but you wer you
don't have them or you didn't see them
and and what their parents were and
until you get back to a pure form
whether it was an Afghan or a taii or a
Mexican or you know where did come from
and um so I still prefer that kind of um
um kind of knowledge about strains
so of
course now I love the passion the F1
hybrid magic and also for keeping things
pure so you can do that and I mean while
we're on that topic I feel like there's
a lot of variable terminology used in
the Cannabis industry you know lots of
words get used which maybe aren't
necessarily the correct word for that
situation and specifically I'd be
interested in knowing your thoughts on
inbred lines and I guess the question
for me is is it is it about reaching a
certain number of back crosses or filial
breeding or is it more just about
getting it to the point where it
expresses fairly true and that's like
kind of independent of the the number of
Generations how do you think about it
well
um I can tell you that honestly when
when I sold a seed or never sold a seed
um no matter what we started
from after
three possibly four generations of
someone doing it taking that seed from
us and going over to another corner of
the world and then choosing his male and
female and making his seat after three
or four or uh four would be for sure
after four crosses and using that Z it
is so far away from what originally sold
even though you call it the same let's
say Northern Lights because most people
have got a completely different version
of it it might have started with NE he
crossed to
nl2 to nl1 or NL and then he selected
the nl5 from one of those combinations
originally there a lot of stories and
I've got a lot of that Original Seed and
and as I said there's male and female
versions of of of these things so um
some people say that I mix it up many
time now but I use the male version and
the female version or the female version
the my old version to make another line
um I don't have the time and and um to
to go through every specific strain and
that with every single person but and
explain why I do certain things but but
just generally when you uh when when you
you start with um things that have um a
name and then you do three or four
versions away they're still the same
name people will still call it Northern
Light for example but it won't be
anything to do with what originally
looked
like yeah certainly it is one of those
things where it does it does change a
lot and it's almost like it Taps into
this secondary topic where sometimes you
find more novice buyers will have this
misconception that a certain strain in
the F4 is inherently better than the F1
or the F2 you know and you must deal
with this a
lot um you don't know how much I deal
with that um it's really a lot but I try
to be patient with those things because
um not not everybody understands exactly
what they're doing you
know um many times when you make a
selection just again let's say you you
bought a skunk one seed from us and the
[__] seed I call it and and you you you
pick a male and a female and you pick
three and three and then you found your
best female and best male you you you
call it number one and and number one M
for male and and you you you do your
work and you know everybody uh loves
what you're producing and it comes out a
particular way and every is is sweet you
know and you're known for that um
however someone else has taken the same
seed that bought it with you at the shop
and they've gone with their favorite
male and their favorite female and
they've produced something that has got
a lot more flavor it's smaller bud it's
exactly the same name same genotype
completely different pheno type and
you're both calling it the same thing
this is unfortunately um
the the very difficult thing to explain
to everybody in this industry especially
newcomers that that not everything with
a generic name is from the same
generational seed that originated from
and why get so animated and
argumentative about things or so
passionate about things that you would
never know even if they put it in front
of you and you had a vision of it you
wouldn't even know because you were not
born in it was probably different to
what the original version was and uh
there's a selection for um making a
production there's a selection for
genetics to make seed sometimes I many
times like I had a widow that was a a
better producer for uh commercial people
that wanted to use that so I give them a
cut of that whereas selling the seed you
know you get a lot of differences coming
up and and some guys in Australia
hitting it on the head and other guys in
Canada not finding it and think it's a
lot of [__]
so it really depends on the person's
knowledge and and what they're looking
for and and if they know anything about
the origins uh and what they were and if
they actually used it because what how I
describe things when I write it down um
many people have just photocopied or cut
and paste and and they that's
used Forever on every other company that
I've see you know I've see how people
are quite lazy they just take what's
online and and they think it as the
gospel truth but you know I still think
that everything that you crack open or
you select you should do two or three
times in a grow room before you really
understand what you're talking about
there and what flavors are there and how
well it it performs because it's easy to
write a lot of [__] and there's no
one um censoring this because we're
still in a in a pirate industry where
we're allowed we're not legal because
making high
THC uh strains and growing flowers is
still breaking the law of 0.3% THC so
the seed's inside and that's legal once
it's there but flow is not so you know
still to this day every seed company is
based on that and uh which makes them
all illegal actually you know
wow there you go there you go I mean
there's not a legal Seed Company in the
world unless they're medically allowed
uh and licensed you know but all of the
commercial
companies uh the Dutch Pion the serious
the green the Mr Nice the everyone we're
all based on that principle don't get
caught while you're producing seed and
uh because you're over 3%
TFC there you go look we're all very
grateful that you do it for us and uh
just as a quick change of topic you know
I've been thinking a lot recently and I
talked to lots of guests about how
integral it is as like sort of a new or
an upand cominging breeder these days to
be on social media and I see you do a
good job on social media but I wanted to
go back a bit back in the day things
like High Times and the like were kind
of the social media in a sense and they
were a massive player compared to say
what they are today
what was it like for you to have won a
cup like was like the mailbox exploding
the next day with orders like what sort
of an effect did these guys have back in
the day they I agree with you the old
social media work
magazines um their relevance has died
away considerably there now there's a
lot of online magazines and you know
they sort of like online newspapers and
stuff they they're red people still like
to read about I I write for uh for this
magazine actually I just writing an
article at the moment doita it's an
Italian
magazine um and I have been for over 105
issues already you know like 20 odd
years I've been writing for them
so written for weed for every magazine
actually and so I I followed that and
and you're right um the day we
[Music]
W with White Widow
95 uh and it was the second and we won
also with the greenhouse seed company as
the first time we beat Cy seed and first
time we entered actually as a seed
company um we had a post office box that
was uh we didn't have EMA it wasn't a
drop like that so at the post office box
it was
7518 or something in in
Amsterdam was unbelievable amount of
mail coming in every day was clearing it
it was like I I was like a f celebrity
or and everyone wanted the the Widow and
then they wanted the Rhino and then they
wanted the shark and then they wanted
super silver then they wanted you know
Lin and it it was a great time actually
I love the post and there's something
still seriously great about receiving
physical mail um with Christmas cards
full of money and and um you know just
ask asking please and with an return
address with Joe Smith on it um I've
seen everything you know people even s
sending coins from Poland and I it's
like yeah you have to educate them they
really think that that this is all it
was all very ille legal and everything
but you know um uh it magazines made it
look like that and they were we were the
reason High Times went to Holland was
because it was illegal in America and
the only place they could hold the cup
was in Holland so we we had you know
fantastic seats for that game and and we
we were there and it was just purely
because Holland was the first place that
allowed the marijuana Refugee to fill it
own and we were able to do these events
there and of course they were huge for
us in those days I don't think they're
very important anymore um I I actually
don't advertise in I work with one or
two me I don't really do anything with
meaz themes anymore I think they lost
their relevance um I think um um they're
still nice for people to to read
sometimes when you're at a waiting room
or something like that but I don't think
there there's nothing new going on in
the industry uh that quickly to allow so
many different uh uh articles to do with
this particular plant and uh so I think
they regurgitate a lot of the time um
old old stuff that hasn't really changed
and the changes are incremental you know
the scientific changes so every time
there's a big one everyone wres about it
all but uh you know they had their
relevance the '90s was fantastic when I
was with the greenhouse and we owe
probably all of our success to the High
Times magazine at that stage uh then
towards the end it was very corruptible
kind of organization as well and and
there was a lot of
corruptible coffee shop owners and you
we were also you know part of that whole
thing and and so I I particularly
didn't yeah my time had come to leave
Fallen around 98 and so I did a big
thing with Neville that year and then I
left that after that I sold my shares
and I I left and went to SS but
um I did it mainly because I always
wanted to be
pharmaceutical I always thought there
was something much bigger than coffee
shop kind of mentality and I still
believe that to this day and um I've
reached that point where I do sell um a
lot of medical items now that I've made
from my selection of my individual
plants that and not in a synthetic way
in a laboratory how they're meant to be
made for you know the the pharmaceutical
standard and Regulatory body um I still
don't believe that the best people are
um are sitting in the right areas and
making the right
judgments um but unfortunately it's like
you know who's the best person for that
job you know and where're you know it's
like politic it's like everything in the
end you know money talk [__] walks
and and uh seems that the the people who
have a lot of money somehow managed to
uh manipulate a little bit stronger than
people who have less
money yeah isn't that the sad truth but
I I guess if nothing else it's awesome
to hear that you got to experience that
fantasy of you know the mailbox
exploding with orders after that
success I can tell you I mean it used to
I I'd go on my bike down to the post
office it was a little bit out it was
near Olympic stadium in
Amsterdam and it was a big one and it
was jam-packed many time they would they
knew me and they would come with other
stuff because they couldn't fit it in
the box and sometime leave with bag and
go home and it's a fan mail it was
[__] unbelievable I mean people used
to send like embroided uh um t-shirts of
our logo and and they made it home
because I were so inspired by growing
that plant or I mean I had leather work
I had jewelry I had I mean it was
[__] fantastic before social media
before TV before these mobile phone
stupidity but uh now we use it all and
uh I I I try to stay relevant but I mean
I got to tell you that most of the time
the changes of a lot of things come from
my kids like at the moment my son has
been put in charge of changing the the
logos and stuff and and getting the
shops working he's much more better uh
on the let's say the framework of the
the site and uh he's a younger guy he's
16 17 and uh he listens and he learns
and he educates himself and get him put
him in charge of of that and I think
he's doing a really good job like my
daughter he runs the auctions and she
talks to these unusual characters daily
and she seems to be so tolerant I mean
he's doing her own thing as well but you
know I I'm really proud of that point of
view I suppose that
that um I came out of the black into the
white and now it's a family business you
know it's kind of very
sweet that's so heartwarming to hear
that it's now a family business I I love
that and I want to touch on the site
after this but I want to quickly just
ask first in the last answer you
mentioned how popular the White Widow
was and I was hoping I could get a
little bit of the back story on that
because I noticed the majority of the
sources online they say you're the
Creator but some of them reference this
guy ingar I was wondering how does that
guy tie into it and how did you make the
seedline um imma was uh was growing he
was working with us at that stage uh
right at that
stage um and
we he had selected some very good plants
there was no doubt that he had some
excellent
stuff um I worked on making the seed
of um selected
material and so Greenhouse was
definitely the first company to make the
seed version of the white
rder however at that time he was
growing shark I mean I can tell you this
we were growing very similar plants
shark he called
Peacemaker um we c a
shark uh there was probably one or two
other plants that he were the same name
and they sometimes were first and second
in some of these competitions you know
they were they were the same plant uh he
was growing flowers Aran was buying
flowers back from him uh later on I
suppose they when I left they start to
make some seed um they were very
different for
sure um I never shared the mail that I
had um and uh the female was probably
shared with ingma and probably two or
three other Growers at that stage who
were growing commercially for the coffee
shops that
version uh and um so of course you know
and he had uh he he wasn't a breeder he
was a flower producer um his story was
that he he when he was asked about it he
said he found it in a piece of hash a
seed um I I I gave the where it came
from carella Brazil and and then what we
did with it and and I actually that's
why I know that I'm I was the first seed
producer of white
widow um and in Holland there was a lot
of claims of everything I mean I've met
guys uh still to this day have told me
that um that they were the original
creator of Master push for example I
said to them well I have Master push SC
and uh and you know I I know that who
knows but what would the parent and they
they would tell me Hindu Kush Hindu Kush
and I going yeah well I mean that
doesn't I mean that's fine shows me the
area the valley it comes from but you
know I mean h Neville was already
working with so many people in the 80s
were working with Afghan STS already
privately in Australia and Canada and
England
everywhere uh you know showing the goods
that was a different thing and that's
why I always say proof is in the seat
bust open the seed and you'll understand
if if they've done their work properly
if they haven't done their work properly
um and most people unfortunately because
of the no regulations in this seed
industry uh wouldn't know what their the
original was because maybe they they
heard about it they maybe seen the photo
but their version is
different you can give 10 Growers The
Identical genetic and they get 10
versions back that look different so you
got to really understand that there's no
real story that is 100% correct it's I
know my story what I did but uh all the
other he say was usually comes from
people who who were trying to um sort of
commercialize something or or have a
reason or angry or jealous I don't know
I mean I I don't care what people do I
changed my name from One Widow to Black
Widow that was how much I I wanted to go
away from the misrepresented version of
what White Widow was turning into and
and um so I I don't think many people
copied me since
then there's a few but I mean uh I won't
mention them but I mean they critical
mass is a perfect version you know it's
a perfect version in
2000 uh in two
1998 I brought it out first time at one
uh plan of the Year in Spain 2000 2001 I
don't know one of those and it just took
off everyone used it
and then there was critical mass it's in
so many European companies uh to this
day um I still sell the original version
you know so uh probably a better a
better example tell you the truth
because you know most people have it
originated from Miss and I and and you
know a lot of people um always claiming
different things about um different
strains and stuff like that and
um to this day um I never really saw
people
prove things you know so when the The
Growers have bought their stuff and
everyone would normally if it was
authentic and real they would run over
to it maybe it was cheaper maybe that
one brought it out at a you know bulk
rate and they giving better deal and so
people slowly um let's say tainted the
the the color of the water and and to
know what is original oh you know it's
difficult but usually you go back to
where the seed was made to that company
and asked to start there that would be
the most original version of who made it
kind of famous in a seed version and
then that's why people come back to me
that's why people come back to nille
before he passed away but now I mean I
still have um the critical the widows
the hazers a lot of the old stuff that
people were looking for and I kept them
alive and I can only do that with
original plants and and so um you know
there's a lot of stories that came out
that people have gone and busted open
thousands of SE in Africa in South
America now I haven't seen
anything that that um helps the Africans
I haven't seen taking femin SE to Africa
and swapping it for some s it's not
really helping anybody I mean you're
tainting the crop and and and you can
claim a lot of things before before
you've achieved them like a lot of
people do looks like they're helping the
locals and that but actually they're
they're helping themselves and and they
haven't really done anything that's
contributed to say the genan bank of the
world I mean there hasn't been anything
special they're taking um they're
commercialist and and you know some
people believe it and and go along and
they get paid and you know other people
know what they're doing and and know
where their origin started from so I
mean um I think it's better if if for
that as a a purist that you start from
the original story of of of where that
thing originated from because usually
they had the parents to produce it you
know yeah certainly and I mean the
proofs in the pudding right and I guess
as an extension of what you just said
what was it like when you did that
Rebrand to Mr ni seeds because I think
on like a technical and a marketing
level the name change was a brilliant
business move but I also feel like it
must have felt really daunting at the
time like how would have you described
it well it's hard to come from a number
one company that have repeatedly for
four five six years in a row been you
know
outstanding had been the the the New
Kids on the Block had done all the right
things got all the right new tools got
all the right new flavors got all
everything and then how do you
how do you better that you know what I
mean and I thought when I met Howard
um I'd already started in the in 96 I
met him and then I was still with the
greenhouse and with Neville he just
moved over to us he was just with a
coffee shop as share of not with the SE
company but we were and I thought you
know we were the the kind of the dream
breeding team at that stage Neville and
myself and then Iran was of all those
things and it was going well we won all
these things and then I started to think
you know it's a little bit um corrupt
the High Times cup was started to go bit
funny and I thought you know um how it
asked me about making company I went and
spoke to Neville and I said listen mate
you haven't been involved with the seeds
at m at Greenhouse how about you
contribute four and I put in eight and
we start Mr like that and and um I
thought Howard was the best name in the
industry better than even green better
than all of us in Holland he was more he
was uh a brilliant spokesperson and and
really uh wonderful orator and
Incredibly colorful character and a
Gentleman and logically there was
nowhere for me to go higher than where I
was then to Switzerland for medical with
starting a new company with Howard and
Neville uh I owned the company I just
bought in things and gave them sh some
finances and stuff like that along the
way as we build it up but it was
daunting and I had to go down the hill
before I went up the other Hill because
when you reach the top there's only one
one thing to do either jump or walk down
and then uh two things then and I walked
down the hill and started again and uh
of course you know um other people went
on with the story and and um but for me
Integrity is everything and and actually
I didn't have really a problem because I
I know what I've got and um look I
wouldn't have been so successful I
wouldn't have um made the critical
masses and the CBD crew and and done a
lot of these Innovations in the industry
if I didn't have the goods and I didn't
have the knowledge and I didn't have the
support from the scientific community so
um everyone can say what they want they
can say the stories what they want or
they they can claim things but I
mean historically you can see things
that have happened and changed the
industry and I've usually been Vanguard
there you know I've been
there yeah certainly I mean that's what
I meant in the intro one of the the
grandfathers pillars of the scene it's
it's been consistent which is incredible
and you mentioned the critical mass a
few times I wanted to ask you because it
is such a staple especially in the
European seen it's these you know
critical mass feminized seeds cross to
most hybrids these days yeah how did you
make that one was it just line bread
from some big bud seeds what was the
process of developing it oh I I actually
selected uh a
different different male um and and hit
it with the original big butt I mean
Neville's big butt to a different male
that I'd
selected and um it was a reworked skunk
actually to truth a super skunk and so
it it was made to to be you know sort of
a huge flower like like you for like a
forearm of a boxer it was compact
fragrant the effect was incredibly
narcotic everything that a a grower a
commercial grower wanted to do there
with the new work big bud we call a
critical mess and it just took off I
mean and still to this day it's
everywhere um I would say that there a
lot of people use it in strains they
probably don't even know what it is but
it it grows like a sativa and it flowers
like an Inda and that's the the
particular um look about it many people
a bit worried that I've given them the
wrong plant because the long leaf that
coming but it's an Excell excellent
plant uh it's still to this day it's a
incredibly good tool for people who are
trying to bring in weight to their their
crops and and strength so you know you
don't have things like that I mean that
was uniquely Mr Knight that was forget
about all the stories of widows of super
silos whatever you want that was
uniquely set up by Mr Nice and then
after that a lot of the Mr ice strains
were used in CBD crew and that went on
and all of them were selling it under
different names until I made their seed
with their two varieties so you know
that's why I keep saying that I'm not
trying to be egotistical on that I know
what I did and and I know and they know
what they did with me and so we kind of
the honest truth is is one thing and and
maybe the brochures or other things I
don't know you know no of of course we
we trust your word which is you know
where really grateful to have you here
and we've been talking about all these
legendary strains you've made and we
finally need to chat about your new s
that's in the works you mentioned your
son's helping to build it what sort of
things can people expect will there be a
store there where they can grab your
seeds and will the auctions continue the
Shany B seeds.com is
that yeah um yeah we got a project um so
what what I was speaking to the kids
about was that that I I've made a lot of
um Mr Nice has got a shop and it will St
how it is at this moment in time um as a
regular seat company um the Integrity is
impecable we we won't um we won't be
compromising that in any way so but
chunky Bubba seeds it we've I've got a
lot of projects going on and I just
thought I've got a lot sometimes um I
usually keep back a bunch of seed of
each project in case something goes
wrong and I can test it myself from what
people see and and then it sits in the
fridge when everything goes right uh we
go on with it and we and that seeds just
out there so the options came about
originally um but now um my son was
talking to me he said dad you know we
we' seem to have quite a lot of
different things that no one knows about
you know that it's like the project
stuff and I said yeah but I mean just
give it away to people who are less
fortunate or people who come and ask me
for help or something and I send them
batches to see he said yeah he got
enough to [__] feed the Army excuse
me to uh um you know and and maybe we
should just release it under a different
project seed so it's a limited editions
that they we've made them and they're
finished and that's a l a deadline and
and if you want to continue it on and
you want some work and there's always
people looking for projects and and so
up until then i' been offering in in the
some some seeds with uh with the
auctions with SAR and my daughter she's
been doing all of that but I thought you
know um Toody hadn't made sense and and
um he's coming back in the Easter time
and we're going to start to separate
some of these batches and I I'll give
the dates when we made them and that so
people know that but we'll probably
offer a lot of those things some bulk
you 100 back like older Seed where the
germinations are down but there's
definitely some interesting genetic to
be
found um I don't sell feminized a but I
will Shany Bubba seeds because I've made
so many for different
people um I'm not making opinion about
it um um just um make available whatever
seed that we're not using and we're not
keeping for back up um to other people
if they want to you know try it I did a
project like I told you with grounded
genetics with their tsunami plant and
five my thing and I've now offered that
out to different Growers just sent it
out this week and and so that's on the
Miss and icing but it's a Shany Bubba
project so when we get the website up
and everything done uh we'll probably
you know still continue to use the Miss
Forum to discuss shuny B seeds and stuff
but it'll probably just a little bit of
other things that that have been um
working on over the years you know wow
that's really exciting I'm sure everyone
listening to this is ears have perked up
and they're Keen to check it out out of
curiosity are there any like names that
come to mind of strains that might be
offered just to give people an idea of
some of the things they might you know
we we um original hash plant um garlic
Bud um heavy duty fruity
nug um some projects that I've done you
know some uh some original uh pushes
some very old uh
Mexican let's just say the preludes to a
lot of skunks that were Mexican
Colombian and um
Afghan um in them
um
oragas uh Howard Howard not Howard
Neville beg you pardon had a lot of
different um numbered Orga plants and
and we've busted open a lot you know I
think someone criticized me for mixing
up the things last time about Ora but
the nille had everything Ora one two 3
four 5 6 Seven 8 nine cross with Orga 1
2 3 4 and so um the seed I was just
trying to copy what he's busting open
and and what we're we're collecting and
and where it came from originally so I'm
documenting everything I mean I I I keep
it as honest and truthful as where it
come from and and where where the source
was but you know I've got so many
different things like got this zamal
which we've been we worked on quite a
lot and and then we stopped because I
just didn't have any room anymore it's a
big plant you know it's a so I mean
there's so many color colors you know in
the
rainbow um I really have don't have a
plan at the moment um Daisy I really
basically thinking that you know my son
is going to probably direct traffic in
that one but but I've got medical rooms
opening up for me this in swiftland so
I'm getting gearing up for uh busting
open some really really old stuff
80s and you know some 90s stuff and and
just see if we
can uh find some really interesting kind
of fenos and and and differences rather
than all these gush skunk mixtures that
are poly hybriding at the moment and
feel like lollipops sometimes you know
what I mean there's too many uh it's
it's more to the Turin and the high can
you know the high THC and and rather
than the whole plant um kind of natural
whole plant that that happened when it
combined with different sort of Origins
you know um so I you know just kind of
looking for some old old school stuff
again you
know wow incredibly exciting I'm sure
some Jaws hit the ground when they heard
that like you know maybe get some garlic
butd or some more TGA I could never
really find good info is that one like
does it come from Jim oraga or is it
like in honor of him in the way like the
Jack Harris train is and how would you
describe those plans well it Neville
Neville um it originally came from um
Neville's in um he was handed some stuff
to MGA I don't know whether I wasn't
there again uh he told me a lot of
things but uh I busted open the seed
that he he left me with and um there's
definitely you know a lot of um heavy
Afghan influence in this line okay it's
a really for me uh
it's solidly coming to probably an area
in that was like a family Legacy line
that was growing in Afghan for many
years uh I don't know if Jer or Neville
um um docked up the story or whatever
but you know when I bust open some of
those old stuff I can see that there's
some really heavy hitting kind of uh
indicia based plant and I never really
been one for that but I mean it's time
to to sort of release the the Kraken and
let it all open up and and see if we uh
if we can find something interesting I
mean I'm I I've been in it too long to
to promise anything to anyone any
because you never know where you're
going that's the thing with seed you
bust it open and you you're on for the
ride you know and it can really surprise
you um it can sometimes disappoint you
and other times you're elated with the
Eureka moments but uh
you know uh that's the beautiful
adventure of busting open
seed that's it you know one of my
favorite quotes every seed is Like a
Prayer I love it it's uh it's it's
interesting the journey it'll take you
on and you must have been reading my
mind CU you've preempted this next
question perfectly with the best caveat
ever but it's actually a fan submitted
question from one of our listeners and
they said I really want to grow out some
Mr Nice seeds I'm wondering how many
packs does Shanty recommend I pop in
order to hopefully find special normally
I I I say a sample a small sample is
usually 100 seats five pack we we'd sell
we say we sell 15 per pack we put 18 in
give the grower a little bit heads up
and and help in case something doesn't
work for them and we've always done that
but you know four five packs of a strain
is probably the best way to go um with
with uh
if you want to give it a fair thing I
understand if you can't do that you
maybe you know minimum would be 20 you
can't do it with two or three not
regular
seeds you mind if I hit my going to hit
my vapor I got a new vaporizer I just
show you can oh cool that looks Nifty oh
wow it's got your logo on it and it what
it does is it it keeps the cartrid in
the battery at the bottom and it has
different uh different modes you can do
it on so we'll be that that'll be in the
shop soon as well I was going to say
Okay cool so people can look forward to
these nice Vapes yeah yeah it's
fantastic Vape I really I've been
looking around for them I usually use
the C cell stuff that uh when I was
driving if I just wanted it but this
one's just a bit more powerful and um
now some of the the THC mixtures that
we're using which are much thicker um
this is better for it's got different uh
heat um um on the coil different heat
settings on the coil and so um yeah it
actually works really well with some of
the the thick THC stuff you know I'd
love to quickly ask do you feel the
future is in these sort of really
convenient portable pen style Vapes um
well you know it's a bit like analog
digital um I think I think a lot of
people still like to roll joints to this
day um a lot of recreational the ritual
of joint rolling still is uh is a big
factor for some people and um uh I think
Vapes make sense
for medical people who really don't want
to consume combustibles and but they
want a quick hit and they want to you
know the volcano was one of the
wonderful things that was developer not
everyone can carry around a volcano with
a big bag attached yeah exactly
um uh I I think um what we what what you
find is that there'll be a a certain
section of the market let's say you know
sort
of I think it's going to rise because
people want
clean um
non-contaminated nonheavy metal non-
pesticide non insecticide material and
that's coming in these distillates that
we're making now because we have very
heavy um um sort of rules for those
things to be made under GMP basically
and and um they're very clean um if
they're not sort of pirated and um and
we've got all the paperwork so if for me
it it's definitely a medical
tool um and I think it's very convenient
for those who are driving long distance
that don't don't want to roll joint
don't want to stick out the car but they
need a quick hit and that just you know
back pain or something I mean for me
what we what I advise is we make a a
pill basically there's THC and CBD in it
and that's for the long hall and then
the Vape is for when it's starting to
fade you hit it up for another hour or
so and we we use that and so we kind of
prescribed that to people who in the
medical fraternity over here and that's
how we use it um so I suppose that it
will be continually growing until you
reach a a level in the market in
Australia that is maybe you know I don't
know
300,000 at the moment maybe a million
people sign up to be medical users over
the next few years you'll reach a level
and maybe you'll see 20 30% of the
market is doing Vapes and that will
probably be the medical Ones Still the
ones doing the pills or the the oils
then you've got a live section of let's
say um freethinking people who use it
for both and uh maybe uh then there's
going to be uh the black Market's going
to be fed by the White Market eventually
because it's going cheaper than Black
Market in Australia and So eventually
those things will happen naturally as
well I mean you can't help them it's
just Logic for people who are in
different situations you know and so I
suppose I I mean you know I'm just
trying to call it how I see it but I
mean it's probably something like that I
would say
yeah on a slightly unrelated note I
wanted to ask Citrus tpin are really
popular in modern Canabis your Mandarin
and orange flavors and lemons yeah and I
noticed that there isn't really a ton of
citrus in your genetic lineup on face
value is this because you're not
particularly into that is it is it just
coincidence how do you feel about orange
and citrus I think um when you bust open
a few things you get the citrusy stuff I
mean the mango and and the super silver
ha there's definitely uh things that go
towards that um I used to have a uh and
and actually that was one of the other
ones the original orange Bud um which
was really orange I mean what we were
selling in the coffee shops in the early
90s um the Californian orange was one of
those first skunks they really combined
its
flavor specifically to that line of
Turpin and and uh and then there were
some that deviated a little bit were a
bit more lemony and and some mandarini
and and you know I I suppose that the
berries and and the you know they all
sort of slightly there it just depends
on the selection of plants but um I kind
of think that I've got a lot of them in
my plants already it's just that I don't
have uh specifically targeted that that
line of toin but I believe that um in in
in my 40 odd strains that that you can
find specific things there but you know
it depends I I try to keep it open like
I explained to you before
70% similar 15 to each side of the
parents that kind of what I consider
stable genetics and and that allows
hobby hobby go Growers to to go to that
15% either side and find things to to
more pure form to work on so you know I
mean I'm passing the the Baton at at
most of the time nowadays and I'm
starting to think that there's some
really good guys out there that that
need just a hand with some old genetic
tools and and I still got them in the in
the Arsenal so uh pass them out you know
that's that's beautiful to hear and i'
I've certainly heard more recently a lot
of the more sort of newer modern
breeders referencing that they're
actually really keen and specifically
throw your name out there as stock they
want to run through and I have to admit
bit of an oversight in my last question
I have a super silver ha hybrid that is
very citrusy so I want to correct the
record I was I was not good in the
phrasing of that one so kudos to you
yeah no it's it's the truth though there
there are a lot of uh sort of strains
that I don't really write it down I
prefer you to find what you're liking
and yeah I mean I heard that many times
from from those trins that there's a lot
of those things available there so yeah
certainly and and it Segways nicely into
the next question which is like you've
worked with this same really solid base
of genetics for the longest time and I
know in the last episode you mentioned
that for the most part you're not
particularly interested in some of the
more new stuff I'd love to know do you
ever see yourself maybe in incorporating
a little more modern or new stuff into
the Arsenal that project with grounded
genetics is using one of their I think
it it arrived from Skittles and um y
Scout I can't maybe I'm wrong but I know
that he's working with that the all the
new stuff he's a young guy I like him a
lot and uh he's very open and honest and
he's very fanatical about um um his sort
of ideas in his head and he he goes for
them and uh I I was hoping to find
something um we sell a lot of seats to
Morocco you know a lot of bulk seats and
and they're they're looking specifically
for hash strains that are really good
that are producing large amounts of
resin and so I think in this tsunami I
think the nor Live 5 ha with the tsunami
or the Black Widow with the tsunami
might be really
interesting hash
varieties uh also there's a G13 with the
tsunami which uh I think he's already
growing indoors and then with the seed
and look toxic so uh you know I think
um um it will be really interesting
either way we you usually see the year
after we've made the seed some people
have bought it put it out and then that
Poland comes back to Europe and you you
gets a name if it's uh if it's knocking
people out and you know it's kind of or
if it's some sort of extreme flavor or
something like that you know so um yeah
I mean we we work with all different
types of characters and and uh try to
take them all
seriously yeah wow that's so interesting
I guess in a in a long- winded sense you
get to reap the fruit of your labor when
you say when the hash comes back out of
out of curiosity is that you just have
like a a contact who you just offload
seeds to and they distribute it locally
or is it just to like a big farm yeah
we've got uh there's let's just say um
how would I best describe this without
hurting any well there's a few people
who uh um who have been working in in
Morocco for many years for example a lot
of Spanish Dutch English people and um a
lot of them have blocks of land now and
they come and purchase you know a few
hundred thousand seeds at a time of you
know four or five different strains and
then they go over and then the year
later you come they come back with a lot
of the uh um pollen or already semi-
pressed or pressed and and goes on the
market commercial marketers the Moroccan
hashes and you know you see uh you see
this year I saw P pineapple skunk and
different all these different things
that we've been you know sort of making
for different people and and it comes
back as pollen and and some of it's
fantastic you know there's nothing
nothing wrong it's it's again like the
wine Mak the hash maker depends on the
hash maker and how clean they are and
what what press it is is what pass it is
if it's a first pass you know you can
see it's really gray and
incredible Ash and uh then it gets down
to the green stuff which is you know
like the old French papers or or
different versions of just commercial
quality stuff you know probably second
third or fourth PR pass you know so um
yeah when it gets too green I start to
go the other direction
usually yeah sure that that's
interesting to hear there you go I would
have I would have never known while
we're kind of on the tail end of it
we've got a few fan submitted questions
I'd love to run by you but the first one
I want to quickly ask before we jump
into them is a bit earlier on we were
talking about the challenges in
maintaining a library over the long term
and I wanted to ask you there's a common
topic discussed in the community about
sort of the loss of vigor or maybe you'd
call it like genetic deterioration
there's various terms used have you seen
this do you think that plants
deteriorate over time and would you say
that it's genetic drift or just some
alternative sort of deterioration no I
mean that's I think that's a lot of
[__] to the truth I think if you're
preserving plants in a very good
environment and uh specifically we grow
we take our old mothers outside after
nine months and we grow them for one or
two months outside and take a new
cutting a new cutting from the new
growth and bring it in for the next
season and we've been doing that for
some plants that are like 30 odd years
old so uh I didn't see any deterioration
I don't see anything the only thing that
I see nowadays is a lot more people
passing different things to different
people and viruses are now becoming
impacting the industry um and uh the
cleanliness and and that's why I don't
bring in any plants in my Greenhouse in
America or in Europe from anywhere else
we do all of our mothers and all of our
clones are done in the facility for the
production only dry flow go out or seeds
go out from that we're already cleaned
have cleaned uh SC laboratory uh
controlled uh testing and uh if anything
uh like just recently there was a a pink
lemonade clone found in in one
particular room uh in swiftland that was
growing and and it looked like it had
the virus so I had my my uh the CEO of
the company I work with now ber gluton
in Switzerland and I went over he went
there straight away took a sample and
then we took a sample
from our mother room and then I took a
sample from another mother room that I
have espcially away from those ones two
of them were infected don't know how
they got infected and one one of them
was not at all so we killed
everything I've got all of them backed
up in the tissue culture but the thing
is that it's going to take nine months
to grow out before we can get it back so
um the the last one which is closer to
me that was clean and I and I was able
to take a cutting from that and bring it
back into the new into the old area when
they cleaned out everything and sprayed
it all down
and and you know it was not it was maybe
from scissors it might have been from
someone touching something who could
have been brought in from other rooms to
that room because there's a lot of
traffic there unfortunately and you know
that's why I say this um I'm not trying
to frighten anyone I'm just trying to
say you know work clean uh dip in
alcohol um wash your hands use gloves uh
when you're working with mothers and
clones just that area for me is the most
important if you keep that solid if you
grow out mothers each year outside in
the sunlight bring them in you those
sort of precautionary things you'll
never have issues to deal with with
genetic drift and this so-called genetic
drift anyway it's they they they treat
it like a photocopy of a photocopy of a
photocopy I don't believe that because
every year I reset it outside and I
bring it in and it's more fit than it
was the nine months before
indoor light um will eventually it's not
natural um anything growing not
naturally uh for for too long we'll
start to have
some um changes taking place and and and
possibly uh they're not as healthy they
might not be there might be some animal
issues that are going on thing and then
all of a sudden you start to see this
plant not performing very well anymore
and and it's not genetic drift it's just
unhealthy
nonfit mothers you
know yeah certainly and look that's
reassuring to hear that you can sort of
reinvigorate them by giving them that
that uh that season outside that the sun
is revitalizing like that and building
on what you've said you know you've
expressed a pretty clear concern about
the hoplon virus and it does feel a bit
out of sight out of mind which is a bit
concerning do you have concerns that
like a new virus will emerge or do you
think The Hop plon is the one to be
concerned about and it's just going to
persist I
think there are I'm a biologist a plant
biologist in in in if you wanted do
label in the end and of course
monoculture breeds new viruses
unfortunately and and we're
monocultural uh really intensely at the
moment like anything that the um
everyone thinks is riging money you know
all of a sudden you get the big guns
come in set up the big greenh houses and
and they don't really they're not
passionate about the plant they're just
looking for the the business and and um
yes with those sort of uh operations
we're going to see a lot more viruses
coming in the beat J there's a there's a
really a couple of weird viruses already
very minutely affecting things I keep an
eye on everything
um and you know there's one that that
that makes the plant kind of look like a
a cousin it at the top of the plant I
forgot the name I think
beat be virus or something this uh so it
looks very unusual you realize that's
distinctly bacterial issues
and uh I don't know I mean you know if
you Rob Rob Rob Clark made a book hemp
and he he went covered a lot of viruses
in that uh that had already been
established in h for many years already
and they're going to jump they're going
to
change uh people uh networking and
crossing over and passing plants I mean
that's for me it's natural we have
viruses living in in in the atmosphere
and and around us but uh I think if you
want to keep your room clean um and
devoid of that sort of stuff then have a
quarantine if you're going to bring in
plants into a certain area quarantine
them in a in another tent first for a
few weeks make sure or or do a flowering
make sure that everything's clean and
you're using clean tools before you let
them come into the main room so we we do
a lot of that protocol nowadays with
everything and and I don't allow people
who don't need to be there to be there
it used to take you know a lot of people
around and show them around and
everything like that but now it was to
our detriment in the end and and you
know some so basically we're close shop
now and I I don't really come out in
public I don't do the show so much
anymore I don't do any of that but I
mean I'm still available online and I'm
very easy to talk to with the if you're
a grower and and um I I I love to be
involved with the kids helping them and
and they're helping me and and it's kind
of I find it in a really good stage at
the moment of life where uh the next
generation is uh I don't say that
they're going to be always interested
but at the moment they they uh they need
some Financial Independence and so I've
got them on a a carrot at the moment and
and hopefully they they do they bring to
the table stuff that I've got no idea
about which is pretty evident they are
and so we're we're a pretty good team at
the moment I really like
that wow yeah look understandable that
you have to tighten the belt with the
quarantine given the viruses and gosh if
only we could all be so lucky to have a
father like yourself dangling such an
incredible carrot that's uh that's
awesome to hear you want I mean you're a
sweet
guy um you mentioned the Next Generation
I wanted to ask you because I know you
work with some big facilities the new
generation of lighting are you sold on
LEDs do you prefer the old school HPS
metal H well not sold on anything that
doesn't prove itself
I um I use a lot of LEDs in the mother
rooms um with a I've gone back to
combination um so in my mother rooms
I've still used some um Sante uh
Phillips uh um High Press
sodium U interspersed with a lot of LEDs
and stuff so I've got a blend of of
spectrum there um the mother
respond well they're good the Clones um
LEDs fine and I use the LEDs in the
Clone I used to use T light you know
fluoresence and and I've always very
soft cool cool white you know kind of um
tubes um so I've G on everything but um
you
know uh in Big Greenhouse in America
we're basically not on LEDs at all we're
only we just changed all the glob on 600
Waters um and we're producing
um huge amounts on living soil and and
excellent quality so uh you know I'm
open to everything it's whatever what
I'm not a guy that that is the first on
the Block to to get new technology I
like to see it proven I might be the
first on the Block to to try out new new
reads and things like that and and the
double in in making keeping males alive
there's no value for people keeping
males alive most of the time and
I'm driving males from five different
countries to all you know I mean my and
there's no value for anybody you know I
have to pay them to keep them there and
and growing in so yeah my jobs uh vary
depending on what jumper I'm wearing
that day and you know now we make
flowers for for certain companies and in
Europe and in Australia and kind of you
know now we we're trying to spread our
wings a little bit and while the the
market is still emerging in Europe the
the legal Medical Market still not tight
and and with a distinct Direction in
Europe and and as it's not as developed
as in Australia or America or Canada at
the moment and and so we're we're just
getting aligned for that time I think
it's coming this year I believe very
strongly that France and Germany will
will um will be at the Forefront of
those things and you know some other
countries Italy Spain and Greece maybe
they're they're lingering behind
watching you know Europe's not one
country it might sound like it's a
conglomerate but it's still they've
still got different uh cultural
differences you know and and there
there's definitely
um some differences in in the stigmas
unfortunately and and but um in Swiss
I'm we great I mean I I I really
appreciate the Swiss for for that reason
that they actually allowing a lot of
stuff to happen take place indoor
facilities in certain things they know
what we're doing we have to announce it
and we have to try to describe it as
best we can before we've done it then
they come along and check and you know
they they they do what they say and we
do what we say and as long as that's all
going along pretty okay our uh our last
question for this interview I've been
waiting to ask you what in your opinion
is some of the best genetic stock you've
ever worked
with well I
suppose um if I have
to think about it over all my
career
okay um I was
probably the most excited of my life
when I came across U when I we started
to develop V something from Main AR in
Australia many years ago when I was at
University we called it m Madness but
there was a lot of diff I think we
talked about this last time I just
remember growing this from seed with
with Rob the one of the guys that with
the main grower and smuggling it down in
pillows you know someone in the pillows
and down at Melbourne University and
goes in a matter of hours you know it
was like it was um it never disappointed
it was one of these strains that it's
like Neville's
Hayes it was very similar I I still see
no matter what anyone says uh how you
use the name Haz or mal or whatever it
was an early development of of of
definitely Colombian
Tha things in that that time you know
and I I we used to grow it year after
year from seed and and it was it never
disappointed it was an exciting thing
and then I came across it when I bumped
into Neville in Europe many years later
in the the the haze version so I that's
why I always called it an Australian Haz
but uh I can't prove that it came from
completely different sources I think but
it might not have the origins originally
the countries it came from it might have
been very similar we weren't there and
so uh you know like I I said to you many
times mate that uh we the hands of
nature at best and we get things from
the last generation and they got things
from the generation before and hopefully
we improve on it and and we don't sort
of uh you know sort of diverse um um
deviate sorry from from the the good
direction and and just make it
commercial we we kind of continue
there's a certain amount of breeders
that do a really good cottage industry
job with certain strains and they don't
need to do 50 strin they need to do two
or one and they do that incredibly well
and uh they should be uh acknowledged
for that as well I mean there's a lot of
really fantastic Growers out there that
have been keeping things alive for a lot
lot of years and um it's just timing of
my life was probably I was in a lucky
situation you know and I had all the
guys around me I didn't know they were
the guys at that time you know we're
just normal guys smoking a joint
drinking a glass of wine or something
you in
Amsterdam wow in incredible I'm I'm so
stoked to hear again how special the
Mullen bimy Madness was to you and the
similarities with Neville Hayes I think
that just about brings us to the end of
it for this one any comments or shout
outs you want to make no I just
appreciate you taking the time to uh
delve into some of these uh things and I
hope uh I I stimulate uh your your um
your viewers uh into and if they ever
want to ask questions they they're more
than welcome to come to the website and
and uh and talk directly there um I'm
pretty approachable I don't I treat
everyone as equal so we uh and boys and
girls every type of whatever and we're
all fine with that you know we're in an
industry which is trying there's still
some people in there trying to maintain
a good integrity and try to do the right
job and and I think we're linking up
with a lot of them so I still think that
there's um as much as the cops of
negative um feedback from even people
within the industry I think there's a
lot of great people and I'm hoping the
direction that takes will be the right
one eventually and uh we'll be there for
the right reasons you know absolutely I
highly encourage everyone to go check
out the Forum go have a chat to Shanti
himself a massive massive thank you
again Titan of the industry
Shany barar of Mr Nice Seedbank thanks
for chatting to us today look forward to
the next
[Music]
one so there you have it friends thank
you so much for making it to the end and
a big thank you to Shanti Bara for
coming back a second time share some
incredible and inspiring words if you
love this episode please consider
supporting both the patreon as well as
Mr ni seeds check out the new website
shanas seeds.com as well as the websites
of our incredible sponsors if you're
looking to transition from combustion to
vaping check out our good friends at dap
you will not be disappointed cheap
affordable and Incredibly efficient
units likewise check out our friends at
Pulse sensors if you want to make sure
that your garden is dialed in and you
are tracking all of the variables that
are going to ensure your next Harvest is
the best to date you've got to get
yourself a pulse guys it's a
no-brainer in order to ensure that your
garden is pest and pathogen free please
check out our friends at copit they are
the number one in BIO predatory
technology the spidex vital sachet have
been a game changer the slow release of
spidex fighter will make sure that your
garden is spidermite free copit thank
you so so so much for your
support likewise a big shout out to our
friends at Organics alive for all the
most incredible powdered organic
products usable in all systems both
organic and hybrid people winning cups
around the globe with their products
it's no surprise because the quality is
second to none a huge thank you to
Organics alive we recommend them highly
please check them out if you want to
take your organic game to the next
level finally massive shout out to our
good friends at CS here now they got
heavy days beans go check them out guys
I promise you will not be disappointed
they got all the latest drops the
hottest breeders fem Auto photo period
CBD whatever you need they're here to
help you out a massive thank you to our
friends at CT now
and big love to the patreon gang we love
you so much thank you for supporting the
show they got Early Access to this
episode over a month ago if you want to
get extra content please consider
supporting the show you score yourself
genetics a whole bunch of swags and our
sponsors and so much
more so that just about brings us to the
end of it for this
one a big thank you to you for getting
to the end yet again and for the
support Big Love is always from your boy
heavy days
signing
off see you
[Music]