foreign
[Music]
welcome to the next episode of the
podcast a cannabis podcast for budding
enthusiasts
as always these episodes could not
happen without the Fantastic support of
our sponsors
[Music]
seeds here now you know I'm in love them
best in the business if you're looking
for a North american-based seat option
featuring the latest and greatest
breeders all the hottest drops and guess
what they got an incredibly Schmick new
website with fantastic new prices
they've been slashing the cost of
everything to give you the best deal
while still offering their guarantee on
both satisfaction and germination don't
delay best in the business thank you so
much
likewise huge shout out to our friends
simply souvenirs our homies holding down
the fort in Europe if you're in the UK
or Europe and you're looking for a
hand-selected range of Boutique genetics
from both local and international
breeders check out Simply souvenirs they
have the best customer service in the
game as well as new drops occurring on
the regular including some amazing
smoking accessories Vapes dab
accessories and rigs so much more check
them out Simply souvenirs we appreciate
you guys
oh
in order to make a name for yourself you
not only need to find and make some good
genetics you need to run them properly
check out our friends cope at biological
systems they have all the best Solutions
in the game for all pests and pathogens
the best way to keep your garden happy
healthy and pumping on all cylinders is
to be proactive don't wait for an
infestation guys get on to it now grab
yourself some massive RM if you're
worried about aphids or some spidex
vital if you've got spider mite issues I
promise you guys knowing that your
garden is pest and pathogen free is next
to heavenliness there's nothing better
than a high quality crop that is 100
free of contaminants and Shout Out
Copart biological systems we appreciate
you guys so much
likewise you've got to make sure you're
getting the most out of your guards and
for that we need to give a big shout out
to our friends at Pulse sensors if
you're after more yield more resin
higher quality concentrates and flowers
you need to get serious about your
growth so get a pulse there are many
hidden variables that can hold your grow
back but you simply may not even be
aware of VPD is a common one you can't
feel it you can't see it you don't know
about it but let me tell you your plans
do if you get a pulse sensor and dial
the parameters in you will see your
plants responding in front of your eyes
from a single tent to a single room to a
multi-facility operations don't hold
your next prop back get serious get a
pulse Center
[Music]
a huge shout out to the patreon game if
you guys want to get early access to
upcoming content unheard exclusive
interviews with some of your favorite
guests as well as access to ad-free
content and genetic giveaways going down
monthly check out the patreon
www.patreon.com forward slash the
podcast
so on this episode we're joined by
highly requested guests
breeder I've wanted to chat to for a
very long time
on this episode we have none other than
the genetic genius snow Heights
[Music]
here to discuss all things land race
breeding
preserving
history future
[Music]
so much more
let's get into it
alrighty gang we're here for another one
and on this episode we are extremely
grateful to welcome the genetic genius
behind snow High seeds the land race
lover and breeder extraordinaire himself
snow hi thank you so much for joining us
today
ah thanks for having me
it's very good to have you on the show
one of our most requested guests so I'm
sure we're gonna get a lot of fanfare
for this episode but I want to ask you
because you mentioned it a bit earlier
to me how's the garden looking today
have you been in there
oh yeah the garden is uh every day so
yes I've been in the garden lately and
what are you working on at the moment
um right now I'm working on a bunch of
Mexicans
um ties some Hawaiians Colombians
I'm trying to bring back some of the
old Colombian red type stuff
um you know people were familiar with uh
like wackyweed it was actually like the
resonance versions of the Colombian red
or the punto Rojo so I've been looking
for the um
the phenotypes that are more specific to
that
um I'm trying to bring back some of the
favorites that people love with the
Colombian gold
um certain varieties of Colombian gold
that are kind of more sought after than
what people know as Colombian gold
because a lot of the Colombian gold
was actually either like a low lead
Colombian red that was bleached or
another Colombian that was like bleached
in the Sun so a lot of what people think
is climbing gold was something other
than what it was
oh and um I'm also working on some
different ties I'm analyzing the
different varieties trying to narrow
down
where the chocolates came from I have a
good understanding of where they are but
I'm I'm verifying what I already know
with what I'm finding
um trying to prove from
Me growing the the varieties of
chocolate Thai that were here in the
states that were sold to sticks and then
taking what was uh or land race or
heirloom varieties grown in Thailand and
Cambodian Laos and trying to figure out
what the genetic stock was that created
these what was their names
um that the Growers were using for these
strains and then as it transship to
different countries like Australia
United States uh Europe
um what was what was the strains
beforehand and what were they um when
they got to like the sellers that people
received so I'm trying to narrow that
down
um a bunch of Highland ties mango ties
purple ties
um Juicy Fruit ties lots of different
uh squirrel tail Thai stick Fridays just
trying to narrow down what the
provenance of these are where they came
from what provinces were more the
majority of these varieties came from
were they lowland Highland
um the microclimates associated with
them the people the history of those
people did they come from China did they
come from India
um that type of thing uh and then I'm
trying to bring back some Hawaiian lines
um that people love which are easier to
grow you know they have the resin and
the high types that people love and I
just something special that you know a
lot of people
really love are the wine types so
um and the Mexicans I'm trying to bring
back some of the heirloom stuff that
people are growing still in Mexico and
some of the older stock that I'm trying
to preserve so that more people can be
um familiar with these lines that I grew
up smoking which is some of my favorite
um of all the different types of herb
Mexican cannabis is a special thing to
me
wow I think one of the catchphrases I
say on this show is you've just given me
so many Avenues we need to go down that
was truly uh fantastic I guess the first
place to start is you know you mentioned
the Colombian red and gold how would you
give someone like myself who has never
been able to have either unfortunately
how would you compare and contrast the
two
well um the Columbian gold let's start
with that Colombian gold
is it ever a really unique High compared
to other varieties it's it's an own it's
its own uh variety uh the high is mostly
in the head
um it's clear
um euphoric it's psychedelic colorful
but does it affect the body so you get a
all in the head type of high the tastes
are
honeysuckle astringent kind of affects
the nose but it's light it's a light
Airy Aroma when the Smugglers went to uh
Santa Marta the Sierra Nevada uh the
peninsula where all the trans shipments
were happening
um the Bales that they were getting they
were getting you know 200 300 bales of
uh Colombian at a time the Columbia Gold
was maybe
you know one bale maybe two they had to
go to
um Farm to farm and they were only able
to collect enough for maybe one to two
bales
uh
you know at a time so it was very rare
that people actually had the true uh
Colombian gold
um there was varieties that were called
Lamona or La Mota La Mota means high on
a hill and Lamona means the blonde those
were like the uh arachio Indians the
Indians that were up in the High Sierra
Nevadas they had a variety of clemming
gold which was more of a
like a Highland Colombian and those were
more of the longer flowering varieties
that were gold red purple
um Turned orange and rainbow different
colors
um and that's a real special stuff now
there was also lowland Sierra Nevada
Colombian gold and those were the
smaller plants also very nice but not
quite as longer flowering as the
Highland varieties
so that was kind of the climbing gold so
climbing Golds the the
um majority of them will turn purple and
gold
um some rare phenotypes will be red and
then rainbow colored
for the
opposite side which is uh the Colombian
Punta Rojos the Colombian Reds
those were more of a narcotic High the
reason is that it has a CBD content in
it so it it actually has like a body
effect unlike the Columbian gold
um so there's uh CBG CBC
um I would
believe that's probably thcv as well
Delta eight and nine THC as well and
then a lot of different
um cannabinoids flavonoids and uh uh
anti-science the things that change the
colors of the plants as you'll find with
the Colombian Puerto Rojos they'll turn
red blue purple
and shades that are more darker kind of
like the Panama Red at one time Panama
Red Panama was part of Colombia so a lot
of the punto Rojos were actually
you know the same as Panama Red but the
varieties that were closer to the border
with Panama now
um were actually more the jungly types
they were hotter they dealt with more
resin they had to deal with the more
extremes of the heat because they were
more of a jungly type
so when people think of Panama Red it's
actually like a Colombian variety so
it's closer to Colombian puto Rojo
um
and so you get these um longer different
tie types that are more physical
um people actually uh when you had a
really good Colombian red thought that
the Columbian red high was more uh more
favorited than the Colombian Golds and
the Really resonance varieties of
Colombian puto Rojo were what what
people called wacky weed and those were
the very resinous dusty types that
people would sell the resellers would
cut wacky weed but it was Colombian
punto Rojo
wow what a comprehensive rundown I feel
like I've learned so much because what's
interesting is that the Colombian as a
as a broad umbrella has really come into
the Zeitgeist because I think that with
the Advent of the black Cuban Haze
becoming very popular in the past few
years we hear a lot about the Colombian
dominance you see in that cut and it got
me wondering do you think do you think
Colombian is one of the unsung heroes in
Haze because a lot of people including
myself used to attribute a lot of the
magic of haze to the tie but I'm now
starting to think more and more was the
Colombian really contributing a lot more
than I maybe gave it credit for
well there's there's more than one Haze
so you gotta you gotta narrow it down to
is it um
is it the haze that first came around
the first Haze was more Mexican punto
rojo with the Colombians that were
coming around so
um Mexican and Colombian were more of
the composition of what people knows
Haze there's Old Timers Haze which seems
to be all Colombian
which is not even not even Haze it's
just considered a haze but it's not what
people know as Haze so those two can be
considered confused because they look
the same but they are from Colombian
genetics
uh but what a lot of people believe is
the special stuff are the Colombians
that ran them the Purple Haze is from
the Colombian purple variety so it could
be from the corinto side or from the
Colombian Punta Rojo side that you get
these purple phenotypes also there's uh
the purple haze from the Colombian Punta
Rojo I mean Colombian um Santa Marta
gold
uh so the combination of these different
Colombians and the purple phenotypes got
what people know as Purple Haze
um later if you're looking at original
Haze
that was messed with with Sam when he
went to Holland they added the ties then
because what they had for Hayes was kind
of lacking so they added the different
hazes and the Kerala and the Vietnamese
in different lines
wow that's incredible so just to clarify
if someone said to you what do you think
the original genetics in Haze was what
would you answer with
huh well it's
me and Neville used to talk he was a
friend of mine I never got to meet him
in person but we used to talk via Skype
um so
I don't want to say anything that would
he was very Coy with his answers
um
he received the seeds in New York
um from some people that were doing the
shipments for
you know they weren't considered
they weren't they they weren't the
people growing the varieties so these
were like the resellers that got the
seeds but the seeds that were
uh turned into original Haze and Devil's
Haze seemed to be more like the Mulan
Benny Madness
wow bombshell
but you know
um
it's hard to tell what what you see from
some of the pictures and what some of
the seed banks had received some of that
stuff seems to be Thai dominant like the
original Haze for Flying Dutchman
some of the earlier stuff seems to be
Thai
um dominant so it's original Haze Thai
Dominic so
you know was it Sam Sam stuff that was
used
with the haze that they got and they
kind of went from there
um or was it you know original Haze that
was
previous to that
um it's hard to say but it seems the tie
stuff was more
original Haze later on but if you look
at some of the structures like now's
Hayes
um some of the phenotypes look like mole
Unity Madness which you know they're
tied derivative so that would make more
sense I was assume
if you look at some of the older
pictures of the haze and some of the
people that were breeding it had said
um Mexican Puerto Rojo was one of the
the
the portions that created Haze and then
the Colombians that came along with it
Santa Marta gold Colombian punto Rojo
um but
I'm growing out all these varieties
trying to
derive what exactly was there trying to
recreate what was the magic from those
lines and then trying to make something
that is uh
new but using the best varieties that we
have or able to use now
oh that's incredible I don't suppose by
any chance you've talked to Bodhi about
this he he kicked that idea around a
year or two ago to me he said someone
should recreate Haze and just and he was
telling me he had a Vietnam that could
work well as the Thai
well actually Bodhi uh Coastal and I
we've been working on this for the last
couple years working on our separate
parts of it so this is an idea that
we've been throwing together trying to
work towards over these last few years
so we're working together trying to get
that uh
to fruition
I'm so stoked to hear that I he he did
tell me that I sort of didn't want to
throw that out there unless you're
comfortable with it so that's that's
great no no we're told with that
it's exciting I mean you know I I got to
chat with a kegu and um he's he's Keen
as well but just to loop back to what
you said so do you believe then that uh
Hayes like a two-parter here do you
believe Hayes has any Indian genetics in
it and as a follow-up recently we had a
gas of Swami on and he said that um he
suspects the tie that we see in Hayes
these days was the squirrel tail do you
have any thoughts on that
okay so there's
when you think of haze Haze has got to
be
um what was sold by you know uh
my Neville
and what was done by um previous people
in Santa Cruz but this wasn't it's not
old-timer's hits so
um what people think is haze it's got to
be like original Haze that's that's Haze
but Old Timers Hayes is considered a
haze but it's not the same thing so
those are two separate
varieties they're not the same
they may look the same but they're not
the same if that makes any sense
um so the tie the tie that was in it uh
squirrel tail uh who knows which which
one's squirrel tail uh there's different
there's quite a few different squirrel
tail ties there's quite a few mango ties
there's purple ties there's Highland
ties there's purple Highland ties
there's low lintizers uh golden ties
lemon ties
there's so many different ties which one
could it be
um I don't know for sure but I'm trying
to figure that out by growing out all
these different ties
squirrel tail is kind of a
uh
you know a kind of a
broad naming of a lot of these strains
the squirrel scale is kind of to depict
these these Thai varieties that have uh
the you know the long colas it would
cause the Zorro they call them in Mexico
you know the the foxtails the squirrel
tail is kind of like the same thing so
it encompasses a lot of these different
Thai stick varieties so it could be a
Thai stick
um or a squirrel tail it's kind of
income in compassionate like a total
name for a lot of different ties but
it's not just one specific tie if that
makes any sense
yeah okay interesting interesting so it
sounds like Colombian definitely plays a
bigger part in it all the more I
initially suspected do you think that
people do see tires with a bit of Rose
shade glasses and maybe Colombians do
deserve a bit more interest because
that's largely been my experience that
people seem to be more interested than
in ties than Colombians for the most
part
well I think uh ties are very special
um and there's a lot of different ties
so uh but a lot of that is Nostalgia you
know a lot of the 60s and 70s you know
people grew up on sticks
um so there's there's a lot of nostalgia
there but from the haze portion
um a lot of what people love about the
haze is the Purple Haze uh the colors
and a lot of that has to do with
Colombian majority of it being Colombian
either all the way Colombian or Mexican
Colombian and then later on
um
they added you know Vietnamese and some
of the other lines
yeah sure so just to look back you
mentioned your friendship with Neville
and this is a discussion Point fans are
always interested to hear more about gas
from Swami uh said that you know he he
knows Dwight and from what he had heard
there's a few sort of I won't say
unreleased Neville strains but just some
some of his work floating around that
never really made it out there I'd be
interested to hear your you know sort of
recollection on your friendship with him
and any interesting sort of discussion
points around his work you might be able
to share
uh well Neville he was koi with a lot of
his answers he didn't want to give too
much
um
you know I asked them directly where a
lot of this genetics came from you know
that he brought over
um I kind of theorized that
um the guy who did um
that was it since Amelia tips
out of Oregon
um
yeah I I think his name was Tom oh God
I'd have to anyway Tom flowers or
something like no I can't be it's
something I'd have to go back and get
the name but I I kind of theorized that
some of the stuff that he was working at
the magazine
um he introduced Neville to
so that was a portion of those genetics
um that he received um the other portion
of those genetics came from Jim Ortega
the Ortega Indica the G13
um and a lot of other lines so Jim uh
Jim should get a lot of the credit for a
lot of the genetics that Neville had
um
because a lot of it came from him
uh Neville also said that when he did
breeding he thought that anything that
was bred to like F4 was pretty much true
breeding anything past that was kind of
being redundant
which I kind of argue with it just
depends on the variety
yes certainly I mean one of the points
we hear discussed a lot was that
um he was a guy who for some people was
someone who was hard to get along with
you know and a lot of people have sort
of resonated with the idea that for some
people it had to be like a separation of
the art and the artist because he uh
burned a lot of bridges and stuff
at the same time a lot of other people
just have sort of straightforward
friendships with him would you describe
your friendship with him as fairly
straightforward or was he like a complex
guy that he gets described as at times
um
he was definitely complex but he was
also straightforward I mean he had uh he
had sickness as well only we would both
have you know
problems with um
in the disease states he had a tick-born
disease kind of like Lyme disease here
in the United States it was a tick-born
um uh variety that was attacking his
system
um from Australia so he was sick uh was
that tick-borne disease and you know it
definitely
led to his his poor health and um
you know that was difficult for him to
get around and to do things because he
was constantly in pain
um
but he definitely wanted to try to he
would he wanted to be honest as he could
with what he was doing but um
you know some of the business
relationships that he
got into weren't necessarily
thought out
you know he he get into it and then um
realized that some of the people flaked
out on him I won't specify who those
people were but um
anyway
um
yeah he seemed um pretty straightforward
for the most part but there's a lot of
Secrets there that he didn't want people
to know
um I don't know if people know but
Neville
he he was in Holland because uh his
family history was from Holland so his
family came from Holland but he went
there for treatment for
um for Narcotics heroin
um so he's being treated by the the
Dutch government and after going through
treatment
um the Dutch give money
um for rebuilding their lives and they
could take that to build a business so
Neville took a loan out and created the
seed bank with that money from the the
treatment program which they didn't
really like but um you know that's he
was able to create a business that way
um and through his knowledge of fish
breeding he was able to use that
knowledge for fish breeding and to
breeding cannabis and he went searching
for different varieties uh in
Afghanistan and Hungary in different
places trying to get varieties that he
used at the seed bank and then
eventually he went to the United States
and got varieties there
yeah that's a great synopsis I um I've
actually heard a few different stories I
suspect yours is correct because you've
spoken to him but I've now heard three
or four different animals people say he
was a breeder I've heard Birds dogs cats
and now fish I wonder which one it is
probably the fish
fish it was that's what he told me and
that made sense
um I don't know about the other ones
fish is definitely the way he told me
um and why would you uh you know fish is
kind of a strange thing and uh you know
fish multiply and you kind of get the um
the Valero Generations that one's f2s
out of it so it makes sense that he used
that
um for his breeding purposes you know
he's kind of used you know that type of
breeding into what he used for plants
yeah certainly and you touched on the
seed bank and I wanted to ask you
there's a growing sentiment among the
real heads and breeders that I know of
that is essentially along the lines of
Neville's stock or stock from the seed
bank is some of the most consistent
slash killer stuff you'll ever get
what's your experience with it and do
you think it probably is some of the
best gear that was ever available so to
speak
um well no I don't necessarily think
it's the best ever the the stuff came a
lot of it came from the United States so
it came from like private breeders and
Growers that were you know doing their
own breeding practices and then they
were brought over and then exposed to
the rest of the world
um
some of the the earlier stock he was
able to get like in Afghanistan uh was
good at first
um but then it was watered down through
Dutch practices of homogenation and
early flowering so these a lot of people
think that that a lot of
Afghani for instance are all
broad-leafed and they're all fast and
you know Indica looking plants they
don't realize that the best varieties of
Afghani were actually narrow Leaf fried
East and those were like the hash
you know for hash
um but they were longer flowering
heirloom varieties
but because in the mid 70s
um there was so much
um want for Afghani hashish that they
couldn't keep up with production so back
in the in the past they'd keep you know
big wheels of hashish with the family
heirlooms and crests imprinted on them
but all those old hashish slabs were you
know sold and then they had nothing left
so what they did was incorporate the
heirloom varieties with the the
varieties that were along the the sides
of the roads the more the tribal types
of hash the stuff that was faster
flowering not quite as good but produce
a lot of resin so they Incorporated the
two and then
it watered down The Afghani genomes the
the varieties that were people got
exposed to after uh like sembi 7 76-77
that started going downhill
um the king got ousted
um
in I think 76
uh 77
um King uh
Zaire Shah but he had maybe 30 40 Years
of Peace maybe even longer in
Afghanistan and what happened was
prior to the paraquant spring in 1979 in
Mexico and in Jamaica
they the CIA had sprayed paraquat
um on the poppies and the hash producing
plants as well as the food crops in
Afghanistan basically ruining their food
supply so basically starving out the
people so once they had permission to do
that they left the CIA and the people
had nothing else to grow so they were
starving Their Food Supplies got ruined
by parapod they were sickened by the
paraquant and so they went back to what
sold and grew the fastest which was
Cannabis and poppies
so in in a way we kind of caused
um you know the the terrorism and all
the stuff that happened later on
um then right after that had happened
there was people starving it caused um
uh the people to revolt the the King was
ousted the cousin went into being power
and then the Soviets um invaded and then
we know what happened from there
um
just like the Taliban
um is going back into Afghanistan now
and taking control a lot of the
varieties that were
freed up
um after the United States went in there
and started coming available are now
going to be disappearing uh same as what
happened after the Soviets invaded those
varieties that people were
um able to get and had you know for many
decades and years had able to get these
nice great afghanis varieties and after
that they weren't able to get these nice
heirloom Afghani lines because of
the invasion of the Soviets
but back to the seed bank
um I think that all over the world
there's lots of breeders that have been
growing these lines a lot of land race
land races and then develop their own
acclimatized stock
those the unsung heroes the the
Smugglers uh The Growers the people that
went to Harm's Way to gather these
varieties
um
those those are the people that should
be recognized and a lot of that is
um not known so a lot of these heads
um you know went through dangerous times
of Camp helicopters in California which
is California against marijuana
production very
um very harsh and stringent laws against
cannabis
um
but yeah there's a lot of unknown people
that should get credit for the stuff
they did to create some of these
varieties and to sustain them
certainly we've heard that sentiment
before that Neville uh certainly was
standing on the shoulders of giants in
what he released and made commercially
available
I'd be interested to know have you been
tracking at all
um the the Northern Lights reproductions
that have been done by Todd McCormick
and CSI slash Matt Riot um it's from
Northern Lights Greg who it seems to be
the legit source of Northern Lights do
you have any thoughts on that have you
seen that
honestly I haven't been online so I
don't know what other people are doing
um I've heard stuff
um but I I don't know what they're
claiming or what what it you know I have
really nothing to say about it because I
I don't know
um
I remember getting Northern Lights in
the 90s when it wasn't a seed line and
what I remember from the the northern
lights that we got it was a very highly
resonance almost blue white crystalline
herb very
um
very narcotic but also made you high
very Stony stuff but unlike the stuff
that was produced by the Dutch later on
that was you know sold as Northern
Lights
um so
yeah I don't know what there was a
Northern Lights variety by classic and
his story is that he um he met up with
um Indian gym up in Washington on a
fishing trip and he was able to get some
of the Northern Lights from him so I've
grown that Northern Lights and that
one's very strong and uh high quality so
other than that and the Northern Lights
I smoked back in the early 90s
um the the Dutch Northern Lights is
something different what other people
are growing I have no idea I'm not
following anybody else so
um can't really say
I would love to quickly ask you what's
your thoughts on nl5 Haze because there
has been a notable Resurgence among you
know consumers and Growers and I guess
more broadly it often does get given the
title of sort of the poster child of
cannabis how did you feel about it is it
a special one for you or just a more
well-known one
it's just a more well-known one it's you
know it's a
a higher yielding hazy-ish
um and a conceiva multi-poly hybrid
um I think it gets a lot more
um
publicity than it should
there you go well look I mean following
on from that I had a number of questions
but more importantly the fans had a lot
of questions about Neville's Hayes and I
guess it speaks to the fact that it is
so rare even now you really don't see it
going around much and people are aware
that you've got a cutting so people were
and myself very keen to hear would you
be able to give us a bit of a rundown on
what your Neville's Haze cut is like and
do you plan to work with it going
forward at all well it's not a cutting
it was a seed line
um and the seed line was originally from
Mr Nice
um it was bred to
um F3 and before I breaded to other
things
um the phenotype that I chose was
um a large yielding candelabra style so
it had
um
you know it had some of that
Northern Light structure but it
basically the haze the larger plant
structure like the Colombians so it had
some bulk but it also contained some of
the haziness to it but it was more like
a Mexican
um creating these long thick bread loaf
like colas
um the smell was incensey
um like an Indian Nang Champa but more
rich and sweet
um is very um
luxurious and unique whenever I'd bring
that to when I was supplying herb to the
different medical clubs in the early
2000s
when I went to the different clubs I'd
you know give samples to the different
Bud tenders and um the female blood
tenders especially love that stuff and
they always wanted more it was uh that
good but the haze was almost near
perfect that that Neville's Haze it was
you get almost as high as you possibly
can
um The Taste the smell the aroma it's
all very
uh very good
um and I crossed the purple tie uh so it
um you know gets the purple traits
um you know the colors the the trichomes
turn purple the resin glands the
trichomes are all you know got some
colors to them
um and that adds a different type of
flavonoid and
um you know Turpin profile then the
regular Neville's Haze by itself makes a
little bit more complex
um
but um it's it's a great and wonderful
plant uh for sure the other Neville's
case is that I've grown
um those ones need to be more sparse um
you know very nice but more hazy-ish but
um the one that I used is more of a
larger yielding but also retains all the
best qualities that you'd want so like a
large yielding Haze it's like what you
want
um as far as yields and Buds and the the
density in a modern variety but with all
the qualities I like the longest
flowering cases almost
if that makes any sense
that's amazing why you brought it up I
guess I'll quickly touch on it I also
noted that you had the Oregon purple tie
is that correct
um no I didn't have Oregon purple tie I
have a chocolate tie that I believe
um was the source of what created
the organ purple tie which is um
a Highland
um oaxacan gold and the chocolate tie to
create the working purple tie except the
chocolate pie doesn't have any of the
mutations and weird [__] that's sorry
weird stuff that's associated with
Morgan purple tie
um
so it's got the colors it's got the the
highs everything that you like about
flow blueberry
um I believe a majority of that comes
from that chocolate tie which
um I believe is a purple tie
but we haven't gotten there to verify it
so I believe that is uh
you know the rootstock of Oregon purple
tying and I bred that into some
varieties I've released a little bit of
it
um so far but I lost the mother
unfortunately during my aunt's funeral
this last Christmas
I have a little bit of seed stock left
I'm going to try to revive but what I've
bred into it is still still available so
um
there will be some magic still and then
I'm working with other chocolate ties
but um yeah it's uh
it's definitely a special line
that's fantastic thanks for the
clarification and I guess as a follow-up
I noticed you've got the blueberry blast
which you know really cool strain it's
got the blueberry and the Neville's Haze
in there I guess I was sort of wondering
how would you describe that one like how
did it turn out it sounds like it could
be like a better version of Blue Dream
to me and as a follow-up what's your
thoughts on the blueberry family in
general are you fond of it or you know
it's just sort of one of the things for
you
uh well more to start let's start on the
uh the blueberry blast so I made the
blueberry blast
um when I was supplying the medical
clubs in Southern California we were
growing in Northern California
um
our our family farm is in the Emerald
Triangle area
um so I was able to see what was selling
in the medical clubs and one of them was
blue dream
um so I was this is before I got famous
so I went to
you know where I was growing and found
the different cuts they were going there
was two different cuts
um a blue dream and then I grew those
commercially uh that same year
um
and this is before most people knew
about blue dream
um so I read two versions of it called
pipe dream and blueberry blast
um the narrow Leaf more hazy version
um blue dream uh was bred into the pipe
train and the male uh for that was the
Acapulco called c99 male
uh the blueberry blast had the Johnny
Blaze which is Neville's Hayes and
blueberry
um it was
slightly larger yielding that blue dream
uh the leaves were a little bit more
broader not by much
um resin production was a little bit
more on the the the narrow Leaf one for
the pipe dream but they were both
awesome and very close and um
effects and yields
um the quality
of the the pie cream was just slightly
better in my opinion I liked it more uh
than the one I used for the blueberry
blast but the blueberry blast was my
version of a commercial
a commercial variety
um it was
um the best Blue Dream at the time and
um you know basically trying to make it
better so there there's quite a few
phenotypes most of them are larger
yielding some of them are more hazy uh
but you can have a seven week blueberry
blast uh for some of the faster
phenotypes and then you can have one
that goes to 14 to 16 weeks for
something longer but um all of them are
super residents have that blueberry
Cedar uh wood Aroma
um very luscious and tasty effect is
kind of like Strawberry Cough it's got
that original Haze type high so you get
really high for a few hours and then
um it'll allow you to eat Munchies or
eat if you like and sleep if you want in
a nice dreamful restful state so it's
kind of like a
all-encompassing high and you know it
kind of lets you go up and then takes
you down if you need to do what you need
to do and be restful because some uh
Haze and sensitivas kind of will keep
you amped for a while and it can be
tiring it can kind of wear you out but
that kind of allows you to do what you
need to do
when you want to
yeah beautiful stuff and what's your
thoughts on the sort of work by DJ in
general I guess I'll preface this that I
noticed you you do the grape Crush F3 so
I'd be Keen to hear your thoughts on
that one I guess you're fond of it
the great crush is uh awesome uh
beautiful line very strong
um has some mutants has a lot of the the
DJ stuff does
um but it you know keeps it interesting
um you know it's very strong potent
um you know smaller yielding indica
um
breeds well with other lines I made some
very powerful varieties breeding with it
it's very tasty
some phenotypes are better than others
um
yeah
um the blueberry lines a lot of the
stuff is um
it was better at one point than it is
now it seems uh some of the genetics
were
more pure at that point I think it's
kind of
Uh something's changed over the time and
I think DJ has said it was the afghani's
war kind of added more into it and it
kind of seems more evident with like the
flow the flow seemed to be more
um Mexican
um
uh
more Mexican and
yield and percentages than it is
nowadays now you get more of Afghani
um
Centric type of variety with a lot of
these uh flow and and blueberry types
the blueberries that I had back in 97
was super tasty flavorful
um the stuff now is also very flavorful
but um the the phenotypes are kind of
all over the place but um you know
awesome stuff you know good breeding
um well if you're looking for specific
plants to grow they're great breeding
can be a little odd because of
the multi-poly hybrid
um
aspects of the lines in general I mean
while we're sort of talking about
strains of yesteryear I'd love to
quickly ask you you know were there any
a notable one for that we hear a lot on
the show is like the sssc did they ever
put out any notable things for you or
were there any other brands from around
that time that really stick out in your
mind is quite memorable
well SSC
um
well I I got to know uh one of the
people that did the shipping for sssc
and some of the strains that he was
growing uh sssc super sativa seed Club
had Incorporated in their lines so the
what's known as Williams Wonder was
actually my friend's strain and um
I I don't want to say where he's from
but he's from the United States
um and um
his name was also my name uh but the
other name for uh John is William so
Williams Wonder was one of his strains
um the Hawaiians were also associated
with my friend
um and some of the other varieties uh as
well who's her Hooten holler
um so just like uh him you know he was
able to incorporate to what a lot of
people loved about
sssc just like Neville you know got
stuff from other people
um and shared that with the rest of the
world so he should be noted as being you
know something that people uh got
something really that they enjoyed from
this individual
um some of the the varieties from SSC
were the same as the seed banks
um
basic five was the Neville's uh sorry
the Northern Lights number five uh the
basic five skunk was like uh skunk
Northern Lights crosses or like Shiva
skunk so a lot of the stuff was just
renamed with some of the same cuttings
that were available to um
um to the seed bank and sscc in Holland
at the time
um the
what people known as the um
Pine Town Durban uh Pinetown is actually
a town in or a little uh District in
Durban so it's not a Piney uh Durban
it's just from that part of uh Durban
and South Africa
a lot of people there's the South
African um
crosses South African is the Durban
in those crosses
okay
it doesn't doesn't it doesn't say that
but it says South African but the South
African is actually the urban it doesn't
say on the description but if you see
South African it's Durban and then
whatever the cross is
ah there you go and a lot of people
speculate that the common Durban
cuttings floating around the USA at the
moment the notable ones have maybe some
Afghan crossed into them do you have any
thoughts on that
well I know a lot of the Dutch ones
definitely seem uh like they have
skunked to them the ones that are in the
United States I don't know
um
um there was
um Durbin that was associated with one
of the uh guys that did some of the
Cannabis books
um it wasn't Rosenthal it was um
the other gentleman the name uh is
escaping me at the moment and this is a
an older gentleman
um Mel Frank
uh Mel Frank yeah Mel actually went to
um
Durbin and brought back some seeds so a
lot of what people got one of the stock
that was released as like Durbin and
then I think some of the seed banks in
in Holland got was his Durban Poison but
what a lot of uh some of the Growers
were growing in Mendocino was different
versions of his Urban Poison yeah so a
lot what people see are these little
stocky uh Durban poisons that's kind of
like from his stock but Durban Poison is
actually a hybrid of
um some of the Bantu tribe
um that came from Northern Africa down
to South Africa to Swaziland and
um
the Zulu Nation
um and then the uh uh East the the
Eastern Cape tribes those varieties got
mixed in with what was um
later came in from the indentured Indian
servants uh in the 1800s from Mostly
South South India from like Kerala orisa
Andhra Pradesh and then a small
percentage from himal Pradesh in the
northern Indian area but majority of the
Indians that were indentured servants
basically uh you know slaves but were
moved from South India to work the sugar
plantations after the free the black
slaves this also happened in the West
Indies in like Jamaica the indentured
servants came to work the sugar
plantations and that's where you get
some of the Jamaican varieties which
were
um Indian and Mexican and then later on
were Indian Colombian
interesting uh but Durban Poison is a
combination of
African and South Indian
uh that's why some of them are more
Compact and bushy and then other ones
more power like a Malawi
um or some Malawi
but um that there's one there's
definitely some variations with the
Durban poisons it's not just one variety
and that's why I think a lot of people
um Mis misunderstand it's not just uh
it's an heirloom land race now but it's
acclimatized over a period of time due
to two people's uh coming together
Lesotho is a version of the same thing
going on where it's like banshu tribes
mixed with
um North Indian because some of the um
the the lesota varieties are very Stoney
and physical
so it makes more sense that that
hybridization is a combination of the
two
yeah
interesting interesting and I mean you
just mentioned you know the Indian
genetics why do you think they're so
sort of underrepresented compared to a
lot of other land races do you think
they've got something to offer that a
lot of people might be overlooking
oh absolutely there's a lot of varieties
in India they were growing cannabis for
many many years
um
um for the people for food purposes for
medicine
um
so yeah uh there's definitely a lot of
stuff under Representatives
um
why it's not getting the notorious like
uh you know um
the highlights like other varieties
um
it all depends maybe it's been watered
down by mixing up so many varieties
um you know uh some of the
Indian varieties you know they they
create a lot of hashish from it so it's
hard to drive to like see the different
varieties from one another
um you know some of the Colombians are
more uh you know colorful as far as
standing out as a sativa so maybe people
will see the Colombians standing out
more so uh like with a haze
um
the Indians I think
don't get the credit they need to
there's such a wide area of growth and
geographical
um peoples there's so many different
people uh such a long history
um they had the what it was called soma
which was you know the sacred uh
cannabis now just like the Persians had
heoma the zoastrian religion
um pre you know Afghan area
um but you know what was
once uh an area of long cannabis history
um has been you know separated by
religion so a lot of what was India
previous to like the 1950s was you know
where Pakistan is now at Bangladesh
um all that what is India was all of
that
um previous to that point
um just you know a mix of different
peoples
um so uh you know there's a lot of stuff
that should be revived and a lot of that
knowledge
um
you know should be explored more a lot
of different varieties and I think
there's some good people from the Indian
Land race exchange by raising some other
people that are trying to put some more
focus on these varieties than these
Farmers that should be supported because
a lot of these people are starving you
know they're not giving much for their
cannabis they're not getting much to
live on in general
um
so I think a lot of governments should
support these people these uh histories
of these cannabis varieties because it's
not only uh
you know a history of these people the
Cannabis is kind of like
a sociological social history it's um
it's something that they can grow that's
also a history of those people it's
knowledge it passed down from you know
father to son to mother to daughter and
should be treasured and there's so much
history there that we just haven't been
able to um
let the rest of the world know and
hopefully with time we can kind of show
people more of what's out there
most certainly definitely need to have
more attention placed on the indigenous
farmers and supporting them
I guess you you sort of touched on the
farmers and a conversation I've been
having more so with friends in private
sort of goes along the lines of
is what we're doing with modern cannabis
breeding
really that good compared to what the
indigenous farmers were doing because it
seems as if we're losing a lot of the
special stuff
and a lot of people complain about how
there's this sort of same everything has
this same quality you know everything in
the dispensary sort of feels about the
same
what's your thoughts on this it's
obviously a deep philosophical Rabbit
Hole to jump down but I'd love to hear
your take
well I don't think it's it's that
difficult I think a lot of what people
are growing and are exposed to are what
was created from the seed banks so a lot
of seed banks were Northern Lights skunk
um and then that was incorporated to
almost everything
so everything's a skunk Afghani Northern
Lights type high but only from certain
varieties The Afghani varieties that the
Dutch were growing I hate to pick on the
Dutch but this is what was happening to
grow varieties that would be more
conducive to indoor flowering they
selected plants that would finish Fast
um would be more homogeneous meaning
they would
um flower and then the whole plant would
flower at one time instead of flowering
and you know
stages
um so when you pick plants that are
early flowering and you know and
homogeneous
um you're actually selecting the
qualities that aren't as potent I mean
you could if you get lucky but when you
pick out varieties that aren't disease
resistant
um aren't for potency aren't for Quality
you're losing the best parts of the
plant
and so you're watering them down so
unfortunately they were watering down
the genetics
um to fit a need because of
um the illegal state of cannabis that's
been happening since the 1930s
um
you know cannabis was illegal so they
had to go indoors for the most part so
they were breeding varieties that would
go grow indoors easily for people so the
Dutch were doing this as a convenience
which made sense but unfortunately
um they watered down a lot of the
genetics and another thing that happened
was the genetic socks that they had were
great but as they were trying to keep
germination fresh seed available to the
customers they were killing off or
destroying their old seed stock the
problem was as they were watering down
their varieties for fast maturing
you know homogeneous plants they can go
back to their old seed stock because
they destroyed it because we're trying
to keep up and keep fresh seed stock
so the only thing that they had were
these old clones but the seed stock
wasn't something they could go back to
unless they had you know long-term
storage or something they could but they
destroyed a lot of genetic
um germplasm unfortunately and that's
why
you know they're searching around the
world for new varieties or old varieties
that farmers were growing in the United
States around the world Australia or
different countries now because of what
happened with the poor breeding
practices so
breeding for potency quality is what I
do
and foremost everything else you can
narrow down you can pick for faster
flowering plants out of those once
you've acquired something that's strong
and has the qualities you want you know
colors taste Aroma all that stuff can be
fixed but if you got a weak plant that
doesn't have the qualities
uh that you know make it unique then
it's not special so the majority of what
people are growing out there are fast
growing you know great for production
you know great for a farmer but the
people that are smoking are getting
the the end result of what is good for
the farmer but not good for the grow for
the smoker so uh people if they want
these higher quality strains should ask
um you know breeding practices to evolve
where some of the better higher quality
plants are made to yield more
and then also request you're getting
ping uh the farmers more for something
that may take longer to grow but has a
higher quality uh that these smokers
would like to enjoy because there's so
much more out there that's possible but
they're just not being able or being
exposed to it because
um the lack of availability and the lack
of commercial Growers growing these
varieties because they just don't yield
as much so if you have a plant that
yields five pounds in another plant that
yields a couple ounces you're gonna grow
the the plant that grows five pounds
because even if you sell it super cheap
you're still getting a lot more money
for the farmers so the farmer's just
thinking you know apples and oranges
they're growing these things because
they're trying to sell them you know
they're trying to make money but it it
doesn't make any sense for a farmer to
grow something that barely yields
anything if they're not going to get
much for it
so that's unfortunate reason why people
aren't getting exposed to these
varieties
um because it's just not worth the
farmer's time because the smokers aren't
paying for that extra time spent to grow
these varieties which take longer and
don't yield as much
eventually some of these strains you can
get the higher yielding plants
with the higher qualities like I try to
incorporate with some of my varieties
but sometimes you just need to spend
extra time to grow them because
people are missing out on the best
quality highs and experiences and if you
grew up on cushes and indicas you may
have not ever gotten high you've just
been stoned and people just don't
understand that high you don't
understand that you can get happy and
giggly and you know laugh yourself into
fits and you know laugh so hard that
your your stomach hurts and you start
spitting up and it's it's a great
wonderful experience and there's so many
different highs that give you happiness
and Euphoria and colors and there's a
lot of magic out there and just most
people haven't been able to experience
that unfortunately
you mentioned it yourself just then that
you tried to breed some strains that
have that high quality and the increased
yield to accompany it for all the
listeners out there whose ears have
perked up do you want to throw some
recommendations out there what have your
Australians fit that bill if for anyone
who's Keen to try
uh well one of them would be uh the
dragon's fire it's um mostly Thai
Hawaiian but it's got the longer flying
tie highs
um but with more of a Hawaiian modern
resin profile so you get the larger
yields and resin from like a modern
variety so you get the yields and looks
that everyone wants and smells and
tastes so it smells tasty wonderful like
pineapple tropical fruits but you get
these wonderful soaring highs euphoric
energy that just makes you happy unlike
many other varieties so that'd be one
but there are so many that
um I could mention blueberry blast was a
good one although I have to
um remake the variety because I'm sold
out but that was another connoisseur
commercial variety it yielded very well
um it was great for Growers and it was
great for smokers so it was kind of
all-encompassing uh there's many
varieties like that but there's also for
like the true connoisseur
um you know you get these modern resin
profiles but with the um the longer
flowering pies associated with you know
ties Colombians that sort of thing
wow that sounds really special I mean a
few questions back you referenced the
Acapulco Gold c99 male and I noticed you
use that quite a bit do those crosses
also fit the bill in a sense because
they seem like you know fun uplifting
sativa do they have the yield as well or
are they more for a different sort of
cross
actually a lot of those were for um you
know commercial purposes so you get a
higher quality
um commercial viable but with the highs
that people want so yeah so the c99
um
Acapulco Gold varieties were more of uh
uh more of a trying to get people to try
out some of these lines but with um a
semi-moderate flowering period so it's
fast enough for many people but it takes
a little bit longer than some but you
get high quality unlike a lot of writing
so you don't get the same
um generic High
yeah sure that sounds like a great sort
of Middle Ground you've touched on it a
bit and I'd love to delve deeper into it
with there's a lot of discussion
currently around what is it that
actually causes us to perceive something
as an indica versus a sativa and I've
heard people more recently say oh it's
it's all the terpenes but I remembered
having a discussion with Bodie I believe
it was and he said to me I've got this
Afghani that smells like this tie I've
got and they both test that like you
know about the same like let's say they
both test it 20 and they both smell the
same but one's clearly indica and one's
clearly sativa and it got me thinking
like yeah like what really is it because
I'm not so sold it's terpenes but I'd
love to hear more and be educated
well a lot of people they they call
multi-poly hybrids sativas when they
have an up high
um and they call indica's uh they have
narcotic Stony High you know Estonia
effects um you know indica
um the truth is that the nomenclature
the names for all this stuff is kind of
all over the place uh sativa would
typically be like a tropical or
equatorial variety
um but it doesn't have to be because
there's microclimates everywhere so like
in Afghanistan there's also sativas
uh there's narrow Leaf varieties
um they have the up Highs but you can
also have a sativa that has a narcotic
effect
um so you know it depends are people
calling the sativa because it's got
narrow leaves in a you know um
a upright you know smaller flower set
um with the up high a sativa but if it
has a narcotic effect is that an indica
or is it a sativa it's still a sativa
but it's got a narcotic effect
so
um the chemotypes associated with a lot
of these varieties
um
basically a lot of stuff should be
renamed and indica should be anything
that should be from India you know
India but um
there should be hash plants there should
be equatorials there should be Tropicals
um there should be jungle varieties
there should be Highland there should be
low end
um more of the environment that's
associated with and the type of plant it
is is it a hash plant or is it a ganja
plant is it something that you smoke for
flowers or is it something that you
harvest for hash
or is it a hash like plant
um so Indica sativa
um
you know it's kind of too broad and
people use it for you know they say OG
cushions sativa because it's kind of up
high well obviously it's an Indica but
you know just because as up high doesn't
mean it's a sativa
clear as mud
yeah I mean I think as the you know the
extension of that what do you think is
the mechanism through which it's
different you know do you think there's
maybe some yet to be characterized
molecules and like if they're there they
give you that more uplifting effect or
how do you think it plays out because it
seems like a lot of the current
speculation is sort of yet to be proven
I guess
well there there's a lot of unknowns in
cannabis mostly of what people have been
studying is the cannabinoids and the
turpins the primary trippings but
there's also long chain Turpin profiles
so there's these things that insects
ward off against because
um the plant is giving off
um a Turpin profile that is like a
pesticide
um also it um you know acts as like a
hormone for humans but for the plant
species
um so there's these unknown Turpin
profiles that
um we have yet to record all of them so
we don't even know
all that are out there so we need to
identify them and then we need to
identify what their properties are
because they work with the primary
turpins to have the tertiary effect you
know they add they go with the
cannabinoids and their primary turbines
to add to the overall
um effects there's also these flavonoids
um that you know cause colors and these
cause effects and defects on a nerve can
result in that nerve firing
um for a longer period of time or
shorter period of time think of a sine
wave you know those things you see on
like an EKG that you know goes straight
and then it goes up and then goes down
that is let's just say a nerve firing so
we have
um
THC for one it fires uh off at a certain
height well you add another cannabinoid
like CBG and that height actually goes
even higher
well you put CBD in that in that same
two molecules might go lower
but it might extend the duration of it
so it lasts longer so you have the same
effect but longer or you have the same
effect but not as high but longer or
shorter so these things that add to
these cannabinoids these different
components either can make the high more
potent or less potent or make it longer
duration or shorter duration it could
also cause effects that give you like a
soaring effect or a heightened color
effect or you know Sensation that is
more associated with the hearing you
know affects your hearing
so the cannabinoids
affect the nerves by either directly
attaching themselves and
um you know
making it more potent stronger duration
lower duration higher duration
um yeah it it it's all these different
effects that need to be cataloged and
what they the uses in and they do
um so
as far as the effects of like Indica
sativa a lot of the the basic
information is
um you can have a Colombian gold or you
have like Acapulco Gold uh these don't
have a CBD in them they have THC a lot
sometimes thcv if they're from like
Thailand or South Africa
um some from Colombia
um or they have CBG CBC but there's no
CBD or if there is it's super small
amount though you can have something
like uh Panama Red or Colombian Punta
Rojo that has CBD but is also considered
like a sativa so you get these narcotic
effects mixed with the high sativa
effects
um but in a different way than say a
hash plant that has more of a narcotic
effect so more CBN so high CBD and high
CBN
um tend to give you the narcotic effects
um lacking CBD with these other
cannabinoids give you the what people
you know feel as a sativa effect
yeah brilliant stuff there I'm gonna
have to go really listen to that myself
and I'm sure the listeners will as well
in terms of a sort of slightly adjacent
topic I've spoken to DJ Short and many
others about this but I'd be interested
to hear your take on what causes modern
strains to have a ceiling you know you
can only get so high and if you keep
smoking you sort of don't go anywhere
else but with a lot of the land races
particularly the sativas you can sort of
just keep going and going what what do
you think causes that ceiling
well the ceiling CBD typically so CBD
can be used if say you're freaking out
or your friend's freaking out and or
you've taken Edibles and you're just too
high uh taking doses of CBD will
modulate the the high effect so then
comfortableness that you get from too
much THC can be brought down with higher
amounts of CBD so it'll bind to the THC
and kind of get you out of that
um you know at least bring it down to a
more comfortable state so higher muscle
CBD will kind of help with that for the
ceiling this highs that seem to Take You
Higher and Higher those strains seem to
have no CBD or very little CBD also
there's also you know cannabinoids that
are in higher amounts like CBG
CBG varieties with THC seem to
potentiate make the THC more potent
so um you know higher amounts of CBG
with the THC along with thcv and you get
even more expressions like Malawi
varieties have the thcv so you get more
of this rushing waves of euphoria and
seems like there's no ceiling as you
smoke more
um basically you smoke a little bit and
you can't physically smoke too much
because you're just so High
um because you keep going higher and
higher but if you had CBD in that you
could kind of counteract the
uncomfortableness of the high THC in
your body and it'll bring you down
if that makes any sense
yeah certainly so I guess I'm wondering
then do you think that we like you know
a lot of these modern strains have some
amount of CBD in them that sort of
unknowingly is limiting us
absolutely yeah most of what people are
smoking has CBD and some concentration
or
um you know that's that's mainly what is
in a lot of these is this it's a
multi-poly hybrid with CBD and almost
all
yeah great some good food for thought so
let's go back to one of the questions we
normally start the interview off with
what are you being smoking on recently
um chocolate Thai
um some Mexican varieties like Michoacan
Verde Limon
um my uh devil skunk
um Devil's tit
which is uh Durban Poison alcohol c99
that's a wonderful strain super potent
wonderful taste
and it can be absolutely too potent
concentrates will freak you out I
remember taking uh two hits at the
emerald cup and I was in a fetal
position for several hours uh just
hoping for uh for myself to come down it
was uh yeah it was very uncomfortable
for quite a while but that was from
concentrates made from the devil's tit
which I tried to get
um judged that year but all my samples
for some reason never got judged so that
was the last time any samples in the
emerald cup
ah very interesting to hear that and uh
I love the idea being in the federal
position it's so potent it sounds up my
alley I noticed online that the devil's
tit as well as the purple Pantera some
of the more popular lines that popped up
a lot on the various forums what was
interesting to me was that you know
given the diversity of the genetics you
work with do you ever feel like you can
predict the winners or what's going to
be the fan favorite or is it really just
a bit up in the air
you know it all depends like um
we the one year we entered in the purple
pineapple bond which is pineapple Thai
and grape Crush it tastes good it tastes
wonderful it's got a great high and
people love it but the thing is it
wasn't our most potent it wasn't the
thing we're most proud of so sometimes
it just depends sometimes if something
is familiar to people but different
enough
uh to go hey well this is this is
actually quite good those usually seem
to be the ones that people gravitate to
so it's got to be something familiar you
know it has that modern profile it has
the colors and looks that people want
that smell you know and then amazing
High to go along with it so it's not
always the most potent the most unique
um the best in my eyes but you know
people dislike something that's familiar
as well
yeah sure sure I mean on the other end
of the spectrum so to speak I noticed
that the railgun seems like such a super
fun mix of like genetics like a sativa
Lover's party and along with that came
quite a hefty 100 plus Day flower time
it got me wondering do these sort of
strains ever get out there that much or
is it really quite difficult to find
people willing to run it
actually some of these strings
um were created in like testing rounds
where I was growing for different
varieties and then we grow them out and
um you know I initially I didn't make a
lot of seed because
you know we're testing out these
varieties
um so what people get out out there is
not too much there's a there's just not
a lot available because
um of the breeding practices because a
lot of preservation was being done
um which takes a lot of time you know
you're spending a year and a half on one
strain trying to do selections and
preserve it
um you don't get a lot of time to create
other varieties
um so you know
um there's some of these strains there's
just not a lot available for people to
grow so I'm trying to work out the stuff
that's more popular I'm trying to go
back to those and do larger selections
um you know for people so they can get
exposed to these varieties which are
quite good like the devil's tit the
dragon's fire the West Coast Purple
Diesel blueberry blast this you know try
to make stuff available to people that
this is wonderful and there's a lot of
varieties that I've made that just knock
people's socks off but I just need to go
back and you know make more of it
available to people
yeah God I can only imagine you've got
such a catalog of work it's really cool
to see
out of curiosity I I look I'm going to
be a stickler here I'm really keen on
the rail gun can you tell me what it's
like
uh railgun is trippy uh very
um
God it's uh very Thai dominant it's got
the zamol in it which has got you know
like South Indian flavors and highs um
it's very psychedelic
um
can be noid inducing where you can kind
of get panic attacks but it's also it's
very very euphoric and very desirable
it's a it's kind of like walking the
edge of being super uncomfortable but
really high in really flying high and
being in a a like a roller coaster dream
it's it's really good but um it's kind
of hard to deal with but um
yeah it's it's it's really tasty and the
flowers are actually pretty
um dense
um due to the Angola red pie purple Thai
uh male it kind of gives you nice good
flowers that yield well but also
retaining a lot of this long flowering
um
hides from these small lines
yeah nice and did you ever try the zamal
and it's pure form it's it's got a bit
of a cult following to it that's for
sure
there's there's quite a few uh three to
five different samal varieties
um they're all kind of uh you know Malay
uh Thai in in like Indonesian Indian
South Indian derived but it's a French
island so there there's a lot of
variability depending on what part of
the island it's from but yeah the the
zamal by itself is really trippy it's
hard to grow seeds are hard to germinate
uh for some reason they seem to um lose
viability quite quick quite quickly so
it's hard to keep around so you gotta
renew and refresh the stock quite often
oh wow that's an interesting trait you
really don't hear about very much
well some some varieties will last
longer I think it's due to the seed
coats some of them are more dense and
seem to
um
you know allow the seed to last longer
but other ones will be more shallow less
um you know density to it smaller and
they just seemed like they they dry out
quicker or they just are more
susceptible to heat and they just lose
viability a lot faster than others you
got me curious now tupada how do you
store your seeds and how do you
germinate them
for storage for what people get uh it's
a cool dry place that's what people are
flying if you store in a refrigerator
whenever you take it out of the
refrigerator you need to germinate those
right away
um if you don't the moisture that seems
to come from the refrigerator
um will actually make them unviable
quite quickly so if you refrigerate
anything you can keep them in there for
quite a while you want to try to not use
desiccants because desiccants
um will work for a while but after a
period of time they will go bad and
actually pull more moisture into where
those seeds are being kept fouling the
seeds but if you use a refrigerator once
you remove from the refrigerator you
want to put them right back as soon as
possible but if they're out with you
know for more than an hour or so then
you would want to germinate them as soon
as possible because they'll lose
viability quite quickly there's also
long-term storage for like uh varieties
that you want to keep for a long period
of time you have to freeze them and they
need to be wrapped within you know glass
vials within rice within coffee
containers and then Frozen and you want
to make sure those are thought out but
don't retain moisture as you're throwing
them out because that moisture will
cause issues with the seeds
but the majority of what people get is
from a cool dry place a germination now
I'm I am recommending what's called
chemical scarification
basically you use hydrogen peroxide
three percent with water 50 50. so most
of the stuff you buy at the stores at
least in the United States three percent
hydrogen peroxide
he makes it 50 50 50 with tap water tap
water in the United States has some
bleaching agents which is good because
it's a disinfectant the hydrogen
peroxide is a disinfectant so you could
also use you know bottled water or
whatever you want to use water but the
idea is you want something that'll
disinfect the hydrogen peroxide will
help soften the shells of the seeds
causing what they call scarification so
it softens it and also disinfects it
because
um the sources that people are getting
these seeds from especially if they're
from outside their country if they're
from outside the country I would
recommend freezing whatever seeds you
get at least overnight and then
defrosting them and make sure they they
dry out within without any moisture if
you freeze the seeds you're killing the
eggs The larva in any live adults
um that may be coming along for the ride
with your seeds a lot of people don't
realize that a lot of the Critters and
stuff that they're getting are from
seeds they're getting from outside the
country and these can destroy your
plants they could uh you know uh eat up
all your seeds in within a period of
time you'll find little webbing inside
the seeds and they'll be eaten from the
inside out as they you know devour your
Priceless seeds so freezing it is a good
way of killing them and then you can
store them for whatever period of time
you want germination once you've done
the chemical scarification you want to
wash with tap water or bottled water you
know running water is usually best and
then you dry them off I recommend using
a paper towel with tap water and then
checking on the seeds with a moist paper
towel wrapped and folded and then placed
inside a sealed baggie and you place
that in a cool dry place or with a
heating mat and you check on the seeds
maybe every eight hours until
germination
now you want to make sure that you wash
your hands with soap and water don't
touch your face or your body because
there's bacteria there's different
um
funguses that could be incorporated from
your body and then you can contaminate
your seeds so they'll mold
um
and if you use a heating mat I recommend
only using it for maybe 24 hours to 48
hours that's it because the heat and
moisture will cause mold over a period
of time so heat will help push along the
germination process it helps
um but I would quit using that after a
couple days there's also some heating
mats that you can adjust and use a lower
um
heat setting and if you have one they
can has adjustable setting then you
could use lower heat and use it for a
longer period of time but if you have a
heating mat that you just plug in and
you have no ability to adjust the heat
then I would use it for more than 24 to
48 hours tops
um but checking on it every four eight
hours of your seat until they germinate
um up to three days so after three days
I recommend
um using a fingernail or
um maybe something uh to open up the
seed cases and then removing the film
that's around the embryo of the seed and
then sowing the seeds in a sterilized
soil starter soil
I use a soilless medium or a medium
that's been sterilized
um and sterilization is um I recommend
something for strutting seeds because uh
what's called damp off
um these seeds or seedlings
um are uh or have built resistance yet
to
um fungus and bacteria that are in the
soil that is great for you know growing
plants but if these plants haven't built
the resistance to them yet they will um
they will cause damp off and they'll die
so a lot of people are killing their
seeds and don't realize it because
they're using recycled soil or they're
using bag soil that's been opened you
know several times which has created a
you know fungal development which isn't
great for these seedlings and Seed
embryos
an easy way of sterilizing your soil is
taking your medium and placing it in the
turkey bag or oven bag and then
moistening the the soil not so it's
soaking wet but so it's moist
um and damp and then basically you put
in a microwave for two minutes and you
do this three to four times and then on
the fourth time you do you seal the bag
with the little zip tie that comes along
with it the moisture that's in the bag
will Steam and sterilize the soil and
that last zap of the microwave is uh
three to four minutes you gotta kind of
estimated or guesstimate it due to the
strengths of the microwaves but that
steam will help kill any of the harmful
pathogens in the soil the good stuff
will come back within a minute or two so
you're not destroying
um what's in the soil for a long period
of time you're just securing the bad
stuff and that's what you want to use
for
um you know seed starting or for a
Seedling transplants or planting plants
in general because you know there's
nothing bad in it at the time
um
and then um
you sow the seeds basically I like to
use a natural light to begin with and
then once they've come above the ground
then I use T5 fluorescence and basically
veg them until you're ready to
transplant them to beer cups and then
you veg them with um you know whatever
light regimen that you want to use the
light regiment that I that I use for
vegging plants is um
uh 13 hours of light in a 24-hour period
And I use 12 hours from uh say 7 A.M to
7 P.M that's 12 hours straight and then
in the middle of the dark period
um so five and a half hours uh after the
lights have uh gone off so you have 12
hours of lights on so say 7 A.M to 7 p.m
and then five and a half hours of
Darkness the lights will come out for
one hour so basically like in the middle
of the night the lights come on
um and then after that hour of light the
lights go back off for another five and
a half hours and then the cycle is
repeated
so basically the hour of light in the
middle of the dark period tricks the
plants in thinking that the days are
longer a longer days will keep plants in
veg and this is a good way of saving on
electric bills and it is a good way of
transitioning when you go to flower the
plants there's not much of a change from
Veg to flour
um for flowering plants and sexing
plants I basically use 10 and a half
hours of light and uh 13 and a half
hours of Darkness the dark period is
actually what triggers flowering not the
light so the 10 half hours is kind of
the right ratio that you need for
extreme flowering ancient sex most
plants within three to four days the
more extreme would be seven to ten days
but most flour most things you can sex
within uh three to four days no problem
that's
what I use for germination
that's incredible what very detailed
answer I guess for me the natural
progression is tell me how you grow how
do you do it are you organic you're a
soil guy are you cocoa what's the
rundown
I'm an organic guy so I like using
organic methods Sun grown is my my
preferred method but I like to do my
selections indoors
um to speed along things
um so
you know I sex plants basically after
the first
um true leaves I actually use what they
call the Femme technique which allows
you to do a topping of the main stem and
leaving two-thirds left over and from
that you're able to create not only just
from topping like uh two different
branches but sometimes three to four the
optimal is four different main branches
from that one pinching and when you
pinch
um the apical buds the main stem of your
um your plant it causes what are called
auxins to go from the the top of the
plant down to the roots and will cause
the roots to grow more
this needs to be repeated basically
every four to five days or three to four
days depending on the the growth rate of
the plant and every time you do this
you're creating more main branches and
you're also creating more Roots so it's
going back and forth so I do this in veg
as I'm waiting for the plants to get to
the right size so from seed for like
indicas and multiplying hybrids from
seed to flour I like to veg the plants
from 30 to 60 days for like indicas and
hybrids for a longer flowering Tropicals
in equatorials I like to veg the plants
from 60 to 90 days from seed
nice nice and what's your thoughts on
selection of males do you like to do it
based on that initial when you're sexing
them or do you wait longer how do you
select males
well I do certain things what I look for
is under natural light when you're
sprouting plants
um under natural light there is like a
day or two which
um the sprout will flash certain traits
like colors like you can see a flash of
red or purple in the Sprouts
um when they first come up above ground
just for a day or two and that's kind of
indication what they'll do in flower so
you can actually do your selections for
colors that way picking out the special
plants
um early on so you have to waste your
time growing out of these different
plants to get those special plants
um but you you basically indicate like
this one had red red traits it's going
to have purple traits and then as you're
vegging it you kind of
um
see that when you maturely flour them
out you can see the the how as a little
Sprout this told you that this is going
to be a super colorful plant and it will
have these special traits
um for
uh selecting males and females
um there's three types of DNA that's
used in cannabis
uh there's like the cellular DNA which
is like the structures
um that's what you see uh outwardly you
know the the structure of the plant
that's kind of like um the female side
so females you want to see the structure
you want to make sure that they have
good branching lots of branching because
if they're not branchy there's kind of
hempy so if there's no not a lot of
branching it's more of a hemp plant you
know it's kind of all stem so you want
super branchy plants for your females
and then also you want to look at the
roots
um you want to pull off the pots I do a
lot of repotting so I get to examine the
roots but you want plants that produce
good root zones you don't want a little
teeny carrot I don't want to go through
growing a plant for nine months and then
seeing that it has a small little carrot
of a root and this is why your plant you
know sucked so when you're breathing and
you're selecting for these plants you
kind of look at the root Zone make sure
they're prolific either growing sideways
or downward or they're good roots
because says if you got 20 or 50 plants
you're you know selecting from
um and there's no real real way of like
telling the difference between the
plants from like the top up but the
roots will tell you which ones will grow
better because that is kind of like the
um mitochondrial DNA the ability for it
to uptake nutrients and then convert
that in the sugars into energy ATP same
as humans humans take sugars from the
mitochondria and they'll switch the
sugars into ATP adenosine triphosphate
which is energy plants do the same thing
um so cannabis has this mitochondrial
DNA and that is something that you can
see through the the way it converts
sugars and creates stem and you know
growth of the plants the other thing to
look for is
the chloroplast DNA what creates the the
terpens the cannabinoids
um
the um
uh the plants that create uh the uh
current uh keratinoids those like the
colors and the plants uh so that's when
I look for colorful plants that have
like Reds and purples because they have
these flavonoids and different things
that impart certain turpins and
cannabinoids
um that make certain plants special not
only for flavors and tastes but the
highs along the social along with that
so stems I rub them uh using like a
piece of paper or something other than
your fingers because you smell one plant
and they smell another plant they kind
of mix together but if you use a piece
of paper you can kind of smell the aroma
of that plant and if it's pungent or
stringent or if it affects nasal
passageways it affects certain different
ways because of those long chain Turpin
profiles that I was telling I was
talking about before those long chain
turpins are something that are kind of
unknown but your body kind of recognizes
so if you have this certain experience
by smelling the aroma of that plant and
that one's special so you kind of
Mark that this one's got the special
Aroma it's got a resin profile it's got
good roots it's branchy
um that's something that is good to
select for for males I kind of
do the same I look for the large root
zones uh the branch she wants and the
ones that have different uh color
content so if you've got a bunch of
males and some of them have you know pay
deals that have purple in them
um but there's nothing else the rest of
the plant is green another one has
purple patials but it has purple stems
and uh the sequels are purple then that
one's got a higher quantity of color to
it so that one might be chosen over one
that has just green effects because you
know there's nothing really you can you
know pick from it other than the colors
so those are just a few things that I
use for the selection criteria as well
as resin content there's also the type
of trichomes on males so if you have a
male that has
trichome production on the sepals of the
the male flowers
um I call them flowers but they're the
the male projections uh that you know
drop the pollen if you see resin on them
then that's also a good trade especially
if they have different colors on the
resins like the
um Neville's Haze purple tie uh F3 male
that I use for some of my lines it had
purple resin trichomes on the males so
that was kind of a added cool thing that
I like to uh see in the males
that's awesome to hear what a
comprehensive rundown gosh I feel like
that's becoming my uh go-to saying for
this interview I'll have to come up with
something better
um but following on with that I wanted
to ask just a few of the common things
we hear nowadays about selection like if
you agree with them the first one that
comes to mind is DJ Short always loved
to say that he wanted the more sativa of
the two parents to be the mother so did
you do you feel like there's any um sort
of correlation with that have you ever
heard that one
uh yeah my my
mine might be the I was reverse that so
with me I think the females are what you
see this so if you want to look a
certain way you want the female to be
that impression but if you want um the
potency and the qualities that comes
from the male
so
for males I look for
um the ones that are stinkiest have uh
the more branching
um and the colors so colors branching
and you know
root development from the male is what I
think Parts qualities and potency and
then the female adds uh the looks and
some of the smells to the line and
that's kind of where I see I see potency
and qualities coming from the males and
structures uh and the the way to use
those uh you know like the mitochondrial
DNA from uh the females
so chloroplast
some mitochondrial DNA and cellular DNA
from the males mostly
mitochondrial and cellular DNA for the
females
yeah that's brilliant I I think I
actually uh sub cool said something
along the same lines essentially so
that's interesting to hear that that's a
line there and he'd sort of noticed that
too I also forgot to mention that other
question when you're talking about your
light cycle you know shout out the Gas
Lantern method you really don't hear
about it too much these days but that's
cool to hear you're rocking it
I guess
what's a modified Gas Lantern it's it's
uh I use it for the the veg period
um
to fool the plants but the flowering
cycle is something I've developed
um and the way I've developed it is the
reason I use 10 and a half uh 13 and a
half hours of darkness is that plants
are growing in Hawaii or at the equator
um aren't stimulated by
um you know longer periods of dark
periods so if you use too much dark
period it doesn't actually cause the
plants to grow any faster so I tried to
um think if I was a plant at the equator
or Hawaii or other places on Earth what
would work in all these different places
so the 13 and a half hours of Darkness
Works in nature but it also works for
all these plants to kind of give you the
right ratio of light and darkness
yeah I love it so if I just Loop you
back to one of the other common breeding
selection tips we hear what's your
thoughts on the old stem rub
stem rub is great and that gives you
their Aromas and the stuff that you
should be you know uh you know the more
pungent or aromatic that the line is
um if it if it basically makes you feel
like a certain
um way then that that is something
special and our our chemistry is evolved
with cannabis
um I mean our endocannabinoid system is
evolved with cannabis so either it's
evolved with us or we evolved with it
um it's it's intrinsic to uh human
development so when you have an aroma
that does something to you with certain
plants there's something specific in
that uh chemical uh compound profile
that is affecting you in whatever
special way is it you know that the
primary turpins with the long chain
terpen profile along with the
cannabinoids that affecting you is it a
a flavonoid with those turpins it's it's
combination of the all the above it's
the stuff that we need to do more
studies on but they just haven't uh
I haven't had the funding and the right
people to yeah definitely
I guess a question I wanted to ask you
given like the amount of diversity there
is within your clone Library when you
finally do go to make a new cross
do you approach it as very conceptual
like you sort of map out on paper or is
it more of like uh let's mix and match
and then sort of go from there based on
what feels good how do you approach
breeding new crosses
well I there's a lot of work that goes
in that no one ever sees so there's a
lot of stuff written down of what would
be great to work together so there's
projects within projects so I'll I'll
attempt to
um grow out a bunch of varieties that I
am working for a certain project well
that project may go ahead because I've
gotten the males and females that I want
with the you know the varieties that I
need to create that project well another
project may be delayed because I'm not
getting the plants that I need for that
project so a lot of it's written down
everything's mapped all the seeds are
grown
um the quantities
um
uh it's it's all written down I have map
after map of a seed trays of all these
different varieties and growing out
these varieties for certain projects
um a lot of them don't get to fruition
and then as you're growing them you know
[__] happens
um plants die there's dampa there's
birds that might destroy them there
might be you know a child that goes in
and pulls up plants I've you name it
things have happened
um you know a light falls down to the
plants killing those plants you know you
can't help life
so you can't always plan for everything
so um
a lot of these happen because you're
just trying to make the best thing
possible with what you have a lot of
times there are attempts at preservation
and if you can't uh do preservation
there's conservation and then if
conservation is not possible meaning you
have only like two plants and you're
just trying to do what you can with them
um but if you can't do that then you
make something special with it and
sometimes that gets you know that's kind
of like with what you have so trying to
make special whatever things you can
make as special as possible with what
you have available
fantastic fantastic so what sort of
things can we expect to see coming out
and how long away are they
uh well there's the haste project that
we talked about and that's been in works
for several years already
um so we were taking like the best
varieties that we've been growing over
the years and kind of like going yeah
this line would be great for the his
project and we'd you know put that aside
and then uh work on other plants so
we've been steadily going through the
different varieties picking out the best
plants for the haze project and then
um we're making our crosses with the
best plants and then we're uh
also once we've done that individually
we're doing them with each other you
know we send each other these different
plants so the haze projects
um
are in the near future and the later
future so there should be some stuff
coming out that will be kind of pre-haze
project stuff that will be released so a
lot of that should be picked up if a
person can because it's going to be
special in itself as well as what will
be coming you know later on uh there's
going to be
I don't want to jinx myself but there's
um there's going to be
um like a hash Haze line but it's it's
basically uh called Mirage it's
basically using the best hash lines to
make like a hash Haze but it's all
different hash uh production varieties
from around the world so like cashmere
um Persian Turkish Lebanese uh Afghani
just using the best hash producing
varieties and creating like a haze
version of that but not not Haze but a
hash
you know mix of the best plants
um chocolate time trying to bring back
several different chocolate ties as well
as different pie varieties so I expect
different Thai stick varieties
um as well as chocolate ties and other
ties
um to
um be available at some point Mexican
righties I'm trying to um
bring back some of the heirloom
varieties that we've you know grown so
the first generation were like saving
the plants
um you know a lot of people go I grew
one plant and it wasn't what I wanted
from the line well one plant is going to
be one variability in a line that
needs work and saving in itself so
people will get to experience
um you know these Mexican varieties that
you know give you happiness and awesome
effects but if you're growing one plant
you're only getting one aspect of the
line so sometimes you need to go out
more than one plant sorry guys you need
to grow up more than one plan uh to
experience the line and say if you like
because some plants will give you or
some mines will give you several plants
that are wonderful and great but some of
them that are absolutely Stellar
um just comes out from a few more plants
not all the times do you have to grow
out 100 plants to get these wonderful
plants but if it's a preservation or
conservation it's only been you know one
year say the seeds were from the 60s or
70s and they were you know maintained
but barely maintained they need
selection so that first year of saving
it
um you're not going to get the best
plants while you're the grower and
growing these out so it may need another
generation or two before those beautiful
Expressions the best expressions of the
line come out for people so I'm going to
be working on bringing summer you know
lines like the Acapulco Gold and others
to make it more something that people
remember as being that awesome smoke
that they had back in the day some other
things are going to be some wine
varieties I'm trying to bring that bring
more of those uh available some of them
were
unknown Hawaiian varieties
um I'm not going to say they were Maui
Wally or Puna butter or something else
because I didn't know but they could be
um some of them are fantastic wine lines
but um I just I'm gonna say the time
frame that was from the island it may
have been sourced from and leave it at
that
um you know you as Growers can you know
decide what you want I'm not going to
butter it up any more than I I know
already but there's going to be some
heirloom Hawaiians coming out
several different Mexicans some of the
haze Purple Haze
Colombian Golds Reds wacky weed
Vietnamese black
[Music]
um Vietnamese dewat
um there's a Vietnamese Haze I'm making
which is basically five different
Vietnamese heirloom strains all like
land race heirloom mixed together so
that one's going to be special for
people
um so you get these you know psychedelic
flowers
that are you know racy to you know
purple and colorful and some of them are
candelabra Styles some of them are like
uh weeping willow so there's gonna be a
lot of Expressions a lot of cool stuff
for people to try so Mexicans Colombians
um
ties
Hawaiians and then the hash lines and
then there's going to be some my other
lines that I need to refresh will be
coming out as well
um and I I have a lot of African stuff
coming in the the near future but um you
know just like the Indian varieties will
be coming after that in afghanis I'm
also doing some Afghani lines uh there's
just so much uh but you can only do so
much but I'm trying to preserve as well
as making these lines
um as much as I can before it's too late
because
um they become a viable pretty quick and
if we can't maintain these the seed
stock then it'll go bad so I'm trying to
maintain them for everybody's future
because if I don't do it who knows who
will and
um
anyway I'm just trying to make more
stuff available for uh people while I'm
here
very Noble act and we're all very
appreciative in amongst all those
All-Star names you mentioned you
reference the black Vietnamese we had a
few questions about that could you just
give us an overview of it it appears to
be quite a uh a fan favorite
yeah I mean there's the the the
Vietnamese black was more of a jungly
weed it was more from
not the southern portion of Vietnam but
more from not quite the China border but
something that was near the Islam
Province but more inside of uh
Vietnam
um in Vietnam it's been they've had a
huge loss of uh genetics I don't know is
it's from the communism there but there
isn't a lot of cannabis production even
um 20 years ago uh there was a lot more
varieties and now it's it's really hard
to find anything so there's been a lot
of genetic loss unlike Thailand that's
had resurgent Laos Cambodia Vietnam has
lost a lot of the lines but uh the
Vietnam Black was
a jungle weed
um
somewhere somewhere around the same
latitude as
um you know the esan area of Thailand
which is more of the northeastern uh
portion of Thailand which borders Laos
and Cambodia that's kind of a special
area there but more so on the Vietnamese
side so it's like a thin Peninsula kind
of like Florida
a lot of the varieties that are now
there are from the southern portion
around
the South into Lots there's really
nothing there anymore
um my friend he's in his family is
indigenous from that uh part of Vietnam
he's an indigenous Vietnamese
um and he went looking for stuff and uh
through his cousins and family and uh he
wasn't able to find anything it's very
rare and hard to find now
um so what we've been able to preserve
is kind of like the last remnants of
what was there at one time in Vietnam it
was um you know they used to have a a
huge cannabis culture but um because of
what happens with um you know making
things illegal over time has caused a
lot of eradication throughout the world
a lot of that eradication happened in
the 1930s after alcohol prohibition was
changed over they decided to make
cannabis illegal but they got that
notion from the apartheid movement in
South Africa so a lot of the anti-drug
laws that were created were to control
people in South Africa to like uh you
know the the the people that were slaves
that were freed were controlled by use
of
creating cannabis being illegal because
a lot of the native people were smoking
cannabis so they made those illegal to
try to control people then so in the
1930s the United States incorporated
some of that uh to also control the
Mexicans and the black people
in the United States
um through uh
you know trying to scare the public into
thinking they were rapists from
consuming cannabis and different things
there's a lot of literature put out
there that was just totally false just
trying to scare people but it was a way
of controlling people and to
um force them to go to a different
country because uh at that time the
stock market had crashed and people were
you know scared of losing their jobs and
didn't have money so they they went to
picking on people from you know
neighboring Mexico or uh in some of the
poorer regions of the Americas so that
unfortunately caused the United States
to incorporate those laws which forced
other countries like India that had a
huge cannabis history and long long
reaching cannabis Street to make things
illegal and that forced all different
countries around the world to create the
drug laws that they have now and a lot
of them haven't reversed
um reversed themselves like they have in
the United States unfortunately really
yeah it's got a very sort of checkered
history doesn't it I guess this would be
a good point to jump into what's your
thoughts on the current state of
legalization and what's your thoughts on
the future of it do you think that we're
going to move to a model where the the
average home grower slash small
producers pushed out and it's all
corporate
well unfortunately a lot of the laws
that we as
um you know
at
democracy we vote for things but they
get changed after we vote them so the
lawmakers change what we vote for so a
lot of stuff is not what the people had
voted for
um and that is sad because it forces out
a lot of um
you know people that could be growing it
you know for medicine
for small farms for small businesses
they can create a lot of things you know
for textiles for cement for medicine
there's so many uses for cannabis but
unfortunately when these laws are voted
on and they're Changed by you know
companies
that buy out these lawmakers and then
no one's happy
um except the people that have money to
be able to circumvent these laws and um
you know establish businesses so
the state of things is not very good
um
legalization would be great uh but the
people need to have be able to grow what
they want and then for people that can't
grow what they can
um they they need other people to grow
for them so there needs to be outlets
for people to
um get their canvas grown for them and
then there needs to be studies on this
stuff and we need to be able to
um you know use this for pain medicine
or for PTSD
um uses for Sleep anxiety depression
there's so many medical uses for
different ratios of cannabis and the
different cannabinoids that can be
useful but the laws need to be changed
where more of that is available for
people to study less of the big
businesses need to
um you know get less availability to uh
what the the typical man doesn't get so
there should be equal laws I guess
around the world it seems like
legalization is kind of opening up so
hopefully I have
um great hope that around the world we
will
you know get to a point where we're in a
better state but right now it's kind of
all over the place and and it's not not
good but um I am hopeful that
uh people will get together and
um vote for something that's truly
helpful for the the world because we
could be offsetting global warming if we
grew enough plants
um we could be changing uh a lot of
these things that are being used for
wood we could be growing cannabis for
construction uses everything there's
just so much that if we just converted
it to cannabis
fuels textiles everything food nutrients
supplements
um it's all there it just we just need
to make more use of it
um
yeah okay that was my answer
yeah certainly we can only hope that uh
governments around the world adopt more
of an open view on these things I guess
on the more individual level I'd love to
ask as we do a lot of our breeders what
would be your advice for someone who's
just looking to get into breeding to
take their game a bit more seriously
what would you uh say to them
uh I say um
just grow just grow plants
um the more you grow the more experience
you get
um try not to take
what you read in these books as fact
because there's a lot of BS out there
there's a lot of stuff that people just
regurgitated that's not necessarily true
so you know
take experience for what it is you know
grow out the plants and and get your
experience first
um go ahead and breed and make some
plants you know do some selections you
don't have to grout hundreds of
thousands of plants to to do some
breeding but it's not helpful to take
stressed out plants do pollen chucks
with clones that you got from somewhere
from someone and then you know try to
push those out to everybody else because
those multi-poly hybrid pollen Chucks
are just not helpful to anybody
um and then getting clones from
everybody I think you should grow more
stuff from seed doing selections
yourself selecting plants it should be
done more everybody's relying on other
people to do the work for them so they
get these cuttings there's so many more
potent strains there's so many high
qualities that people are just not
experiencing you've seen people don't
experience you know a lot of the
different highs and qualities it's
because they're doing these clones that
everybody else is growing out so you're
only getting what other people are doing
but if they're growing stuff from seed
they can see they can create their own
clones from these lines and you know
have special plants it's very easy to
find a one pack of seed and get some
very very good
um traits out of them and you just need
to grow out the plants and experience
them and don't be afraid of growing
plants for a long period of time you
know
the best plants aren't the fastest
plants and don't kill plants that need
some nurturing because you know those
plants usually are the best plants if
you just you know give them the time to
to grow it's kind of like the ugly
duckling you know it might look weird
and you know offset but it'll grow out
of that it'll grow out of those weird
traits at first and once it's
established itself and you get these
beautiful plants that you get to
experience
so grow all the plants don't kill
everything and just because a plant is
experiencing intersex traits doesn't
mean that they got bad seeds or
something usually that's a sign that
they're under stress so they're they're
being over watered or there's too much
nitrogen in the soil or there's insects
invading and chewing out their roots or
you know sucking the life out of the
plant there's they're telling you
there's something wrong so usually
figure out what that problem is and then
and remedy the problem and then keep
growing that plant
but the real thing is for breeders that
are trying to get into it just grow the
plants and keep it simple
some great advice there for sure and I
definitely get behind that guys you can
do some cool stuff even if you're not
popping hundreds of thousands of seeds I
guess I would love to quickly ask you
though if someone wanted to try to up
their game a bit maybe take on a more
raw line you know like try to feel your
breed some Thai seeds or something you
know like have a good go at it how many
seeds do you think they should run given
we know you tend to need a run through a
few more what what sort of number would
you throw at there is like just a
ballpark figure
uh well it's it's this it's hard to say
so if if a line is raw there's no
selections done you're gonna need a lot
more seeds uh if a person has done a
preservation and there's done selections
over a couple Generations or if it's a
true breeding strain that's you know
been preserved
um
you'll need less seeds so if a person's
worked the line
um you may only need a pack of ten but
20 is better
um but if you if you got a raw seed line
that you know you're gonna need
selections you might need 30 50 seeds it
all depends but you can still grow out
those plants
from a small selection
make more seed and then from those seeds
you'll have a lot more seeds to work
with so you can work with 10 to 20 seeds
it's going to take you a little longer
you know use all the males females grow
those out make seed from them and then
you have thousands of seeds to select
from
the problem is when you get that many
plants is what do you select after that
point you know it just gets to be where
there's so many plants that it it's hard
to to make the selection so you really
don't need thousands of plants unless
you're doing full large-scale breeding
practices that's a that's a lot of work
so basically you can narrow it down to
you know 10 15 females uh four to six
males and you can do a lot of good
breeding that way and you know as long
as you have you're selected for certain
things
um you know branchy plants you know
things that are have odor resin
production good roots
um you'll do well you know but there
should be a goal involved with the
breeding you should you should do it to
improve the line there shouldn't be just
you know Crossing this and that because
it's cool because you know what's the
use in that I mean that's fun but if
you're if you really want to do some
breeding you should have an end goal you
know you want to
um take a line that grows small and make
it grow big but keeping the same type of
quality flowers that's you know a nice
goal to have for a lot of people
for instance
certainly you can only reach what you
aim for I've seen in your work that
you've uh Incorporated deep chunk into a
few of your lines and I guess it sort of
fits that category of preservation
what's your thoughts on Tom Hill's line
I've always been a fan
deep chunk I might have used one a long
long time ago with some purple Bubba
Kush
um but I don't usually use deep chunk
much deep chunk is very um
uh it it stops all over the genetics
meaning it um it takes over it's it's a
good quality
um
Indica broadleaf hash plant Afghani you
know more of like a Missouri Sharif
shorter uh but larger flowers but not
too tall chunky
um it's good breeding material because
you can kind of you know what you're
going to get out of it so if you breed
something into it and you see those
traits you can kind of see what
um what the other line imparts into it
so it's a it's a good training line for
breeding I guess
because you know it's going to be
consistent
certainly and do you have any experience
with any of these other lines like Pine
tarkush x18 his Haze
yeah I actually I I took the plantar
Kush and I bred it into the
um
it's a trolley and I bred that into the
OG Kush project I did and the reason I
did that was I wanted to impart real
cush into the modern OG Kush so When
people grew up my varieties they
couldn't say oh there's no real cushion
it because
you know it imparts both lines so I I
grew out those
um the pine tartar Kush which is is
pretty good line it kind of has an
Afghani look to it but it's Pakistani
um
has a good aroma profile and um yeah the
the stable breeds from Tom Hill's work
um so yeah uh Tom Hill's got some good
work the x18 was good
um a nice uh Pakistani line similar to
the citrulli
um
lots of different Aromas fruit flavors
nice stuff uh not overly potent but a
good breeding material kind of good to
kind of breed with other things
lovely lovely and I mean you just
touched on OG a moment ago you've done
quite a few different crosses with
different OG cuts and so I'd love to
hear your take on the different ogs if
you have a preferred one and how some of
those crosses turned out
sure
um so when I was growing for the medical
clubs in the early 2000s
um we were growing uh what was available
in Northern California and then bring it
to the medical clubs the medical clubs
wanted OG Kush
um so the medical clubs that I went to
they would take their OG Kush cuttings
and they would have thousand watt HPS
high pressure sodium lights growing
under each plant lollipopped
um so huge lights lots of energy you
know huge electric bills and um in rooms
just with these
um you know small plants producing not a
whole lot but uh it was worth it to them
because they were people were buying it
for a high dollar
um but they they didn't yield with the
[__]
um they they grew poorly rooted poorly
because most of them were derived from
like bag seeds someone's bag seed was oh
this was some really good stuff so they
grew it out usually from like you know
stressed out situations it harmed so
those stability issues with it but the
the smoke was really good
um
so I decide I asked the the one of the
guys the place was uh uh G3 Collective
it was an Upland uh Southern California
and um there they try to fight the the
state in the D.A and lost uh but anyway
uh
I asked him what are the two lines that
um have the highest quality flowers that
you guys love but don't yield much and
don't root well I'll I'll breed these
and and improve them and so he gave me
the so-called so-called G13 cut and the
um
uh the true Kush uh cut and he said
these These are the best we have I wish
they'd yield more and I wish they rooted
better so I basically bred
um my idea was to breathe the modern
Kush with real Kush
um so I decided that I didn't like to
reverse anything so this no reversing
the pollen you have unstable plants you
you can't make anything stable from
instability so I decided to use real
mail so I used the citralei which is a
Pakistani uh line uh with the uh Pine
Trek Bush and I found a male that was
more Afghani land race looking and I
used that to pollinate
um
the true Cush and then from there I I
basically grew up 50 plants and I
selected the best
um males and females so I worked down
from 50 plants down to like 17 females
down to like
um nine males and then finally worked
out to the best
10 females and four best males and then
it worked down to the last uh three
males and the last seven females and
then I bred those to create the what I
call true gangster Cush
um those two males I also use to breed
uh to the other OG cushes that was I was
growing out and I over uh several years
of going to all the clubs I collected
all the different OG cushes from the San
Fernando Valley Kush the Skywalker
um the Hell's Angels OG which is not the
same as my Hell's Angel line
um there's also the Diablo OG the
abusive Ochi Kush
um there was the Fire OG from Northern
California and the SoCal Fire OG the Nor
Cal Fire OG was a lot better
um
and there was a lot of other ogs and uh
you know Master Kush and different lines
I grew at the same time Taho G
um trying to find the best ogs so my my
selection criteria was finding the most
potent highest quality ogs but at the
same time I was trying to find ones that
grew well
um and rooted well for the breeding
purposes because
um
ones that would produce really good
flour but didn't grow very well weren't
worth it to me
um so I excluded the San Fernando Valley
Kush because it didn't grow very well it
was a short little plant produces
wonderful great buds but from what I was
trying to do it didn't cut the mustard
um though I'd like to go back and do
some breeding with it but not at the
time because it wasn't what I was
looking for so the best cuttings that I
found were
um the NorCal Fire OG and OG Kush we got
from the Hell's Angels in Oakland it was
uh at the time 27 year old cut that they
had they just called OG Kush
um I used that line to create the Hell's
Angel line
um
I also grout the Skywalker OG
um which was the best one I felt it just
did the trick every time every time he
smoked it it just you know check all the
different boxes uh the abuse of OG was
another one that was very good yielding
also high quality
um the two the best one was the OG Kush
we've got for the Hell's Angels and the
Skywalker those were my two favorite uh
the Tahoe was also a larger yielding
good OG
um but not quite as good as the
Skywalker and the ojukush we got
um
the fire o g at a SoCal was not very
good yielding it was kind of wiry and it
was good good uh buds but it just wasn't
growing very good the north calpharo G
yielded very well and had you know the
same good characteristics as a SoCal one
but it was just a better plant in
general and I did some breeding with
that to make the uh the uh OG purple
fire timelines
um but uh Skywalker the abusive uh the
OG Kush we we made different lines with
those so I had bread with those
unfortunately I had a warehouse in
Southern California which I was using um
when I came down here to do some
breeding but uh it got sabotaged so all
the cuttings all the different
um
things I was doing to to bulk the OG
lines the true gangster Kush projects
that I'd done
um was lost so I only have a small
amount of seed left but I need to
revisit those for people but that that
whole OG project got squashed because of
all the loss of all the plants for
reproduction and all the different uh
the Clones that I lost I lost a juice
fruit Thai
um you know the one the various lines
the Maui Wowie different things that uh
you know I don't have anymore
wow that's a bummer to hear you lost
that I mean right at the end of the
story you mentioned yeah you lost the
one what's your thought on that it sort
of come more to the Forefront of
discussions with um a few different
breeders using it do you think it's as
good as what some people make it out to
be
well I I smoked it years ago and uh but
at the time
um when I smoked it there was an
earthquake
so uh I didn't I I didn't know if there
was the earthquake or the smoke that
kind of hit me a certain way I think it
was kind of the the combination the two
so
um it's it's definitely got
um it's a special potent weed it's
definitely got some great qualities to
it for sure
foreign
what do you think
huge shout out to snow hire for swinging
by
dropping that part one of two knowledge
bombs on us and as always huge thank you
to our incredible sponsors seeds here
now all the latest breeders the hottest
drops an incredible new website they've
been slashing prices to give you the
best deals while still offering their
patent guarantee on satisfaction and
germination check them out likewise
simply souvenirs if you're after and
selected range of Boutique genetics both
local and international check them out
guys they've got everything you need
from seeds to smoking accessories to
baits
everything under the sun simply
souvenirs they'll look after your best
customer service in the game huge shout
out Simply souvenirs
[Music]
big shout out to our friends at
corporate biological systems providing
all the Predators you need to keep your
garden pests and pathogens free check
out the spidex vital if you're worried
about spider mites you should release
these things periodically guys I promise
you you will view it as an investment in
your garden ensuring that you never have
any spider mites in your garden should
be one of your key priorities as a
cultivator
huge shout out Copa biological systems
we appreciate you and your support
likewise pulse sensors you're more yield
more resin better flour better
concentrates who doesn't check out pulse
guys if you're ready to get serious get
a pulse sensor from a single tent to a
single room to a multi-facility
operation just don't let hidden
variables hold your crop back get your
grow parameters in check and start
yielding the highest quality possible
huge shout out pulse sensors thank you
so much
likewise big shout out to the patreon
gang we love and appreciate you please
consider checking out the patreon if you
want early access to upcoming episodes
additional interviews you won't get
access to unless you're on there as well
as genetic giveaways and ad-free content
check it out friends that's the patreon
www.patreon.com forward slash the
podcast or one word we love and
appreciate you
[Music]
really
and there you have it my friends part
one of this two-part hitter from the man
himself snow High
[Music]
come on back for the next one and I'll
see you there
foreign
[Music]