[Music]
well hello my friends and welcome back
for another episode of the podcast a
cannabis podcast for budding enthusiasts
as always you're joined by your boy
heavy days here from the upside down
Library we want to give a massive shout
out to all of our incredible sponsors
who help ensure the show continues to
happen seeds here now number one seed
bank in the industry all the hottest
breeders the latest drops everything you
can look for and more whether you're
after indoor outdoor feminized regular
autoflow they've got everything under
the sun to keep you loaded on all the
hottest genetics producing the most most
fire Bud you've ever had I hear they've
got some incredible lines from heavy
days still in stock if you want to go
check that out make sure to do it before
it's too
late big shout out to CT now we
appreciate you so
much as usual a massive massive thank
you and shout out to our good friends at
copit biological if you want to harvest
the best crop today you have to Ure your
garden is pest and pathogen free pumping
on all cylinders if you're battling
spidermite check out the incredible
spidex red likewise I know a lot of you
guys are battling AIDS at the moment
check out their apip parm this is
another product I absolutely stand
behind from copit if you want to get rid
of apids get rid of spidermites check
out the AIP parm check out the spidex
red big shout out to copit biological
thank you so much we appreciate your
ongoing
support the final piece of the puzzle to
ensure that your room is killing it is
our good friends at Pulse their sensors
are second to none industry leading and
just recently they announced the pulse
Hub what more could you want an
integrated unit for all of your sensors
to ensure that your garden is automated
and tracking all of the variables you
may not be consciously aware of from VPD
to ppf dupoint temperature humidity so
much more you've got to get yourself a
pulse sensor guys it has revolutionized
the way I grow flower and increase the
turpine content the cannaboid content
the yield so so so so much more shout
out as always to our friends at Pulse
senses likewise if any of you guys have
been listening to the show you know that
I am passionate about helping people
transition to vaporized options if
they're considerate about their
respiratory health and for me dap are
the world leaders in this dnat helped me
to transition from bongs to vaping and I
tell you what I've never looked back
their unit is the most potent the most
highly replicating of a bong hit I've
ever come across and through their
incredible M unit I was able to
successfully get off bongs a few years
ago now truly one of the most Innovative
and interesting Vapes on the market
using a totally different design to
others you have found check these guys
out you will not be disappointed massive
shout out to daat thank you so
much and last but not least we want to
give a massive shout out to the
incredible patreon gang without you guys
we could not continue to make episodes
if you want to get early access to
upcoming episodes exclusive content just
on the patreon including the likes of
mean Jean Bob Hill bod triome jungle so
much more be sure to go check out our
patreon we give away genetics every
month to our supporters along with
artwork Vapes sensors so much more
please check out the patreon guys I
promise you you won't regret it you'll
get your money back in swag to helping
supporter show you love thank you so
much everyone from the patreon
yo yo yo welcome back for another
episode as always you're joined by your
boy heavy days here from the upside down
library and I am so incredibly grateful
as always to our patreon
[Music]
supporters on the episode today we are
incredibly stoked to have the man the
myth the
legend Eternal happiness and love one of
my absolute favorites
[Music]
bod here to get into it in a
two-parter so without further
delay let's get into
it hello and welcome to another episode
of the podcast on today we have a big
one a followup from what has to be one
of our most fan favorite episodes from a
few years ago an absolute Titan in the
breeding World a real breeders breeder
who prolific both in their output as
well as the wide variety of strains they
work with from Land race to Hype Beast
one of the most kindest most empathetic
and loving people I've ever met and
someone who I'm honored to call a friend
a big welcome to Bod of bod seeds hey
doing my friend oh I'm so good my
superpowered cannabis comrade you got me
now I'm like blushing I feel you can't
start off like that no I'm stupified
thank you you're very kind and generous
with your all you said thank you uh look
I was going to say a man who needs no
introduction and then I thought nah
stuff it he does need an
introduction yeah so look I guess you
know the question we ask everyone
recently what have you been smoking on
recently uh well to be super honest I
haven't really been smoking for the last
maybe two months you know ever since my
son uh bod past I've been really trying
to cultivate my My Clarity and really
kind of rest in the emotions and rest in
this place of really feeling it and
really trying to understand it and you
know grief is such an incredibly
powerful substance like I feel like it's
the ultimate kind of solvent in a way it
just completely dissolves you and I feel
like I'm in a place where I can do it
but cannabis is such an
emotional like substance too in a way
it's you know it's tied to smell which
is emotional there's so much in it that
I was also too a little bit not scared
but I just needed a break you know like
you've been swimming and you just want
to jump on the raft so but the good news
is I'm feeling good I feel like um this
weekend I'm going to start back on the
plant medicines it's the next journey in
my healing so yeah I will probably be I
think I'll
try for the first one maybe I've been
enjoying this one it's called it's a
kongoi Mana so it's like GOI congales
and then Hawaiian Afghani together and
it has it really I mean I have to do it
when I don't have to get up for kids in
the morning for school but it has this
really clean like ex like some you know
how some plants are kind of like Spirit
nourishing they just kind of take you on
this like soft buoyant ride through all
the things that you're interested in and
all the things that you want to give
gratitude for and it just you know and I
love it I I was smoking it before and I
really love listening to music on it and
you know even better is like searching
for music like I'm a treasure hunter at
heart and everything I do and I go one
of my most favorite things to do is get
super blazed and then go like on to band
camp or something someplace that you can
kind of follow the tidbits and look for
new music and you know go from like
crazy world music to electronic to to
field recordings like they have like
Maria Saina chance to like there's so
much cool stuff and I that is super
enjoyable and kind of makes me happy so
I think that's coming up really soon but
uh to answer your question before that
you know I was smoking that and I was
been working on kind of like a this La
pure kush that was really had a really
kind of good experience for me it was a
little bit kind of too
edgy um what else uh I've been doing
this one called Blue camper that's like
an ogkb
orgasmatron and then even before that
the best stuff was all of the samples
from the big um Haze Valley growout grew
out we do so the land races and sativas
and there's so many amazing samples in
that but you
know um I don't know I haven't really
been smoking as much as I used to and
I'm really trying to get back into it
because you know it's just been it's
been a wild ride the last few years so I
don't know but I feel good and I feel
cannabis is truly one of my best friends
and teachers
so sorry for the long rolling
answer no no please you know like I just
love to start off by passing on both
mine and the listeners sincere
condolences for the loss of your son you
know like I was I was fortunate enough
to have met bod a few times and it was
immediately clear to me how loved he was
by his family and how important he was
to you his mom his brothers uh so you
know again our sincere condolences and
I'm I'm glad to hear that you feel like
you're sort of coming out the other end
it's it's obviously something that we
can't even imagine you know so that's uh
that's cool to hear that you've been
getting back into music you know while
we're on the topic one of the little
Easter eggs of the show is that if you
go to if you go to the show SoundCloud
and you look at the favorites That's My
Little Secret random SoundCloud Treasure
Trove for the listeners oh that's cool I
should put up my band camp I mean what
I've been digging recently I'm trying to
think of what the only time I get to
listen now is like when I'm in the car
taking the kids like back from scho
what is it that's
so I know like one that we've been what
is it the there's like an is it Moroccan
or Algerian band let's fit woman with
one guy like Les fil something like it's
just it's kind of like
Naish and it has this really cool female
kind of chanting drone but with and I
think they're use a gimber or something
that goat skin
Bas I don't know um I feel like a dork
though because all my friend like oh
what are you listening and like I'm
supposed to be kind of but I think I
think I've just been you know like the
whole whole process of going through all
these challenges is really kind of just
brought me to like a base place of like
surrender and I feel like my mind hasn't
caught
up yeah sure no I understand definitely
hard being put on the spot isn't
it well look in in your last answer you
referenced that you've uh you've been
enjoying some new sativas and i' I'd
love to hear like how how do you think
we can try to bring sativas back into
the picture and one of the ideas I heard
recently that resonated with me was
Shanti when I interviewed him made this
sort of comment about how Neville's ha
is like the champagne of cannabis and I
sort of thought that's actually like
quite an interesting and possibly
Innovative way to Market some really
hardcore sativas you know because they
kind of are like that if you experienced
them what's your thoughts how do how do
we bring it round back to sativas and
and what have you been enjoying lately
sativa wise I think the problem with
sativas is the pro is the profitability
and the duration so I think if we can
try and capture some of these highs and
package them into a shorter flower time
or like Empower farms and Growers to uh
really find sativas that they love and
they can cultivate well and and somehow
get those out to the people and then
also get to this out to everybody like
my whole thing right now is I realize
like we're in a pickle like it the state
of the nation is just so messed up and
it's like we realize that when anytime
Babylon gets involved it never turns out
it's kind of going back to Our Roots
like of over planet of just making seeds
giving out seeds trading seeds to
finding people in your community or
finding websites finding forums finding
any way you can to connect Facebook
groups you know uh discords to make
these these connections and trade and
you you know I mean with the Hop L that
throws a little bit of a thing into it
but trade seeds then like um and really
PE you know people coming out of the
woodwork like that's one thing that
inspires me is going on to different
forums even though I'm not really active
because it's just been a little
overwhelming for me um I do love to look
at it and see what people's doing and
even on Facebook there's some wild like
forums even on there people trading and
people coming um out from different
parts of the world and you know as as
things are getting more and more
polluted and more and more people are
getting interested the education levels
is gone down too and so things are
getting that's going to be problematic
as well because you have all these
people that are so excited and are
getting seeds from people in other parts
of the country and they may think they
have something but it may have already
been five generations down it was mixed
with something else you know kind of
like Mexican genetics you go in you're
like oh actually the
Narco Force already hidiz that one like
you know 25 years ago with skunk or you
know it's it's really difficult so I
mean the best place too ask your
grandparents ask your friend's Uncle ask
that crazy looking guy at the gas
station ask everybody like hey do you
have any old seeds grow them out like I
don't know it's such a the sativa thing
is problematic so I think you know maybe
things I love there's like a I'm kind of
mumbling a bit but the whole New York
City uh piff kind of Revival and those
guys kind of bringing that all back and
you know with all those older hybrids
and people getting interested in that
way there's these new kind of
outcroppings and I come almost see like
the the era of land race or pseudo like
Heritage farmline land race is kind of
over and it's almost this new hype Haze
kind of thing of people coming together
and creating new new sativas with older
thing you know if you listen to the
plants and you go deep you can coax out
all of the the
attributes um that you're looking for so
and then as far as sativas that I really
enjoy you know I I used to like edgy
ones and then you know and now I'm kind
of in this category I call it like
Spirit nourishing I'm looking for
sativas that you don't even really feel
feel like you know what I mean it's like
you I've had a few you smoke and just
like your day is better um maybe your
music sounds cooler maybe uh it makes
you friendlier maybe it just puts a
little magic tinge like when I was going
through the Vietnamese beans that I
found the Vietnamese 7 and I think doc d
got to smoke some of these the one we
kept was like a classic psychedelic
beautiful Vietnam old school Vietnamese
but all of its sisters there was ones
that had the weirdest effects you know
like ones that would just make music
sound better ones where you would think
you were high but you weren't but your
day just went better almost lubricated
reality or almost was a put out like a
field around you that brought in new
experiences like I'm all about finding
these like magical plants that are
almost they're not just you're not just
getting high or stoned or thing you're
creating um you're creating like an ally
to let let it guide you through the
world you know and if you have enough of
these it's like you're each day you
could go walk with one you could go out
into the world and you know and you see
what it brings to you so but
traditionally I like if we want to get
back to the thing um I love Himalayan
hand rub sativas like your classic you
know Nepali and North Indian like those
are something about the bright joyful
energy that they bring um I love some
some like uh like maybe like Highland w
hocke in kind of like from either up
high or above wak or kind of the coastal
mountains that have that kind of
really sunny kind of fun but psychedelic
eyes what else do I like I love the that
Vietnamese I had I love that big sir
Nigerian was such a cool one it was
so strong and like but it took you and
it was strong but like in a friendly way
kind of like a big brother or something
like you were never like scared it was
just like let's do this kind of thing
um I yeah and you know what at this
point there's there's broad now that
we're kind of moved into this new
nomenclature of narrow leaf and Broad
Leaf it kind of frees you up a lot
because there's a lot of uh narrow Leaf
like traditional kind of indicia style
plants that have that experience to that
high and I think the beauty of the uh
the broad leaves is some of the most
like one of my favorites I call it like
a
um I used to have a term I used to call
it but it was
a when you smoke a certain Broad Leaf
that completely relaxes your body and
Euphoria and let your and then lets your
mind go free so like it's almost like
these dreamy like traveling journeying
broad leaes where you know your head is
completely liberated and you're and it's
just so Exquisite and beautiful but
you're completely relaxed and I almost
am maybe I'm getting older I really love
that too so for me it's it's not so much
sativa Inda it's finding these special
effects and each person's different you
know some people smoke indas and they
can't sleep for the next two and a half
weeks and and you know and some people
smoke divas and it totally chills them
out so I think it's you know it's about
growing plants it's about planting seeds
it's about experiencing all these
different things so you can find these
plants just like your friends and family
like I guess you can't choose your
family but you can choose your friends
you can choose your plants you can um
find your Nee you can find what really
um nourishes you and and share that and
and also push it further if there's
something a plant that just you love
then work with it and try and bring that
out and bring and let people experience
that and um long-winded answer on what
my favorite sativas are but that's kind
of where I'm at I'm just at just
enjoying the plant Spirit of cannabis
like just really just it's you know it's
it's our plant Ally It's the dog of
plants you know and I know especially in
this day and age it's like we have a lot
of these kind of scientist breeders
telling us that we're doing it wrong oh
you're not using the right words it's
like we've been doing this for 10,000
years okay humans have been working with
with cannabis for 10,000 years we're not
doing anything wrong this is like a
cannabis human love affair that's gone
on for thousands of generations so don't
let anyone tell you you're doing
something wrong that you're not calling
it the right thing it's like it's for
everyone whether it's a grandma trying
to make CBD Auto flowers so that she can
walk down the street to visit her
grandson or is the guy that wants to
shoot out to meet the Doon you know it
it's about finding your heart and your
connection to the plan I I love that
give me some of that spiritual
nourishment and there's so many things I
have to follow up on with that statement
and the first one is that V at7 it's
it's still possibly the most most
memorable all all of my most memorable
weeds are coming from you honestly um
there's the V7 there's the the tie I
can't remember if it was the lowland or
the Highland it was the Pearl one the
pearls that um the
nl2 um you know so many of the things
you've given me are so so so memorable
but some of our fans also were really
interested in that V7 cuz you know it's
so beautiful the most common question we
got was where did you get that seed
stock from cuz I guess people were so
impressed like is it is there an
interesting story or is it just like no
just you know got some cool seats yeah
there is an interesting story and this
is like something like if you're a good
person you put out a good vibe like good
things happen to you and this it was
like I think it was on like icy mag
forever ago and this old guy Alby he was
you know and I've looked for him
recently I can't find any of his
postings maybe someone knows him or
something he kept seeds from like the
70s on or 80s on and um whenever you
would go someplace and he would bring
them back and he's like hey I'm getting
older I have these really cool seeds
would you like them I I see that you
preserve seeds I see that you have a
good rep like do you want these and like
I'm like yeah I would love them I'll do
my best to preserve them to to uh do
whatever I can to you know carry this
you know all the time and energy putting
into collecting them um I would love to
so I got them from him and I I still
have a lot of them I haven't cracked too
many but the vietnames was the first one
that I crapped into and that plant yeah
it really is that classic kind of like I
guess it would be like that late 70s
import he got it there but it it's
different than a lot of the new stuff
you know it really still has its
original vibration like I always you
know because nature is the ultimate
selector you know through it's time and
environment and that's it's that's its
hands when it works with cannabis it's
utilizing its environment and its time
and it's like that's that's a lot of
breeding and there's so many unique
inputs like there's the latitude of
ltitude the dirt the people that that
tended it the the de and the inhale like
it's a whole so it's a time capsule it's
like a teaching it's like it's song it's
like it's it's it's almost like it's
living artwork and it's like an access
point like a vibrational access point
where we can explore that culture that
time if we really open up into it and
really feel like what it was also
putting out you know it's like a piece
of art that you get to experience those
those really Timeless undiluted plants
and they're pain in the ass to work with
they're pain in the ass to get they're
pain in the ass to grow but and you know
a lot of times uh they don't always when
they grow in a new environment they
don't
always have they're there but you know
something about point of origin cannabis
and I really encourage people to to
travel to experience these I know it's
traveling is a lot more difficult these
days and expensive but if you can even
travel on Facebook by finding people
that are also and just trading seats is
yeah is open your pallet like oh grow
all kinds of stuff so you can really
understand what you enjoy and how to
work with it so that's the basic story
on the v87 and and this courageous and
amazing guy I'll be you know I'm gonna I
think now that I have finally have a
place to start up and work again I'm
gonna crack into some of his other seeds
he had some Nepali he had some stuff
from
Jamaica a lot of Caribbeans he had some
pakist he has these pakistanis that he
said oh these are better than that stuff
the kids are growing now and I've tried
to pop those and I can get them to crack
but I can't get them to come up so but I
still a lot of those so I'm excited to
you know I have so many seeds I realize
and this is problematic too because it's
time you know I keep them in the fridge
but I'm right now I'm trying to figure
out ways to not only preserve them but
to share them like I got a whole I think
I got a plan Brewing about opening up my
collection to people you know I might um
you know where I been kind of thinking
about it's kind of like even before we
were talking last night like looking in
my fridge I could never my kids my whole
family this entire town can can Sprout
all these seeds so you know maybe doing
them through narka and people can if
someone wants to choose that one that's
really that they've always wanted to do
then they can grow it make seeds and
maybe send half back to narica and drift
distribute it or if there's some kind of
B seed strain that's really old that
everybody's wanted to try that you know
is extinct I would lovingly give packs
for people to F2 or you know I also
might dig into all the seeds that I've
gotten from other people I have so many
different reader packs and I'm thinking
about maybe auctioning some of those on
Great Lakes genetics just to kind of be
able to afford a hoop house for next
year so I want to get my collection out
before it's too late and also because I
know a lot of these the know that're
kind of Providence and I know where they
came from and I know how I got them and
I I can be reasonably sure you can never
know really but I know I can be more
sure from stuff that I got 20 years ago
or 10 years ago than I can now you know
and there's a lot of seed reselling
Place get land receipts from all over
world but it's there's no kind of
there's no checks and balances so I
applaud everybody that does that but at
the same time I'm like oh this is kind
of this is another problem it's a
beautiful problem you know yeah wow
that's so excting starting to hear you
know I'm sure there's a lot of people
out there who would be very down to you
know sort of open populate or F2 in some
capacity some seeds and and give back
and gosh we're going to have to loop
back and talk about narica but I just
wanted to quickly ask because we had a
few people interested in asking and
you're probably the only person who I
trust to give a good answer for this one
but you kind of touched on it there but
like what what advice would you give to
someone who wants to be for lack of a
better words like a modern ethical
cannabis Adventurer you know they want
that land race experience a where would
you say is a place they could do it but
B what are some of the things they
should keep in mind about you know
making sure that they're not
inadvertently doing more harm than good
so to
speak yeah I mean that's hard it all
depends on if it's for personal use or
if they're gon to spread it out I don't
know I wish I wish there you got a
little certificate with each time you
you got one but no I think the number
one thing is find a place
that you've always wanted to go that you
have a connection to make sure that they
actually grow cannabis but pretty much
everywhere does except the North Pole or
um and then make friends you know spend
some time don't just go hey you got
seeds or like um like make friends with
the family that you get the seeds like
make a lasting relationship bring bring
pens for the kids bring antibiotics like
topical antibiotics Bing bring some
non-hybridized seeds that are safe for
that area you know uh um share just do
whatever you can and make them know that
this is something special to you and it
should be something special to them and
work from there I mean there's not I
mean there's so many great places I I
would you know if number one place if
any I tell anyone to go it's kind of a
Galant but it's not super expensive when
you get there go to Nepal like go go
trekking super easy it's super beautiful
you hike four hours you get to a tea
house these are like these are like
beautiful Pathways going through the
Himalayas they've been there for
thousands of years you stop at all kinds
of cool places um there's so much
incredible ganja um you don't have to
have a tent there's always a place to
stay and you just get to blaze and just
see the beauty of Nature and be in these
places and meet cool people and make
lasting friendships and you know smuggle
some seeds back wherever you need
to and um yeah Nepal is I would say
great I mean you know North India like
the whole parva valley I think that's
cool but it's kind of it it's got a it's
got an element that that I I don't think
that's maybe seasoned if you really want
to blaze I think Nepal has the biggest
heart you know but there's so many cool
places like Thailand is opening up so
much there's so much cool stuff La
Vietnam Mexico Guatemala bise um the
Caribbean I mean it's everywhere I mean
the only places that I would kind of go
that I want wanted to go to like Molly
in you know um or maybe certain parts of
the Congo where it was like more pigy
tribes um where else I'm trying to think
of any place maybe if you could China's
a little rough right now but
shinjan the you know on the other side
of the stands like Afghanistan all those
the other side of the mountains um used
to be a big part of the Silk Road I
think there's still some ancient stuff
there but you know there's not a lot of
places but two another thing is if you
make friends with people that have they
interested in cannabis in Africa in
South Africa in Guatemala wherever you
make a friendship with that and they
usually hey why don't you next time why
don't you come visit and you're like
hell yeah go make some friends somewhere
and and smoke it there and you know
proofs in the pudding if it's a feeling
that you really enjoy and you've never
felt it before in the regular stuff you
smoke it probably has a pretty good
amount of heirloom genetics in it but I
think we're also reaching a point where
where things are getting
rapidly turned into a giant uh Treasure
Chest so I've never been one been able
to do like selections at at scale or at
field field scale but I feel like at
some point that's to truly find unique
things we're going to have to get to
that level because there'll be like 500
different strains in one
strain which is kind of cool you imagine
looking through like 2,000 plants to
find the most ultimate plant that that
just popped out of like a a cookies
gelato um
GMO sherbet runs um strawberry um
Michi Pakistani land rice
like thr that in there too just stick
them all in there you know like that's
what you'll find at in the you know the
uh the Kaiba pass somewhere oh my God I
yeah I mean it's it's true I mean look
at like greenhouse and they some of
their exploit
I mean it's a little Colonial and it's a
little bit um they're just goofballs
it's not like I don't even think they
they have necessarily like they're not
being malicious they're just kind of
like like it's a totally different
mindset um and I wonder I'm like okay
but where did all those seeds go you
guys gave them some really cool um
gelato hybrids but what did you bring
back I me yeah I don't I don't know it's
just such a strange new world and it's
beautiful amazing but it is really hard
to
navigate but there's
people I just want to give Big Ups to
all of the people you know like Deo and
um all these young people that are so
super passionate that are in you know
it's like there's the guys that Kevin
droy went with in Pakistan and there's
that Babu in Afghan all these people
that are really going to these places
that we are never going with a huge
passion and a huge dedication and really
doing the work and writing things down
trying things say saving things in
places that are probably the last places
on Earth that we can still get pure
lines you know and I really think that
is incredible and like there people are
popping up all over the place and
they're like I can do this too and I
think that is really Noble Pursuit and I
think it it is quite amazing and
beautiful that we have these you know
these other kind of Expressions popping
out of this current situation that is
it's almost like a a Saving Grace in a
way yeah yeah totally totally and I
think one of the things that really
resonates a lot with what you just said
is the uh the importance of those
organic friendships I I actually
remember it was uh I think maybe mid
2019 I was talking to deep park irisin
for anyone listening I was like man I'd
love to go walk around Nepal a bit and
we we started chatting about it and then
you know sadly covid-19 hit just shortly
after so never came to fruition but it
speaks to what you were saying like you
know those organic friendships are often
what's going to help sort of get you to
you know I love the idea of doing it but
it's such a foreign idea but to have
someone there on the ground like yeah
what a what an awesome thing so that's
uh that that's really cool to hear and
you just reminded me the last time we
spoke it was so long ago it was before
you did that really cool Indian trip oh
yeah can you tell us a little bit about
that do you remember much I know it was
a minute ago but gosh it seemed cool
yeah that was um so that was the art
Kumba that was like the half Ma and the
crazy thing is um in January is the Maha
Kumba again that's the 12year one and
I'm doing everything I can to try and
get me and my wife there we'll see what
happens the finances are a little um
skit but uh if anybody wants to go it's
a great place to go experience but okay
but we cycle back so the last half MAA
um I met um uh deepo Ariz in and is
amazing and super cool friend um what is
it it's like deep um snake magic it's
means like deep snake magic I'm always
so bad with names what is it he had such
a cool friend like Naga Spirit Realms or
had it's one of I don't know what his
handle but it's like that has snakes in
it and deep and ancient and I met those
guys at the kuma which is for people
that don't know it's it's considered
like the world's largest spiritual
Gathering it's kind of I think it's like
250 th000 times no 250
2500 200 times bigger than burning man
wow so d uh I literally had to buy a
bike last time I was there to get around
because it would take me like eight
hours to walk into the middle and I
think it has 150 million people come
during the event and it's just it's the
most
incredible place because people are
there it's such a high Vibe because it's
the place all everybody in India is like
the kuma it supposedly it
you bathe on these certain bathing days
in the the rivers it's three rivers that
kind of meet up and it's all
astrological and it removes all of your
your karma and really infuses you with
with deep like uh transformational Magic
and I met up with those guys at the
melee and we stayed in the same camp and
they were so cool and we would go out
and go hang out with the Babas and look
for new tents and they brought the most
insane Ash ever like it was blowing
boba's Minds like these people didn't
know what like that Cas all the stuff
you saw them post like the cashm and
stuff just a big bag like the place our
camp was a put on by a guy Nam rad Baba
he was this amazing old sadu and he was
so stoked he had all of his baba Bubbies
come and they would just get they would
Blaze him up and we be singing and um
yeah it it was it was such a good time
it was so
Co meet this m itself I was doing kind
of like I know people are G to be like
kind of a like how do you know when you
collect these seeds but I would do like
Baba we would go to Baba camps and we'd
smoke chilling with them and share and
if we smoke something good they flick
the seeds all over the place when
they're packing their things I'd be like
where are you from what's your name
where are you from and then I would pick
up the seeds and I would write their
name and write wherever they came from
because they're from all over India
places and they usually don't come out
out of the hills they're using and they
usually have pretty good stuff and stuff
that's way way out so I came back with
maybe 20 different SE Indian seed lines
from all over India from each from
different Babas who that was their own
personal stock or their own personal
best stuff from the area so it's like
this massive like collection point and
just the experience of just going around
and at night it's so wild amazing and
Smoky and there's thousands of these
camps and all different kinds of spirit
Pursuits and like there I don't even
know how to explain it like it's really
unexplainable like you could watch a
video on YouTube and see it but it's
literally like the most ancient burning
man you could ever go to it's it's been
they've been doing it for like I think
1500 years and it is incredible and wild
but it's intense like you know everybody
you have to poop everybody's pooping
everywhere you gotta use your hands
toilet paper use mud which my my kids
always give me a lot of hassle for oh
Dad did you really use your hand and
like it to it super works like use mud
instead of soap it pulls everything off
because it's like it's kind of like
using charcoal on your hands I mean it's
a little TMI but um you know and you got
to watch out what you're eating and
drinking and you know there's a lot of
Chillum cough going around
um but it's incredible and that was that
was that experience and that was kind of
like the bass big one I mean we went on
a couple I think I went to Waka with the
atams Stray and dock or no we went to
Guatemala after that you know we've gone
on a couple trips together us three
doing collections we went to Guatemala
and then we went to uh Mexico on two
different trips to
collect that's always fun but yeah the
that last big India one that was amazing
I think I posted it on a breed Bay and
maybe uh canak Cabana and a few others
to kind of give people keep keep all bu
but I got a bust into those like I have
so many seeds I collected on my own that
I just popped some uh purple chitry that
are 20 years old I was surprised that
they po but I still have napali seeds
from 20 years ago it's like it's time to
everybody that's got old seeds it's like
get them going or give them to someone
that can because Now's the Time we're
reaching and all the old you know all
the all these
incredible oldtimers are leaving our
this reality they're beaming up you know
they it's time for their time you their
bodies are are finally letting go of
their spirits and with them all those
seeds all that know is leaving and like
I feel like this is the time of the
shake up the big kind of transition
point and we really need to as a
community come together and and create
something for the future you know yeah
yeah totally totally I I too am I'm
looking at cracking into some old seeds
I encourage everyone to do the same and
beautiful to hear about the the
pilgrimage that sounds like it was a
blast and bit of a culture shock for
some people like myself I'm sure but to
to follow up on that I saw on your
Instagram you posted some photos and you
said oh these are some Rajasthani plants
were they from that trip and what what
were they like because I think of all
the land Racers Indian they they're so
like undocumented and like a lot of
people including myself it's like I just
don't really know what they're
like yeah I mean well that's the cool
like if we were talking about Spirit
nourishing plants um some of those
ristani plants are really unique some of
them are duds and some of them are
really incredible like um the I think
the last time there was a baba that
was uh R Bob is one of his good buddies
that lived in the area and he brought an
enti he got a car he brought an entire
truckload of this stuff called Mount Abu
and they call it like Mount Abu mango
and that's what they would smoke all day
long they just sat here at somehow he
made it all the way there like chichin
Chong Adventure but they don't really
mess with sadu but is basically the back
whole back of his car filled up so he
could share because you know at the KUB
you want to bring your best stash it's
also like the you know Babas are like
kids you know and there's you know 99%
of the Babas are just uh basically
Shaggy from Scooby-Doo they don't do
anything they become babbas and there's
only like 1% that are super like you
know that have cities that have powers
that have these connections to states
that we don't but so it's it's pretty
fun but this guy had a little bit of
everything and he connected but he loved
his gun so the mount Abu mango was from
that that that batch and I think deot
got some too but I got some seats from
another Baba called rajani SE car I made
that rajy space probe with it one of the
strains I made I think that was like a
supernatural selection talk about like
Spirit nourishing that plant it wasn't
it wouldn't knock you down it wouldn't
make you super high but it just had this
clarity to it like and it had such a
delicate smell like this kind of floral
incen almost like like nog Champa but
like um if you ever smelled like
Magnolia like a red Champa like just
this beautiful thing and there such a
beautiful effect effect it was very
feminine and very like um it just was a
day brightener but it wasn't you
sometimes almost not know if you smoked
it or not um and that you know I'm
thinking that some of those they're
pretty Ron's pretty much a desert
that that's a totally untapped kind of
uh genre or like or or section of the
Indian uh cannabis genan pool that needs
to be explored and I know in in India
there's a place I mean sorry in Nepal
there's a place called The chai It's Lan
junko they have rhinos and all kinds of
stuff it looks like kind of like a
Africa in a way like the savanas and
they have a um the people that live in
the chitwan and Bia National Forest um I
forgot where they but they traced
themselves back to gypsies from rajastan
and they brought their ganja with them
so there's like a super narrow Leaf um
like a almost jungle ganja plant that
actually at one point was a desert plant
and over time and environment that plant
that you would get in like just an AED
environment has now turned into a total
jungle plant so I was really amazed with
that and that that plant also has a
really unique effect so I don't know how
things work but and this is a whole
another subject about you know old
plants and new environments but there
are some really amazing plants out there
just in spots that people haven't really
looked you know and it's a lot of times
they don't get you super roasted it's
not like you know that's what hash is
for they just give your life something
special you know they're just a little
gift to become part of your culture and
I think that gives them a lot of
magic yeah totally totally I mean I
guess it sort of goes without saying
that you don't know what you don't know
right there's a lot of stuff that we
haven't given enough attention to and
they're just probably not aware of how
how interesting it is and when you were
talking about the spirit nourishing
stuff like one of the things that jumped
to mind straight away was last time I
saw you I was lucky enough you gave me
some pink boost goddess oh my God what a
what a soul nourishing herb can you can
you tell me a little more about it I
only recently learned a little more um
but I mean I still feel like it's
criminally under represented and
underknown within the
community yeah I mean I I don't know
tremendous but I can tell you what I do
know um you know it's it's one of those
cultivar that's that's super rich in
thcv and this amazing woman up I believe
she's in the Triangle Ava would probably
Ava knows her would know more she found
this is kind of the story I was told me
before she found a plant that she really
liked and she and worked with it and she
Not only was kind of doing a plant uh
she her breeding process was based in
science and spirit like she would
connect to the plants like talk to the
plants do kind of like a plant spirit
communication and work in that way and
then then she would also test your
plants as kind of a as a backup queuing
and the way she did that as she moved
and she progressed she created this
incredibly High thcv
cultivar um using her her in innate like
sensing abilities in connection to
Nature and cannabis um along with
science and yeah it's an amazing it's
amazing amazing uh I don't know you call
it cold strain whatever it it is is
really cool and it had a little bit of a
Heyday because people kind of got smoked
and like wow but it I haven't heard as
much about it it's one of those things
you would think would be everywhere so I
mean big up to to people that that find
their passion and their Niche and make
incredible things for the community but
yeah that stuff's
cool yeah yeah totally I mean for me I
found it like it it just felt like the
perfect sativa it had just this awesome
raciness to it and I don't know if
that's what th CV is like in general or
if that was just the way it affected me
but it was it was so beautiful and uh I
was lucky enough to be talking to Mojave
Richmond just the other week and I know
they offer it with the breeder's best so
I was hoping maybe it would make its way
into like some facilities or something
but I guess we'll just have to wait and
watch but this whole topic it gets me
thinking that I think even even now
really all of the sort of innovative
strains you know the new strain to
become the next big popular thing it
seems like even though big facilities
have been around for quite a while now
it it's still comes from like the
smalltime producer and I guess the thing
that jumps straight to mind is I know
that it's been around for forever but
like you know things like mac and um
some of these strains like trop cookies
and all the stuff over the past sort of
15 years it's all just come from small
home Growers like it doesn't seem like
the facilities are you know putting out
new strin like you'd expect you know I
thought if you're going to have a big
facility and you pop a bunch of seeds
you're bound to find something really
cool I guess my question is I'm now
starting to think that it'll probably
stay that way that the new cool things
will come from the homeg grower the
passionate the smaller operation what's
your thoughts do you think facilities
will ever actually start putting out new
stuff like you know the next big GMO
strain is like from a facility or do you
think it'll stay with the passionate
smaller guys I think I mean all we have
to do is kind of look back in time and
see where all the best strains have come
from and it's yeah it's bag seeds it's
like it's like electric Larry down the
street who's been sailing since the 70s
it's like it it's it's these all these
little Growers it's these people that
took two packs of their favorite stuff
and it's like I think it's always going
to come out of these little pockets of
of care and creativity you know I know
there are like
midlevel um producers that do do pheno
hunts and are kind of your lines like
you know like jbz he does all of his own
things and I think cap he they do a lot
of fenal hunting and testing I think you
find that but I still think like the new
new or all or anything that's truly
unique is going to come out of just the
most the places you would never thinkc
you know because that's how it happens
it just it it h it's a Treasures that
are just needed to be hunted and they
hide in different spots and creation I
don't always think it's it's a field
a field selection kind of thing I don't
you know maybe would if if scientific
breeding was so cool then why is there
not any cool scientific strains it's
like they all come
from people that buy seats online or are
traded it's like um I don't know I think
there's always treasure you just have to
look it's like panning for gold anyone
can go down to the river and get and if
you have a little slle and you find a
cool spot you'll get it it's like it's
not it's it's for everyone like cannabis
has been like that I think if you just
have your heart turned on and your mind
in a in the right place like it's it's
rip for picking and I would hope that
new things are going to come along and I
hope that big facilities will do these
these hunts but all I see is like the
bigger kind of seed companies and the
bigger facilities they just kind of do
goofy things like make triploids or
things that like you know it's like why
do we need all these things like we've
been doing this for 10,000 years I said
that before it's like we have a love
affair with cannabis just make out with
it like it's like do your thing it's
there you know don't listen to all these
other grof balls that's it's just find
your Niche open your heart Blaze your
way in to a new
world totally I I love that and I I
agree with everything you've said it's
uh it's certainly the passionate ones
that are that are driving things forward
I think it's it's undeniable but
something I wanted to ask while we're
sort of at that intersection of uh you
know spiritually nourishing plants and
uh modern hype stuff is there anything
recently even gosh I think the last time
we chatted was about sevenish years ago
so you got a long time for recently that
sort of impressed you or maybe something
you didn't expect to be impressed by I
know that I get lots of messages from
people who are still surprised that Tom
Hill said he really liked gelato
41 yeah I mean there certain plants do
amazing things for certain people you
know and I think that the hype strains
it's I think there's great benefit in
there you know like it's they're really
good for uh enjoying video games they're
really they're like an
MSG for uh Modern urban um life you know
they take the edge off you they're fun
to hang out with your friends it's kind
of it can be competitive you can grow it
you have little gardens like you can go
to The Dispensary like it's
a pop art kind of situation taking all
different strains and putting them
together and doing this thing and
hanging out with your friends like I see
the benefit like that's cannabis is so
multi-purpose like it it's cool like I
think hype modern hype strengths go for
it like I think that's super cool that
people are finding joy and finding
solace in this kind of emergent kind of
uh ultraviolet kind of glossy pop art
like how many different kinds of Noodle
Soup cans can you make style the same
string like that's that's cool um and
now but to loot back what were we what
was the question I just went into I just
went totally into the hype mode and lost
my whole train of thought there um what
what are some strains doesn't even
necessarily have to be strains what's
some stuff that's impressed you or maybe
unexpectedly impressed you let me think
what did I see that I thought was kind
of cool like Oreo's um
is uh you know it serves its purpose I
think it's really cool it helps people
grow in in conditions that are harsh and
it's quick and it's very frosty um the
smell isn't necessarily my favorite but
I got to you know sometimes I get to go
over to when I live by the ocean I got
to go to Hayes Valley a lot and I get to
see some of the new stuff and some of
the Oreos hybrids were really cool I was
I was pleasantly surprised like they had
the frost level but they had new smells
I like some of the like
um the Burgery stuff kind of like skunk
Master makes some fun stuff um what else
canavor had some cool ones like Karma
like I got to see a lot of neat stuff
it's like just people that are finding
their Niche and not just smashing things
together and throwing it out but kind of
finding that plant that they really dig
and then kind of introducing that plant
to all of the hype it's kind of like
taking your nerdy friend friend who's
super good at something and bring him to
meet a bunch of cool kids and then they
all you know they all kind of hang out
and something new happens what else I'm
trying to think of what I really liked
there was one what was it called it had
a Spanish
name i don't know you know I to tell you
the truth too I've been kind of a Hermit
these last couple years and it's been a
little bit challenging so I haven't had
the exposure that I used to I mean I
haven't had a garden for the last two
years um so I'm trying to think of what
really inspires me
I I don't know I should go back down
there and see what was the one that was
really cool recently I don't know the
last time I was down there it was
getting to smell some Orioles hybrids
but actually it was a really good use of
of hybridization like showing that you
could take a plant that had everything
except the smell and taste and fusing
them together and actually getting a
plant that that's that's better than the
the two parents combin and I love that
like if you can get two things and put
them together and you get something
better than the two like go for it like
you just you're a big winner there you
like you did it you know and I think
that's what it's all about is you know
making a mountain out of a mole hill
totally totally you know you can
definitely find some really nice crosses
in in anything really but yeah I agree
you know Oreo's got big for a reason you
know it's obviously got some stuff to
offer earlier on in the answer you you
referenced the work you do with Hayes
Valley Nursery I'm sure people have seen
it on your Instagram uh it's cool to
have the collaboration ability with them
to see what you can do at scow you know
do you have any plans to give them any
stuff to to see them run through it or
how what's your thoughts on future do
you want to try to get any anything in
particular you want to see on big scale
I mean well they're rerunning a lot of
the stuff that was the best like the
cream of the crop from last time and
then I gave them a lot of seeds it's
harder since I I moved to kind of get
it's it's like four hours away now so
it's a little bit more difficult but I
would love to go down soon and see how
the new trials are coming along they do
those late season trials um but yeah
they are so kind and they're such
amazing beautiful people and they have
their heart in the right place and they
just do it for like the love and passion
like it's this huge Bay and it pretty
much they don't can't do it's just the
labor of love growing all these old and
ancient and plants that are barely
finishing you know like just getting to
see them and experience them like it's a
huge uh Financial uh
issue but they do it for the love like
that's the way I think it it should be
you know and there's so many things um
yeah I pray that I always work with them
they're good friends and good family and
I love what they're doing and you know
and they kind of saved me in a way like
when I didn't have a garden that was one
of the few places I could go and be with
the plants you know and really uh and
people good-hearted people and just be
there and look you know around put you
know got their little piece of colored
plas that they around think I was pink
and someone else is yellow and so you
can mark the plants that you liked and
kind of watch them progress and like so
you know it's it's such a mental health
boost to be with plants and then you get
all the oxygen you know it's like plants
are healing if you hang out with a lot
of cannabis plants like it's like going
into a hyperbolic oxygen chamber and
just the the vibe like it's so soothing
and calming and there so much so rich
with volatile essential oils that are
just doing you who knows what they're
doing to your system but you feel good
it's like you know the the notion of the
Japanese have that Forest bath where
they go on Hikes through the like high
pining forest and they just come out and
it's like it's better than prac for
these people they go in having a hard
day they walk out the end of their hike
and they feel great because they're
getting the oxygen they're getting the
pining which is all stimulating and
enlivening like being around plants is
just you know I think that's one of the
greatest gifts that we have as humans is
to be able to tend Gardens you know this
is that going back to the original
Garden this is the garden planet where
the stewards you know it could be Adam
and Eve it's like or Adam and Steve
whatever you're into but just make it
yeah make it happen totally totally
that's that's so cool to hear that you
are still able to get that fix you know
shout out to Ryan I was uh lucky enough
to hang out with him a few times when
he's been down under yeah um that's that
that's awesome to hear you know look
while we're on the topic of plants tell
me a little bit about what you've been
doing with plants lately you you
referenced earlier that um You' you've
had a few around after having a break
where are you at what are you sort of
looking at going forward um well now I
mean it's kind of like I have to kind of
do the backstory and to be able to sell
this the front end of the story but I'll
try and you know I I'll try and make it
quick so uh take take your time how I
explain this um it's been about three
years
and you know massive Transformations and
challenges for B seeds and friends and
family and you know we had to leave the
farm and we did a mass Exodus to the the
Sierra Foothills which is about four
hours away so we used to be in the Santa
Cruz area um in the red for forest and
now we're up in the Oak Forest you know
and there's a lot of trials and
tribulations a lot of losing plants
losing hair losing my eyesight losing
dogs and kids Farms um what else my
musical equipment the B seeds computer
like there was a lot of surrender and a
lot
of um I don't know it was kind of like I
almost felt like some of the families
that felt that would go um start in like
Oklahoma and make that trip in the
covered wagons to California to uh um
pay for gold or go to Gold Country and
now we're in Gold Country so after you
know all these trials and tribulations
and not having a garden and doing a lot
of unique things along the way like the
cookies experience that was that was
brought on by that whole
Exodus yeah so through through many
trials and tribulations we made an a
massive Exodus um to the foothills of
the sieras and we're here now um we
moved here with my mom who we took care
of while she was passing um and now we
have this beautiful piece of land um
it's kind of a diamond in the rough uh
we grew our first little outdoor fruits
and veggies Garden um it's quite hot
here like I definitely have never been
in this kind of heat like I thought hot
was 85 de down in Santa Cruz but we had
some days that were in the hundreds and0
and you know the joys of that is like I
I really dug it but you know plants
that's hard to keep bugs at bay that's
hard to keep things going like you know
cannabis loves hot temperatures but I
was something I wasn't
super ever experienced or exposed to so
I have a workshop now and I up some
tents in there the workshop stays about
99 degrees which is you know I get a
little bit of a it's like a sweat lodge
combination you know I sweat out a lot
of toxins while I work which is kind of
cool and just got her first little first
round of um kind of test plants gone off
and you know hav had a haven't had a
space in two years the only times got to
really had a had a space um oh sorry
someone just texted me right in um but
basically um diamond in the rough got a
great uh new spot and hopefully next
year we'll uh generate enough income to
create like some outdoor space like a
little hoop house or um to really get
some projects going because before we
moved there was so many visions and
dreams and projects that were ongoing
just about to kind of kick into gear and
everything we want to do and then you
know life changes and and life
progresses and life takes you in so many
amazing places you never thought you
would it would take you and that's it it
teaches you things it makes you a better
person it creates the the the you know
the true essence of who you are and so I
feel so honored to be someplace where I
can finally start and restart all those
visions and dreams and projects and yeah
wow you know I'm I'm sorry to hear about
your your mom passing Six Month months
ago it just sounds like as you said a
truly a transitionary sort of time for
you in general and I guess we're all
just so appreciative that you're sort of
feeling that you're coming back to us
and I know everyone would be more than
happy to get on board with any projects
you launch in the near future uh in
consideration of how it would fund
future project goes without saying I'd
love to hear you know what might be
something people can get excited about
in the near future cuz I'm sure even
even just beyond the fact that we we're
hearing it's going to go towards further
projects I I know people are just keen
on your work just just for the inherent
genetic projects what sort of stuff
would you have in mind do you do you
have some of the Old Faithful males or
have you moved on from some well you
know I lost a tremendous amount of
plants trying to take them from Santa
Cruz here through the different houses
that
we um had to inhabit on the weight here
it's just oh I don't yeah it it was a
it's always hard to lose plants but you
know I always feel like losing plants is
an opportunity to move on and maybe move
into something that is that's you know
just waiting for you like just the a
thing that's truly going to inspire you
and I always think you know if you lose
parent stock it's time to move on and
there's and it lives on in all its
hybrids and stuff you know so most all
the males are gone old males which is
good too because you know they were
getting old and I was a little worried
about the hplv and you can never tell
when plants are getting super old what
unless you testing what's really going
on so um let me think what you know a
few plants have made it the funny thing
is the plant I think I've had the
longest um Stevie Wonder I call it
Stevie's Wonder or now I call it Saints
Crossing just so I don't get busted by
Stevie Wonder's estate even because I
like Stevie Wonder M with him um I've
had that one for 20 plus years I think I
think it got made in 2005 so that's one
of my that's my oldest clone that I
still keep so that's going strong um but
not really none of the old males make it
it's all new males and all the new stuff
that I'm going through so what um like I
think I'm trying to think of like what
we're really the basis of what we're
trying to do is to kind
of preserve and Inspire like um preserve
all of those special plants that that
are maybe in the fridge or um and then
also inspire people to to utilize those
plants and to really follow their path
because I always feel like it's like a
you know a strain or Cult of our is kind
of like an Afghan rug it's like
everybody it's like you it's a weave
it's like you start it and you kind of
pass it on someone works on the other
family part and someone else it's like
we're a big family we're all working on
everybody's working on each other's work
and I think that's the beauty of it it's
this cry that moves through lives and
you know I've done a lot of line work
and I make a lot of tools for myself but
predominantly I always would make
hybrids you know because I thought it
was the best way for people to kind of
get involved and get evolved with it is
just is grow this out see how cool it is
if you like it or not if you don't let
it go if you do then move forward take
it to F2 like really break it down see
the parents see what's going on if you
like what you're seeing then move it in
the direction that you really love and
get it out like experiences like take it
you know it's like put your own outfit
on it it's like make it yours and really
I don't know just just go I I don't
think cannabis should ever be there
should be no limits there should be
no shackles there should be no one
saying oh you can't do this you can't do
that I don't think it's fair if you sell
like f2s for profit but if you sell f3s
go for it or you know it's like just put
your spin on it um
I don't
know I'm having my you know when you get
in your head so much that you're your
it's like when the Mind opens the mouth
closes um yeah no that's that's good I I
love that and I guess look just just a
quick one like is it is it the case that
uh if there's a certain strain out there
from say you know the 88 G13 male that
someone was really fond of like you
should probably go buy that if you can
find it because it's it's not it's
there's no
more yeah there's a limited stock that
left like I don't I think know lot of
strains that are extinct but you know
what's cool like on over and grow and
stuff they have whole I this is like big
up to all these people like this is
incredible there's like a b Co-op F2
group that f2s all kinds of rare packs
I'm like that is the radest thing I've
ever heard of or seen I'm like it's so I
think that's one of the most awesome
things I want to like send old packs and
be like hey are you guys looking for
this if you want to fire up this pack
yeah go ahead preserve it like I think
that's the best like I can ask for a
better compliment than that like people
wanting to preserve work that that I've
done and it's just I'm just one hand
like I'm literally it's like I made it's
almost like
making uh rice and saying hey now it's
your turn to like add the CER you know
it's like it's like that's kind of a
weird analogy but it's it just feels
good to know that people want to
preserve something you made and then
with that be able give that out give it
out for free do whatever you want trade
um and then people make new stuff with
that I mean that's the very essence of
what our cannabis culture should be it
should be this caring
inspirational uh Cooperative like
working together to to give everybody
everything they need to create exactly
what their heart desires and their
creativity affords you
know yeah of course that I think that's
the best way to to to get noticed as
well for anyone out there who's like
looking to build their
rep I uh I I wonder then have you have
you got anything that's sort of piqued
your interest in terms of males you've
got at the moment or is it just still
very much in that initial phase of you
know not nothing standing out quite yet
still searching through things um you
know today I was in the mail and I was
going through all stuff and I counted I
have about 50 new males but you know I
need to whittle them down to about 12 or
so but there's so many cool things I've
been doing a lot of work with all the my
like kind of like daes stuff like old
Afghani hybrids like there was an M8
which is the hairspray cush Pakistani um
I'm doing this Triad with my three
favorite ones the A1 the angel wing
Afghan and the big J Afghan like that
mail is incredible it looks like
Jurassic Park like dinosaur like don't
get too close to it it's like feed me
see more it's going to it's going to I
think that's going to be really special
what else I did a bunch of like
non-released dlas that I might make for
as
f2s like the M8 hairspray Kush um gash
or 88 G13 um what else I even I think I
even wrote that oh I did like a udub A1
I did a hp13
A1 did the like a dsb that a0s Afghan
um
A1 um what else I've been getting into
the pipeline stuff that that's where the
blood like the dragon's blood was kind
of derived from uh what else I have a
beautiful Vietnamese black I have this
really cool old BX holy weed Congo
counted hars from Vision creator that
are so amazing beautiful kind of like
that really smell like that old Big Sir
holy weed um um yeah there's so many uh
what I did I've did a bunch of lavender
lemonade hybrids just to kind of check
them out so I can make see if they're
ready to kind of filter out for
release some old '90s hash
plants um stuff from Charlie like mexa I
busted out the chocolate trips I did the
afcan um gold stars trying to think of
all the things that I just that are just
about to get flowered in the new room um
what is that it's on that's kind of on
the tip of my brain what's happening
some killer orgasm stuff which I like a
lot
um some of the work I did for burner
believe it or not um uh I took uh I took
an extra step to try and find I want you
know it's and let's see what the what
was it it was that Skittles lavender
lemonade and I took it to F2 and did a
big hunt to find something that I really
wanted because I would like to have I
don't want to get that that seedline to
just get lost in in the shuffle I want
you know I decided I'm going to find a
really killer specimen and let it out
into the wild so can actually I think
that was a a really cool line it just it
just you know had a hard release and to
get that out I think I might even offer
it back up to cookies saying hey this is
here's your baby you know this was a
special time in history um so they can
have what else I've been doing um oh
I've been doing the new dragon soul work
which I really like it's the pine Soul
um dragon's blood I'm trying to think
all the different weird stuff there's a
lot of um older lines like to skin te I
have going some purple kush uh old
mother gani that looks really cool um I
did some purple kush King's
cross and then the next round is more
kind of like preservation like the
purple chitri from Nepal and then
getting into some of my old stock that
that I found with the you know with docy
and stray when we went went on our two
hunts like a lot of some of the
Guatemalans and some of them um W
Hawkins and then so much cool stuff I've
been going through my seed collection
like breaking it down like
what think people like to use that I
might not use like so many cool things
you know all kinds of old JJ that people
would like I have the original cap you
know Mac I have so many packs of Billy
Goat stuff like all the old stuff all
the U all the old breeders from the
overgrow days you know like I think we
have um three little birds and JoJo Rizo
and um so many old lines that are just
so were so cool that just need to come
back so it's just been a big you know
whenever I get down I just go and I bre
take out the seeds and I like to just
dig through seeds and I get excited when
I see some of those packs I haven't seen
in a long time but it's like a I don't
want to be like golum like seed golum
like my precious like you know I might
I'm going to keep like a tenth of my
collection to work on but
yeah I want people to be able to find
cool stuff and I think that was the
whole the whole reason that that that
went through the cookies experience like
that was a that I thought that was going
to be the coolest thing ever like
extreme possibilities like F1 hybrid
which taking the best the best
infrastructure or the best whatever you
call that that like
um where they have the most reach
there's a name for it um
well cookies is a marketing
force and I F thought if I could bring
in these plant these totally new plants
we could
basically kind of like a gravitationally
blast away from this
uh conglomeration of plants that were
just taking over the planet and we could
create something really special new um
yeah we could talk more I know people
always want to know about that I'm sure
we could talk more about it and um and I
know a lot a lot of Street Credit on
that one but um yeah I had to see beyond
uh the whole experience or maybe we'll
just talk about that in a little bit um
and I can start from beginning because I
know that's something people always ask
me about but back to the original
question of what I was doing um yeah
that's the current stuff and then I have
a lot of cool um Medicine Mountain lines
and that's kind of my like s work also
working on a secret new company um
called I guess if I call tell you what
it's called it's not secret but it's
called yum and it's kind of going to be
like it's like a hype company like I'm
going to try and make really cool new
hype things out of totally different
plants than anyone else has and try and
squeeze them into that uh the general
popul community and see if we can't like
get some new flavors and fresh new funky
stuff happening you
know that sounds super exciting is it is
it just yourself in that one is it is it
pronounced yam
yeah Yama is like it's a I like it it's
a funny word it's a it's in kind of
Buddhism it's the it's the the mixture
of wisdom and compassion and you usually
see it as as uh it's usually like a
female yogini and a male and they're
sitting on each other's laps kind of
like in a in like a love making position
I don't know if you seen it it's like
looks like a you'll see like a a lady
Buddha sitting on the like a in they're
in Lotus and he's kind of sitting on her
lap and they're in this kind of H it's a
basically it's like a coidal metaphor
for uh the the fusion of wisdom and
compassion so and it has such a funny
and fun name so I thought that's great
yum yum I love that I love that oh so
we've got something to be excited about
then yeah and that's like a little side
project I think the
first I might even send out some testers
of those to people like in the community
just so I could you know get some really
good feedback on that Edge because we
haven't had a tester so program in so
long and I tend to like think every
plant is cool so like I always try and
find there's always a redeeming
character in every plant I look at I
like oh wow I love the smell it'll be
like you it'll it have like you know you
get like a gram out of a whole plant I'm
like oh this is really cool but it's
like you
know there has to be a balance but yeah
I think the
first the first seeds are already done I
made three different hybrids with this
male that is kind of going to be the the
first flagship of this new
Endeavor and then what else and more
medicine Mountain those just take
forever because you're working with like
these long flowering sativas it's a
little bit more of a labor of loving I
think this year next season um I can
braid the heat a lot of those will be
coming out and I also want to do a lot
of uh um preservation work like I have a
few Charlie's lines I Les his heart I
don't I guess I don't know I haven't
heard from him in a long time I mean he
I thought he might be in Columbia or
stuff I don't know if he's still around
but I would love to let people try some
of those you know like skiny and mexa
and I have a bunch of different lines
from him some you know the the uh
Vietnamese black from Billy Goat is an
amazing line um I have so many cool
things that I'd love to just you know
people that I respect that I feel like
their their lines are kind of
Disappearing you know people never it's
like it kind of it's like a gray area
you know where people um is people
weren't around in the like early 2000s
they don't really
understand or even in the 215 era how
much more cultivars and how much more uh
variety we had it's kind of like a the
Fruit Market at fruits and vegetable
markets at the turn of the century like
what was there like 126 apples in 19 or
1895 or something and now we have six to
eight apples in stores you know because
they're the ones that don't bruise they
they stay on the shelf longer they
things they're not the tastiest not this
we've totally totally eliminated our
gene pool for convenience and capitalism
so I'd like to just bring back some
variety and really allow people to
experience I could I think that's the
best education is experience and I pray
that you know I see a lot of other
people doing it too and I think this is
one of the ways that we can uh progress
into the future where we have a very
vibrant and magical cannabis jepol
again yeah totally totally and I I think
something that really resonates with
what you said at the end there is you
really do have to experience it because
a lot of the most memorable experiences
that have really change my perceptions
and thinking wow like some of these land
races can can actually be just so
otherworldly it it it can't be
articulated really you know and and
you're trying to explain it to someone
but you just
you know words words aren't enough so I
agree that's that's awesome on on all
fronts and I want to ask you uh you
mentioned a few times we'll we'll loop
back to the cookie stuff but I want to
ask you you've mentioned the big so
Nigerian a few times we had a few people
who were really interested to hear a
little more about it I know it's a
strain that's shrouded in a lot of sort
of um mystery can you just tell us a bit
of the backstory and what it smells and
looks like cuz I know you made a few
hybrids with it maybe for anyone who's
eying those
off yeah so um another good resource for
this too is Mojave because he grew up
there and he knows all about these
things but basically um I had a friend
Mike who kind of uh was a friend of a
grower down there and what was that
other guy I don't know if I'm supposed
to say his name but there was a lot of
people amazing um Growers That Grew down
on The Ridges over big sir and Mike got
these seeds in the I think mid 80s and
he had him forever and um he he's an
older guy I think he's probably in his
80s now he found these somehow in his
old stuff and he had three seeds he got
two up in his little house he has a
little low rent house he put him under
like a little fluorescent light um and I
think one of them went up and then
another one went up it said it said he
took him about a month in a little
flower pot and um he one of them died
shortly after but he brought me down
this one to kind of preserve he's like
hey I have this this uh this big S this
Nigerian Sea that we used to grow uh in
the 80s and I've got it up it's like
it's a miracle it's like I don't know
how I did it like and so he gave it to
me and I I kind of nursed it back to
health and nursed it up and it was one
of the coolest plants like it was it was
relatively quick you know I think like
12 weeks maybe you know you could take
it at 10 it such a beautiful amazing
structure like so loves outside so
beautiful like you could tell like it
love my area cuz I'm pretty close to
big and just this wild kind of like
metallicky kind of herbal meaty Herbs de
provant kind of sage
brushes um smell but just kind of smell
dangerous like it just
smelled powerful and it was like it just
had the greatest
effect like it was so powerful was so
great in hybrids like it would really
just take over in a good way and you
know when anytime I really wanted to
kind of get out there on like on a Ledge
I would I would smoke it and you know I
had it for a while and it you know did a
couple different hybrids and using a lot
of different things because I loved it
so much and you know I tried everything
I I could but eventually I lost it you
know along with the7 a lot of plants had
the house that we moved
uh
from after the farm was in this amazing
beautiful house and it held everybody in
and we could have the animals there and
stuff but it was the worst place to grow
there was this little garage it was so
damp and it was so funky and it was so
impossible to clone and do anything
there and I think it died in a tray like
I would take like 20 cuts of all my
favorites just so that I'd know i' get
like one out of the deal and I think
that was one of the times that some kind
of it got infected or something but I
lost a whole tray of like my favorites
it was just like a it was really tragic
so it lives on in hybrids um it's just
one of those original old 80s Big Sir
Africans you know they had I believe
that they grew quite a bit of Africans
and Mexicans I mean there's a I I'm you
know I didn't grow up there and there's
people that know a lot more but from
what I've heard um you know strings like
Dolores and chamba and this Nigerian
and uh I know we used to get u a silver
Pearl that came out of there and they
had a Durban that came out of there when
I first moved to Santa Cruz like you'd
always get really special stuff that
came from Big Sir it was people that
really did it for the for the love and
you know it had it was a very special
environment you know so it made really
cool plants but basically to the gist is
it really cool old African that
climatized itself and big S um brought
back to life by a really great guy um
who lived in that area in that time
that's some really cool backstory and
you know people have to pop those Seas
it's it's got to live on for sure and
yeah uh another question that you you
know you sort of referenced it in the
past answer when you were talking about
various males we had a lot of people who
were Keen to hear more about this
lavender lemonade mail what what can you
tell us about it well that's kind of
cool like you know when I
I started to get you know as I went to
more and more to Wallflower I mean to
radio Ridge which turned into Wallflower
to turned into Haz Valley um all the
same people uh just that
that that um that journey of sharing
with them and sharing clones and getting
to understand nurseries and like
everything it was so fascinating it
really opened my eyes to the whole world
of like commercial production like I my
brain was never really in there I was a
hermit like I wasn't creating plants for
nurseries or for commercial production I
was just kind of following my Bliss and
trying to bring out the best possible
plants from where my connection to the
plant was but I got fascinated with like
you know plants that had to finish in a
certain time that had to look a certain
way that had to be resistant to these
things that had to be able to even
though one thing that really blew my
mind is oh this has to go through a
trimmer I'm like oh so I this plant I
thought oh this plant's Super Rad
everybody's going to want this and
they're like oh it's not going to go
through the trimmer right I'm like what
what kind of you know I just had all
these epiphanies so I started on uh
making trying to make kind of a line
that I thought would be really cool for
uh for Big Time
production and so I know that was back
when the TP the everybody was like Ted
up Supreme like everybody wanted like
the very you know all everything at hot
was like citrus and like you know orange
and lemon and lime you know cuz we come
from the land of lemon tree and um
everybody just that seemed to be the
thing so I'm like oh cool I'm you know I
could do lemon tree and wook two
extraordinarily turpy strains and try
and make something that would Encompass
both of those but even better like I
really wanted to get the structure down
like I always you know structure is
great and all but it wasn't always on
the top of my list for for breeding so
that one was like it was primarily
making something that was structurally
easy to to grow and also to have the
look and the smell that everybody wanted
so I worked on it for a while and grew
out different ones and we even had a
couple really cool phenos that went
around and and
um and it kind of culminated eventually
in you know into the line that I thought
would be perfect for for cookies they
could you know like they they were B
they're so big on you know Aromas and
tastes and flavor
that it could be something that could re
really Revitalize uh part of their their
uh their stick kind of like their their
jam and so that's how it kind of worked
into that and so a lot of these under
lemonade hybrids that are coming out
were kind of
made in really thinking kind of like the
commercial Market or the nursery Market
or just allowing people to have plants
that maybe have these really exotic chps
that are going to just flop over and
just you know something I don't know
it's just something new I'm always
trying to push myself into these new
places and new Realms to you know to
really see what I can do and it it was
kind of my version of my first kind of
foray into like kind of making something
like hype like something that everybody
would like that could be moved through a
commercial
situation and also that was kind of when
I was losing the farm too so I was also
thinking of other ways to like well how
can I apply myself I I can't I'm not
growing like how can I apply myself to
be the best thing I can for the
community and and also be able to
generate income to do the projects like
what what can I what can I move into and
I really thought for a while like I was
really into I'm like strain design that
sounds so cool I don't have you know
it's it's kind of a labor of love making
seeds and having big mom rooms like you
don't ever get to do anything and you
know anytime I'd ever travel I'd always
lose like so many cool plants like it's
kind of like but it just have to it just
has to happen sometimes so the strain
design part was was really a cool
Challenge and it it really opened my
mind and allowed me to see deeper into
the Cannabis as a whole I I I realized
that was kind of my opic just being a
little bit hermetic and not focusing on
the bigger picture and by moving into
that commercial space you know it was
fascinating and I kind of I enjoyed
pushing myself and and learning about it
and and creating something for it yeah
yeah definitely and I can I can see 100%
where that comes from you know I I think
I'm I'm exactly just as guilty as you
you know sometimes I've I hang on to
these plants that are just nightmares to
trim and uh and people tell me and we're
not even in the commercial
setting I want to ask you a bit of a a
random one quickly it's it's almost
undeniable that the General market
demand and Trends has shifted very
significantly towards feminized seeds
especially over say you know it's been
happening for a while but I I think in
the past 5 years there's been a dramatic
shift even among home Growers and
generally speaking their willingness to
grow regulars I think you're probably
quite immune to that because you've got
a a very specific sort of clientele who
who enjoy regulars and there's always
going to be like pretty much anyone
listening to this show is always going
to be happy to grow regulars because
we're just like you know that sort of of
Enthusiast level but I do Wonder have
you thought any more about feminized at
all um you know it's just it's it's just
not my thing I guess I'm just old school
I'm kind of coming from like the Luther
Burbank style I um there's so many
amazing breeders that do it it's I think
it's a really cool tool especially on
Old plants that you may maybe you only
have a female and you want to uh
preserve it it's really cool to open up
the the of a plant to see what it
possibly could be and to search out its
parents like it's the ultimate kind of
like um Crack the Code like go in and
and you know it's like a forensic tool
you know like I always think like
inspector like he's he's the probably
the best the most
uh uh devoted and Brilliant and
uh uh you know S1 worker that I know of
like he really does an incredible ARR
and vast amount of work and he does a
good job and that's his thing and like I
respect people that they find their
Niche and they find uh what they can do
well and they go with it but yeah I'm
just the I'm kind of just like the old
wizard on the hill and just do it the
oldfashioned way and you know I thought
at one point when the um when there was
the I guess the bandid S one pcon or
something like that and there's all that
ho I thought oh that might be fun to
like partner up with someone and and do
some like uh Band-Aid Haze feminized
like with all kinds of the cool
sativas um I think I even talked to uh R
Ridge maybe I'm sorry D I still call him
radio Ridge because it's go all the way
back to that um hay Valley um all those
cool sativas that we found in the last
big hunt kind of mixing it up with the
band 87 but you know I don't know that
just we haven't really moved for on that
and I don't know I'm just not a big S S1
guy
yeah maybe I could just shorten that up
and just say yeah just I I appreciate
all the directions that people go and
and I have great respect for all the
people that find their Niche and that's
femin just isn't mine and I think it's
amazing I have been known back I think
it was 20 years when I got the stuff on
eBay and I mixed it up all the STS and I
just basically roasted the hell out of
all my plants and I thought well that
was no fun you know I I don't know I
don't like to mix up chemicals I don't
you know Alchemy I do like inner Alchemy
but outer Alchemy is not one of my
strong
suits and yeah the coolest part about it
is I realized is you know if you have
two verified
Cuts you can make the same seeds as like
you you have a thousand people get the
you know get runs and and cookies the
two cuts and feminize them and everybody
will have the same
seeds yeah
I think that's how it would work so I
mean that's kind of cool like it really
levels the playing field you can uh you
know I think maybe in the
future now I'm just rambling but um s1's
super cool I mean no actually not super
cool I how about I'm not gonna do any
s1s in the future but I really
appreciate everybody that's involved in
that work and I think it's kind of cool
doing the S2s and threes and all that
and I know that's how they do it in
scientific reading but I just like two
plants making love and getting to
experience all their kids when they come
out tot no totally totally I I love what
you said there like I mean I myself I I
make F and I do weird stuff like that
but you know what's interesting like it
took me a while I I had a bit of the
like hippie guilt about like I've come
to accept that like yourself you know I
like f1s you know I'm happy to do it as
a f but I like that F1 generation the
most I've toyed around with others and
there's just something magical about
that first recombination with especially
diverse genetics coming together you get
something really interesting there and
that's what I love the most for sure so
I I'm definitely on board with you in
that sense and and in and amongst that
answer it's it's come up a few times
actually you mentioned the uh the the
guys running pcon and I guess by
extension you know the the the Cuban
black Haze which has really had a
massive Resurgence over the past say
three or so years and and shout out to
the guys who run pcon it's one of the
few successful like he events though I
haven't been to it but everyone I speak
to who's gone is like yeah it's it's
like really it's like what the emerald
cup was doing back in the day you know
just like cool people really good herb
um unique effects and then when you also
put this in contrast with the fact that
you got people like uh you know Tom
Hills recently come out with his Haze
Todd McCormack's doing his thing with
the haze and and top dog is also doing
some Haze and um you know very Haze
heavy sort of work what's your thoughts
on the Resurgence of haze specifically
and in my mind I think it's either down
to like Cuban black Haze or super silver
haze is going to sort of become the new
front runner they're definitely both
really Rising back up do you have any
thoughts over which one might be the
bigger of the two contenders to be
reinjected
yeah I don't know I mean there's so many
fresh new minds and heads and people
creating these new hazes I think it's
amazing I think it's so cool I think
that you know piif con that is people
rallying up for like heady highs like
that is incredible and it kind of
hearkens back I think we talked about
this a long time ago about how those uh
heirloom sativas coming in when Hip Hop
was first starting and in New York like
a lot of that
early hip-hop culture was was fueled by
these like Colombians and uh Mexicans
and these like Haze you know Haze type
plants like that were really you know
that were sparking the minds and and
really filling the streets and like
having that it's just like another
expression of people it's Heritage it's
basically it's a cultural it's a
cultural treasure hazes in New York and
I think what an amazing beautiful place
for that uh that pipc con to happen and
how cool is that I mean what what hazes
are going to be popular in the future I
don't know I think ones that have the
most uh unique effects like super silver
haze it is like that if that is kind of
like the working
man's Haze like there's nothing quite
like it just the smell the structure the
way it is I mean maybe it's not the
headiest but it's just it checks all the
boxes it's a truly extraordinary
and then by default like Neville's Hayes
which is kind of like the the more crazy
grandpa there that you know it's hard it
takes longer it's harder to uh grow and
it you know it has that more a little
bit more refined and then the Cuban
black that we grew that that was such a
wild plant like it was so big but it
would take a while but it would get so
big and it was it had that Unique Kind
of effect of like it still had some of
its northern lights um in it you know
giving it that big structure but it had
such this beautiful kind of buoyant head
space um but I think the future of Haz
is going to be in people doing really
cool stuff like you know doc d Works
does a lot of cool hay stuff and like
nobody's Nursery they do it I know all
those piff guys like they're all kind of
pushing your art JJ comes up with cool
stuff like and I see a lot of the people
overseas like yo Sammy and like um some
of the Gold Guys on icy mag and then
there's the guy The White Buffalo guys
in Canada those guys are awesome what
they're doing like those yeah it's it's
a it's a really incredible and Tom Hill
of course he you saw his pictures of him
pumping out his new round
like it's beautiful it's very
heartwarming and it's very cool to see
that there's s that that's kind of
bubbling up I don't know what's going to
be the best um you know and and people
like you know I read some of the
comments like band7 that's not even a
haze and it wasn't about Haze I guess
the pcon is about piff piff snort and
lights Haze I don't think I don't think
bandid s is necessarily that exciting of
a haze but what it is is it's a it is
like an A1 Primo working man's sativa
guys like bread and butter like kind
it's like the steak of haze is prolific
it smells good it has a a stoning effect
you can work on it it's for people that
smoke a lot of gun I think it hits just
right and I you know and in this state
and in this environment
the states and Holland and New York and
all these places like the new
environment that's putting the selective
pressure on it is the youth the culture
the like you know the music the the
underground and I think uh I think it's
going to be this cultural icon that that
really serves as this vehicle to really
move people into a positive direction
for the future with for um for really
heav herb so kudos to everybody involved
I think is so awesome in rad I think
everybody should grow some hazes at some
point and I think we should have them
back in the marketplace and I think
people should be striving to make
greater and greater versions and unique
offshoots and whatever because yeah I
think hazes is one of the truly it's one
of the greats that we have in our
cannabis
Heritage yeah 100% and uh you know
obviously shout out to our former
episode guest you know Tom the The White
Buffalo guys and y Sammy those guys
obviously doing killer work with the
haze while we're talking about haze just
a quick little cheeky one I remember
ages back I was talking to you and you
sort of joked around about the idea of
doing a haze Recreation with snow high
and kagu have you have you thought about
it because as time goes by I I'm just I
I ruminate on that thought I'm like oh I
really hope they do that yeah yeah I
think we've been doing it for about 15
years now it's like every year it's like
okay we I think Michael like K he's he's
the most gung-ho on it he's like so yeah
you got you got your plant ready for the
things you know John did his two years
ago like he is he's a force of nature
he's always getting everybody to uh get
involved I'm like uh I don't know I just
moved like I always have some like you
know I some it's like supposedly we're
like handing off plants and I think it's
going to do it in its own time but it's
definitely it's been started and it's
gone through a couple iterations but I I
think I might have dropped the ball here
and there and I think John probably drop
drop a ball but it is it is it you know
it's out there it's in the ethers it
full it hasn't fully germinated yet but
it is something that that is close to
our hearts that we should be working on
so thank you for putting a fire under my
butt on that
one no no I'm sorry I I I agree with you
it's still it's still happening it's
just it's just progressing at the rate
it needs to progress at yeah you got to
have a lot of space and you got to have
a lot of um oh yeah time and you got to
have the right environment people think
that don't that I think get turned off
about hazes is hazes you got to look
through a lot of hazes like that's
that's why hazes are so cool it's not
like hazes are you get a pack and
they're these awesome plants hazes is
like the ultimate treasure hunt it's
like the it you know if you want to find
a good Haze you're gonna have to look
through a lot of plans and that turns a
lot of people off and you know I don't
to give me like if you gave me a vial of
a thousand original haast seats that's
not that not something that I want to do
you know I don't want that's a lot of
work so I think
also finding these special Cuts is going
to be very beneficial because yeah it's
a lot
of the one and I think that's the one
reason why H really caught on it's a
pain in the
ass yeah of course that's a big
commitment to make and uh it's
understandable on the Practical scale
people are a bit apprehensive
in in the last answer when we were
talking about pcon I I wanted to ask
because there's there's this interesting
situation that play in New York where
there's undeniably this huge Renaissance
with cannabis especially in regards to
like talking about the piff and some of
those guys in the real he scene but at
the same time the sprayed pack phenomena
tpine infused cannabis is also clearly
got a stronghold in New York there's a
lot of people more so the average Hunter
acknowledge uh who are very very much
into this sprayed pack cannabis and the
thing that I find the most interesting
about the spray pack phenomena is that
people are not oblivious to it like
they're very aware that that's cuz that
was the immediate kneejerk reaction was
like oh they don't know but a lot of
them are in fact almost everything I've
seen on it says that people are aware um
and it's interesting there's a podcast
out there it's just specifically about
rating various sprayed packs I thought
that's a sign like that's how mainstream
this is so I'd love to know what's your
thoughts on the sprayed pack
turps I isn't that amazing is that the
craziest wild thing that you've ever
heard I mean I think it's a I mean then
also you have all like the th what is it
Delta 8 or was it you know all
the I think that's wild like it's a
slurpie culture it's like it's junk food
it's like fast food it's like it it's
like pop art it's like you know people
don't care what they put in their body
so why would they care what they put
into their lungs I mean I think it's
it's cool and you can come out with the
weirdest wildest thing I don't even know
what do they use real T beIN they use
real essential oils like what do they
spray them with like do you just get
some f or do you like go get some some
like you know like some Citrus olve or I
mean what they is there companies that
sell the spray like up I mean I guess
I'd love to like the the my tongue and
cheek answer is is this just not what
people were doing back in the day when
they chucked orange peels in with bags
yeah serious yeah tortilla tortillas and
orange peels right right but uh no so I
I I recently um had uh sticker Farmer on
um the new show I've I've been doing
with me and Jean and he's tied in with
the guys who sell this stuff so he knows
all about it and he said that the stuff
they spray on it is is the same flavored
solution people use for like nicotine
solutions for Vaping so you get like so
it's just that same like
viscous food grade artificial flavoring
and there's like a machine that sprays
it on it so yeah not not like plant
derived or anything like that that's so
wild
they wow I mean I wonder what do they
what kind of gunch do they spray on just
like just just the just the booth or
like is there a special strain that they
like to use interestingly enough what he
said was that of course yep there are
definitely people trying to you know
sort of Polish a turd but he said the
companies that are doing the best are
actually putting quality product in and
then spraying it which is really quite
sort of perplexing well I know like
companies like app like some of the big
tpine companies like what like abstract
sector what all those different ones
that sell or what was the old clear
water or what those places that sold t
mixtures um and you could add them to
your carts or butt or whatever I guess
that's the same kind of
thing but so what does that do if if
they're spraying it so I always say like
the chirpings are the plant story you
know it's it's what it's it's trying to
tell you so by spraying it I don't know
I mean you want to maybe we should try
and get you some so you can do a um you
could do some bio essaying and tell us
if you notice any differ it it kind of
like remember when like all those uh
research canabo like
jw18 and all those different Wild Ones
and people would smoke those like what
if you use that and the spray together
and do put it on like those old High
Times 80s like a centerfold remember the
fake buds you could buy in the back of
the
magazines yeah like on you could just
spray fake canono and then uh the spray
and then put it on like Moline or some
kind of like real healthy lung herb
you know I feel like we've we've sort of
cut out the middleman there and it's at
the point now where I hear that many of
the like the the cheapest sort of carts
you can buy are essentially like mostly
tpin and some sort of filler and a
little bit of Delta 8 or like you know
what I mean like it's almost at the
point where it it's what you're
describing it's like there's nothing
real there well it's like cheap beer I
mean I think we just reached that we'
reached the lows of kind of like or just
the capitalistic lows of of of a product
you know people want the the cheapest
possible experience and then people also
want the highest like Pinnacle of
experience and so we have the complete
bandwidth to work with
now yeah I I wanted I wanted to ask you
I've been I've been very much thinking
about this idea for a while and I've
been sort of slowly getting more and
more into wine and the thing I think
about the most is like how come no one
breeds in wine anymore and then um I
started thinking about that in the
context of cannabis and I'm sort of
thinking do you think like we're going
to get to the stage where everything
will be so bred to specifically suit a
certain production style that like over
a longer period of time not a short
period of time but a longer period of
Time commercial production turns into
like what wine production is where it's
like there's just like these 30 or 40
recognizable varieties and even of those
it's like eight of them are just by far
the most common of them all and it's
just what is considered you know and
it'll be like OG will be like chardonay
and run is like Merlo you know what I me
it's just like there's just a few things
do you think that is like a possible
risk or do you think like it's it's too
variable it won't ever get like that I
think it kind of is like that I think
it's just that it rotates a lot faster
than than grapes and stuff you know is
like it sends we it seems like there is
like 60 Main cultivars and they go on
kind of in and out and they kind of
cycle through and go into the you and
they're always kind of cycling out I
don't because we don't have a v there's
not a vast pet or maybe we're rapidly
moving into that stage I mean it's the
same thing that we have happen with all
of our fruits and vegetables it just
gets to the point where profit takes
hold and you know I mean we're I think
we're kind of doomed in that regard I
think the only way we're going to be
able to get out of this is to just get
everybody everybody in the
just arrows every everything just throw
SE do this and then also you know maybe
a new model like a like a dra to consume
where small farms that have grown like
something really beautiful they had in
their family for so long and they're
really proud of it and they do all
organic inputs they can have a little
website and seller their story and sell
Direct in the mail to someone that
really wants to experience that or
farmers markets or you know I think
we're in we' set it we're like we're
basically set up to fail and we kind of
just have to ditch the whole system and
go back to like you know before uh
prohibition cannabis prohibition
everybody grew it ganja it was
everywhere it was used for everything
10,000 years it's been used for
everything it's like why not let's just
go back to that make it make it our you
know our main Ally plant grow in your
front lawn do ornamentals do CBD plants
do whatever don't don't get don't let
the the government take a hold of this
one or big business like do people
really want I mean it's cool to go to
dispensary and see everything but even
if you have a friend you always have
that funny friend guy that has the
garden in the back oh check out my
tomatoes like you know there's always
someone in your group and that's that's
gonna want to grow so I don't know I
think that it's just Grass Roots at this
point is to and just kind of grow down
Babylon it's like it's not going to get
any better and it's only G
to I don't know I it's I used to have a
lot of faith that you know that there
would be people that do it so much for
the love that they were willing to take
the biggest Financial hit barely make
any money but produce this most amazing
stuff at the top and then then there
would people big corporations that would
make the most boof stuff at the bottom
and it would just wipe out the whole
middle but I think it's just everything
is it's just erased to the bottom and I
don't see things getting better and I
don't see any legislation that is
helping at
all it's it's sad so yeah to answer that
question I mean spraying packs is that
that's just a natur that's just a
natural expression of where we're at you
know and it's it's fascinating it's kind
of cool it's it's kind of avant guard it
people love new stuff you know if
they're lungs melt or something from I
just wonder what's in it you know what
and what kind do they use what do they
use as a carrier like propylene glycol
or something really
gross yeah certainly certainly I I share
some similar concerns and and and you
know the race to the bottom sentiment is
is a real concerning one as a super
quick followup do you do you think that
that rescheduling of things to schedule
3 made any real difference and and do
you think that Federal legalization is
is going to make much change because it
seems like it's coming pretty
quickly yeah I mean with all this
everybody and the who knows with the
election every all the different
political figures are saying they're
going to do this and that I think they
should deschedule like just make it back
to a plan again rescheduling it to the
pharmaceutical like kind of level is
going to screw everything up but it's
also you know I try always trying to
find a silver lining it also gives
everybody that wants to grow a lot more
freedoms because it's not going to be
like it it takes it down a few notches
for enforcement like you're not going to
get so shafted at at three as you would
at schedule one so it kind of gives
everybody a little more freedom to just
go berserk and just grow gon everywhere
do whatever they want because it's going
to be un it's already kind of
unenforceable we're re reaching that
Omega point where so many it's so part
of our society now the cats out of the
bag it's like taking it to three is
going to suck it's going to mess up
everything it's going to be so bad for
all the people that spent so much time
and energy to get to where they're at
but it's also going to give everybody
more freedom to to just you know who
cares about all the laws just go for it
just do what you
want totally totally totally it feels
like we're at that point almost you know
it won't be long before before every
state it's legal and and then I'd really
be interested to seeing what the mass
sort of producers are doing you know
when the opportunity to be in every
petrol station is uh is gas station is
is suddenly an option you have to
imagine there'll be there'll be like
supply issues at first and then they'll
be making the big facilities and it'll
be interesting yeah I mean isn't the
Delta eight market like bigger now than
the than the um the regular Market isn't
it it's some crazy amount like there and
there it's because they're it's
everywhere every gas station you can go
to in United it seems like in the whole
country has some kind of fake G
substitute
so I mean they might it just legalized
nature they just just go back it's the
only way things are going to anything's
going to happen it's like they it's just
getting weirder and weirder the more
they do these stupid things and it's
going to get so absurd and dangerous and
dumb it's just like just re just
legalize the thing it was it's part of
everybody's life before what Harry
anslinger got
involved yeah to totally I mean hey on
on that topic I I know that you know
cannabis isn't isn't the only
ethnobotanical plant in your life and a
lot of people wanted me to ask you you
know what's what's been going on in
bod's Garden I know you've just moved
are you you have you got any Cactus with
you you growing anything
else oh yeah I've been well the cool
thing is not having canvas Garden I get
to do all the other so I got yeah I got
super into Cactus like I love doing
Cactus seeds but it's such a it's such a
waiting game but it's so fun it's like
you know it's like you don't check every
day because it's like oh what's
happening but yeah at Cactus is amazing
you know especially the spirit
nourishing ones um super into Cactus and
I love pupping and cutting and doing
every just getting into it and trading
and getting things and now you know it's
kind of a it can you know takes up a lot
of space um I love mushrooms I got to do
a little more uh foray into mushrooms
when I didn't have a garden to you know
that's kind of like one of my first
loves you know and I have all the other
plants that I that I enjoy um you know I
used to collect Salvia
strains divor before it became schedule
I have the CH that I grow that I love
from Ethiopia in Yemen um so many
amazing Spirit plants and they're
so they're so you know they do such
amazing things the key to that is just
really respecting them you
know and
really giving them you know they're
powerful powerful tools and Powerful
allies and to really go into that space
you know and connect with them with your
heart so they know that you're in there
to learn and love and live and uh and
get the teachings that they want to give
you yeah totally I'm I'm so glad to hear
that you you've been able to continue
with some of those I guess for a lot of
people you know growing a cactus is you
know I don't actually know but like you
know I've grown cactuses it's really fun
it didn't seem like a big deal but I
haven't really ventured out into
something like salvia which you know
I've had Salvia I think it's cool um
what would you say is you know besides
Cactus for example what's one that
someone should give a go that's like
pretty user friendly it's you know easy
enough to
do well another one the cat out of the
bag everybody in there everybody should
be growing
mushrooms you know Culinary first you
know whatever um matake shitake oysters
oysters you can go pretty much anything
you literally grow them in your in your
hair you know if you just kept a a spray
bottle Spritz bottle by on your um work
belt um grow mushrooms everybody should
grow mushroom are so amazing and
especially grow the the Psychedelic ones
it's so easy and so many it's so you
know there's especially United States
now we have all these places like Santa
Cruz Oakland Denver where it's totally
cool to to explore that and it's such an
fascinating world that um you know
people don't realize I mean people do
now but the mushroom the mushroom
Community is huge they have Forum they
have so much stuff and it's so uh the
breeding are just people are really
starting to get into breeding it it's
very driven by um by mutants like
everybody's looking for the newest
mutants looking for like listic ones and
albinos and there's so many cool new
expressions and people breeding them in
this way and that way and getting these
new effects and colors and ones that
look like you know you've seen like
Enigma have you ever seen some of the
new like uh mushrooms that look like
literally like a loaf of Swiss cheese or
look like little spaceships or and
they're so you know they're so rich in
indul and in you know in spirit
molecules like it's incredible I you
know everybody in everybody should grow
mushrooms I think that's yeah just get
get yourself go on YouTube get some
spores do whatever you can but
experience that like I think that's a
really powerful way
to um reinitiate yourself on this planet
as a person for Change and and growth
and for to make this planet a better
place you know get your spores going
totally this is this is a call to action
I I'm obliged to follow I'm going to
give it a go you know what you've
inspired me because you're right it's
not that hard and uh I should I should
give it a go so that's cool the the
other one I wanted to ask you about this
is more of a I know other people are
interested but me personally I'm very
invested have you uh had much chance to
to do any thinking or doing in the um
the old factory DJing uh adventure of
yours you know I've still got a few of
your perfumes left they're my special
occasion perfumes and I'm sadly out of
the uh the the black rose but um and uh
I'm I'm very low on the K but that's you
know that's the very special
occasions uh yeah definitely I'm so
ready to get back into that like I I've
made a bunch before I moved just knowing
that they ate you know it's all about
aging with the some of those and yeah I
I love essential oils and I love plant
compounds and that and and the O and
making the oils and blending is kind of
like a combination of music and breeding
and each you know biochemical spells and
Alchemy like it's it's such a rewarding
and
special um thing that you can do you
know because SC is all memory there's
more near neur and in our nasal there's
more nasal neurons there is site like we
use it so much more it's like it's it's
the you know even with our rig is up
touch taste well not taste but smell and
uh vision and hearing is all vibrational
you know smell is like it is is a is a
song it's a tapestry it's like the
language of creation on a Botanical
level like you know there's I heard the
guy from what the abstract Tech the
tpping guy say there's 400,000 tping now
I don't know if that's correct I there
was only like 20,000 he said 400,000
there's only 200,000 words in the
English language like that's like double
the language potential of create of of a
Botanical expression like these are the
every plant that grows like sings its
own biochemical song and like every year
that those are distilled it's different
because of different weather patterns
different soil different people that
cultivated the plants like it's just
this I don't know I think a
well-prepared
perfume or atar or Galia or whatever you
want to call it is like a symphony of
life that's enclosed in time and space
like it's a interactive uh I don't know
it's like a I can't even explain so yes
to answer that I am super jived I have
about 12 ones that have been aging and I
want to get back into it I mean it's
just you know how I got into UDS really
hardcore and that just that is not a
good hobby for someone on a budget let
me tell you so I I stopped
UDS even though I love UD I think UD is
like the grand wizard uh tpine
experience like if you really think
you're like the TP uh wizard like moving
into UDS and really experiencing UDS for
all that nature can create smell wise as
like as things volatilize and evaporate
off and smell that smell Journey like
that oods are one it like that's a you
know people want a tip on really if they
enjoy scent enjoy smelling to get into
maybe like not not um age not more like
a new Farm dudes not like the uh um the
older wild dudes which can be too
expensive to initiate but yes to I'm the
landscape of Desire all the smells uh
will be coming out as soon as I can get
enough time to kind of put them on an
Etsy store or make a a
thing um but yeah I love scent and I
love working with this with essential
oils
I'm I'm excited and I know others are
too I think uh a fair few of our patreon
members actually have messaged me and
they've told me know I got Hive as well
so that's that's uh that's cool to hear
that there's some more on the horizon
and and as's a quick little thank you I
don't know if you can see I've still got
this bit of Eagle Wood you gave me years
ago and it's my goto I have it right
here ready to go cuz I I hit it with uh
this little blowtorch and uh I love it
you know like I've obviously gotten into
UD on your recommendation but even just
you know something like pal Santo or you
know Eagle would like people will love
it give it a go guys dive in head first
and and while we're on that train of
thought you know we were sort of talking
about it earlier but just for for more
specifics like we had a few people who
were like hey I've gotten into
meditation and more sort of spiritual
stuff and just increase awareness while
I'm in the garden and I want to I want
to know from bod like what's a strain
that he feels complements that you know
that maybe is good for meditation or
yoga or you know in the garden what's
something you
like um you know it's hard because it's
so individual it's kind of finding it's
kind of find you know there's like it's
finding that strain that works for you
to to uh be mindful you know because
cannabis kind of enlivens the mind and
you know in meditation you're trying to
kind of tame the mind or at least not
attach to all the all the chatter that's
going on
so I'm trying to think of
what it's funny because all the Babas
smoke and they meditate I I've had
really good experiences smoking and
meditating and then I've had times where
I'm like oh I shouldn't have smoked like
it's just not happening but let me think
I
mean like a that's a hard one it's I
think it just it goes back down to just
try a lot of strains and you know ride
your bike on them hike on them go de
with your stuff with your kids play
sudco meditate kind of map those strains
in your life that that uh help you in
those instances and then another thing
it's like people with medical conditions
um map those strains that really help
you with your medical conditions so you
can share them you know they don't
always work for everybody but there are
tend to be strains that kind of work
better for certain conditions you know
like the Sunshine Daydream of mine
always people always tend to say that it
works really good for neurological
conditions and pain um you know and
there's strains that work for people
that have kidus it's like I it's hard
for me to tell you what's going to be
good for meditation but if you want to
maybe do something historical and more
of a Heritage base do you know maybe uh
look to some uh hash or hand rubbed or
stuff from the Himalayas or India places
where they've traditionally smoked and
meditated at the same
time that's fantastically practical
advice I I love that you know definitely
you know India is it's uh it makes
perfect sense of course the stuff there
and nearby would complement that sort of
[Music]
thing and there you have it friends the
first part of two come back stay tuned
edge of your
seat as always a huge huge shout out for
bod taking the time to come join us
we're incredibly
grateful if you love this episode please
consider supporting both the patreon as
well as the websites of our incredible
sponsors if you're looking to transition
from combustion to vaping check out our
good friends at dap you will not be
disappointed cheap affordable and
Incredibly efficient units likewise
check out our friends at Pulse sensors
if you want to make sure that your
garden is dialed in and you are tracking
all of the variables that are going to
ensure your next Harvest is the best to
date youve got to get yourself a pulse
guys it's a
no-brainer in order to ensure that your
garden is pest and pathogen free please
check out our friends at copit they are
the number one in bior predatory
technology copit thank you so so so much
for your
support likewise a big shout out to our
friends at Organics alive for all the
most incredible powdered organic
products usable in all systems both
organic and hybrid a huge thank you to
Organics alive we recommend them highly
please check them out if you want to
take your organic game to the next
level finally massive shout out to our
good friends at seeds here now they got
heavy days beans go check them out guys
I promise you will not be disappointed
they got all the latest drops the
hottest breeders fem Auto photo period
CBD whatever you need they're here to
help you out a massive thank you to our
friends at seeds here
now and big love to the patreon gang we
love you so much thank you for
supporting the show they got Early
Access to this episode over on month ago
if you want to get extra content please
consider supporting the show you'll
score yourself genetics a whole bunch of
swag from our sponsors and so much
more so that just about brings us to the
end of it for this
one big thank you to you for getting to
the end yet again and for the
support big love as always from your boy
heavy
days signing
off see you