[Music]
[Applause]
hello and welcome to the next episode of
the podcast your cannabis podcast for
budding enthusiasts as always
this show is brought to you by our
amazing sponsor seeds here now best in
the business hit em up if you want
guarantee not just on germination but
satisfaction why would you mess with
[ __ ] genetics they don't stock them hit
em up and our newest sponsor we are
stoked stoked stoked to have them on
board radio ridge nursery
these guys have got you sorted if you
need the best clones in the game they've
got breeder cuts of many of the most
elusive cultivars out there all them
strands
stranded
with a d you know it hit them up they're
the ones they're amazing we love them
and as always a big thank you to organic
gardening solutions
your one-stop shop for all things
organic hit them up if you want to grow
that top shelf
and last but not least
420 australia best 420 apparel in the
game even if you're not in australia it
still makes perfect sense for you to buy
this stuff i mean come on
as always a big shout out to the one and
only dragonfly earth medicine we love
y'all
quick shout out to the patreon gang love
you guys a long time
on this episode we are joined by the one
and only matt wright 2.0
hope you guys are ready for some fun
this one was a blast to record we got
three hours deep this time plenty of
stuff to listen to hope you guys enjoyed
as much as i did
much love gang
let's get into it
alrighty so a big thank you and welcome
to one of our favorite guests on the
show big fan favorite and a personal
favorite of my own thanks for making the
part 2 happen my man matt wright thanks
for joining us
happy to happy too
so first question what are you currently
smoking on
um you know someone sent in some cookie
berry crunch
from uh
i think oregon oregon his and hero they
were one of the last people keeping
medicroppers a special cut of it and
they thought they lost it and they sent
it in and then i also have some
something called cult cake from a local
grower king cultivars and it's a part
cheesecake for mad scientist genetics
and uh
i want to say euphoria
euphoria cake or something for mad
scientist genetics a combination of it
cool cool and jesus medicropper it's
been a minute since i've heard that name
i remember when i was first getting into
weed i was watching his videos on
youtube did you ever interact with him
much
um yeah a little bit um i sent him the
cookie berry crunch and stuff to run he
was a real nice dude but we never got
real close and then he disappeared
yeah i remember that he dropped off and
then he like put up a post being like
i'm in new zealand and i was like what
and then like i think that just fell
through as well
yeah
yeah i don't i don't i don't
he popped up
maybe i want to say five months ago but
and i talked to him for like a second
just to ask him if he still had that gut
and he's like no i don't still have it i
don't have anything
oh that's a bummer that was that was
interesting man because i think i've
mentioned this to you on instagram i
love the uh the names of your strains i
can like i hear the name and i'm like
that's a matte riots train and i gotta
admit i i stole that line from him
because he was the one who was talking
about it in his videos he was like heard
the cookie berry crunch and he's like
that's a matte riot strain
yeah my naming conventions are a little
off some people don't like them at all
like the coke head [ __ ] was not super
popular but you know it is what it is
that's so funny because i literally had
a question about that which i guess
we're going to jump to right now i was
going to say um
yeah like when when i was cruising your
site like an hour ago i saw the cokehead
[ __ ] and i just started laughing i was
like [ __ ] that's a good name i love that
on so many levels
do you feel like strain names
should be embodying of kind of like what
the strain has to offer or do you think
like a good strain name is a good strain
name
you know i look at it like art man um
everything that that that i do with
breeding i look at like art you know
i've always been a musician and stuff
like that and
art's been a big part of my life and i
feel like you know like
the ultimate outcome of reading is is
what your desired goal is and it's
almost like having a canvas that you're
painting and you have that ultimate
desired goal and if you're not happy
with it you'll throw it away you know
and all that comes around and then all
the way to naming that painting and it's
just whatever mood i'm in whatever i'm
thinking about whatever possessed me to
make that creation you know that's that
all goes into it
yeah perfect okay so if you had a strain
that you felt like was bang on a
particular flavor let's just say it's
like it's bang on cherries or something
do you feel like you really want to call
it like have cherries in the name or
that doesn't really influence you so
much
um some of the time yeah but like
i see a lot of names out there like
cookies that doesn't taste like [ __ ]
cookies but it's it's been established
as you know this is cookies this is the
look this is the the [ __ ] you know so
i've been trying to to migrate away from
that but like with my banana stuff
obviously the banana og was a big one
and so that that's usually in the names
because the terpene profile and the way
i i took the line was totally banana um
so when it comes to flavors sometimes if
there's like an amplified flavor usually
that'll be in the name
yeah of course of course
so a lot has happened since we last
spoke so give me a bit of a rundown what
are you currently up to
um right now i'm going through the whole
blue the blue lines um that's always
been a big passion of mine was the blue
stuff not just because of the the
chirping profile which is my favorite
terpene profile the true blueberry jam
blueberry muffins type terpenes but um
the high the high from very very select
special blueberry uh like the highland
thai thai pies um it's it's clear
clear-headed
very euphoric in many ways but not
slammingly potent it's it's really hard
to describe to someone like a lot of
modern um
a lot of modern smokers uh people from
the generation right below mine they
probably wouldn't see as much value in
it as i do because a lot of them are
used to the the narcotic afghani thai
pies but uh
yeah this is special to me and i lost my
riot very og mom in a tissue culture
debacle which we can talk about later if
you want um let's talk about it now
mooney moon what do you got to say
oh
you know that i have to be careful
because i don't want to
to get
uh in trouble legally because he's a
little rat but um yeah he killed he
literally killed everything that i owned
everything that i owned um his big
takeaway was that he didn't physically
touch it but um and that's true but the
the the thing was he he had a business
um i was moving and he's like hey let me
let me take your moms and i'll hold them
for you while you move and i'll tissue
culture while i'm doing that so he sent
someone up to pick them up he supposedly
had a facility in la with this dude dude
came picked him up i'm i i stayed in
contact with the dude and mooney during
all of this and no one mentioned
anything about them just [ __ ] killing
everything and uh it took me moving and
being like yo i'm coming to get my [ __ ]
you know i'm sending someone to come get
my [ __ ] now you know i had to get real
mean about it and uh when i did i found
out everything was just liquid in bags
no more moms they just took cuts off
[ __ ] threw it in bags in a box and that
was it been sitting there for months
dude that's so brutal to hear i actually
uh lost my uh
what how would you call it you know my
my strain that i've been working on for
the longest time raspberry marmara and i
was so devastated when i found out that
it was just gone you know like no one
still has it i was so bummed out but
then
i saw the silver lining it kind of
forces you to move on is that how you
feel about this situation
yeah um
there is a few few good things to come
from it one um i was gonna start working
heavily with moon so i learned he was a
little piece of [ __ ] from the beginning
which is cool
um
secondly
yeah it's forced me to look in all
different directions um and i get to
rework all those blueberry lines the old
blue sativa lines that i love so that's
kind of cool to be able to do it again
and thirdly i got to see who my my real
friends were there was a lot of people
that reached out were like hey i got
this of yours i'm sending it like right
now you know without me even asking
it was is pretty heartwarming you know
and then i also got to see who is true
to their word um there were several
people that
i made trades with uh like ten thousand
dollars worth of my spray reversal spray
um
and it was right before i did this with
moon because i always want to have a
plan b just in case something [ __ ] up
right
and uh i did a big trade with a few
people a few different people and i said
look if i ever lose anything i want to
be able to grab certain cuts back right
away so you know just this is just a
card in pocket and they're like yeah
yeah cool cool now they have all these
fem lines out and the second i needed
them they're like yeah i don't got
anything for you bro
so
yeah [ __ ] it's kind of par for the
course isn't it
it is it is but you know again now i
know that they're they're you know who
they are
yeah okay yeah it's uh it's almost like
that legend og situation where you're
almost like just testing people seeing
who's gonna be the real homies
yep yep
interesting okay so you brought up the
blueberry thing that's interesting
because it was only about like two days
ago i saw swami not the uh the one who
walks around in the white garb but uh
the the one who [ __ ] with those cool
genetics swami seeds they were saying
something about how you know it seems
like basically dj shorts work has hit a
dead end and they came to that
conclusion by the fact that jd's work
with it has just been
you know in their opinion quite
lackluster how do you feel about that
and how do you feel about the idea that
you know the work has been somewhat
bottlenecked
well
there's a few there's a few levels to
that question you've got to start off
with the source
swami
swami's
he doesn't know jack [ __ ] about breeding
neither does gay afghanistan i've put
them both under the [ __ ] the fire you
know on my live feed and otherwise they
wouldn't come on but um what they were
doing was attempting to make the one
from um
uh uh
the other [ __ ] i can't remember his
name but um who is it is it mountain
organics or coot no
toots
yeah
so they were trying to make that look
like an old dj short line by saying it
was highland tie and all this [ __ ] and i
actually popped a bunch of it to see and
there's no relation at all in any of
that to the blueberry
so there is that factor to it they don't
i don't think they have a right nor
the history that they claim being a part
of brotherhood of eternal life it seems
like a lot of liars pull from that
brotherhood of eternal love [ __ ] card
pack golden coast you know idiots like
that um
but yeah like
but i will say that
dj's lines have transformed a lot over
the years and and the blueberry indica
stuff the afghani based stuff it's not
particularly blueberry anymore um
you know i have a bunch of that running
with all the old blueberries right now
and it's
it's uh yeah i don't know if it's due to
inbreeding not being able to take it
back in that direction maybe not a want
to to visit that direction anymore
um but then i see him release stuff like
newberry
and i haven't run that so i can't
comment on that i don't know if he's
trying to go back in that direction
but you know i'm not a big fan of any of
the modern blueberry stuff um
i like that
jd's going towards the f-13 and stuff
like that it's one of the best
dj lines ever
and he's been real cool easy to talk to
dj not so much dj's not as easy to talk
to um when i the last time i've met him
several times but the last time i saw
him he he told me that my company was
not owned by me
so i thought that was pretty interesting
interesting observation yeah i thought
he's like yeah you don't you don't own
riot seeds there's a guy named ryan
solly schecter that owns riot seeds and
i was like
no i'm pretty sure he owns oregon seed
bank uh he's a cool dude but yeah no he
doesn't own my company he's like no
um no i i think he owns riot seeds and i
was like okay cool nice seeing you dude
i seen you again dj
yeah wow yeah i remember at emerald cup
i was able to smoke on his one of his
newest trains first light and that was
very much drawing from the more kind of
flow flavors and terpenes so i think i
would agree with you on that blueberry
comment about how it's not so present
anymore
yeah yeah i wish i wish it were
um when i had my rye berry cup before
moon had so graciously murdered it um i
i offered it to dj because it was so it
was it was so much in the direction the
blueberry jam very purple looked a lot
like oregon purple tie so i figured man
this is like it's it's a lot it spread
in the direction of the baseline like
the oregon purple tie but with all the
blueberry traits um blueberry terps and
everything and i offered it to him he
just was not [ __ ] interested in it i
don't know if he didn't believe me or if
he just didn't want to go that direction
and you know that's his prerogative but
yeah um i tried offering that to him and
i kind of wish he would have taken it
now just so i could have gotten it back
from someone
yeah most certainly so one of the newer
blueberry kind of players to hit the
scene is humboldt seed company who have
their blueberry muffin have you had a
chance to try that oh
what do you think
um all right so i mean the blueberry
muffin was a cut and it was my right
berry og cut and it's been that for
i don't know over a decade
um now these guys supposedly are
mountain people who don't really give
two shits about
naming conventions or otherwise and
that's fine and dandy but
um you're gonna offend people doing that
like putting out a jackhammer that has
nothing to do with jack hair uh genetics
a headband has nothing to do with
headband i know ethos did that too just
i don't know if that's a new thing to do
just steal a name and slap it on
[ __ ] but um
i've been told they're nice people
with all that said i've been told
they're nice people by by good friends
of mine so i don't want to go too heavy
on it but i no i have not tried it um
i don't know it's just one of those
things where it's like kind of i want to
try it but at the same time i don't want
to support someone who just jacked me
and used all the the energy i put behind
something to make their line sell you
know
yeah i i was able to have a quick chat
with the owner nat at the emerald cup
and he definitely is a nice guy however
i was also able to have a chat with
their head breeder and i was less
convinced when i was asking him some
serious questions about you know
like you know because they claim it's an
f4 and then on the packaging it says
it's an f8 so i was like so so which one
is it and he didn't really give me a
convincing answer and i was like oh okay
cool man see you later
yeah it's an s1 f4 f8px yeah bro yeah
one of those [ __ ] [ __ ] yeah i
don't know i don't know
yeah i'm not a fan
all right well let's uh let's keep on
the naming conventions for a minute
right i had a question thrown to me the
other day and i couldn't answer it but i
think you might be able to someone said
they made they used some femme spray
they made the s-ones popped the seeds
and then they found some males in it and
i was like well that could be like rogue
pollen by the sounds of it but anyway
let's just assume that it is from the
pollen that they thought it was they
were like if i make f2s with these seeds
what would they be named and i was like
would that be like s1 f2 like i don't
know how to name it what would you call
that
f2r
yeah f2 reversal yeah i mean that's
that's essentially what it would be but
you know like the the mail
um the mail is popping up from femme
seeds is it's a uh
it's a it's a topic like a lot of people
are very staunch in their beliefs on um
there was a paper the other day i wish i
had it handy um
that that my friend bittersweet pulled
up and it was from i want to say the 70s
talking about it and it gave a full
rundown of what's happening and
basically it is that nature finds a way
that's the answer to it um now when
they're tested i know caleb from csi
humboldt has sent in some stuff uh males
that have been found or plants that have
been expressing male found in s1s or or
reversed hybrids sending those in and
they're coming up testing as female
but they're only expressing male like
they're not expressing any female traits
so i don't know
it's it's a weird topic man it's not
always going to be that way
but um it tends to be
the most common the most common argument
is that it's pollen contamination and i
think 99 of the time it will be pollen
contamination but there there's many
times where it's popped up and there's
no way it could be and then you're left
with
well was it is it a
female that's just expressing male is it
an actual male with male chromosomes
like what is it you know and and it's
different seems to be different in every
case yeah of course so something i
really wanted to ask you do you feel
like the chemicals used in the reversal
spray could be a contributing factor
you know i i tend to think that but um
you know there's people that disagree
with me that have just as much time
reversing and maybe even more experience
reversing than i do so i take that into
account as well um i truly believe that
that in stressing a plant you're you're
changing its epigenetic changing it at
the epigenetic level and um you know i
was watching an interesting ted talk the
other day talking about epigenetics and
it had to do with rats um
and and mothers nursing their their rats
their rattlings whatever you [ __ ]
call little rats
but yeah like if they didn't if they
didn't nurse them it changed them it
changed these little rats at the
epigenetic level
and they're already born they already
have their set set of genetics but at
the epigenetic level just by not nursing
it changed them for life and it changed
the future
children 10 generations in
so i mean i think that if you do it with
uh uh stress and and strictly stress
because there's a lot more hormones that
are involved in stress than there are in
simple reversals where you're just
blocking uh
blocking ethylene and um and promoting
gibbrelli you know that those are the
two main things that you need to reverse
however in stress there's a lot more
hormones involved and i think that it
changes the the plants at the epigenetic
level to be more prone to to herm stress
um
if you go that method which i believe
soma calls rotalization um
which is a [ __ ] term in my eyes uh
but you know torture your plants and and
make seeds that that is a method that
people use or run them too long and have
them herm and hopefully that make seeds
that's it that's a method people use uh
it's not my choice method uh and this is
just a theory i could be totally [ __ ]
wrong i could be totally [ __ ] wrong
it might one might be just as perfect as
the other and not change anything at an
epigenetic level but until we have the
ability to test for that who knows
you know i i totally agree and the the
effects of vertical transmission of
stress are well documented in humans so
it makes sense that it would apply to
plants right
i thought it was fascinating that 10
generations down they're seeing that
epigenetically everything is fully
affected like up to 10 generations down
so even people that smoke cigarettes
males that smoke cigarettes during
conception right or females that smoke
cigarettes after conception and in the
uh and when it's in her
[ __ ]
uterus that's the one yeah here i am
talking botany you know a [ __ ] about
biology but um apparently yeah even
smoking cigarettes and stuff like that
affects
generations 10 generations down
i mean if i believe the quote was if
someone starts smoking at the age of 9
to 11 it will affect their children's
children 10 generations down negatively
that's i mean that's mind-blowing so
decisions we make as children can affect
future generations
scary yeah for sure i've actually got
this friend who's a doctor and he was
saying to me that he finds it very
peculiar how there's this similarity
within uh unstable cannabis genetics and
like really low socioeconomic humans in
terms of everyone kind of jokingly
acknowledges that like
you know women from low socioeconomic
backgrounds tend to have kids at a
younger age than if you're like kind of
more or well-off you'd have them a
little bit older and maybe a bit more
financially set up and he was like it's
so peculiar how it's like similar to
plants you know like an unstable plant
will hermaphrodite and want to produce
these offspring at like a much earlier
age and it's got these epigenetic
effects that go on for generations much
the same as like what happens in humans
i was like [ __ ] i never thought of it
like that that's such a brilliant
analogy
yeah and that's along the same theory
that i have like you know if it's stress
stress induced as opposed to just
chemically induced without all the other
stress markers that it it changes [ __ ]
at the epigenetic level
for sure so while we're on the topic of
fem spray we've seen a few new frame
sprays come out since we last spoke
what's your take on this like different
companies producing them
um i think it's good man like it
in in business you need you need
competition to grow and push everyone to
make the best product possible so i
think it's a great thing dude
i the one thing i don't like is is
people putting out [ __ ] that's just
gonna waste people's money and time
though and i've seen a lot of that a
[ __ ] load of that i can't tell you
how many emails i get from like tyrese
mis customers messaging me and saying
hey this [ __ ] didn't work i've got a
[ __ ] problem with it you know i've
got to rush through this and then i have
to rush ship them spray so they can
finish their [ __ ] you know um yeah but
as far as uh any competition um hybe of
course he's been doing it longer than me
his spray is very effective um
csi humboldt was able to reverse
triangle with it and he he used my spray
his spray and hives and hives worked
great for it great it did burn the plant
up but in in reversals you're not really
worried about keeping it pretty you're
worried about pollen dumping and and his
in that case was very effective so there
there is also
people need to keep in mind like there
are certain sprays that are more
effective for different phenoes of
different things so yeah i mean it's
good it drives us all to be better
yeah of course and i'll give you a quick
shout out my friend myfam seeds were
made from your spray i 100 back it but
yeah yeah yeah one for the homies but uh
yeah yeah that's awesome most notably
with these new fem sprays coming out
we've seen our buddy swerve put up a
post a while back saying like oh you
know i'm thinking of offering a new
spray and the part which caught my eye
was that he said like you know it's
going to be done properly and i guess
the implication was that others on the
market are maybe not done properly how
do you feel about that
i swears a little bit so i mean he's
going to take shots anyone he's going to
try to come in anywhere in the market
like if you look at how the quality of
his seeds and how he did it producing
[ __ ] auto flowering herms in a line
that was supposed to be neither um it's
probably going to be the same with this
spray he's never been really effective
at doing reversals again tons of pollen
contamination and tons of males in a lot
of his lines um and he's kind of doing
it just to be an [ __ ] but whatever
more power to him
bring on the competition [ __ ]
that's what i say
yeah yeah if you listen and swerve shout
out bro you can come on soon i know
we've been talking about it
i'm such a little [ __ ]
oh yeah but he's got a story to tell as
well and i want to hear you know i and
even though i don't like swerve um i
will say
a lot of the ogs in the market um the og
kush's were based on his seed line like
a lot of people renamed a lot of his
lines um so i'll give credit where it's
due to that dude on that but it's just
you know the first emerald cup i finally
got to see him in person and we were not
cool
and uh it was right after i had my
interaction with uh [ __ ] dave from
golden coast and um i walked up behind
him threw him in a quick choke and then
i let go because i was like okay i'm
being an [ __ ] now kind of being a
bully on this little kid and uh then he
walked up and he was being he was being
nice after he's like yo you know it's
you know we're both og's blah blah blah
and i was like you know what if you're
changing if you're changing your
attitude in life and [ __ ] that's cool
you know hit me up here's my number and
i [ __ ] you not the day i get home he's
already talking [ __ ] and it's just like
wow did you just do that not to get your
ass beat that's sad that's sad because i
i was looking forward to him changing uh
his tune yeah well i mean something you
mentioned which i think is undeniable is
that there's certainly a lot of work out
there that does use his stuff and one of
the more notable ones is purple punch
you know they used his larry og a male
from that to make that
i thought about that for a minute and i
was like well there's a lot of people
who don't really rate purple punch so is
that like how does that does is it a
good marketing point is it a bad
marketing point what's your thoughts on
purple punch
um you know i like smoking it especially
because the terps are [ __ ] amazing in
it i've had some really really good
purple punch that's almost berry that i
really liked um
i don't mind i don't need to get smashed
every time i smoke so i don't mind it
but i get why people are like okay it's
really resinous it gives the appearance
that it's going to be really potent and
then it's not it's disappointing in that
in that sense but it's made us it's it's
made its
uh
it's made its mark on our market and
that's undeniable
yeah and how do you feel in general
about some of the purple strains because
to me at least it's like it seems like
it's the first purple strain that's
really made a mark on the hype market in
a long time so i kind of think like i
mean props for doing that right
yeah yeah definitely um the first people
doing hardcore purple work or naboo
um
sunny chiba off of naboo's work um
i don't like to credit myself with a lot
but i was one of the first people really
putting purples out there because they
were hard to find they were real hard to
find purples back in the day and people
see it today everywhere so they don't
really understand how how rare it was
and how much breeding it took to bring
that to the forefront and then you know
csi did a lot of beautiful work with
urkel um
with purple indica
um
you had cvf doing some purple indica
work
uh so yeah you know i'm a fan of purples
dude i love that aesthetic beauty in my
garden at all times so would you
generally agree with the kind of idea
that purples generally speaking are not
as potent as kind of their greener
counterparts
you know i i'd say it would be a
case-by-case basis because purple oracle
the original cut is one of the most
smashing potent
[ __ ] plants i can't smoke it it puts
me into a tizzy as it were
it i mean it [ __ ] me up so bad in in a
bad way so i can't really smoke it but i
love breeding with it because of how it
breeds and because i like i like that
flavor so i always have to hybridize it
before i can smoke it but yeah in that
case it's one of the more potent ones um
so it's really hard to say
yeah okay well i mean while we're on the
topic of urkel as time goes by i'm
getting more and more convinced that
urkel is a part of the cookie's genetic
makeup given given your work with the f1
derb as well as a lot of other things in
general yeah what's your stance on this
and what's your what's your uh kind of
you know thoughts on the cookie genetic
lineage
so i was the first person to put out
cookie and seed form
oh i i guess almost
nine eight or nine years ago now and i
was just talking about that today i
didn't realize it's been that long since
it's been out um
back then i noted okay
i've seen this before i've seen this in
urkel and og hybrids you can pull this
out this exact pheno out with just urkel
and og including the ogkb phenotype
which is a common occurring phenotype
that you see in herbal and og hybrids
however uh cookies probably was done
with gdp
um
which isn't another oracle hybrid and
gdp and that florida og um i know that
not so dog my buddy has that florida og
and it's had it for a while so that is a
real og cut that did exist
um
yeah and and things like cherry pie
though cherry pie is the mendo derb
expression which i think is just mendo
derb and the og without the herbal
but you can see very very much that the
the mendo derb aka f1 derv aka purple
pain aka a million other names
um yeah that's that's where you see the
expression in cherry pie the most but in
cookies you really don't see any of that
expression
yeah yeah okay shout out francis not so
dogs really cool guy i um yeah
i like how he's been like kind of
resurrecting slash really working with
the trinity have you got much experience
with that one
yeah i have it um our our little circle
has it um
shout out to the can illuminati
that's a lot that's all i can say about
it but yeah uh we all have it we're all
playing with it um we're learning a lot
about it that it does have a dud trait
in it that doesn't always express um
like you can take a branch off of it and
uh sometimes it's a great branch
sometimes it's a dud branch and if you
get a dud branch you're kind of [ __ ]
um unfortunately
i have a dud branch so i'm waiting for
the uh clean branch to come but yeah
i've smoked a lot of his trinity up at
uh during emerald cup this last year we
had the big party and and we got smoking
much of it there
yes i'm actually really bummed out i
wasn't able to make it i just need to
get my own car next time i'm over so i
can drive to these very
kind illuminati parties
that was a wild party man the people
that showed up it was pretty legendary
it was legendary the amount of like at
one point um you know there was josh d
bode uh
uh caleb uh not so dog everyone in a
room all of us in a room just talking
genetics dude just nerding the [ __ ] out
miami mango was there uh marty from
triangle kush was there you know just
like looking around my buddy resin lung
shout out to him he's the one who
actually threw it and was the host of
the party um but yeah it was a legendary
moment not many people got to be there
for it or see it but it was uh everybody
was there it's very memorable for all of
us
hell yeah dude well you mentioned
one of the favorite people on the show
the b man himself bodie
how's things going between you guys i've
heard that bodhi is looking to maybe do
some collabs going forward is there
anything you might want to
kind of get in the works with him
me and him have done the purple unicorn
collabs for a long time like uh for a
while i was only one with that cut and i
he gifted it to me and that was that was
special it was sweet of him uh me and
him are still
as as close as ever if not more close he
came down and we hung out went out to
dinner he's just a trip to be around
he's a he's a
very unique human being and and one of
one of the people i respect most on
earth um as far as like there's a lot of
people you meet him and they're so nice
and you're like that shit's fake that
[ __ ] is fake no one's that nice and with
him it's it's it's legitimate he is that
[ __ ] nice he's that good of a human
being and uh again after this moon
situation he was one of the people that
stepped up and you know like a lot of
breeders look at each other's
competition and me and him never have
and he stepped up and and said okay i'm
coming down i'm coming down and i'm
going to bring you a bunch of [ __ ] and
that's that and he did he
he came down came to my house we hung
out he dropped off [ __ ] like 20
different strains and
yeah i that's the second time he's
helped save my company second time um so
i owe that man the world
yeah truly uh one of a kind person as
you said
yeah so
you touched on it earlier but i want to
get more a bit deeply into it the the
concept of people outsourcing their
breeding is becoming a more and more
common
kind of uh
occurrence within the the kind of
community how do you feel about this do
you feel like it's a bad or a good thing
or where do you sit
um i can't i can't say it's terrible
because i've been one of those people
that
people call to outsource their breeding
i think i think people are starting to
learn their strengths in this industry
some people are really good at marketing
and really good at packaging and
presentation but not so good at breeding
and i think i think that's uh
it's hard when you have an ego we all
have egos to a certain extent and as as
artists and breeders we all have egos
however um
it's
we have to put our egos down to say okay
someone else is better than me at this
particular thing
and i'm going to have them do it now
with that said i think there should be
transparency in it there should always
be transparency in it ghost spreading
kind of sucks you know
and being able to just buy
street cred and breeding to me is is
pretty lame um
but outsourcing breeding as long as it's
transparent i think i think it's going
to be something we see more often you
know um
yeah
yeah yeah that's dance so i guess that
was a kind of a neat little segue into
what i love to ask everyone the whole
candy rain debacle from cookie fam you
know that was one such example of this
outsourcing how do you feel about that
situation and more specifically how do
you feel about their response to the
issues do you feel like they adequately
responded to the situation or they kind
of dropped the ball
well i mean they themselves when they
first showed up said
and i quote yeah they're breeding shits
for [ __ ] nerds so they you know i
mean
anybody who invested in that that they
got what they deserved i mean there was
plenty of warning everyone when they
even talked about it a lot of us came
out and said you know if you're going to
spend good money on on seeds that are
bred
why would you go to people who are not
breeders why would you go to people who
don't understand genetics and they got
exactly what they paid for um i know
that i think two or three people might
have been
made good on the candy rain where they
gave them another cross from jbz um i'm
conf
i'm confused why jbz would want to work
with them but that's his prerogative you
know i mean maybe it was a good
financial situation good financial move
and i can't i can't hate on him for that
but at the same time like i just trashed
to me they're trash
yeah so i mean does that
frustrate you in a way the price point
they set given the quality because i
know that you know everyone's probably
familiar that you know you're not
looking to cater to the cheapest pack in
the store and that's fine because the
quality is there to back up the price
tag but when you've got this situation
of an even in like much higher price
much lower quality such as the candy
rain do you feel like that makes it
harder for you to stand your own ground
when you're justifying why you do have
the pricing you do
um you know really customers set the
price
eddie it's only worth what people are
willing to pay for it and if people
were willing to pay that for it then
it's worth exactly that those those
non-germinatable seeds were worth
exactly 500 a pack or whatever it was
and um
you know whether that the quality is
there with it that's up to them to
determine maybe they like trash and
maybe they like they like just the fact
they maybe they spent that money for the
packaging
you know or to make them feel better so
it you know i don't know um
yeah
it's it's a weird situation with that i
mean there's a lot of people who i think
like like csi humboldt i see his prices
hundred dollars a pack or 200 for the
chem 91 s ones or it was 100 and then
200 for the triangle cush s ones i think
that blew my mind because i know how
much goes into reversals and a lot of
people don't understand what really goes
into reversals the main thing being what
determines the price on reversals for me
is how many times did i fail before i
[ __ ] have a room that i produced
viable seeds from that sometimes you'll
have three runs of nothing
so then okay that sucks you just lost
you know x amount of money per each room
that you wasted on a reversal and it's
not a matter of skills it's just how
reversals work um so i know he had tried
chem 91 several times and triangle kush
several times and people were bitching
that he charged 200 a pack i could have
slapped every single one of them because
i he should have charged 600 a pack in
my opinion that's what they're worth
they're that rare it's that hard to do
there was that many failures involved um
yeah
yeah totally i mean considering no one's
ever successfully been able to reverse
the tk by him it totally validates your
point right
yep absolutely
i got six seeds from my first triangle
push reversal six oh
damn
so i mean
we'll come back to cookies in a minute
but while we're talking about the tk you
know the tk origins crew has come out of
the shadows since we last spoke i've
spoken to a few people such as josh d
who i i'm a big fan of josh d i think
he's a lovely guy um you know he said to
me he he really thinks the story is
legit you know he he backs it you know
how do you feel about it
um i'm friends with marty i like marty a
lot um he's tk origins guy
um
i don't know
there are things that have changed over
the years in that story the main part
being the hindu kush edition and that it
was intentional
um
other than that i don't i don't see a
reason
i don't see any holes in the story that
he was a part of that original crew i do
believe that probably to be true um
there's also the super knot dude um and
he can he backs up some of the story i
believe um
so yeah i mean i i don't see a lot of
holes in that story i think maybe the
intention
and the
you know might be different and the
knowledge of what's in it might be
different
um it sounds a lot more positive and and
sure than it was you know x amount of
years ago when he came online and talked
about it but that's the only difference
i see but i do think he was a part of
that original crew and and i don't know
that triangle would be around if he
hadn't been a part of it so yeah
and how do you feel about this uh
emerald triangle strain that was the
supposed mother i'm really struggling to
find any information about it have you
got any thoughts around that one
um
no uh i it's kind of like dog butt it's
one of those things that's up in the air
what the [ __ ] was it you know um
yeah yeah
it probably was just a strain from the
emerald triangle but what it actually
was
hindu kush probably i think he's even
right in guessing that
i i would assume that's probably a good
direction to to go with it would be a
hindu kush a stretchy more golf ball
nugget hindu kush which those do exist
um the hayes brothers old kali kush was
like that the vintage is the 80s
what was it called vintage 80s
hayes brothers california kush that was
the full name that they gave it but uh
it was similar to that so yeah there
were there was cushes around like that
and and that strain might have had a
name originally it might not have but if
it came from the emerald triangle
you know that's that's probably what it
was
and so how do you think we got to the
point where we have all the ogs from
there do you think that you know the
kind of standard lemon og type of thing
was locked inside those initial tk and
josh d ogs or do you think there was
more added to the the pool
i'm sure there's been more added to the
pull over time um with ogs a lot of
people say oh it's just an s1 of that
yeah we don't know if it's s-ones or if
it's uh another plant that hurt in a
room i think that there's a lot of that
going i think people recognize that it
was amazing weed and that's why you
started seeing people keep seeds from
these bags of this weed you know and as
it moved across the country and through
different groups each person each group
kept a little little bit of a different
version like in california resin long's
crew had their og i have that copy and
that was
what is
supposed to be the original
josh d-o-g and we still have it it's
actually a lot more different a lot
different from uh the the cuts out there
called josh d that i've seen it's more
stocky it's more it stays about five
feet tall whereas like
uh triangle will [ __ ] grow straight
up like a vine you know i that i have an
eight footer in the room right now just
growing up you know all lanky this one
is lenky but not as lenky as the pure
kush not as lanky as loompas headband
and stuff like that so um and then louie
was another uh early og crew you know
the louis
kazarin i think his name was and then
you had the jew cut with habibi and
those dudes those are all the early ogs
people selecting that backseat
essentially and finding it running their
own and that's how all these started
popping up but whether they were pure or
not
you know we'll never really know
yeah yeah most certainly so interesting
one you brought up the lumpus headband
i've been talking to a few people behind
the scenes and i won't reveal any names
but a few people have said to me that um
they're they're a little bit i don't
want to say ticked off but like you know
they've got their kind of grievances
around the fact it's called lumper's
headband because apparently there was a
lot of people who had it before lumper
did and to me part of me feels like well
i mean if he just stepped up to the
plate and said this is my headband it's
called lumper's headband then it's just
kind of okay he got in first how do you
feel about that like if someone named
australian after themselves if it was
given to them by someone you know what i
mean like there's lots of other people
who've got it
um i you know lupus really didn't name
it after himself he was on he was on a
thc farmer a lot and um
a lot of people just referred to because
he was showing off this cut he had
called headband his name was lupa on the
thing and people started referring to
his lupus headband and he just went with
it um not the best choice really but
it's also not the same headband that was
around before it and i think that's been
fairly established that it's an og kush
cut um it's not the original headband
but it was an early cut that he called
headband
there's a lot of origin stories on it
that have popped up from him
specifically
um i i
he says it came from new york out of
someone's pocket someone smuggled that
out of a room that's one of the stories
and there's a few other stories that it
was just from someone's [ __ ] room
in a in somewhere up in norcal
you know so it's
you know there's a few origin stories on
it it's a it's one of the best og kush
cuts out there i think right up there
with triangle so that that is uh
that's that's for sure we know that for
sure but it is an og kush gut it is not
a a traditional headband in the sense of
a northern light super skunk type line
yeah certainly i feel like um whenever
you smell it you can smell that og nose
on it right oh yeah yeah it's one of the
heaviest like soapy noses you can get
yeah yeah cool cool it's actually i
swear it's one of my favorites and i
never thought i would like actually say
that but like most of the time when i'm
in the states someone will like have
simon i'd like give it to me it's what i
want to smoke
have you found a way to smuggle it out
back to australia yet
dude i wish man full disclosure please
australian please don't come after me um
basically um i
i i had sent a tk cut back and it had
made it and i was like yes and then the
person that it landed at they didn't
really know how to look after plants and
it died after it had landed they sent me
photos when it landed and i was like oh
my god it's alive it's still good and uh
and then like a few days later they sent
me another photo while i was still in
the states and it was dead and i was
like
[ __ ] that sucks dude yeah the one thing
the best advice i will give someone if a
cut is uh magically magic through the
air to someone immediately get it and
either stick it in a cube in a dome
because it's coming out of a hundred
percent humidity whether you realize it
or not it's you have to re-harden it off
or stick it in a cup of water that's it
that's all you have to do is stick it in
a [ __ ] cup of water let it sit
there for two days harden off
then then start rooting it you know um
that's that's the best advice i can give
anyone in that situation because that
[ __ ] sucks when you get something super
rare that's so hard to get over anywhere
you know and and just to watch it die
i've had it happen so many times over
the years and that's been the the major
fix for it
oh man thank you i'll uh if any cuts uh
what is it
transcentiate themselves over here we'll
uh we'll see if we'll see if that works
recently on your instagram i mean you're
talking about the the true headband
lineage being like that nl super skunk
hybrid i saw you made that post about
one of your friends who was running the
jesus ones
and they had got like that recessive
super skunk fino made me think to myself
where is the real super skunk you know
people talk about it but does it
actually still exist
no
um for all intents and purposes as far
as we know it is dead that doesn't mean
that someone doesn't have it tucked away
but it's not accessible to anyone that
we know of and no one we know um in our
little circles holds it and i think our
circles are pretty pretty complete right
now with people that had it back then
we're all friends and
yeah we it's the the and it was actually
i thought it was a jesus one but it
turned out it was my skunk spray cam
which is diesel crossed a sour dub um so
even in that hybrid it expressed itself
purely as the mass super um it came out
skunk spray smelling and
it's it's the legit real deal
pheno of super skunk as as it was and
that's pretty amazing because i was
worried that it would just be the
structure and look but not have the
smell you know the high all that stuff
so um yeah it's cause caused quite a bit
of hubbub and and a lot of the original
dudes that ran the super skunk you know
want it they want it back you know so i
think that's cool it's cool for the
person that bought the seeds and popped
them um it's you know it's his way to
make them make his mark on the community
and rightly so he he popped those seeds
he kept it alive he did all that and he
should be able to make profits off that
you know
for sure and so i mean the super skunk
it's such a fabled strain and
yet it's there's still so much
uncertainty around it and my biggest
question is what are the genetics you
know we've heard from skunk va that he
thinks it was like you know maybe like
an original skunk f2 type of thing but
then also you know you've got like the
the actual genetics which is like an
afghan cross skunk type of thing where
do you sit on this one
um it's absolutely in a hundred percent
my opinion based on running all the old
super skunks it is just a super skunk
afghani afghan tea which i don't believe
like neville said i do not believe that
it was from maple leaf indica i think it
was an afghani one crossed the skunk one
and it it has some skunk traits uh skunk
one traits but it does not have skunk
one terps because i think the biggest
confusion is that skunk one is nothing
like what we know in america as skunk
smelling um the american skunk being a
little animal
what it sprays smells nothing like skunk
ones skunk ones the the furthest
expression or closest expression to
skunk would be
what he was available with wasn't going
to be skunk spray smelling but it was
the skunk old skunk one and i think a
lot of assumptions were made on that by
the people buying the seeds because they
weren't educated and uh yeah
but with that said that afghani one of
all the breeding that i've done with
afghani one the laf old laffy cut um
it that is a baseline like no other it's
very similar to that heirloom afghani
line that i have that's caused a lot of
commotion with all of its skunk traits
and and burnt rubber and and piss in it
yeah okay i mean you bring up a really
interesting point there with that laffy
i mean the lacon got a really good rap
on its first release and i was always
told that that was because they had the
real cut that first time
where is that cut now do you reckon
i i think it's dead i don't know um
there's a cut going around that looks
like bubba
that is not the original i still have
pictures of the original and it's
identical to the scentsy seeds afghani
one um i uh there's a catalog from 1999
and if you look in in that catalog uh
from scentsy seeds you can see a picture
of the afghani one and it is literally
identical to that picture um that clone
that's been long gone for me the last
person i gave it to was walking dude and
i traded it to him for the hayes
brothers cali kush and he has since
passed away he was one of me and sonny
chiba's good friend so shout out to our
our deceased buddy uh walking dude
yeah that's obama to hear he's no longer
with us
yeah it is he he was an interesting dude
um
when i
when i was first like hearing about sub
cool and all that um on on breed bay and
i was trying to figure out what that
dude was all about walking dude was the
guy who saved jack's cleaner for subcool
when he was in prison and gave it back
to him and sub kind of slapped him in
the face so he pulled me aside he's like
yo bro you don't even want to go down
this road with this [ __ ] dude he's a
lamer
so shout out again to him for [ __ ]
making sure i didn't go down that route
that route and he introduced me to sunny
back then
and i learned a lot and all the all the
stuff that i was really liking that i
was seeing come from tga i learned was
from sunny all that black russian work
all that beautiful purple stuff which is
what what intrigued me about tga early
on
yeah certainly i mean we're gonna get to
tga in just a minute but let's uh let's
wrap up this one first so yeah jumping
back to the roadkill or you know those
kind of skunk spray smells it's it's a
focal point of many people's phenohunts
what have your views on this mythic
strain change since we last spoke like i
mean i know that
a lot of people have the view that your
skunk spray afghani is one of the
closest things we've got to it do you
think we'll eventually nail it down
yeah yeah i see no reason we can't you
know i mean i think uh i nailed it down
in the diesel sour dub there's skunk
spray total skunk spray coming out of
that um and i did it with the heirloom
afghani line and i and i truly believe
that heirloom afghani line is either an
afghani one or uh afghani ones super
skunk hybrid or just super skunk one of
the three um when i was given to me by
bite me he didn't tell me anything other
than it's an afghani and i asked him
well which afghan he said well there was
a lot of afghani one going around at the
time it was uh late 80s early 90s so
that's when he was popped he kept those
seats for a long time only a few pop for
me
um the male i wish i would have kept him
and the female was killed again by
mooney moon dog so now we're doing a big
hunt through the s-ones uh me and my my
partner skunk tech are doing that
and and i gave some to friends too for
them to use because i don't believe that
that
i own that really you know
i found it it doesn't have anything to
do with me other than i made s-ones of
it but i think that it should be shared
with the community because a lot of
people are looking for it so i've given
it out to like my buddy pipsweed el jefe
there's a lot of people who've gotten
the afghani for me um for free just to
bring it back into modern lines and work
in all these different directions i know
my buddy surfweed also did that crossed
it to my banana tie
crossed it to a bunch of stuff old
family purple from caleb so yeah yeah
it's there um and i think people can
find it dude just by running running
even jesus ones or
old chem s-ones um you're not finding it
necessarily in the chem 91 you're
getting more of the burnt rubber kemi
stuff
but you can find it in old super skunk
lines if you can trace an old super
skunk line or old afghani one line
yeah of course and so are you of the
opinion that the road kill per se at
least in the way people talk about it
was not necessarily one specific cutting
but just more maybe like a general
terpene profile or do you think it very
much was one very specific thing
oh no i think it was just people were
getting afghani it was the first time
they were experiencing afghani which
started um
talking to seattle northern lights greg
he was saying that that northern lights
afghani which was called this or the
steve murphy afghani that was used in
northern lights came in the early 80s
and that's always been my contention the
earliest you'll ever see in afghanistan
1978 roughly
maybe the earliest of one person might
have had it would be 76 but you don't
see anything earlier than that
so during that era afghanis started to
disperse and people were used to
colombian gold
you know they were used to mexicans once
that afghanis started spinning around
and people in america that were used to
smelling skunks they started calling it
skunk
i'm not sure that roadkill skunk was
ever a term used back then it was more
of a term used in uh referring to what
had been around back then and had been
lost
and referring to many different
phenos of an afghani type plant
so you just mentioned skunk tech is
someone who you're currently working
with would you be willing to share any
little secrets in terms of what we might
be able to expect from you guys
oh yeah um yeah skunk's one of my best
friends we have all the shirts that
we've been releasing
so i've been going back and uh
buying up all the old um
i guess you uh thermal transfer shirts
from the 70s and 80s and i've been going
back buying them up and
bringing them
back like because there's some beautiful
old colombian gold art acapulco gold art
lebanese red art all this stuff and so
we've been working together on that he
has a beautiful like 45 000 t-shirt
printing machine that does the best
t-shirt prints i've ever seen and better
than even hand screening and uh so we've
been putting those out slowly but surely
and people are catching on to that
but yeah we're also doing pheno hunts
big fino hunts through a lot of
different things like like my heirloom
afghani
we're going to help reproduce high-end
lonesomes appalachia f2s together
actually it would be f3s that we're
going to be working on
yeah we have a lot of projects
i might be moving up to livermore by him
so we can continue to actually
have him be part of riot seeds and
that's that's the ultimate goal
i've never really had a partner in riot
seeds that that is that established i've
had a lot of people work with me on a
lot of different things and there's a
lot of people in riot seats but as a
direct partner in right ct would be the
first
yeah exciting times
yeah man you uh you raised a really good
point about how you know you guys are
finna hunting through stuff you're going
to be working with that something i've
noticed and it is you know i mean i'll
take it with a grain of salt because the
australian scene it's so in its infancy
in every way basically but sure i've
noticed that there's certain people and
it's probably the same internationally
they just can't seem to find like they
can't phenoh hunt on a very rudimentary
level like they pop seeds and they can't
really discern the keeper it sounds like
a bit of a foreign concept but i
legitimately find it like they're
popping seeds and they've never got
anything to offer back and it's not that
like
i don't think it's the case that there's
no keepers in the packs because you pop
a pack from a reputable breeder you're
pretty much always going to find
something worthy of hanging around so my
question is
how do people pop seeds and not find
keepers
i think okay in order to find a true
keeper you you one have to run the seed
but you should probably run a clone of
it as well to see how it continues to
express in clone form because it's
always going to be different than the
seedling secondly you have to have your
environment at least dialed in enough to
be able to see that phenotype expressed
at its highest value and i think that's
where a lot of it occurs man like it's
again in australia it's in its infancy
um indoor growing is is a lot different
you know i mean that's probably a newer
idea in australia because so many people
grow in the bush out there you know a
lot of people grow outdoors out there so
indoor growing is a lot different than
outdoor growing and to get these these
things to express at their best value
you have to be able to grow in your
environment at its best and i think
that's why they're not finding these
keepers like they're thinking oh damn
this [ __ ] sucks and it's like
it's because it wasn't super happy a lot
of this stuff a lot of the best stuff's
coming from the us
and it's being bred in the u.s it's
acclimated to the u.s so when you bring
it to a foreign environment you have to
acclimate it you have to acclimate it
and that's another big part of it um you
know it may hurt right away when it when
it hits uh the australian climate and
and that's to be expected with cannabis
so acclimation's a big thing and a lot
of people don't understand that part of
it
yeah definitely seems like a very valid
point
so a while back we had a breeder steve
on the show it was a really good episode
in my opinion he discussed this idea of
how when he was looking to find keeper
females to breed with he would grow them
outside like two or three times and just
be culling the females away until he's
left with like the best ones and then he
would take him indoors and then do the
same thing again and so at the end of it
all he'd have like this female that
performed well outside perform well
indoors all ticks all the boxes
and as a result a lot of people make the
comment that like yeah he's some of his
strains you'd run him outside and people
wouldn't be able to tell whether it was
indoor or outdoor wheat and that that
seems to make a lot of sense to me do
you think that there might be a push to
kind of do that type of more extensive
pheno hunting and breeding going forward
for a lot of breeders um i think it's a
smart idea breeder steve's obviously a
legend in the community and shout out to
kootenay i see mag his original breeding
partner [ __ ] dude is so cool so cool
um
yeah you know one of my favorite strains
is the blue satellite blue satellite
number one i think that's a a very
special special breeding project um that
they did and i think steve hat he's he's
and kootenay for that for that matter
are were well ahead of their times in
doing all that kind of stuff i think
it's the smart idea
me i'm not as i'm not as geared towards
outdoor growing so i probably won't do
that um
my all my lines are tested and run
indoors by me and i don't have outdoor
space so i don't know that i'll be doing
that maybe in the future i'll get bigger
spaces and whatnot and do it but until
then but i think it's a great idea
because there is that outdoor seed
demand
all over the world
of course so
just to change topics for a minute
just uh
i'm always interested in hype strains
i'm always interested in what's ahead of
the curve not because i get super caught
up in the hype strains like you're not
going to see me cruising around in a
skittles t-shirt but at this
but at the same time like i i find it
very interesting you know it's like uh
like markets and the way they behave
it's it's really interesting to me so
basically here's the question
gmo's had its run it's done well then we
moved on to max next what's next
unfortunately the wave has been cheese
that i've been seeing that people are
asking most about in my live feed i have
a um
it's got an okay following you know like
it's it's it's small but it's building
um but i do get a lot of questions from
a lot of people and the cheese has been
the one that's like no please don't
bring that [ __ ] back please i mean it's
it's okay uk guys love it but for a
while everything was [ __ ] cheese
everything like and and i've already
seen that happen and i did never thought
i'd be around for the resurgence of
cheese i thought it would be at least 20
years but that shit's coming back
and in full form um
definitely that's one of them um
i think there's going to be a resurgence
with stuff like the nl5 haze you know i
mean i like i was talking about earlier
with you uh before the show nl5 haze
seems to be peaking people's interest
that was the most uh
grown strain in the 90s was nl5 hayes
yeah most certainly and i mean you know
our most recent guest ak bean brands
actually no sorry second most recent
karma was on yeah you know he spoke
about that tkno5 haze and a lot of
people's ears perked up to that have you
heard much about that one at all
um yeah uh there's been there's been
some interesting thoughts on that tknl5
haze um
i am a big fan of ak bean brains he just
sent me you know the rest of the catalog
some of his blueberry work i'm running
his uh blueberry cut which is very very
interesting it reminds me a lot of blue
dream in the sense of the smells that
are coming out of it minus the
trapinoline not as much of the menthol
but it's like a sour blueberry
it's weird it's really good it has some
autoflowering traits in it which i i've
been able to kind of push back but i'm
not sure how it's going to breed in the
future with it
he's a very very cool [ __ ] dude
though
yeah definitely he's certainly a very
genuine guy and i just wanted to say
before i forget you're being very humble
about your live streams i think they're
phenomenal and people should get in on
them whenever they can i certainly try
to um
with that being said
i wanted to bring it up before i forgot
i mentioned mac a second ago
let's talk about
caps colombian give me the low down
so there before i talk about is
colombian um one of the things that moon
had had killed was his uh colombian
cross to neville's haze
and i you know it was clearly labeled on
the plants i had a bunch of them
sent them over when i got it back in the
bag of liquid it was labeled caps
colonial so all of me and my friends all
refer to it as caps colonial from now on
because it was such a joke that they
couldn't even
keep the name straight on what [ __ ] was
um the colombian you know
i like cap and again very nice guy
i get along with him i like a lot of
points he makes about our industry
the mac one cut is very very good it's
not great for taking pollen but for
smoke people love it and it's it's very
resinous i think the reason it can't
take pollen is because it's so resinous
and it puts so much of its um energy
into building resin
that and and yield that it doesn't focus
at all on pistola production it's a
really weird thing but um yeah it
doesn't take pollen at all i found that
myself um as far as the colombian in it
he's he specifically said they were the
colombian was from seeds that he got
while he was in colombia
he also said it was a nine week strain
which
most people like myself that have grown
a lot in a lot a lot of heirloom
colombian lines they're usually you know
21 plus weeks sometimes sometimes
they're as low as 14 if it's a worked
american line version of it um i've seen
it down as low as 11 with the uh
farmer's choice colombian which was a
project across the boards in the um
early 2000s um
with that said i don't think it's
colombian in it in my opinion i think
it's uh super lemon haze to be honest
with you but he says that's not the case
and you know he has more experience with
it obviously obviously than i
so you've always got to take that into
account um and it may not be that the
actual cut has super lemon haze in it
but the seed line everybody is pulling
super lemon haze finos out of the the
max seeds um
you're not seeing a lot of keepers come
out of the max seeds that were released
and there were a lot sold
yeah so that's that's my next exact
question do you feel like it's the case
that because the mac one cutting is so
good that people compare their keeper
from the packs of seeds and go it's just
not as good and so we don't see keepers
because of that or do you think that it
was just like a fluke the mac one
cutting and the seed stock itself is not
as good it's not a representation of the
mach one cutting per se
i think that seeds are probably
a hybridized form of that
of the line that that cutting came from
and whatever he hybridized with it super
eliminates um it you know it could be
why it's coming out so [ __ ] because
super lemon haze is it's not necessarily
[ __ ] but it's it's it's not what people
are necessarily looking for when they go
by max seeds per se
yeah certainly certainly so
on that same topic how do you feel about
uh late last year we saw those 100
eighths of mac from big al and more
importantly how do you feel about cap's
response to that situation do you feel
like a breeder has the right to try to
impose some sort of structure or
business structure around their strains
once you let it cut out dude if you try
doing that [ __ ] you're gonna catch
backlash it just is what it is um people
have again
something's only worth what people are
willing to pay for it if people are
willing to pay for it that's what it's
worth and if that worked for that dude
big day out then that's fine you know um
that's how it works uh
cap's new to that aspect of it and and i
understand he wants to protect his
breeding rights and protect the plant
that he
so
hardly worked on um
that
you know it's it's his first reaction to
say you can't do you can or can't do
this with it you can or can't do that
with it and that's cool if people you
know respect that and want to respect
his wishes but they're always going to
be the outliers that don't respect his
wishes at all and trying to hold them to
a standard in a black market is is not
going to happen
this is the black market man you can't
do that [ __ ] and granted there is a
legal market to speak of but
i don't know much about that [ __ ]
we don't take kindly to those folks
around here
yeah so i mean it's interesting you
raised the point like the idea of
middlemen you know and i had a chat to
al and he seemed like a really
reasonable guy and he mentioned how you
know like he's been growing for years
and he doesn't really grow so much
anymore he's like a middle man now and
it raised this idea to me because it's
like i mean burn is kind of the same
thing right like you know he's not
really a grower but um
you know i just wonder how the scene is
going to evolve where we've now got you
know like these exclusive hype men
yeah um
you know with uh with the generation
that i'm from we didn't really have that
breeders either hyped their own strains
or the strains hyped themselves you know
it was one or the other and usually the
people that were hyping their own [ __ ]
if it turned out to be [ __ ] you were
tossed from the community or you were
made to look like a jackass and no one
talk to you swerve for example total
jackass and uh constantly posting on
instagram that he gets no respect but
that's why he gets no respect because he
acted like that he was he was trying to
be his own hype man he was he was
not necessarily moral with how he
treated people and dealt with people um
and that was a a really good example of
of how that was dealt with in the old
days now with the modern age
younger people associate weed with
rappers rappers are always rapping about
weed they're the perfect
middleman hype man for this generation
um
and in trying to educate them is really
hard we saw that with seth rogen not too
long ago there was a lot of pushback
with him
he came out with house plant and uh
and started calling like chem 91 house
plant sativa which was just on so many
levels insulting to so many people um
not not only was it spelled weird it was
not supposed to be a sativa in the first
place um
all kinds of [ __ ] with that but he has a
massive pull from the entertainment
community and people look up to him as a
a comedian who smokes a lot of weed and
as a famous person he must know good
weed that's that's where it goes um
again but he's not a grower he's not a
breeder he's a glorified hype man and
it's going to be interesting to see how
that direction goes if it changes if
people choose to educate themselves or
if they just buy into the hype and
that's where it goes and and it's ruined
for good
yeah of course i mean it was just
earlier i think today maybe yesterday
that uh shibinsky made a post about how
there was like a ride up in i think it
was an la magazine and it and it used as
like it it referenced the amount of
times he had been name dropped in rap
songs
as like as like a metric for how popular
he was
and
on the one hand you're kind of like okay
it's undeniable things are becoming more
accepted and mainstream but at the same
time i just got such a weird feeling
about it it was like like how is that a
metric for anything
yeah it's really not but he's not
he's not uh someone that's in any kind
of circle of real growers and real
breeders um so maybe that's his personal
metric for success i mean he's always
about the followers how many followers
you get and [ __ ] and then you'll see you
know people who are breeders that are
private
and there's a reason for that because we
want our followers to equate to real
real world sales we care about that um
it's just a different world man like
where where social media is is a base
level for a lot of people's way of
looking at who's successful and the fact
that you could buy followers
is is just a another
another tricky tool in all of that um
shirbinski he is obviously the sherb is
in a lot of people's strains i've worked
with it um he's a very nice guy himself
so i i don't want to say anything
terrible about the guy he is a nice guy
he's one of the few people from that
that cookie fam uh
place uh that group um that that is
tolerable but there are some some
cringe-worthy stuff that is said by him
too
yeah okay i feel you on that and i mean
i definitely would love to say as well
please come on the show shibinsky you
know um but uh but at the same time i
wonder where he's going to go next i
wonder where cookie fam is going to go
next because it was like you know
sherbet cross to cookies makes gelato
and now gelato cross some other cookies
makes moki or however you want to say it
biscotti it's like where do where do we
go from here is it just perpetually
cookies into cookies into cookies or
will there ever be like some creative
outcrossing i wonder
uh i don't think we're gonna see
anything creative come from any of those
guys or that crew
all we're seeing is muddled cookies to
cookies to cookies to cookies done 90
different ways and slapped with a bunch
of
names of [ __ ] you could buy at starbucks
or somewhere else you know it's not very
creative
it's a lot of incestuous breeding that's
going to lead to a lot of inbred
depression and shitty plants eventually
and people's rooms are stuck with this
[ __ ] they're not growing anything else
because it's what the the modern market
wants and eventually they'll find that's
all that they have
that's all they have access to
and there's nothing left for them and
that's going to be a sad day for them
because that's that's that's how weed
gets ruined
so do you think these guys have any of
these original seeds left that could
potentially bring to life something new
because i mean for me i always see a pie
guy what's his name powers up
yeah lay off the caps lock homie that's
what i'd say to him
but he's always posting like some new
strains about to drop and nothing ever
drops so it's like what's the deal with
that
he's just trying to
keep himself relevant he doesn't have
anything to offer in fact he was the one
that said breeding is for [ __ ] nerds
and he ain't no nerd that's the guy who
made the quote dude so the fact that
he's talking about dropping strains and
[ __ ] you can't have it both ways you
can't call yourself a breeder and then
say breeders are [ __ ] nerds you know
um implying that you're so street that
you can't breed um
yeah i i yeah i don't know man all i see
is bad from all that um with that said
you know like i said i it was eight nine
years ago when i was working with
cookies um i see new companies coming
out and using cookies still
um
it's time to it's time to expand it's
time to move on you know like that's the
way i feel maybe the market doesn't feel
that way though and and that's why it
hasn't moved on you know people are
still
new to cookies every day there's new
smokers reading high times cookies is in
there that's their first experience with
something that frosty that [ __ ]
pretty that dense and uh so yeah i don't
know how long it's gonna stay around i
would like to see a change from it but
it but i think there are unique things
you can do with cookies um
there's unique ways to take cookies uh
the chocolate thai cookies that i did i
was really stoked about um that was on
um who was it be real smoked some on his
show
and
he he expected it to be like a a and uh
hit him like an afghani type line where
he was waiting for it just to hit him
right away you know and over time you
got to see him turn into a giggly a
giggly soul you know through it you know
it's cool to watch but there's there's
there are interesting ways to take
cookies lines and some of us do that
but i think the whole cookies into
cookies hybrid into another cookies the
gelatos the sherbs the
it's just incestuous breeding leading to
inbreeding
depression of course
so this one's maybe a bit of an extended
one so my apologies but one thing i
noticed most recently when i was in the
states was that there's just this
undeniable consumer
appetite for cookies and it became most
clear to me when i was at like this kind
of farmer's swap meet and there was a
jar of uh
that
head lumper's headband grown by um mr
bob hemphill growing phenomenally thank
you i was smoking out the whole trip and
uh my homie was telling me yeah like
people are only gonna pay like you know
like a thousand a pound for this type of
thing and um then next to it he has a
jar of wedding cake had no terps to it i
think it was like you know i mean it was
grown to look nice but it didn't have
you know like what you would expect of
really high quality wheat yeah it looked
the part but it didn't fit it and he's
like yeah people will also pay a
thousand for this and i'm like how does
that work like anyone with a nose would
be able to discern that the headband is
way better and he just looks at me and
he's like yeah but people have smelt
that nose before
and i was just like really like that's
[ __ ] all this is and so like how can
we as a community
get the general public to acknowledge
that like yeah wedding cakes well and
good but you know what lumpus headbands
is a [ __ ] bomb
i think it's just through education and
and i you know i i've been a very big
pessimist that people want to be
educated i don't think they do i and and
my whole career i firmly believe that
but then i started getting my live feed
going and i see how many people are
coming in now to learn and the only
reason people come to to my life eat is
because they want to learn about
breeding they want to learn about
strains i think that's what what's been
established as a place people can come
actually ask questions about breeding
and actual breeding and learn about
strains as opposed to just sitting there
watching me dab because i'm not into
that you know like i i see a lot of
breeders come on do live feeds and all
they do is dab and [ __ ]
i i'm not into that that's not that's
not what i'm about you know we all smoke
i'm not impressing anyone by [ __ ]
hitting the bong or dabbing you know so
i want to be able to answer real
questions and the fact that it's getting
more and more popular every day blows my
[ __ ] mind and it shows i'm not
exactly right people were wanting to be
educated they just didn't have anywhere
to go get this education um then again
i'm not the all-knowing narrator so i
want more breeders to do what i'm doing
i want more people that are um
that have a big platform in the breeding
community
starting to do live feeds answering
breeding questions and i think it will
also show people the guys that don't
they're not doing it because they have
no [ __ ] real experience or education
in any of this and they're just pulling
the wall over your eyes so i implore all
the breeders to do that um duke will do
it you know he comes on talks um
you know karma's done it you know
karma's come on with me and talked bodhi
will talk to people about breeding caleb
will talk to people about breeding but
there's very few people who will and i
think that speaks volumes but people
want this education let's give it to him
the more people that are educated the
more breeders doing this like it doesn't
scare me for other breeders to do live
feeds i think the more people being
educated by the larger amount of us the
better for all of us the better for
breeding the better for cannabis the
more education that goes out there
and so how do you feel about the advent
of kind of like
people who will say go live with me bro
let's settle this beef right now let's
do it live you know it seems almost like
reminiscent of like the the wwf you've
been calling for for so long
well you know uh one of my friends does
does the whole life with me bro thing
and um it's a part of his his character
and i love seeing characters in this
business i think it keeps it
interesting i think it keeps it creative
you know like people always looked at me
like the villain for a long time and i i
at first i was kind of
i didn't love it you know it's like i
don't feel like i'm a total villain but
as i embraced it i started [ __ ]
loving it dude you know and and people
look to me to be this villainous type
character when they get to know me they
see that maybe that's not the case but i
think characters make make for
interesting tales and this is our our
tale of breeding this is our era this is
our tale
so inevitably when are we gonna see the
real deal weed wrestling federation
where breeders settle beefs in the ring
i've been dying for that dude i have
been dying
dying to do that um every time i go to
these these events you know like people
look at me and i'm short and fat like i
think they think that i'm gonna
not be the person that i am
that i that i am on the live feed or and
i'm i'm unfortunately for them i am
every bit the same person that i pre
that i that i profess to be um
yeah
like i you know
i've learned that people in our
community that like to act tough and
talk tough um you saw you saw
yourself at the cup you were right there
with me as one little [ __ ] golden
coast hunkered down in a corner after he
got [ __ ] treated like a little [ __ ]
you know i couldn't punch him because he
was gonna sue me but it is what it is
and that's what usually happens if the
last one joint breath came up to the
table acted like he was gonna get tough
skunk tech was right in front of me um
it was a pretty cute little little dance
we did i took all the weapons out of my
pockets laid them on the table so he
knew that there were no [ __ ] weapons
in my pockets i said bring it
[ __ ] scurried away so i don't
know if we'll ever have this event
because so so many people are such
[ __ ] and so scared to get hit but i
think like we could we could sell
tickets to it we could donate that to
[ __ ] the money to good [ __ ]
uh funds you know like i think it would
be funny as [ __ ] i think it would
get rid of a lot of the animosity in our
community and you know i
i i i'm
pretty open to say what i feel about
people but at the same time i realize
that the the division in our community
sucks it does suck but at the same time
we have to get rid of the trash so
before we can
be united we have to divide and conquer
the [ __ ] the retards and the scam
artists
i love it man first first fight i'm
gonna be the matchmaker it's gonna be
your wrestling name is the trash man you
take out the trash that's right it's
gonna be it's gonna be the trash man
versus flat earth crew aka gate oh yes
oh yes i'm so damn well you know i don't
know if that one would be able to be
public it might get a little more bloody
than uh people would like
uh so since our last talk have you had
any interactions with the ggg crew
um not really dude i haven't had
interactions specifically with keyplay
who used to be a good friend of mine
many many years ago
um i gave him his start in breeding i
gave him his start uh as a company
giving him a big push got him on the
attitude got him in books
um gage green for all intents and
purposes would not be where it's at
without that big [ __ ] push that they
got for me and i'll say that until the
day i die and he knows that that's the
truth um
with that said he i he won't speak to me
last time we spoke was many many years
ago and that's when he tried shaking me
down telling me people know we're
friends and they'll believe anything i
say about you give me money and give me
strains um that's who that dude is
that's who he is at his base um that
that one kid jason fong or michael
whatever he calls himself now they ate
the little scrawny asian brat um he
wasn't around during all this he was not
around he had nothing to do with
anything i don't really know much about
him but he seems to be the one talking
the most [ __ ] about me and he's not
it's not ideal for him to do that
because he's he's all of 40 pounds
soaking wet um
yeah i don't have much interaction with
them other than seeing like every once
in a while they'll post like this seed
list where things are like four thousand
five thousand dollars and uh talking
about flat earth and and just weird [ __ ]
like that dinosaurs never existing
um yeah i try to have as little
interaction with those idiots as much as
possible but when i'm at these events i
go around looking for them just in case
yeah i mean i i would i would love for
them to tell their story so uh you know
that would be an interesting one to hear
but something i got to bring up you know
to be fair i like i like to you know try
to be fair where i can so i'd love to
know do you agree with this kind of
observation in that i i'm of the opinion
that they kind of got screwed with mendo
breath you know like at the end of the
day i think it's a killer strain i
really like it i've got some hybrids of
it i think they're good plants but it
seems like everyone picked up that work
and ran with it except for them and i
wonder
did was that them just missing the boat
on their own strain like they rarely get
a mention in the genesis of it or even
just in the context and i can't help but
feel like they kind of got the short end
of the stick in regards to a strain they
made or do you see it a little
differently
i see a little differently because i had
already made a strain similar to that
using the og kb uh before the mendo
breath was out so it was already out
there people were using that the 26
cookies um it didn't catch it did not
catch on like their mendo breath did
that's for god damn sure because mental
breath is literally everywhere i think
they dropped the ball on it i think they
were too focused on the negative aspects
and fighting with people as opposed to
putting their nose to the grindstone and
making it making it their legacy you
know it was one of the few strains that
wasn't from jojo wasn't from me wasn't
from medic seed collection wasn't from
lumpa that they weren't renaming and
weren't doing that [ __ ] it was something
that they actually made and uh yeah they
missed the boat on it and
that's their own fault because they were
just so focused on fighting with
everyone about it and not just that they
were fighting with other people about
flat earth they were fighting with
people about [ __ ] that had nothing to do
with anything um
i think
i think the reason people don't mention
it is because of all their bad energy
attached to it nobody wants to to bring
their name up and [ __ ] because it just
brings so many bad vibes
yeah i'd have to agree for a crew that
goes around espousing that they're all
about good vibes they seem to put out a
lot of negative vibes themselves yeah
yeah and and that's that's the irony of
it all man and that happens a lot you
know uh people people pull the hippy
dippy [ __ ] to try to uh because they
know that catches on in the cannon
community a lot of people are into that
you know peace and love stuff but they
don't really espouse it you know and
then you see guys like bodhi that really
do that are absolutely you know all
about the earth and and paying attention
to the energy of everything and and they
live their life that way and and it
shows the the amount of love that he
gets and the amount of love that they
don't get
yeah okay so let's keep getting a bit
more edgy how do you feel about breeders
who espouse the random [ __ ] we hear
like from gage green you know like i
mean i read a post the other day from uh
uh feng shen however you say his name uh
jason
please come on the show
yeah he's coming on after this
yeah so i i read a post says talking
about like if you eat berries and [ __ ]
you'll purify your lymphatic system and
it can cure cancer or there's like caps
famous chemtrails post how do you feel
when people kind of take a foot off the
edge with some of these claims
uh you know i mean
being that they claim to be breeders
they should be
science-driven and if you're
science-driven you know that you know
you have to go through trials you have
to have things be able to be repeatable
you have to you know i mean like there's
a there's a method a scientific method
for a reason and if they are breeders if
they are scientists they would probably
think a little bit more before they
speak and and it just shows like
it shows their competency level it shows
all that [ __ ] with that said
you know i myself
have been called a conspiracy theorist
by philos and many other people and in a
sense you know i've studied a lot of
that stuff but i've also studied it
because i like to know before i speak on
things and i mean i have my own views on
[ __ ] aliens and ufos and [ __ ] but
you know i don't think it really has
much to do with breeding
yeah of course of course so i mean final
question on our friend's gauge um you
know recently they put a post up saying
that they had received an offer in the
past for 15 million dollars for their
company and they said
they turned it down because ggg is worth
more than that
you want to uh give your interpretation
of that situation
those broke [ __ ] didn't get no
15 million offer they would have sucked
the dick of [ __ ] whoever was giving
it to him i don't buy it i don't buy it
at all nobody's giving them a 15 million
dollar offer like from from the way
they're charging for their strains dude
and how many times they've been hit for
doing illegal [ __ ] you know not just uh
not just growing weed but other [ __ ] you
know that they get involved with meth
[ __ ] like that it's uh yeah
you know i think they would have sold
out right away they don't give a [ __ ]
about this community if someone offered
him 15 million they would have done
anything for it so i don't buy that [ __ ]
at all but it makes a nice story it's
it's it's trying to convince people of
their value that doesn't exist there is
that i mean people do that all the time
yeah okay so i mean you know to kind of
change to a slightly different topic
given that there is this prevalence for
people to kind of be more compassionate
centric within our community you know
like there's not a lot of purely
businessmen within our scene at least
not ones that are embraced how do you
feel like breeders are going to be able
to survive moving forward given the
advent of what seems like an inevitable
commercialization and like a big ag
takeover of things
i'm scared
i'm scared um but those of us who who
thrived in the black market long before
all this in the early forum days and
whatnot that's how we made our name you
know getting on the forums passing stuff
out um selling stuff through word of
mouth um we'll be fine man this is how
we've always rolled but with the big ad
takeover they may take over recreational
and [ __ ] but people eventually realize
like there's always going to be a demand
for quality weed and you're not going to
get that from walmart weed you know what
i mean
yeah of course i mean and it raises
another point i had about you know uh
vape pens they're so on the rise a lot
of people will hate on them but a lot of
people will also point out that they are
kind of like a stepping stone between
the the connoisseur community and just
the casual enthusiast how do you feel
about the old [ __ ] sticks
the whole [ __ ] sticks yeah um
i don't know man i vape uh nicotine i
don't you know so i i guess i'm kind of
involved in in that kind of [ __ ] but
that's just because i think cigarettes
are stinky and i don't want to smoke
them however with cannabis um yeah
there's a lot of people that will do
that and never smoke a joint because
they still have that fear of associating
with something like that so there's
always going to be a demand for it and i
think eventually
there it will be a bigger demand for it
worldwide you know the the younger
community is going to keep going that
direction and that's fine but there will
always be a connoisseur community and
those that that breed connoisseur seeds
they're going to have to fight for those
positions and the people that are
[ __ ] not really good at breeding and
and just preyed upon people's you know
like the average high times reader
they're uh they're gonna fall down in
that market you know what i mean there's
only gonna be a few people making that
market and they're definitely not going
to be anything in the connoisseur market
those are the kind of people that are
going to fall off and not be around but
like people like me people like bodhi
people like csi we're going to be around
doing this long after the money's gone
long after you know the interest is
there this is what we do this is who we
are you know
yeah of course so around that same
debate of the vape pens we have this
like a sub debate around whether the
introduction of cannabis-derived
terpenes to these carts is like a good
or a bad thing and then a further
sub-debate of like well are those
terpenes cannabis derived are they
derived from other sources like natural
sources so to speak do you have much of
an opinion on this and i guess the very
specific question is do you feel like
externally added terpenes are kind of
like detrimental to a product or like
kind of reduce it from what it could be
i think scientifically finding out that
cannabis derived terpenes are indeed
different than like fruit derived
terpenes or from other places
originally initially they said that a
terpene is a terpene is a terpene right
um limonene is limiting is limiting no
matter where it comes from but that's
not they're finding out that's not
necessarily the case um the entourage
effect is very real a lot of these hot
dog carts uh the vape carts hot dog
water parts whatever they're called um
isn't that i think that's the nickname
yeah i love it
uh
you know like you smoke them and you'll
get the same high that you would get
from say poorly extracted bho to where
everything is stripped all the terpenes
are stripped you get the same height and
to me it's kind of speedy it's bland
it's not it's not really super enjoyable
the entourage effect is a real thing you
need cannabis derived terpenes whether
and i don't know that whether extracting
it from cannabis and then re-adding it
if there's something that is missing um
i don't i don't know i can't speak to
that i've never really
i don't think a lot of these people that
are claiming that they have cannabis
derived terpenes are really going that
route because it's cheaper to get um you
know fruit extracted terpenes than it is
from cannabis extracted terpenes i think
most people are going the easier route
in saying it's cannabis extracted
because there's no way to really prove
that you know what i mean so i think
there's a lot of shortcuts being taken
and that's just going to happen that's
the nature of business and they're going
to try to take advantage of people at
every step to save a buck
of course
so how do you feel about the idea of
some of the more well-known and let's
just say accepted breeders within our
community
doing work for big ag because i have a
feeling it's inevitable where someone's
like oh i'm creating a hybrid that's
going to be planted in fields and it's
going to be
you know just harvested by big combines
all over the place
do you feel like that would be a
negative thing or it's kind of like hey
we may as well meet him in the middle if
it's going to happen
oh that's such a hard one dude like i've
been watching some of my friends that i
respect slowly drift over to the
corporate world and and some of these
people are people that are that have
been through the really big hardships of
getting popped watching their family get
thrown on the floor by dea agents you
know and and uh back during the really
illegal days watching their you know
watching their family go through that
and then finally having an avenue to not
have to worry about that again i get the
want for that um with that said it's a
personal decision and it's definitely
not for me not [ __ ] for me no no
amount of money is worth [ __ ] selling
all my friends down and really that's
what's going to happen
you may think it's only affecting you
it's only one person but if everybody
starts making those moves it's going to
start taking out a lot of your friends
it's going to make a lot of your friends
lives a lot harder um
that that that's exactly what's going on
with philos as we've watched it which is
another hot button topic
yeah okay
so i mean just to kind of jump off the
old doom and gloom big ag situation
earlier on you mentioned when we were
talking about the uh the the skunk spray
afghani seeds that they were from like
the late 80s early 90s i think you said
from memory do you have any other stock
left from back in that time frame that
you're kind of itching to get into
i have a bunch of stuff from that
individual bite me um he gave me so many
like i think 13 or 14 different things
only three or four were labeled the rest
are supposed to be you know colombian
golds colombian blacks colombian reds
colombian rainbows and then other
nepalese different things that were
coming down the pipe in florida during
that era um and i have stuff from that
i've saved from my own collection that
i've gotten over the years but a lot of
those seeds are really hard to pop so
it's going to take tissue culture
popping and
that in itself has become another
problem there's a lot of scammers in
that world too
they realize that there's money to be
made there they realize that you know
some breeders like me i'm not on top of
tissue culture i i don't know that i
don't know all the ins and outs of it so
it's really easy to take advantage of
people and uh
yeah and you know i hope that you know
more people step forward finest has been
really kind to me um
and there's other people mike hydro is
doing [ __ ] great work with jungle
boys and tissue culture stuff
nice nice i mean you just mentioned
finest i'd heard from some people that
they got caught with their pants down at
the emerald cup in terms of like some of
the cuts they were selling were like had
issues with them have you heard anything
about that
ah no um
you know with tissue culture comes an
issue
that you have to use certain hormones in
order to
make them go through that process and
some of those cuts aren't necessarily
the best for cropping let's say you buy
a thousand cuts just to bloom out right
away you know from that have been tissue
culture they've been treated with so
many hormones and it takes x amount of
months for that to happen to get it out
of its system before you can bloom it
and i think that's some of the issues
they're running into i know some people
said pm and stuff like that at the cup
and
you know when you bring
clean clones very sterile clones into an
environment where there's a bunch of
growers walking around from their rooms
you're gonna get [ __ ] i don't even know
how people can sell clones at events
like that and not worry about that
yeah definitely feels like a good choice
to maybe quarantine those bad boys off
initially
yeah oh yeah yeah treat them with some
micronized sulfur put them in a corner
for a while treat them again
figure it out before you bring them in
the room
of course of course so given so many of
your strains have been used by other
breeders to kind of make new lines and
whatnot have you ever found yourself in
a situation where you made a strain you
released it everything's all good and
then you kind of forgot about it and
then someone's used it and they've made
like a new hybrid and it's kind of like
really got some jazz to it and you're
like damn maybe i need to go back and
pull out those seeds again like maybe i
kind of pulled the plug on that a little
early in terms of i should have explored
that one a bit more
uh you know not really i i like when
people do that and they find their own
special [ __ ] in it and they they
hybridize it and find something that
they love in it and at that point i'm
usually my mindset is wow i'm glad they
found something special in it i hope
they take it a new direction and that's
that i've left it if i've left it behind
then i've left it behind that's that
it's very rare that i pick up an old
strain and i'm like wow there was a lot
more in that i should have looked for
it's very rare that that happens because
i i do good i do good pops of my stuff
to go through enough phenos to see it
all
and
sometimes what they find that they love
and that other people love isn't what i
love so yeah um i
and also i look at everybody who buys my
seeds like they're investing in my
company and i they're buying rights to
use those lines as they see fit and you
know they have the option to
reproduce them if they want it's not
necessarily going to get the best
reaction if they're like reproducing it
to undercut me on price and you know
keeping the same name and all that [ __ ]
because uh it may not be a good
representation of where i wanted the
line to go but um
you know it's all part of the game it's
all a part of it and and i i think the
highest honor is someone carrying on a
strain and using it and finding
something special in it that they love
yeah of course
would you ever consider remaking one of
your previous strains that you maybe
were kind of thinking was just going to
be a one-off but you were like hey this
is actually something special
strawberry switchblade was one of those
um it was one that i made as a one-off
usually i have a direction uh and a goal
with everything that i put in a room
that i'm that i'm using um i don't put
anything in there usually for you know
just because there's space throw it in
there for shits and gigs
but in that case that is the one time
when i did that and it became something
that people really truly loved and i
went back worked that line um
yeah that was that was an anomaly for
sure
so how would you describe your general
approach to new projects do you just
kind of everything just kind of comes
organically and just like you know you
do it yourself or do you have like more
of like a methodical like a whiteboard
like i'm kind of mapping things out how
do you approach it
dude i i have a a
brain where everything's just chaos so i
don't have any white boards i don't have
any any
any like note pads anywhere my chick's
laughing because she knows how chaotic i
am um
yeah it's
everything is just kind of off the cuff
you know like i see what i have
sometimes i'll hit uh a mental block and
i don't do anything for a year because i
just don't have any creative juices
flowing nothing's nothing's coming from
it and i don't like to make things just
to make things you know
yeah certainly i mean i think there's
probably a few breeders who have been
guilty of putting out some stuff that
fits that criteria
oh yeah i've had a lot of people message
me asking me about
why top dog as a breeder is still so
popular
despite the fact like a lot of the
crosses have produced like less than
ideal results
and like why why does he have such a die
hard fandom you know like i totally
respect everything jj's done for the
scene and a lot of money mike's work is
really well received but it seems like
some of you know the newest stuff put
out by jj is a bit hit and miss maybe
more of a miss
you know jj's been around a long time um
it's i think a lot of us old guys
including myself it's it's a struggle to
stay relevant you know um we realize
that
as much as we want to really you know
work lines hard um
take several years to work a line
properly and release it
that's not what the
the community and the seed buying public
really demands they want something new
shiny in front of their face all the
time
so it's it's it's a struggle to stay
relevant it's a struggle to keep your
name
out there and that always runs the risk
of releasing something that is subpar
that comes back and affects your legacy
jj is very fortunate that he made star
dog um he has the the i-95 um kmd kmdi95
has been a very popular one um
i've worked with this white dog which i
think is totally underrated his ddnl
lines his dnl releases are totally
underrated
but um yeah i think it's just like a lot
of us old guys are trying to find
a way to stay relevant in a time where
in a time of cookies and wedding cake
you know in a time of all that [ __ ] that
has no interest to us at all so trying
to to meld that into breeding that we do
um it's hard it's hard it's it's a hard
world it's a hard brutal world um you
know he had the popularity of being at
high times a bunch getting all these
kinds of uh
nods and stuff from high time saying you
know best breeder of this year best
breeder of that year and a lot of that
was real man he was he was really making
his mark on the world but with that
comes a demand from the the seed buying
public and new customers to on to want
new why aren't you using the wedding
cakes why aren't you using the cookies
why aren't you using this why why am i
having to wait for this um so yeah it's
it's hard to temper those two things and
and we're all finding our our ways of of
working through it and some you know
i've hit speed bumps i'm sure he has and
and you know i put out stuff some people
don't like and it is a personal
perspective on it i think also
uh jj has a lot of newer growers that
buy his stuff that maybe aren't the best
growers too and that's why you're not
seeing um
a majority of the stuff come out as good
it's because
his his clientele has changed before it
was a lot of breeders buying his stuff
now it's a lot of uh modern growers um
and and you know jj will even admit
sometimes he reacts to things a little
uh
um i'm trying to think of the word for
it um
he reacts pretty quickly to stuff and i
have that same issue so i ca it's not
like i'm throwing him under the bus for
reacting [ __ ] like kind of hot-headedly
um he's a passionate man so
when people talk [ __ ] about what he's
doing he's passionate about it and gives
it back to him and and and of course
with that comes backlash people don't
like being talked to you like that and
i've had that same problem myself
yeah i mean totally i i agree with you
you know i grew out his skunk og and i
found a keeper in there no worries but
the overwhelming feedback i get is that
people tend to be a little less than
thrilled with some of the results they
find and so i guess in a
in a sense a lot of people point to this
factor of how he doesn't keep males he
uses like a new male every time
so people will often reference how like
the first star dog release was like this
[ __ ] it was what you wanted and then
subsequent ones have not been as good do
you feel like overall this is a good
strategy or it might be actually working
against the people employing it
um you know i don't keep a lot of i try
to keep males but i lost a lot during
the moon thing i've lost some when i
moved from san diego back to bakerfield
um
i don't keep a lot of males around long
i i do one good run with them i'll keep
them around just in case as best i can
but if i don't i don't but i also take
the time to select them which is really
important um you want to you want to run
them you you don't know if the mail is
good or not until you run the progeny
and that's just a fact you know
that said i don't
like to
let's say i have bubble gum cookies and
i use uh whatever mail for it and i then
want to make bubble gum cookies because
it has a
awesome reception and then
put out the same name i you know i
always have to denote it with a v2 if
i'm using a different male for that run
or you know whatever so people can
differentiate between the two and don't
think they're getting the same first
product
or um
if it's a filial generation like an f2
or f3 or f4 of whatever i'm doing i like
to denote that so they know they're not
getting the f1 and not going to see the
same exact results that the f1 got
i think it's important to clarify that
kind of stuff
yeah of course and i mean i guess a
final little kind of question i wanted
to tease out based around this is i'd
heard a while back and admittedly i
should probably just message high and
lonesome and find out but i'd heard that
maybe some people from that whole new
york crew had politely asked him
lonesome to you know quit with these
awesome tres dog hybrids because
you know like the appalachia like the
dog waltz they were phenomenal hybrids
and i guess the idea was like
you know maybe he was doing a better job
than they were um how would you feel
about that idea that you know maybe they
politely asked him to stop breeding with
that work
um
i know a little bit of the inside on
that i don't know what hayan lonesome
would want me to disclose because he's
so [ __ ] laid back he didn't give a
[ __ ] about anything drama-wise but i do
know that um
he was asked
to work with a certain company that you
i mean that we just recently mentioned
and he wasn't really into it just
because he's a he's kind of a lobo he's
a lone wolf you know um
and that might be why
they then kind of twisted the narrative
to sound like they asked him to stop
it was more his choice to just kind of
walk away from everything he left
he just wasn't into it he and if you
noticed a lot of people thought dog
waltz was jj's work a lot of people
thought that for a long time and i don't
know that anyone ever took the time to
say no no that's not that's actually
high in lonesomes you know um and that's
that's disappointing over time but um
that dude is one of the coolest
[ __ ] i've ever met um he's a
legit old school dude old school
virginia dude um
yeah
really cool [ __ ] and and i think
i i have all the respect in the world
for him and the fact that he asked me to
continue the appalachia line for him
that was
what an honor you know that's [ __ ]
crazy and um i had the honor of going
and getting him back the uh the poodle
nuts cut of the dog waltz so yeah that's
that's one guy i really really respect i
don't know that they asked him to not
work that they might have felt like that
and that it was showing up uh some of
the work that was being released with
the trade dog and stuff like that but
yeah no i think i'm probably of the same
opinion actually i think it was probably
never expressed but they probably they
probably felt it but um oh yeah i will
admit you know in one of the very early
interviews i think i attributed dog
waltz to to mass g of all people so hey
you know i'm just as guilty as every one
of these things
yeah i don't know that that g did much
breeding
um lots of accidents happened i'm still
trying to get uh and you know match to
use one of my buddies dude like we've
been friends for a while and uh but i
still can't get the answer from him
about jesus when was it created seems
like a simple answer but i cannot get a
lot of answers out of that dude um
we can't get the answers about kim d and
why there's so many different chemd's
that all came sourced from him there's a
lot of a lot of questions that go around
and because he's my buddy i don't i
don't put the the screws to him too hard
about it he was a young dude when all
the chem stuff happened and i think
i think if people realized how young he
was when all that happened a lot of the
expectations that they have for how
stuff was handled would go away um he's
a super nice dude
yeah a hundred percent you know shout
out mass g and i always remind myself of
that you know like no matter what anyone
has to say about the story or the gaps
in it or whatever like dude was 17 when
he popped the seeds like [ __ ] me when i
was 17 i couldn't even keep a plan alive
let alone exactly let alone preserve it
for years so like so much credit to that
guy
yeah absolutely i i totally agree and
you know and then there's other things
like certain people that were involved
during that first transaction that hang
around and verify people's cuts for them
that really don't know [ __ ] about [ __ ]
when it comes to the chem but have
attached their name permanently to the
chem and i i can't tell you how many
people i've had coming to me saying oh
this person verified this cup for me and
no you know they're part of the early
chem fam so i'm pretty sure it's legit
you know and that same person handing
out cuts to [ __ ] like joint breath
and others that there's there's a lot of
frustrating stuff and a lot of a lot of
weird expectations a lot of weird
assumptions made with how the kim family
stuff operated in the early days and how
how attached these guys really were to
each other how much they interacted how
much they actually bred um and how much
were accidents and and
like i said gee was young man like i i
would love to hear the true tell of d
the chem d i would love to hear the true
tale of all of those and i don't know
that we'll ever hear that um and and
i think it's a shame because
i think it would be an interesting story
to hear the actual
facts of each d and how it came to be
what really happened with the sister
what was which was a sister s1 why was
that used as the d why was that passed
as the d
et cetera things like that
yeah i've always personally felt like uh
joe brand could probably fill some of
these holes in but unfortunately i've
been told by too many sources that you
just can't trust what he says
yeah he's off the rails and that's
unfortunate um that's real unfortunate
uh yeah
that sucks but it just is what it is
with that
yeah that's life i guess so to kind of
change things up a bit since the last
time we spoke um you're now vending
through some seed banks you know shout
out seeds here now and james bean
friends of both of us how did this come
about and how does it feel to now be
affiliated with two rather big seed
banks most notably seats here now
um
after the moon situation
during that time i i've always been
protective about who my merchant account
was because
it's really hard for breeders and seed
sellers to have a merchant account
that's something you have to guard with
your life but
i take chances on friends and and mooney
and his buddy uh i can't remember the
dude's name uh not really important but
he um they wanted to start a seed
company and because i trusted them he
had my mom's and was taking care of them
for me
supposedly i i told them who my merchant
account was and the second that i found
out my plants were dead i got reported
to my merchant account for selling seeds
um
so i lost that and i lost the ability to
accept credit cards and in this can in
this in this world if you can accept
credit cards it's a really hard road to
travel most people are these are impulse
buys um they'll make an order and won't
send the cash because it takes a lot of
effort and we're all a bunch of [ __ ]
stoners and that's the way it is so it
was really important to have that
also during that time i mean early on me
and james were not really necessarily
friends
i was very
judgmental of james because of who he
was associated with when he first came
into the business
but over the years i've watched james
work really hard to get to the point of
where he's at that dude [ __ ] hustles
non-stop nonstop and and over the years
i even though like we argue and [ __ ]
i've always had an appreciation for how
hard he's worked and and
if people work and pay their dues dude
who am i to [ __ ] judge him you know
um
so with that said when all that happened
me and james started talking and we had
talked about working together for a bit
but you know we just kind of
hemmed in hard he didn't quite trust me
because i've i've called him a [ __ ]
[ __ ] publicly plenty of times and i
didn't really trust him because i don't
trust seed banks like i've had a lot of
bad interactions in the old days with
european seed banks the attitude uh
the serious seeds are not serious i'm
sorry not serious seeds uh sensible
seeds different than the original
sensible seed bank sensible seeds they
scanned me out of you know 20 grand i
had trichome kings uh nyc kid aka th
underscore gobs that that piece of [ __ ]
who pretends he has asian fantasy i had
him scan me scan me out of [ __ ] tens
of thousands of dollars along with he
scammed the rev he scammed a lot of
people um so it's been a hard hard work
hard world trusting seed banks but um i
i eventually
tried it with james and it's been
working great it's been working awesome
he's been true to his word everything he
said he'd do he's done
um and then i also work with breeders
direct seed co who is a good friend of
mine we're kind of helping him get
established and
he's he's doing it right dude he's only
picking up breeders that
for the most part there may be a few
odds and ends of of people that aren't
really haven't been around a long time
but for the most part i mean he's got me
csi he's picking up hip sweet el jefe
like a lot of people like that that that
are that are older breeders and are
established and he's trying to do it
right
yeah for sure i mean i think uh yeah i
can echo the sentiments about ct now
they've always been really awesome in
regards to our relationship
um and james in general you're right man
i don't i don't think i know many if any
people who hustle harder than that guy
definitely no he's the king of the
hustle dude king of the hustle for sure
yeah
so i noticed um for a while
you know as i mentioned earlier i love
your feminizing spray that um there was
basically like some issues with like
payment gateways and stuff and so what i
was wondering is how hard is it to
operate a can of business giving like
the range of limitations that like
financial institutions place on us like
i mean you you must have patience beyond
words given that whole debacle
um i constantly have a worry in my gut
every morning that i'm going to wake up
with an email saying
you're no longer active with a merchant
account
because it's really really really hard
to get them um
yeah and now with hemp being legal
people are more open-minded to the seed
aspect of it but it hasn't always been
that way dude and and you know i get a
lot of requests from a lot of readers
asking me how the [ __ ] are you pulling
this off and you know like now after the
moon situation i don't say [ __ ] anymore
i know i can't trust anyone with my
merchant account [ __ ] um but it's hard
man it takes a lot of patience um things
will go down things will go wrong and uh
and frankly just accepting cash it is
not a working model for me there's about
a 10 follow through rate on on orders
and uh you know i've told other breeders
this that are big that go that route and
they've confirmed it 10 follow-through
rate on orders that means 90 of people
who order aren't going to pay
that's rough that is so rough it's
defeating you know like you see all
these orders come through you're stoked
maybe you're doing a big drop of
something really special 90 of those
orders of it are [ __ ] and so you
stop you you apportion this amount of
seeds for that and then all of a sudden
you know three weeks down the line you
have them to re have to resell a bunch
of them and people are calling you out
yeah you said you were only gonna make
so much well you've sewn it again you
know they don't understand the ins and
outs of the cash business
having a merchant account is everything
and and it's hard it's really hard
yeah so these same kind of financial
restrictions that we're talking about
were basically imposed on last year's
emerald cup which i think prior to the
most recent one was a really good event
but last year you know
it felt different you know there wasn't
the same energy in the air it just it
just wasn't the same event basically
how do you feel these events are going
to go down in the future and do you plan
to go to the next emerald cup
um
i i have
personal feelings about the people
behind emerald cup that put it on
um that make me not want to work with
them
i think i think they are the same kind
of guys
bringing [ __ ] like filos around
backing them up
and bringing scummy ceo types and saying
they're cool you know let's work with
them it's a big money event and it was
bound to happen um yeah last year was
not remotely the same feeling as the
first one the first one um i mean it's
stressful being around a bunch of people
as is having a bunch of people come up
to you that know what you look like and
you don't know who they are what they
look like or what their agendas or
intentions are um this last one dude i
felt sick when i was in there but i i
had never my live feed wasn't as big the
first year the second year like last
year uh this most recent one when i was
walking around i was getting grabbed
every few seconds and and being in a
crowd of that many people and getting
grabbed from all angles it's a little
intimidating right like you don't know
who's gonna [ __ ] shake you in your
back or or want to shake your hand for
that matter um
yeah it was a different energy all
around it was very corporatized it was
not it wasn't anything that i really
liked i'll be at the emerald cup but not
neces i'll be in the city of the emerald
cup i may not attend next year's emerald
cup um but i'll be there throwing
throwing our little shin dig of course
that that we are now making annual
uh hell yeah something to look forward
to
yeah yeah it's gonna be i mean last year
it was kind of put together at the last
minute you know and and we weren't sure
who was gonna show up um one person
tried to hijack the whole thing and
saying that there was a [ __ ] dui
checkpoint no one go there come to my
party because i had a little i had a
little instagram um
like uh circle you know where a bunch of
us were in the message and uh that's how
we were communicating about what was
gonna happen where it was gonna be and
all that and the last minute after the
emerald cup when everybody was about to
go someone's like hey dui checkpoint
everybody watch out which there was no
dui checkpoint and they were like hey
come to this barbecue place
so yeah
yeah opportunistic to say the least i
mean just just relating back to the
point about the emerald cup itself i'd
heard some whispers from people that
like
you know basically there was like a
small if not large consensus from
breeders that they were possibly going
to shrug off the next emerald cup and go
to the cup that was being held in mass
on that same weekend
you given any thought to that one at all
and i mean if you heard that there was a
sizable group of people doing that would
you consider doing that
um
no because we have our party uh and
everything like that but i know that one
person in particular was trying to push
everyone in that direction
and saying that this person and that
person was going to be there but then i
talked to the actual people and they're
like no i'm not going there so i think
one person in particular is trying to
make that happen and uh
yeah i don't know i i think it's cool i
mean there should be events going on at
both places and stuff but we have we
have our annual party now the the canned
illuminati party so yeah
for sure something to drag people in if
they were being allured by that uh that
other offer
yeah yeah
so a little bit off topic but i really
really really want to delve into it what
are some of the lines from other
breeders coming out in the future that
you're aware of that you're looking
forward to um
csi a lot of the stuff he's been doing
the triangle kush s1s his old family
purple reversals and the trump reversals
those are going to be phenomenal um
i don't make any secret of it that him
and body are like my top two favorite
breeders and i consider uh csa kind of a
mentor man like he's he's
he's uh
he's hard to get close to he's very hard
to get close to and there's a reason for
that there's a lot of scammers and stuff
and he doesn't want to deal with it and
i don't blame him but um
when we started becoming good friends he
really has taken care of me brought me
in
put me where i needed to be
and to meet a lot of people that i that
i should have been already met you know
um
his lines he he tests
he tests way more seeds than i even do
um he does large populations of pops
before they're ever released um the abc
that's a line i've hunted for over a
decade he's been on hunting it for
probably two decades hunting the abc the
australian bastard cannabis and a lot of
people don't see the value in it because
it's weird looking it's kind of hempy
it's not really potent um
but there's a lot more value to strains
than just recreational potency so i'm
looking forward to that a lot um that's
something a lot of people have been
hunting and he managed to to bring
to bring forward with painted forest
farms which is really cool and a young
guy getting into this the scene that
happened to stumble upon that and and is
making his name with it which is really
cool and it seems like he's taking a
genuine interest in cannabis history and
we need more young people like that
doing it
yeah definitely who else who else um
i'm hoping with the dj short work with
the newberry and stuff like that we're
gonna see a return to the old blue
sativa stuff i really hope that that's
gonna be the case with it um i have some
of my friends el jefe he's doing chem 91
work um i'm really really proud of him
and the bx work he's doing with that um
i'm excited to see skunk va doing some
projects um i think that's really cool
someone worked with that line that long
uh not so dog really stoked to see his
work that he's doing the the creator of
mendo perps the one who brought it to
the table um
let's see who else pip swede one of my
one of my best friends uh his irene sour
diesel stuff i've smoked it it's [ __ ]
killer killer killer [ __ ] he's doing a
lot of sour work a lot of irene work a
lot of death star work um
yeah man uh so good seeds he's new to
seed breeding he's behind breeders
direct seed co uh he's working a lot of
pipelines but he's trying to keep him
unique and and i applaud him for that
you know so yeah
yeah that's just to name a few i'm
probably forgetting a bunch
yeah so much to talk about i mean the
first one which picked my ears when you
mentioned it was how i totally forgot uh
csi who i i totally agree an amazing
breeder um he's
he's got that cutting the you know the
keeper one that he calls the trump or
like you know it's got the word trump in
the name and uh it was interesting to
see the backlash like how many people
are so against trump as a politician
that they were like willing to boycott
this cut and it's [ __ ] phenomenal
like i mean the old family purple like
geez that's some good weed like what do
you think about like people just being
put off australian purely because of the
name
they must not understand the history of
how that name was came up with it was
done by um
our buddy redbeard uh at uh portland csi
um
uh i i don't wanna say his real name but
yeah he did the obamacush he's
responsible for the obamacare he
selected that cut made his name with
that cut he also selected the trump and
named it it wasn't it wasn't caleb who
named it and it was because he had an
obama it was made during that era now we
have the trump era doesn't mean he
supports him in any
way shape or form i don't think
most breeders would be a huge trump
supporter just because of the uh
the pushback from corporatocracy you
know that's invading our community but
then again i don't you know i don't know
i don't support any politicians i think
they should all be hung
anarchy matt
yeah they're all dirty but yeah you know
i i think if they understood that it
wasn't necessarily like a pro-trump move
it was just because the first one was
named obama the second one named trump
that's why you know i think if they
understood that it would be a lot
different
of course so you mentioned
uh pip swede working with the irene
sauer that's interesting because a lot
of people talk very highly of irene yeah
it also goes quite you know it's it's
not as well known among the circles
there's a lot of other cuts and combined
with the sour like it's it's like a
powerhouse it's like these two
really highly regarded cuts when do you
think we can expect to see some of that
going live
you know pip is another one that um
he's a perfectionist and when you're a
perfectionist in in the artistic
breeding world
it
you want to make sure everything's
[ __ ] sound and he will not release
that [ __ ] until it's absolutely perfect
and i think i think in the next year
you're going to see the irene sour
irene i think isn't as used because it's
not as photogenic as a lot of other cuts
it's not a beautiful cut it's not very
resinous it's very awkward looking it
doesn't look like most og cushes
but the chirps on that [ __ ] is crazy it
has a beautiful high
and it breeds really well in fact it has
a better structure than most og kush's
it looks like it has some bubba in it um
and it looks like it might have
something else in it too i'm not sure
what else is in it but it's it's most
likely an og bubba across to something
else and it maintains that that above a
structure where you don't have to
[ __ ] majorly stake it
yeah
yeah okay so do you know what sour he
used in order to make these seeds is it
a femme cross or did he use like karma's
sour release and get like a male from
that
he uses uh he has a few sours he keeps
he has what's referred to as the choco
or a cob well it has a lot of different
names but that old cut of sour the
what's considered the manny cut the
original cut
which is the original name for the sour
from the sour crew it would be the manny
cut
fondo i think is the one that named that
um
he also has a sour
i believe from res dogs work that was
used to
make the original death star and i do
believe that is the one that he used in
the irene sour diesel but i might be
wrong he might have used the choco cut
he's done his own sour bx work along the
along the lines that karma did using
obviously a different cut than karma's
using to do this um karma has his own
selected cut from res dog's work
and
pip's been doing both the i believe the
the original manny cut choco cut and the
the one used in death star he's been
doing back crosses using that stuff
interesting and what do you think about
karma's sour i mean i don't i've never
smoked or anything but i mean
it looks it looks true to form right it
does look like a salary yeah he's done a
great job with it the head banger and
all that stuff came out beautiful and it
came out true to form with a sour you
know headbanger i think is is probably
the best non-traditional but amer i
would say
modern headband
you could call it like the sour og
headband as opposed to the northern
light super skunk i think it's probably
one of the best releases of a modern
headband line and seed form
and so what are your thoughts on the
very original sour i mean just to clara
i might be [ __ ] you know insert that
alex jones meme where it's like i'm kind
of [ __ ] but um
you know like is the original sour
around or is that just long gone
okay so if you're not [ __ ] this has
been something that is it's one of the
hardest nuts to crack um i've talked to
almost everyone involved
except for manny and i don't think
anyone's really talked to manny um
vondo and klopp were roommates back then
and this is the story from bondo uh
vondo was the one who had the bag of
seeds for manny and it was labeled our
diesel now their diesel was either chem
91 or
a bad seed from the chem 91 which could
be a chem 91 hybrid
or an s1 of chem 91 they don't know
they're not sure but it was from seed
supposedly
that's from that bag of our diesel was
selected the manny cut which is what we
know as the choco sour diesel today
that's the best that anybody's put it
together um
that you have michael klopp um who is
who is the weasel and he is given many
stories on many different podcasts that
don't quite jive with each other he's a
super nice dude but i'm not sure how
accurate he remembers it or can retell
it
but he was the the partner of or not
partner but uh roommate of vondo um i
don't want to go into details about
all the personal interactions of people
dating each other's girlfriends and
stuff but vondo eventually left london
left new york went to cali and it was
out of the picture when
the weasel started pushing sour diesel
which was supposedly from the pakistanis
that said our diesel now i don't know
how much of that's true you know it's
one person's
recollection of it but it was the person
who was involved heavily in it so you
you kind of have to tender
uh the human story with facts and try to
put together
facts from a bunch of different sources
and that seems to jive the most
yeah of course
so
seems like the sour to me has like an
even more muddy story than the chem dog
would you agree
oh [ __ ] yeah it's it's it's so muddy
dude and it's just because people have
uh
an agenda i mean you have aj who has his
agenda to be mr sauer you have the
weasel who aj kind of attributes to it
but
the weasel wants to pretend that he was
more of a breeder in it than it being
just kind of happenstance and
maybe he remembers himself being more of
a breeder than he was and that's cool
you know um
that you know people remember [ __ ] way
differently looking back uh you know it
was a long time ago
but somewhere in there is the truth and
uh
the one thing that that goes
in line with both the 91 and the sour to
me in my opinion is the super skunk you
always see super skunk expressions in
both of those lines that's the thing
that's the bind that ties you know
of course of course so
at the end of the day
it seems to me like a lot of genetics
just tie back to super skunk and
northern lights
how do you feel about that
yeah no i mean uh afghani one skunk one
northern lights and haze that's that's
the basis of almost everything now
granted you have malawi you have other
africans you have other lines that have
been brought in over time but but the
overall gene pool is afghani one skunk
one northern lights super skunk you know
like all those baseline haze
specifically those are the ones that
make up a majority of the population of
what we have today
yeah okay so the final one i wanted to
ask you about which i always get
messages about from me is it's a smaller
community of followers but god they're
passionate the piff
is it around
tell me about it
yeah the piff's still around um
hazer has a pif and i do believe from uh
people he's given it to and that i trust
their palette um that it is the real pif
um it's an old nl5 haze cut old nl5 haze
and that's all it is but it's a very
specific cut the the cut most people are
searching for when they say the word
pith
um is the frankie it has a lot of
different names the frankie the poo day
the the washington heights hayes the
uptown hayes stuff like that
it's all referring to a specific case
that smells like a catholic church like
the frankincense and myrrh type uh smell
along with some metallic which you'll
find in old like positronics haze along
with some ammonia which you're getting
from the northern light aspect in the
steve murphy afghani that's what people
mostly refer to now there's also the
mango pif which is an older mango type
pheno that came out of the same northern
light 5 haze
you can see that same similar phenotype
and work
in the in enchantees mango haze line
you're seeing that same pheno being
worked with similar type highs
granted
most people see less of the mango pith
up in new york because it takes a lot
longer to grow
it's not as in high demand as the
frankie piff
but now i think that the term piff has
been thrown on a lot of [ __ ] that
has nothing to do with the pif the um
the cuban black haze cut going around a
lot of people call that pif it's not
piff it's it's not the frankie
specifically but people also use the
term piff interchangeably with dank fire
things like that refer to really good
weed as that that pif you know that's a
big rapper thing to do
so
yeah that that's that's kind of the the
roundabout story on the piff
yeah yeah another one of those ones
where it's just it's been elusive for
the most of the general public i guess
yeah i was fortunate to have it early on
um i didn't know what the [ __ ] it was
when i was handed it i had no idea i'm
not from the east coast so i'm not i
wasn't privy there wasn't anything
online about the pif during that era
nobody was talking about the pif during
that era when i got it but it was from a
friend i was actually a nemesis online
nemesis the dude that would troll the
[ __ ] out of me um early on they ended up
becoming friends with me because he had
the same passion i did and we eventually
saw that in each other and he said yo
i'm gonna hand you these seeds dude
it's called the piff you're gonna thank
me later he said you know and then he
put the stipulations on it you can't
breed with it pure never release it pure
or you're gonna have some dominicans
after your ass and you don't want that
no i don't want that
um
and i didn't know what it was but when i
got it when i grew it when i used it i
realized how special it truly was
so if we just kind of link back to a
point you made you mentioned shanti and
you know some of the mango in his lines
just take a little sidestep of him for a
moment it wasn't all too long ago maybe
you know a bit over a month or more that
we sadly saw the passing of neville how
do you feel about neville given you know
you had that interaction with him and
more importantly how do you think he's
going to be remembered what do you think
his legacy should be
neville was a complex man um
i i did work with neville in 2010 2011
during his resurgence i was i wasn't
friends with him during the heyday of
the seed bank or anything like that i'm
way too young for that but i did have
the privilege of interacting with him
and doing a little bit of work with him
during 2010 and 2011. um
he's a complex man
um
a lot of guys that operated during that
era had to have some shade to him you
know um
he may not have been the best at keeping
promises or delivering on them
i don't want to bad-mouth him though
because there is no doubt there is no
doubt that cannabis
genetics would not be where they are now
without the seed bank in his early work
and all this [ __ ] he is an absolute
legend in that and he had the [ __ ]
balls to run that it took a large set of
steel [ __ ] cajones to [ __ ] pull
off running the sea bank like he did in
such a gangster fashion you know the
cannabis castle
that's his legend and that's what i hope
he's remembered for i we all have our
quirks i mean there's a lot of people
that don't like anything about me and
and
maybe that's that's justified you know
in their in their eyes um
you know it's going to be the same way
with neville we're all complex quirky
characters to even be involved in this
business it's it's
it's uh
it is sad that he passed there were a
lot of stories left to tell from neville
there are a lot of questions left to be
answered from neville um and we can't
get those answers now i know he has a
son that was also interested in breeding
and i expect to see a resurgence from
him at some point
um
i don't know how heavily involved he got
with his dad's stuff or how much he more
he knew than anyone else about his dad's
stuff
with that said i hope i hope if he does
pop up he carries on the legacy even
better
of course and so it seems as though
a lot of people in magazines articles
have been quick to
kind of say that you know his haze was
his big contribution and undeniably he
cleaned it up but i feel like there are
some other lines that are really in
contention for his legacy like i mean
we've been talking about nl hayes for a
while now and i feel like that's more
his than what just pure haze is
how do you feel about how do you feel
about him being labeled as like you know
like haze was his contribution
um yeah his wasn't really his
contribution the nl5 haze was his actual
work and i think it's uh
it may be even more important than the
than the haze by itself um granted he
couldn't have made it without the haze
but as far as bringing forward potency
and modern lines nl5 haze was absolutely
integral it was the most grown line in
the 90s if you go back and look at all
the high times issues from the 90s all
you'll see from your submissions is nl5
has that's it um
that the super skunk um ultra skunk i
believe was the original name for it
that kind of stuff the afghan tea work
which may or may not be afghani one he
said it was maple leaf indica but that
may be because sam's afghani won that
was sam's and him and sam were ultimate
enemies you know in everything they did
have some interaction early on but
you know they became very hate-filled
for each other and i think that that
drove uh a lot of their brilliance and a
lot of their madness you know
yes i mean undeniably it was inevitable
we're gonna get to this but uh how do
you feel about our buddy dave watson's
acquisition of the fire lost shares and
uh the coinciding announcement of their
breeding program
wow
um
dave watson's another very interesting
character
you know
you can't talk about dave without
talking about rob clark
they go hand in hand there is no one in
this
world i respect more when it comes to
breeding than rob clark he's done more
for advancing the breeding of this plant
whether through science and through
education
no one's done more than rob clark with
that sam is an amazing breeder he's a
brilliant dude there again no denying
that he is he was some of the first
doing male reversals uh some you know
early on doing reversals
there's so much that he's offered this
community and he's a uh
he is an often vilified figure and and
not for no reason not for no reason
i think his attitude and how he
interacts with people drives a lot of
that um there is a lot of debate on
whether there was some
cohesion with the dea whether that was
true or not
um
there's not a lot of
physical paper proof but when you know i
was working with neville neville said
yeah he was known as uncle sam because
he walked around with this goddamn de
agent and everybody knew that dude the
dea agent
but
whether he ratted on people or not
there's no real paper proof of that and
i don't like to call someone a rat
unless it's on paper that's that's
classless
with that said can sam has always been
about
personal
gain
with cannabis and i know a lot of people
don't feel good about that especially
when it leads to to corporatocracy
bringing in these corporate [ __ ]
like gw pharma and and rob and sam were
integral in gw pharma and cannabis and
their their work with it um
we don't know how much they still have
to do with that uh
the first mentions of philos we can find
online
are from
sam
sam was on icymag we still have the
quotes we still have the screenshots we
still have all that stuff of sam
mentioning philos asking people to send
in their seeds that won't pop these old
seeds that you have in your just send
them in just send in these seeds yeah
they're not worth anything to you just
send them into us and a lot of people
didn't know about tissue culture popping
they didn't know about genetic mapping
they didn't know about crispr they don't
know about any of this stuff and they
don't see the value in it um
and i you know i i almost sent stuff
into them because of it and i'm really
glad i didn't but a lot of really
special stuff was submitted to philos
based on rob and sam's work
um
yeah it's the whole philos fall down has
been kind of interesting to watch i've
been saying for a long time i've been
one of the the loudest people
um fighting against philos for years now
two years i think it was when i first
started really understanding who they
were what they were about that they were
doing these weird shady things like
vouching for themselves by using a shell
company called open cannabis project
um
but i got a lot of backlash from it i
got kept getting called conspiracy
theorists tin foil hat matt you know
like
and and that that isn't a good way to to
feel and being the only person standing
up with a big platform standing up
against a multi-billion dollar
corporation that's not fun that's not a
position i even wanted to be in and i i
thought a lot of nights about it before
i said anything um
so there is some
good feelings coming from the fact that
everybody's finally [ __ ] starting to
wake up and all it took was
a few years of collecting what philos
themselves said and went on the record
as saying and
showing using that and showing them a
mirror of themselves and putting their
words back out there in a cohesive form
that people can understand and look at
and say they are obviously contradicting
themselves they used underhanded and and
non-transparent means to get the
genetics that they have in the data they
have for the purpose of breeding and the
the presentation that was circulated
from 2015
clearly shows that philos had the
direction and goal of ultimately
breeding and right now they're trying to
say it was a new idea that they had and
they're just getting into it but they
were presenting investors with a a
presentation saying that that was their
ultimate goal even back then um how rob
and sam well we know rob is on the chair
uh he's a chairman on the board of
philoso we know that
how sam
and gw pharma are ultimately tied in i'm
not sure philos is working with a
company called gw industries also known
as groundworks industries there's no
clear tie yet to gw pharma but i'm gonna
find that [ __ ] tie i will if there's
one to be found i'm gonna find it um
there's proof cultivar that also goes
under the name of gw industries we have
jeremy plum who started uh open cannabis
project with mowgli homes also involved
with the cultivation classics being a
partner of philos and all this being
this weird incestuous circle of
uh corporations and shell companies all
trying to all for the purpose of
deceiving people and getting the said
data to sell
as a whole to scots they often say that
they're open source but they don't have
an open source license so they're not
open source they when you ask them about
it they'll say that they're working on
getting their license to be open source
but in their rebuttal to this whole
thing they keep saying the using the
word open source to try to trick people
into believing that they're open with
the data everybody can see the data they
haven't published a data set in two
years during those two years they've
tried selling off to scots and monsanto
i asked paige from filos directly have
you ever courted scots monsanto to sell
the data and she said uh
i don't know
which was one of my favorite answers of
all time because scots has heavy ndas
and
she couldn't quite say yes because they
have non-disclosure agreements she
couldn't say no because she's too stupid
and didn't and maybe they've already
been caught in so many lives she didn't
want to get caught in another
of course i mean
it seems to me like if nothing else it's
just the way they've handled the
situation has been quite problematic i
mean even if like let's just let's just
play devil's advocate and say that they
did have best intentions and it was a
recent idea and it wasn't very well
thought out and all of these things
which don't necessarily seem true but
let's just say they are it seems like
it's still being like a pr nightmare 101
on their part so it just seems to
back give you know give credence to the
idea that like no it is what they're
trying to deny
yeah
um i think it's it's blatant
um a lot of people are losing focus on
the idea that they are quote unquote
stealing [ __ ] genetics they didn't
steal anything it was handed to them but
it was handed to them under a false
pretense that's the problem the problem
was the lies the lack of transparency
that um i mean they called me they
outright called me a liar and a
conspiracy theorist when i brought up
their breeding program and their tissue
culture lab six months ago
they called me a conspiracy theorist and
said that that tissue culture lab didn't
exist after they made a press release in
a business publication about the tissue
culture lab so they're talking out both
sides of their mouth and they really
think that our community is so stupid
and so stoned we're not going to catch
on to it and um that that really shows
how they look at us and that they are
not part of our community and they
clearly don't understand what we're
about who we are
yeah certainly certainly
i do however
have some questions myself around
the actual applicability of this data
like you know having a bit of a
molecular biology background i can kind
of understand a lot of the technology
they're talking about and i still don't
understand how they plan to use this
data set to help them breed better
because it seems like it's still a bit
fanciful in some ways like i mean unless
they're planning on doing some actual
like casper 9 christmas stuff but i feel
like that would take a long time to
develop you know the specific primers
they need to change certain loci
so
yeah it just seems like it's so ill
thought out but maybe i'm just [ __ ]
no um i think it's misdirection i think
it's clearly misdirection they intend to
sell the data which is why it's not up
there to view publicly i don't think
they intend to breed [ __ ] um maybe
they'll do some cbd work and lame
attempts at putting markers in but the
problem is that they have short read
data that's why they're having a problem
selling it that's why scott's monsanto
didn't buy is because it's short read
data
i talked with kevin mckernan from
medicinal genomics and and as a
disclaimer they are a direct competitor
of philos so of course he's going to say
certain things that they cast a negative
light on them but i i have to say he's
been very fair in this whole debacle
with philos in explaining the the
science behind it and the fact that
they're using short read data so their
their data sets are incomplete there's a
reason why they're still
confused why forum and the forum cut of
cookies and ogkb are showing up as the
same exact clone when they clearly are
not
um they're still thinking all the og
cushes or s ones of each other even
hybrids and and they they look they come
back as being the same clone it's
because their data sets aren't complete
and with that without complete data sets
with incorrect data sets they're not
going to be able to do the breeding that
they want to do that's and i think they
know that now so all this breeding stuff
is misdirection
from what they're really doing which is
trying to sell everyone's data
yeah okay so how do you feel about uh
molecular farms being granted the rather
broad sweeping utility patents last year
which you know there wasn't an analysis
done by it i can't remember the author's
name but they basically said you know if
i've got my you know my things correct
here seems as if at any point if they
wanted they could pull the plug on the
entire cannabis industry in terms of
like these utility patterns seemingly
cover all cannabis that currently exists
yeah they are very broad sweeping and
the problem with patents once they're
granted it takes an act of god and a lot
of money to fight them it takes a lot of
money to fight them so um
it's it's terrifying um but again
cannabis wasn't
it's always been in the black market the
black markets always existed let them
try to sue us when the [ __ ] black
market let them figure it out you know
we'll go under a thousand different
[ __ ] names so they have no idea who
to sue that's what we'll do um they
fight legally we fight real you know so
they can try to use their [ __ ] but
it's not gonna work and not be affecting
the black market uh the legal market has
already shown in many cases whether it's
bedrock on in in amsterdam or the uh i
can't remember the name of one in israel
they want a monopoly there is going to
be a monopoly
where people have to buy from one
certain source to get their weed they
may make it look like it's not a
monopoly by having a bunch of shell
companies and shell corporations under
them but there's going to be one owner
doing this stuff that's the way it's
going and and that's what it's going to
be we have to fight back the black
market
so do you think that there might be a
certain
event or like you know kind of something
specific to happen before they do you
know bring everything online and just
try to pull the plug on everyone
yeah they're waiting for federal uh
legal legalization at the federal level
um
and it's going to be through people like
when i was going through proof cultivar
and all their employees they have their
own lobbyist they and they have
literally it shows on their page a
multi-billion dollar fluid finances so
they're able to afford these lobbyists
pushing through uh bills when they want
to be pushed through and they're behind
a lot of anti-home grower bills and i
think once people realize that these big
companies proof [ __ ] gw industries
whoever the [ __ ] they really are um
philos all these people are behind these
anti-home growing bills
once people realize that then it's going
to get real disgusting because you're
you're [ __ ] with people's livelihoods
and these aren't people that go to
lawyers these aren't people that use
lawyers to settle [ __ ] and they're gonna
they're gonna run into
a few scary places for them for their
their personal uh their personal
protection you know and that's not for
me that's not me saying i'm gonna do
anything but it's a reality that's this
is what they're dealing with they're not
made
they're not made uh to work in an uh
quasi-legal industry they're soft
they're daddy's money boys
gang gang
straight up um
so i mean ultimately how do you feel
about the idea of technology assisted or
like entirely facilitated breeding
programs would work do you think it's
inevitable that we'll reach a point
where like you know tech assisted
breeding just supersedes like using
first principles and just us you know
picking what we think is good
this is where you'll hear the hippie
side of me come out which there is very
little that exists in my punk rock soul
but god damn it
i truly believe that the plants are
sentient beings and this robo-breeding
[ __ ]
and i think the best quote i ever heard
was from bodhi
i don't need your machine to
to tell me what my plant is i smoke my
bud i know how it is i grow my bud i see
the phenotypes at hand i don't need your
machine to tell me how to breed i've
been doing this long before it and and
the whole machine breeding is it it's
going to have it's it's going to have a
place in it but i think it loses a lot
of the soul a lot of the art behind it a
lot of the art and the soul behind it it
loses a lot of the love between the
plant and the and the grower which
i don't care what anyone says dude like
when i'm depressed my plants are
depressed and it's not just because of
maybe i'm not watering as much maybe i'm
not paying as much attention they feel
it they interact with you you're you
know um
yeah it's it's gonna lose all that if it
all goes to that that kind of breeding
um it has its place in certain medical
applications it will exist um i think
it's cool to work in tandem with it but
never lose the soul never lose the soul
in the art and breeding
i agree i feel like yeah there's a lot
of there's a lot of evidence to suggest
that they definitely interact with us
you know if not just being stimulated by
our voices
exactly
so to kind of change things up get a
little more lighthearted i want to jump
back to some older strains for a minute
you know one i've been thinking about
for a while that i think you probably
have some experience with cali missed
used to hear about it a lot and then it
just kind of fell off you know what do
you think happened there
so kelly missed um i believe
simon himself
i don't want to misquote him because
i've seen people misquote him and he
gets super pissed
but he had lost some of the original
parents to cali mist in a bust back in
the the older days and since then it
hasn't been able to be recreated the
same however i do have an old pack of
original cali mist
here
and
i've been kind of waiting to pop them
myself i don't have the the desire to
to really go down the cali mist route um
i'm kind of hoping that someone comes
along that has that major desire and the
ability to do that and puts these seeds
to good use and and brings it back you
know but um i know i have so many other
projects that i haven't focused on it
but those seeds are there and they're
well stored um for for any real breeder
um with skin in the game so don't don't
be hitting me up [ __ ]
noobs don't be hit me up for my cali
mist it's only going to go to special
people that i know that really have skin
in the game that have a want and desire
to bring this line back
yeah of course
so
you know from all of my observations it
seems like the largest component of good
breeding or a good breeding program at
least is having like really good p1
parental stock on top of good selection
however
for everyone living outside of the us it
can be hard to find truly phenomenal
clones to breed with so you're forced to
deal with seeds
so with so many of us in that situation
should we just constantly be buying
seeds cracking them trying to find
better parents and breed with that or
should we focus on creating strains
um in terms of like
like just trying to make an offspring
that's better than the parents if you
get what i mean by that
yeah um
i think maybe not constantly be buying
seeds because i don't think there's a
constant supply of good parentage out
there i think there's a finite supply
yet there is a lot of seeds out there to
buy but there's a finite supply of good
parent stock
be mindful of it go back and learn a lot
of these baselines these baselines you
can still buy from certain dutch
companies that
and they may not be the best versions of
what they once were but you can still
find those old phenos in those lines i
think that's a great place to start
clones are what they are like the clone
onlys they're great there's a high
demand of them in the us because there's
hype behind certain ones some of them
have some of them have created their own
hype and and are as good as they they
say they are however all these started
with the seed everything starts with the
seed you know um
i think i think things can be created
absolutely magical in any land that
you're at as long as you have good
parent stock and seed stock to work from
overall
how do you feel outdoor bud compared to
indoor and the reason why i asked this
is because you know i love outdoor i
like maybe i should say i love the idea
of outdoor but the reality is i just
still haven't found any outdoor bud that
makes me feel like this is better than
indoor
i think it needs to be um there are
certain lines that want to be run
outdoor as opposed to indoor being the
old colombians the old ties stuff like
that they really truly express better
outdoor than indoor but like modern
lines
it's rare that you'll find something
grown outdoor organically and all that
that really does compare to what you can
get in a uh
in a room that's that's built for that
line
but with that said i mean some of these
old ties the old colombians they only
they only do well outdoors there's a lot
of lines that i have that i don't run
that i keep old heirloom and land race
lines because i don't have an outdoor
space and i don't want to do them the
disservice of trying to grow them indoor
and not getting their full
the full range of phenotypes and
expressions because they were always
grown outdoor and never acclimated for
indoor
so with that being said what's the most
medicinal strain for you personally like
what kind of cures things the best for
you
uh my riot very line helped with my
depression
um i think that's from its tie
expressions in it um it helped i had a
tooth abscess for like two weeks nothing
was helping no no narcotic pills nothing
was [ __ ] helping it was it was
excruciating pain and that riot very the
second that i tried that even though
recreational potency it was minimal
minimal um
but it helped with that pain that nerve
pain and that's when i found that
special medical uh part of it
yeah awesome answer this is this is one
i've got a lot of questions for and uh
if you don't talk about it i understand
but you know i've a lot of a lot of
people in the cannabis community i don't
want to say a lot but you know there's a
substantial minority who come to
cannabis because they're dealing with
addictions in one form or another and
you know they view this as a gateway to
a better life
how has cannabis been involved in your
life in regards to addiction like how do
you view it as like a tool to help
overcome that and what would be your
message for people who maybe are looking
to use cannabis as a means to help fight
whatever kind of demon they're battling
you know in our in our community there
is a lot of shaming um of people that
use our use or have used other drugs uh
but from the era i came from usually if
you were dealing weed you were dealing
other [ __ ] too and in dealing other [ __ ]
you usually got involved in other [ __ ]
um for personal use or otherwise i've
been pretty open about my use of opiates
in my my you know my past with heroin my
past with female my past with all kinds
of narcotics i i went on the whole gamut
it was it was a part of our punk rock
scene unfortunately a lot of my best
friends have died because of it
cannabis took me in a whole new
direction it gave me a lot of hope that
i didn't have um it gave me a way to
kind of realize that i had value in this
world
that i had something to offer this world
you know aside from just playing punk
rock music and being [ __ ] up and just
doing [ __ ] up [ __ ]
um with that said
every day there isn't a day that goes by
that some of the people who don't like
me don't call me a [ __ ] junkie
that's they do it to be hurtful but at
the same time it shows their ignorance
and it shows their ability to understand
that most of the old school dealt with
this at some point most of a lot of the
old breeders around were at one time
dealing with opiate abuse you know it
was just a part of the deal
i wish people would stop the shaming
because i mean
whether people want to admit it or not
cannabis is a drug it is a drug it
affects your central nervous system you
can get high from it that is a drug
for all intents and purposes
whether you're using it for escaping
reality or not it you know we're using
it medically that's up to you you're you
know it's what you can deal with
yourself looking at yourself in the
mirror and be happy with i i try to be
outspoken about
the the harm reduction using cannabis as
opposed to getting off of opiates using
cannabis to do it i try to be open about
it and talk about it only because every
time i do i get messages from you know
20 30 people thanking me saying you know
i'm dealing with this and i'm scared to
even talk about it out in the open
because i don't want to be called a
junkie like you get called a junkie but
if it helps them if then that's that's
all that i give a [ __ ] about i don't
care about the people who call me a
junkie they obviously don't know me you
know but it but it is it's a hard stance
to take in this community and lately
i've been seeing other breeders um
family members of breeders come out and
talk about their their struggles with
addiction and i'm it makes me so [ __ ]
proud to see it because it's not an easy
stance to take people are very very
judgmental in this community and you'd
think this would be the most accepting
community for it
yeah that's a really wonderful sentiment
so just to kind of jump back to some of
your work you're currently doing i
totally forgot to ask you about this
earlier my apologies
the platinum banana line you mentioned
it at the start you know it's obviously
a very popular line do you have future
plans to work it out further
i do um i need to get my mail back
luckily before the whole moon situation
i stored my mail with uh cecil
and uh
why yeast farms has my mail as well so
hopefully i can get that back and and
continue to work the line it's very very
special in uh breeding against dominant
traits like the deep chunk
is notorious for being a really hard
plant to breed with it always always
always dominates everything that it
touches and uh the platinum banana is
one of those lines where it allowed the
best traits of deep chunk to come
through which is the resin production
it's a uh density and
and its overall look that beauty of the
blackness that it has
but it's it's terps aren't that great
and the potency it's okay but it's not
the best and platinum banana allowed the
best traits to come through and i'm
really proud of that line the chunky
monkey line um
as well as the when i crossed into the
highland tie it allowed the best traits
of the highland tie to come through the
juicy fruit tie and uh and and kept with
some of the banana trades kept that
banana terp i mean when people people
want banana og it's usually because
they're searching for banana terps not
because they want og you can find og
anywhere but that banana terp is very
special and it and it brings that to
every line it touches
yeah definitely i'm certainly on the
lookout for that one but to jump to
another hybrid
another male you've been using recently
you've been working with the skittles
cube line and i wanted to know what was
it specifically about that like maybe
for example it was the structure or like
the nose or like whatever it may be what
was it about you that drew you towards
that one and what's your plans going
forward with it
i don't have any plans going forward
with it um what i found in the z cube
line the the mail and how it bred was
that it actually was nothing like this
girls clone
and that's what really drew me to it i'm
not i'm not too enthused about the
skittles clone i had a friend that
pushed me to pop a bunch of the the
skittle stuff he was saying it's hype
you know it's got the best [ __ ] this is
what people want i wasn't enthused about
it but also i tried to remember you know
i have my own views on stuff and maybe i
need to open up you know and look at a
way other people view [ __ ] maybe they
know better than me in modern age with
modern strains because i don't pay a lot
of attention to it
um
with that said what i found i loved in
it i found an old hindu kush type plant
that was [ __ ] rank absolutely ranked
not fruity um it does breed some fruity
traits in certain lines but they're
recessive so you don't see it as often
but i loved everything it brought to all
the lines that i crossed with it um it
just taken it back to a throwback hindu
kush and i thought that was [ __ ] rad
um but with that said
it's not very skittles-y
it's not what people expect from
skittles so there is that but i try to
make that super clear
wow that's it's a really interesting
point because i've got a friend who's
about to pop the same pack i believe and
he asked me he said oh do you think i'll
find like hindu kush
finos and i was like oh is that the mail
they used initially and he's like yeah
and i was like well i mean if it's a bx3
you probably shouldn't like i mean if
they've done their job you probably
shouldn't if they feel about it
if they've done their job like in a bx3
so back crossing is perfect for
stabilizing a single trade and i think a
lot of people because of
brothers grim specifically with their
work with c99 telling people that it
makes a a pure representation of a clone
that's not how it works reading forward
is the way to
lock in several several traits at once
back crossing locks in a single tray um
taking that to the bx3
it was very uniform i'll say that but it
was so uniform and and and nothing like
skittles
that they'd missed the mark like a
[ __ ] with it um but i see that
in a lot of that process i don't think
people understand the purpose of bat
crossing and i think because of brothers
grimm saying that you know yeah this is
how you back cross and get a perfect
representation of the clone because
technically it's you know 88 of the
genetics et cetera et cetera that's not
how it really works though it's it's for
stabilizing a single trait not multiple
traits um but it was uniform it was
uniform i'll say that in structure and
appearance but it was nothing like
skittles at all
with that said
i've seen many people pop z cube and get
completely different but uniform things
from that line and i don't know that
that line was really
what they said it was
i don't know that they didn't take that
line whatever seeds they had and throw
it into several different lines with
different names that's what i saw when
popping a big wide swath of the dying
brain stuff um
i like shiloh i don't i i think brandon
was a kind of
clown shoes
um
yeah [ __ ] dude that's my favorite thing
that's ever come out of the cannabis
community
the clown shoes one dude just that one
video like i'll die a happy man having
been involved with the cannabis
community and just seeing that video
like [ __ ] it's brilliant i it's saved on
my phone forever or ever
please send it to me please oh yeah i'll
send it to you oh god yeah i've kept it
forever because it's it's [ __ ]
hilarious but yeah that dude's a wingnut
um
shiloh is is is an interesting dude i i
he's likable but i i don't think that um
he was as involved with a lot of these
projects as maybe he should be because
people have all kinds of stories
plants tell the truth and when you pop
you know 12 different strains from a
company they're supposed to be 12
different things and they all look
identical
there's an issue there's an issue
they stuffed the seeds
they beat and switched
yeah wow there you go i have to let my
buddy know
so
just to jump on to something we spoke
about earlier when you were talking
about how you know different land races
perform better outdoors and it's almost
like you know a bit of an injustice to
do them indoors
what are some land race lines that you
would really love to see pop their heads
up you know not necessarily that you
think will because like you know
someone's got the seeds or whatever but
you would just be really stoked if they
did happen
i'd like to see the lines that i
selected of colombian black to pop up
that gage green uh used and claimed as
his own
um
i'd like to see that pop back up and
with that said that was from brazilian
seed co who is a well-known scammer um
one of one of uh
kind of our circle's friends went over
to his operation and saw how he was
running it and it was all
cross-contamination cross-pollination so
calling that line colombian black may
not be
a truism you know but it was the li what
he called the line and that specific
line was really special and a lot of
people used it over the years but i'd
like to see it come back pure um i think
gage released it in something he called
a bastard series which was
probably because i selected it and he
just wanted to [ __ ]
throw shade you know but it was special
but it was a long 23 week 26 week line
yeah dude i think i actually had some of
those seeds before uh my seed collection
a few years back got stolen so
damn
yeah that's that hurts
yeah i feel like you haven't haven't
really been in the community for very
long if you haven't had it happen to you
oh yeah that's for sure dude it'll
happen at some point
that's it man
so
what are some of the boxes that you're
looking for like a strain or a clone to
tick before you bring it into the
library and are you regularly looking to
bring new things into the library or are
you just kind of waiting for something
special to more so present itself
you know i go off um i don't really go
hunting i don't trade a lot with people
with that said i brought a lot in after
the moon incident but i don't do a lot
of trading um which is funny because i
you know i've been accused of stealing
clones from people's rooms and [ __ ] and
i'm a hermit i don't go into other
people's rooms and i don't trade i don't
like trading it's not a big thing that i
do
because of of certain things like that
um
i when i look for bringing something in
it's usually because someone i really
respect and trust tells me this [ __ ] is
[ __ ] insane you've got to try it um a
lot of my friends know that
personally like for my smoke i can't
smoke afghani based stuff it makes me
paranoid and depressed so if they tell
me it's something that's really special
on a spectrum of of something that i can
smoke and enjoy that's something that
that interests me especially if i
respect that person and know that they
really know good weed
yeah yeah definitely on to our last
questions before the quickfire ones
it incorporates your favorite person sub
cool
oh yeah
here we go
yeah no buddy of everyone
so
some people say that certain parents
contribute certain uh traits to
offsprings you know and sub says that
the male is what imparts the potency and
the female is more like the structure
have you ever found anything like
yourself or do you just find it's a mix
of random traits expressed from each
parent and there's no like hard fast
rule of thumb
there's there's definitely no hard fast
rule of thumb science tells us that
different different traits align
differently with different parents it's
there's no that is such a odd blanket
statement and tells me he has no [ __ ]
clue what he's talking about when it
comes to breeding um everything is a
case-by-case uh basis not just strain by
strain but fino by fino how those traits
will and alleles will align with align
with each other so yeah there's no way
to do that with that said i remember
neville saying specifically with hayes
that he did not like how the female haze
bred but he liked how the male hazes
bread that it imparted the best traits
of haze and with someone like that that
worked so extensively with the haze i
would i would probably uh listened to
him in that fashion but with that said
it won't be always indicate it's a case
by case and parent by parent and uh
basis you know you really have to
to keep that in mind in science things
don't line up necessarily all the time
the same ways
yeah for sure for sure
so yeah he's a [ __ ]
so on to our last questions
i need to have a little thing where it's
like the views expressed on the show are
not exactly that of my own
yeah you do you really do
so on to our last set of questions um
first and foremost i wanna i wanna run
some similar ones by what we wrapped up
with last time to see if your point of
view has changed at all so the first one
what is your favorite strain of all time
uh
it'd be a few it'd be the bubba sativa
um
my clockwork orange
and rye berry so i i don't remember what
i said last time but that's and oh east
coast sour diesel strawberry cream from
cbf that is the best uh male i've ever
found from anything for being true
breeding and breeding amazing trades
nice last time you said right berry
oh yeah it's always gonna be tops
yeah i think you even mentioned bubba
sativa in the mix as well so there's
some consistency i dig i dig it so
next one what is the worst strain in
your opinion
buckeye purple
shots fired
yeah yeah i remember see
there are a few people
that would be
a lot less respected if c depot the old
forum was still around but they scammed
a lot of people so they shut their forum
down
but there are a few people from that
forum that have made some really bold
claims lately whether they're saying
that urkel is from their family or
they're saying they created buckeye
purple out of all northern lights
genetics that you know this and that um
melvan
she started
not that many years ago it was during
the sea depot days we all saw her first
grows we saw her bragging about buying
bodies you know recently released nl5
line
and uh we saw the trash that she was
putting out there known as as buckeye
purple it's garb um
people probably hadn't been
as as knowledgeable about chitrali and
its beautiful magenta traits and and
stuff that it throws and that it dries
pretty brown for the most part and
smells like hay and they look at that it
looks pretty in magenta and that's new
to them so they go for it but i have
rarely met anyone that goes damn that's
some dank [ __ ] you know uh that that's
actually smoked it and run it
yeah no that's a valid point so next one
this is a bit of a new one but i love
asking all of our new guests
what's your favorite food
favorite food
choco tacos
i love it
choco tacos and and what was that [ __ ]
at disneyland the pineapple i can't
remember what it's [ __ ] called off
the top of my head but it's at the tiki
room you can get these pineapple things
uh iced pineapple things that are
delicious
oh man i wouldn't know but you got my
mouth watering
yeah it's it's [ __ ] delicious but
yeah choco tacos and um bread i like
bread a lot okay
what sourdough whole grain what are we
talking
i like yeast rolls that are kind of
sweet and hawaiian rolls that are sweet
yeah dude sweet hawaiian rolls are the
[ __ ] bomb
aren't they dude i can eat like i
literally eat that all the time all the
time
i stay fully stocked too much
we'll definitely leave that in
[Laughter]
alrighty so next question you're on a
desert island you can only take two
strains with you you don't have to
cultivate him you've just somehow got an
endless supply what two
um if i were gonna cultivate him it
would be nl5 and haze
just because i know how much variance
comes from nl5 haze and how much amazing
[ __ ] uh has resulted from it
if i only had it to smoke right barry
and bubba sativa and maybe maybe silver
pearl maybe silver pearl in there i'm
pretty a pretty big fan of the silver
pearl cut pips has
man that's one that doesn't get a lot of
you know good publicity and i always
thought maybe it was because like early
pearl was like you know more of like
that cash crop of variety and obviously
it used silver pearl what's what's the
real silver pearl like
um if you if you go and look at his feed
i i suggest that anybody who listens to
this goes and checks out at that sign
pip sweet on instagram he's got
beautiful pictures up of it it's it it's
it's very photogenic like any modern
variety crazy resin production it is not
narcotic potent it is it is not it's a
very clear-headed quality sativa type
high on an indica frame what people
would normally associate with a sativa
type high
you can find that high in afghanis you
can find it everywhere it's not
necessarily a sativa type high but it's
what people would normally associate
with sativas and i [ __ ] love that
thing plus my girlfriend has lupus and
it treats the nausea from lupus for her
insanely nothing treats it better and uh
yeah that that's that's it's a special
plan
there you go something we all need to
keep an eye out for
yeah
all right he's got a kung fu grip on it
though so
ain't nobody getting i don't even have
it so yeah
no there you go so final question for
our interview today
what is one strain
where if you could go back in time and
get it
you would the one you would pick to go
back and kind of save from being lost to
uh you know the ages
steve murphy's afghani or the afghan tea
you're gonna have to fill us in a little
more on what they are
so steve murphy's afghani is the basis
for all northern lights uh northern
lights one through
twelve i believe we're all based on the
steve murphy afghani line each with
different parents combined in it
afghan tea is what neville said was the
basis for
super skunk and he said it was from the
maple leaf line but i don't believe that
i think it's an afghani one selection
and it's responsible for all the chems
all the sours all the og's that's that
that's that special special plant and i
think that's why i would choose those
two specific lines um you know there's
chocolate tie and other lines i'd love
to see but if i had to go back and
rescue two strains it would be those two
what a fantastic selection
ah
good one huh so
with that being said did you have any
comments or shout outs you wanted to
make
uh yeah shout out to to all the people
who helped me after the moon debacle uh
mad elite from elite cannabis one of my
best friends on earth
um big bread for going and getting my
seeds back from moon because i was no
longer in michigan
he's been a good friend to me surfweed
for taking beautiful shots of the banana
thai um all of our our canned illuminati
crew the pre-pre um all the guys that
you know denali uh actually i shouldn't
name them never mind but all those guys
they know it um csi humboldt and bodhi
of course for being [ __ ] amazing
friends and just being good mentors both
of them and being good human beings and
you know there's so many more people i
could shout out but yeah those those are
the the ones that are constantly closest
to me my buddy resin long who right now
is taking a hiatus from life and kind of
disappeared um he's one of my best
friends on earth and i hope i see his uh
his his smiling face again soon
yeah that sounds like a wonderful
message i hope we all see him back soon
um yeah he's amazing
yeah for sure so with that being said
thank you so much for coming on the show
and for dropping all the knowledge and
the shots fired and the controversy
bombs where would we be without it
thanks for having me brother
not a problem
[Music]
[Applause]
as always a big thank you to matt for
taking the time to come on the show
what'd you guys think
i thought it was killer
shibinsky
fung shan
cali khan
come on the show
make sure as always guys if you enjoyed
it check out the patreon plenty more
exclusive content there for you helps to
make sure the show keeps happening as
always a big shout out to our sponsors
radio ridge nursery the one and only and
newest sponsors
seats here now best in the business
420 australia
organic gardening solutions
patreon gang
as always big old shout out to the one
and only dragonfly earth medicine we
love y'all
[Music]
just kidding i actually hate myself for
doing that
[Music]
i'll see you
somebody
[Music]
so
foreign
[Music]
you